<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622517-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622517</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13653779</doc-number>
<date>20121017</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2011-231749</doc-number>
<date>20111021</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>2</main-group>
<subgroup>15</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>2</main-group>
<subgroup>145</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 40</main-classification>
<further-classification>347 65</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e61">Method of manufacturing liquid ejection head and liquid ejection head</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2012/0212540</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Dietl</name>
<date>20120800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347 29</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2007-55071</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20070300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>14</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>14</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347  9- 12</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 20</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 40</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 42</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 44- 45</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 47</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 49</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 56</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 61</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 65</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 67</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 84- 85</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>10</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>19</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130100208</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130425</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="obligated-assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Canon Kabushiki Kaisha</orgname>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ishikawa</last-name>
<first-name>Masashi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kawasaki</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ono</last-name>
<first-name>Takayuki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kawasaki</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Furukawa</last-name>
<first-name>Masao</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yokohama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Canon USA, Inc., IP Division</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Canon Kabushiki Kaisha</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Nguyen</last-name>
<first-name>Thinh</first-name>
<department>2861</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A method of manufacturing a liquid ejection head includes: defining a first imaginary reference line along the longitudinal direction of a base member and measuring the distances between the first imaginary reference line and at least two liquid supply port portions of a liquid supply port row, including defining a second imaginary reference line passing the liquid supply port portion at the shortest distance from the first imaginary reference line and the liquid supply port portion at the longest distance from the first imaginary reference line respectively from among the at least two liquid supply port portions and defining the second imaginary reference line between two imaginary lines parallel to the first imaginary reference line.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="60.96mm" wi="149.27mm" file="US08622517-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="215.39mm" wi="177.38mm" file="US08622517-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="205.57mm" wi="153.84mm" file="US08622517-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="169.67mm" wi="142.58mm" file="US08622517-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="195.75mm" wi="175.26mm" file="US08622517-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="200.66mm" wi="187.28mm" file="US08622517-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="213.28mm" wi="177.04mm" file="US08622517-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="193.97mm" wi="188.64mm" file="US08622517-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="113.37mm" wi="167.22mm" file="US08622517-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="209.13mm" wi="193.29mm" file="US08622517-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="190.75mm" wi="178.48mm" file="US08622517-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a method of manufacturing a liquid ejection head and a liquid ejection head.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A liquid ejection recording apparatus configured to eject a liquid such as ink (hereinafter, referred to simply as a recording apparatus) is widely used and implemented in output apparatuses and the like relating to computers. In recent years, there has been a demand for a liquid ejection head (hereinafter, also referred to simply as a recording head or a head) having a longer printing width in order to output high quality images at higher speed.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Examples of widely known general recording apparatuses include a system of performing printing by scanning a recorded medium such as paper with the recording head while ejecting ink. Also known is a so-called full-line-type recording apparatus which is capable of performing high-speed printing by fixing a head having a long printing width corresponding to the length of the recorded medium above a conveyor belt that conveys the recorded medium and scanning the recorded medium therewith.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The proposed configuration of the full-line-type recording head described above is a configuration in which a plurality of liquid ejection devices having a suitable length (having a suitable number of nozzles) are arranged on a base member to realize a recording head having a long printing width as a whole described in Japanese Patent Laid-Open No. 2007-55071.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In the recording head in this configuration, a method of forming reference points on the base member to allow the liquid ejection devices to be bonded at predetermined positions on the base member and applying an adhesive agent or bonding the liquid ejection devices with respect to the reference points is employed.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">However, if the length of the base member is increased to obtain a longer printing width, the base member may warp in the short side direction. In other words, the reference points formed on the base member are shifted in the short side direction, and if the adhesive agent is applied on the basis of the shifted reference points, there arises a problem that the adhesive agent may enter liquid supply port portions for supplying ink to the liquid ejection devices. As a countermeasure for such a situation, a method of detecting an amount of warping of the base member and changing positions where the adhesive agent is applied individually from one liquid supply port portion to another according to the amount of warping has been contemplated. However, with this method, the productivity of the heads is reduced.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">A method of manufacturing a liquid ejection head including a base member having a liquid supply port row including a plurality of liquid supply port portions for supplying liquid formed in the longitudinal direction, and a plurality of liquid ejection devices arranged at positions corresponding to the liquid supply port portions and bonded to the base member with an adhesive agent, the method including: defining a first imaginary reference line along the longitudinal direction of the base member and measuring the distances between the first imaginary reference line and at least two liquid supply port portions of the liquid supply port row; defining a second imaginary reference line passing through the liquid supply port portion at the shortest distance from the first imaginary reference line and the liquid supply port portion at the longest distance from the first imaginary line respectively from among the at least two liquid supply port portions and defining the second imaginary reference line between two imaginary lines parallel to the first imaginary reference line; applying the adhesive agent on the base member on the basis of the second imaginary reference lines; and bonding the liquid ejection devices on the base member with the adhesive agent applied on the base member.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">A method of manufacturing a liquid ejection head including a base member having a liquid supply port row including a plurality of liquid supply port portions for supplying liquid formed in the longitudinal direction, and a plurality of liquid ejection devices arranged at positions corresponding to the liquid supply port portions and bonded to the base member with an adhesive agent, the method including: defining a second imaginary reference line between a first imaginary reference line extending along the longitudinal direction of the base member and a reference point at the largest distance from the imaginary reference line from among a plurality of reference points formed along the longitudinal direction so as to extend along the first imaginary reference line; applying the adhesive agent on the base member on the basis of the second imaginary reference lines; and bonding the liquid ejection devices on the base member with the adhesive agent applied on the base member.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">A liquid ejection head includes a base member having a liquid supply port row including a plurality of liquid supply port portions arranged in the longitudinal direction and liquid ejection devices arranged at positions corresponding to the liquid supply port portions and bonded to the base member with an adhesive agent formed around the liquid supply port portions, wherein the distance between a first opening end of a first liquid supply port portion formed at one end side in the direction of arrangement from among the plurality of liquid supply port portions in the direction of a first short side orthogonal to the longitudinal direction and an outer peripheral end of the adhesive agent formed outside the first opening end on the outer peripheral side is larger than the distance between a second opening end in a second short side direction opposite from the first short side direction and an end portion of the adhesive agent formed outside the second opening end, and the distance between a third opening end of a second liquid supply port portion formed at a center in the direction of arrangement from among the plurality of liquid supply port portions in the direction of the first short side and an end of the adhesive agent formed outside the third opening end on the outer peripheral side is smaller than the distance between a fourth opening end in the second short side direction and an outer peripheral end portion of the adhesive agent formed outside the fourth opening end.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Further features of the present invention will become apparent from the following description of exemplary embodiments with reference to the attached drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic perspective view of a base member used in a method of manufacturing according to a first embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exploded perspective view of the base member illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic perspective view illustrating a measuring device configured to measure positions of reference points on the base member.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a plot showing a positional relationship of reference points formed on the base member in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A and 5B</figref> are explanatory drawings for explaining processes of defining reference lines for applying an adhesive agent according to the first embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a state in which the adhesive agent is applied to the base member in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref> is a plan view of the base member in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a schematic perspective view of a liquid ejection head according to the first embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a schematic plan view of a liquid ejection head according to a second embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a schematic perspective view of a base member used in a method of manufacturing according to a fourth embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a plot showing a positional relationship of reference points formed on the base member in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11A and 11B</figref> are explanatory drawings for explaining processes of defining reference lines for applying an adhesive agent according to the fourth embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a plan view illustrating a state in which the adhesive agent is applied to the base member in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13A</figref> is a schematic perspective view of a liquid ejection head according to the fourth embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13B</figref> is a schematic plan view of the liquid ejection head shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is an explanatory drawing for explaining steps of defining reference lines for applying an adhesive agent according to a fifth embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is a schematic plan view of a liquid ejection head according to the fifth embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Referring now to the drawings, embodiments will be described.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">First Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">A liquid ejection head manufactured by a method of manufacturing according to a first embodiment includes a base member formed with a liquid supply port row having a plurality of liquid supply port portions arranged in a row in the longitudinal direction, and liquid ejection devices arranged at positions corresponding to the liquid supply port portions.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic perspective view of the base member as a supporting member that supports liquid ejection devices <b>4</b> used in the manufacturing method of the first embodiment described later. The material used for a base member <b>1</b> is alumina material having insulating properties, thermal conductivity, and mechanical strength. The base member <b>1</b> is provided with liquid supply port portions <b>2</b> formed in a line in the longitudinal direction and configured to supply ink to the liquid ejection device (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). In the first embodiment, the liquid supply port portions <b>2</b> are composed of two openings, which are through holes, but are not limited thereto, and may be composed of an arbitrary number of openings. Furthermore, the base member <b>1</b> is formed with reference points <b>3</b><i>a </i>to <b>3</b><i>e </i>for measuring positions of the liquid supply port portions <b>2</b> as described later.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">A method of manufacturing the base member <b>1</b> will be described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. In this embodiment, the base member <b>1</b> is unified by laminating a plurality of layers <b>1</b><i>a </i>to <b>1</b><i>e </i>as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The reference points <b>3</b> (<b>3</b><i>a </i>to <b>3</b><i>e</i>) are formed on the first layer <b>1</b><i>a </i>by laser beam machining together with the openings of the liquid supply port portions <b>2</b>. In this case, a laser beam machining apparatus (not shown) is controlled to form the openings of the liquid supply port portions <b>2</b> and the reference points <b>3</b> by performing machining through a series of processes after the first layer <b>1</b><i>a </i>prior to being subjected to laser beam machining is fixed in position. Therefore, the accuracy of the relative positions of the openings of the liquid supply port portions <b>2</b> and the reference points <b>3</b> is very high, and the reference points <b>3</b><i>a </i>to <b>3</b><i>e </i>are formed in a line. Only the openings of the liquid supply port portions <b>2</b> are formed on the second layer <b>1</b><i>b</i>, and a flow channel (not shown) for supplying ink to the liquid supply port portions <b>2</b> is formed on the third layer <b>1</b><i>c</i>. Subsequently, when the layers <b>1</b><i>a </i>to <b>1</b><i>e </i>are stacked and sintered at approximately 1200&#xb0; C., the respective layers <b>1</b><i>a </i>to <b>1</b><i>e </i>are sintered and the unified base member <b>1</b> is formed. The formation of the openings of the liquid supply port portions <b>2</b> or the reference points <b>3</b> on the respective layers <b>1</b><i>a </i>to <b>1</b><i>e </i>may be performed by punching using a die.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The base member <b>1</b> unified by being sintered in this manner is subjected to slight contraction at the time of sintering, and simultaneously is subjected to warping. The warping occurs both in the thickness direction of the base member <b>1</b> (mainly in the longitudinal direction of the base member) and in the in-plane direction (mainly in the short side direction of the base member). The warping in the thickness direction of the base member <b>1</b> (mainly in the longitudinal direction) may be reduced by grinding the base member <b>1</b>, but there is no way to reduce the warping in the in-plane direction (mainly in the short side direction), and the warping that was generated at the time of sintering remains.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Subsequently, a process flow of the method of manufacturing of the first embodiment will be described.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">First of all, a process of measuring the positions of the reference points <b>3</b> will be performed using a measuring device illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. In this process, the base member <b>1</b> is arranged on a plate <b>10</b> with the surface from which the liquid supply port portions <b>2</b> (not illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) are opened facing upward. The plate <b>10</b> is placed on a stage <b>11</b> driving the base member <b>1</b> in the longitudinal direction of the base member <b>1</b> and a stage <b>12</b> configured to drive in the short side direction of the base member <b>1</b>. A camera <b>13</b> for photographing the reference points <b>3</b> is installed above the base member <b>1</b>, and the camera <b>13</b> and the stages <b>11</b> and <b>12</b> are connected to a control device <b>14</b>. The positions of the reference points <b>3</b> are measured by the control device <b>14</b> from the positions of the stages <b>11</b> and <b>12</b> and an image photographed by the camera <b>13</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates the positional relationship of the reference points measured in this manner, and plots <b>20</b><i>a </i>to <b>20</b><i>e </i>corresponding to the respective reference points <b>3</b><i>a </i>to <b>3</b><i>e </i>are illustrated. The plots <b>20</b><i>a </i>to <b>20</b><i>e </i>as described above are arranged along a curved line in keeping with the warping in the short side direction of the base member <b>1</b> generated when manufacturing the base member <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Subsequently, a process of defining the reference lines for applying the adhesive agent on the basis of the positions of the measured reference points is performed. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A and 5B</figref> are explanatory drawings for explaining the process, and are drawings corresponding to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>, an imaginary line connecting the plots <b>20</b><i>a </i>and <b>20</b><i>e </i>at both ends is designated as an inclined reference line (first imaginary reference line) <b>21</b>. Subsequently, distances (interval) a to e from the inclined reference line <b>21</b> to the respective plots <b>20</b><i>a </i>to <b>20</b><i>e </i>(a=e=0 in this embodiment) are calculated. In this embodiment, the plot <b>20</b><i>c </i>is farthest from the inclined reference line <b>21</b> and the distance therefrom is &#x201c;c&#x201d;. Then, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>, an imaginary line which is an imaginary line parallel to the inclined reference line <b>21</b> and which falls within a range of 0&#x3c;A&#x3c;c, where A is a shift amount from the inclined reference line <b>21</b> is defined as a reference line (second imaginary reference line) <b>23</b> for applying the adhesive agent. The reference line <b>23</b> for applying the adhesive agent is most preferably defined so that the shift amount A from the inclined reference line <b>21</b> becomes half the distance c from the farthest plot <b>20</b><i>c </i>(A=c/2). Accordingly, the maximum distance from among the distances between the reference line for applying the adhesive agent and the respective plots is minimized.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Subsequently, a process of applying an adhesive agent <b>30</b> is performed. In this process, the adhesive agent <b>30</b> is applied to the base member <b>1</b> using an application needle <b>31</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref> so as to surround peripheries of the liquid supply port portions <b>2</b> to conform with to the second imaginary reference line <b>23</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref>. Accordingly, a value of the maximum shifted amount from among the positional shifted amounts of the respective liquid supply port portions with respect to the second imaginary reference line <b>23</b>, that is, the position at which the adhesive agent is to be applied is minimized. In the first embodiment, a method of using the application needle <b>31</b> is described as the method of applying the adhesive agent <b>30</b>, other methods such as a transfer system may be employed.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Subsequently, a process of bonding the liquid ejection devices <b>4</b> to the base member <b>1</b> having the adhesive agent applied thereto is performed as described above. In this process, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the liquid ejection devices <b>4</b> as recording element substrates that eject liquid are bonded to the base member <b>1</b> to conform with the positions where the adhesive agent is applied, that is, to conform with the second imaginary reference line <b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In the liquid ejection head obtained in this manner, in addition to the capability of applying the adhesive agent to effective positions which inhibit entry of the adhesive agent into the liquid supply port portions, a large bonding surface area between the adhesive agent and the liquid ejection devices is secured. Therefore, a high bonding strength of the liquid ejection devices is obtained. In this case, the positions of the liquid ejection devices are different from one liquid ejection head to another, and hence it is to be noted that ink ejection timing needs to be controlled individually when mounting the heads on a main body.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The liquid ejection head obtained by the method of manufacturing described above has a form in which the relationship between an opening end and the adhesive agent satisfies the following relationship in the outermost (on end portion side in the direction of arrangement) first liquid supply port portion from among the plurality of liquid supply port portions. In other words, the distance between a first opening end and an outer end of the adhesive agent applied outside the first opening end which is determined in the direction orthogonal to the longitudinal direction of the base member is different from the distance between a second opening end opposite the first opening end and an outer end of the adhesive agent applied outside the second opening end. The magnitude relation of the distances is different from that in the case of the second liquid supply port portion in the vicinity of a center portion of the base member, and the difference between absolute values of the distances is equal to that in the case of the second liquid supply port portion.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In the first embodiment, the positions of the reference points <b>3</b> are measured instead of measuring the positions of the respective liquid supply port portions <b>2</b> of the liquid supply port row. However, the positions of the liquid supply port portions <b>2</b> may be measured directly. However, if the base member <b>1</b> is formed of a stacked member, and hence the liquid supply port portions are formed across the plurality of layers, there is a probability of erroneous detection of the positions of the liquid supply port portions due to the influence of inter-layer shifting occurring at the time of the image processing of the liquid supply port portions. Therefore, as in the first embodiment, the measurement of the positions of the reference points <b>3</b> is preferable. In this case, in order to avoid the erroneous detection of the positions of the reference points due to the inter-layer shifting, the reference point is preferably formed only on the first layer of the base member. In the first embodiment, five of the reference points are provided. However, only at least three of the reference points at both ends of the base member in the longitudinal direction and in the vicinity of the center portion have to be provided. The reference points at the both ends of the base member are preferably provided outside the liquid supply port portion located at the outermost position from among the plurality of liquid supply port portions. The arrangement of the reference points may be selected from any suitable shape as long as positions can be measured accurately.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">Second Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">A second embodiment is different from the first embodiment in that the liquid ejection devices bonded to the base member to conform with the reference line (second imaginary reference line) for applying the adhesive agent in the first embodiment are bonded to the reference points of the base member. In conjunction with this, the most desirable position of the second imaginary reference line is also changed. Other configurations are the same as the first embodiment. In the following description, only processes different from those in the first embodiment will be described, and description of other processes will be omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6A and 6B</figref>, a process of defining the second imaginary line of the second embodiment will be described. In terms of preventing entry of the adhesive agent into the liquid supply port portion, the second imaginary reference line <b>23</b> is an imaginary line parallel to the inclined reference line (first imaginary reference line) <b>21</b> and is defined as an imaginary line in a range 0&#x3c;A&#x3c;c where the shift amount from the inclined reference line <b>21</b> is A. This is the same as the first embodiment. However, if the shift amount A is increased, the shifting amount between the position of the imaginary line connecting the reference points at the both ends of the base member, that is, the liquid ejection devices to be bonded onto the inclined reference line <b>21</b> and the adhesive agent to be applied in conformity with the second imaginary reference line <b>23</b> is increased. If the liquid ejection devices and the adhesive agent are shifted, the adhesive agent adhered to back surfaces of the liquid ejection devices are biased and the positions of the liquid ejection devices may be deviated due to hardening or contraction of the adhesive agent. As the countermeasure for entry of the adhesive agent into the liquid supply port portions the same effects are obtained in the case where the shift amount A of the second imaginary reference line <b>23</b> is 0&#x3c;A&#x3c;c/2 and the case where the shift amount A of the same is c/2&#x3c;A&#x3c;c. Therefore, in terms of reduction of the shift amount A, the second imaginary reference line <b>23</b> is preferably defined as the imaginary line whose shift amount falls within the range of 0&#x3c;A&#x3c;c/2.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Subsequently, in the process of bonding the liquid ejection devices of the second embodiment to the base member, the liquid ejection devices <b>4</b> are bonded to the base member <b>1</b> on the inclined reference line <b>21</b> connecting the reference points at the both ends as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, and hence are bonded at positions deviated from the second imaginary reference line <b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In the liquid ejection head obtained in this manner, in addition to the reduction of probability of entry of the adhesive agent to the liquid supply port portions, definition of the positions of the liquid ejection devices by the positions from the imaginary line connecting the reference points at the both ends of the base member <b>1</b> with respect to all the base members. Therefore, according to the method of manufacturing of the second embodiment, mounting of other head components and ejection control at the time of mounting of the heads on the main body is facilitated.</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">Third Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">A third embodiment is a mode of performing the method of bonding the liquid ejection devices of the first embodiment in a specific method. In other words, in this embodiment, after the bonding of the first liquid ejection device so as to conform to the position where the adhesive agent is applied, positioning of the second liquid ejection device is performed using the bonded liquid ejection device. In this manner, the liquid ejection device bonded previously is used for the positioning of the liquid ejection device to be bonded next to bond the liquid ejection devices in sequence. In this embodiment, the first liquid ejection device is bonded in conform to the positions where the adhesive agent is applied. However, the liquid ejection device may be bonded to conform with the reference point of the base member as in the second embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In the liquid ejection head obtained in this manner, the entry of the adhesive agent into the liquid supply port portions may be reduced. In addition, since the adjacent liquid ejection device may be positioned with high degree of accuracy, deterioration of a printed image at the joint portions between the liquid ejection devices is effectively reduced.</p>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">Fourth Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">A liquid ejection head manufactured by a method of manufacturing according to a fourth embodiment includes a base member formed with a liquid supply port row having a plurality of liquid supply port portions arranged in a plurality of rows in the short side direction, and liquid ejection devices arranged at positions corresponding to the liquid supply port portions.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a schematic perspective view of the base member used in the method of manufacturing according to the fourth embodiment. The base member <b>1</b> is provided with the liquid supply port portions <b>2</b> which constitute two rows of ink ejection port rows formed in a zigzag shape and extending in the longitudinal direction. The base member <b>1</b> is formed with reference points <b>3</b><i>a </i>to <b>3</b><i>j</i>. In the fourth embodiment, there are provided five of the reference points for each of the liquid supply port rows including outside of the liquid supply port portions positioned at both ends of the liquid supply port row and intermediate points of the respective liquid supply port portions. However, the invention is not limited thereto and only at least three of the reference points including the both ends and a point in the vicinity of the center point the liquid supply port row of each of the liquid supply port row have to be provided.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Subsequently, a process flow of the method of manufacturing of the fourth embodiment will be described.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">First of all, in the same manner as the first embodiment, the process of measuring the positions of the reference points will be performed using the measuring device illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> illustrates the positional relationship of the measured reference points, and plots <b>20</b><i>a </i>to <b>20</b><i>j </i>corresponding to the respective reference points <b>3</b><i>a </i>to <b>3</b><i>j </i>are illustrated.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Subsequently, a process of defining the reference lines (second imaginary reference lines) for applying the adhesive agent on the basis of the positions of the measured reference points. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11A and 11B</figref> are explanatory drawings for explaining the process, and are drawings corresponding to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11A</figref>, the line connecting the plots <b>20</b><i>a </i>and <b>20</b><i>e </i>at the both ends of the liquid supply port row for the lower level is defined as an inclination reference line <b>50</b> for lower level, and a line connecting the plots <b>20</b><i>f </i>and <b>20</b><i>j </i>at the both ends of the liquid supply port row on the upper level is defined as an inclination reference line <b>51</b> for the upper level. Subsequently, the distances a to j from the inclined reference lines <b>51</b> and <b>52</b> to the respective plots (a=e=f=j=0 in this embodiment) are calculated. In the liquid supply port row for the lower level, the plot <b>20</b><i>c </i>is farthest from the inclination reference line <b>50</b> for lower level, and the distance is c. In the liquid supply port row on the upper level, the plot <b>20</b><i>h </i>is farthest from the inclination reference line <b>51</b> for upper level, and the distance is h. In the embodiment, the relation of magnitudes of the distances is h&#x3e;c, and the states of warping are different between the liquid supply port rows on the upper level and the lower level. A reference line <b>60</b> for applying the adhesive agent for the lower level is an imaginary line parallel to the inclined reference line <b>50</b> for the lower level, and is defined as an imaginary line in a range 0&#x3c;B&#x3c;c where the shift amount from the inclined reference line <b>50</b> for the lower level is B. The second imaginary reference line <b>60</b> for the lower level is most preferably defined so that the shift amount B from the inclined reference line <b>50</b> for the lower level becomes half the distance c from the farthest plot <b>20</b><i>c </i>(B=c/2). Accordingly, in the liquid supply port row for the lower side, the largest distance among the distances between the second imaginary reference line <b>60</b> and all the plots <b>20</b><i>a </i>to <b>20</b><i>e </i>may be reduced. Therefore, the reference line <b>60</b> for applying the adhesive agent, that is, the largest positional shift amount between the position where the adhesive agent is applied and the liquid supply port row may be reduced to a small value. Therefore, the fourth embodiment is the most advantageous mode in terms of reducing the entry of the adhesive agent into the liquid supply port portions <b>2</b>. As regards the upper level as well, a reference line <b>61</b> for applying the adhesive agent is defined so that the shift amount C from the inclination reference line <b>51</b> for upper level falls within a range 0&#x3c;C&#x3c;h, and a case where the shift amount C is half the distance h (C=h/2) is most effective for the entry of the adhesive agent into the liquid supply port portions <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Subsequently, a process of applying the adhesive agent <b>30</b> is performed. In this process, the adhesive agent <b>30</b> is applied to the base member <b>1</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> so as to surround the peripheries of the liquid supply port portions <b>2</b> to conform with the upper and lower reference lines <b>60</b> and <b>61</b> for applying the adhesive agent.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Subsequently, a process of bonding the liquid ejection device <b>4</b> to the base member <b>1</b> having the adhesive agent applied thereto is performed as described above. In this process, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13A and 13B</figref>, the liquid ejection devices <b>4</b> are bonded to conform with the adhesive agent applied to the upper and lower second imaginary reference lines <b>60</b> and <b>61</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">In the liquid ejection head obtained in this manner, since the adhesive agent is applied to the most effective positions in all the liquid supply port rows, the entry of the adhesive agent into the liquid supply port portions may be reduced. In addition, a larger bonding surface area is obtained between the adhesive agent and the liquid ejection devices, and hence the higher bonding strength of the liquid ejection devices may be obtained. In this embodiment as well, since the positions of the liquid ejection devices are different from head to head, the ink ejection timing is needed to be controlled individually to accommodate such difference at the time of mounting the head on the main body in the same manner as the first embodiment.</p>
<heading id="h-0009" level="1">Fifth Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">A fifth embodiment is a modification of the fourth embodiment in which the position of the second imaginary reference line is changed. More specifically, the reference line (second imaginary reference line) for applying the adhesive agent is defined for one of the liquid supply port rows in the same manner as the fourth embodiment, and the position of the reference line for the other liquid supply port row is determined on the basis of the prescribed second imaginary reference line. Other configurations are the same as the fourth embodiment. In the following description, only processes different from those in the fourth embodiment will be described, and description of other processes will be omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref>, a process of defining the reference lines for applying the adhesive agent according to the fifth embodiment will be described. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is an explanatory drawing for explaining the process, and the plots <b>20</b><i>a </i>to <b>20</b><i>j </i>corresponding to the respective reference points on the base member are illustrated. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref>, for the sake of convenience of explanation, the plots are illustrated with respect to both of the upper and lower liquid supply port rows (the positions of the reference points are measured). However, the positions of the reference points have to be measured only for the liquid supply port rows for which the second imaginary reference line is defined from among the plurality of liquid supply port rows.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">In this embodiment, the second imaginary reference line <b>60</b> is defined in the method illustrated in the third embodiment with respect to the plots <b>20</b><i>a </i>and <b>20</b><i>e </i>for the liquid supply port row for the lower level. The shift amount B from the inclined reference line <b>50</b> for the lower level of the second imaginary reference line <b>60</b> for the lower level is most preferably defined to be half the distance c from the farthest plot <b>20</b><i>c</i>. Then, an imaginary line obtained by translating the second imaginary reference line <b>60</b> for the lower level in parallel by a pitch of the liquid supply port row is defined as a second imaginary reference line <b>62</b> for the upper level.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">After the definition of the second imaginary reference line, the process of applying the adhesive agent and the process of bonding the liquid ejection device are performed in the same manner as in the fourth embodiment, whereby the liquid ejection head illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> will be completed.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">With the liquid ejection head in this configuration, application of the adhesive agent to the positions most effective for the reduction of entry of the adhesive agent into the liquid supply port portions is enabled for the liquid supply port row on the lower level. As regards the liquid supply port row on the upper level, entry of the adhesive agent into the liquid supply port portions may be reduced. Since the pitches between rows of the liquid ejection devices may be equalized, ejection control at the time of mounting the head on the main body is facilitated.</p>
<heading id="h-0010" level="1">Sixth Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">In a sixth embodiment, the liquid ejection devices are bonded in conformity with the inclination reference line in the same manner as in the second embodiment after determination of the positions of the respective second imaginary reference lines in the manner described in the fifth embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The liquid ejection head obtained in the sixth embodiment is subjected to deviation between the positions where the adhesive agent is applied and the positions of the liquid ejection devices as in the second embodiment. Therefore, the preferable mode in the fifth embodiment is as follows. In other words, the second imaginary reference lines are defined by using the liquid supply port row having the smallest positional displacements of the respective reference points with respect to the imaginary line (inclination reference line) connecting the reference points at the both ends of the liquid supply port row from among the plurality of liquid supply port rows. Then, as regards other liquid supply port rows, the lines obtained by translating the second imaginary reference line in parallel defined as described above by a pitch of the liquid supply port row is defined as the second imaginary reference lines of other liquid supply port rows.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In the liquid ejection head obtained in this manner, the distances between the imaginary lines connecting the reference points at the both ends of the respective liquid supply port rows and the adhesive agent in all the liquid supply port rows may be set to half the distance or smaller from the imaginary line to the reference point farthest from the imaginary line. Accordingly, the entry of the ink to the liquid supply port rows in all of the liquid supply port rows may be reduced, and the influence of the positional displacement between the adhesive agent and the liquid ejection devices on the movement of the liquid ejection devices may be reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">While the present invention has been described with reference to exemplary embodiments, it is to be understood that the invention is not limited to the disclosed exemplary embodiments. The scope of the following claims is to be accorded the broadest interpretation so as to encompass all such modifications and equivalent structures and functions.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">This application claims the benefit of Japanese Patent Application No. 2011-231749 filed Oct. 21, 2011, which is hereby incorporated by reference herein in its entirety.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method of manufacturing a liquid ejection head including a base member having a liquid supply port row including a plurality of liquid supply port portions for supplying liquid formed in the longitudinal direction, and a plurality of liquid ejection devices arranged at positions corresponding to the liquid supply port portions and bonded to the base member with an adhesive agent, the method comprising:
<claim-text>defining a first imaginary reference line along the longitudinal direction of the base member and measuring the distances between the first imaginary reference line and at least two liquid supply port portions of the liquid supply port row;</claim-text>
<claim-text>defining a second imaginary reference line passing through the liquid supply port portion at the shortest distance from the first imaginary reference line and the liquid supply port portion at the longest distance from the first imaginary line respectively from among the at least two liquid supply port portions and defining the second imaginary reference line between two imaginary lines parallel to the first imaginary reference line;</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying the adhesive agent on the base member on the basis of the second imaginary reference lines; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>bonding the liquid ejection devices on the base member with the adhesive agent applied on the base member.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of manufacturing a liquid ejection head according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the distance of at least the two liquid supply port portions is measured on the basis of a plurality of reference points provided on the base member.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of manufacturing a liquid ejection head according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the plurality of reference points include two of the reference points provided at both ends of the base member in the longitudinal direction.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of manufacturing a liquid ejection head according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the two reference points are formed respectively outside the two liquid supply port portions at outermost positions from among the plurality of liquid supply port portions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of manufacturing a liquid ejection head according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the first imaginary reference line is defined so as to connect the two liquid supply port portions at the outermost positions from among the plurality of liquid supply port portions.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of manufacturing a liquid ejection head according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the second imaginary reference line is parallel to the first imaginary reference line.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of manufacturing a liquid ejection head according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the second imaginary reference line is at an equal distance from the two imaginary lines.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method of manufacturing a liquid ejection head according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the liquid supply port portion includes a plurality of openings.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A method of manufacturing a liquid ejection head including a base member having a liquid supply port row including a plurality of liquid supply port portions for supplying liquid formed in the longitudinal direction, and a plurality of liquid ejection devices arranged at positions corresponding to the liquid supply port portions and bonded to the base member with an adhesive agent, the method comprising:
<claim-text>defining a second imaginary reference line between a first imaginary reference line extending along the longitudinal direction of the base member and a reference point at the largest distance from the imaginary reference line from among a plurality of reference points formed along the longitudinal direction so as to extend along the first imaginary reference line;</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying the adhesive agent on the base member on the basis of the second imaginary reference lines; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>bonding the liquid ejection devices on the base member with the adhesive agent applied on the base member.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of manufacturing a liquid ejection head according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the first imaginary reference line is defined so as to connect the reference point on one end side and the reference point on the other end side from among the plurality of reference points.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of manufacturing a liquid ejection head according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the second imaginary reference line is defined between the reference point at the center from among the plurality of reference points disposed in the longitudinal direction of the base member and the first imaginary reference line.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of manufacturing a liquid ejection head according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the reference points are formed between the plurality of liquid supply portions.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A method of manufacturing a liquid ejection head including a base member having a liquid supply port row including a plurality of liquid supply port portions for supplying liquid formed in the longitudinal direction, and a plurality of liquid ejection devices arranged at positions corresponding to the liquid supply port portions and bonded to the base member with an adhesive agent, the method comprising:
<claim-text>defining a second imaginary reference line between a first imaginary reference line extending along the longitudinal direction of the base member and a liquid supply port portion at the largest distance from the imaginary reference line from among the plurality of liquid supply port portions formed along the longitudinal direction so as to extend along the first imaginary reference line;</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying the adhesive agent on the base member on the basis of the second imaginary reference lines; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>bonding the liquid ejection devices on the base member with the adhesive agent applied on the base member.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A liquid ejection head comprising:
<claim-text>a base member having a liquid supply port row comprising a plurality of liquid supply port portions arranged in the longitudinal direction; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>liquid ejection devices arranged at positions corresponding to the liquid supply port portions and bonded to the base member with an adhesive agent formed around the liquid supply port portions,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the distance between a first opening end of a first liquid supply port portion formed at one end side in the direction of arrangement from among the plurality of liquid supply port portions in the direction of a first short side orthogonal to the longitudinal direction and an outer peripheral end portion of the adhesive agent formed outside the first opening end on the outer peripheral side is larger than the distance between a second opening end in a second short side direction opposite from the first short side direction and an end portion of the adhesive agent formed outside the second opening end, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the distance between a third opening end of a second liquid supply port portion formed at a center in the direction of arrangement from among the plurality of liquid supply port portions in the direction of the first short side and an end portion of the adhesive agent formed outside the third opening end on the outer peripheral side is smaller than the distance between a fourth opening end in the second short side direction and an outer peripheral end portion of the adhesive agent formed outside the fourth opening end. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
