<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624442-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624442</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13199444</doc-number>
<date>20110829</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>187</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>307139</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Illuminated pushbutton switch with embedded interface and driver logic</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3683350</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Shedenheim</name>
<date>19720800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4535396</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Guthrie</name>
<date>19850800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4592003</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kobayashi et al.</name>
<date>19860500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0231946</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Guthrie</name>
<date>20051000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00005">
<othercit>International Search Report issued on May 12, 2010 in connection with International Patent Application No. PCT/US2010/023423.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00006">
<othercit>Written Opinion issued on May 12, 2010 in connection with International Patent Application No. PCT/US2010/023423.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>307139</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>9</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>12</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation-in-part>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12701543</doc-number>
<date>20100206</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8222771</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13199444</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation-in-part>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>61377969</doc-number>
<date>20100829</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>61207016</doc-number>
<date>20090206</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120187861</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120726</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Edwards</last-name>
<first-name>Steven A.</first-name>
<address>
<city>North Richland Hills</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Edwards</last-name>
<first-name>Steven A.</first-name>
<address>
<city>North Richland Hills</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Aerospace Optics, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Fort Worth</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Deberadinis</last-name>
<first-name>Robert L.</first-name>
<department>2836</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Illuminated pushbutton switches are improved by replacing the traditional time delay relays, Boolean interface logic or driver components often incorporated within interface wiring and harnesses with a subminiature electronic logic module located within the illuminated pushbutton switch housing. This Logic Module provides numerous additional benefits beyond the standard illuminated push button switch by incorporating functional capability such as pulse timing, edge detecting or Boolean logic that allow the unit to replace external electro mechanical relays, diode logic, or time delay relays that are typical in current applications. These additional features provide enhancements by allowing lower size and weight, longer switch life, no electrical spikes, remote set and reset capability, display blinking, and high reliability electronic driver circuits that can drive modest electrical loads.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="94.15mm" wi="144.61mm" file="US08624442-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="210.40mm" wi="154.18mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624442-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="171.53mm" wi="144.53mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624442-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="225.30mm" wi="154.60mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624442-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="219.03mm" wi="143.85mm" file="US08624442-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="250.87mm" wi="161.12mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624442-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="206.93mm" wi="143.51mm" file="US08624442-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="253.66mm" wi="164.59mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624442-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="244.69mm" wi="151.81mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624442-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="240.88mm" wi="163.91mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624442-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION(S) AND CLAIM OF PRIORITY</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority to U.S. Provisional Patent Application Ser. No. 61/377,969 filed Aug. 29, 2010 and is a continuation-in-part of commonly assigned, U.S. patent application Ser. No. 12/701,543 filed Feb. 6, 2010 now U.S. Pat. No. 8,222,771 and entitled ILLUMINATED PUSHBUTTON SWITCH WITH ELECTRONIC LATCHING AND BLINKING FEATURE, which claims priority to commonly assigned U.S. Provisional Patent Application No. 61/207,016, filed Feb. 6, 2009, all of which are hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure is directed, in general, to illuminated pushbuttons switches, and more specifically to implementing interface and driver logic within the housing for illuminated pushbutton switches, including logic for implementing electronic latching and blinking features for the illuminated pushbutton switch.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Illuminated pushbutton switches used in commercial and military aircraft, boats and other vehicles are fairly uniform in size across various commercial suppliers. The switches are usually a generally rectangular cuboid with a length of approximately 2.5 inches and an end face ranging from about 0.75&#xd7;0.75 inches to 1.5&#xd7;1.5 inches, including non-square configurations (e.g., 1.0&#xd7;1.5 inches). These switches normally include a cap and a frame or body, collectively housing incandescent or light emitting diode (LED) illumination sources, optical filters, legend plates, snap action mechanical switches, connectors, driver circuits, and other components. Switch sizing is generally selected by the aircraft, boat or vehicle manufacturer based on compatability with existing designs, interoperability with on-board control systems, and space and/or weight considerations.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Normally the interface and drive logic for connecting illuminated pushbutton switches to control systems within the vehicle is external to the switch. A controller prompting illumination or responding to actuation of the switch is disposed somewhere in the vehicle, normally connected to multiple illuminated pushbutton switches. The interface provides circuits, for example, for stepping down the 14 or 28 volts (V) direct current (DC) voltage normally available in aircraft in order to implement voltage-controlled dimming.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Specialized applications involving illuminated pushbutton switches may require electronic interface and drive functions such that depressing the pushbutton switch initiates an action, a conditional action or a timed response. The functional operation can be initiated by receiving inputs from the switch or may be a signal received from a remote location. The interface logic signal or timing pulse results in a signal output that can then be used to energize the local illuminated switch or/or activate another unit such as an illuminated indicator or a remote interface within a different device. Such functionality may involve a plurality of illuminated pushbutton switches in differing locations all interfacing through the same interface or logic units, wherein a switch depressed at one location may be modified by the interface circuitry or driven by the local switch circuitry.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">For example, within the realm of illuminated pushbutton switch usage, specialized applications are emerging requiring inclusion of latching, blinking or remote control functions to be included within the illuminated pushbutton switch housing. Such applications may require depressing the pushbutton switch to initiate a remote action request, activating switch functions from a remote location, energizing or blinking a local or remote display, and resetting the switch state automatically upon remote acknowledgement. Other applications may involve a plurality of illuminated pushbutton switches in differing locations, all controlling the same functions, wherein a switch depressed at one location must change the state of a switch or display at another location. Nearly all applications require the added safety feature of an automatic reset to a default state after loss of power.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Proposed designs may incorporate local latching and remote release functions through the use of internal electromagnetic holding coils, in some cases together with various electronic or electromechanical means to interrupt the holding coil current locally without remote intervention. Many of the proposed designs that rely upon an internal electromagnetic holding coil suffer from excessive power consumption, excessive heat, sensitivity to shock and physical jarring, electrical spikes, holding coil drop-out on low voltage, and low reliability. The internal holding coil also makes the resulting illuminated pushbutton switch substantially longer and heavier than standard models that do not incorporate a holding coil.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">There is, therefore, a need in the art for improved implementation of interface and relay functions for pushbutton illuminated switches.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Illuminated pushbutton switches are improved by replacing the traditional time delay relays, Boolean interface logic or driver components often incorporated within interface wiring and harnesses with a subminiature electronic logic module located within the illuminated pushbutton switch housing. This Logic Module provides numerous additional benefits beyond the standard illuminated push button switch by incorporating functional capability such as pulse timing, edge detecting or Boolean logic that allow the unit to replace external electro mechanical relays, diode logic, or time delay relays that are typical in current applications. These additional features provide enhancements by allowing lower size and weight, longer switch life, no electrical spikes, remote set and reset capability, display blinking, and high reliability electronic driver circuits that can drive modest electrical loads. In particular, within an illuminating pushbutton switch, an electronic circuit replaces an electromagnetic holding coil for latching or releasing a state of the illuminated pushbutton switch, and further provides blinking functionality. The electronic circuit includes inputs receiving set, reset and toggle control signals, outputs delivering open, closed and blink control signals, latch logic controlled by the set and reset control signals and delivering signals maintaining the illuminated pushbutton switch in either an open or closed state, and a frequency divider and oscillator coupled together to deliver a blink control signal. The electronic circuit fits within the illuminated pushbutton switch housing in space sized to hold two snap action switching devices without increase in the length, weight or mounting depth of the illuminated pushbutton switch. The inputs and outputs are coupled to external pins from the illuminated pushbutton switch and may be remotely controlled.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Before undertaking the DETAILED DESCRIPTION below, it may be advantageous to set forth definitions of certain words and phrases used throughout this patent document: the terms &#x201c;include&#x201d; and &#x201c;comprise,&#x201d; as well as derivatives thereof, mean inclusion without limitation; the term &#x201c;or,&#x201d; is inclusive, meaning and/or; the phrases &#x201c;associated with&#x201d; and &#x201c;associated therewith,&#x201d; as well as derivatives thereof, may mean to include, be included within, interconnect with, contain, be contained within, connect to or with, couple to or with, be communicable with, cooperate with, interleave, juxtapose, be proximate to, be bound to or with, have, have a property of, or the like; and the term &#x201c;controller&#x201d; means any device, system or part thereof that controls at least one operation, such a device may be implemented in hardware, firmware or software, or some combination of at least two of the same. It should be noted that the functionality associated with any particular controller may be centralized or distributed, whether locally or remotely. Definitions for certain words and phrases are provided throughout this patent document, those of ordinary skill in the art should understand that in many, if not most instances, such definitions apply to prior, as well as future uses of such defined words and phrases.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">For a more complete understanding of the present disclosure and its advantages, reference is now made to the following description taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, in which like reference numerals represent like parts:</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A</figref>, <b>1</b>B and <b>1</b>C are exploded perspective views of a pushbutton illuminated switch (or components thereof) with four snap-action switch modules;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1D and 1E</figref> are perspective views illustrating incorporation of an embedded interface and driver logic module into the pushbutton illuminated switch of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A-1C</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a high level functional block diagram of an embedded configurable pulse timer interface module within the pushbutton illuminated switch of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A-1C</figref>, contained within electronic module <b>111</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a circuit diagram for the embedded configurable pulse timer interface module of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a high level functional block diagram of an embedded pulse selectable timer interface module within the pushbutton illuminated switch of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A-1C</figref>, contained within electronic module <b>111</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a circuit diagram for the embedded configurable pulse timer interface module of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a high level functional block diagram of an embedded universal logic interface module within the pushbutton illuminated switch of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A-1C</figref>, contained within electronic module <b>111</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a circuit diagram for the embedded universal logic interface module of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a circuit diagram for an electronic latching and/or blinking module according to one embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A through 8</figref>, discussed below, and the various embodiments used to describe the principles of the present disclosure in this patent document are by way of illustration only and should not be construed in any way to limit the scope of the disclosure. Those skilled in the art will understand that the principles of the present disclosure may be implemented in any suitably arranged system.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A</figref>, <b>1</b>B and <b>1</b>C are exploded perspective views of a pushbutton illuminated switch (or components thereof) (or components thereof) with four snap-action switch modules. The pushbutton switch <b>100</b> includes a switch cap <b>101</b> and a switch body <b>102</b>. The switch cap <b>101</b> is located at the front of the switch <b>100</b> and is received by the switch body <b>102</b>. The switch cap <b>101</b> includes a switch cap housing <b>103</b> receiving an array <b>104</b> of surface mount diode (SMD) light emitting diodes (LEDs). The 2&#xd7;4 LED array <b>104</b> depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> has two rows of four LEDs arranged to illuminate four quadrants of a face plate (not shown) on the front of switch cap body <b>103</b>, with two LEDs (a 1&#xd7;2 subarray) per quadrant. In other embodiments, the array <b>104</b> may include sixteen LEDs arranged in an overall 4&#xd7;4 array, with 2&#xd7;2 subarrays illuminating each of four quadrants of the face plate.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The LEDs are mounted over a switch cap back plate <b>105</b> and are connected to an electrical driving circuit (not visible in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref>) mounted on the switch cap back plate <b>105</b>. A member <b>106</b> for mechanical latching and release of the pushbutton switch when the switch cap <b>101</b> is depressed within the switch body <b>102</b> protrudes from the rear of switch cap back plate <b>105</b>. Electrical connections (not shown) to the driving circuit are also exposed on the rear surface of switch cap back plate <b>105</b>. The structure depicted and described is consistent with the design of the switch bodies for the models 4 pole <b>95</b>, R<b>2</b> and LR<b>3</b> pushbutton illuminated switches sold by Aerospace Optics, Inc. of Fort Worth, Tex. The switch bodies have dimensions of less than 1.5&#xd7;1.5&#xd7;3 inches, typically either about 0.75&#xd7;0.75 or about 1&#xd7;1 and about 2.5 inches in length. Each of the circuits and applications disclosed herein may be housed within such switches in the manner described in further detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In some embodiments, switch body <b>102</b> includes a housing <b>107</b> receiving a mechanical and electrical subsystem <b>108</b> for mechanical latching and release of the pushbutton switch <b>100</b>, for transmitting electrical signals to the driving circuit, and for transmitting mechanical forces to actuate four-pin snap-action switching devices <b>109</b><i>a </i>through <b>109</b><i>d</i>. Pins for the switching devices <b>109</b><i>a </i>through <b>109</b><i>d </i>are received by mounting block <b>110</b> and provide electrical switching by connections of the pins to external signal sources and/or through the subsystem <b>108</b> to the driving circuit. The pins of devices <b>109</b><i>a </i>through <b>109</b><i>d </i>extend through the mounting block <b>110</b> and may be connected at the rear of pushbutton switch <b>100</b> to external signals, to each other, and/or through subsystem <b>108</b> to the driving circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Those skilled in the art will recognize that the complete structure and operation of a pushbutton switch of the type normally used in avionics is not depicted or described herein. Instead, for simplicity and clarity, only so much of the structure and operation of a pushbutton switch as is necessary for an understanding of the present disclosure is depicted and described. For example, filters between the LEDs and the switch cap face plate allow legends on the switch cap face plate to be illuminated in different colors as disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 6,653,798, which is incorporated herein by reference. Driving circuits mounted on flexible substrates may be mounted within the switch cap to drive each subarray of LEDs, providing voltage-controlled dimming as described in U.S. Pat. No. 6,323,598, which is also incorporated herein by reference. Numerous other features not depicted or described herein are or may be included within pushbutton switch <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1D and 1E</figref> are perspective views illustrating incorporation of an embedded configurable pulse timer interface module within the pushbutton illuminated switch of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A-1C</figref>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1D</figref>, an electronic module <b>111</b> is inserted in place of snap-action switch modules <b>109</b><i>b </i>and <b>109</b><i>c</i>, with pins received by mounting block <b>110</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1E</figref> depicts a mounting frame <b>112</b> on which integrated electronic circuitry may be mounted, within one of the recesses <b>113</b>. The electronic module <b>111</b> is coupled to a plurality of interface pins <b>114</b> (eight in the exemplary embodiment) each extending from the electronic circuitry through a portion of the mounting frame <b>112</b> to an endpoint and configured to pass through additional frames or housings (not shown) and engage additional electronic circuitry (not shown), in the same manner as pins for switching devices <b>109</b><i>b </i>and <b>109</b><i>c</i>. This approach provides the added functionality of the electronic module <b>111</b> with no increase in length, weight or mounting depth while retaining two uncommitted snap-action switching devices <b>109</b><i>a </i>and <b>109</b><i>d </i>that can be used to interact with the electronic module <b>111</b> or control other system functions.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a high level functional block diagram of an embedded configurable pulse timer interface module within the pushbutton illuminated switch of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A-1C</figref>, contained within electronic module <b>111</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a circuit diagram for the embedded configurable pulse timer interface module of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. Electronic circuitry <b>200</b> within the configurable pulse timer interface module includes several functional units: input buffering unit <b>201</b>; logic power supply unit <b>202</b>; edge detection and pulse generation unit <b>203</b>; pulse timing units <b>204</b><i>a </i>and <b>204</b><i>b</i>; and output drivers unit <b>205</b>. A pulse timer interface module contained within a push button switch provides a number of benefits over traditional illuminated push button switches and timed relays by combining multiple functions into one unit. The pulse timer interface module can replace traditional electro-mechanical hold relays with an internal timed output that may be used in a plurality of different ways, such as to provide timed illumination to the illuminated push button switch or to drive external devices such as a horn or buzzer. In addition, the pulse timer interface module enables a latched condition to provide a momentary pulsed output, a capability that permits either a local or remote latching of a steady state input from an alternate action type switch to generate a pulsed time output on any positive or negative level transition. The pulse timer interface module thus adds a capability that does not currently exist within existing push button illuminated switches by allowing an alternate action illuminated push button switch to produce both a latched steady state output and a momentary pulsed output from the same unit. The latched condition is produced by the mechanical latch and mechanical contacts of the switch and the momentary pulse is produced by the pulse timer unit. The electronic nature of the pulse timer provides the additional feature of remote disable or reset using the reset inputs. When the reset lines are held at ground the pulse output is disabled causing these inputs to perform an enable/disable capability, an enhancement over a traditional fully mechanical push button illuminated switch that cannot be remotely enabled or disabled with an electronic signal.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">TABLE I below contains the pulse timer logic signals and functions for the configurable pulse timer interface module of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, while TABLE II describes the logic input and output functions:</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00001" num="00001">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="4">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="35pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="42pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="70pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="70pt" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" rowsep="1">TABLE I</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>4-POLE</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>SIGNAL</entry>
<entry>HOUSING</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>NAME</entry>
<entry>PIN</entry>
<entry>LOGIC FUNCTION</entry>
<entry>COMMENTS</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>/RESET1</entry>
<entry>J1</entry>
<entry>Input: Low = Resets</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>and disables pulse</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>outputs when held</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>low.</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>/RESET2</entry>
<entry>K3</entry>
<entry>Input: Low = Resets</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>and disables pulse</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>outputs when held</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>low.</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>TR2</entry>
<entry>J2</entry>
<entry>Input: Triggers pulse</entry>
<entry>TR inputs will be</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>on Q2 outputs from a</entry>
<entry>factory configured as</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>transition. See</entry>
<entry>TR+, TR&#x2212; or TR+/&#x2212;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>function table below.</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>TR1</entry>
<entry>J3</entry>
<entry>Input: Triggers pulse</entry>
<entry>TR inputs will be</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>on Q1 outputs from a</entry>
<entry>factory configured as</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>transition. See</entry>
<entry>TR+, TR&#x2212; or TR+/&#x2212;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>function table below.</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>+28 VDC</entry>
<entry>J4</entry>
<entry>Power</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Ground</entry>
<entry>K1</entry>
<entry>Ground</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Q1</entry>
<entry>K4</entry>
<entry>Output:</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>H: Default =</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>grounded. Becomes</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>high impedance for</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>length of pulse</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>L: Default = high</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>impedance. Becomes</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>grounded for length</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>of pulse</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Q2</entry>
<entry>K2</entry>
<entry>Output:</entry>
<entry>High(H) or Low (L)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>H: Default =</entry>
<entry>output options are</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>grounded. Becomes</entry>
<entry>selected and adjusted</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>high impedance for</entry>
<entry>at time of manufacture</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>length of pulse</entry>
<entry>in the factory</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>L: Default = high</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>impedance. Becomes</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>grounded for length</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>of pulse</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00002" num="00002">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="98pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="119pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="2" rowsep="1">TABLE II</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Inputs</entry>
<entry>Outputs</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="6">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="28pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="21pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="21pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="28pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="63pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="56pt" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>/RESET</entry>
<entry>TR+</entry>
<entry>TR&#x2212;</entry>
<entry>TR+/&#x2212;</entry>
<entry>H</entry>
<entry>L</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="6" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>L</entry>
<entry>L&#x2192;H</entry>
<entry>H&#x2192;L</entry>
<entry>L&#x2192;H</entry>
<entry>Output transitions</entry>
<entry>Output transitions</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>or</entry>
<entry>from ground to</entry>
<entry>from high</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>H&#x2192;L</entry>
<entry>high impedance for</entry>
<entry>impedance to</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>the specified</entry>
<entry>ground for the</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>pulse period</entry>
<entry>specified pulse</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>period</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>L</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>Output is</entry>
<entry>High impedance</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>grounded.</entry>
<entry>(open drain).</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="6" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The pulse timer interface module <b>200</b> has a total of eight (8) interface pins, four interface pins devoted to logic input signals TR<b>1</b>, TR<b>2</b>, /RESET<b>1</b> and /RESET<b>2</b> and two interface pins devoted to logic output signals Q<b>1</b> and Q<b>2</b>. Two additional interface pins are devoted to power: +28 VDC and Ground.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The pulse timer interface module <b>200</b> includes a mono-stable multi-vibrator integrated circuit <b>3</b>U<b>1</b> with functional operation as described in TABLE I and connected as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. The logic power supply <b>202</b> for mono-stable multi-vibrator <b>3</b>U<b>1</b> (e.g., CD<b>14538</b>B) is provided by a zener shunt regulator <b>3</b>D<b>9</b> from the +28 VDC Power input <b>3</b>J<b>4</b> and ground connection at input <b>3</b>K<b>1</b>. Due to the low operating current of the complementary metal-oxide-semiconductor (CMOS) circuitry, a current limiting resistor <b>3</b>R<b>13</b> has been assigned the value of 10 kilo-Ohms (K&#x3a9;) in order to limit the current of any electromechanical contact (EMC) or other voltage transient on the +28 VDC power pin.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Input buffering <b>201</b> provides transient suppression and voltage regulation on the +7.5 VDC logic power supply by diode <b>3</b>D<b>10</b> and capacitor <b>3</b>C<b>3</b> filtering of input <b>3</b>J<b>3</b> and logic transients. Because the logic power supply is a simple shunt voltage regulator, the pulse timer interface module <b>200</b> can operate over a wide input voltage range from below +10 VDC to in excess of +30 VDC.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Each logic input <b>3</b>J<b>1</b>, <b>3</b>J<b>2</b>, <b>3</b>J<b>3</b> and <b>3</b>K<b>3</b> to the pulse timer interface module <b>200</b> includes input filter circuitry within the input buffering <b>201</b> designed to protect the integrated circuits from voltage transients such as electromechanical contact bounce and to shift the 28 VDC logic level to a 7.5 VDC logic level. The EMC protection, voltage transient protection and logic level shift function is accomplished with resistors <b>3</b>R<b>1</b>, <b>3</b>R<b>2</b>, <b>3</b>R<b>3</b>, <b>3</b>R<b>4</b>, <b>3</b>R<b>11</b> and <b>3</b>R<b>25</b> and zener diodes <b>3</b>D<b>5</b>, <b>3</b>D<b>8</b>, <b>3</b>D<b>10</b> and <b>3</b>D<b>12</b>. Furthermore, CMOS latch-up on extreme transients such as lightning or conducted electromagnetic pulse (EMP) is prevented by clamping the logic inputs at 0.5 VDC below the logic power supply voltage. Suppression of electromechanical contact bounce is provided by resistor capacitor time constant on all inputs using resistors. /RESET<b>1</b> (&#x201c;/RST<b>1</b>&#x201d;) and /RESET<b>2</b> (&#x201c;/RST<b>1</b>&#x201d;) input <b>3</b>J<b>1</b> and <b>3</b>K<b>3</b> time constants also guarantee a default power-up state for mono-stable multi-vibrator <b>3</b>U<b>1</b> because the power-up time constant of these components is substantially longer than that of both the logic power supply and TR<b>1</b> and TR<b>2</b>. A default static logic level is established for the logic inputs through pull-up resistors to the input power, preventing floating logic states on unconnected inputs. The 7.5 volt internal operating voltage raises the input voltage level sufficiently so that single external blocking diode on any control line will not interfere with the normal operation of the unit.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The desired pulse timing is selected for each channel by the appropriate selection of a timing resistor and capacitor for each channel: <b>3</b>R<b>10</b> and <b>3</b>C<b>4</b> for one channel and <b>3</b>R<b>12</b> and <b>3</b>C<b>5</b> for the other channel. Mono-stable multi-vibrator <b>3</b>U<b>1</b> is the primary timing circuit control that responds to the logic inputs TR<b>1</b>, TR<b>2</b>, /RESET<b>1</b>, /RESET<b>2</b> as described in TABLE I. Both TR<b>1</b> and TR<b>2</b> may be configured as either a negative (High to Low) or Positive (Low to High) signal by addition or removal of the appropriate zero ohm jumpers (R<b>1</b>, R<b>2</b>, R<b>3</b> and R<b>4</b>). Either the Q or /Q outputs of each output channel of mono-stable multi-vibrator <b>3</b>U<b>1</b> may be routed to the corresponding output by the selection of the appropriate jumpers (<b>3</b>R<b>26</b>, <b>3</b>R<b>27</b>, <b>3</b>R<b>28</b> and <b>3</b>R<b>29</b>). The outputs from mono-stable multi-vibrator U<b>1</b> drives the /NORMALLY OPEN output metal-oxide-semiconductor field effect transistors (MOSFETS) <b>3</b>Q<b>1</b> and <b>3</b>Q<b>2</b>. The select ability of the Q or /Q output routing provides maximum flexibility by allowing either output to be active High (normally low with a high impedance during pulse) or active Low (normally high impedance with ground applied during an active pulse).</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Each logic output <b>3</b>K<b>2</b> and <b>3</b>K<b>4</b> from the pulse timer interface module <b>200</b> includes a power MOSFET and an output filter designed to protect each output device from transients and overload conditions. Each of the MOSFETs <b>3</b>Q<b>1</b> and <b>3</b>Q<b>2</b> are rated at 4 ampere (A) at 45 VDC, with both voltage and current parameters chosen to be substantially greater than operational requirements. Transient protection for the MOSFETs is provided by impedances <b>3</b>Z<b>1</b> and <b>3</b>Z<b>2</b>, with a breakdown voltage of 39 VDC. Overload protection is provided by fuses <b>3</b>F<b>1</b> and <b>3</b>F<b>2</b>. In order to provide the highest possible reliability, each logic output has been derated to a maximum operating current of 1.0 ampere.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a high level functional block diagram of an embedded pulse selectable timer interface module within the pushbutton illuminated switch of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A-1C</figref>, contained within electronic module <b>111</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a circuit diagram for the embedded configurable pulse timer interface module of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. Electronic circuitry <b>400</b> within the pulse selectable timer interface module includes several functional units: input buffering unit <b>401</b>; logic power supply unit <b>402</b>; pulse timer generation unit <b>403</b>; pulse timing unit <b>404</b>; and output drivers unit <b>405</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">A pulse selectable timer interface module contained within an illuminated pushbutton switch provides a number of benefits over traditional illuminated pushbutton switches and timed relays by combining the functions into one unit. The pulse selectable timer interface module can replace traditional electro-mechanical hold relays with an internal timed output, used in multiple ways such as to provide timed illumination to the illuminated push button switch or driving an external device such as a horn or buzzer. In addition, the pulse selectable timer interface module enables a latched condition to provide a momentary pulsed output, a capability that allows either a local or remote latching of a steady state alternate action switch type switch to generate a pulsed time output on any positive or negative level transition. The electronic nature of the pulse timer provides the additional feature of remote disable or reset using the reset inputs. The reset will cancel the output pulse if the pulse has been initiated, which is especially useful for long timing pulses or when an instantaneous override is desired of an initiated function such as canceling or shutting off of a warning buzzer.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">TABLE III below contains the pulse timer logic signals and functions for the pulse selectable timer interface module of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, while TABLE IV describes the logic input and output functions:</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00003" num="00003">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="4">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="42pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="42pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="77pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="56pt" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" rowsep="1">TABLE III</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>4-POLE</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>SIGNAL</entry>
<entry>HOUSING</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>NAME</entry>
<entry>PIN</entry>
<entry>LOGIC FUNCTION</entry>
<entry>COMMENTS</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>RESET</entry>
<entry>J1</entry>
<entry>Input: Resets and</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>disables pulse outputs</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>when held high. Low -</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>Timer is operational.</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Trigger</entry>
<entry>J2</entry>
<entry>High to low initiates or</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>restarts timing pulse</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Q Select</entry>
<entry>J3</entry>
<entry>Low = Output low going</entry>
<entry>High = high</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>high during pulse</entry>
<entry>impedance open</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>High = output high and</entry>
<entry>drain output</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>goes low during pulse</entry>
<entry>Low = Ground</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>A</entry>
<entry>K3</entry>
<entry>See frequency selection</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>B</entry>
<entry>K4</entry>
<entry>table, TABLE IV below</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>+28 VDC</entry>
<entry>J4</entry>
<entry>Power</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Ground</entry>
<entry>K1</entry>
<entry>Ground</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>M2</entry>
<entry>K2</entry>
<entry>Output:</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>H: Default = grounded.</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>Becomes high impedance</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>for length of pulse</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>L: Default = high</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>impedance. Becomes</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>grounded for length of</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>pulse</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00004" num="00004">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="14pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="42pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="42pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="105pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="5" rowsep="1">TABLE IV</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>Number of</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>A</entry>
<entry>B</entry>
<entry>count stages</entry>
<entry>Count 2<sup>n </sup>(X frequency)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="14pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="42pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="42pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="105pt" align="char" char="."/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>13</entry>
<entry>8192</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>10</entry>
<entry>1024</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>8</entry>
<entry>256</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>16</entry>
<entry>65536</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The pulse selectable timer interface module <b>400</b> has a total of eight (8) interface pins, five logic inputs TRIGGER, A, B, MODE and RESET and one devoted to logic output M<b>2</b>. Two additional interface pins are devoted to power: +28 VDC and Ground. The logic power supply for timer integrated circuit <b>5</b>U<b>10</b> is provided by a zener shunt regulator D<b>3</b> from the +28 VDC power input. Due to the low operating current of the CMOS circuitry, a current limiting resistor <b>5</b>R<b>7</b> has been assigned the value of 10 K&#x3a9; in order to limit the current of any EMC or voltage transient on the +28 VDC power pin. Transient suppression and voltage regulation on the +7.5 VDC logic power supply is provided by diode and capacitor filtering of input and logic transients. Because the logic power supply is a simple shunt voltage regulator, the pulse selectable timer interface module <b>400</b> can operate over a wide input voltage range from below +10 VDC to in excess of +30 VDC.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Each logic input to the pulse selectable timer interface module <b>400</b> includes input filter circuitry designed to protect the integrated circuits from EMC, voltage transients, electromechanical contact bounce and shift the 28 VDC logic level to a 7.5 VDC logic level. The EMC protection, voltage transient protection and logic level shift function is accomplished with resistors and zener diodes. Furthermore, CMOS latch-up on extreme transients such as lightning or conducted EMP is prevented by clamping the Logic Inputs 0.5 VDC below the logic power supply voltage. Suppression of electromechanical contact bounce is provided by resistor capacitor time constant on all inputs. RESET Input time constants also guarantees a default power-up state for timer <b>5</b>U<b>10</b> because the power-up time constant of these components is substantially longer than that of both the logic power supply and TRIGGER, a default static logic level is established for the logic inputs through pull-up resistors to the input power, preventing floating logic states on unconnected inputs. The 7.5 volt internal operating voltage raises the input voltage level sufficiently so that single external blocking diodes in any control line will not interfere with the normal operation of the unit.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The pulse selectable timer interface module <b>400</b> includes a timer integrated circuit U<b>10</b> (e.g., <b>14541</b>B) that consists of a binary counter and an internal oscillator with functional operation as described in TABLE III and connected as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. The desired pulse timing is selected by a combination of the value of pins A and B (see TABLES III and IV for details) and the appropriate selection of a timing resistor and capacitor. This timing resistor and capacitor set the frequency of the internal oscillator. Timer U<b>10</b> is the primary timing circuit control that responds to the inputs as defined in TABLE III.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The logic output from the pulse selectable timer interface module <b>400</b> includes a power MOSFET <b>5</b>M<b>2</b> and an output filter designed to protect the output device from transients and overload conditions. The MOSFET M<b>2</b> is rated at 4 ampere at 45 VDC, with both voltage and current parameters chosen to be substantially greater than operational requirements. Transient protection for the MOSFET is provided by variable resistance <b>5</b>U<b>2</b> connected across the source/drain terminals of the MOSFET <b>5</b>M<b>2</b> to ground, with a breakdown voltage of 39 VDC. Overload protection is provided by fuse <b>5</b>F<b>1</b> connected between the output terminal of MOSFET <b>5</b>M<b>2</b> and circuit output Q. In order to provide the highest possible reliability, the logic output has been de-rated to a maximum operating current of 1.0 ampere.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The gate of MOSFET <b>5</b>M<b>2</b> driving circuit output Q is connected to the output Q of timer U<b>10</b>. A Q/Q Sel input to timer U<b>10</b> receives the input signal Q SELECT through a reverse bias connected diode <b>5</b>D<b>1</b> and a resistor <b>5</b>R<b>4</b>, and is coupled to ground through reverse bias connected zener diode <b>5</b>D<b>10</b> and capacitor <b>5</b>C<b>9</b> for transient and overvoltage protection. A pull-up resistor <b>5</b>R<b>11</b> connects the anode of diode <b>5</b>D<b>1</b> to a supply voltage derived from power supply input +28VDC, at the connection between the cathode of diode <b>5</b>D<b>6</b> (which is connected at the anode to power supply input +28VDC) and resistor <b>5</b>R<b>7</b>. The other end of resistor <b>5</b>R<b>7</b> is coupled by parallel-connected resistor <b>5</b>R<b>3</b>, capacitor <b>5</b>C<b>2</b> and reverse bias connected zener diode <b>5</b>D<b>3</b> to ground, with a resistor <b>5</b>R<b>13</b> and capacitor <b>5</b>C<b>6</b> connected in series between the terminal of resistor <b>5</b>R<b>7</b> and ground, in parallel with resistor <b>5</b>R<b>3</b>, capacitor <b>5</b>C<b>2</b> and zener diode <b>5</b>D<b>3</b>. A reverse bias connected zener diode is connected in parallel with resistor <b>5</b>R<b>13</b>, with the connection between resistor <b>5</b>R<b>13</b> and capacitor <b>5</b>C<b>6</b> connected to input AR of timer U<b>10</b>. The cathode of zener diode <b>5</b>D<b>9</b> and zener diode <b>5</b>D<b>3</b>, along with one terminal of each of resistor <b>5</b>R<b>13</b>, resistor <b>5</b>R<b>3</b>, and capacitor <b>5</b>C<b>2</b>, is connected to the power supply input Vdd of timer U<b>10</b>. Input Ctc of timer U<b>10</b> is connected via resistor <b>5</b>R<b>2</b> to input Rtc of timer U<b>10</b> and via series-connected capacitor <b>5</b>C<b>5</b> and resistor <b>5</b>R<b>1</b> to input Rs of timer U<b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Input MR of timer U<b>10</b> is connected through resistor <b>5</b>R<b>6</b> and reverse bias connected diode <b>5</b>D<b>5</b> to the circuit terminal RESET, with a pull-up resistor <b>5</b>R<b>9</b> coupling the node between diode <b>5</b>D<b>5</b> and resistor <b>5</b>R<b>5</b> to the node between diode <b>5</b>D<b>6</b> and resistor <b>5</b>R<b>7</b> and with transient and overvoltage protection to ground provided by capacitor <b>5</b>C<b>3</b> and reverse bias connected zener diode <b>5</b>D<b>7</b>. Likewise control input MODE of timer U<b>10</b> is connected through resistor <b>5</b>R<b>4</b> and reverse bias connected diode <b>5</b>D<b>4</b> to the circuit terminal MODE, with a pull-up resistor <b>5</b>R<b>16</b> coupling the node between diode <b>5</b>D<b>4</b> and resistor <b>5</b>R<b>4</b> to the node between diode <b>5</b>D<b>6</b> and resistor <b>5</b>R<b>7</b> and with transient and overvoltage protection to ground provided by capacitor <b>5</b>C<b>7</b> and reverse bias connected zener diode <b>5</b>D<b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Circuit inputs A and B are connected to timer inputs A and B, respectively, through reverse bias connected diode <b>5</b>D<b>13</b> and resistor <b>5</b>R<b>15</b>, and through reverse bias connected diode <b>5</b>D<b>15</b> and resistor <b>5</b>R<b>14</b>. Pull-up resistor <b>5</b>R<b>12</b> couples the node between diode <b>5</b>D<b>13</b> and resistor <b>5</b>R<b>15</b> to the node between diode <b>5</b>D<b>6</b> and resistor <b>5</b>R<b>7</b>, and transient and overvoltage protection to ground is provided by capacitor <b>5</b>C<b>4</b> and reverse bias connected zener diode <b>5</b>D<b>11</b>. Likewise pull-up resistor <b>5</b>R<b>15</b> couples the node between diode <b>5</b>D<b>15</b> and resistor <b>5</b>R<b>14</b> to the node between diode <b>5</b>D<b>6</b> and resistor <b>5</b>R<b>7</b>, and transient and overvoltage protection to ground is provided by capacitor <b>5</b>C<b>8</b> and reverse bias connected zener diode <b>5</b>D<b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a high level functional block diagram of an embedded universal logic interface module within the pushbutton illuminated switch of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A-1C</figref>, contained within electronic module <b>111</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a circuit diagram for the embedded universal logic interface module of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. Electronic circuitry <b>600</b> within the universal logic interface module includes several functional units: input buffering unit <b>601</b>; logic power supply unit <b>602</b>; Boolean logic array unit <b>603</b>; and output drivers unit <b>604</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">A universal logic interface module contained within an illuminated pushbutton switch provides a number of benefits over traditional illuminated pushbutton switches, combining normally external logic functions with the illuminated push button switch into one unit. This combination of a Boolean logic with the illuminated pushbutton switch can replace traditional electro-mechanical relays and diode logic with an internal module, and may be used in multiple ways such as to provide conditional logic for illumination of the local switch or to drive external devices such as a remote switch, a horn or a remote unit. The capability allows either a local or remote input to utilize the conditional Boolean logic contained within the switch, enhancing the overall switch functionality. In addition, the universal logic interface module can also be used to invert the logic of any signal, a capability traditionally performed using an external relay. The resulting combined switch and, electronics permit elimination of the external relay and associated wiring, saving weight and improving the overall reliability of the application.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">TABLE V below contains the logic signals and functions for the universal logic interface module of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, while TABLE VI describes the Boolean logic capability and TABLE VII describes the Boolean logic functions that may be implemented with 4 logic inputs and one logic output:</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00005" num="00005">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="4">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="35pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="42pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="63pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="77pt" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" rowsep="1">TABLE V</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>4-POLE</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>SIGNAL</entry>
<entry>HOUSING</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>NAME</entry>
<entry>PIN</entry>
<entry>LOGIC FUNCTION</entry>
<entry>COMMENTS</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>A</entry>
<entry>J1</entry>
<entry>Boolean logic input</entry>
<entry>See TABLES VI and</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>VII below</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>B</entry>
<entry>J2</entry>
<entry>Boolean logic input</entry>
<entry>See TABLES VI and</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>VII below</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>C</entry>
<entry>J3</entry>
<entry>Boolean logic input</entry>
<entry>See TABLES VI and</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>VII below</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>D</entry>
<entry>K3</entry>
<entry>Boolean logic input</entry>
<entry>See TABLES VI and</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>VII below</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>+28 VDC</entry>
<entry>J4</entry>
<entry>Power</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Ground</entry>
<entry>K1</entry>
<entry>Ground</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Q1</entry>
<entry>K2</entry>
<entry>Output:</entry>
<entry>Value is based on</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>H: high impedance</entry>
<entry>logic selected and</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>L: ground</entry>
<entry>value of inputs A, B, C</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>and D</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Q2</entry>
<entry>K4</entry>
<entry>/Q1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00006" num="00006">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0" pgwide="1">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="12">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="8" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="9" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="10" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="11" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="12" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="12" rowsep="1">TABLE VI</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="12" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>/A</entry>
<entry>/A</entry>
<entry>/A</entry>
<entry>/A</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>A</entry>
<entry>B</entry>
<entry>AND</entry>
<entry>NAND</entry>
<entry>OR</entry>
<entry>NOR</entry>
<entry>AND B</entry>
<entry>NAND B</entry>
<entry>OR B</entry>
<entry>NOR B</entry>
<entry>XOR</entry>
<entry>XNOR</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="12" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="12" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>/C</entry>
<entry>/C</entry>
<entry>/C</entry>
<entry>/C</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>C</entry>
<entry>D</entry>
<entry>AND</entry>
<entry>NAND</entry>
<entry>OR</entry>
<entry>NOR</entry>
<entry>AND D</entry>
<entry>NAND D</entry>
<entry>OR D</entry>
<entry>NOR D</entry>
<entry>XOR</entry>
<entry>XNOR</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="12" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="12" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00007" num="00007">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="9">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="14pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="8" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="8" rowsep="1">TABLE VII</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="8" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>A</entry>
<entry>B</entry>
<entry>C</entry>
<entry>D</entry>
<entry>AND</entry>
<entry>OR</entry>
<entry>NAND</entry>
<entry>NOR</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="8" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="8" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The universal logic interface module <b>600</b> has a total of eight (8) interface pins, four devoted to logic inputs A, B, C and D and two devoted to logic outputs Q<b>1</b> and Q<b>2</b>. Two additional interface pins are devoted to power: +28 VDC and Ground.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The logic power supply for the logic circuits is provided by a zener shunt regulator from the +28 VDC power input. Due to the low operating current of the CMOS circuitry, current limiting resistor has been assigned the value of 10K in order to limit the current of any EMC or voltage transient on the +28 VDC power pin. Transient suppression and voltage regulation on the +7.5 VDC logic power supply is provided by diode and capacitor filtering of input and logic transients. Because the logic power supply is a simple shunt voltage regulator, the universal logic interface module <b>600</b> can operate over a wide input voltage range from below +10 VDC to in excess of +30 VDC.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Each logic input to the universal logic interface module <b>600</b> includes input filter circuitry designed to protect the integrated circuits from EMC, voltage transients, electromechanical contact bounce and shift the 28 VDC logic level to a 7.5 VDC logic level. The EMC protection, voltage transient protection and logic level shift function is accomplished with resistors and zener diodes. Furthermore, CMOS latch-up on extreme transients such as lightning or conducted EMP is prevented by clamping the logic inputs 0.5 VDC below the logic power supply voltage. Suppression of electromechanical contact bounce is provided by resistor capacitor time constant on all inputs. A default static logic level is established for the Logic Inputs through pull-up resistors to the input power, preventing floating logic states on unconnected inputs. The 7.5 volt internal operating voltage raises the input voltage level sufficiently so that single external blocking diodes in any control line will not interfere with the normal operation of the unit.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The universal logic interface module <b>600</b> includes NAND gate and inverter integrated circuits <b>5</b>U<b>11</b> and <b>5</b>U<b>12</b>. The functional operation of universal logic interface module <b>600</b> is described in TABLE V and universal logic interface module <b>600</b> is connected as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>. The ground input <b>7</b>K<b>1</b> (corresponding to input K<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>) provides a terminal for selective jumper connections to ground. The power supply voltage input +28VDC (corresponding to circuit input J<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>) is connected by forward bias connected diode <b>7</b>D<b>10</b> to resistor <b>7</b>R<b>9</b>, with the other terminal of resistor <b>7</b>R<b>9</b> connected to ground through parallel connected resistor <b>7</b>R<b>18</b>, capacitor <b>7</b>C<b>5</b> and reverse bias connected zener diode <b>7</b>D<b>9</b>. The node connected to that terminal of resistor <b>7</b>R<b>9</b> provides a terminal for selective jumper connections to a logic high voltage (e.g., +5VDC). Each of circuit inputs A, B, C and D are connected to the cathode of a diode <b>7</b>D<b>5</b>, <b>7</b>D<b>4</b>, <b>7</b>D<b>3</b> and <b>7</b>D<b>2</b>, respectively, with the anode of each of those diodes connected to the cathode of diode <b>7</b>D<b>10</b> by a pull-up resistor <b>7</b>R<b>5</b>, <b>7</b>R<b>4</b>, <b>7</b>R<b>3</b> and <b>7</b>R<b>2</b> respectively. The anode of diode <b>7</b>D<b>5</b> is connected to one terminal of a resistor <b>7</b>R<b>8</b>, the other terminal of which is connected to ground through parallel connected capacitor <b>7</b>C<b>4</b> and reverse bias connected zener diode <b>7</b>D<b>8</b>. The anode of diode <b>7</b>D<b>4</b> is connected to one terminal of a resistor <b>7</b>R<b>7</b>, the other terminal of which is connected to ground through parallel connected capacitor <b>7</b>C<b>3</b> and reverse bias connected zener diode <b>7</b>D<b>7</b>. The anode of diode <b>7</b>D<b>3</b> is connected to one terminal of a resistor <b>7</b>R<b>6</b>, the other terminal of which is connected to ground through parallel connected capacitor <b>7</b>C<b>2</b> and reverse bias connected zener diode <b>7</b>D<b>6</b>. The anode of diode <b>7</b>D<b>21</b><i>s </i>connected to one terminal of a resistor <b>7</b>R<b>1</b>, the other terminal of which is connected to ground through parallel connected capacitor <b>7</b>C<b>1</b> and reverse bias connected zener diode <b>7</b>D<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The signal from circuit input A (corresponding to circuit input J<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>), after passing through diode <b>7</b>D<b>5</b> and resistor <b>7</b>R<b>8</b>, is input to inverter <b>754</b> and to one terminal of resistor <b>7</b>R<b>17</b>. The output of inverter <b>754</b> is connected to one terminal of resistor <b>7</b>R<b>16</b>, the other terminal of which is connected, together with the second terminal of resistor <b>7</b>R<b>17</b>, to a first input of NAND gate <b>7</b>N<b>2</b>. Likewise the signal from circuit input B (corresponding to circuit input J<b>2</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>), after passing through diode <b>7</b>D<b>4</b> and resistor <b>7</b>R<b>7</b>, is input to inverter <b>753</b> and to one terminal of resistor <b>7</b>R<b>14</b>. The output of inverter <b>753</b> is connected to one terminal of resistor <b>7</b>R<b>15</b>, the other terminal of which is connected, together with the second terminal of resistor <b>7</b>R<b>14</b>, to a second input of NAND gate <b>7</b>N<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The signal from circuit input C (corresponding to circuit input J<b>3</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>), after passing through diode <b>7</b>D<b>3</b> and resistor <b>7</b>R<b>6</b>, is input to inverter <b>752</b> and to one terminal of resistor <b>7</b>R<b>13</b>. The output of inverter <b>752</b> is connected to one terminal of resistor <b>7</b>R<b>12</b>, the other terminal of which is connected, together with the second terminal of resistor <b>7</b>R<b>13</b>, to a first input of NAND gate <b>7</b>N<b>1</b>. Likewise the signal from circuit input D (corresponding to circuit input K<b>3</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>), after passing through diode <b>7</b>D<b>2</b> and resistor <b>7</b>R<b>1</b>, is input to inverter <b>751</b> and to one terminal of resistor <b>7</b>R<b>10</b>. The output of inverter <b>751</b> is connected to one terminal of resistor <b>7</b>R<b>11</b>, the other terminal of which is connected, together with the second terminal of resistor <b>7</b>R<b>10</b>, to a second input of NAND gate <b>7</b>N<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The output of NAND gate <b>7</b>N<b>2</b> is connected to the input of inverter <b>756</b> and to one terminal of resistor <b>7</b>R<b>19</b>, the other terminal of which is connected to resistor <b>7</b>R<b>20</b> that is connected in series with inverter <b>756</b>, at the terminal opposite the output of inverter <b>756</b>. Likewise the output of NAND gate <b>7</b>N<b>1</b> is connected to the input of inverter <b>755</b> and to one terminal of resistor <b>7</b>R<b>21</b>, the other terminal of which is connected to resistor <b>7</b>R<b>22</b> that is connected in series with inverter <b>755</b>, at the terminal opposite the output of inverter <b>755</b>. The node connecting resistors <b>7</b>R<b>19</b> and <b>7</b>R<b>20</b> is connected to one input of NAND gate <b>7</b>N<b>3</b> and (through resistor <b>7</b>R<b>27</b>) to the gate of MOSFET <b>7</b>M<b>2</b>, while the node connecting resistors <b>7</b>R<b>21</b> and <b>7</b>R<b>22</b> is connected to the other input of NAND gate <b>7</b>N<b>3</b> and (through resistor <b>7</b>R<b>23</b>) to the gate of MOSFET <b>7</b>M<b>2</b>. The output of NAND gate <b>7</b>N<b>3</b> is connected through resistor <b>7</b>R<b>24</b> to both inputs to NAND gate <b>7</b>N<b>2</b>, through resistor <b>7</b>R<b>25</b> to the output of NAND gate <b>7</b>N<b>4</b>, and through resistor <b>7</b>R<b>26</b> to the gate of MOSFET <b>7</b>M<b>2</b>. The output of NAND gate <b>7</b>N<b>4</b> is connected through resistor <b>7</b>R<b>28</b> to the gate of MOSFET <b>7</b>M<b>1</b>. The gates of MOSFETs <b>7</b>M<b>2</b> and <b>7</b>M<b>1</b> are connected, through resistor <b>7</b>R<b>30</b> and <b>7</b>R<b>29</b>, respectively, to ground. Impedances <b>7</b>Z<b>2</b> and <b>7</b>Z<b>1</b> are connected across the source and drain terminals of MOSFETs <b>7</b>M<b>2</b> and <b>7</b>M<b>1</b>, respectively, and at one terminal to ground and at the opposite terminal through fuse <b>7</b>F<b>2</b> to circuit output <b>7</b>K<b>4</b> (corresponding to circuit output K<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>) and through fuse <b>7</b>F<b>1</b> to circuit output <b>7</b>K<b>2</b> (corresponding to circuit output K<b>2</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>), respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The desired logic circuit is configured by the application and removal of zero ohm jumpers in conjunction with the NAND and inversion logic. For example, inverting the inputs to a NAND will cause the logic to be an OR. Using this technique, all basic Boolean logic can be achieved with just the inverters and NAND gates, allowing a single design to achieve maximum flexibility and be configured as needed for each application. Four input Boolean logic is also obtained by the inclusion of 2 additional NAND gates that tie the two independent channels together, which further enhances the capability of the unit.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Each logic output from the universal logic interface module <b>600</b> includes a power MOSFET and an output filter designed to protect each output device from transients and overload conditions. Each of the MOSFETs Q<b>1</b> and Q<b>2</b> are rated at 4 ampere at 45 VDC, with both voltage and current parameters chosen to be substantially greater than operational requirements. Transient protection for the MOSFETs is provided by Z<b>1</b> and Z<b>2</b>, with a breakdown voltage of 39 VDC. Overload protection is provided by fuses F<b>1</b> and F<b>2</b>. To provide the highest possible reliability, each logic output has been de-rated to a maximum operating current of 1.0 ampere.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a circuit diagram for an electronic latching and/or blinking circuit according to one embodiment of the present disclosure. Electronic latching and/or blinking circuit <b>800</b> is contained within the electronic module <b>111</b> in switch <b>100</b>. TABLE VIII below contains the input and output signal descriptions for circuit <b>800</b>, while TABLE IX describes the logic input and output functions:</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00008" num="00008">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="4">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="49pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="42pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="35pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="91pt" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" rowsep="1">TABLE VIII</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>SIGNAL</entry>
<entry/>
<entry>ACTIVE</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>NAME</entry>
<entry>FUNCTION</entry>
<entry>STATE</entry>
<entry>DESCRIPTION</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>/RESET</entry>
<entry>Input</entry>
<entry>Low</entry>
<entry>Forces /N_OPEN to OFF</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>(open).</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>Forces /N_CLOSED to ON</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>(ground).</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>Forces /BLINK to Steady ON</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>(ground).</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>See Note 1 below.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>/TOGGLE</entry>
<entry>Input</entry>
<entry>&#x2193;</entry>
<entry>Toggles /N_OPEN and</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>/N_CLOSED</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>outputs. Toggles blink</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>mode. See Note 2</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>below.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>/SET</entry>
<entry>Input</entry>
<entry>Low</entry>
<entry>Forces /N_OPEN to ON</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>(ground).</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>Forces /N_CLOSED to OFF</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>(open).</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>Initiates 1 Hz blink mode to </entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>/BLINK output.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>+28 VDC</entry>
<entry>Power</entry>
<entry>&#x2014;</entry>
<entry>Power (+10 VDC to +30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>VDC)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Ground</entry>
<entry>Common</entry>
<entry>&#x2014;</entry>
<entry>Common for power and</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>signals.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>/N_OPEN</entry>
<entry>Output</entry>
<entry>Low</entry>
<entry>Open drain output.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>Forced OFF (open) by</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>/RESET input.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>Forced ON (ground) by /SET</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>input.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>Toggled by falling edge of</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>/TOGGLE input.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>/N_CLOSED</entry>
<entry>Output</entry>
<entry>Low</entry>
<entry>Open drain output.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>Forced ON (ground) by</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>/RESET input.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>Forced OFF (open) by /SET</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>input.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>Toggled by falling edge of</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>/TOGGLE input.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>/BLINK</entry>
<entry>Output</entry>
<entry>Low</entry>
<entry>Open drain output.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>Forced ON (ground) while</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>/RESET is held low. See</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>TABLE II below.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00009" num="00009">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="84pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="133pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="2" rowsep="1">TABLE IX</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Inputs</entry>
<entry>Outputs</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="6">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="42pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="49pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="42pt" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>/SET</entry>
<entry>/RESET</entry>
<entry>/TOGGLE</entry>
<entry>/N_OPEN</entry>
<entry>/N_CLOSED</entry>
<entry>/BLINK</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="6" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>L</entry>
<entry>H</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>L (ground)</entry>
<entry>H (open)</entry>
<entry>1 Hz blink</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>mode.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>H</entry>
<entry>L</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>H (open)</entry>
<entry>L (ground)</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>L</entry>
<entry>L</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>See Note 3.</entry>
<entry>See Note 3.</entry>
<entry>Steady ON.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>See Note 1.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>H</entry>
<entry>H</entry>
<entry>&#x2193;</entry>
<entry>Toggle</entry>
<entry>Toggle</entry>
<entry>Toggle.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>state.</entry>
<entry>state.</entry>
<entry>See Note 1.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="6" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0067">Note 1: /BLINK output is held steady ON (ground) while /RESET is held low. /BLINK output goes OFF (open) when /RESET returns to the inactive high level. This feature provides essentially three states to the /BLINK output: OFF, ON and BLINK.</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0002" num="0068">Note 2: /TOGGLE input causes /BLINK output to alternate between 1 Hertz (Hz) blink state and OFF (open).</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0003" num="0069">Note 3: This is an illegal state that will have unpredictable effect upon the outputs when the inputs are returned to their normal inactive high state.</li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0070">The logic input circuitry <b>801</b> for has a total of eight (8) interface pads each connected to an external pin of electronic module <b>111</b>. Three interface pads are inputs: /SET, /RESET and /TOGGLE. Three interface pads are outputs: /N_OPEN (normally open), /N_CLOSED (normally closed) and /BLINK. Two additional interface pads are devoted to power: +28 VDC (volts, direct current) and Ground.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0071">Each input pad is connected by two parallel resistors: resistors <b>8</b>R<b>1</b> and <b>8</b>R<b>2</b> for input /SET; resistors <b>8</b>R<b>3</b> and <b>8</b>R<b>4</b> for input /TOGGLE; and resistors <b>8</b>R<b>5</b> and <b>8</b>R<b>6</b> for input /RESET. One resistor of each parallel pair (<b>8</b>R<b>1</b>, <b>8</b>R<b>3</b> and <b>8</b>R<b>5</b>) is connected at the one terminal to the +28 VDC input power. The other resistor of each pair (<b>8</b>R<b>2</b>, <b>8</b>R<b>4</b> and <b>8</b>R<b>6</b>) is connected to one terminal of a capacitor (<b>8</b>C<b>1</b>, <b>8</b>C<b>2</b> and <b>8</b>C<b>3</b>, respectively) and to the cathode of a zener diode (<b>8</b>D<b>1</b>, <b>8</b>D<b>2</b> and <b>8</b>D<b>3</b>, respectively). The other capacitor terminals and the anodes of the zener diodes are connected to ground. Resistors <b>8</b>R<b>1</b>, <b>8</b>R<b>2</b>, <b>8</b>R<b>3</b>, <b>8</b>R<b>4</b>, <b>8</b>R<b>5</b> and <b>8</b>R<b>6</b> each have a resistance of 33 kilo-Ohms (K&#x3a9;). Capacitor <b>8</b>C<b>1</b> has a capacitance of 0.1 micro-Farads (&#x3bc;F) and each of capacitors <b>8</b>C<b>2</b> and <b>8</b>C<b>3</b> has a capacitance of 1.0 &#x3bc;F in the example depicted.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0072">Each input to circuit <b>800</b> includes input filter circuitry designed to protect the integrated circuits from EMC, voltage transients, electromechanical contact bounce and shift the 28 VDC logic level to a 5 VDC logic level.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0073">Resistors <b>8</b>R<b>2</b>, <b>8</b>R<b>4</b> and <b>8</b>R<b>6</b> and zener diodes <b>8</b>D<b>1</b>, <b>8</b>D<b>2</b> and <b>8</b>D<b>3</b> provide electromagnetic charge (EMC) protection and voltage transient protection to circuit <b>800</b>, and shift the 28 VDC logic level to a 5 VDC logic level. Furthermore, complementary metal-oxide-semiconductor (CMOS) latch-up on extreme transients such as lightning or a conducted electromagnetic pulse (EMP) is prevented by clamping the inputs 0.5 VDC below the logic power supply voltage. Capacitors <b>8</b>C<b>1</b>, <b>8</b>C<b>2</b> and <b>8</b>C<b>3</b> suppress electromechanical contact bounce. Resistors <b>8</b>R<b>5</b> and <b>8</b>R<b>6</b> and capacitor <b>8</b>C<b>3</b> on the /RESET input guarantee a default power-up state for circuit <b>800</b> since the power-up time constant of those components is substantially longer than that of both the logic power supply VCC (which has a lower resistance) and the /SET input (which has a much smaller capacitance). Pull-up resistors <b>8</b>R<b>1</b>, <b>8</b>R<b>3</b> and <b>8</b>R<b>5</b> establish a default static logic level for the inputs, preventing floating logic states on unconnected inputs.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0074">The logic power supply functional unit <b>802</b> generating the logic power supply voltage VCC for circuit <b>800</b> includes resistor <b>8</b>R<b>7</b> (which has a resistance of 15 K&#x3a9;), zener diode <b>8</b>D<b>4</b> and capacitor <b>8</b>C<b>4</b> (which has a capacitance of 1.0 pF) from the +28 VDC power input. Due to the low operating current of the CMOS logic circuitry within circuit <b>800</b>, the value of resistor <b>8</b>R<b>7</b> is selected to limit the current of any EMC or voltage transient on the +28 VDC power pad. Transient suppression and voltage regulation on the +5.6 VDC logic power supply is provided by <b>8</b>D<b>4</b> while <b>8</b>C<b>4</b> provides filtering of input and logic transients. Because the logic power supply is a simple shunt voltage regulator, circuit <b>800</b> can operate over a wide input voltage range from below +10 VDC to in excess of +30 VDC.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0075">Circuit <b>800</b> includes two high speed CMOS integrated circuits: a dual D-Type latch (FF<b>1</b> and FF<b>2</b>) and a quad NAND gate (<b>8</b>NAND<b>1</b>, <b>8</b>NAND<b>2</b>, <b>8</b>NAND<b>3</b> and <b>8</b>NAND<b>3</b>) implementing the latch logic <b>803</b> and the blink circuitry <b>804</b>. The inverted preset input PRE of latch <b>8</b>FF<b>1</b> is connected by resistor <b>8</b>R<b>1</b> to the /SET input, while the input D of latch <b>8</b>FF<b>1</b> is connected to the inverting output of latch <b>8</b>FF<b>1</b>. The clock input CLK of latch <b>8</b>FF<b>1</b> is coupled by NAND gate <b>8</b>NAND<b>4</b>, configured as an inverter with the inputs tied together, by resistor <b>8</b>R<b>4</b> to the /TOGGLE input. The inverted clear input CLR of latch <b>8</b>FF<b>1</b> is connected by resistor <b>8</b>R<b>6</b> to the /RESET input.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0076">Latch <b>8</b>FF<b>1</b> is the primary latching circuit that responds to the inputs /SET, /RESET and /TOGGLE as described in TABLE II above. NAND gate <b>8</b>NAND<b>4</b> is connected between the /TOGGLE input and the clock input of latch <b>8</b>FF<b>1</b> for the purpose of inverting the positive (leading) edge trigger of latch <b>8</b>FF<b>1</b> to a negative (trailing) edge trigger. The inverting output of latch <b>8</b>FF<b>1</b> is connected to the D input so that successive /TOGGLE inputs to latch <b>8</b>FF<b>1</b> result in a toggling action of latch <b>8</b>FF<b>1</b> non-inverting and inverting outputs Q and /Q. The non-inverting output Q from latch <b>8</b>FF<b>1</b> drives the normally open output /N_OPEN via n-channel enhancement mode metal-oxide-semiconductor field effect transistor (MOSFET) <b>8</b>Q<b>3</b>, and the inverting output /Q from latch FF<b>1</b> drives the normally closed output /N_CLOSED via MOSFET <b>8</b>Q<b>2</b>. The non-inverting output Q of latch <b>8</b>FF<b>1</b> also holds latch <b>8</b>FF<b>2</b> in the reset state any time latch <b>8</b>FF<b>1</b> is in the reset state.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0077">Blink circuitry <b>804</b> includes series connected NAND gates <b>8</b>NAND<b>1</b> and <b>8</b>NAND<b>2</b> configured as inverters with the respective inputs tied together and are interconnected as a dual inverting buffer that, together with resistor <b>8</b>R<b>8</b> (having a resistance of 220 K&#x3a9;) connecting a feedback loop from the output of NAND gate <b>8</b>NAND<b>2</b> to the input of NAND gate <b>8</b>NAND<b>1</b> with the input to NAND gate <b>8</b>NAND<b>2</b> and capacitor <b>8</b>C<b>5</b> (having a capacitance of 1.9 &#x3bc;F) connected in the feedback loop, form a free running square wave oscillator with a fundamental frequency F=1/(2.2&#xd7;<b>8</b>R<b>8</b>&#xd7;<b>8</b>C<b>5</b>) of approximately 2 Hertz (Hz). The output of that oscillator feeds the clock input CLK of 8latch FF<b>2</b>, where the inverting output /Q of latch FF<b>2</b> is connected to the D input so that latch <b>8</b>FF<b>2</b> functions as f/2 frequency divider. The inverted preset input PRE of latch <b>8</b>FF<b>2</b> is tied to the logic supply voltage VCC. Because the inverted clear input CLR of latch <b>8</b>FF<b>2</b> is connected to the non-inverting output Q of latch <b>8</b>FF<b>1</b>, the f/2 divider circuit is effectively disabled any time latch <b>8</b>FF<b>1</b> is in the reset state. The f/2 divided frequency output of latch <b>8</b>FF<b>2</b> creates the 1 Hz blink mode oscillator, enabled only when latch <b>8</b>FF<b>2</b> is in the set state.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0078">The enabled 1 Hertz blink signal from the inverting output /Q of latch <b>8</b>FF<b>2</b> is connected, along with the filtered /RESET input, each to one input of NAND gate <b>8</b>NAND<b>3</b>. NAND gate <b>8</b>NAND<b>3</b> thus serves as blink logic, forcing the /BLINK output to be held in a steady ON state any time the /RESET input signal is held low. The output of NAND gate <b>8</b>NAND<b>3</b> is connected to MOSFET <b>8</b>Q<b>1</b> to provide the /BLINK output of circuit <b>800</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0079">Each output from the circuit <b>800</b> includes a power MOSFET <b>8</b>Q<b>1</b>, <b>8</b>Q<b>2</b> or <b>8</b>Q<b>3</b> each rated at 2.5 ampere (A) at 45 VDC (both parameters chosen to be substantially greater than operational requirements) and an output filter designed to protect each output device from transients and overload conditions. Transient protection for the MOSFETs <b>8</b>Q<b>1</b>, <b>8</b>Q<b>2</b> and <b>8</b>Q<b>3</b> is provided by impedances <b>8</b>Z<b>1</b>, <b>8</b>Z<b>2</b> and <b>8</b>Z<b>3</b>, each having a breakdown voltage of 39 VDC. Overload protection is provided by resettable Positive Temperature Coefficient (PTC) resistors <b>8</b>R<b>9</b>, <b>8</b>R<b>10</b> and <b>8</b>R<b>11</b> with a holding current of 0.5 A at elevated temperatures. These devices perform the function of a fuse, limiting current in the event of a short or overload, but automatically return to their normal state when the short or overload is removed. In order to provide the highest possible reliability, each output /N_OPEN, /N_CLOSED and /BLINK is derated to a maximum operating current of 0.5 A.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0080">The features of activating switch functions from a remote location, energizing or blinking a local or remote display, resetting the switch state automatically upon remote acknowledgement, changing the state of a switch or display at one location based on another, remote switch controlling the same function being depressed, and automatic reset to a default state after loss of power are implemented in the present disclosure by replacing the traditional electromagnetic holding coil within the illuminated pushbutton switch housing with a subminiature electronic logic module. The logic module provides many additional features beyond the simple latching or on/off toggling functionality that is typical of an electromagnetic holding coil, including lower size and weight, longer switch life, no electrical spikes, remote set and reset capability, display blinking, and high reliability electronic driver circuits that can drive modest electrical loads.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0081">Although the above description is made in connection with specific exemplary embodiments, various changes and modifications will be apparent to and/or suggested by the present disclosure to those skilled in the art. It is intended that the present disclosure encompass all such changes and modifications as fall within the scope of the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A circuit for an illuminating pushbutton switch comprising:
<claim-text>an electronic module fitting within a space in the illuminating pushbutton switch housing sufficient to accommodate two snap-action switches, the electronic module comprising one of a configurable pulse timer interface module, a pulse selectable timer interface module, and a universal logic interface module.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the electronic module comprises a configurable pulse timer interface module, the configurable pulse timer interface module comprising:
<claim-text>an input buffer configured to receive one or more trigger signals;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an edge detection and pulse generation circuit configured to produce, in response to one of the one or more trigger signals, a pulse of selectable timing relative to an edge of the one trigger signal, of selectable orientation, and of selectable duration; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>one or more pulse timing control circuits for setting the selectable timing, orientation and duration of pulses produced by the edge detection and pulse generation circuit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the edge detection and pulse generation circuit is configured to produce pulses on two channels.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the selectable orientation comprises one of active high and active low.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the edge detection and pulse generation circuit comprises a mono-stable multi-vibrator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the electronic module comprises a pulse selectable timer interface module, the pulse selectable timer interface module comprising:
<claim-text>an input buffer configured to receive a trigger signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pulse timer generation circuit configured to produce, in response to the trigger signal, a pulse at a selectable time relative to an edge of the trigger signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pulse timer control circuit for setting the selectable time based on one or more control inputs to the pulse selectable timer interface module.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the selectable time is one of a plurality of predetermined numbers of clock cycles.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the pulse timer generation circuit comprises a binary counter and an internal oscillator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the electronic module comprises a universal logic interface module, the universal logic interface module comprising:
<claim-text>an input buffer configured to receive a plurality of logic input signals; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a logic array configured to produce a selected logic result based on at least two of the logic input signals.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the selected logic result is selected from AND, NAND, OR, NOR, XOR and XNOR.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A method of operating an illuminating pushbutton switch, comprising:
<claim-text>providing power to an electronic module fitting within a space in the illuminating pushbutton switch housing sufficient to accommodate two snap-action switches, the electronic module comprising one of a configurable pulse timer interface module, a pulse selectable timer interface module, and a universal logic interface module; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>employing the electronic module during operation of the illuminating pushbutton switch.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the electronic module comprises a configurable pulse timer interface module, the method further comprising:
<claim-text>receiving one or more trigger signals at an input buffer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>producing, in response to one of the one or more trigger signals, a pulse of selectable timing relative to an edge of the one trigger signal, of selectable orientation, and of selectable duration; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>setting the selectable timing, orientation and duration of pulses produced by the edge detection and pulse generation circuit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, further comprising producing pulses on two channels.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the selectable orientation comprises one of active high and active low.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, further comprising utilizing a mono-stable multi-vibrator to produce the pulse.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the electronic module comprises a pulse selectable timer interface module, the method further comprising:
<claim-text>receiving a trigger signal at an input buffer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>producing, in response to the trigger signal, a pulse at a selectable time relative to an edge of the trigger signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>setting the selectable time based on one or more control inputs.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the selectable time is one of a plurality of predetermined numbers of clock cycles.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, further comprising utilizing a binary counter and an internal oscillator to produce the pulse.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the electronic module comprises a universal logic interface module, the method further comprising:
<claim-text>receiving a plurality of logic input signals at an input buffer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>producing a selected logic result based on at least two of the logic input signals.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the selected logic result is selected from AND, NAND, OR, NOR, XOR and XNOR. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
