<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624948-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624948</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12776451</doc-number>
<date>20100510</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2009-0089650</doc-number>
<date>20090922</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>162</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>2</main-group>
<subgroup>47</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>2</main-group>
<subgroup>435</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347235</main-classification>
<further-classification>347250</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Apparatus and method of detecting horizontal synchronization signal in image forming apparatus</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5570195</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Honbo</name>
<date>19961000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>358302</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6124948</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kamioka</name>
<date>20000900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>358409</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6459520</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Takayama</name>
<date>20021000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>3592041</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0092493</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yoshikawa et al.</name>
<date>20060500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>359216</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0067024</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Shiraishi</name>
<date>20090300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>359205</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2008126587</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20080600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>21</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>10</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>16</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110069135</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110324</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Han</last-name>
<first-name>Hyun-Jin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Han</last-name>
<first-name>Hyun-Jin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Staas &#x26; Halsey LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Suwon-Si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Luu</last-name>
<first-name>Matthew</first-name>
<department>2861</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Liu</last-name>
<first-name>Kendrick</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Provided is a device for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal of an image forming apparatus. The device includes a light intensity converter to convert light intensity of a first beam emitted from a first light source and light intensity of a second beam emitted from a second light source to be different from each other, and outputting the first and second beams; a photo detector to receive the first beam and the second beam output from the light intensity converter, and outputting a first signal having a first level at a time of receiving the first beam and a second level at a time of receiving the second beam; and a horizontal synchronization signal detector to detect a horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam and a horizontal synchronization signal of the second beam by using the first signal.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="102.36mm" wi="111.51mm" file="US08624948-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="212.17mm" wi="168.06mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624948-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="178.90mm" wi="145.63mm" file="US08624948-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="203.28mm" wi="95.84mm" file="US08624948-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="202.61mm" wi="124.54mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624948-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="180.26mm" wi="142.66mm" file="US08624948-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="163.41mm" wi="147.91mm" file="US08624948-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="159.85mm" wi="138.60mm" file="US08624948-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="174.92mm" wi="144.27mm" file="US08624948-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="171.70mm" wi="132.76mm" file="US08624948-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="133.35mm" wi="133.77mm" file="US08624948-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of Korean Patent Application No. 10-2009-0089650, filed on Sep. 22, 2009, in the Korean Intellectual Property Office, the disclosure of which is incorporated herein in its entirety by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present general inventive concept relates to an apparatus and method of detecting a horizontal synchronization signal of an image forming apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Image forming apparatuses form images on printing media according to input signals, for example, printers, copying machines, faxing machines, and multifunctional devices combine functions of printers, copying machines, and faxing machines.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Tandem-type image forming apparatuses adopt an electrophotographic image forming method. Generally, a tandem-type image forming apparatus include a photosensitive medium, the number of which corresponds to the number of colors used in a printing operation. Since a color image forming apparatus generally uses toners of four colors, that is, yellow, magenta, cyan, and black colors, the tandem-type image forming apparatus includes four light sources and four photosensitive media, which respectively correspond to the four color toners.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Therefore, the color image forming apparatus forms an electrostatic latent image by focusing laser beams emitted from the four light sources according to image signals on photosensitive media corresponding to each of light sources. Here, a horizontal synchronization signal is used to coincide light scanning times of the four colors, and four photosensors are required to detect the horizontal synchronization signal from each of the colors. Therefore, there is a need to simplify a structure of an image forming apparatus and reduce fabrication costs by detecting the horizontal synchronization signal of each color with a small number of photosensors.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">An embodiment or embodiments provide an apparatus and/or method of detecting a horizontal synchronization signal of an image forming apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">An embodiment, includes a device for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal of an image forming apparatus, the device including: a light intensity converter to convert light intensity of a first beam emitted from a first light source and light intensity of a second beam emitted from a second light source to be different from each other, and to output the first and second beams; a photo detector to receive the first beam and the second beam output from the light intensity converter, and to output a first signal having a first level at a time of receiving the first beam and a second level at a time of receiving the second beam; and a horizontal synchronization signal detector to detect a horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam and a horizontal synchronization signal of the second beam by using the first signal is provided.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Another embodiment, includes a method of detecting a horizontal synchronization signal of an image forming apparatus, the method including: converting light intensity of a first beam emitted from a first light source and light intensity of a second beam emitted from a second light source to be different from each other and outputting the first and second beams; receiving the first beam and the second beam by a photo detector, and outputting a first signal having a first level at a time of receiving the first beam and a second level at a time of receiving the second beam; and detecting a horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam and a horizontal synchronization signal of the second beam by using the first signal is provided.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to another embodiment, there is provided a computer readable recording medium having embodied thereon a computer program for executing the above method.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The above and other features and advantages of the embodiment will become more apparent by describing in detail exemplary embodiments thereof with reference to the attached drawings in which:</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram illustrating a beam path in a light scanning device of an image forming apparatus according to an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram of a device for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal in the image forming apparatus, according to an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram of a light intensity converter in a device for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal in the image forming apparatus, according to the embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagram of a light intensity converter in a device for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal in an image forming apparatus according to another embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a diagram of a light intensity converter in a device for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal in an image forming apparatus, according to another embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a block diagram of a horizontal synchronization signal detector in a device for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal in an image forming apparatus according to an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a circuit diagram of the horizontal synchronization signal detector of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, in a device for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal in an image forming apparatus, according to an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a waveform diagram of a first signal output from a photo detector of a device for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal in an image forming apparatus, according to an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a waveform diagram of a third signal output from a first transistor, according to an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a waveform diagram of a fourth signal output from a first Schmitt trigger inverter, according to an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a waveform diagram of a horizontal synchronization signal of a first beam in a device for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal in an image forming apparatus, according to an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a waveform diagram of a fifth signal output from a third transistor, according to an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a waveform diagram of a sixth signal output from a second Schmitt trigger inverter, according to an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is a waveform diagram of a seventh signal output from a fourth transistor in a device for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal in an image forming apparatus, according to an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is a waveform diagram of a horizontal synchronization signal of a second beam in the device for detecting the horizontal synchronization signal in the image forming apparatus according to an embodiment; and</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref> is a flowchart illustrating a method of detecting a horizontal synchronization signal of an image forming apparatus, according to an embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">An embodiment or embodiments will now be described more fully with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which exemplary embodiments are shown.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram illustrating paths of beams in a light scanning device in an image forming apparatus according to an embodiment of the present invention. A light scanning device of a color image forming apparatus includes four light sources, which respectively scan yellow (Y), magenta (M), cyan (C), and black (K) beams to form electrostatic latent images on four photosensitive media, respectively. In the light scanning device of the image forming apparatus shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, two light sources, that is, C and K light sources, are only shown, and paths of C and K beams emitted from the C and K light sources are denoted. Although it is not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, beams emitted from Y and M light sources may have the same paths as the paths of C and K beams emitted from the C and K light sources shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Hereinafter, the paths of the beams in the light scanning device of the image forming apparatus according to an embodiment will be described as follows. For convenience of description, the light source of the C beam is denoted as a first light source <b>110</b><i>a</i>, and the light source of the K beam is denoted as a second light source <b>110</b><i>b</i>. The first light source <b>110</b><i>a </i>and the second light source <b>110</b><i>b </i>respectively emit a first beam and a second beam which have the same light intensity as each other at a predetermined time interval. The first beam and the second beam respectively emitted from the first light source <b>110</b><i>a </i>and the second light source <b>110</b><i>b </i>are collimated by collimating lenses <b>120</b><i>a </i>and <b>120</b><i>b</i>, and the first and second beams transmitting the collimating lenses <b>120</b><i>a </i>and <b>120</b><i>b </i>are condensed on a reflective surface of a polygon mirror <b>140</b> after transmitting through cylinder lenses <b>130</b><i>a </i>and <b>130</b><i>b</i>, respectively. In addition, the first and second beams which are respectively emitted from the first and second light sources <b>110</b><i>a </i>and <b>110</b><i>b </i>are condensed on different reflective surfaces of one polygon mirror <b>140</b>, and then, are reflected in a first direction and a second direction, respectively. The polygon mirror <b>140</b> is rotated at a constant speed by a driving motor <b>145</b> to scan the first beam and the second beam at a constant linear velocity. The first and second beams of constant velocity are reflected by the polygon mirror <b>140</b>, and then, aberrations of the first and second beams are corrected by corresponding focusing lenses <b>150</b><i>a </i>and <b>150</b><i>b </i>and the first and second beams are respectively focused on surfaces of photosensitive media <b>170</b><i>a </i>and <b>107</b><i>b </i>as electrostatic latent images by reflecting mirrors <b>160</b><i>a </i>and <b>160</b><i>b</i>. Alternatively, since a horizontal synchronization signal for coinciding the light scanning times of the Y and C colors is used, a device (not shown) for detecting the horizontal synchronization signal in the image forming apparatus of the embodiment includes horizontal synchronization signal detecting mirrors <b>180</b><i>a </i>and <b>180</b><i>b </i>on the paths of the beams reflected by the reflecting mirrors <b>160</b><i>a </i>and <b>160</b><i>b </i>toward the photosensitive media <b>170</b><i>a </i>and <b>170</b><i>b</i>, and receives the first and second beams reflected by the horizontal synchronization signal detecting mirrors <b>180</b><i>a </i>and <b>180</b><i>b </i>by using one photosensor (not shown) to detect the horizontal synchronization signal. In the embodiment, the horizontal synchronization detecting mirrors <b>180</b><i>a </i>and <b>180</b><i>b </i>are located on the paths of the beams reflected by the reflecting mirrors <b>160</b><i>a </i>and <b>160</b><i>b </i>toward the photosensitive media <b>170</b><i>a </i>and <b>170</b><i>b </i>to receive the first and second beams emitted from the first and second light sources <b>110</b><i>a </i>and <b>110</b><i>b</i>; however, the present invention is not limited thereto. That is, the horizontal synchronization signal detecting mirrors <b>180</b><i>a </i>and <b>180</b><i>b </i>may be located on another location provided that the beam paths are configured so that one sensor receives the first and second beams emitted from the first and second light sources <b>110</b><i>a </i>and <b>110</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram of a device <b>200</b> for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal a the image forming apparatus, according to an embodiment of the present invention. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the device <b>200</b> for detecting the horizontal synchronization signal includes a light intensity converter <b>210</b>, a photo detector <b>220</b>, and a horizontal synchronization signal detector <b>230</b>. An example of the photo detector <b>220</b> is a photodiode.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The first beam emitted from the first light source <b>110</b><i>a </i>and the second beam emitted from the second light source <b>110</b><i>b </i>are input into the light intensity converter <b>210</b>. Here, the first and second beams are reflected by the horizontal synchronization signal detecting mirrors <b>180</b><i>a </i>and <b>180</b><i>b </i>shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, and then, input into the light intensity converter <b>210</b>. The light intensity converter <b>210</b> converts the light intensities of the first beam and the second beam to be different from each other, and outputs the first and second beams. The device <b>200</b> for detecting the horizontal synchronization signal according to the embodiment reduces the light intensity of the second beam so as that the light intensities of the first and second beams are different from each other.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram showing a structure of a light intensity converter <b>210</b><i>a </i>in a device for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal of an image forming apparatus, according to an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the light intensity converter <b>210</b><i>a </i>of the present embodiment includes first and second beam detecting lenses <b>212</b><i>a </i>and <b>214</b><i>a </i>and a slit <b>216</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The first beam detecting lens <b>212</b><i>a </i>is located on a proceeding path of the first beam, and converts the first beam so as to be received by the photo detector <b>220</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The slit <b>216</b> is located on a proceeding path of the second beam, and reduces the light intensity of the second beam. Here, the slit <b>216</b> may be formed as a rib form, or may be formed of a sub-material.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The second beam detecting lens <b>214</b><i>a </i>is located on the proceeding path of the second beam which transmits through the slit <b>216</b>, and converts the second beam that transmitted through the slit <b>216</b> so as to be received by the photo detector <b>220</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">As described above, when the first beam detecting lens <b>212</b><i>a </i>is located on the proceeding path of the first beam and the slit <b>216</b> and the second beam detecting lens <b>214</b><i>a </i>are located on the proceeding path of the second beam, the light intensity of the second beam may be reduced. The first beam emitted from the first light source <b>110</b><i>a </i>and the second beam emitted from the second light source <b>110</b><i>b </i>may have the same light intensities as each other; however, only some of the second beam may be transmitted through the slit <b>216</b>. Thus, the light intensity of the second beam becomes less than that of the first beam. It is understood that the first beam intensity and the second beam's intensity may be different from each other.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagram of a structure of a light intensity converter <b>210</b><i>b </i>in the device for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal of an image forming apparatus, according to another embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the light intensity converter <b>210</b><i>b </i>includes first and second beam detecting lenses <b>212</b><i>b </i>and <b>214</b><i>b </i>and a filter <b>218</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The first and second beam detecting lenses <b>212</b><i>b </i>and <b>214</b><i>b </i>of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> have the same structures as those of the first and second beam detecting lenses <b>212</b><i>a </i>and <b>214</b><i>a </i>shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, and thus, detailed descriptions thereof are not provided here. The filter <b>218</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is located on the proceeding path of the second beam, like the slit <b>216</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, and reduces the light intensity of the second beam. An optical member having a light transmittance and adjusting the light intensity of received beam due to an interference between transmitted light and reflected light, for example, a neutral density (ND) filter, may be used as the filter <b>218</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a diagram showing a structure of a light intensity converter <b>210</b><i>c </i>in a device for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal in an image forming apparatus, according to another embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the light intensity converter <b>210</b><i>c </i>according to the present embodiment includes first and second beam detecting lenses <b>212</b><i>c </i>and <b>214</b><i>c. </i></p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The first beam detecting lens <b>212</b><i>c </i>is located on the proceeding path of the first beam to convert the first beam to be suitable for the photo detector <b>220</b> and output the first beam. In addition, the second beam detecting lens <b>214</b><i>c </i>is located on the proceeding path of the second beam to convert the second beam to be suitable for the photo detector <b>220</b> and output the second beam. The first beam detecting lens <b>212</b><i>c </i>and the second beam detecting lens <b>214</b><i>c </i>have different transmittances from each other. In the light intensity converter <b>210</b><i>c </i>of the present embodiment, the second beam detecting lens <b>214</b><i>c </i>has a transmittance which is lower than that of the first beam detecting lens <b>212</b><i>c </i>so that the light intensity of the beam transmitting through the second beam detecting lens <b>214</b><i>c </i>is reduced. Here, any kind of lens that may change the light intensity of a beam may be used as a beam detecting lens.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the photo detector <b>220</b> receives the first beam and the second beam output from the light intensity converter <b>210</b>, and outputs a first signal having a first level at the time of receiving the first beam and having a second level, which is lower than the first level, at the time of receiving the second beam. In general, a photo detector receives light and converts the received light into electric current. Therefore, the photo detector <b>220</b> of the embodiment receives the beams from the light intensity converter <b>210</b>, and converts the received beams into an electric signal and outputs the electric signal. It is noted that the photo detector may be a photodiode.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The horizontal synchronization signal detector <b>230</b> detects a horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam and a horizontal synchronization signal of the second beam using the first signal transmitted from the photo detector <b>220</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a block diagram of a horizontal synchronization signal detector <b>600</b> in a device for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal of an image forming apparatus, according to another embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the horizontal synchronization signal detector <b>600</b> according to the present embodiment includes a current mirror <b>610</b>, a first beam horizontal synchronization signal detector <b>620</b>, and a second beam horizontal synchronization signal detector <b>630</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The first beam horizontal synchronization signal detector <b>620</b> includes a first transistor <b>622</b>, a first Schmitt trigger inverter <b>624</b>, and a second transistor <b>626</b>. In addition, the second beam horizontal synchronization signal detector <b>630</b> includes a third transistor <b>632</b>, a second Schmitt trigger inverter <b>634</b>, a fourth transistor <b>636</b>, and a regulator <b>638</b>. It is understood that the horizontal synchronization signal detector <b>600</b> is an example of a horizontal synchronization signal detector <b>630</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a circuit diagram of a horizontal synchronization signal detector <b>600</b> in a device for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal of an image forming apparatus, according to an embodiment. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows a circuit diagram of the horizontal synchronization signal detector <b>600</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, and the operations of the horizontal synchronization signal detector <b>600</b> will be described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The current mirror <b>610</b> receives a first signal from the photo detector <b>220</b>, and outputs the received first signal to the first beam horizontal synchronization signal detector <b>620</b> and the second beam horizontal synchronization signal detector <b>630</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a waveform diagram of the first signal output from the photo detector <b>220</b> in a device for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal in an image forming apparatus, according to an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The photo detector <b>220</b> receives the first beam and the second beam at a predetermined time interval. Since the photo detector <b>220</b> outputs an electric signal according to a received beam, the photo detector <b>220</b> outputs the first signal having a first level and a second level at a predetermined time interval. Here, the first and second levels are in proportion to the light intensities of the beams, and the second level of the first signal is lower than the first level of the first signal.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The first signal is inputs to both the first beam horizontal synchronization signal detector <b>620</b> and the second beam horizontal synchronization signal detector <b>630</b>; however, the operations of the first and second beam horizontal synchronization signal detectors <b>620</b> and <b>630</b> are different from each other.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">First, the operations of the first beam horizontal synchronization signal detector <b>620</b> will be described as follows. The first transistor <b>622</b> is electrically conducted in a period of the first level of the first signal, and then, outputs a third signal which is inverted from a second signal having a first level at a time of receiving the first beam. The first transistor <b>622</b> includes an NPN-type transistor, where a collector of the first transistor <b>622</b> is connected to a driving voltage Vcc, a base of the first transistor <b>622</b> is connected to a current mirror, and an emitter of the first transistor <b>622</b> is grounded. In the first transistor <b>622</b>, when a base-emitter voltage is <b>0</b>.<b>7</b> V or greater, the collector and the emitter are conducted electrically. The first signal has high values of a first level and a second level, where the first level and the second level of the first signal are different from each other. The first transistor <b>622</b> sets a resistance of a resistor R<b>1</b> so as to be conducted electrically at the first level or greater. It is because when a constant electric current is supplied to the first transistor <b>622</b>, the base-emitter of the first transistor voltage varies depending on the resistance of the resistor R<b>1</b>. Otherwise, a transistor having a base voltage which is electrically conducted at the first level or greater is used as the first transistor <b>622</b> so that the first transistor <b>622</b> is electrically conducted in a section of the first level of the first signal. As described above, since the first transistor <b>622</b> is only electrically conducted in the section of the first level of the first signal, and not conducted in a section of the second level. Therefore, the first transistor <b>622</b> outputs a third signal which is obtained by inverting the second signal having the first level at a time of receiving the first beam.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a waveform diagram of the third signal output from the first transistor <b>622</b> according to an embodiment. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the third signal is obtained by inverting the second signal of the first level, and has a waveform having a low value in the section of the first level.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The third signal is input to the first Schmitt trigger inverter <b>624</b>, and the first Schmitt trigger inverter <b>624</b> outputs a fourth signal which is a square wave signal which is obtained by inverting the third signal. According to the characteristics of a Schmitt trigger inverter, the third signal is inverted, and the fourth signal is output from the first Schmitt trigger inverter <b>624</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a waveform diagram of the fourth signal output from the first Schmitt trigger inverter <b>624</b> according to an embodiment. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, the fourth signal has a square waveform having a high value in the section of the first level of the first signal.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The fourth signal is input to the second transistor <b>626</b>, and the second transistor <b>626</b> is electrically conducted in the section of the first level of the first signal, that is, in the section in which the fourth signal has a high value, so as to output a signal which is obtained by inverting the fourth signal and detect the output signal as the horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam. The second transistor <b>626</b> includes an NPN transistor. A collector of the second transistor <b>626</b> is connected to the driving voltage Vcc, a base of the second transistor <b>626</b> is connected to the first Schmitt trigger inverter <b>624</b>, and an emitter of the second transistor <b>626</b> is grounded. When the fourth signal is in a high state, the collector and the emitter conduct electrically so that a voltage of the emitter is output. In addition, when the fourth signal is in a low state, the driving voltage Vcc is output, and the horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam has a waveform that is obtained by inverting the fourth signal.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a waveform diagram of a horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam in a device for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal of an image forming apparatus, according to an embodiment. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, the horizontal synchronization signal has a waveform which is inverted from the fourth signal of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The operations of the second beam horizontal synchronization signal detector <b>630</b> are as follows. The third transistor <b>632</b> is electrically conducted in a section having the first and second levels of the first signal so as to output a fifth signal which is obtained by inverting the first signal. The third transistor <b>632</b> also includes an NPN transistor like the first transistor <b>622</b>. In the third transistor <b>632</b>, a collector is connected to the driving voltage Vcc, a base of the third transistor <b>632</b> is connected to a current mirror, and an emitter is grounded. In the third transistor <b>632</b>, when a base-emitter voltage is 0.7 V or greater, the collector and the emitter of the third transistor <b>632</b> are conducted electrically. The first signal has a high value at the first level and the second level, which are different from each other. The third transistor <b>632</b> sets a resistance of the resistor R<b>5</b> so that the third transistor <b>632</b> may be conducted electrically in the section of the first level and the second level or greater. Alternatively, a transistor having a base voltage which is conducted electrically at the first level and the second level of the first signal may be used as the third transistor <b>632</b>. As described above, since the third transistor <b>632</b> is conducted electrically in the section having the first level and the second level of the first signal, the third transistor <b>632</b> outputs the fifth signal which is obtained by inverting the first signal at an output terminal of the third transistor <b>632</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a waveform diagram of the fifth signal output from the third transistor <b>632</b>, according to the an embodiment. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, the fifth signal is obtained by inverting the first signal, and has low values in the section of the first level and the section of the second level of the first signal.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The fifth signal is input to the second Schmitt trigger inverter <b>634</b>, and the second Schmitt trigger inverter <b>634</b> outputs a sixth signal which is a square wave signal obtained by inverting the fifth signal. According to the characteristics of a Schmitt trigger inverter, the fifth signal is inverted, and the sixth signal is output from the second Schmitt trigger inverter <b>634</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a waveform diagram of the sixth signal output from the second Schmitt trigger inverter <b>634</b> according to an embodiment. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, the sixth signal has a square waveform having the high value in the section of the first level of the first signal and the section of the second level of the first signal.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The sixth signal is input to the fourth transistor <b>636</b>, and the fourth transistor <b>636</b> is electrically conducted in the section of the first level of the first signal and the section of the second level of the first signal, that is, in the section in which the sixth signal has the high value, and outputs a signal obtained by inverting the sixth signal. The fourth transistor <b>636</b> includes an NPN transistor. In the fourth transistor <b>636</b>, a collector of the fourth transistor <b>636</b> is connected to the driving voltage Vcc, a base of the fourth transistor <b>636</b> is connected to the second Schmitt trigger inverter <b>634</b>, and an emitter of the fourth transistor <b>636</b> is grounded. In the fourth transistor <b>636</b>, when the sixth signal is in the high state, the collector and the emitter of the fourth transistor <b>636</b> conducts electrically and a voltage of the emitter which is grounded is output. In addition, when the sixth signal is in the low state, the driving voltage Vcc is output, and thus, a seventh signal which is obtained by inverting the sixth signal is output by the fourth transistor <b>636</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is a waveform diagram of the seventh signal output from the fourth transistor <b>636</b> in a device for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal an the image forming apparatus, according to the embodiment. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref>, the seventh signal has a waveform that is obtained by inverting the sixth signal.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam is input to a regulator <b>638</b> from the second transistor <b>626</b>, the seventh signal is input to the regulator <b>638</b> from the fourth transistor <b>636</b>, and then, the regulator <b>638</b> performs an operation between the horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam and the seventh signal. In addition, the regulator <b>638</b> outputs the performed signal as the horizontal synchronization signal of the second beam. It is noted that the operation can be performed by an Exclusive NOR gate.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is a waveform diagram of the horizontal synchronization signal of the second beam in a device for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal of an image forming apparatus, according to an embodiment. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref>, the horizontal synchronization signal of the second beam has a waveform that is obtained by performing an operation between the horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam and the seventh signal.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">As described above, according to the device for detecting the horizontal synchronization signal of the image forming apparatus of the embodiment, the light intensities of the first beam and the second beam emitted from two light sources are different from each other, and one photo detector receives the two beams having different light intensities. Therefore, the horizontal synchronization signals may be detected by two photo detectors in the color image forming apparatus including four light sources.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref> is a flowchart illustrating a method of detecting a horizontal synchronization signal of an image forming apparatus, according to an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">Hereinafter, the method of detecting a horizontal synchronization signal of an image forming apparatus according to the embodiment will be described as follows.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">In operation <b>1600</b>, the first beam emitted from the first light source <b>110</b><i>a </i>and the second beam emitted from the second light source <b>110</b><i>b </i>are converted to have different light intensities from each other. Here, the slit <b>216</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the filter <b>218</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, or the beam detecting lenses having different transmittances from each other shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> may be used to change the light intensities of the first and second beam to be different from each other.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">In operation <b>1610</b>, the horizontal synchronization signal detector <b>600</b> receives the first and second beams output from the photo detector <b>220</b>, and outputs the first signal having the first level at the time of receiving the first beam and the second level at the time of receiving the second beam. The waveform of the first signal is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">In operation <b>1620</b>, the first horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam and the second horizontal synchronization signal of the second beam are detected by using the first signal. The first signal output from the photo detector <b>220</b> is input to the two transistors via the current mirror. At this time, the two transistors are conducted at different sections from each other by setting base voltages thereof to be different from each other. That is, one of the two transistors is set to be conducted in the sections of the first level and the second level in the first signal, and the other of the two transistors is set to be conducted in the section of the second level of the first signal. The processes of detecting the horizontal synchronization signals of the first and second beams are described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, and thus, the descriptions thereof are not provided here. In addition, the waveform of the horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> and the waveform of the horizontal synchronization signal of the second beam is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">In addition, other embodiments of the present invention can also be implemented through computer readable code/instructions in/on a medium, e.g., a computer readable medium, to control at least one processing element to implement any above described embodiment. The computer readable code can be recorded/transferred on a medium in a variety of ways, examples of the medium including recording media, such as magnetic storage media (e.g., ROM, floppy disks, hard disks, etc.) and optical recording media (e.g., CD-ROMs, or DVDs), and transmission media such as Internet transmission media.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">While an embodiment or embodiments have been particularly shown and described with reference to exemplary embodiments thereof, it will be understood by those of ordinary skill in the art that various changes in form and details may be made therein without departing from the spirit and scope of the embodiments as defined by the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A device for detecting a horizontal synchronization signal of an image forming apparatus, the device comprising:
<claim-text>a light intensity converter to convert light intensity of a first beam emitted from a first light source and light intensity of a second beam emitted from a second light source, and outputting the first and second beams;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a photo detector to receive the first beam and the second beam output from the light intensity converter, and to output a first signal having a first level at a time of receiving the first beam and a second level at a time of receiving the second beam; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a horizontal synchronization signal detector to detect a horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam and a horizontal synchronization signal of the second beam by using the first signal,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the conversion of the light intensity of the first beam is different from the conversion of the light intensity of the second beam such that the first level and the second level are different from each other.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the light intensity converter comprises:
<claim-text>a first beam detecting lens, which is located on a proceeding path of the first beam, to convert the first beam to be suitable for the photodiode;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a slit located on a proceeding path of the second beam for reducing the light intensity of the second beam; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second beam detecting lens to convert the second beam transmitting through the slit to be suitable for the photodiode.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the slit is a form of rib.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the light intensity converter comprises:
<claim-text>a first beam detecting lens, which is located on a proceeding path of the first beam, to convert the first beam to be suitable for the photodiode;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a filter located on a proceeding path of the second beam for reducing the light intensity of the second beam; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second beam detecting lens to convert the second beam transmitting through the slit to be suitable for the photodiode.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the light intensity converter comprises:
<claim-text>a first beam detecting lens, which is located on a proceeding path of the first beam, to convert the first beam to be suitable for the photodiode; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second beam detecting lens, which is located on a proceeding path of the second beam, for converting the second beam to be suitable for the photodiode,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first beam detecting lens and the second beam detecting lens have different transmittances from each other.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the horizontal synchronization signal detector comprises:
<claim-text>a first beam horizontal synchronization signal detector to detect a square wave signal which is obtained by inverting a second signal having the first level at the time of receiving the first beam as the horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second beam horizontal synchronization signal detector to detect a signal which is obtained by performing an operation between the horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam and a square wave signal which is obtained by inverting the first signal as the horizontal synchronization signal of the second beam.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the horizontal synchronization signal detector further comprises a current mirror to output the first signal to the first beam horizontal synchronization signal detector and the second beam horizontal synchronization signal detector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the first beam horizontal synchronization signal detector comprises:
<claim-text>a first transistor to receive the first signal, and electrically conducted in a section of the first level in the first signal to output a third signal which is obtained by inverting the second signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first Schmitt trigger inverter to receive the third signal, and outputting a square wave signal which is obtained by inverting the third signal as a fourth signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second transistor to receive the fourth signal, and electrically conducted in a section of the fourth signal which corresponds to the section of the first level in the second signal to detect a signal which is obtained by inverting the fourth signal as the horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the second beam horizontal synchronization signal detector comprises:
<claim-text>a third transistor to receive the first signal, and electrically conducted in a section of the first level and a section of the second level in the first signal to output a fifth signal which is obtained by inverting the first signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second Schmitt trigger inverter to receive the fifth signal and outputting a square wave signal which is obtained by inverting the fifth signal as a sixth signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth transistor to receive the sixth signal, and electrically conducted in sections of the sixth signal which correspond to the sections of the first level and the second level in the first signal to output a signal which is obtained by inverting the sixth signal as a seventh signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a regulator to output a signal which is obtained by performing an operation between the horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam and the seventh signal as a horizontal synchronization signal of the second beam.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the regulator is an Exclusive NOR gate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the photo detector is a photodiode.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. A method of detecting a horizontal synchronization signal of an image forming apparatus, the method comprising:
<claim-text>converting light intensity of a first beam emitted from a first light source and light intensity of a second beam emitted from a second light source and outputting the first and second beams;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the outputted first beam and the outputted second beam by a photo detector, and outputting a first signal having a first level at a time of receiving the first beam and a second level at a time of receiving the second beam; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting a horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam and a horizontal synchronization signal of the second beam by using the first signal,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the converting of the light intensity of the first beam is different from the converting of the light intensity of the second beam such that the first level and the second level are different from each other.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the outputting of the first beam and the second beam comprises converting the light intensities of the first beam and the second beam to be different from each other by using a slit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the outputting of the first beam and the second beam comprises converting the light intensities of the first beam and the second beam to be different from each other by using a filter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the outputting of the first beam and the second beam comprises converting the light intensities of the first beam and the second beam to be different from each other by using beam detecting lenses having different transmittances.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the detecting of the horizontal synchronization signals comprises:
<claim-text>detecting a square wave signal which is obtained by inverting a second signal having a first level at a time of receiving the first beam by the photo detector as a horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting a signal obtained by operating between the horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam and the square wave signal which is obtained by inverting the first signal as a horizontal synchronization signal of the second beam.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the detecting of the horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam comprises:
<claim-text>receiving the first signal, and electrically conducted in a section of the first level in the first signal to output a third signal which is obtained by inverting a second signal by a first transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the third signal, and outputting a square wave signal which is obtained by inverting the third signal as a fourth signal by a first Schmitt trigger inverter; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the fourth signal, and electrically conducted in a section of the fourth signal which corresponds to the section of the first level in the second signal to detect a signal which is obtained by inverting the fourth signal as the horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam by a second transistor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the detecting of the horizontal synchronization signal of the second beam comprises:
<claim-text>receiving the first signal, and electrically conducted in a section of the first level and a section of the second level in the first signal to output a fifth signal which is obtained by inverting the first signal by a third transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the fifth signal and outputting a square wave signal which is obtained by inverting the fifth signal as a sixth signal by a second Schmitt trigger inverter;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the sixth signal, and electrically conducted in sections of the sixth signal which correspond to the sections of the first level and the second level in the first signal to output a signal which is obtained by inverting the sixth signal as a seventh signal by a fourth transistor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>outputting a signal which is obtained by operating an operation between the horizontal synchronization signal of the first beam and the seventh signal as a horizontal synchronization signal of the second beam by a regulator.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the regulator is an Exclusive NOR gate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the photo detector is a photodiode.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. A computer readable recording medium having embodied thereon a computer program for executing the method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
