<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622734-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622734</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13176803</doc-number>
<date>20110706</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>29</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>45</main-group>
<subgroup>12</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>29</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>45</main-group>
<subgroup>14</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>29</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>45</main-group>
<subgroup>27</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>425588</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">System and method for forming a shoe sole</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3915608</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hujik</name>
<date>19751000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>425119</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0225305</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Morgan et al.</name>
<date>20061000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 36 59 R</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1106094</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20010600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1612035</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20060100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>FR</country>
<doc-number>2107813</doc-number>
<kind>A2</kind>
<date>19720500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>GB</country>
<doc-number>2039716</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19800800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>9956576</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19991100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>2010012401</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20100200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>7</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>425588</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>14</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>14</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120139156</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120607</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Zhang</last-name>
<first-name>Jian</first-name>
<address>
<city>Zhongshan</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Zhang</last-name>
<first-name>Jian</first-name>
<address>
<city>Zhongshan</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Ziolkowski Patent Solutions Group, SC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Chaussures Regence Inc.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Quebec</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Ochylski</last-name>
<first-name>Ryan</first-name>
<department>1743</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A system and method for forming a shoe sole (<b>10</b>) is disclosed. Specifically, there is provided a sole mould for fabricating high-quality shoe soles with great efficiency and a method of using such a mould, wherein the soles feature good air permeability and perfect match with the feet by automatically adapting themselves to the shape of the feet. The sole mould includes a first mould (<b>26</b>) for injection-moulding the underside of a leather layer, and a second mould (<b>28</b>) for injection-moulding the upper surface of the leather layer to form the sole. Further, the first mould is configured in the same shape as the fore sole of the foot and the second mould is configured in the shape of a complete sole.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="168.91mm" wi="146.39mm" file="US08622734-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="231.39mm" wi="147.32mm" file="US08622734-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="177.72mm" wi="152.15mm" file="US08622734-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="202.52mm" wi="164.93mm" file="US08622734-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="212.34mm" wi="173.74mm" file="US08622734-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="121.41mm" wi="160.78mm" file="US08622734-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="173.74mm" wi="167.30mm" file="US08622734-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="170.52mm" wi="155.28mm" file="US08622734-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="220.98mm" wi="116.08mm" file="US08622734-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="176.11mm" wi="186.52mm" file="US08622734-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="179.32mm" wi="166.54mm" file="US08622734-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="168.91mm" wi="152.91mm" file="US08622734-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="245.79mm" wi="172.13mm" file="US08622734-20140107-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="88.90mm" wi="179.32mm" file="US08622734-20140107-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00014" num="00014">
<img id="EMI-D00014" he="139.45mm" wi="118.62mm" file="US08622734-20140107-D00014.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims benefit of Chinese application Serial No. 201010218488.7, filed on Jul. 6, 2010. All documents above are incorporated herein in their entirety by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a technology for making shoes, and particularly relates to a mould for making shoe soles and its usage.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Ordinary shoe soles are generally formed up by one or two types of materials, which have poor air permeability and tend to fatigue the feet after long-term wear. Besides, they fit badly with the feet and may easily cause the fore part of the foot to deform if worn for a long time.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The present invention discloses a technology which overcomes the above-mentioned shortcomings by providing a sole which can fit snugly with the foot, has good air permeability and elegant appearance. It can automatically adapt to the shape of the foot, and is therefore suitable for long-term wear.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">According to a preferred embodiment of the present invention, there is provided a system and method for forming a shoe sole comprising a fore sole and a rear sole. The system comprises a first mould for injection-moulding an underside of a midsole, such as a leather layer, to form an injection-moulded outsole wherein the first mould is configured in the shape of the fore sole. The system also comprises a second mould for injection-moulding an upper surface of the midsole to form an injection-moulded sole wherein the second mould is configured in the shape of a complete sole. The midsole is processed by the first mould and the second mould to fabricate the shoe sole having the injection-moulded insole and the injection-moulded outsole.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Preferably, the sole mould is used to fabricate high-quality soles with great efficiency, wherein the sole features good air permeability and is suitable for long-term wear because it can fit snugly with the foot by adapting itself automatically to the shape of the foot.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Further, the first mould may include a first female mould and a first male mould fitting into each other, both of which are in the shape of the fore part of the foot. The first female mould further includes a first downward concave which corresponds to a raised area (to be injection-moulded) on the underside of the leather layer; and the first male mould has a cylindrical bore and a first injection hole in the first injection area which corresponds to the first downward concave of the first female mould. Therefore, a raised injection area can be made on the underside of the leather layer by injection moulding after the first female mould and the first male mould is assembled.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The second mould may further include a second female mould and a second male mould, both configured in the same shape as a complete foot sole and can fit into each other. Further, the aforementioned first female mould and the first male mould, both resembling the fore part of the sole, also match the fore part of the sole-shaped second female mould and the second male mould. The said second female mould further includes a second downward concave in the same shape as and at the corresponding position of the first downward concave of the first female mould. The said second male mould further features a second injection area in the same shape as and at the corresponding position of the second downward concave. Still further, a second injection hole (which passes through the leather layer) is designed on the said second injection area. The second male mould further features an upward-concaved third injection area in the rear part of the sole, as well as a second injection hole (which passes through the leather layer) in the said third injection area. The leather layer, having been processed by the first female mould and the first male mould, is further processed by the second female mould and the second male mould, generating an injection-moulded shoe sole with an embedded leather layer. Meanwhile, a raised injection area is formed on the upper side of the said leather layer.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">A middle plate may be inserted between the second female mould and the second male mould when the two are assembled to process the leather layer through injection moulding, so as to produce a cambered or arcuate shoe sole.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Preferably, the first injection hole passes through the first male mould through an injection channel; the second injection hole passes through the second male mould through an injection channel.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to the present invention, there is also provided a method of forming a shoe sole comprising a fore sole and a rear sole. Preferably, the method comprises a step A of assembling a fore sole-shaped first mould onto an injection machine and placing a midsole in said first mould for injection moulding to form a first raised injection area on an underside of said midsole to form an injected-moulded outsole. The method also comprises a step of taking said midsole out of said first mould and placing it into a shoe sole-shaped second mould for injection moulding to form the shoe sole comprising a second raised injection area on an upper surface of said midsole to form an injected-moulded insole.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Step A may include assembling the fore sole-shaped first mould onto the injection machine. After that, placing the leather layer into the first mould for injection moulding to form a raised injection area on the underside of the leather layer.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Step B may include taking the leather layer out of the first mould and put it into the sole-shaped second mould for injection moulding to produce a shoe sole with imbedded leather layer. Meanwhile, an injection area which protrudes outwardly is formed on the top surface of the leather layer of the said shoe sole.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Step A may include:</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Step A1: Assemble the fore sole-shaped first female mould onto an injection machine. Place the leather layer on top of the first female mould with the underside facing downwards, aligning the pre-designed cylindrical bore and the leather injection hole on the leather layer with the first downward concave of the first female mould;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Step A2: Assemble and fix the fore sole-shaped first male mould and the first female mould, making sure that the cylindrical bore and the first injection hole located on the first male mould are aligned with the cylindrical bore and the leather injection hole on the leather layer respectively;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Step A3: Infuse the soft plastic into the first male mould through the first injection hole of the first male mould by using an injection machine. The soft plastic, after going through the first injection hole on the first male mould and the leather injection hole on the leather layer, is channelled into the first downward concave of the first female mould and shaped up, resulting in an outward-protruding injection area on the underside of the leather layer. Further, the soft plastic inside the first downward concave moves through the cylindrical bore of the leather layer to form a pyramidal protuberance, which is integrated with the leather layer. After that, split the first male mould and the first female mould to take out the leather layer bearing an injection area in the underside.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Step B may include:</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Step B1: Place the sole-shaped second female mould of the second mould on a platform, making sure that the underside of the leather layer shall face downward on top of the second female mould, and that the injection area on the underside of the leather layer shall match with the second downward concave of the second female mould;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Step B2: Assemble and fix the sole-shaped second male mould and the second female mould of the second mould, making sure that the second injection area of the second male mould is aligned with the second downward concave, and that the pyramidal protuberance on the leather layer shall be suspended inside the second injection area;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Step B3: Infuse a second formula soft plastic into the second male mould through the second injection hole of the second male mould by using an injection machine. The second soft plastic is moulded into a shoe sole with imbedded leather layer inside the second injection area and the third injection area. During this process, a raised injection area is generated on the upper surface of the leather layer.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Step B1 may include:</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Place the sole-shaped second female mould of the second mould on a platform, and position the middle plate on top of the second female mould. Then place the leather layer on the said middle plate with its underside facing down. Make sure that the injection area on the underside of the leather layer matches with second downward concave of the second female mould. Then infuse second formula plastic into an upwardly-concaved third injection area for forming a rear part of the shoe sole The final purpose is to produce arcuation on the leather layer.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The soft plastic used may be thermoplastic polyurethane (TPU). Preferably, the first formula plastic is softer than said second formula plastic.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Preferably, the cylindrical bores and the injection holes have a diameter of about 2 mm-10 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The sole mould described in this Invention is simple in structure and easy to operate. It is capable of manufacturing quality foot soles of good air permeability with high efficiency. Moreover, these shoe soles can perfectly match the feet by automatically adapting themselves to the shape of the feet, and are therefore suitable for wear for a long time. Moreover, the product yield is relatively high.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a side sectional view of a shoe sole formed by the sole mould and method, according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a top view of the shoe sole of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a sectional view of a first female mould and a first male mould in an assembled position, according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a sectional view of a second female mould and a second male mould in an assembled position, according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a top view of two leather layers used by a sole mould for making shoe soles, according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a top view of a left and right first female moulds, according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a bottom view of a left and right first male moulds, according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a sectional view of the leather layer of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> after being injection moulded using a first female mould and a first male mould, according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a top view of a left and right second female moulds, according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a bottom view of a left and right second male moulds, according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a flow process of one example of a method for using the sole mould, according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a flow process of another example of a method for using the sole mould, according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a sectional view of an illustrative shoe sole after being injection moulded using a second female mould and a second male mould, according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is a bottom view of a second male mould, according with another illustrative embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The preferred embodiments of this Invention will now be described by referring to the attached drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, there illustrated a shoe sole <b>10</b> fabricated according to the system and method of the present invention. The shoe sole has good air permeability and is suitable for long-time wear, as mentioned in the Background. This shoe sole <b>10</b> fits snugly with the foot (not shown) by automatically adapting itself to the shape of the foot. The main body or midsole <b>12</b> of the fore sole <b>14</b> is illustratively a leather layer which is primarily made of leather materials. By way of injection-moulding soft plastics, one or more first raised sole lines <b>16</b> and one or more second raised sole lines <b>18</b> are formed respectively on an underside <b>20</b> of the midsole <b>12</b> to thus form an outsole <b>17</b> and an upper surface <b>22</b> of the midsole <b>12</b> of the said leather layer <b>12</b> to thus form an insole <b>19</b>. A rear part <b>24</b> of the sole <b>10</b> is also obtained by injection-moulding the same plastics and is integrated with the leather layer <b>12</b> to constitute a complete shoe sole <b>10</b>. The raised sole lines <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> are shaped like ribs that define channels in between these ribs, which ensure good air circulation.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, in addition to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, there is illustrated a sole mould according to an illustrative embodiment of the present invention. The sole mould includes two parts: a first mould <b>26</b> which resembles a fore sole <b>14</b> and a second mould <b>28</b> which has the shape of a complete foot sole. The first mould <b>26</b> and the second mould <b>28</b> are used successively to produce the shoe sole <b>10</b>. Firstly, the first mould <b>26</b> is used to treat the leather layer <b>12</b>, in particular the fore part <b>14</b> of the shoe sole <b>10</b>, by injection moulding, which forms the one or more first raised sole lines <b>16</b> on the underside <b>20</b> of the leather layer <b>12</b>. Secondly, the second mould <b>28</b> is used to treat the leather layer <b>12</b> bearing the first raised sole lines <b>16</b>, resulting in one or more second raised sole lines <b>18</b> on the upper surface <b>22</b> of the leather layer <b>12</b>. Meanwhile, the rear part <b>24</b> of the shoe sole <b>10</b> is obtained by injection-moulding soft plastics in the second mould <b>28</b> such that the rear part <b>24</b> is integrated with the leather layer <b>12</b>. A finished sole <b>10</b> comprising one or more second raised sole lines <b>18</b> of the fore sole <b>14</b> on the upper surface <b>22</b> of the midsole <b>12</b> to form the insole <b>17</b> and the one or more first raised sole lines <b>16</b> of the fore sole <b>14</b> on the underside <b>20</b> of the shoe sole <b>10</b> to form the outsole <b>19</b> is produced by the moulds, <b>26</b> and <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, in addition to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the first mould <b>26</b> further includes a first female mould <b>32</b> and a first male mould <b>34</b>, both of which are available as a pair to produce a pair of shoe soles <b>10</b>. The first female mould <b>32</b> and the first male mould <b>34</b> are configured in the same shape as the fore sole <b>14</b> of the foot and fit into each other when assembled as illustrated. The first female mould <b>32</b> further contains one or more first downward concave cavities as in <b>36</b> which when injected moulded, or infused with plastic, form a first raised area <b>38</b> on the underside <b>20</b> of the leather layer <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, in addition to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the first male mould <b>34</b> includes one or more cylindrical bores <b>40</b> and one or more first injection holes <b>42</b> in a first injection area <b>44</b> each one of which are in fluid communication with one of the one or more first downward concave cavities <b>36</b> via each of one or more second injection hole <b>45</b> and each of one or more second cylindrical bore <b>47</b> respectively provided for in the layer <b>12</b>. The one or more second cylindrical bores <b>47</b> and the one or more second injection hole <b>45</b> provide fluid communication for the plastic between the one or more first downward concave cavities <b>36</b> and the one or more first cylindrical bores <b>40</b> and the one or more first injection holes <b>42</b> through the layer <b>12</b> when respectively aligned therewith. Illustratively, through the one or more first injection hole <b>42</b>, each of which are in fluid communication with an injection channel <b>46</b>, soft plastic is supplied from the injection channels <b>46</b> to be infused into the one or more first downward concave cavities <b>36</b> via the one or more second injection holes <b>45</b>. Once plastic is infused into the one or more first downward concave cavities as in <b>36</b>, plastic is allowed to pass through the layer <b>12</b> via the one or more second cylindrical bores as in <b>47</b> and into the one or more of first cylindrical bore <b>40</b> provided for in the first male mould <b>34</b> such that one or more plastic protuberances as in <b>49</b> are embedded within the midsole <b>12</b> and extend from the upper surface. The first female mould <b>32</b> and the first male mould <b>34</b> are then assembled to mould the plastic, leaving the one or more first raised sole lines <b>16</b> on the under side <b>20</b> of the leather layer <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, the second mould <b>28</b> further includes a second female mould <b>48</b> and a second male mould <b>50</b>, both of which are available in pair to produce a pair of shoe soles <b>10</b>. The said second female mould <b>48</b> and second male mould <b>50</b> are configured in the same shape as a complete foot sole <b>10</b> and can fit into each other. Furthermore, the aforementioned first female mould <b>32</b> and the first male mould <b>34</b> also match the fore part <b>14</b> of the sole-shaped second female mould <b>48</b> and the second male mould <b>50</b>. The second female mould <b>48</b> further includes one or more second downward concave cavities as in <b>52</b> in the same shape as and at the corresponding position of the one or more first downward concave cavities as in <b>36</b>. The second male mould <b>50</b> further features a second injection area <b>54</b> comprising one or more second upward concave cavities as in <b>55</b> in the same shape as and at the corresponding position of the one or more second downward concave cavities as in <b>52</b>. Still further, one or more second injection holes <b>56</b> are provided in the second injection area <b>54</b> for each of the one or more second upward concave cavities as in <b>55</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, the second male mould <b>50</b> further features an upward-concaved third injection area <b>58</b> to form the rear part <b>24</b> of the sole <b>10</b> when it is injected moulded, as well as a second injection hole <b>56</b> for injecting plastic into the third injection area <b>58</b>. The leather layer <b>12</b>, having been processed using the first female mould <b>32</b> and the first male mould <b>34</b>, is further processed using the second female mould <b>48</b> and the second male mould <b>50</b>, generating an injection-moulded shoe sole <b>10</b> with an embedded leather layer <b>12</b> by infusing soft plastic into the second injection area <b>54</b> and the third injection area <b>58</b> through the second injection hole <b>56</b> and the injection channels <b>46</b>. As a result, the one or more second raised sole lines <b>18</b> are formed on the upper surface <b>22</b> of the leather layer <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">It should be noted that the soft plastic being used for injection purposes for the sole mould described herein is illustratively thermoplastic polyurethane (TPU). Illustratively, the plastic used to form the one or more first raised sole lines <b>16</b> may be harder than the plastic used to form the one or more second raised sole lines <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Now referring back to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the sole mould provided in the present Invention further includes a middle plate <b>60</b>, which is inserted between the second female mould <b>48</b> and the second male mould <b>50</b> when the two are assembled for injection moulding the leather layer <b>12</b>. The ultimate purpose is to produce a curved shoe sole, for instance the curved rear part of high-heeled leather shoes for women.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The sole mould described in this Invention is simple in structure and easy to operate. It is capable of manufacturing quality foot soles of good air permeability with high efficiency. Moreover, these shoe soles <b>10</b> can perfectly match the feet by automatically adapting themselves to the shape of the feet, and are therefore suitable for wear over a long period of time. Moreover, the product yield is relatively high.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, there is provided an illustrative example of the method of using the sole mould which comprises the following steps.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Step S<b>102</b>: Assemble the fore sole-shaped first mould <b>26</b> onto an injection machine (not shown). After that, place the leather layer <b>12</b> into the first mould <b>26</b> for injection moulding to form the first raised area <b>38</b> on the underside <b>20</b> of the leather layer <b>12</b> comprising one or more first raised sole lines <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Step S<b>104</b>: Take the leather layer <b>12</b> out of the first mould <b>26</b> and put it into the foot sole-shaped second mould <b>28</b> for injection moulding to produce a shoe sole <b>10</b> with an embedded leather layer <b>12</b> comprising the second raised injection area <b>54</b> on the upper surface <b>22</b> of the leather layer <b>12</b> comprising the one or more second raised sole lines <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, there is provided another illustrative example of the method of using the sole mould is composed of the following steps:</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Step S<b>202</b>: Assemble the fore sole-shaped first female mould <b>32</b> of the first mould <b>26</b> onto the injection machine. Place the leather layer <b>12</b> on top of the first female mould <b>32</b> with the underside <b>20</b> facing downwards and align the each pre-designed one or more second cylindrical bores <b>47</b> and one or more second injection holes <b>45</b> on the leather layer <b>12</b> with the each of the one or more first downward concave cavities <b>36</b> of the first female mould <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Step S<b>204</b>: Assemble and fix the fore sole-shaped first male mould <b>34</b> and the first female mould <b>32</b>, making sure that each of the first cylindrical bores <b>40</b> and each of the first injection holes <b>42</b> located on the first male mould <b>34</b> are aligned with each of second cylindrical bores <b>47</b> and each of the second injection holes <b>45</b> on the leather layer <b>12</b> respectively. Then, place a puller plate <b>64</b> on top of the first male mould <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Step S<b>206</b>: By way of the one or more first injection hole <b>42</b> and the one or more injection channels <b>46</b>, infuse the soft plastic into the first male mould <b>34</b> by using an injection machine (not shown). The soft plastic, after going through the one or more first injection holes <b>42</b> on the first male mould <b>34</b> is channelled into the one or more first downward concave cavities <b>36</b> of the first female mould <b>32</b> and shaped up, resulting in the first raised area <b>38</b> on the underside <b>20</b> of the leather layer <b>12</b> to form the first one or more first raised sole lines <b>16</b>. Further, the soft plastic inside the one or more first downward concave cavities <b>36</b> moves through the one or more second cylindrical bores <b>47</b> of the leather layer <b>12</b> and into the one or more first cylindrical bores <b>40</b> to form one or more pyramidal protuberances <b>49</b>, which are integrated with the leather layer <b>12</b>. After that, the first male mould <b>34</b> and the first female mould <b>32</b> are split to remove the leather layer <b>12</b> bearing a first injection area <b>44</b> on the underside <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Referring back to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, it is preferable to pre-punch the midsole <b>12</b> to form holes matching with the cylindrical bores <b>47</b> and the injection holes <b>45</b> prior to placing the midsole <b>12</b> on top of the first female mould <b>32</b>. Alternatively, the cylindrical bores <b>47</b> and the injection holes <b>45</b> may be punched in the midsole <b>12</b> once the midsole is in the first female mould <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Step S<b>208</b>: Assemble the foot sole-shaped second female mould <b>48</b> of the second mould <b>28</b> onto the injection machine and place the middle plate <b>60</b> on the said second female mould <b>48</b>. Lay up the leather layer <b>12</b> onto the middle plate <b>60</b>, making sure that the underside <b>20</b> of the leather layer <b>10</b> faces downward and that the first injection area <b>44</b> on the underside <b>20</b> of the leather layer <b>10</b> shall match with the second downward concave cavities <b>52</b> of the second female mould <b>48</b>. The final purpose is to produce arcuation on the leather layer <b>12</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Step S<b>210</b>: Assemble and fix the foot sole-shaped second male mould <b>50</b> and the second female mould <b>48</b> of the second mould <b>28</b>, making sure that the second injection area <b>54</b> of the second mould is aligned with the one or more second downward concave cavities <b>52</b>. When aligned, the one or more pyramidal protuberances <b>49</b> on the leather layer <b>12</b> are suspended, or project, inside the second injection area <b>54</b>. Then, place the puller plate <b>64</b> on top of the second male mould <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Step S<b>212</b>: By way of the one or more second injection holes <b>56</b> on the second male mould <b>50</b> and the one or more injection channels <b>46</b>, infuse the soft plastic into the second male mould <b>50</b> by using an injection machine. The soft plastic is moulded into a shoe sole <b>10</b> to combine with embedded leather layer <b>12</b> and the one or more pyramidal protuberances <b>49</b> inside the second injection area <b>54</b> and the third injection area <b>58</b>. During this process, the one or more pyramidal protuberances <b>49</b> as mentioned in Steps S<b>206</b> and S<b>210</b> are embedded into the plastic injected into the one or more second upward concave cavities <b>52</b>, therefore leaving a second raised injection area <b>54</b> of second raised sole lines <b>18</b> on the upper surface <b>22</b> of the leather layer <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, there is further provided a connection grove <b>66</b> in the sole <b>10</b> to affix a heel <b>68</b> thereto. There may also be provided a piece of decorative leather (not shown) on the arch <b>70</b> of the sole <b>10</b>. Furthermore, a polyurethane (PU) filler <b>72</b> may be provided in the upper surface <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref>, in addition to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, in accordance with another illustrative embodiment of the present invention, the one or more first downward concave cavities <b>36</b> are provided in communication to form the first raised area <b>38</b> in the shape of one or more first curved connection lines (not shown), and the one or more second upward concave cavities <b>55</b> are in communication to form the second raised area <b>54</b> in the shape of one or more second curved connection lines (also not shown), such that the one or more first curved connection lines are symmetrically opposite to the one or more second curved connection lines.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Easy to operate, the sole mould described in this Invention is capable of manufacturing quality shoe soles of good air permeability with high efficiency. These shoe soles can perfectly match the feet by automatically adapting themselves to the shape of the feet, and are therefore suitable for wear over a long time. Moreover, the product yield is relatively high.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The shoe sole is particularly comfortable to wear when using a leather midsole. Indeed, because of the relatively high elasticity of leather, the shoe sole may wrap up feet of different shapes. Because parts of the leather midsole are not covered with plastic, it provides with good air permeability and ventilation. The shoe sole is comfortable, cooler and drier compared to other existing shoe soles and solves problems of long-time wearing, poor air permeability, dampness and heating.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The foregoing descriptions of specific examples are intended to illustrate but not to limit this Invention. Any changes and modifications may be made by those skilled in the art and therefore shall fall within the scope of this Invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A system for forming a shoe sole (<b>10</b>) comprising a fore sole (<b>14</b>) and a rear sole (<b>24</b>), the system comprising:
<claim-text>a first mold (<b>26</b>) for injection-molding an underside (<b>20</b>) of a midsole (<b>12</b>) to form an injection-molded outsole (<b>17</b>), wherein said first mold (<b>26</b>) is configured in the shape of the fore sole (<b>14</b>); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second mold (<b>28</b>) for injection-molding an upper surface (<b>22</b>) of said midsole (<b>12</b>) to form an injection-molded insole (<b>19</b>), wherein said second mold (<b>28</b>) is configured in the shape of the shoe sole (<b>10</b>);</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said midsole (<b>12</b>) is processed by said first mold (<b>26</b>) and said second mold (<b>28</b>) to fabricate said shoe sole (<b>10</b>) comprising said injection-molded insole (<b>19</b>) and said injection-molded outsole (<b>17</b>);</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said first mold (<b>26</b>) comprises a first female mold (<b>32</b>) and a first male mold (<b>34</b>) each configured in the shape of the fore sole (<b>14</b>);
<claim-text>wherein said first female mold (<b>32</b>) comprises one or more first downward concave cavities (<b>36</b>) for injection-molding a first area (<b>38</b>) on said underside (<b>20</b>); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said first male mold (<b>34</b>) comprises a first injection area (<b>44</b>) comprising one or more of first cylindrical bores (<b>40</b>) and one or more first injection holes (<b>42</b>), wherein each of said one or more first cylindrical bores (<b>40</b>) and said one or more first injection holes (<b>42</b>) are respectively aligned with each of one or more second cylindrical bores (<b>47</b>) and one or more second injection holes (<b>45</b>) for each of said one or more first downward concave cavities (<b>36</b>);</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said first raised area (<b>38</b>) is injection molded to form said injection-molded outsole (<b>17</b>) when said first female mold (<b>32</b>) and said first male mold (<b>34</b>) are assembled; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said second mold (<b>28</b>) comprises:
<claim-text>a second female mold (<b>48</b>) and a second male mold (<b>50</b>), wherein said second female mold (<b>48</b>) and said second male mold (<b>50</b>) match the shape of said first female mold (<b>32</b>) and said first male mold (<b>34</b>);</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said second female mold (<b>48</b>) comprises one or more second downward concave cavities (<b>52</b>) configured in the same shape as and at a corresponding position of said one or more first downward concave cavities (<b>36</b>);</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said second male mold (<b>50</b>) comprises:
<claim-text>a second injection area (<b>54</b>) comprising one or more second upward concave cavities (<b>55</b>) configured in the same shape as and at said corresponding position as said one or more first downward concave cavities (<b>36</b>) for injection-molding a second raised area (<b>54</b>) on said upper surface (<b>22</b>);</claim-text>
<claim-text>one or more second injection holes (<b>56</b>), each of said one or more second injection holes (<b>56</b>) corresponding to each of said one or more second upward concave cavities (<b>55</b>);</claim-text>
<claim-text>an upwardly-concaved third injection area (<b>56</b>) for forming the rear sole (<b>24</b>) when injected molded; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>one or more third injection holes (<b>59</b>) for injection molding said upwardly-concaved third injection area (<b>58</b>),</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein after said midsole (<b>12</b>) is processed by said first female mold (<b>32</b>) and said first male mold (<b>34</b>), said midsole (<b>12</b>) is further processed by said second female mold (<b>48</b>) and said second male mold (<b>50</b>) to make said midsole (<b>12</b>) an embedded midsole comprising said injection-molded insole (<b>19</b>); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said injection-molded insole (<b>19</b>) and said injection-molded outsole (<b>17</b>) are in communication with each other via said one or more second cylindrical bores (<b>47</b>) to form said embedded midsole (<b>12</b>).</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a middle plate (<b>60</b>) positioned between said second female mold (<b>48</b>) and said second male mold (<b>50</b>) to produce a curved shoe sole (<b>10</b>) when said midsole (<b>12</b>) is injection molded.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of said one or more first injection holes (<b>42</b>) are in communication with a first injection channel (<b>46</b>) passing through said first male mold (<b>34</b>) and said one or more third injection holes (<b>59</b>) are in communication with one or more third injection channels (<b>61</b>) passing through said second male mold (<b>50</b>).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said one or more first downward concave cavities (<b>36</b>) are in communication to form said first raised area (<b>38</b>) in the shape of one or more first curved connection lines, and said one or more second upward concave cavities (<b>55</b>) are in communication to form said second raised area (<b>54</b>) in the shape of one or more second curved connection lines, such that said one or more first curved connection lines are symmetrically opposite to said one or more second curved connection lines.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said cylindrical bores (<b>40</b>, <b>47</b>) and said injection holes (<b>42</b>, <b>45</b>) comprise a diameter of 2 mm-10 mm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said midsole (<b>12</b>) is a leather layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein said midsole (<b>12</b>) comprises a polyurethane filler (<b>72</b>). </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
