<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625317-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625317</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13509749</doc-number>
<date>20110713</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-159483</doc-number>
<date>20100714</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>66</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20070101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>M</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>36</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>363 97</main-classification>
<further-classification>363 49</further-classification>
<further-classification>323271</further-classification>
<further-classification>323284</further-classification>
<further-classification>323908</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Isolated switch-mode power supply device</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6856519</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Lin et al.</name>
<date>20050200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>363 16</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7667445</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Hiasa</name>
<date>20100200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>323284</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7746672</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Nishikawa</name>
<date>20100600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>363 2116</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8018208</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Kahn et al.</name>
<date>20110900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>323224</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0042239</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kitano</name>
<date>20040300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00006">
<othercit>International Search Report for PCT Application No. PCT/JP2011/004019 dated Oct. 18, 2011, pp. 1-4.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>18</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>323238</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>323271</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>323282-285</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>323901</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>323908</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>363 18- 2118</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>363 49</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>363 97</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>12</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>12</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120281440</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121108</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hayashi</last-name>
<first-name>Masaaki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Saitama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Narisawa</last-name>
<first-name>Hiroshi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Saitama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hayashi</last-name>
<first-name>Masaaki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Saitama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Narisawa</last-name>
<first-name>Hiroshi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Saitama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Shindengen Electric Manufacturing Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Han</last-name>
<first-name>Jessica</first-name>
<department>2838</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/JP2011/004019</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20110713</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20120514</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2012/008157</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20120119</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present invention provides an isolated switch-mode power supply device capable of sufficiently reducing power consumption in a standby mode. An isolated switch-mode power supply device includes: a capacitor that supplies control power for controlling switching of a switching element; a first control unit that includes a constant current supplying unit that controls switching of the switching element; a switching element that connects or disconnects the first control unit and the capacitor; a capacitance element unit having a capacitor to which a constant current is supplied from the constant current supplying unit, a capacitor charge voltage of the capacitance element unit changing according to an outputted voltage in the standby mode; and a second control unit that controls power supply to the first control unit by closing or opening the switching element during a switching pause period in the standby mode according to the capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="171.87mm" wi="259.16mm" file="US08625317-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="252.22mm" wi="158.16mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625317-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="204.13mm" wi="178.14mm" file="US08625317-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="263.14mm" wi="182.80mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625317-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="67.90mm" wi="77.55mm" file="US08625317-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="199.31mm" wi="188.38mm" file="US08625317-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="114.05mm" wi="158.92mm" file="US08625317-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="102.53mm" wi="158.92mm" file="US08625317-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="117.94mm" wi="127.51mm" file="US08625317-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="91.02mm" wi="186.52mm" file="US08625317-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="84.58mm" wi="105.07mm" file="US08625317-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="108.97mm" wi="104.48mm" file="US08625317-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="250.53mm" wi="178.14mm" file="US08625317-20140107-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is International Application No. PCT/JP2011/004019, filed Jul. 13, 2011, which claims priority from Japanese Patent Application No. 2010-159483, filed Jul. 14, 2010.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to isolated switch-mode power supply devices, and in particular, to an isolated switch-mode power supply device capable of reducing power consumption in a standby mode.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND ART</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Conventionally, an isolated switch-mode power supply device converts an inputted voltage into a desired voltage by switching a switching element and outputs the desired voltage. Such an isolated switch-mode power supply device employs a technique of burst-controlling the switching element in a standby mode in order to reduce power consumption in the standby mode. According to this technique, in the standby mode, an oscillation period in which switching of the switching element is performed at a predetermined cycle and a switching pause period in which the switching of the switching element is temporarily stopped are repeated. As this reduces the number of switching per unit time, it is possible to reduce a switching loss per unit time, and as a result, power consumption in the standby mode can be reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Further, various techniques have been proposed as a technique of further reducing power consumption in the standby mode (see Japanese Unexamined Patent Application Publication Nos. 2002-58238, 2002-58238 and 2000-270544, and Japanese Unexamined Utility Model Application Publication No. H03-113986, for example).</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Japanese Unexamined Patent Application Publication No. 2002-58238 discloses a technique of, in the standby mode, stopping the switching of the switching element when the outputted voltage is higher than an upper limit voltage, and starting the switching of the switching element when the outputted voltage is lower than a lower limit voltage. According to this technique, it is possible to increase a bursting cycle by increasing output ripples, and thus, power consumption in the standby mode can be further reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">However, according to the technique disclosed in Japanese Unexamined Patent Application Publication No. 2002-58238, during the switching pause period in the standby mode, control power is kept supplied to circuits and elements for controlling driving of the switching element. Accordingly, a power loss occurs in these circuits and elements even during the switching pause period in the standby mode.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">By contrast, Japanese Unexamined Patent Application Publication No. 2004-88959 discloses a technique of, in an isolated switch-mode power supply device, providing a switch circuit along a line for supplying control power to the circuits and the elements, and of stopping supplying control power to the circuits and the elements during the switching pause period in the standby mode. According to this technique, it is possible to prevent a power loss from occurring in the circuits and the elements during the switching pause period in the standby mode.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Further, Japanese Unexamined Utility Model Application Publication No. H03-113986 discloses a technique of providing switching means for turning on and off the supply of the control power to the circuits and the elements, and of causing the switching means to turn off the supply of the control power when the outputted voltage exceeds a predetermined value that has been preliminarily determined. According to this technique, it is possible to prevent a power loss from occurring in the circuits and the elements when the outputted voltage exceeds the predetermined value. Here, as the outputted voltage increases during the oscillation period in the standby mode, switching to the switching pause period when the outputted voltage exceeds the predetermined value that has been preliminarily determined can prevent a power loss from occurring in the circuits and the elements during the switching pause period in the standby mode.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Moreover, Japanese Unexamined Patent Application Publication No. 2000-270544 discloses a technique of, in an isolated switch-mode power supply device, providing control power to the circuits and the elements by a startup circuit in which a starting resistance and the switch circuit are connected in series. When the outputted voltage is higher than the upper limit voltage in the standby mode, the isolated switch-mode power supply device stops the switching of the switching element and turns the switch circuit to the OFF state to stop the startup circuit. By contrast, when the outputted voltage is lower than the lower limit voltage in the standby mode, the isolated switch-mode power supply device turns the switch circuit to the ON state and operates the startup circuit, thereby starting the switching of the switching element. According to such an isolated switch-mode power supply device, it is possible to prevent a power loss from occurring due to the starting resistance during the switching pause period in the standby mode.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to the technique disclosed in Patent Literature 2, as described above, during the switching pause period in the standby mode, the supply of the control power to the circuits and the elements for controlling driving of the switching element is stopped. Accordingly, the outputted voltage decreases over time as the switching of the switching element is stopped during the switching pause period in the standby mode. Therefore, a primary-side circuit is provided with a differential amplifier for determining a signal level of an outputted voltage detection signal transmitted from a secondary-side circuit to detect whether or not the outputted voltage has decreased down to a preliminarily determined lower limit voltage. According to the isolated switch-mode power supply device disclosed in Patent Literature 2, as shown in FIG. 3 of Patent Literature 2, for example, when the outputted voltage decreases down to the lower limit voltage, the primary-side circuit again starts supplying control power to the circuits and the elements to resume the switching of the switching.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Specifically, according to the technique disclosed in Patent Literature 2, it is required for the primary-side circuit to keep operating the differential amplifier in order to stably control the lower limit voltage of the outputted voltage during the switching pause period in the standby mode, and thus the primary-side circuit has to keep supplying current to the differential amplifier. As the power consumption of the differential amplifier is large, it is not possible to sufficiently reduce power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device during the switching pause period in the standby mode. Accordingly, it has been extremely difficult to sufficiently reduce power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device while stably controlling the lower limit voltage of the outputted voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Likewise, according to the technique disclosed in Patent Literature 4, the startup circuit is operated during the oscillation period in the standby mode while the startup circuit stops during the switching pause period in the standby mode, and therefore it has not been possible to sufficiently reduce power consumption in the standby mode.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">It should be noted that a method of stopping the supply of control power to all of the elements and the circuits relating to the switching of the switching element including the differential amplifier described above during the switching pause period in the standby mode is conceivable.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In this case, when attempting to stop the supply of control power by switching according to the techniques disclosed in Patent Literature 2 and such, electric power is necessary to maintain the switch to the OFF state during a period in which the supply of control power is stopped. Accordingly, with the techniques disclosed in Patent Literatures 2-4, it is not possible to stop the supply of control power to all of the elements and the circuits described above.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">By contrast, a method of making a control voltage supplied to the circuits and the elements for controlling driving of the switching element to 0 V is conceivable. According to this method, the switch for stopping the supply of control power is not required, and it is possible to stop the supply of control power to all of the elements and the circuits described above without supplying control power to maintain the switch to the OFF state. However, when shifting from the switching pause period to the oscillation period in the standby mode, it is necessary to operate the startup circuit in order to quickly increase the control voltage from 0 V to a predetermined level. Accordingly, electric power is consumed by the startup circuit every time when shifting from the switching pause period to the oscillation period in the standby mode.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Consequently, even when the supply of control power to all of the elements and the circuits relating to the switching of the switching element is stopped during the switching pause period in the standby mode, an object of sufficiently reducing power consumption may not be achieved.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In view of the above problems, an object of the present invention is to provide an isolated switch-mode power supply device capable of sufficiently reducing power consumption in a standby mode.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In order to address the above problems, the present invention proposes the following solutions. (1) The present invention proposes an isolated switch-mode power supply device (for example, corresponding to an isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) capable of controlling switching of a switching element (for example, corresponding to a switching element Q<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) in one of a continuous operation (for example, corresponding to a continuous operation that will be later described) and a burst mode operation (for example, corresponding to a standby mode that will be later described), and of controlling conversion of an inputted voltage into a required outputted voltage. The isolated switch-mode power supply device is provided with: a control power supply source (for example, corresponding to a capacitor C<b>5</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) configured to supply control power required for controlling the switching; a first control unit (for example, corresponding to a first control unit <b>10</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) having a current supplying unit (for example, corresponding to a constant current supplying unit <b>14</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) for supplying a preliminarily determined current during at least a part (for example, corresponding to a time period from time t<b>6</b> to time t<b>8</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>) of a time period in which power supply is received from the control power supply source (for example, corresponding to a time period from time t<b>4</b> to time t<b>8</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>), and configured to control the switching of the switching element in one of the continuous operation and the burst mode operation; a control power supply switch (for example, corresponding to a switching element Q<b>11</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) configured to either connect or disconnect the first control unit and the control power supply source; a capacitance element unit (for example, corresponding to a capacitance element unit <b>121</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) having a first capacitor (for example, corresponding to a capacitor C<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) to which the current is supplied from the current supplying unit, a capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor changing according to an outputted voltage in the burst mode operation; and a second control unit (for example, corresponding to a second control unit <b>12</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) configured to control the power supply to the first control unit by opening the control power supply switch during at least a part (for example, corresponding to a time period from time t<b>3</b> to time t<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>) of a switching pause period (for example, corresponding to a time period from time t<b>2</b> to time t<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>) in the burst mode operation according to the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor (for example, corresponding to a voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">According to this invention, the isolated switch-mode power supply device is provided with the control power supply source, the first control unit, the control power supply switch, and the second control unit. Further, the control power supply source supplies the control power required for controlling the switching, the first control unit controls the switching of the switching element, and the control power supply switch connects or disconnects the first control unit and the control power supply source. Moreover, the second control unit controls the power supply to the first control unit by opening the control power supply switch during at least a part of the switching pause period in the burst mode operation. Accordingly, during the time period in which the control power supply switch is opened in the switching pause period in the burst mode operation, it is possible to stop the power supply from the control power supply source to the first control unit. Therefore, power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device in the burst mode operation can be reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Further, according to this invention, the first control unit is provided with the current supplying unit for supplying the preliminarily determined current to the first capacitor during at least a part of the time period in which the power supply is received from the control power supply source. In addition, the second control unit controls the power supply to the first control unit as described above according to the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor. Accordingly, the supply of the current from the current supplying unit to the first capacitor can be performed within the time period in which the first control unit receives the power supply from the control power supply source. Therefore, it is possible to incorporate the current supplying unit in the first control unit, and the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device in the burst mode operation can be further reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Moreover, according to this invention, as described above, the isolated switch-mode power supply device is provided with the control power supply source, the first control unit, the control power supply switch, the capacitance element unit, and the second control unit. Accordingly, during the time period in which the control power supply switch is opened in the switching pause period in the burst mode operation, it is possible to stop the power supply from the control power supply source to the first control unit. Therefore, the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device can be reduced without making the control voltage 0 V during the switching pause period in the burst mode operation. Thus, as it is not necessary to operate the startup circuit when shifting from the switching pause period to a switching time period in the burst mode operation, the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device can be sufficiently reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">(2) In the above isolated switch-mode power supply device, the current supplying unit may change a value of the current to be supplied to the first capacitor according to the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In such case, it is possible to supply the first capacitor with a large current only when it is necessary to increase the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor. With this, it is possible to reduce a loss when it is not necessary to increase the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor, and to quickly charge the first capacitor when it is necessary to increase the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor. Therefore, a proportion of a time period during which the power supply to the first control unit is performed to an intermittent oscillation cycle can be made small, and the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device in the burst mode operation can be further reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">(3) In the above isolated switch-mode power supply device, when the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor is no lower than a second set voltage (for example, corresponding to a voltage Vth<b>3</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>) and the outputted voltage is no lower than an upper limit voltage, the first control unit may stop the switching of the switching element.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In such case, the oscillation can be stopped immediately when the outputted voltage reaches the upper limit voltage, and therefore it is possible to decrease a proportion of the oscillation period to the intermittent oscillation cycle, that is, an oscillation duty of the intermittent oscillation, as well as a number of oscillation times of the switching element per unit time. Therefore, the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device in the burst mode operation can be further reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">(4) In the above isolated switch-mode power supply device, when the outputted voltage becomes no lower than the upper limit voltage during the time period in which the power supply from the control power supply source to the first control unit is performed, the current supplying unit may start supplying the current to the first capacitor, and when the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor is no lower than a second set voltage (for example, corresponding to the voltage Vth<b>3</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>) and the outputted voltage is no lower than the upper limit voltage, the first control unit may stop the switching of the switching element.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In such case, even during the time period in which the power supply from the control power supply source to the first control unit is performed, the first capacitor may not be charged unless the outputted voltage increases up to the upper limit voltage. Therefore, it is possible to charge the first capacitor after the outputted voltage is acquired to some extent, and to prevent an erroneous operation from occurring.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">(5) The present invention proposes an isolated switch-mode power supply device (for example, corresponding to an isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) capable of controlling switching of a switching element (for example, corresponding to a switching element Q<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) in one of a continuous operation (for example, corresponding to a normal mode that will be later described) and a burst mode operation (for example, corresponding to a standby mode that will be later described), and of controlling conversion of an inputted voltage into a required outputted voltage. The isolated switch-mode power supply device is provided with: a control power supply source (for example, corresponding to a capacitor C<b>5</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) configured to supply control power required for controlling the switching; a first control unit (for example, corresponding to a first control unit <b>10</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) having a constant current supplying unit (for example, corresponding to a constant current supplying unit <b>14</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) for supplying a preliminarily determined constant current during at least a part (for example, corresponding to a time period from time t<b>6</b> to time t<b>8</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>) of a time period in which power supply is received from the control power supply source (for example, corresponding to a time period from time t<b>4</b> to time t<b>8</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>), and configured to control the switching of the switching element in one of the continuous operation and the burst mode operation; a control power supply switch (for example, corresponding to a switching element Q<b>11</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) configured to either connect or disconnect the first control unit and the control power supply source; a capacitance element unit (for example, corresponding to a capacitance element unit <b>121</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) having a first capacitor (for example, corresponding to a capacitor C<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) to which the constant current is supplied from the constant current supplying unit, a capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor changing according to an outputted voltage in the burst mode operation; and a second control unit (for example, corresponding to a second control unit <b>12</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) configured to control the power supply to the first control unit by opening the control power supply switch during at least a part (for example, corresponding to a time period from time t<b>3</b> to time t<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>) of a switching pause period (for example, corresponding to a time period from time t<b>2</b> to time t<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>) in the burst mode operation according to the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor (for example, corresponding to a voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">According to this invention, the isolated switch-mode power supply device is provided with the control power supply source, the first control unit, the control power supply switch, and the second control unit. Further, the control power supply source supplies the control power required for controlling the switching, the first control unit controls the switching of the switching element, and the control power supply switch connects or disconnects the first control unit and the control power supply source. Moreover, the second control unit controls the power supply to the first control unit by opening the control power supply switch during at least a part of the switching pause period in the burst mode operation. Accordingly, during the time period in which the control power supply switch is opened in the switching pause period in the burst mode operation, it is possible to stop the power supply from the control power supply source to the first control unit. Therefore, power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device in the burst mode operation can be reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Further, according to this invention, the first control unit is provided with the constant current supplying unit for supplying the preliminarily determined constant current to the first capacitor during at least a part of the time period in which the power supply is received from the control power supply source. In addition, the second control unit controls the power supply to the first control unit as described above according to the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor. Accordingly, the supply of the constant current from the constant current supplying unit to the first capacitor can be performed within the time period in which the first control unit receives the power supply from the control power supply source. Therefore, it is possible to incorporate the constant current supplying unit in the first control unit, and the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device in the burst mode operation can be further reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Moreover, according to this invention, as described above, the isolated switch-mode power supply device is provided with the control power supply source, the first control unit, the control power supply switch, the capacitance element unit, and the second control unit. Accordingly, during the time period in which the control power supply switch is opened in the switching pause period in the burst mode operation, it is possible to stop the power supply from the control power supply source to the first control unit. Therefore, the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device can be reduced without making the control voltage 0 V during the switching pause period in the burst mode operation. Thus, as it is not necessary to operate the startup circuit when shifting from the switching pause period to a switching time period in the burst mode operation, the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device can be sufficiently reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">(6) In the above isolated switch-mode power supply device the constant current supplying unit may change a value of the constant current to be supplied to the first capacitor according to the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In such case, it is possible to supply the first capacitor with a large current only when it is necessary to increase the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor. With this, it is possible to reduce a loss when it is not necessary to increase the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor, and to quickly charge the first capacitor when it is necessary to increase the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor. Therefore, a proportion of a time period during which the power supply to the first control unit is performed to the intermittent oscillation cycle can be made small, and the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device in the burst mode operation can be further reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">(7) In the above isolated switch-mode power supply device, when the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor is no lower than a second set voltage (for example, corresponding to a voltage Vth<b>3</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>) and the outputted voltage is no lower than an upper limit voltage, the first control unit may stop the switching of the switching element.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In such case, the oscillation can be stopped immediately when the outputted voltage reaches the upper limit voltage, and therefore it is possible to decrease a proportion of the oscillation period to the intermittent oscillation cycle, that is, an oscillation duty of the intermittent oscillation, as well as a number of oscillation times of the switching element per unit time. Therefore, the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device in the burst mode operation can be further reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">(8) In the above isolated switch-mode power supply device, when the outputted voltage becomes no lower than the upper limit voltage during the time period in which the power supply from the control power supply source to the first control unit is performed, the constant current supplying unit may start supplying the constant current to the first capacitor, and when the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor is no lower than a second set voltage (for example, corresponding to the voltage Vth<b>3</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>) and the outputted voltage is no lower than the upper limit voltage, the first control unit may stop the switching of the switching element.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In such case, even during the time period in which the power supply from the control power supply source to the first control unit is performed, the first capacitor is not charged unless the outputted voltage increases up to the upper limit voltage. Therefore, it is possible to charge the first capacitor after the outputted voltage is acquired to some extent, and to prevent an erroneous operation from occurring.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">(9) In the above isolated switch-mode power supply device the second control unit may include the capacitance element unit, the capacitance element unit may include the first capacitor, a first switching element (for example, corresponding to a switching element Q<b>22</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>), and a second switching element (for example, corresponding to a switching element Q<b>24</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>), one end of the first capacitor may be connected to a control terminal of the first switching element, the other end of the first capacitor may be connected to an output terminal of the first switching element, and to an output terminal of the second switching element, an input terminal of the first switching element may be connected to a control terminal of the second switching element, and to the control power supply source via a driving unit for driving the second switching element, (for example, corresponding to a driving unit <b>123</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>), and an input terminal of the second switching element may be connected to a control terminal of the control power supply switch.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In such case, the first switching element closes or opens according to the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor, the second switching element opens or closes according to the state of the first switching element, and a level of the control voltage inputted to the control terminal of the control power supply switch changes according to the state of the second switching element, thereby connecting or disconnecting the first control unit and the control power supply source. Accordingly, it is possible to open the control power supply switch according to the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor during the switching pause period in the burst mode operation.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">(10) In the above isolated switch-mode power supply device provided with first discharge means (for example, corresponding to an outputted-voltage lower-limit detecting unit <b>60</b> and a phototransistor PT<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) configured to decrease the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor when the outputted voltage may become no higher than a lower limit voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Here, as the power supply to the first control unit is stopped at least in a part of the switching pause period in the burst mode operation, the switching of the switching element is stopped, and as a result, the outputted voltage decreases.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In such case, when the outputted voltage becomes no higher than the lower limit voltage, the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor decreases. Therefore, by closing the control power supply switch by the second control unit that opens the control power supply switch according to the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor, it is possible to supply power to the first control unit and resume the switching of the switching element. Thus, by setting the lower limit voltage of the outputted voltage, it is possible to supply power to the first control unit before the outputted voltage becomes too low, and to prevent the outputted voltage from decreasing excessively.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">(11) In the above isolated switch-mode power supply device, when a state switching signal for shifting the state to the continuous operation is inputted (for example, corresponding to a mode switching signal that will be later described), the first discharge means may decrease the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In such case, the first discharge means can be commonly used between a case in which the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor is decreased when the outputted voltage becomes no higher than the lower limit voltage in the burst mode operation, and a case in which the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor is decreased when the state switching signal is inputted. Therefore, the reduction of the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device in the burst mode operation can be realized at low cost.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">(12) In the above isolated switch-mode power supply device provided with a second capacitor (for example, corresponding to a capacitor C<b>21</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) configured to be charged during the switching pause period in the burst mode operation, and based on a capacitor charge voltage of the second capacitor, a case in which supply of the inputted voltage is started may be discriminated from a case in which the power supply from the control power supply source to the first control unit is resumed in the burst mode operation.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Here, for the first control unit, the case in which the supply of the inputted voltage to the isolated switch-mode power supply device is started, that is, power activation of the isolated switch-mode power supply device is started and the case in which the power supply from the control power supply source to the first control unit is resumed in the burst mode operation are the same condition in that the power supply is started in a state where the power supply is not performed. Accordingly, it is difficult to discriminate the two cases from each other.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Thus, the second capacitor that is charged during the switching pause period in the burst mode operation may be provided for the isolated switch-mode power supply device. Then, based on the capacitor charge voltage of the second capacitor, the case in which the supply of the inputted voltage is started is discriminated from the case in which the power supply from the control power supply source to the first control unit is resumed in the burst mode operation. Accordingly, it is possible to identify whether the power activation to the isolated switch-mode power supply device is started or the power supply from the control power supply source to the first control unit is resumed in the burst mode operation. Therefore, when the power supply from the control power supply source to the first control unit is resumed in the burst mode operation, it is possible to perform an operation suitable for the case in which the power supply to the first control unit is resumed that is different from an operation in the case in which the power activation to the isolated switch-mode power supply device is started.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">(13) In the above isolated switch-mode power supply device may be provided with second discharge means (for example, corresponding to a resistance R<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) connected in parallel to the first capacitor.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Here, there is a case in which the outputted voltage decreases in an occurrence of abnormity that a peak load over an output capacity of the isolated switch-mode power supply device is caused in the burst mode operation. Accordingly, in a case in which an element or circuit for identifying whether or not the outputted voltage has become no higher than the lower limit voltage operates based on the outputted voltage, the outputted voltage may possibly fall below a voltage with which the element or circuit is operable before the first capacitor is discharged in an occurrence of abnormity as described above, and as a result, the first capacitor cannot be discharged.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Thus, in such case, even in an occurrence of abnormity as described above, it is possible to discharge the first capacitor by the second discharge means. Therefore, it is possible to resume the operation of the startup circuit and the power supply to the first control unit from the control power supply source within time determined by capacities of the second discharge means and the first capacitor and a residual voltage, and the isolated switch-mode power supply device can be restored to a normal state from an abnormal state.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">(14) In the above isolated switch-mode power supply device when the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor becomes no lower than a first set voltage (for example, corresponding to a voltage Vth<b>2</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>), the second control unit may open the control power supply switch.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In such case, it is possible to increase the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor up to the first set voltage during the time period in which the control power supply switch is closed, that is, during the time period in which the power supply from the control power supply source to the first control unit is performed. Therefore, by setting the first set voltage, it is possible to extend the state in which the electric charge remains in the first capacitor, and in turn to extend the intermittent oscillation cycle, and as a result, the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device in the burst mode operation can be further reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">(15) In the above isolated switch-mode power supply device a startup circuit (for example, corresponding to a startup circuit unit <b>13</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) configured to activate the first control unit and the second control unit by the inputted voltage may be provided, and when the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor becomes no lower than the second set voltage, an operation of the startup circuit may be prohibited.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In such case, as the startup circuit does not operates even if the power supply to the first control unit is stopped, the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device can be further reduced without providing any special circuit for monitoring the voltage of the control power supply source and stopping the operation of the startup circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">(16) IN the above isolated switch-mode power supply device when the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor becomes lower than the second set voltage, the prohibition of the operation of the startup circuit may be lifted and the control power supply switch may be closed by the second control unit.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In such case, when the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor becomes lower than the second set voltage, the control power is supplied to the first control unit, and the switching of the switching element is started. Therefore, by setting the lower limit voltage of the outputted voltage and the second set voltage, it is possible to start the switching of the switching element by the first control unit before the outputted voltage becomes too low, and to prevent the outputted voltage from decreasing excessively.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Further, when the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor becomes lower than the second set voltage, the prohibition of the operation of the startup circuit is lifted. Here, while the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor decreases when the outputted voltage becomes no higher than the lower limit voltage as described above, the startup circuit becomes operable when the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor becomes lower than the second set voltage. Therefore, by setting the lower limit voltage of the outputted voltage and the second set voltage, the startup circuit can be operated even if the voltage of the control power supply source at which the startup circuit is required to be operated during the switching pause period in the burst mode operation, and it is possible to prevent the outputted voltage from decreasing excessively.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">(17) In the above isolated switch-mode power supply device during a specific time period (for example, corresponding to a time period from time t<b>4</b> to time t<b>5</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>) in the burst mode operation, the operation of the startup circuit may be stopped, the specific time period being a time period until a first time period (for example, corresponding to a time period determined by a time constant of a time constant circuit <b>122</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) elapses after closing the control power supply switch in an open state.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Here, as described above, it is possible to stop the power supply to the first control unit from the control power supply source at least in a part of the switching pause period in the burst mode operation. Further, as the power consumption of the second control unit is extremely small and the control voltage outputted from the control power supply source does not decrease to a large extent, the startup circuit is not normally operated. However, during a transitional time period before the voltage is stably supplied after the power supply to the first control unit is started, the startup circuit may temporarily perform an erroneous operation.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Thus, the operation of the startup circuit may be stopped during the specific time period in the burst mode operation. Here, the specific time period refers to a time period until the first time period elapses after the control power supply switch in the open state is closed. Accordingly, by setting the first time period, it is possible to prevent the startup circuit from unnecessarily operating, and the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device in the burst mode operation can be further reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">(18) The above isolated switch-mode power supply device may comprise a specific control unit (for example, corresponding to a low-voltage-error preventing circuit unit <b>15</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) configured to, when the control voltage supplied to the first control unit is no lower than a first threshold voltage, stop the operation of the startup circuit and start controlling the switching of the switching element, and to, when the control voltage is no higher than a second threshold voltage that is lower than the first threshold voltage, start the operation of the startup circuit and stop controlling the switching of the switching element, wherein during the specific time period in the burst mode operation, a threshold voltage used by the specific control unit is fix to the second threshold voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Here, during the switching pause period in the burst mode operation, the control voltage outputted from the control power supply source often decreases due to factors such as discharge albeit gradually. Accordingly, when attempting to continue the switching pause period for over several tens of seconds, for example, the control voltage may decrease down to or below the first threshold voltage, and the startup circuit may be operated.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Thus, the isolated switch-mode power supply device is provided with the specific control unit that controls, according to the control voltage supplied to the first control unit and the threshold voltage, the operation of the startup circuit and the switching of the switching element. Specifically, the specific control unit, when the control voltage is no lower than the first threshold voltage, stops the operation of the startup circuit and starts controlling the switching of the switching element, and, when the control voltage is no higher than the second threshold voltage that is lower than the first threshold voltage, starts the operation of the startup circuit and stops controlling the switching of the switching element. Further, during the specific time period in the burst mode operation, the threshold voltage used by the specific control unit is fixed to the second threshold voltage. Accordingly, during the specific time period until the first time period elapses after closing the control power supply switch in an open state in the burst mode operation, the second threshold voltage that is lower than the first threshold voltage is used instead of the first threshold voltage. Therefore, as it is possible to immediately start the switching-control of the switching element without operating the startup circuit even if the intermittent oscillation cycle is increased, the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device can be further reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Accordingly, it is possible to sufficiently reduce power consumption of an isolated switch-mode power supply device in a burst mode operation.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a circuit diagram of an isolated switch-mode power supply device according to one embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a timing chart of the isolated switch-mode power supply device;</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a circuit diagram of a control circuit provided for the isolated switch-mode power supply device;</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a circuit diagram of a control power supply switching unit provided for the control circuit;</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a circuit diagram of a second control unit provided for the control circuit;</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a circuit diagram of a startup circuit unit provided for the control circuit;</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a circuit diagram of a constant current supplying unit provided for the control circuit;</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a circuit diagram of a low-voltage-error preventing circuit unit provided for the control circuit;</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a circuit diagram of an oscillation control unit provided for the control circuit;</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a circuit diagram of an oscillation stop control unit provided for the control circuit;</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a circuit diagram of a capacitor charge voltage detecting unit provided for the control circuit; and</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a timing chart of the control circuit in a standby mode.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">An embodiment of the present invention will now be described with reference to the drawings. It should be noted that components in the following embodiment are replaceable with existing components as needed, and can be variously realized including combinations with existing components. Thus, the following description of this embodiment does not limit the scope of the present invention as defined in the claims.</p>
<p id="h-0007" num="0000">Configuration of Isolated Switch-Mode Power Supply Device</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a circuit diagram of an isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> according to one embodiment of the present invention. The isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> is provided with a transformer T, a control circuit <b>2</b>, an outputted-voltage upper-limit detecting unit <b>50</b>, an outputted-voltage lower-limit detecting unit <b>60</b>, a mode switching signal generating unit <b>70</b>, a switching element Q<b>1</b> configured by an N-channel MOSFET, capacitors C<b>1</b>-C<b>5</b>, diodes D<b>1</b> and D<b>2</b>, phototransistors PT<b>1</b> and PT<b>2</b>, and a resistance R<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">First, a configuration on the primary side of the transformer T is described. The control circuit <b>2</b> is provided with six terminals P<b>1</b>-P<b>6</b>. The terminal P<b>3</b> is connected to a terminal GND<b>1</b> that is connected to a reference potential source, and to an input terminal IN via the capacitor C<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">The terminal P<b>1</b> is connected to the terminal P<b>3</b> via the capacitor C<b>4</b>. The capacitor C<b>4</b> is connected to the resistance R<b>1</b> and the phototransistor PT<b>1</b> that are connected in parallel. The phototransistor PT<b>1</b> is configured to be turned on and off according to signals outputted from the outputted-voltage lower-limit detecting unit <b>60</b> and the mode switching signal generating unit <b>70</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">The terminal P<b>2</b> is connected to the terminal P<b>3</b> via the phototransistor PT<b>2</b>. The phototransistor PT<b>2</b> is configured to be turned on and off according to a signal outputted from the outputted-voltage upper-limit detecting unit <b>50</b>. The terminal P<b>4</b> is connected to the terminal P<b>3</b> via the capacitor C<b>5</b>, and to a cathode of the diode D<b>1</b>. An anode of the diode D<b>1</b> is connected to the other end of a control coil T<b>2</b> of the transformer T. One end of the control coil T<b>2</b> is connected to the terminal P<b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">The terminal P<b>5</b> is connected to the input terminal IN. The input terminal IN is also connected to one end of a primary coil T<b>1</b> of the transformer T. The other end of the primary coil T<b>1</b> is connected to the terminal P<b>3</b> via the capacitor C<b>2</b>. The other end of the primary coil T<b>1</b> is also connected to a drain of the switching element Q<b>1</b>. A source of the switching element Q<b>1</b> is connected to the terminal P<b>3</b>, and a gate of the switching element Q<b>1</b> is connected to the terminal P<b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">Next, a configuration on the secondary side of the transformer T is described. One end of a secondary coil T<b>3</b> of the transformer T is connected to a terminal GND<b>2</b> that is connected to a reference potential source. The other end of the secondary coil T<b>3</b> is connected to an anode of the diode D<b>2</b>. A cathode of the diode D<b>2</b> is connected to an output terminal OUT, and to the terminal GND<b>2</b> via the capacitor C<b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">The output terminal OUT is connected to the outputted-voltage upper-limit detecting unit <b>50</b> and the outputted-voltage lower-limit detecting unit <b>60</b> that are connected to the terminal GND<b>2</b>. The outputted-voltage upper-limit detecting unit <b>50</b> is configured to turn the phototransistor PT<b>2</b> to the ON state if an outputted voltage outputted from the output terminal OUT is not lower than an upper limit voltage. The outputted-voltage lower-limit detecting unit <b>60</b> is configured to turn the phototransistor PT<b>1</b> to the ON state if the outputted voltage is not higher than a lower limit voltage. In addition, the mode switching signal generating unit <b>70</b> is configured to transmit a mode switching signal to the phototransistor PT<b>1</b> so as to turn the phototransistor PT<b>1</b> to the ON state, when the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> is operated in a continuous operation. By contrast, the mode switching signal generating unit <b>70</b> is configured to cancel the ON state of the phototransistor PT<b>1</b> based on the mode switching signal so as to allow the outputted-voltage lower-limit detecting unit <b>60</b> to turn on or off the phototransistor PT<b>1</b>, when the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> is operated in a standby mode.</p>
<p id="h-0008" num="0000">Operation of Isolated Switch-Mode Power Supply Device <b>1</b></p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">The isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> thus configured controls to convert an inputted voltage inputted from the input terminal IN into a required outputted voltage by controlling to switch the switching element Q<b>1</b> between the normal mode and the standby mode using the control circuit <b>2</b> according to the outputted voltage and the mode switching signal, and outputs this outputted voltage through the output terminal OUT. It should be noted that according to this embodiment, the control circuit <b>2</b> burst-controls the switching element Q<b>1</b> in the standby mode.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a timing chart of the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b>. A reference symbol V<sub>C5 </sub>represents a capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor C<b>5</b>, V<sub>OUT </sub>represents the outputted voltage outputted through the output terminal OUT, and a reference symbol V<sub>C4 </sub>represents a capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor C<b>4</b>. A reference symbol V<sub>P2 </sub>represents a voltage of the terminal P<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, while the switching element Q<b>1</b> oscillates and the outputted voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>is substantially constant in the normal mode, in the standby mode, the switching element Q<b>1</b> performs intermittent oscillation, and a period in which the outputted voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>gradually decreases and a period in which the outputted voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>rapidly increases are alternately repeated.</p>
<p id="h-0009" num="0000">Configuration of Control Circuit <b>2</b></p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a circuit diagram of the control circuit <b>2</b>. The control circuit <b>2</b> is provided with a first control unit <b>10</b>, a control power supply switching unit <b>11</b>, a second control unit <b>12</b>, and a startup circuit unit <b>13</b>. The first control unit <b>10</b> is provided with a constant current supplying unit <b>14</b>, a low-voltage-error preventing circuit unit <b>15</b>, an oscillation control unit <b>16</b>, an oscillation stop control unit <b>17</b>, a capacitor charge voltage detecting unit <b>18</b>, a soft start circuit unit <b>19</b>, a latch protection circuit unit <b>20</b>, and a control voltage generating unit <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0010" num="0000">Configuration of Control Power Supply Switching Unit <b>11</b></p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a circuit diagram of the control power supply switching unit <b>11</b>. The control power supply switching unit <b>11</b> is provided with a diode D<b>11</b>, and a switching element Q<b>11</b> configured by a P-channel MOSFET. Through the switching element Q<b>11</b>, a contact point A<b>1</b> and a contact point A<b>4</b> are connected. Specifically, a source of the switching element Q<b>11</b> is connected to the contact point A<b>1</b>, and a drain of the switching element Q<b>11</b> is connected to the contact point A<b>4</b>. The source of the switching element Q<b>11</b> is also connected to a contact point A<b>2</b> and a cathode of the diode D<b>11</b>, and the drain of the switching element Q<b>11</b> is also connected to an anode of the diode D<b>11</b>. A gate of the switching element Q<b>11</b> is connected to a contact point A<b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0011" num="0000">Configuration of Second Control Unit <b>12</b></p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a circuit diagram of the second control unit <b>12</b>. The second control unit <b>12</b> is provided with a driving unit <b>123</b>, a capacitor C<b>21</b>, a comparator CMP<b>21</b>, a diode D<b>21</b>, a flip-flop FF<b>21</b> configured by an NAND gate, an inverter INV<b>21</b>, switching elements Q<b>21</b>-Q<b>25</b> each configured by an N-channel MOSFET, and resistances R<b>21</b>-R<b>23</b>. It should be noted that, while the description with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> emphasizes that the comparator CMP<b>21</b>, the flip-flop FF<b>21</b>, and the inverter INV<b>21</b> are connected to a control voltage source VDD and a reference potential source GND for convenience sake, the comparator, the flip-flop, and the inverter are also connected to the control voltage source VDD and the reference potential source GND while not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="h-0012" num="0000">Configuration of Capacitative Element Unit <b>121</b></p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">The switching elements Q<b>22</b> and Q<b>24</b> and the capacitor C<b>4</b> constitute a capacitance element unit <b>121</b>. One end of the capacitor C<b>4</b> is connected to a gate of the switching element Q<b>22</b> via a contact point B<b>0</b>. The other end of the capacitor C<b>4</b> is connected to the reference potential source GND, to which a source of the switching element Q<b>22</b> and a source of the switching element Q<b>24</b> are also connected.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">A drain of the switching element Q<b>22</b> is connected to a gate of the switching element Q<b>24</b> via the switching element Q<b>21</b> and the driving unit <b>123</b>. Specifically, the drain of the switching element Q<b>22</b> is connected to a source of the switching element Q<b>21</b>, and a drain of the switching element Q<b>21</b> is connected to the gate of the switching element Q<b>24</b> via the driving unit <b>123</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">Further, the drain of the switching element Q<b>22</b> is connected to one end of the capacitor C<b>5</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, via the switching element Q<b>21</b>, the driving unit <b>123</b>, a contact point B<b>1</b>, and the terminal P<b>4</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. Specifically, the drain of the switching element Q<b>22</b> is connected to the source of the switching element Q<b>21</b>, and the drain of the switching element Q<b>21</b> is connected to the contact point B<b>1</b> via the driving unit <b>123</b>. The contact point B<b>1</b> is connected to the terminal P<b>4</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, and the terminal P<b>4</b> is connected to the one end of the capacitor C<b>5</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">Referring back to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the contact point B<b>1</b> is also connected to a contact point B<b>2</b>. The contact point B<b>2</b> is connected to the contact point A<b>1</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">A drain of the switching element Q<b>24</b> is connected to the gate of the switching element Q<b>11</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> via the contact point B<b>4</b> and the contact point A<b>3</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, and to a contact point B<b>3</b> via the driving unit <b>123</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0013" num="0000">Configuration of Second Control Unit <b>12</b> Excluding Capacitative Element Unit <b>121</b></p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">A gate of the switching element Q<b>21</b> is connected to the contact point B<b>1</b> via the resistance R<b>21</b>, and to the reference potential source GND via the switching element Q<b>23</b>. Specifically, the gate of the switching element Q<b>21</b> is connected to a drain of the switching element Q<b>23</b>, and a source of the switching element Q<b>23</b> is connected to the reference potential source GND.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">The contact point B<b>4</b> is also connected to the diode D<b>21</b> and a time constant circuit <b>122</b> constituted by the resistance R<b>22</b>, and the capacitor C<b>21</b>. Specifically, the contact point B<b>4</b> is connected to an anode of the diode D<b>21</b> and to one end of the resistance R<b>22</b>. A cathode of the diode D<b>21</b> and the other end of the resistance R<b>22</b> are connected to a gate of the switching element Q<b>25</b> and to the reference potential source GND via the capacitor C<b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">A source of the switching element Q<b>25</b> is connected to the reference potential source GND, and a drain of the switching element Q<b>25</b> is connected to the control voltage source VDD via the resistance R<b>23</b> and to an input end of the inverter INV<b>21</b>. The input end of the inverter INV<b>21</b> is connected to a contact point B<b>7</b>. An output end of the inverter INV<b>21</b> is connected to contact points B<b>5</b> and B<b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">A gate of the switching element Q<b>23</b> is connected to an output terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>21</b>, and a set terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>21</b> is connected to a contact point B<b>9</b>. A reset terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>21</b> is connected to an output terminal of the comparator CMP<b>21</b>. An inverting input terminal of the comparator CMP<b>21</b> is connected to a contact point B<b>8</b>, a non-inverting input terminal of the comparator CMP<b>21</b> is connected to a positive terminal of a direct-current power source Vref, and a negative terminal of the direct-current power source Vref is connected to the reference potential source GND.</p>
<p id="h-0014" num="0000">Configuration of Startup Circuit Unit <b>13</b></p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a circuit diagram of the startup circuit unit <b>13</b>. The startup circuit unit <b>13</b> is provided with switching elements Q<b>31</b>-Q<b>35</b> each configured by an N-channel MOSFET, and resistances R<b>31</b> and R<b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">A source of the switching element Q<b>31</b> is connected to a contact point E<b>6</b>, and a drain of the switching element Q<b>31</b> is connected to a contact point E<b>2</b> via the resistance R<b>31</b>. A gate of the switching element Q<b>31</b> is connected to the contact point E<b>2</b> via the resistance R<b>32</b>, and to drains respectively of the switching elements Q<b>32</b>-Q<b>35</b>. A gate of the switching element Q<b>32</b> is connected to a contact point E<b>1</b>, a gate of the switching element Q<b>33</b> is connected to a contact point E<b>5</b>, a gate of the switching element Q<b>34</b> is connected to a contact point E<b>4</b>, and a gate of the switching element Q<b>35</b> is connected to a contact point E<b>3</b>. Sources respectively of the switching elements Q<b>32</b>-Q<b>35</b> are connected to the reference potential source GND.</p>
<p id="h-0015" num="0000">Configuration of Constant Current Supplying Unit <b>14</b></p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a circuit diagram of the constant current supplying unit <b>14</b>. The constant current supplying unit <b>14</b> is provided with a flip-flop FF<b>41</b> configured by an NAND gate, an inverter INV<b>41</b>, a negative AND NAND<b>41</b>, switching elements Q<b>41</b> and Q<b>42</b> each configured by a P-channel MOSFET, and current sources S<b>41</b> and S<b>42</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">A reset terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>41</b> is connected to a contact point F<b>1</b>, a set terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>41</b> is connected to a contact point F<b>2</b>, and an output terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>41</b> is connected to an input terminal of the inverter INV<b>41</b> and one of two input terminals of the negative AND NAND<b>41</b>. The other of the two input terminals of the negative AND NAND<b>41</b> is connected to a contact point F<b>3</b>, and an output terminal of the negative AND NAND<b>41</b> is connected to a gate of the switching element Q<b>41</b>. A drain of the switching element Q<b>41</b> is connected to a contact point F<b>4</b>, and a source of the switching element Q<b>41</b> is connected to the current source S<b>41</b> connected to the control voltage source VDD. An output terminal of the inverter INV<b>41</b> is connected to a gate of the switching element Q<b>42</b>, a drain of the switching element Q<b>42</b> is connected to a contact point F<b>5</b>, and a source of the switching element Q<b>42</b> is connected to the current source S<b>42</b> connected to the control voltage source VDD.</p>
<p id="h-0016" num="0000">Configuration of Low-Voltage-Error Preventing Circuit Unit <b>15</b></p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a circuit diagram of the low-voltage-error preventing circuit unit <b>15</b>. The low-voltage-error preventing circuit unit <b>15</b> is provided with a comparator CMP<b>51</b>, switching elements Q<b>51</b> and Q<b>52</b> each configured by an N-channel MOSFET, and resistances R<b>51</b>-R<b>53</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">The resistance R<b>51</b> and the resistance R<b>52</b> are connected in series, and the control voltage source VDD and the reference potential source GND are connected to each other via the series-connected resistances R<b>51</b> and R<b>52</b>. To the resistance R<b>52</b>, a part in which the resistance R<b>53</b> and the switching element Q<b>51</b> are connected in series and apart in which the resistance R<b>53</b> and the switching element Q<b>52</b> are connected in series are connected in parallel. Specifically, a connecting point between the resistance R<b>51</b> and the resistance R<b>52</b> is connected to one end of the resistance R<b>53</b>, and the other end of the resistance R<b>53</b> is connected to drains respectively of the switching elements Q<b>51</b> and Q<b>52</b>. Sources respectively of the switching elements Q<b>51</b> and Q<b>52</b> are connected to the reference potential source GND. Agate of the switching element Q<b>51</b> is connected to a contact point G<b>1</b>, and a gate of the switching element Q<b>52</b> is connected to a contact point G<b>4</b>. Further, a connecting point between the resistance R<b>51</b> and the resistance R<b>52</b> is also connected to an inverting input terminal of the comparator CMP<b>51</b>. A non-inverting input terminal of the comparator CMP<b>51</b> is connected to a contact point G<b>2</b>, and an output terminal of the comparator CMP<b>51</b> is connected to a contact point G<b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0017" num="0000">Configuration of Oscillation Control Unit <b>16</b></p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a circuit diagram of the oscillation control unit <b>16</b>. The oscillation control unit <b>16</b> is provided with an outputted-voltage upper-limit control unit <b>161</b>, an on-trigger generating unit <b>162</b>, an on-width control unit <b>163</b>, a flip-flop FF<b>61</b> configured by an NAND gate, an inverter INV<b>61</b>, and a negative AND NAND<b>61</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">The outputted-voltage upper-limit control unit <b>161</b> is connected to contact points H<b>5</b> and H<b>6</b>, and to the on-width control unit <b>163</b>. The on-width control unit <b>163</b> is connected to the contact point H<b>6</b>, and to a second reset terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>61</b>. A set terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>61</b> is connected to the on-trigger generating unit <b>162</b>, and a first reset terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>61</b> is connected to a contact point H<b>4</b>. Four input terminals of the negative AND NAND<b>61</b> are respectively connected to contact points H<b>1</b>-H<b>3</b> and an output terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>61</b>. An output terminal of the negative AND NAND<b>61</b> is connected to an input terminal of the inverter INV<b>61</b>, and the output terminal of the inverter INV<b>61</b> is connected to a contact point H<b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0018" num="0000">Configuration of Oscillation Stop Control Unit <b>17</b></p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a circuit diagram of the oscillation stop control unit <b>17</b>. The oscillation stop control unit <b>17</b> is provided with a flip-flop FF<b>71</b> configured by an NAND gate, an inverter INV<b>71</b>, and a negative AND NAND<b>71</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">A reset terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>71</b> is connected to a contact point J<b>5</b>, an output terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>71</b> is connected to a contact point J<b>2</b>, and an inverting output terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>71</b> is connected to contact points J<b>1</b> and J<b>7</b>. A set terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>71</b> is connected to an output terminal of the negative AND NAND<b>71</b>, one of two input terminals of the negative AND NAND<b>71</b> is connected to a contact point J<b>4</b>, and the other of the two input terminals of the negative AND NAND<b>71</b> is connected to an output terminal of the inverter INV<b>71</b>. An input terminal of the inverter INV<b>71</b> is connected to contact points J<b>3</b> and J<b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0019" num="0000">Configuration of Capacitor Charge Voltage Detecting Unit <b>18</b></p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a circuit diagram of the capacitor charge voltage detecting unit <b>18</b>. The capacitor charge voltage detecting unit <b>18</b> is provided with an inverter INV<b>81</b>, a switching element Q<b>81</b> configured by an N-channel MOSFET, and a resistance R<b>81</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111">A gate of the switching element Q<b>81</b> is connected to a contact point K<b>2</b>, a source of the switching element Q<b>81</b> is connected to the reference potential source GND, and a drain of the switching element Q<b>81</b> is connected to the control voltage source VDD via the resistance R<b>81</b>. The control voltage source VDD is also connected to an input terminal of the inverter INV<b>81</b> via the resistance R<b>81</b>. An output terminal of the inverter INV<b>81</b> is connected to contact points K<b>1</b> and K<b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0020" num="0000">Operation of Control Circuit <b>2</b> in Normal Mode</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">The control circuit <b>2</b> thus configured will be now described, first, in relation to an operation in the normal mode, with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">In the normal mode, the mode switching signal generating unit <b>70</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> turns the phototransistor PT<b>1</b> to the ON state. Then, the capacitor C<b>4</b> is discharged by the resistance R<b>1</b> and the phototransistor PT<b>1</b>, and the capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor C<b>4</b> decreases down substantially to zero. With this, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a voltage at the contact point B<b>0</b> of the second control unit <b>12</b> connected to the capacitor C<b>4</b> via the terminal P<b>1</b> also decreases, and the switching element Q<b>22</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is turned to the OFF state.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">Further, the gate of the switching element Q<b>21</b> is connected to the capacitor C<b>5</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> via the resistance R<b>21</b>, the contact point B<b>1</b>, and the terminal P<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, and the capacitor C<b>5</b> is connected in parallel to the control coil T<b>2</b> via the diode D<b>1</b>. Here, in the normal mode, as the switching element Q<b>1</b> oscillates as described above, a voltage is generated in the control coil T<b>2</b>. Therefore, the capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor C<b>5</b> is substantially equal to the voltage generated in the control coil T<b>2</b>. Thus, a gate voltage is applied to the switching element Q<b>21</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. However, the switching element Q<b>21</b> is turned to the OFF state by the comparator CMP<b>21</b>, the flip-flop FF<b>21</b>, and the switching element Q<b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">Specifically, the inverting input terminal of the comparator CMP<b>21</b> is connected to the capacitor C<b>4</b> via the contact point B<b>8</b> and the terminal P<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. The comparator CMP<b>21</b> compares the capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor C<b>4</b> with a voltage of the positive terminal of the direct-current power source Vref, and outputs an H-level voltage when the capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor C<b>4</b> is lower than Vth<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116">Here, in the normal mode, as the capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor C<b>4</b> decreases down substantially to zero as described above, the capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor C<b>4</b> becomes lower than Vth<b>2</b>, and as a result, the comparator CMP<b>21</b> outputs the H-level voltage. The H-level voltage is applied to the reset terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>21</b>. By contrast, as the capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor C<b>4</b> is also lower than Vth<b>3</b>, the switching element Q<b>81</b>, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, whose gate is connected to the capacitor C<b>4</b> via the terminal P<b>1</b> and the contact point K<b>2</b> of the capacitor charge voltage detecting unit <b>18</b>, is turned to the OFF state, and the inverter INV<b>81</b> outputs an L-level voltage. The L-level voltage is applied to the set terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>21</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> via the contact point K<b>3</b> and the contact point B<b>9</b> of the second control unit <b>12</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0117">Consequently, in the flip-flop FF<b>21</b>, the H-level voltage is applied to its reset terminal, and the L-level voltage is applied to its set terminal. Accordingly, the H-level voltage is outputted from the output terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>21</b>, and the switching element Q<b>23</b> is turned to the ON state. With this, the gate voltage of the switching element Q<b>21</b> drops, and the switching element Q<b>21</b> is turned to the OFF state.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0118">The driving unit <b>123</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> turns the switching element Q<b>24</b> to the ON state when at least one of the switching elements Q<b>21</b> and Q<b>22</b> is in the OFF state. Accordingly, as the switching elements Q<b>21</b> and Q<b>22</b> are both in the OFF state as described above, the switching element Q<b>24</b> is turned to the ON state, and as a result, the contact point B<b>4</b> and the reference potential source GND become conductive.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0119">The contact point B<b>4</b> is connected to the contact point A<b>3</b> of the control power supply switching unit <b>11</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, and the contact point A<b>3</b> is connected to the gate of the switching element Q<b>11</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. Accordingly, when the contact point B<b>4</b> and the reference potential source GND become conductive as described above, the switching element Q<b>11</b> is turned to the ON state, and the contact point A<b>1</b> and the contact point A<b>4</b> become conductive.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0120">The contact point A<b>1</b> is connected to the capacitor C<b>5</b> via the contact point B<b>2</b> of the second control unit <b>12</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the contact point B<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, and the terminal P<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. Accordingly, when the switching element Q<b>11</b> is turned to the ON state, the capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor C<b>5</b> is supplied to the first control unit <b>10</b>. When the capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor C<b>5</b> is supplied to the first control unit <b>10</b>, the control voltage generating unit <b>21</b> supplies a control voltage to various circuits in the control circuit <b>2</b> as the control voltage source VDD. With this, the various circuits in the control circuit <b>2</b> are operated, and a control signal is supplied to the gate of the switching element Q<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> according to a cyclic signal outputted from the on-trigger generating unit <b>162</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> to cause the switching element Q<b>1</b> to oscillate.</p>
<p id="h-0021" num="0000">Operation of Control Circuit <b>2</b> in Standby Mode</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0121">Next, an operation of the control circuit <b>2</b> in the standby mode will be described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> shown above and to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> that will be shown below.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0122"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a timing chart of the control circuit <b>2</b> in the standby mode. The reference symbol V<sub>P2 </sub>represents the voltage of the terminal P<b>2</b>, and the reference symbol V<sub>C4 </sub>represents the capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor C<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. A reference symbol ST<sub>Q1 </sub>represents a state of the switching element Q<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, and the reference symbol V<sub>C5 </sub>represents the capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor C<b>5</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. A reference symbol ST<sub>13 </sub>represents a state of the startup circuit unit <b>13</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. A reference symbol ST<sub>Q11 </sub>represents a state of the switching element Q<b>11</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, and a reference symbol ST<sub>CMP51 </sub>represents a state of the comparator CMP<b>51</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0123">First, at time t<b>1</b>, the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b> is zero. Accordingly, the switching element Q<b>22</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is in the OFF state.</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0124">Further, the capacitor C<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is connected to the gate of the switching element Q<b>81</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> via the terminal P<b>1</b> and the contact point K<b>2</b> of the capacitor charge voltage detecting unit <b>18</b>. Accordingly, when the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b> is zero, the switching element Q<b>81</b> is turned to the OFF state, and an L-level voltage is outputted from the output terminal of the inverter INV<b>81</b>. The L-level voltage is applied to the set terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>21</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> via the contact point K<b>3</b> and the contact point B<b>9</b> of the second control unit <b>12</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. Therefore, an H-level voltage is outputted from the output terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>21</b>, and the switching element Q<b>23</b> is turned to the ON state. Thus, as described above, the gate voltage of the switching element Q<b>21</b> drops, and the switching element Q<b>21</b> is in the OFF state.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0125">Consequently, as the switching elements Q<b>21</b> and Q<b>22</b> are both in the OFF state, as described above, the driving unit <b>123</b> turns the switching element Q<b>24</b> to the ON state, and the switching element Q<b>11</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is in the ON state.</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0126">With this, the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C5 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>5</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is supplied to the first control unit <b>10</b>, and the control voltage is supplied from the control voltage source VDD to the various circuits in the control circuit <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0127">The control voltage supplied to the first control unit <b>10</b> is applied to the non-inverting input terminal of the comparator CMP<b>51</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> via the contact point G<b>2</b> of the low-voltage-error preventing circuit unit <b>15</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. The comparator CMP<b>51</b> has hysteresis characteristics. The comparator CMP<b>51</b> outputs an H-level voltage when the voltage of the non-inverting input terminal is not lower than a first threshold voltage, and outputs an L-level voltage when the voltage of the non-inverting input terminal is not higher than a second threshold voltage that is lower than the first threshold voltage. Here, the control voltage supplied to the first control unit <b>10</b> is higher than the first threshold voltage. Accordingly, when the control voltage supplied to the first control unit <b>10</b> is applied to the non-inverting input terminal, the H-level voltage is outputted from the output terminal of the comparator CMP<b>51</b>, and a voltage of the contact point G<b>3</b> is H-level.</p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0128">The H-level voltage is applied to the reset terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>41</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> via the contact point F<b>1</b> of the constant current supplying unit <b>14</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. By contrast, as the outputted voltage has reached the upper limit voltage at time t<b>1</b>, the outputted-voltage upper-limit control unit <b>161</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> outputs an L-level voltage. The L-level voltage is applied to the set terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>41</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> via the contact point H<b>5</b>, the contact point J<b>6</b> of the oscillation stop control unit <b>17</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the contact point J<b>3</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, and the contact point F<b>2</b> of the constant current supplying unit <b>14</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0129">Consequently, in the flip-flop FF<b>41</b>, the H-level voltage is applied to its reset terminal, and the L-level voltage is applied to its set terminal. Accordingly, the H-level voltage is outputted from the output terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>41</b> and converted into an L-level voltage by the inverter INV<b>41</b>, and the switching element Q<b>42</b> is turned to the ON state. With this, a constant current outputted from the current source S<b>42</b> is supplied to the capacitor C<b>4</b> via the switching element Q<b>42</b>, the contact point F<b>5</b>, and the terminal P<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, thereby charging the capacitor C<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0130">Further, the H-level voltage outputted from the output terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>41</b> is also applied to one of the two input terminals of the negative AND NAND<b>41</b>. By contrast, to the other of the two input terminals of the negative AND NAND<b>41</b>, the L-level voltage from the output terminal of the inverter INV<b>81</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is applied via the contact point F<b>3</b> and the contact point K<b>1</b> of the capacitor charge voltage detecting unit <b>18</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. Accordingly, as the switching element Q<b>41</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is turned to the OFF state, the constant current is not supplied to the capacitor C<b>4</b> from the current source S<b>41</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0132" num="0131">Thus, at time t<b>1</b>, the charging of the capacitor C<b>4</b> by the constant current supplied from the current source S<b>42</b> starts, and the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b> increases over time, up to Vth<b>3</b> at time t<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0133" num="0132">Next, at time t<b>2</b>, when the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b> becomes Vth<b>3</b>, the switching element Q<b>81</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is turned to the ON state. Then, an H-level voltage is outputted from the output terminal of the inverter INV<b>81</b>, and the H-level voltage is applied to the other of the two input terminals of the negative AND NAND<b>41</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> via the contact point K<b>1</b> and the contact point F<b>3</b> of the constant current supplying unit <b>14</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. Accordingly, the switching element Q<b>41</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is turned to the ON state, and the constant current outputted from the current source S<b>41</b> is supplied to the capacitor C<b>4</b> via the switching element Q<b>41</b>, the contact point F<b>4</b>, and the terminal P<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, thereby charging the capacitor C<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0134" num="0133">Thus, at time t<b>2</b>, the charging of the capacitor C<b>4</b> is started by the constant current supplied from the current source S<b>41</b> and the constant current supplied from the current source S<b>42</b>, and the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b> increases over time, up to Vth<b>2</b> at time t<b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0135" num="0134">Further, at time t<b>2</b>, when the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b> becomes Vth<b>3</b>, the voltage of the contact point E<b>3</b> of the startup circuit unit <b>13</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> becomes Vth<b>3</b>, and the switching element Q<b>35</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is turned to the ON state. Accordingly, the gate voltage of the switching element Q<b>31</b> drops, and the switching element Q<b>31</b> is in the OFF state.</p>
<p id="p-0136" num="0135">Thus, at time t<b>2</b>, the switching element Q<b>31</b> is fixed to the OFF state, and the operation of the startup circuit unit <b>13</b> is prohibited.</p>
<p id="p-0137" num="0136">Moreover, at time t<b>2</b>, the outputted-voltage upper-limit control unit <b>161</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> outputs an L-level voltage as the outputted voltage reaching the upper limit voltage. The L-level voltage is applied to the input terminal of the inverter INV<b>71</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> via the contact point H<b>5</b> and the contact point J<b>6</b> of the oscillation stop control unit <b>17</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, and an H-level voltage is applied to the other of the two input terminals of the negative AND NAND<b>71</b>. By contrast, to one of the two input terminals of the negative AND NAND<b>71</b>, an H-level voltage is applied from the output terminal of the inverter INV<b>81</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> via the contact point J<b>4</b> and the contact point K<b>3</b> of the capacitor charge voltage detecting unit <b>18</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0138" num="0137">Consequently, an L-level voltage is outputted from the output terminal of the negative AND NAND<b>71</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, and the L-level voltage is applied to one of the four input terminals of the negative AND NAND<b>61</b> via the flip-flop FF<b>71</b>, the contact point J<b>7</b>, the contact point H<b>4</b> of the oscillation control unit <b>16</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, and the flip-flop FF<b>61</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>. With this, regardless of the voltages applied to the remaining three of the four input terminals of the negative AND NAND<b>61</b>, an H-level voltage is outputted from the output terminal of the negative AND NAND<b>61</b>. The H-level voltage is converted into an L-level voltage by the inverter INV<b>61</b>, and then applied to the gate of the switching element Q<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> via the contact point H<b>7</b> and the terminal P<b>6</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0139" num="0138">Thus, at time t<b>2</b>, the switching element Q<b>1</b> is fixed to the OFF state, and the oscillation of the switching element Q<b>1</b> is prohibited.</p>
<p id="p-0140" num="0139">Further, at time t<b>2</b>, when the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b> becomes Vth<b>3</b>, the switching element Q<b>22</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is turned to the ON state. By contrast, the switching element Q<b>21</b> is maintained in the OFF state by the comparator CMP<b>21</b>, the flip-flop FF<b>21</b>, and the switching element Q<b>23</b> that are shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0141" num="0140">Specifically, as the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b> at time t<b>2</b> is Vth<b>3</b> lower than Vth<b>2</b>, the comparator CMP<b>21</b> outputs an H-level voltage. Accordingly, the H-level voltage is applied to the reset terminal the flip-flop FF<b>21</b>. By contrast, an H-level voltage is applied to the set terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>21</b> from the output terminal of the inverter INV<b>81</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> via the contact point B<b>9</b> and the contact point K<b>3</b> of the capacitor charge voltage detecting unit <b>18</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0142" num="0141">Consequently, in the flip-flop FF<b>21</b>, the H-level voltage is applied to its reset terminal, and the H-level voltage is applied to its set terminal. Accordingly, the H-level voltage is outputted from the output terminal of the flip-flop FF<b>21</b> without any change from the previous state that has been maintained, and the switching element Q<b>23</b> is maintained in the ON state. With this, as described above, the gate voltage of the switching element Q<b>21</b> drops, and the switching element Q<b>21</b> is maintained in the OFF state.</p>
<p id="p-0143" num="0142">Consequently, at time t<b>2</b>, while the switching element Q<b>22</b> is turned to the ON state, the switching element Q<b>21</b> is maintained in the OFF state. As described above, if at least one of the switching elements Q<b>21</b> and Q<b>22</b> is in the OFF state, the driving unit <b>123</b> turns the switching element Q<b>24</b> to the ON state. Accordingly, the switching element Q<b>24</b> is maintained in the ON state, and the contact point B<b>4</b> and the reference potential source GND become conductive via the switching element Q<b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0144" num="0143">Thus, at time t<b>2</b>, the switching element Q<b>11</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is maintained in the ON state.</p>
<p id="p-0145" num="0144">Next, at time t<b>3</b>, as the comparator CMP<b>21</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> outputs an L-level voltage when the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b> becomes Vth<b>2</b>, the switching element Q<b>23</b> is turned to the OFF state, and the capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor C<b>5</b> is applied to the gate of the switching element Q<b>21</b> via the resistance R<b>21</b>, the contact point B<b>1</b>, and the terminal P<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. Accordingly, the switching element Q<b>21</b> is turned to the ON state. While the driving unit <b>123</b> turns the switching element Q<b>24</b> to the ON state when at least one of the switching elements Q<b>21</b> and Q<b>22</b> is in the OFF state as described above, the driving unit <b>123</b> turns the switching element Q<b>24</b> to the OFF state when both of the switching elements Q<b>21</b> and Q<b>22</b> are in the ON state. With this, the capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor C<b>5</b> is applied to the gate of the switching element Q<b>11</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> via the contact point A<b>3</b>, the contact point B<b>4</b> of the second control unit <b>12</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the driving unit <b>123</b>, the contact point B<b>1</b>, and the terminal P<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0146" num="0145">Thus, at time t<b>3</b>, the gate of the switching element Q<b>11</b> is not driven, and the switching element Q<b>11</b> is turned to the OFF state. Accordingly, the supply of the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C5 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>5</b> to the first control unit <b>10</b> is stopped, and the supply of the control voltage from the control voltage source VDD to the various circuits in the control circuit <b>2</b> is stopped. With this, the operation of the first control unit <b>10</b> stops, and the operations of the comparator CMP<b>21</b>, the flip-flop FF<b>21</b>, and the inverter INV<b>21</b> in the second control unit <b>12</b> also stop. Specifically, when the switching element Q<b>11</b> is in the OFF state, a part of the second control unit <b>12</b>, in addition to the first control unit <b>10</b>, stops its operation.</p>
<p id="p-0147" num="0146">Further, at time t<b>3</b>, the charging of the capacitor C<b>4</b> by the constant current supplied from the current source S<b>41</b> and the constant current supplied from the current source S<b>42</b> stop. Accordingly, the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b> decreases over time as the capacitor C<b>4</b> is discharged due to the resistance R<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0148" num="0147">Moreover, at time t<b>3</b>, as the voltage of the contact point B<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is H-level as described above, the capacitor C<b>21</b> is charged.</p>
<p id="p-0149" num="0148">Next, at time t<b>4</b>, the outputted-voltage lower-limit detecting unit <b>60</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> detects that the outputted voltage has decreased down to the lower limit voltage, and turns the phototransistor PT<b>1</b> to the ON state. Then, the capacitor C<b>4</b> is discharged quickly, and the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b> becomes zero.</p>
<p id="p-0150" num="0149">At time t<b>4</b>, when the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b> becomes zero as described above, the switching element Q<b>22</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is turned to the OFF state, and therefore the switching element Q<b>11</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is turned to the ON state as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0151" num="0150">Thus, at time t<b>4</b>, as the switching element Q<b>11</b> is turned to the ON state and the control voltage is supplied to the various circuits in the control circuit <b>2</b>, the switching element Q<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is allowed to oscillate.</p>
<p id="p-0152" num="0151">Further, at time t<b>4</b>, when the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b> becomes zero as described above, the switching element Q<b>35</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, whose gate is connected to the capacitor C<b>4</b> via the terminal P<b>1</b> and the contact point E<b>3</b> of the startup circuit unit <b>13</b> that are shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, is turned to the OFF state. Accordingly, the fixation of the switching element Q<b>31</b> to the OFF state is released. With this, the prohibition of the operation of the startup circuit unit <b>13</b> is lifted.</p>
<p id="p-0153" num="0152">However, at time t<b>4</b>, by the capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor C<b>21</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> thus charged, the switching element Q<b>25</b> is turned to the ON state. Accordingly, an H-level voltage is applied to the gate of the switching element Q<b>32</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> via the inverter INV<b>21</b>, the contact point B<b>5</b>, and the contact point E<b>1</b> of the startup circuit unit <b>13</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, and the switching element Q<b>32</b> is turned to the ON state. With this, the gate voltage of the switching element Q<b>31</b> drops, and the switching element Q<b>31</b> is turned to the OFF state.</p>
<p id="p-0154" num="0153">Thus, at time t<b>4</b>, the switching element Q<b>31</b> is turned to the OFF state, and the operation of the startup circuit unit <b>13</b> is stopped.</p>
<p id="p-0155" num="0154">Further, at time t<b>4</b>, the switching element Q<b>25</b> is in the ON state as described above. Accordingly, an H-level voltage is applied to the gate of the switching element Q<b>51</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> via the inverter INV<b>21</b>, the contact point B<b>6</b>, and the contact point G<b>1</b> in the low-voltage-error preventing circuit unit <b>15</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. Therefore, the switching element Q<b>51</b> is turned to the ON state, and the resistance R<b>52</b> is connected to the resistance R<b>53</b> in parallel. With this, a threshold voltage used by the comparator CMP<b>51</b> is fixed to the second threshold voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0156" num="0155">Thus, at time t<b>4</b>, the threshold voltage used by the comparator CMP<b>51</b> is fixed to the second threshold voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0157" num="0156">Next, at time t<b>5</b>, the capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor C<b>21</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> thus charged decreases down to a level at which the switching element Q<b>32</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> and the switching element Q<b>51</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> are both turned to the OFF state. It should be noted that a time period from time t<b>4</b> to time t<b>5</b> is determined based on a time constant of the time constant circuit <b>122</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0158" num="0157">Thus, at time t<b>5</b>, the stopping of the operation of the startup circuit unit <b>13</b> is released, the startup circuit unit <b>13</b> is allowed to operate, and the fixation of the threshold voltage used by the comparator CMP<b>51</b> to the second threshold voltage is canceled.</p>
<p id="p-0159" num="0158">From time t<b>6</b> to time t<b>8</b>, the control circuit <b>2</b> operates in the same manner as has operated from time t<b>1</b> to time t<b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0160" num="0159">According to the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> described above, the following effects can be provided.</p>
<p id="p-0161" num="0160">The isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> turns the switching element Q<b>11</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> to the OFF state to stop the power supply from the capacitor C<b>5</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> to the first control unit <b>10</b> in a part of a switching pause period in the standby mode, for example, as in a time period from time t<b>3</b> to time t<b>4</b> out of a time period from time t<b>2</b> to time t<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>. Accordingly, the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> in the standby mode can be reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0162" num="0161">Further, the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> performs the supply of the current from the constant current supplying unit <b>14</b> to the capacitor C<b>4</b> within a time period in which the first control unit <b>10</b> receives the power supply from the capacitor C<b>5</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, for example, as in a time period from time t<b>1</b> to time t<b>3</b> or from time t<b>6</b> to time t<b>8</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>. Accordingly, it is possible to incorporate the constant current supplying unit <b>14</b> in the first control unit <b>10</b>, and the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> in the standby mode can be further reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0163" num="0162">Moreover, as described above, the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> turns the switching element Q<b>11</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> to the OFF state to stop the power supply from the capacitor C<b>5</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> to the first control unit <b>10</b> during the part of the switching pause period in the standby mode. Accordingly, the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> can be reduced without making the capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor C<b>5</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> 0 V during the switching pause period in the standby mode. Therefore, as it is not necessary to operate the startup circuit unit <b>13</b> when shifting from the switching pause period to the oscillation period in the standby mode, the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> can be sufficiently reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0164" num="0163">Furthermore, the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> turns the phototransistor PT<b>1</b> to the ON state when the fact that the outputted voltage has become no higher than the lower limit voltage is detected by the outputted-voltage lower-limit detecting unit <b>60</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, and causes the capacitor C<b>4</b> to be rapidly discharged as in time t<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, for example. With this, the second control unit <b>12</b> turns the switching element Q<b>11</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> to the ON state to resume the switching of the switching element Q<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. Accordingly, it is possible to prevent the outputted voltage from being lower than the lower limit voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0165" num="0164">In addition, the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> turns the phototransistor PT<b>1</b> to the ON state, when the fact that the outputted voltage has become no higher than the lower limit voltage is detected by the outputted-voltage lower-limit detecting unit <b>60</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, and when operating in the normal mode. Accordingly, as the phototransistor PT<b>1</b> can be commonly used in the both cases, the reduction of the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> in the standby mode can be realized at low cost.</p>
<p id="p-0166" num="0165">Further, according to the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b>, the capacitor C<b>21</b> is charged during the time period in which the switching element Q<b>11</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is in the OFF state, for example, as in the time period from time t<b>3</b> to time t<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>. Accordingly, it is possible to discriminate, based on the capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor C<b>21</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, a case in which the power activation of the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> is started from a case in which the power supply from the capacitor C<b>5</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> to the first control unit <b>10</b> is resumed in the standby mode. Accordingly, when the power supply from the capacitor C<b>5</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> to the first control unit <b>10</b> is resumed in the standby mode, it is possible to perform an operation suitable for the case in which the power supply to the first control unit <b>10</b> is resumed and that is different from an operation in the case in which the power activation to the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> is started.</p>
<p id="p-0167" num="0166">Moreover, the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> is configured such that the capacitor C<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is connected to the resistance R<b>1</b> in parallel. Accordingly, even in a case in which it is not possible to discharge the capacitor C<b>4</b> by turning the phototransistor PT<b>1</b> to the ON state in an occurrence of abnormity that a peak load over an output capacity of the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> is caused in the standby mode, the capacitor C<b>4</b> can be discharged by the resistance R<b>1</b>. Therefore, it is possible to resume the operation of the startup circuit unit <b>13</b> and the power supply to the first control unit <b>10</b> within time determined by capacities of the resistance R<b>1</b> and the capacitor C<b>4</b> and a residual voltage, and the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> can be restored to a normal state from an abnormal state.</p>
<p id="p-0168" num="0167">Furthermore, the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> controls, depending on whether or not the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is no lower than Vth<b>3</b>, whether to charge the capacitor C<b>4</b> based only on the current outputted from the current source S<b>42</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> or on the currents outputted from both of the current sources S<b>41</b> and S<b>42</b>. Accordingly, it is possible to reduce a loss when it is not necessary to increase the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b>, and to quickly charge the capacitor C<b>4</b> when it is necessary to increase the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b>. Therefore, a proportion of a time period during which the power supply to the first control unit <b>10</b> is performed to an intermittent oscillation cycle can be made small, and the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> in the standby mode can be further reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0169" num="0168">In addition, the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> turns the switching element Q<b>11</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> to the OFF state when the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b> becomes no lower than Vth<b>2</b>, for example, as shown at time t<b>3</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>. Accordingly, it is possible to increase the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> up to Vth<b>2</b> during the time period in which the switching element Q<b>11</b> is in the ON state, that is, during the time period in which the power supply to the first control unit <b>10</b> is performed. Therefore, it is possible to extend the state in which the electric charge remains in the capacitor C<b>4</b>, and in turn to extend the intermittent oscillation cycle, and as a result, the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> in the standby mode can be further reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0170" num="0169">Further, the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> stops the switching of the switching element Q<b>1</b>, when the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b> is no lower than Vth<b>3</b> and the outputted voltage is no lower than the upper limit voltage, for example, as shown at time t<b>2</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>. Accordingly, the oscillation can be stopped immediately when the outputted voltage reaches the upper limit voltage, and therefore it is possible to decrease a proportion of the oscillation period to the intermittent oscillation cycle, that is, oscillation duty of the intermittent oscillation, as well as a number of oscillation times of the switching element Q<b>1</b> per unit time. Therefore, the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> in the standby mode can be further reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0171" num="0170">Moreover, the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> stops the switching of the switching element Q<b>1</b> when the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b> is no lower than Vth<b>3</b> and the outputted voltage is no lower than the upper limit voltage. Accordingly, it is possible to control the switching of the switching element Q<b>1</b> according to the outputted voltage, and to prevent the outputted voltage from exceeding the upper limit voltage. Here, as described above, the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> can prevent the outputted voltage from becoming lower than the lower limit voltage. Therefore, the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> can control the upper limit and the lower limit of the outputted voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0172" num="0171">Furthermore, the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> starts supplying the current from the constant current supplying unit <b>14</b> to the capacitor C<b>4</b> when the outputted voltage becomes no lower than the upper limit voltage during the time period in which the power supply to the first control unit <b>10</b> is performed, as shown at time t<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, for example. Accordingly, even during the time period in which the power supply to the first control unit <b>10</b> is performed, the capacitor C<b>4</b> is not charged unless the outputted voltage increases up to the upper limit voltage. Therefore, it is possible to charge the capacitor C<b>4</b> after the outputted voltage is acquired to some extent, and to prevent an erroneous operation from occurring.</p>
<p id="p-0173" num="0172">In addition, the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> prohibits the operation of the startup circuit unit <b>13</b> when the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b> becomes no lower than Vth<b>3</b>, as shown at time t<b>2</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, for example. Accordingly, as the startup circuit unit <b>13</b> does not operates even if the power supply to the first control unit <b>10</b> is stopped, the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> can be further reduced without providing any special circuit for monitoring the capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor C<b>5</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and stopping the operation of the startup circuit unit <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0174" num="0173">Further, according to the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b>, when the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b> becomes lower than Vth<b>3</b>, as shown at time t<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, for example, the second control unit <b>12</b> turns the switching element Q<b>11</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> to the ON state to start the switching of the switching element Q<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. Accordingly, it is possible to start the switching of the switching element Q<b>1</b> before the outputted voltage becomes too low, and to prevent the outputted voltage from decreasing excessively.</p>
<p id="p-0175" num="0174">Moreover, the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> lifts the prohibition of the operation of the startup circuit unit <b>13</b>, when the capacitor charge voltage V<sub>C4 </sub>of the capacitor C<b>4</b> becomes lower than Vth<b>3</b>, as shown at time t<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, for example. Accordingly, the startup circuit unit <b>13</b> can be operated when the capacitor charge voltage of the capacitor C<b>5</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> decreases down to a voltage at which the startup circuit unit <b>13</b> is required to be operated during the switching pause period in the standby mode, and it is possible to prevent the outputted voltage from decreasing excessively.</p>
<p id="p-0176" num="0175">Furthermore, the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> stops the operation of the startup circuit unit <b>13</b> during a time period until a time period determined based on the time constant of the time constant circuit <b>122</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> elapses after the switching element Q<b>11</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> that is in the OFF state is turned to the ON state in the standby mode, as in the time period from time t<b>4</b> to time t<b>5</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, for example. Accordingly, it is possible to prevent the startup circuit unit <b>13</b> from unnecessarily operating, and the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> in the standby mode can be further reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0177" num="0176">In addition, the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> fixes the threshold voltage used by the comparator CMP<b>51</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> to the second threshold voltage during a time period until a time period determined based on the time constant of the time constant circuit <b>122</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> elapses after the switching element Q<b>11</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> that is in the OFF state is turned to the ON state in the standby mode, as in the time period from time t<b>4</b> to time t<b>5</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, for example. Accordingly, as it is possible to immediately start the switching-control of the switching element Q<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> without operating the startup circuit unit <b>13</b> even if the intermittent oscillation cycle is increased, the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> can be further reduced. In other words, as it is possible to extend the time period in which the switching-control of the switching element Q<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> can be immediately started without operating the startup circuit unit <b>13</b>, the power consumption of the isolated switch-mode power supply device <b>1</b> can be further reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0178" num="0177">The present application is based on Japanese Patent Application No. 2010-159483 filed in Japan by the applicant of the present application on Jul. 14, 2010, the entire content of which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0179" num="0178">The present invention is not limited to the embodiment described above, and various modifications and applications can be made without departing from the spirit and the scope of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0180" num="0179">For example, in the embodiment described above, the constant current supplying unit <b>14</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> supplies the constant current to the capacitor C<b>4</b>. However, the present invention is not limited to this example, and a current can be supplied to the capacitor C<b>4</b>. Supplying the current to the capacitor C<b>4</b> can be realized by replacing at least one of the current sources S<b>41</b> and S<b>42</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> with a resistance, for example. It is possible to provide the same effect as described above even when at least one of the current sources S<b>41</b> and S<b>42</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is replaced by a resistance.</p>
<p id="p-0181" num="0180">Further, in the embodiment described above, the outputted-voltage upper-limit detecting unit <b>50</b> turns the phototransistor PT<b>2</b> to the ON state if the outputted voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>is no lower than the upper limit voltage. The upper limit voltage can be set to the same voltage level both in the normal mode and the standby mode, or the upper limit voltage in the normal mode can be set to a different voltage level from that in the standby mode. For example, when the upper limit voltage is set to the same voltage level both in the normal mode and in the standby mode, the outputted voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>in the normal mode and a maximum value of the outputted voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>in the standby mode become identical. Further, when the upper limit voltage in the normal mode is set to a different voltage level from that in the standby mode, or more specifically, when the upper limit voltage in the normal mode is set to the same voltage level as the lower limit voltage in the standby mode, the outputted voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>in the normal mode and a minimum value of the outputted voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>in the standby mode become identical.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An isolated switch-mode power supply device capable of controlling switching of a switching element in one of a continuous operation and a burst mode operation, and of controlling conversion of an inputted voltage into a required outputted voltage, the isolated switch-mode power supply device comprising:
<claim-text>a control power supply source configured to supply control power required for controlling the switching;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first control unit having a current supplying unit for supplying a preliminarily determined current during at least a part of a time period in which power supply is received from the control power supply source, and configured to control the switching of the switching element in one of the continuous operation and the burst mode operation;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control power supply switch configured to either connect or disconnect the first control unit and the control power supply source;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a capacitance element unit having a first capacitor to which the current is supplied from the current supplying unit, a capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor changing according to an outputted voltage in the burst mode operation; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second control unit configured to control the power supply to the first control unit by opening the control power supply switch during at least a part of a switching pause period in the burst mode operation according to the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The isolated switch-mode power supply device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the current supplying unit changes a value of the current to be supplied to the first capacitor according to the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The isolated switch-mode power supply device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein when the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor is no lower than a second set voltage and the outputted voltage is no lower than an upper limit voltage, the first control unit stops the switching of the switching element.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The isolated switch-mode power supply device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein when the outputted voltage becomes no lower than upper limit voltage during the time period in which the power supply from the control power supply source to the first control unit is performed, the current supplying unit starts supplying the current to the first capacitor, and when the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor is no lower than a second set voltage and the outputted voltage is no lower than the upper limit voltage, the first control unit stops the switching of the switching element.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The isolated switch-mode power supply device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second control unit includes the capacitance element unit,
<claim-text>the capacitance element unit includes the first capacitor, a first switching element, and a second switching element,</claim-text>
<claim-text>one end of the first capacitor is connected to a control terminal of the first switching element,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the other end of the first capacitor is connected to an output terminal of the first switching element, and to an output terminal of the second switching element,</claim-text>
<claim-text>an input terminal of the first switching element is connected to a control terminal of the second switching element, and to the control power supply source via a driving unit for driving the second switching element, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an input terminal of the second switching element is connected to a control terminal of the control power supply switch.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The isolated switch-mode power supply device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising: first discharge means configured to decrease the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor when the outputted voltage becomes no higher than a lower limit voltage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The isolated switch-mode power supply device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein when a state switching signal for shifting the state to the continuous operation is inputted, the first discharge means decreases the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The isolated switch-mode power supply device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising: a second capacitor configured to be charged during the switching pause period in the burst mode operation, wherein based on a capacitor charge voltage of the second capacitor, a case in which supply of the inputted voltage is started is discriminated from a case in which the power supply from the control power supply source to the first control unit is resumed in the burst mode operation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The isolated switch-mode power supply device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising: second discharge means connected in parallel to the first capacitor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The isolated switch-mode power supply device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein when the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor becomes no lower than a first set voltage, the second control unit opens the control power supply switch.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The isolated switch-mode power supply device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, further comprising: a startup circuit configured to activate the first control unit and the second control unit by the inputted voltage, wherein when the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor becomes no lower than the second set voltage, an operation of the startup circuit is prohibited.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The isolated switch-mode power supply device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein when the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor becomes lower than the second set voltage, the prohibition of the operation of the startup circuit is lifted and the control power supply switch is closed by the second control unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The isolated switch-mode power supply device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein during a specific time period in the burst mode operation, the operation of the startup circuit is stopped, the specific time period being a time period until a first time period elapses after closing the control power supply switch in an open state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The isolated switch-mode power supply device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further comprising: a specific control unit configured to, when the control voltage supplied to the first control unit is no lower than a first threshold voltage, stop the operation of the startup circuit and start controlling the switching of the switching element, and to, when the control voltage is no higher than a second threshold voltage that is lower than the first threshold voltage, start the operation of the startup circuit and stop controlling the switching of the switching element, wherein during the specific time period in the burst mode operation, a threshold voltage used by the specific control unit is fixed to the second threshold voltage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. An isolated switch-mode power supply device capable of controlling switching of a switching element in one of a continuous operation and a burst mode operation, and of controlling conversion of an inputted voltage into a required outputted voltage, the isolated switch-mode power supply device comprising:
<claim-text>a control power supply source configured to supply control power required for controlling the switching;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first control unit having a constant current supplying unit for supplying a preliminarily determined constant current during at least a part of a time period in which power supply is received from the control power supply source, and configured to control the switching of the switching element in one of the continuous operation and the burst mode operation;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control power supply switch configured to either connect or disconnect the first control unit and the control power supply source;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a capacitance element unit having a first capacitor to which the constant current is supplied from the constant current supplying unit, a capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor changing according to an outputted voltage in the burst mode operation; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second control unit configured to control the power supply to the first control unit by opening the control power supply switch during at least a part of a switching pause period in the burst mode operation according to the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The isolated switch-mode power supply device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the constant current supplying unit changes a value of the constant current to be supplied to the first capacitor according to the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The isolated switch-mode power supply device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein when the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor is no lower than a second set voltage and the outputted voltage is no lower than an upper limit voltage, the first control unit stops the switching of the switching element.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The isolated switch-mode power supply device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein when the outputted voltage becomes no lower than upper limit voltage during the time period in which the power supply from the control power supply source to the first control unit is performed, the constant current supplying unit starts supplying the constant current to the first capacitor, and when the capacitor charge voltage of the first capacitor is no lower than a second set voltage and the outputted voltage is no lower than the upper limit voltage, the first control unit stops the switching of the switching element. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
