<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623763-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623763</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13150899</doc-number>
<date>20110601</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>138</us-term-extension>
<disclaimer>
<text>This patent is subject to a terminal disclaimer.</text>
</disclaimer>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>21</main-group>
<subgroup>44</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438667</main-classification>
<further-classification>257E21511</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e55">Protective layer for protecting TSV tips during thermo-compressive bonding</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7365436</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Yamano</name>
<date>20080400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7407833</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Wu</name>
<date>20080800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438108</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8298944</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>West</name>
<date>20121000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438667</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8313982</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Dunne et al.</name>
<date>20121100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438110</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0280435</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Klootwijk et al.</name>
<date>20081100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0278244</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Dunne et al.</name>
<date>20091100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257676</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0038800</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yoon et al.</name>
<date>20100200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0171226</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>West et al.</name>
<date>20100700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0230759</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yang et al.</name>
<date>20100900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>32</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438667</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438666</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438668</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120306085</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121206</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>West</last-name>
<first-name>Jeffrey Alan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Dallas</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>West</last-name>
<first-name>Jeffrey Alan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Dallas</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Shaw</last-name>
<first-name>Steven A.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Brady, III</last-name>
<first-name>Wade James</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="03" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Telecky, Jr.</last-name>
<first-name>Frederick J.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Texas Instruments Incorporated</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Dallas</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Nikmanesh</last-name>
<first-name>Seahvosh</first-name>
<department>2812</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Patel</last-name>
<first-name>Reema</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A method of protecting through substrate via (TSV) die from bonding damage includes providing a substrate including a plurality of TSV die having a topside including active circuitry, a bottomside, and a plurality of TSVs that include an inner metal core that reaches from the topside to protruding TSV tips that extend out from the bottomside. A protective layer is formed on or applied to the bottomside of the TSV die including between and over the protruding TSV tips. The TSV die is bonded with its topside down onto a workpiece having a workpiece surface and its bottomside up and in contact with a bond head. The protective layer reduces damage from the bonding process including warpage of the TSV die by preventing the bond head from making direct contact to the protruding TSV tips.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="161.54mm" wi="240.11mm" file="US08623763-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="171.11mm" wi="130.22mm" file="US08623763-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="243.76mm" wi="153.75mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623763-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="239.10mm" wi="163.07mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623763-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">Disclosed embodiments relate to electronic devices, and more particularly to assembly of integrated circuit (IC) die or a wafer comprising a plurality of die having protruding through substrate via tips to at least one workpiece, and electronic devices therefrom.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">As known in the art, through-substrate vias (referred to herein as TSVs), which are commonly referred to as through-silicon vias in the case of silicon substrates, are vertical electrical connections that extend the full thickness of the IC die from one of the electrically conductive levels formed on the topside semiconductor surface of the IC die (e.g., contact level or one of the back end of the line (BEOL) metal interconnect levels) to its bottomside surface. Such IC die are referred to herein as &#x201c;TSV die.&#x201d; The vertical electrical paths are significantly shortened relative to conventional wire bonding technology, generally leading to significantly faster device operation. In one arrangement, the TSVs terminate on the bottomside of the TSV die as protruding TSV tips, such as protruding a distance of 5 to 15 &#x3bc;ms from the bottomside substrate (e.g., silicon) surface. To form the protruding tips, the TSV die are commonly thinned in wafer form to expose the TSVs and to form the tips, such as to a die thickness of 25 to 100 &#x3bc;m, using a process generally including backgrinding. The TSV die can be bonded face-up or face-down, and can be bonded to from both of its sides to enable formation of stacked die devices.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In die areas having TSVs, there can be no active devices because TSVs extend the full thickness of the TSV die. TSVs on the TSV die are generally arranged in a plurality of separate TSV arrays that cover a relatively small percentage of the TSV die area, and thus TSVs collectively do not approach uniformly covering the area of the TSV die. The TSVs within the TSV arrays are typically regularly spaced having a fixed pitch. Regions beyond the TSV arrays, or TSV-free regions, result in an irregular bottomside topography caused by the protruding TSV tips being elevated, with the TSV-free regions having a consistent lowest elevation.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The TSV tips may include a metal cap thereon, such as a cap including a nickel comprising layer, that can function as an inter-metallic compound (IMC) barrier to overlying Sn-based solder in the case of solder mediated joints to a workpiece (e.g., a package substrate or another die or a die stack) to avoid, or at least delay, the consumption of the inner metal core (e.g., copper) of the TSV from forming an IMC which can lead to cracking of the outer dielectric sleeve of the TSV, and resulting failures (e.g., leakage or shorts) on the TSV die. The metal cap can significantly increase the height of the TSV tips relative to the TSV-free regions.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Thermo-compression (TC) bonding is a common IC assembly method that involves the use of pressure (e.g., 40 to 80 N/cm<sup>2</sup>) applied by a bond head and a significant temperature (e.g., a temperature high enough to melt solder, such as 230 to 300&#xb0; C.) to join two materials by interdiffusion across the boundary of the materials. The TC bonding process relies on pressure to push pillars or other bonding features on the topside surface of TSV die or a TSV wafer against opposing pads on a substrate, wafer or another die that are to be bonded, and to heat and melt the solder. During TC bonding of a thin (e.g., &#x3c;100 &#x3bc;m thick) TSV die having bottomside TSV tips to a substrate (e.g., package substrate, die, or die stack) in which the topside of the TSV die is bonded to pads on a substrate, the TC bond head comes in direct contact with the TSV tips that protrude far above the surrounding TSV-free regions, effectively resulting in non-uniformly distributed pressure applied to the bonds formed on the topside of the die.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Disclosed embodiments are based on several recognitions of happenings during TC bonding the topside (active side) of thin TSV die or thin TSV wafers (e.g., &#x3c;100 &#x3bc;m thick) to a workpiece, where the TSV die or TSV wafers have TSV-free regions across their area on their bottomside. The TSV-free regions have a consistent lowest elevation relative to protruding TSV tips resulting in an irregular bottomside topography than can cause pick-up problems and substantially non-uniformly distributed pressure applied during subsequent bonding operations that can cause problems including die warpage, damage to brittle low-k dielectrics between the TSVs and the bonded topside surface, and cracking of the TSV's dielectric sleeve where the TSV exits the die bottomside.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Regarding pick-up problems, the exposed TSVs on the bottomside of the TSV die or TSV wafer can be damaged during vacuum pick-up, which can lead to poor bond integrity during subsequent bonding of the TSV tip to another workpiece. Moreover, thin TSV die and thin TSV wafers can easily bend when subjected to non-uniformly distributed pressure during bonding. This can lead to intra-die warpage post-bonding that induces non-uniform tensile stresses on the topside bonds which has been found by the Inventor to cause low bond yield to a workpiece, such as an organic substrate, and can also result in degradation of the &#x201c;co-planarity&#x201d; of the protruding TSVs that can create problems for subsequent bonding of the collective TSV tips to a workpiece with a nominally co-planar bonding surface.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Disclosed embodiments solve the above-described tip damage problem by adding a protective layer over the protruding TSV tips on the bottomside of the TSV die for reducing or eliminating damage during TC bonding to a workpiece (e.g., organic substrate), which results in a more uniform pressure applied by the TC bond head during TC bonding. Such a protective layer has been found to eliminate or at least significantly reduce TC-bonding induced opens on the bonded topside of the TSV die, and subsequently bonded devices to the bottomside TSV tips of the TSV die. Since disclosed protective layer is on the bottomside of the TSV die, no active die area is lost.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a flow chart that shows steps in an example method of protecting TSV die including protruding TSV tips on the bottomside of the TSV die from bonding damage by adding a protective layer between and over the protruding TSV tips, according to an example embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a simplified cross-sectional depiction of a TSV die comprising a plurality of TSVs that include protruding TSV tips having a protective layer between and over the protruding TSV tips on the bottomside of the TSV die, according to an example embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows an example protected stacked die precursor comprising the TSV die shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> bonded to a workpiece, according to an example embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Example embodiments are described with reference to the drawings, wherein like reference numerals are used to designate similar or equivalent elements. Illustrated ordering of acts or events should not be considered as limiting, as some acts or events may occur in different order and/or concurrently with other acts or events. Furthermore, some illustrated acts or events may not be required to implement a methodology in accordance with this disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a flow chart that shows steps in an example method <b>100</b> of protecting TSV die including protruding TSV tips on the bottomside of the TSV die from bonding damage by adding a protective layer between and over the protruding TSV tips, according to an example embodiment. Step <b>101</b> comprises providing a substrate (e.g., a wafer) comprising a plurality of TSV die having a topside including active circuitry, a bottomside, and a plurality of TSVs.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The TSVs include an inner metal core and an outer dielectric sleeve that extends the full thickness of the TSV die from the topside surface (generally coupled to the contact level or one of the back end of the line (BEOL) metal layers (e.g., M<b>1</b>, M<b>2</b>, etc.) to the protruding TSV tips that emerge from the bottomside of the TSV die. In one embodiment a length of the protruding TSV tips measured from the bottomside of the TSV die is from 2 to 15 &#x3bc;m. In one embodiment the TSV diameter is &#x2266;12 &#x3bc;m, such as 4 to 10 &#x3bc;m in one particular embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The inner metal core can comprise Cu in one embodiment. Other electrically conductive materials can be used for the inner metal core. The outer dielectric sleeve can comprise materials such as silicon oxide, silicon nitride, phosphorus-doped silicate glass (PSG), silicon oxynitride, or certain chemical vapor deposited (CVD) polymers (e.g., parylene). The outer dielectric sleeve is typically 0.2 &#x3bc;m to 5 &#x3bc;m thick.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In the case of copper and certain other metals for the inner metal core, a metal diffusion barrier layer referred to herein as a &#x201c;TSV barrier&#x201d; is generally added and is deposited on the dielectric sleeve, such as a refractory metal or a refractory metal nitride. For example, TSV barrier materials can include materials including Ta, W, Mo, Ti, TiW, TiN, TaN, WN, TiSiN or TaSiN, which can be deposited by physical vapor deposition (PVD) or CVD. The TSV barrier is typically 100-500 &#x212b; thick.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The TSV tips generally include a metal cap thereon that comprises at least a first metal layer that includes a metal that is not in the inner metal core. The metal layer for the cap is exclusive of solder can be electrolessly or electrolytically deposited (i.e., electroplating) on a distal portion of the protruding TSV tips. The first metal layer forms an electrical contact with at least the topmost surface of the inner metal core of the TSV tip.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The first metal layer can be generally 1 to 8 &#x3bc;m thick. The first metal layer can provide both an IMC block. The first metal layer can comprise materials including Ni, Pd, Ti, Au, Co, Cr, Rh, NiP, NiB, CoWP or CoP, for example. In one specific embodiment, the first metal layer can comprise a 3 to 8 &#x3bc;m thick electroplated Cu plated layer. In one embodiment the inner metal core comprises copper and the TSV tips include a metal cap that includes at least one of Ti, Ni, Pd, and Au. An optional metal barrier layer may also be included between the first metal layer and the distal portion of the TSV tips. For example, a Ti or Ta comprising layer of about 1 k&#x212b; to 3 k&#x212b; may be used as a barrier layer.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The metal caps can include a second metal layer exclusive of solder that is different from the first metal layer. The combined thickness of the first and second metal layers can be 1 &#x3bc;m to 10 &#x3bc;m. One metal cap arrangement comprises Ni/Au.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The substrate (e.g., a wafer) provided in step <b>101</b> can also include a first dielectric layer on the bottomside of the substrate between the TSV tips that is generally formed and etched back to expose the TSV tips before the metal caps are formed. For example, in one particular embodiment the TSV tips extend out about 5 &#x3bc;m from the bottomside surface of TSV die, the metal caps <b>240</b> add about 5 &#x3bc;m in height to the TSV tips, and the first dielectric layer is about 3 &#x3bc;m thick. In this particular embodiment, the metal capped TSV tips protrude about 7 &#x3bc;m above the first dielectric layer.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Step <b>102</b> comprises forming or applying a protective layer on the bottomside of the TSV die including between and over the protruding TSV tips. The protective layer can planarize over protruding TSV tips to provide a substantially planar surface. As defined herein, a &#x201c;substantially planar surface&#x201d; has a maximum height range of 1 &#x3bc;m.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In one embodiment the protective layer is a blanket layer that is spun on to cover over the top of existing topography, including over the metal capped TSV tips and the first dielectric layer between the TSV tips described above. In embodiments where a portion of the protective layer remains on the TSV die after step <b>105</b> described below, the protective layer is generally a dielectric material. Some exemplary dielectric materials for the protective layer include polymers such as benzocyclobutene (BCB), polybenzoxazole (PBO), and some polyimides (PI) that are formed from photosensitive precursor materials. In this embodiment the protective layer can comprise the same dielectric material as is used for the first dielectric layer so that if desired, the protective layer can be left on the substrate (e.g., wafer) after exposing the TSV tips by partial etchback as described below in step <b>105</b>. The method can include optionally curing the protective layer in the case of curable protective layer materials to increase the stiffness of the protective layer before bonding (step <b>104</b> described below).</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In another embodiment the protective layer comprises a metal tape, such as an aluminum tape. A metal tape of suitable material and thickness (e.g., a 15 to 20 &#x3bc;m thick aluminum tape) is readily malleable to provide planarization over the metal capped TSV tips and can be applied and secured to the bottomside of the substrate (e.g., a wafer) including all TSV die on the substrate (e.g., wafer) by a suitable adhesive.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Step <b>103</b> comprises singulating the substrate (e.g., wafer) into a plurality of singulated TSV die. Conventional sawing techniques may be used. Step <b>104</b> comprises bonding the singulated TSV die with the topside down onto a workpiece surface with the bottomside up and in contact with a bond head. The workpiece can comprise an organic substrate in one embodiment, such as a substrate strip. The bonding can comprise TC bonding that can involve the use of pressure (e.g., 40 to 80 N/cm<sup>2</sup>) applied by a bond head. As described above, the protective layer being on top of the TSV tips prevents the bond head from making direct contact to the protruding TSV tips such that magnitude of the pressure exerted on TSV tips is reduced by &#x201c;spreading&#x201d; bond head contact area to entire die bottomside of the TSV die instead of just the area of the TSV tips.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Step <b>105</b> comprises partially removing or completely removing the protective layer to expose the TSV tips for subsequent bonding. Dry etching or ashing can be used for this step. Wet etch processing may also be suitable. If etching is used in step <b>105</b> the etch is engineered to be highly selective so that the underfill that is typically between the TSV die and the workpiece (e.g., organic substrate) is not damaged at its exposed periphery during step <b>105</b>. In the embodiment for which the protective layer comprises a metal tape, the metal tape can be completely removed by a suitable adhesive removal process that does not degrade the underfill between the TSV die and the workpiece.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Significantly, method <b>100</b> is applicable to any TC bonder apparatus as the disclosed protective layer is applied to the TSV die and not to the bond head. Moreover, the spreading of the bond head pressure, provided by disclosed protective layer, reduces TC bonding-induced warpage of the TSV die, and can eliminate or at least significantly reduce cracking of the TSV's dielectric sleeve.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a simplified cross-sectional depiction of a TSV die <b>200</b> comprising a plurality of TSVs <b>216</b> that include protruding TSV tips <b>217</b> having a protective layer <b>231</b>(<i>b</i>) over a first dielectric layer <b>231</b>(<i>a</i>) between and over the protruding TSV tips <b>217</b> on the bottomside <b>210</b> of the TSV die, according to an example embodiment. The protruding TSV tips <b>217</b> are shown having a metal cap <b>240</b> on the distal tip end <b>217</b>(<i>a</i>).</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">TSV die <b>200</b> comprises a substrate <b>205</b> including a topside surface <b>207</b> including active circuitry <b>209</b> and a bottomside surface <b>210</b>. The active circuitry <b>209</b> on TSV die <b>200</b> is configured to provide an IC circuit function, such as a logic function, for example. The connectors <b>208</b> shown depict the coupling between the TSVs <b>216</b> on the topside surface <b>207</b> to the active circuitry <b>209</b>. The connection to active circuitry <b>209</b> is optional, since the TSV may simply provide a through-die connection through the substrate <b>205</b> without connecting to active circuitry <b>209</b> (e.g., to a device attached to bottomside <b>210</b> of TSV die <b>200</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The TSVs <b>216</b> comprise an outer dielectric sleeve <b>221</b> and an inner metal core <b>220</b>, and a metal diffusion TSV barrier layer <b>222</b> between the outer dielectric sleeve <b>221</b> and the inner metal core <b>220</b>. The TSVs <b>216</b> extends from the topside surface <b>207</b> to protruding TSV tip <b>217</b> emerging from the bottomside surface <b>210</b>. The protective layer <b>231</b>(<i>b</i>) is shown as a planarizing layer over protruding TSV tips <b>217</b>. For example, in one particular embodiment the TSV tip ends <b>217</b>(<i>a</i>) extend out about 5 &#x3bc;m from the bottomside surface <b>210</b>, the metal caps <b>240</b> add about 5 &#x3bc;m in height to the TSV tips <b>217</b>, the protective layer <b>231</b>(<i>b</i>) thickness is in the range from 10 to 15 &#x3bc;m with first dielectric layer <b>231</b>(<i>a</i>) being about 3 &#x3bc;m thick. In this particular embodiment, the protective layer <b>231</b>(<i>b</i>) is about 3 to 8 &#x3bc;m above the metal caps <b>240</b> on the TSV tips <b>217</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows an example protected stacked die precursor <b>300</b> comprising the TSV die <b>200</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> bonded to a workpiece shown as substrate <b>330</b>, according to an example embodiment. The protected stacked die precursor <b>300</b> having TSV tips encapsulated enables shipping of such units with a reduced risk of damaging the TSV tips. TSV die <b>200</b> is bonded topside <b>207</b> down to pads <b>337</b> on substrate <b>330</b> that is shown as a package substrate (e.g., organic substrate). The package substrate can comprise a ceramic or an organic substrate, that may be thin (e.g., &#x3c;350 &#x3bc;m). The package substrate is generally provided as a substrate panel (or strip). The assembling can comprise TC bonding.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The TSV die <b>200</b> is shown including pillars <b>325</b> that are capped with solder <b>326</b>. Underfill <b>328</b> is shown between the TSV die <b>200</b> and the package substrate <b>330</b>. The package substrate <b>330</b> is shown including a ball grid array (BGA) comprising a plurality of solder balls <b>331</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Protected stacked die precursor <b>300</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> can be used to form a stacked die device (e.g., system in package (SIP)) including TC bonding the stacked die precursor <b>300</b> to a workpiece. The protective layer <b>231</b>(<i>b</i>) on the bottomside <b>210</b> of the TSV die <b>200</b> is partially or completely removed to expose the TSV tips <b>217</b> for subsequent bonding. A top IC die can be assembled onto the exposed TSV tips <b>217</b> of the TSV die <b>200</b>. In one embodiment the top IC die comprises a memory die, and the TSV die <b>200</b> comprises a logic die.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In another embodiment the top die comprises an IC die stack comprising a plurality of stacked IC die that are bonded to one another. As described above, the reduced warpage of the TSV die <b>200</b> following TC bonding provided by the protective layer described above can also reduce failures with top die assembly onto the protruding TSV tips due to loss of co-planarity. Overmolding can follow, and then singulation to form a plurality of stacked die devices. When the workpiece comprises a package substrate, method can further comprise attaching a BGA of solder balls to the bottom of the workpiece before singulation.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The active circuitry formed on the substrate having a semiconductor surface comprises circuit elements that may generally include transistors, diodes, capacitors, and resistors, as well as signal lines and other electrical conductors that interconnect the various circuit elements to provide an IC circuit function. As used herein &#x201c;provide an IC circuit function&#x201d; refers to circuit functions from ICs, that for example may include an application specific integrated circuit (ASIC), a digital signal processor, a radio frequency chip, a memory, a microcontroller and a system-on-a-chip or a combination thereof. Disclosed embodiments can be integrated into a variety of process flows to form a variety of devices and related products. The semiconductor substrates may include various elements therein and/or layers thereon. These can include barrier layers, other dielectric layers, device structures, active elements and passive elements, including source regions, drain regions, bit lines, bases, emitters, collectors, conductive lines, conductive vias, etc. Moreover, disclosed embodiments can be used in a variety of semiconductor device fabrication processes including bipolar, CMOS, BiCMOS and MEMS processes.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Those skilled in the art to which this disclosure relates will appreciate that many other embodiments and variations of embodiments are possible within the scope of the claimed invention, and further additions, deletions, substitutions and modifications may be made to the described embodiments without departing from the scope of this disclosure.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>I claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method of protecting through substrate via (TSV) die from bonding damage, comprising:
<claim-text>providing a substrate comprising a plurality of TSV die, said plurality of TSV die having a topside including active circuitry, a bottomside, and a plurality of TSVs comprising an inner metal core that reaches from said topside to protruding TSV tips that extend out from said bottomside;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming or applying a protective layer on said bottomside including between and over said protruding TSV tips; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>bonding said TSV die with said topside down onto a workpiece having a workpiece surface and said bottomside up and in contact with a bond head, wherein said protective layer prevents said bond head from making direct contact to said protruding TSV tips, wherein said TSV tips include a metal cap thereon comprising at least one metal layer that includes a metal that is not in said inner metal core.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising singulating said substrate into a plurality of said TSV die before said bonding.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said forming said protective layer comprises a spin-on process, and at least one curing process subsequent to said spin-on process.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said workpiece comprises an organic substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said protective layer is a blanket layer that substantially planarizes said bottomside of said TSV die.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A method of protecting through substrate via (TSV) die from bonding damage, comprising:
<claim-text>providing a substrate comprising a plurality of TSV die, said plurality of TSV die having a topside including active circuitry, a bottomside, and a plurality of TSVs comprising an inner metal core that reaches from said topside to protruding TSV tips that extend out from said bottomside;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming or applying a protective layer on said bottomside including between and over said protruding TSV tips; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>bonding said TSV die with said topside down onto a workpiece having a workpiece surface and said bottomside up and in contact with a bond head, wherein said protective layer prevents said bond head from making direct contact to said protruding TSV tips, wherein said workpiece comprises an organic substrate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, further comprising singulating said substrate into a plurality of said TSV die before said bonding.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein said protective layer is a blanket layer that substantially planarizes said bottomside of said TSV die.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein said forming said protective layer comprises a spin-on process, and at least one curing process subsequent to said spin-on process.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein said workpiece is mounted to a carrier wafer during said bonding.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A method of protecting through substrate via (TSV) die from bonding damage, comprising:
<claim-text>providing a substrate comprising a plurality of TSV die, said plurality of TSV die having a topside including active circuitry, a bottomside, and a plurality of TSVs comprising an inner metal core that reaches from said topside to protruding TSV tips that extend out from said bottomside;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming or applying a protective layer on said bottomside including between and over said protruding TSV tips;</claim-text>
<claim-text>bonding said TSV die with said topside down onto a workpiece having a workpiece surface and said bottomside up and in contact with a bond head, wherein said protective layer prevents said bond head from making direct contact to said protruding TSV tips;</claim-text>
<claim-text>removing at least a portion of said protective layer to expose said plurality of TSV tips after said bonding; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>bonding a top die having bonding features to said plurality of TSV tips on said TSV die after said expose, wherein said removing comprises a dry etch.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein said forming said protective layer comprises a spin-on process, and at least one curing process subsequent to said spin-on process.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further comprising singulating said substrate into a plurality of said TSV die before said bonding.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein said workpiece comprises an organic substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein said protective layer is a blanket layer that substantially planarizes said bottomside of said TSV die.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein said workpiece is mounted to a carrier wafer during said bonding.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. A method of protecting through substrate via (TSV) die from bonding damage, comprising:
<claim-text>providing a substrate comprising a plurality of TSV die, said plurality of TSV die having a topside including active circuitry, a bottomside, and a plurality of TSVs comprising an inner metal core that reaches from said topside to protruding TSV tips that extend out from said bottomside;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming or applying a protective layer on said bottomside including between and over said protruding TSV tips; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>bonding said TSV die with said topside down onto a workpiece having a workpiece surface and said bottomside up and in contact with a bond head, wherein said protective layer prevents said bond head from making direct contact to said protruding TSV tips, wherein said forming said protective layer comprises a spin-on process, and at least one curing process subsequent to said spin-on process.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, further comprising singulating said substrate into a plurality of said TSV die before said bonding.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein said workpiece comprises an organic substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein said protective layer is a blanket layer that substantially planarizes said bottomside of said TSV die.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein said workpiece is mounted to a carrier wafer during said bonding.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. A method of protecting through substrate via (TSV) die from bonding damage, comprising:
<claim-text>providing a substrate comprising a plurality of TSV die, said plurality of TSV die having a topside including active circuitry, a bottomside, and a plurality of TSVs comprising an inner metal core that reaches from said topside to protruding TSV tips that extend out from said bottomside;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming or applying a protective layer on said bottomside including between and over said protruding TSV tips; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>bonding said TSV die with said topside down onto a workpiece having a workpiece surface and said bottomside up and in contact with a bond head, wherein said protective layer prevents said bond head from making direct contact to said protruding TSV tips, wherein said workpiece is mounted to a carrier wafer during said bonding.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, wherein said forming said protective layer comprises a spin-on process, and at least one curing process subsequent to said spin-on process.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, further comprising singulating said substrate into a plurality of said TSV die before said bonding.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text>25. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, wherein said workpiece comprises an organic substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text>26. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, wherein said protective layer is a blanket layer that substantially planarizes said bottomside of said TSV die.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text>27. A method of protecting through substrate via (TSV) die from bonding damage, comprising:
<claim-text>providing a substrate comprising a plurality of TSV die, said plurality of TSV die having a topside including active circuitry, a bottomside, and a plurality of TSVs comprising an inner metal core that reaches from said topside to protruding TSV tips that extend out from said bottomside;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming or applying a protective layer on said bottomside including between and over said protruding TSV tips; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>bonding said TSV die with said topside down onto a workpiece having a workpiece surface and said bottomside up and in contact with a bond head, wherein said protective layer prevents said bond head from making direct contact to said protruding TSV tips, wherein said inner metal core comprises copper and said TSV tips include a metal cap thereon that includes at least one of titanium, nickel, palladium, and gold.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text>28. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00027">claim 27</claim-ref>, wherein said forming said protective layer comprises a spin-on process, and at least one curing process subsequent to said spin-on process.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029" num="00029">
<claim-text>29. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00027">claim 27</claim-ref>, further comprising singulating said substrate into a plurality of said TSV die before said bonding.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030" num="00030">
<claim-text>30. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00027">claim 27</claim-ref>, wherein said workpiece comprises an organic substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031" num="00031">
<claim-text>31. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00027">claim 27</claim-ref>, wherein said protective layer is a blanket layer that substantially planarizes said bottomside of said TSV die.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032" num="00032">
<claim-text>32. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00027">claim 27</claim-ref>, wherein said workpiece is mounted to a carrier wafer during said bonding. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
