<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622695-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622695</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12583024</doc-number>
<date>20090812</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>1153</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>25</main-group>
<subgroup>24</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4152141</main-classification>
<further-classification>415220</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Flow trim for vane-axial fans</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4221546</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Papst et al.</name>
<date>19800900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>417354</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4780052</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Pradelle</name>
<date>19881000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>415119</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6953320</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Davis et al.</name>
<date>20051000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>415147</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0073008</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Penlesky et al.</name>
<date>20060400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>415  1</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0237168</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Belady et al.</name>
<date>20061000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>16510433</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0020098</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Foster et al.</name>
<date>20070100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>415220</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>11</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4151731</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4152141</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4152181</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4152191</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>415220</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>415221</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>415912</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4174231</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>41742314</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110038724</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110217</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Decker</last-name>
<first-name>John J.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Cypress</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Balan</last-name>
<first-name>Chellappa</first-name>
<address>
<city>Niskayuna</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lawless</last-name>
<first-name>Patrick B.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Pismo Beach</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Decker</last-name>
<first-name>John J.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Cypress</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Balan</last-name>
<first-name>Chellappa</first-name>
<address>
<city>Niskayuna</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lawless</last-name>
<first-name>Patrick B.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Pismo Beach</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Query, Jr.</last-name>
<first-name>Henry C.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Xcelaero Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>San Luis Obispo</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Look</last-name>
<first-name>Edward</first-name>
<department>3745</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Davis</last-name>
<first-name>Jason</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A fan comprises a fan housing which includes a fan inlet, a motor which is connected to the fan housing, and an impeller which is removably connected to the motor. The impeller includes an impeller hub, a number of impeller blades which extend radially outwardly from the impeller hub, an impeller leading edge, an impeller trailing edge and an impeller tip. The fan housing includes an inlet shroud which is positioned over the impeller. The inlet shroud comprises an upstream end portion within which the fan inlet is formed and a downstream end portion which is removably connected to a separate portion of the fan housing. The inlet shroud further includes a first section which extends axially from the upstream end portion to approximately the impeller leading edge, a second section which extends axially from the first section to approximately the impeller trailing edge, and a third section which extends axially from the second section to approximately the downstream end portion. The second section comprises a configuration which conforms to the configuration of the impeller tip, and the third section comprises a radius which increases from approximately the upstream end of the third section to approximately the downstream end of the third section.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="167.22mm" wi="151.38mm" file="US08622695-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="189.82mm" wi="150.96mm" file="US08622695-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="207.09mm" wi="122.26mm" file="US08622695-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="186.77mm" wi="151.05mm" file="US08622695-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="215.82mm" wi="190.84mm" file="US08622695-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates generally to vane-axial fans. In particular, the invention relates to a vane-axial fan whose flow characteristics may be changed by modifying its impeller and inlet shroud so that the operation of the fan will remain stable for reduced flow requirements.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Typical vane-axial cooling fans include a motor-driven impeller which propels a stream of air through a fan housing. Such fans may include an outlet guide vane assembly which is positioned downstream of the impeller and acts to both de-swirl and increase the static pressure of the air. These fans may further include a diffuser section which is located downstream of the outlet guide vane assembly and functions to decelerate and thereby further increase the static pressure of the air.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Generally, a cooling fan is designed to meet a specific flow and pressure rise requirement, which is called the design point, for a specific rotational speed, which is referred to as the design speed. At a particular design speed, the flow and pressure rise are related by the fan's characteristic curve, an example of which is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The characteristic curve reveals that when a low pressure rise is required, the fan will deliver a high flow, but as the required pressure rise increases, the flow delivered will decrease. However, as the required pressure rise reaches a certain point, the fan will exhibit flow instability, which is commonly called stall. In many applications this instability may be potentially hazardous, and operation at the required design point is therefore not allowed. Instead, a different fan design will have to be used which is capable of producing the required pressure rise at a lower flow.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In accordance with the present invention, a fan is provided which is capable of producing a required pressure rise while maintaining stable operation. The fan comprises a fan housing which includes a fan inlet; a motor which is connected to the fan housing; and an impeller which is removably connected to the motor. The impeller comprises an impeller hub, a number of impeller blades which extend radially outwardly from the impeller hub, an impeller leading edge, an impeller trailing edge and an impeller tip. The fan housing includes an inlet shroud which is positioned over the impeller. The inlet shroud includes an upstream end portion within which the fan inlet is formed and a downstream end portion which is removably connected to a separate portion of the fan housing. The inlet shroud further includes a first section which extends axially from the upstream end portion to approximately the impeller leading edge, a second section which extends axially from the first section to approximately the impeller trailing edge, and a third section which extends axially from the second section to approximately the downstream end portion. Also, the second section comprises a configuration which conforms to the configuration of the impeller tip, and the third section comprises a radius which increases from approximately the upstream end of the third section to approximately the downstream end of the third section.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In accordance with one embodiment of the invention, the second section comprises a radius which is generally constant from approximately the upstream end of the second section to approximately the downstream end of the second section.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In accordance with another embodiment of the invention, the second section comprises a radius which increases from approximately the upstream end of the second section to approximately the downstream end of the second section. For example, the radius of the second section may increase linearly from approximately the upstream end of the second section to approximately the downstream end of the second section. In another example, the radius of the second section may increase non-linearly from approximately the upstream end of the second section to approximately the downstream end of the second section.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In accordance with yet another embodiment of the invention, the downstream end portion of the inlet shroud is removably connected to an outlet guide vane assembly which is connected to the motor. Also, the third section defines an intermediate diffuser section between the impeller and the outlet guide vane assembly. Furthermore, the intermediate diffuser section may comprise an area ratio of about 1.2 or greater.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In accordance with a further embodiment of the invention, a fan is provided which comprises a fan housing which includes a fan inlet; a motor which is connected to the fan housing; and an impeller which is removably connected to motor. The impeller comprises an impeller hub, a number of impeller blades which extend radially outwardly from the impeller hub, an impeller leading edge, an impeller trailing edge and an impeller tip. The fan housing includes an inlet shroud which is positioned over the impeller. The inlet shroud includes an upstream end portion within which the fan inlet is formed and a downstream end portion which is removably connected to a separate portion of the fan housing. The inlet shroud further includes a first section which extends axially from the fan inlet to approximately the impeller leading edge, a second section which extends axially from the first section to approximately the impeller trailing edge, and a third section which extends axially from the second section to approximately the downstream end portion. Also, the impeller blades comprise a diameter which increases from the impeller leading edge to the impeller trailing edge, and the second section comprises a configuration which conforms to the configuration of the impeller tip.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In accordance with another embodiment of the invention the diameter of the impeller blades increases linearly from the impeller leading edge to the impeller trailing edge.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In accordance with yet another embodiment of the invention, the diameter of the impeller blades increases non-linearly from the impeller leading edge to the impeller trailing edge.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In accordance with a further embodiment of the invention, the third section comprises a radius which increases from approximately the upstream end of the third section to approximately the downstream end of the third section. Also, the third section defines an intermediate diffuser section immediately downstream of the impeller blades. Furthermore, the intermediate diffuser section may comprise an area ratio of about 1.2 or greater.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The present invention is also directed to a method for altering the performance of a fan having a fan housing, a motor which is connected to the fan housing and a first impeller which is connected to the motor, the first impeller comprising a plurality of first impeller blades which define a first impeller tip and the fan housing comprising a removable first inlet shroud which is positioned over the first impeller. The method comprises the steps of providing a second impeller which comprises a plurality of second impeller blades that define a second impeller tip; providing a second inlet shroud which comprises a configuration that conforms to the configuration of the second impeller tip; removing the first impeller from the motor and the first inlet shroud from the fan housing; and connecting the second impeller to the motor and the second inlet shroud to the fan housing.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In accordance with one embodiment of the invention, the average diameter of the second impeller blades is smaller than the average diameter of the first impeller blades. In addition, the second impeller tip may comprise a generally cylindrical configuration, a generally conical configuration, or a curved configuration, among other configurations.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Thus, the cooling fan of the present invention comprises a matched impeller and inlet shroud which allow the fan to achieve a higher pressure rise at a lower flow. This enables the cooling fan to meet a higher pressure rise requirement while maintaining stable flow. In addition, the impeller tip may be designed with various configurations to meet a variety of pressure rise requirements while maintaining stable flow.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Also, the method of the present invention allows the impeller and inlet shroud to be modified as a matched pair, with the magnitude of the modification depending on the amount of flow reduction required. In accordance with this method, the remainder of the fan is unchanged. Thus, a particular fan may be tuned for various system impedances by substituting only two parts, namely, the impeller and the inlet shroud. Consequently, a single fan design can be optimized to suit many different applications, saving the additional design and manufacturing costs which are normally associated with multiple designs.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">These and other objects and advantages of the present invention will be made apparent from the following detailed description with reference to the accompanying drawings. In the drawings, the same reference numbers are used to denote similar components in the various embodiments.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a cross-sectional view of a prior art vane axial cooling fan;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a graph depicting the flow characteristics of the fan of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a cross-sectional view of an exemplary vane axial cooling fan in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a graph comparing the flow characteristics of the fan of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> with the fan of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross-sectional view of an exemplary vane axial cooling fan in accordance with another embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The present invention is applicable to a variety of air movers. For purposes of brevity, however, it will be described in the context of an exemplary vane-axial cooling fan. Nevertheless, a person of ordinary skill in the art will readily appreciate how the teachings of the present invention can be applied to other types of air movers. Therefore, the following description should not be construed to limit the scope of the present invention in any manner.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a representative prior art cooling fan, generally <b>10</b>, is shown to comprise a tubular fan housing <b>12</b>, a motor <b>14</b> which is supported within the fan housing <b>12</b>, an impeller <b>16</b> which is driven by the motor <b>14</b>, and an outlet guide vane assembly <b>18</b> which extends radially between the motor <b>14</b> and the fan housing <b>12</b>. The cooling fan <b>10</b> may also include a diffuser section <b>20</b> which is located downstream of the outlet guide vane assembly <b>18</b> and which includes a diffuser tube <b>22</b> that is connected to or formed integrally with the fan housing <b>12</b> and a tail cone <b>24</b> that is connected to or formed integrally with the downstream end of the motor <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The motor <b>14</b> includes a motor housing <b>26</b>, a stator <b>28</b> which is mounted within the motor housing, a rotor <b>30</b> which is positioned within the stator and a rotor shaft <b>32</b> which is connected to the rotor. The rotor shaft <b>32</b> is rotatably supported in a front bearing <b>34</b> which is mounted in the motor housing <b>26</b> and a rear bearing <b>36</b> which may be mounted in, e.g., the tail cone <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The impeller <b>16</b> comprises an impeller hub <b>38</b> and a number of impeller blades <b>40</b> which extend radially outwardly from the impeller hub. Each blade <b>40</b> comprises a leading edge <b>42</b>, a trailing edge <b>44</b> and a tip <b>46</b>. The leading edges <b>42</b> of all the blades <b>40</b> taken together may be considered the leading edge of the impeller <b>16</b>. Likewise, the trailing edges <b>44</b> of all the blades <b>40</b> taken together may be considered the trailing edge of the impeller <b>16</b>. Similarly, the tips <b>46</b> of all the blades <b>40</b> taken together may be considered the tip of the impeller <b>16</b>, or the impeller tip. Each blade <b>40</b> may be considered to comprise a diameter which is defined as twice the radial distance between the centerline C of the impeller and the tip <b>46</b>. This diameter may be constant from the leading edge <b>42</b> to the trailing edge <b>44</b>, as in the impeller <b>16</b>, or it may vary from the leading edge to the trailing edge. Moreover, the impeller tip, or more generally the impeller, may be considered to comprise a configuration which is defined by the variation in the diameter of the blades <b>40</b> from the leading edge <b>42</b> to the trailing edge <b>44</b>. Thus, where as in the impeller <b>16</b> the diameter of the blades <b>40</b> is constant from the leading edge <b>42</b> to the trailing edge <b>44</b>, the impeller tip is considered to be cylindrical.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The impeller hub <b>38</b> includes an axial bore <b>48</b> through which the rotor shaft <b>32</b> extends, and the shaft is secured to the impeller hub by, e.g., a pair of counteracting nuts <b>50</b>, <b>52</b>. The impeller hub <b>38</b> may also include a nose cone <b>54</b>, which in this case is connected to the rotor shaft <b>32</b> by a screw <b>56</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The outlet guide vane assembly <b>18</b> includes an inner ring <b>58</b> which is attached to or formed integrally with the motor housing <b>26</b>, an outer ring <b>60</b> which is connected to or formed integrally with the fan housing <b>12</b> and a plurality of guide vanes <b>62</b> which extend radially between the inner and outer rings. For purposes of the following description, the outer ring <b>60</b> may be considered part of the fan housing <b>12</b>. In addition to its normal function of straightening the air stream produced by the impeller <b>16</b>, the outlet guide vane assembly serves to connect the motor <b>14</b> to the fan housing <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The fan housing <b>12</b> comprises an inlet shroud <b>64</b> which is positioned over the impeller <b>16</b>. The inlet shroud <b>64</b> includes an upstream end portion <b>66</b> within which the fan inlet is formed and a downstream end portion <b>68</b> which is removably connected to a separate portion of the fan housing <b>12</b>. For example, the downstream end portion <b>68</b> may be connected to the outer ring <b>60</b> of the outlet guide vane assembly <b>18</b> by, e.g., a number of screws <b>70</b>. The inlet shroud <b>64</b>, or more precisely the inner surface of the inlet shroud, comprises a generally constant radius R between its upstream and downstream end portions <b>66</b>, <b>68</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In operation, the motor <b>14</b> is energized to spin the impeller <b>16</b> and thereby draw air into and through the fan housing <b>12</b>. The impeller <b>16</b> forces the air through the outlet guide vane assembly <b>18</b>, which redirects the air stream into a substantially axial direction. The diffuser section <b>20</b> receives the air stream from the outlet guide vane assembly <b>18</b> and decelerates it in order to increase the static pressure of the air exiting the fan housing <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a graph depicting the flow characteristics of the cooling fan <b>10</b>. In this graph, curve <b>72</b> represents the characteristic curve of the fan <b>10</b> at a specific operating speed. As shown by the curve <b>72</b>, the performance of the fan <b>10</b> is dependent on the pressure rise across the fan. When a low pressure rise is required, the fan will deliver a high flow. As the required pressure rise increases, the flow delivered decreases until the fan begins to stall, which will occur at about the point <b>74</b>. A stall line <b>76</b> may be plotted using a similar analysis of the characteristic curves for different operating speeds. The stall line <b>76</b> generally delineates between stable and unstable, or stall, regions of operation of the fan.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Normally, if a particular application requires that an existing fan operate at a design point which falls within the unstable region for the required design speed, a different fan design will have to be used. In accordance with the present invention, however, the characteristic curve of an existing fan can be altered by changing or modifying the impeller and the inlet shroud as a matched pair so that the required pressure rise can be achieved at a lower, stable flow.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">One embodiment of a cooling fan which has been constructed in accordance with the principles of the present invention is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. The cooling fan of this embodiment, generally <b>100</b>, is similar to the cooling fan <b>10</b> described above. However, in this embodiment the impeller <b>16</b> and inlet shroud <b>64</b> of the cooling fan <b>10</b> have been removed and replaced with a different impeller <b>102</b> and inlet shroud <b>104</b>. The impeller <b>102</b> and inlet shroud <b>104</b> are designed to provide the cooling fan <b>100</b> with operating characteristics which were not attainable with the cooling fan <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The impeller <b>102</b>, which is similar in many respects to the impeller <b>16</b>, comprises an impeller hub <b>106</b> and a number of impeller blades <b>108</b> which extend radially outwardly from the hub. The impeller hub <b>106</b> may be identical to the impeller hub <b>38</b> of the impeller <b>16</b>, and it may be connected to the rotor shaft <b>32</b> in a similar fashion. As with the blades <b>40</b>, the blades <b>108</b> comprise a generally constant diameter from their leading edge to their trailing edge. However, compared to the blades <b>40</b>, the blades <b>108</b> have been trimmed, i.e., the diameter of the blades <b>108</b> is smaller than the diameter of the blades <b>40</b>. Since the tip of the impeller <b>102</b> is generally cylindrical, the impeller tip may be considered to have been trimmed cylindrically. By &#x201c;trimmed&#x201d; we simply mean that the blades <b>108</b> are shorter than the blades <b>40</b>. This may be achieved by removing the impeller <b>16</b> and reducing the diameter of the blades <b>40</b> by a suitable machining process. Alternatively, the impeller <b>16</b> may be replaced with a new impeller <b>102</b> whose blades <b>108</b> are designed with the desired diameter and configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the inlet shroud <b>104</b> is designed to conform to the impeller <b>102</b>. Thus, the inlet shroud <b>104</b> of this embodiment is designed to have a number of axial sections: a first section <b>110</b> which extends from approximately the upstream end portion <b>66</b> of the inlet shroud to approximately the leading edge of the impeller <b>102</b>, a second section <b>112</b> which extends from the first section to approximately the trailing edge of the impeller, and a third section <b>114</b> which extends from the second section to approximately the downstream end portion <b>62</b> of the inlet shroud. The first and second sections <b>110</b>, <b>112</b> comprise a generally constant radius R<sub>1</sub>, while the radius of the third section <b>114</b> increases, preferably linearly in this embodiment, from the radius R<sub>1 </sub>at the upstream end of the third section to a radius R<sub>2 </sub>at the downstream end of the section. Thus, the second section <b>112</b> comprises a generally cylindrical configuration which conforms to the cylindrical tip of the impeller <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The third section <b>114</b> defines an intermediate diffuser section <b>116</b> between the impeller blades <b>108</b> and the guide vanes <b>62</b> within which the air stream is allowed to expand. In contrast to intermediate diffuser sections of prior art cooling fans, the diffuser section <b>116</b> comprises a much larger area ratio, which is defined as the ratio of the area of the downstream end of the diffuser section, in this case &#x3c0;(R<sub>2</sub><sup>2</sup>&#x2212;r<sub>2</sub><sup>2</sup>), to the area of the upstream end of the diffuser section, in this case &#x3c0;(R<sub>1</sub><sup>2</sup>&#x2212;r<sub>1</sub><sup>2</sup>), where r<sub>1 </sub>is the inner radius of the upstream end of the diffuser section and r<sub>2 </sub>is the inner radius of the downstream end of the diffuser section. In the present invention, the area ratio of the diffuser section <b>116</b> is about 1.2 or greater.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In combination with the impeller <b>102</b>, the multi-sectioned inlet shroud <b>104</b> provides the cooling fan <b>100</b> with operating characteristics which were not attainable with the cooling fan <b>10</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a graph comparing the operating characteristics of the cooling fan <b>100</b> with those of the cooling fan <b>10</b>. This graph shows how the operating characteristics of the cooling fan <b>10</b> are altered when the impeller <b>16</b> and inlet shroud <b>64</b> are removed and replaced with the impeller <b>102</b> and inlet shroud <b>104</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the cooling fan <b>100</b> has a characteristic curve <b>118</b> which is shifted to the left with respect to the characteristic curve <b>72</b> of the fan <b>10</b>. This results in the fan <b>100</b> having a stall line <b>120</b> which is also shifted to the left with respect to the stall line <b>76</b> of the fan <b>10</b>. Consequently, the stall line <b>120</b> will occur at lower flow. As a result, the fan <b>100</b> is able to achieve similar pressure rises at lower flows than the fan <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In accordance with one aspect of the present invention, a number of different cooling fans comprising a variety of operating characteristics can be constructed using a single fan subassembly. Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, for example, it may be seen that the cooling fan <b>10</b> includes a subassembly which is comprised of the motor <b>14</b>, the outlet guide vane assembly <b>18</b> and the optional diffuser section <b>20</b>. The fan <b>10</b> may therefore be assembled by connecting the impeller <b>16</b> to the rotor shaft <b>32</b> and the inlet shroud <b>64</b> to the outer ring <b>60</b> of the outlet guide vane assembly <b>18</b>. In a similar fashion, the cooling fan <b>100</b> may be assembled by connecting the impeller <b>102</b> to the rotor shaft <b>32</b> and the inlet shroud <b>104</b> to the outer ring <b>60</b>. Any number of other fans comprising distinct operating characteristics can be similarly constructed by connecting the appropriate impellers and inlet shrouds to the subassembly of the motor <b>14</b>, the outlet guide vane assembly <b>18</b> and the optional diffuser section <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, for example, another embodiment of a cooling fan which embodies the principles of the present invention is shown. The cooling fan of this embodiment, generally <b>200</b>, comprises an impeller <b>202</b> which is connected to the rotor shaft <b>32</b> and an inlet shroud <b>204</b> which is connected to the outer ring <b>60</b> of the outlet guide vane assembly <b>18</b> of the fan subassembly discussed above. The impeller <b>202</b> comprises an impeller hub <b>206</b> and a number of impeller blades <b>208</b> which extend radially from the impeller hub. In this embodiment, the diameter of the impeller blades <b>208</b> increases, preferably linearly in this embodiment, from the leading edge of the blades to the trailing edge of the blades. Accordingly, the impeller tip comprises a generally conical configuration. However, in this embodiment the average diameter of the impeller blades <b>208</b> is ideally still less than the average diameter of the impeller blades <b>40</b>. The average diameter of the impeller blades may be determined by adding the diameters of the impeller blades at a number of different axial positions between the leading and trailing edges and then dividing this result by the number of positions.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">As with the cooling fan <b>100</b> discussed above, the inlet shroud <b>204</b> of the cooling fan <b>200</b> comprises a number of axial sections: a first section <b>210</b> which extends from approximately the upstream end portion <b>66</b> of the inlet shroud to approximately the leading edge of the impeller <b>202</b>, a second section <b>212</b> which extends from the first section to approximately the trailing edge of the impeller, and a third section <b>214</b> which extends from the second section to approximately the downstream end portion <b>62</b> of the inlet shroud. While, the first section <b>210</b> comprise a generally constant radius R<sub>3</sub>, the radius of the second section <b>212</b> ideally varies to conform to the impeller tip, that is, it increases from the radius R<sub>3 </sub>at the upstream end of the second section to a radius R<sub>4 </sub>at the downstream end of the section. Thus, the second section <b>212</b> comprises a generally conical configuration which conforms to conical impeller tip.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Also, the radius of the third section <b>214</b> increases from the radius R<sub>4 </sub>at the upstream end of the third section to a radius R<sub>5 </sub>at the downstream end of the section. The third section <b>214</b> therefore defines an intermediate diffuser section <b>216</b> between the impeller blades <b>208</b> and the guide vanes <b>56</b> within which the air stream is allowed to expand. As with the diffuser section <b>116</b>, the area ratio of the diffuser section <b>216</b> is about 1.2 or greater.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Thus, it may be seen that a variety of impeller and inlet shroud combinations may be used to construct a cooling fan with desired operating characteristics. Also, although the inlet shroud ideally includes an axial section which conforms to the shape of the impeller tip, the inlet shroud may comprise other axial sections which are configured to achieve a desired affect for a given application. As will be appreciated by those of skill in the art, the operating characteristics of a fan having a specific impeller and inlet shroud configuration may be determined using numerical analysis. Thus, depending on the desired operating characteristics for a particular application, a suitable impeller and inlet shroud may designed.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">As an alternative to the impeller and inlet shroud pairs described above, for example, a cooling fan in accordance with the present invention may comprise an impeller whose tip is curved. In this embodiment, the diameter of the impeller blades increases non-linearly from the leading edge of the blades to the trailing edge of the blades. In addition, the inlet shroud may have an axial section adjacent the blades whose radius varies non-linearly from the upstream end of the section to the downstream end of the section in order to conform to the impeller tip.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In accordance with another feature of the present invention, a cooling fan having desired operating characteristics may be constructed from an existing cooling fan having a compatible subassembly. This may be achieved, for example, by removing the impeller and inlet shroud of the existing cooling fan and replacing them with an impeller and inlet shroud which have been determined, using numerical analysis, for example, to possess the configuration required to provide the fan with the desired operating characteristics. In this manner, an inventory of existing fans having operating characteristics which are no longer desirable can be retrofitted with new impellers and inlet shrouds to make them usable.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">A cooling fan having desired operating characteristics may also be constructed by assembling the appropriate impeller and inlet shroud with an available fan subassembly. In this manner, a fan manufacturer may inventory a large quantity of fan subassemblies and then assemble them with the appropriate impellers and inlet shrouds in order to produce a variety of fans having distinct operating characteristics. This will greatly reduce the cost and complexity of the manufacturing process.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">It should be recognized that, while the present invention has been described in relation to the preferred embodiments thereof, those skilled in the art may develop a wide variation of structural and operational details without departing from the principles of the invention. Therefore, the appended claims are to be construed to cover all equivalents falling within the true scope and spirit of the invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A vane-axial fan which comprises:
<claim-text>a fan housing which includes a fan inlet;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a motor which is connected to the fan housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an impeller which is removably connected to the motor, the impeller comprising an impeller hub, a number of impeller blades which extend radially outwardly from the impeller hub, an impeller leading edge, an impeller trailing edge and an impeller tip;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the fan housing including an inlet shroud which is positioned over the impeller, the inlet shroud including an upstream end portion within which the fan inlet is formed and a downstream end portion which is removably connected to a separate portion of the fan housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the inlet shroud further including a first section which extends axially from the upstream end portion to approximately the impeller leading edge, a second section which extends axially from the first section to approximately the impeller trailing edge, and a third section which extends axially from the second section to approximately the downstream end portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second section comprises a configuration which conforms to the configuration of the impeller tip;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the third section comprises a radius which increases from approximately the upstream end of the third section to approximately the downstream end of the third section;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second section comprises a radius which increases from approximately the upstream end of the second section to approximately the downstream end of the second section; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the radius of the second section increases linearly from approximately the upstream end of the second section to approximately the downstream end of the second section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The fan of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second section comprises a radius which is generally constant from approximately the upstream end of the second section to approximately the downstream end of the second section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The fan of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the downstream end portion of the inlet shroud is removably connected to an outlet guide vane assembly which is connected to the motor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The fan of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the third section defines an intermediate diffuser section between the impeller and the outlet guide vane assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The fan of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the intermediate diffuser section comprises an area ratio of about 1.2 or greater.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A vane-axial fan which comprises:
<claim-text>a fan housing which includes a fan inlet;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a motor which is connected to the fan housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an impeller which is removably connected to the motor, the impeller comprising an impeller hub, a number of impeller blades which extend radially outwardly from the impeller hub, an impeller leading edge, an impeller trailing edge and an impeller tip;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the fan housing including an inlet shroud which is positioned over the impeller, the inlet shroud including an upstream end portion within which the fan inlet is formed and a downstream end portion which is removably connected to a separate portion of the fan housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the inlet shroud further including a first section which extends axially from the fan inlet to approximately the impeller leading edge, a second section which extends axially from the first section to approximately the impeller trailing edge, and a third section which extends axially from the second section to approximately the downstream end portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the impeller blades comprise a diameter which increases continuously from the impeller leading edge to the impeller trailing edge;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second section comprises a configuration which conforms to the configuration of the impeller tip; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the diameter of the impeller blades increases linearly from the impeller leading edge to the impeller trailing edge.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The fan of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the diameter of the impeller blades increases non-linearly from the impeller leading edge to the impeller trailing edge.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The fan of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the third section comprises a radius which increases from approximately the upstream end of the third section to approximately the downstream end of the third section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The fan of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the third section defines an intermediate diffuser section immediately downstream of the impeller blades.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The fan of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the intermediate diffuser section comprises an area ratio of about 1.2 or greater.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The fan of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the downstream end portion of the inlet shroud is removably connected to an outlet guide vane assembly which is connected to the motor. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
