<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623452-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623452</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12965733</doc-number>
<date>20101210</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>421</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>11</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>427129</main-classification>
<further-classification>4288111</further-classification>
<further-classification>257421</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Magnetic random access memory (MRAM) with enhanced magnetic stiffness and method of making same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0098354</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Parkin</name>
<date>20060500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>3603242</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0229111</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Zhao et al.</name>
<date>20090900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 2960308</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0169111</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hu et al.</name>
<date>20110700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257421</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00004">
<othercit>R. Cao et al, IEEE Transactions on Magnetics, vol. 45, n. 10(2009), 3434-3440.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>19</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>427129</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>42881111</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>428839</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4288205</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>428800</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E29323</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120148735</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120614</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Zhou</last-name>
<first-name>Yuchen</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Zhou</last-name>
<first-name>Yuchen</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Imam</last-name>
<first-name>Maryam</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>IPxLAW Group LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Avalanche Technology, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Fremont</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Cleveland</last-name>
<first-name>Michael</first-name>
<department>1712</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Eslami</last-name>
<first-name>Tabassom Tadayyon</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A spin toque transfer magnetic random access memory (STTMRAM) element and a method of manufacturing the same is disclosed having a free sub-layer structure with enhanced internal stiffness. A first free sub-layer is deposited, the first free sub-layer being made partially of boron (B), annealing is performed of the STTMRAM element at a first temperature after depositing the first free sub-layer to reduce the B content at an interface between the first free sub-layer and the barrier layer, the annealing causing a second free sub-layer to be formed on top of the first free sub-layer and being made partially of B, the amount of B of the second free sub-layer being greater than the amount of B in the first free sub-layer. Cooling down the STTMRAM element to a second temperature that is lower than the first temperature and depositing a third free sub-layer directly on top of the second free layer, with the third free sub-layer being made partially of boron (B), wherein the amount of B in the third sub-free layer is less than the amount of B in the second free sub-layer.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="106.51mm" wi="224.11mm" file="US08623452-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="226.23mm" wi="116.67mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623452-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="239.01mm" wi="181.36mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623452-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="235.20mm" wi="134.54mm" file="US08623452-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates generally to magnetic memory elements having magnetic tunnel junctions (MTJ) and particularly to improving the internal magnetic stiffness of the free layer of the MTJ to reduce threshold voltage/current during writing thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Prior Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Magnetic random access memory (MRAM) is rapidly gaining popularity as its use in replacing conventional memory is showing promise. Magnetic tunnel junctions (MTJs), which are essentially the part of the MRAM that store information, include various layers that determine the magnetic behavior of the device. An exemplary MTJ uses spin torque transfer to effectuate a change in the direction of magnetization of one or more free layers in the MTJ. That is, writing bits of information is achieved by using a spin polarized current flowing through the MTJ, instead of using a magnetic field, to change states or program/write/erase/read bits.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In spin torque transfer (STT) MTJ designs, when electrons flow across the MTJ stack in a direction that is perpendicular to the film plane or from the pinned (sometimes referred to as &#x201c;reference&#x201d; or &#x201c;fixed&#x201d;) layer to the free (or storage) layer, spin torque from electrons transmitted from the pinned layer to the free layer orientate the free layer magnetization in a direction that is parallel to that of the reference or pinned layer. When electrons flow from the free layer to the pinned layer, spin torque from electrons that are reflected from the pinned layer back into the free layer orientate the free layer magnetization to be anti-parallel relative to the magnetization of the pinned layer. Thus, controlling the electron (current) flow direction, direction of magnetization of the free layer magnetization is switched. Resistance across the MTJ stack changes between low and high states when the free layer magnetization is parallel or anti-parallel relative to that of the pinned layer.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">However, a problem that is consistently experienced and that prevents advancement of the use of MTJs is the threshold voltage or current used to switch the free layer magnetization. That is, such current and threshold voltage requirements are currently too high to allow practical applications of the spin torque transfer based MTJ.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Existing MTJ designs include a free layer, generally made of a cobolt-iron-boron (CoFeB) alloy, formed on top of a barrier layer, which is typically formed on top of the pinned (or fixed) layer. Prior to annealing, the thickness of the CoFeB is typically approximately one to a few nanometers. After annealing, the free layer separates into two distinct layers, one of such layers, closest or adjacent to the barrier layer, is formed with CoFe whereas the other of such layers, farthest and removed from the barrier layer, is made of CoFeB with a rich boron (B) content. The thickness of these layers is typically approximately 0.5 nm or less for the layer that is made of CoFe and the other one of the layers that has a rich B content has a thickness that is the thickness of the free layer minus the thickness of the layer that is made of CoFe, or in the example provided above, 2 nm. Due to this formation, when annealing is performed, such MTJs exhibit a considerable low stiffness. Thus, during programming or writing to the MTJ, the amount of threshold voltage required to switch the MTJ is undesirably high. For example, an MTJ such as that described above with the material an increase in internal stiffness of approximately 0.8&#xd7;10-6 erg/cm, in its CoFeB part of its free layer after annealing, with a normalized switching reducing approximately 16%, in large part due to the layer of the free layer that is farthest removed from the barrier layer, the CoFeB part of the free layer.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Thus, the need arises for enhanced internal stiffness of the free layer of a spin torque transfer-based MTJ, used in a magnetic memory element, to reduce the threshold voltage or current required to switch the free layer magnetization of such MTJs.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Briefly, a spin toque transfer magnetic random access memory (STTMRAM) element and a method of manufacturing the same is disclosed having a free layer structure with enhanced internal stiffness. Some of the steps of manufacturing include depositing a first free sub-layer on top of a barrier layer, the first free sub-layer being made partially of boron (B), annealing the STTMRAM element at a first temperature after depositing the first free sub-layer to reduce the B content at an interface between the first free sub-layer and the barrier layer. The annealing causes a second free sub-layer to be formed on top of the first free sub-layer, the second free sub-layer being made partially of B, the amount of B of the second free sub-layer being greater than the amount of B in the first free sub-layer. Cooling down the STTMRAM element to a second temperature that is lower than the first temperature and depositing a third free sub-layer directly on top of the second free sub-layer, with the third free sub-layer being made partially of boron (B), wherein the amount of B in the third sub-free layer is less than the amount of B in the second sub-free layer or void of B.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">These and other objects and advantages of the present invention will no doubt become apparent to those skilled in the art after having read the following detailed description of the various embodiments illustrated in the several figures of the drawing.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">IN THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows the process of enhancing the free layer of a STTMRAM <b>10</b>, using a method of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2(</figref><i>a</i>) shows the relevant portion of a STTMRAM element <b>50</b>, in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2(</figref><i>b</i>) shows a graph <b>60</b>, representing the switching characteristics of the element <b>50</b> vs. the switching characteristics of a prior art STTMRAM element, both having CFB layer exchange of 1&#xd7;10<sup>&#x2212;6 </sup>erg/cm, and further shows a graph <b>62</b>, representing the switching characteristics of the element <b>50</b> vs. the switching characteristics of a prior art STTMRAM element, both having CFB layer exchange of 0.2&#xd7;10<sup>&#x2212;6 </sup>erg/cm.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a flow chart of the steps performed in manufacturing the various embodiments of the present invention, in accordance with a method of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In the following description of the embodiments, reference is made to the accompanying drawings that form a part hereof, and in which is shown by way of illustration of the specific embodiments in which the invention may be practiced. It is to be understood that other embodiments may be utilized because structural changes may be made without departing from the scope of the present invention. It should be noted that the figures discussed herein are not drawn to scale and thicknesses of lines are not indicative of actual sizes.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In an embodiment of the present invention, a spin toque transfer magnetic random access memory (STTMRAM) element and a method of manufacturing the same is disclosed. Relevant layers of the STTMRAM element include a free layer structure, having enhanced internal stiffness, and made of sub-layers using an annealing process. In forming the free layer structure, a first free layer is deposited on top of a barrier layer, the first free layer being made partially of boron (B), then, an annealing process is performed on the STTMRAM element at a first temperature and after depositing the first free sub-layer to reduce the B-content of the deposited first free sub-layer, at an interface between the first free sub-layer and the barrier layer. This annealing process causes the B in the first free sub-layer to migrate from the interface between the first free sub-layer and the barrier layer to the top of the first free sub-layer and away from the barrier layer. The STTMRAM element is then cooled to a second temperature that is lower than the first temperature and a second free sub-layer is deposited directly on top of the first free sub-layer, with the second free sub-layer being made partially of B or void of B, wherein the amount of B in the second sub-free layer is less than the amount of B in the first free layer.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In an alternative embodiment, after deposition of the second free sub-layer, another annealing process is performed using a third temperature that is higher than the second temperature and lower than the first temperature.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows the process of enhancing the free layer of a spin torque transfer magnetic random access memory (STTMRAM) element <b>10</b>, using a method of the present invention. The STTMRAM element <b>10</b> is shown initially (at the far left of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) to include a bottom electrode <b>16</b> on top of which is formed an anti-ferromagnetic (AFM) layer <b>18</b> on top of which is shown formed a pinned layer <b>20</b> (sometimes referred to as &#x201c;pinning layer&#x201d;), on top of which is shown formed an exchange coupling layer <b>22</b>, on top of which is shown formed a reference layer <b>24</b> on top of which is formed a barrier layer <b>26</b> on top of which is formed a (magnetic) free layer <b>28</b>. The pinned layer <b>24</b>, the barrier layer <b>26</b> and the (magnetic) free layer <b>28</b> (in addition to other free layers directly formed on top of the free layer <b>28</b>, such as the free layer <b>30</b>) are collectively referred to as &#x201c;magnetic tunnel junction (MTJ)&#x201d;. Deposition of the layer <b>28</b> on top of the layer <b>26</b> forms a &#x201c;magneto-resistive junction&#x201d;. It is noted that the layers <b>24</b>, <b>28</b>, <b>29</b> and <b>30</b> are each, at times, referred to herein as a &#x201c;magnetic layer&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In alternative embodiments, the element <b>10</b> (and the element <b>50</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2(</figref><i>a</i>)) is a magneto-resistive (MR) element.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The layer <b>26</b> (also referred to as a &#x201c;junction layer&#x201d;), in some embodiments, is made of oxide and in other embodiments is metallic.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The pinned layer <b>20</b> and the exchange coupling layer <b>22</b> and the reference layer <b>24</b>, which is also commonly referred to as the reference layer (sometimes referred to as &#x201c;pinned layer&#x201d; or &#x201c;fixed layer&#x201d;), are collectively referred to as a &#x201c;synthetic-antiferromagnetic (SAF) layer&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The layer <b>28</b> includes B as one of its material, as discussed below.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Upon annealing, as will be described in further detail below, the STTMRAM element <b>10</b> takes on the structure shown in the middle of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> with the free layer <b>28</b> becoming a layer that is formed of sub-layers, an interface layer <b>29</b>, immediately abutting the barrier layer <b>26</b>, and a boron-rich layer <b>30</b>. The layer <b>29</b> in one embodiment of the present invention has an effective thickness that is less than 1 nm and further has a lower boron (B) content than the free layer <b>28</b> and is positioned directly on top of the layer <b>26</b>, effectively interfacing with this layer. The layer <b>30</b>, does not interface with the layer <b>26</b> and is in fact positioned above the layer <b>29</b> and accordingly removed from the layer <b>26</b>. The layer <b>30</b> has a higher boron (B) content than the free layer <b>28</b>. Subsequently, as shown on the far right side of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, another free layer, free layer <b>32</b> is deposited directly on top of the free layer <b>30</b>. The layer <b>32</b>, in one embodiment of the present invention has no B content and in another embodiment, has a B content that is less B content than that of the layer <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">It is understood that layers typically formed on top of a free layer in STTMRAM elements are formed on top of the free layer <b>32</b>. An example of such a layer is a top electrode.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The process shown and described relative to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> serves to enhance the effective within-film exchange strength of the free layer.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The steps discussed above, relative to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, are now described in further detail with exemplary materials disclosed regarding each of the layers. The barrier layer <b>26</b>, in an exemplary embodiment, is made of magnesium oxide (MgO). The free layer <b>28</b>, in exemplary embodiments is made, but not limited to, cobolt (Co), iron (Fe), nickel (Ni), boron (B), tantalum (Ta), titanium (Ti), copper (Cu), zirconium (Zr), chromium (Cr) and platinum (Pt). The free layer <b>28</b> may be formed as a uniform composition single layer or formed as a multi-layer structure where the layer adjacent to and on top of the barrier layer <b>26</b> is a different composition than the layer further away from the barrier layer <b>26</b>. One example of such multi-layer structure of the free layer <b>28</b> can be, but not limited to, a thin CoFeBX layer, with X being any of Ni, B, Ta, Ti, Cu, Zr, Cr and Pt, that is in one example less than 1 nanometers (nm) in thickness, with its Fe content being approximately 60%. In another embodiment, such a layer has a thicker of more than 1 nano meters CoFeBY layer with Fe content &#x2266;40%, where X and Y can be any of Ni, B, Ta, Ti, Cu, Zr, Cr and Pt.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">During the annealing step discussed above, the barrier layer <b>26</b> and the free layer <b>28</b> are annealed and as such are referred to herein as the &#x201c;annealed structure&#x201d;. Annealing is performed under normal MTJ annealing condition, which is annealing the structure under a first temperature that is approximately more than or equal to 200 degrees Celsius (&#xb0; C.) and less than or equal to 500&#xb0; C., and preferably 270&#xb0; C.&#x2dc;350&#xb0; C. for a period of a few minutes up to a few hours. During annealing, there may also be a first magnetic field applied to the annealed structure.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">After the annealing step, the STTMRAM element <b>10</b> is cooled down to a second temperature that is lower than the first temperature. Due to the annealing process, the barrier layer <b>26</b> forms a crystalline structure and the free layer <b>28</b> also forms crystalline structure at the interface between the barrier layer <b>26</b> and the free layer <b>28</b> with B being pushed away from the interface and forming the layer <b>29</b> in structure <b>12</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, and another B rich layer <b>30</b> above layer <b>29</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The free layer <b>29</b> has lower B content, and the free layer <b>30</b> has a higher B content, than that of the free layer <b>28</b>. At the second temperature, the free layer <b>32</b> is deposited on top of the free layer <b>30</b>. As exemplary materials, the free layer <b>32</b> is made of: Co, Fe, Ni, B, Ta, Ti, Cu, Zr, Cr or Pt. The free layer <b>32</b> typically has between 80%&#x2dc;100% content of any of the following materials: Co, Fe and Ni. After deposition of the free layer <b>32</b>, additional non-magnetic and magnetic layers that are required to make a functional the STTMRAM element <b>10</b> can be further deposited on top of the free layer <b>32</b>. The free layer <b>32</b> may also be a multi-layered free layer and in such example, is made of two free layers. In fact, additional free layers, either in the form of a single layer or in the form of multiple layers may be utilized with each such layer formed on top of an adjacent free layer.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">After completion of deposition of the rest of the STTMRAM element <b>10</b>, as shown and discussed relative to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the entire STTMRAM element may optionally undergo another annealing step with a third temperature that is higher than the second temperature but lower than the first temperature.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">For a typical MgO-based MTJ, the free layer is composed of Co, Fe, B, and sometimes other materials, for example, Ti, Ta, Cr, Ni, is deposited adjacent to the barrier layer <b>26</b>, which is usually amorphous after deposition. After a high temperature (&#x3e;200&#xb0; C.) anneal process of the methods described herein, the barrier layer <b>26</b> forms a lattice structure, which in turn helps form a thin layer of CoFe with a lattice structure matching that of the barrier layer to be formed at the interface between the free layer and the barrier layer. The matching lattice structures of the barrier layer and free layer produces a high magneto-resistance signal through the barrier layer in a typical MgO-based MTJ. However, the free layer <b>30</b> that is away from the free layer-barrier layer interface (&#x201c;upper free layer&#x201d;) typically has less Co and Fe content than when initially deposited because B is depleted from the interface region and migrates to the upper free layer. With B content increasing in the upper free layer after annealing, the upper free layer is regarded more amorphous than after deposition, where CoFe crystalline nano-structures may exist in the upper free layer in uniform distribution but random orientation. Neighboring CoFe crystals affect each other less through crystalline exchange coupling, which requires overlapping of electron clouds from adjacent atoms, due to increased spacing by B and random orientation. Rather, they affect each other more through magneto-static coupling, which is a much weaker energy term than exchange energy. With weak exchange interaction between CoFe crystals within the upper free layer, dynamic switching process of the upper free layer together with the interface layer <b>28</b> is more chaotic and less uniform, where higher order spin-wave modes can be easily excited due to weak effective exchange energy within the free layer. The higher order spin-wave mode is generally an energy relaxation path, which will adversely slow down the switching process of the free layer by transferring the spin torque injected energy to other higher order spin-wave modes not related to the switching process. Therefore, it is beneficial if the effective internal exchange energy (or internal stiffness) of the free layer (or switching layer, including layer <b>29</b> and layer <b>30</b>) can be increased so that higher order spin wave mode can be suppressed and energy dissipation during switching process can be reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In accordance with the various embodiments of the present invention, easier switching of the storage magnetic layer by spin torque current with reducing effective damping of the free layer is realized by increasing the effective internal stiffness of the free layer, random modes during switching are suppressed and coherent mode is enhanced. With more coherent behavior of the magnetization of the free layer during switching process, spin torque efficiency is increased, effective damping is dropped and switching becomes easier. Any STTMRAM element design with any shape is contemplated. This method is to achieve lower switching current in STTMRAM by quenching the additional damping effect from low internal stiffness of the free layer.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2(</figref><i>a</i>) shows the relevant portion of a STTMRAM element <b>50</b>, in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention. The STTMRAM element <b>50</b> is analogous to the STTMRAM element <b>14</b> except that the barrier layer and the free layer of the STTMRAM element <b>50</b> are shown and described in more particular detail, as is discussed below.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The STTMRAM element <b>50</b> is shown to include a barrier layer <b>52</b>, which would be formed on top of the layer <b>24</b> of the element <b>14</b>, in addition to a free sub-layer <b>54</b>, formed on top of the layer <b>52</b>, a free sub-layer <b>56</b>, formed on top of the sub-layer <b>54</b>, and a free sub-layer <b>58</b>, formed on top of the sub-layer <b>56</b>. The sub-layers <b>54</b>-<b>58</b> form the free layer of the STTMRAM element <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">As in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the element <b>50</b> may be a magneto-resistive (MR) element in some embodiments and the layer <b>52</b> may be a &#x201c;junction layer&#x201d; made of oxide or is metallic. Deposition of the layer <b>54</b> on top of the layer <b>52</b> forms a magneto-resistive junction.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Upon the completion of an annealing step, such as described relative to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the free layer of the STTMRAM element <b>50</b> is transformed into multiple sub-layers, namely, an interface layer (also referred to herein as &#x201c;free sub-layer&#x201d;) <b>54</b>, the free sub-layer <b>56</b> and the free sub-layer <b>58</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2(</figref><i>b</i>). The free sub-layer <b>54</b> is made of a CoFe composition having a thickness of approximately 0.5 nm, with B being mostly depleted. The sub-layer <b>56</b> becomes rich in B and is directly on top of the sub-layer <b>54</b> and is approximately 1.3 nm in thickness. The sub-layer <b>58</b>, which is formed directly on top of the sub-layer <b>56</b> is made of CoFe and has an approximate thickness of 0.3 nm.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The element <b>50</b> achieves stronger free layer within-film exchange strength with the benefit of the sub-layer <b>58</b> being capped on top of the sub-layer <b>56</b>. This is at least in part realized by the notion that the total Mst, which is the saturation moment (Ms) times thickness, of the free layer (including sub-layer <b>54</b>, <b>56</b> and <b>58</b>), after annealing, is advantageously the same as those of prior art STTMRAM elements. With the MTJ shape of the element <b>50</b> not changing, effective anisotropy of the free layer and thermal stability related to the effective anisotropy also remain unchanged. However, because the sub-layer <b>58</b> has a within-film exchange of Aex=2&#xd7;10<sup>&#x2212;6 </sup>erg/cm, the free layer's effective within-film exchange is higher than that experienced by prior art STTMRAM elements because the sub-layer <b>56</b>, which is rich in B, is coupled to the sub-layers <b>54</b> and <b>58</b>, which are high exchange CoFe layers on either side of the sub-layer <b>56</b> and the high exchange CoFe layers, i.e. sub-layers <b>54</b> and <b>58</b>, determine more of the dynamics of the switching process.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2(</figref><i>b</i>) shows a graph <b>60</b>, representing the switching characteristics of the element <b>50</b> vs. the switching characteristics of a prior art STTMRAM element, both having CFB layer exchange of 1&#xd7;10<sup>&#x2212;6 </sup>erg/cm, and further shows a graph <b>62</b>, representing the switching characteristics of the element <b>50</b> vs. the switching characteristics of a prior art STTMRAM element, both having CFB layer exchange of 0.2&#xd7;10<sup>&#x2212;6 </sup>erg/cm. The x-axis of each graph represents the normalized switching voltage and the y-axis shows the normalized MTJ resistance. The solid lines with circles prior art and the dashed lines with dots represent the element <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The curves of each graph <b>60</b> and <b>62</b> are the MTJ resistance after application of a given voltage for 5 nanoseconds (ns) to try to switch the MTJ from high resistance state to low resistance state. The step function shape of each of the graphs <b>60</b> and <b>62</b> represents a switching event, where the voltage at which the switching event occurs is the switching voltage threshold. By using the sub-layer <b>58</b>, the switching voltage is reduced by 9% over prior art in the case of free layer Aex=1&#xd7;10<sup>&#x2212;6 </sup>erg/cm, as shown by the graph <b>60</b>, and 16% over prior art in the case of free layer Aex=0.2&#xd7;10<sup>&#x2212;6 </sup>erg/cm, as shown by the graph <b>62</b>. Thus, using the sub-layer <b>58</b>, the lower the B-rich free layer within-film exchange, the larger the performance improvement realized by reduction of the switching voltage. In fact, the switching voltages as shown by the dashed curves in the graphs <b>60</b> and <b>62</b> show little difference, indicating that when the sub-layer <b>58</b> is used, the sub-layer <b>56</b>'s within-film exchange strength is not a critical parameter any more.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">However, the structure whose behavior is exhibited as shown by the graph <b>62</b> is not readily realizable with existing film processing technology. For example, if the sub-layer <b>58</b> of 0.3 nm thickness is deposited directly on top of the sub-layer <b>56</b> and annealing is performed on the film to form the sub-layer <b>54</b> of 0.5 nm in thickness and the B-rich sub-layer <b>56</b> of 1.3 nm in thickness, the high temperature used to obtain a suitable barrier layer and CoFe crystalline structure will inevitably cause B migration into the sub-layer <b>58</b> causing it to be undesirably amorphous-like and reducing the within-film exchange of the sub-layer <b>58</b>. Thus, the &#x201c;glue&#x201d; purpose by the CoFe-2 layer is defeated. In accordance with a method of the present invention, a two-step deposition process is disclosed to achieve the switching current density reduction as in the various embodiments thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">To take advantage of lower switching voltage threshold, the free layer's effective within-film exchange needs to be increased. However, since CoFeB is required for crystalline forming of CoFe interface layer and self-alignment of CoFe lattice to that of the MgO after annealing, CoFeB low exchange material is still required for high TMR ratio MgO MTJ.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a flow chart of the steps performed in manufacturing the various STTMRAM elements of the present invention, in accordance with a method of the present invention. Examples of such STTMRAM elements are the elements <b>14</b> and <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">During the process of manufacturing the STTMRAM element, various layers are deposited on top of one another as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and the steps of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> pick up the formation of figures starting from deposition of the barrier layer. The steps of flow chart <b>70</b> therefore show only those steps performed after the barrier layer has been deposited. At step <b>72</b>, a free layer (FL<b>1</b>), such as the free layer <b>28</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is deposited on top of the deposited barrier layer. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2(</figref><i>a</i>), this layer is the sub-layer <b>54</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Next, at step <b>74</b>, an annealing process is performed, using a first temperature, on the STTMRAM element, as formed thus far. In an exemplary method, the first temperature used at step <b>74</b> is approximately more than or equal to 200 degrees Celsius (&#xb0; C.) and less than or equal to 500&#xb0; C. Accordingly, the deposited barrier layer and FL<b>1</b> are annealed as well. Next, at step <b>76</b>, the STTMRAM element is cooled down to a second temperature that is lower than the first temperature. At this point, two sub-layers are formed, such as the layers <b>29</b> and <b>30</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> or the sub-layers <b>54</b> and <b>56</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2(</figref><i>a</i>).</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Next, at step <b>78</b>, another free layer, FL<b>2</b>, is deposited over the FL<b>1</b> while the STTMRAM element is at the temperature of step <b>76</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2(</figref><i>a</i>), the FL<b>2</b> is the sub-layer <b>58</b> and in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the FL<b>2</b> is the layer <b>32</b>. Next, at step <b>82</b>, another annealing process is performed using a third temperature that is higher than the second temperature but lower than the first temperature.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Optionally, additional non-magnetic and magnetic layers are deposited on top of the FL<b>2</b>, as may be suited and optionally a magnetic field is applied to the STTMRAM element thereby improving the magnetic property of the FL<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Although the present invention has been described in terms of specific embodiments, it is anticipated that alterations and modifications thereof will no doubt become apparent to those skilled in the art. It is therefore intended that the following claims be interpreted as covering all such alterations and modification as fall within the true spirit and scope of the invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method of manufacturing a spin transfer torque magnetic random access memory (STTMRAM) element comprising:
<claim-text>first depositing a first free sub-layer on top of a barrier layer to form a magnetic tunnel junction (MTJ), the first free sub-layer being made partially of boron (B) and having a first within-film magnetic exchange;</claim-text>
<claim-text>after the first depositing step, annealing the STTMRAM element at a first temperature after depositing the first free sub-layer, the annealing causing a second free sub-layer to be formed on top of the first free sub-layer</claim-text>
<claim-text>after the annealing step, cooling down the STTMRAM element to a second temperature that is lower than the first temperature; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>after the cooling down step, second depositing a third free sub-layer directly on top the second free sub-layer, the first, second, and third free sub-layers forming a free layer,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the third free sub-layer having a second within-film magnetic exchange, the second within-film magnetic exchange being different than the first within-film magnetic exchange, the amount of B in the third sub-free layer being less than the amount of B in the second free layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A method of manufacturing, as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further including the step of second annealing after the second depositing step, using a third temperature that is lower than the first temperature and higher than the second temperature.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A method of manufacturing, as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, further including the step of depositing additional layers on top of the third free sub-layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A method of manufacturing, as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the third free layer is made of cobolt-iron (CoFe).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A method of manufacturing, as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first temperature is approximately more than or equal to 200 degrees Celsius (&#xb0; C.) and less than or equal to 500&#xb0; C.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A method of manufacturing, as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first free sub-layer comprises: Co, Fe, Ni, B, Ta, Ti, Cu, Zr, Cr or Pt.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A method of manufacturing, as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second within-film magnetic exchange is greater than the first within-film magnetic exchange.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A method of manufacturing, as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the annealing step reduces the B content at an interface between the first free sub-layer and wherein the barrier layer, the second free sub-layer being made partially of B, the amount of B in the second free sub-layer being greater than the amount of B in the first free sub-layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of manufacturing, as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of the first, second, and third free sub-layers have a magnetization associated therewith and further wherein, the magnetization of each of the first, second, and third free sub-layers is switchable.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of manufacturing, as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the third free sub-layer is made partially of boron (B).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of manufacturing, as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first, second, and the third free sub-layers are each magnetic.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. A method of manufacturing a spin toque transfer magnetic random access memory (STTMRAM) element comprising:
<claim-text>first depositing a first free sub-layer on top of a barrier layer to form a magnetic tunnel junction (MTJ), the first free sub-layer being made partially of boron (B), the first free sub-layer having a first within-film magnetic exchange;</claim-text>
<claim-text>after the first depositing step, annealing the STTMRAM element at a first temperature; the annealing causing a second free sub-layer to be formed on top of the first free sub-layer</claim-text>
<claim-text>after the annealing step, cooling down the STTMRAM element to a second temperature that is lower than the first temperature; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>after the cooling down step, second depositing a third free sub-layer directly on top of the second free sub-layer with the third free sub-layer being substantially void of B and having a second within-film magnetic exchange, the first, second, and third free sub-layers forming a free layer,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second within-film magnetic exchange is different than the first within-film magnetic exchange.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A method of manufacturing, as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, further including the step of second annealing after depositing the third free sub-layer, using a third temperature that is lower than the first temperature and higher than the second temperature.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. .A method of manufacturing, as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further including the step of depositing additional layers on top of the third free sub-layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A method of manufacturing, as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the second within-film magnetic exchange is greater than the first within-film magnetic exchange.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A method of manufacturing, as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the annealing step reduces the B content at an interface between the first free sub-layer and the barrier layer, and wherein the second free sub-layer being made partially of B, the amount of B in the second free sub-layer being greater than the amount of B in the first free sub-layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of manufacturing, as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein each of the first, second, and third free sub-layers have a magnetization associated therewith and further wherein, the magnetization of each of the first, second, and third free sub-layers is switchable.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of manufacturing, as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the third free sub-layer is made partially of boron (B).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of manufacturing, as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the first, second, and the third free sub-layers are each magnetic. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
