<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624331-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624331</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12659644</doc-number>
<date>20100316</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2009-0110594</doc-number>
<date>20091117</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>783</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>29</main-group>
<subgroup>76</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257390</main-classification>
<further-classification>257225</further-classification>
<further-classification>257246</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Non-volatile memory devices, methods of manufacturing and methods of operating the same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0128840</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Rinerson</name>
<date>20050600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0097343</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Parkinson</name>
<date>20060500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257528</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0303013</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Happ et al.</name>
<date>20081200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257  3</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0272958</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ufert et al.</name>
<date>20091100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257  2</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0012911</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Akinaga et al.</name>
<date>20100100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257  2</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2003-0014653</doc-number>
<date>20030200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2003-0023556</doc-number>
<date>20030300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257390</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257225</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257246</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>13</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>24</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110115049</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110519</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Deok-kee</first-name>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cho</last-name>
<first-name>Choong-rae</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Deok-kee</first-name>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cho</last-name>
<first-name>Choong-rae</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Harness, Dickey &#x26; Pierce</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Gyeonggi-do</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Gebremariam</last-name>
<first-name>Samuel</first-name>
<department>2811</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A non-volatile memory device includes: at least one horizontal electrode; at least one vertical electrode disposed to intersect the at least one horizontal electrode at an intersection region; at least one data layer disposed at the intersection region and having a conduction-insulation transition property; and at least one anti-fuse layer connected in series with the at least one data layer.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="119.89mm" wi="157.23mm" file="US08624331-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="217.93mm" wi="115.65mm" file="US08624331-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="221.15mm" wi="115.91mm" file="US08624331-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="229.62mm" wi="167.64mm" file="US08624331-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="230.55mm" wi="160.70mm" file="US08624331-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="240.96mm" wi="167.56mm" file="US08624331-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="233.00mm" wi="162.48mm" file="US08624331-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="236.47mm" wi="159.77mm" file="US08624331-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="135.13mm" wi="153.42mm" file="US08624331-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="239.69mm" wi="169.59mm" file="US08624331-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="239.10mm" wi="167.98mm" file="US08624331-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="130.64mm" wi="149.69mm" file="US08624331-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="231.56mm" wi="145.37mm" file="US08624331-20140107-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="224.71mm" wi="146.98mm" file="US08624331-20140107-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION(S)</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority under 35 U.S.C. &#xa7;119 to Korean Patent Application No. 10-2009-0110594, filed on Nov. 17, 2009, in the Korean Intellectual Property Office, the entire contents of which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Example embodiments of inventive concepts relate to semiconductor devices, for example, non-volatile memory devices capable of storing data according to a conduction-insulation transition property. Example embodiments of inventive concepts also relate to methods of manufacturing and methods of operating non-volatile memory devices.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of Conventional Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Although sizes of conventional semiconductor devices have considerably decreased, the amount of data processed by semiconductor devices has increased. Accordingly, improvements in operating speeds and integration densities of non-volatile memory devices used in semiconductor devices are desirable.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">When a non-volatile memory device having a multi-layer structure is used, more memory cells may be stacked in a space having the same size as that occupied by a non-volatile memory device having a single-layer structure. However, manufacturing and operating non-volatile memory devices having multi-layer structures are relatively complicated.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">At least one example embodiment of inventive concepts provides a non-volatile memory device including: at least one horizontal electrode and at least one vertical electrode. The at least one horizontal electrode and the at least one vertical electrode are disposed to intersect one another at an intersecting region. The non-volatile memory device further includes at least one data layer and at least one anti-fuse layer. The at least one data layer is disposed at the intersecting region and has a conduction-insulation transition property. The at least one anti-fuse layer is connected in series with the at least one data layer.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to at least some example embodiments, the at least one data layer may include a transition metal oxide. For example, the at least one data layer may include a vanadium oxide, an aluminum oxide, a bismuth oxide, a titanium oxide, a niobium oxide, a nickel oxide, a copper oxide, zinc oxide, a tin oxide, a zirconium oxide, a silicon oxide, a hafnium oxide, a cobalt oxide, an iron oxide, or combinations thereof. In a more specific example, the at least one data layer may include a V<sub>2</sub>O<sub>5</sub>, VO<sub>2</sub>, VO, or combinations thereof. The at least one anti-fuse layer may include oxide layers, nitride layers, oxy-nitride layers, or combinations of the layers. The at least one data layer may have a threshold voltage V<sub>TH </sub>that is less than a breakdown voltage V<sub>AB </sub>of the at least one anti-fuse layer.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to at least some example embodiments, the at least one anti-fuse layer may be interposed at the intersecting region between the at least one data layer and the at least one horizontal electrode.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to at least some example embodiments, the at least one anti-fuse layer may be interposed at the intersecting region between the at least one data layer and the at least one vertical electrode.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">At least one of the data layers and the anti-fuse layers may have a pattern at the intersecting region.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to at least some example embodiments, one or more of the at least one horizontal electrode and the at least one vertical electrode may include one or more trenches at the intersecting region. One or more of the at least one data layer and the at least one anti-fuse layer may be disposed in the one or more trenches.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to at least some example embodiments, one or more of the at least one data layer and the at least one anti-fuse layer may be disposed to surround the at least one vertical electrode. The at least one horizontal electrode and the at least one vertical electrode may be disposed to cross each other perpendicularly or substantially perpendicularly.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The at least one horizontal electrode may include a first semiconductor having a first conductive type. The at least one vertical electrode may include a second semiconductor having a second conductive type. The second conductive type may be different from the first conductive type.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The at least one horizontal electrode, the at least one vertical electrode, or both may include: polysilicon, tungsten (W), aluminum (Al), copper (Cu), molybdenum (Mo), titanium (Ti), tantalum (Ta), ruthenium (Ru), platinum (Pt), palladium (Pd), nickel (Ni), gold (Au), silver (Ag), beryllium (Be), bismuth (Bi), hafnium (Hf), indium (In), manganese (Mn), molybdenum (Mo), lead (Pb), rhodium (Rh), rhenium (Re), tellium (Te), zinc (Zn), zirconium (Zr), cobalt (Co), iridium (Ir), platinum (Pt), an alloy thereof, an oxide thereof, a nitride thereof, a silicide thereof, or a combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">At least one other example embodiment of inventive concepts provides a non-volatile memory device including: a plurality of horizontal electrodes stacked in a plurality of layers; and a plurality of vertical electrodes formed in a plurality of rows disposed to intersect the plurality of horizontal electrodes at intersecting regions. The non-volatile memory device further includes: a plurality of data layers and a plurality of anti-fuse layers. Each of the plurality of data layers is disposed at a corresponding intersecting region and has a conduction-insulation transition property. The plurality of anti-fuse layers are connected in series with the plurality of data layers.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">According to at least some example embodiments, the plurality of data layers may extend across the stacked layers of the plurality of horizontal electrodes. The plurality of anti-fuse layers may extend across the stacked layers of the plurality of horizontal electrodes. Each of the plurality of horizontal electrodes may include a plurality of first horizontal electrodes and a plurality of second horizontal electrodes that are spaced apart from each other.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">At least one other example embodiment of inventive concepts provides a non-volatile memory device including: first and second conductive layers that face each other. The non-volatile memory device further includes a plurality of data layers and a plurality of anti-fuse layers. Each of the plurality of data layers is interposed between the first and second conductive layers and has a conduction-insulation transition property. Each of the plurality of anti-fuse layers is interposed between the first and second conductive layers and connected to the plurality of data layers.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Example embodiments of inventive concepts will be more clearly understood from the following detailed description taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings in which:</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a unit cell of a non-volatile memory device according to an example embodiment of inventive concepts;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A through 2C</figref> are perspective views of unit cells of non-volatile memory devices according to other example embodiments of inventive concepts;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view of a non-volatile memory device according to an example embodiment of inventive concepts;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a perspective view of a non-volatile memory device having a stacked-layer structure according to another example embodiment of inventive concepts;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross-sectional diagram of the non-volatile memory device shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> taken along the line V-V&#x2032;;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a perspective view of a non-volatile memory device having a stacked-layer structure according to another example embodiment of inventive concepts;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A through 7G</figref> are perspective views illustrating a method of manufacturing a non-volatile memory device according to an example embodiment of inventive concepts;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8A through 8E</figref> are perspective views illustrating a method of manufacturing a non-volatile memory device according to another example embodiment of inventive concepts;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> schematically illustrates a method of operating a non-volatile memory device according to an example embodiment of inventive concepts;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a graph showing an example voltage-current characteristic of data layers formed of variable resistive materials and included in the non-volatile memory device according to an example embodiment of inventive concepts;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a block diagram of a card according to an example embodiment of inventive concepts; and</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a block diagram of a system according to an example embodiment of inventive concepts.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Reference will now be made in detail to the example embodiments illustrated in the accompanying drawings. However, inventive concepts are not limited to the example embodiments illustrated hereinafter. These example embodiments are introduced to provide easy and complete understanding of the scope and spirit of inventive concepts. In the drawings, the thicknesses of layers and regions are exaggerated for clarity.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">It will be understood that when an element, such as a layer, a region, or a substrate, is referred to as being &#x201c;on,&#x201d; &#x201c;connected to&#x201d; or &#x201c;coupled to&#x201d; another element, it may be directly on, connected or coupled to the other element or intervening elements may be present. In contrast, when an element is referred to as being &#x201c;directly on,&#x201d; &#x201c;directly connected to&#x201d; or &#x201c;directly coupled to&#x201d; another element or layer, there are no intervening elements or layers present. Like reference numerals refer to like elements throughout. As used herein, the term &#x201c;and/or&#x201d; includes any and all combinations of one or more of the associated listed items.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">It will be understood that, although the terms first, second, third, etc., may be used herein to describe various elements, components, regions, layers and/or sections, these elements, components, regions, layers and/or sections should not be limited by these terms. These terms are only used to distinguish one element, component, region, layer or section from another region, layer or section. Thus, a first element, component, region, layer or section discussed below could be termed a second element, component, region, layer or section without departing from the teachings of exemplary embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Spatially relative terms, such as &#x201c;above,&#x201d; &#x201c;upper,&#x201d; &#x201c;beneath,&#x201d; &#x201c;below,&#x201d; &#x201c;lower,&#x201d; and the like, may be used herein for ease of description to describe one element or feature's relationship to another element(s) or feature(s) as illustrated in the figures. It will be understood that the spatially relative terms are intended to encompass different orientations of the device in use or operation in addition to the orientation depicted in the figures. For example, if the device in the figures is turned over, elements described as &#x201c;below&#x201d; or &#x201c;beneath&#x201d; other elements or features would then be oriented &#x201c;above&#x201d; the other elements or features. Thus, the exemplary term &#x201c;above&#x201d; may encompass both an orientation of above and below. The device may be otherwise oriented (rotated 90 degrees or at other orientations) and the spatially relative descriptors used herein interpreted accordingly.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The terminology used herein is for the purpose of describing particular example embodiments only and is not intended to be limiting. As used herein, the singular forms &#x201c;a,&#x201d; &#x201c;an&#x201d; and &#x201c;the&#x201d; are intended to include the plural forms as well, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise. It will be further understood that the terms &#x201c;comprises&#x201d; and/or &#x201c;comprising&#x201d; when used in this specification, specify the presence of stated features, integers, steps, operations, elements and/or components, but do not preclude the presence or addition of one or more other features, integers, steps, operations, elements, components and/or groups thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Example embodiments are described herein with reference to cross-sectional illustrations that are schematic illustrations of example embodiments (and intermediate structures). As such, variations from the shapes of the illustrations as a result, for example, of manufacturing techniques and/or tolerances, are to be expected. Thus, example embodiments should not be construed as limited to the particular shapes of regions illustrated herein but may be to include deviations in shapes that result, for example, from manufacturing. For example, an implanted region illustrated as a rectangle may, typically, have rounded or curved features and/or a gradient of implant concentration at its edges rather than a binary change from implanted to non-implanted region. Likewise, a buried region formed by implantation may result in some implantation in the region between the buried region and the surface through which the implantation takes place. Thus, the regions illustrated in the figures are schematic in nature and their shapes may be not intended to illustrate the actual shape of a region of a device and are not intended to limit the scope of inventive concepts.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Unless otherwise defined, all terms (including technical and scientific terms) used herein have the same meaning as commonly understood by one of ordinary skill in the art to which example embodiments belong. It will be further understood that terms, such as those defined in commonly used dictionaries, should be interpreted as having a meaning that is consistent with their meaning in the context of the relevant art and will not be interpreted in an idealized or overly formal sense unless expressly so defined herein.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Hereinafter, one or more example embodiments are described with reference to the accompanying drawings. In the drawings, transformation of forms in the drawings may be expected according to a manufacturing technique and/or tolerance. Accordingly, example embodiments are not limited to the specific forms illustrated in the drawing and may include, for example, changes in the forms which may occur during manufacturing.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a unit cell of a non-volatile memory device according to an example embodiment of inventive concepts.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a unit cell <b>1</b> of a non-volatile memory device includes at least one horizontal electrode <b>10</b>, at least one vertical electrode <b>20</b>, at least one data layer <b>30</b>, and at least one anti-fuse layer <b>40</b>. Hereinafter, the terms &#x2018;horizontal&#x2019; and &#x2018;vertical&#x2019; are used to distinguish the electrodes <b>10</b> and <b>20</b> from each other, not to limit the electrodes <b>10</b> and <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In the unit cell <b>1</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and the vertical electrode <b>20</b> are disposed to cross each other. In one example, a vertical electrode <b>20</b> is disposed between a pair of horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> so as to be perpendicular or substantially perpendicular to (e.g., vertical with respect to) the pair of horizontal electrodes <b>10</b>. However, example embodiments are not limited to this arrangement. For example, the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and the vertical electrode <b>20</b> may be disposed to cross each other at a given, desired or predetermined angle.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and the vertical electrode <b>20</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> have the shape of a square pillar; however, example embodiments are not limited thereto. Rather, the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and the vertical electrode <b>20</b> may have various shapes such as a polygonal pillar or a cylindrical pillar.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and the vertical electrode <b>20</b> may be formed of, for example, semiconductor layers such as epitaxial layers or polysilicon layers. Alternatively, the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and the vertical electrode <b>20</b> may be formed of a metal layer including tungsten (W), aluminum (Al), copper (Cu), molybdenum (Mo), titanium (Ti), tantalum (Ta), ruthenium (Ru), platinum (Pt), palladium (Pd), nickel (Ni), gold (Au), silver (Ag), beryllium (Be), bismuth (Bi), hafnium (Hf), indium (In), manganese (Mn), molybdenum (Mo), lead (Pb), rhodium (Rh), rhenium (Re), tellium (Te), zinc (Zn), zirconium (Zr), cobalt (Co), iridium (Ir), platinum (Pt) an alloy thereof, an oxide thereof, a nitride thereof, a silicide thereof, combinations thereof or the like. In addition, each of the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and the vertical electrode <b>20</b> may be formed of a single layer or multi-layer structure. The multi-layer structure has a stacked layer structure. The materials of the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and the vertical electrode <b>20</b> are not limited to the above examples.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">According to at least the example embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the at least one data layer <b>30</b> is disposed at intersecting regions where the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and the vertical electrode <b>20</b> intersect each other. More specifically, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a data layer <b>30</b> is disposed to extend along each side wall of the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> that faces the vertical electrode <b>20</b>. Alternatively, a data layer <b>30</b> may be disposed along each side wall of the vertical electrode <b>20</b> at which a horizontal electrode <b>10</b> is formed. The shape of the data layers <b>30</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> are only examples, and the data layer <b>30</b> may have other shapes as will be described more fully with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A through 2C</figref>. The data layers <b>30</b> may store data by varying the electrical resistance thereof, and controlling a flow of electrical current between the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and the vertical electrode <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The data layers <b>30</b> may be conductive or variable resistance materials, which have a resistance that changes according to an applied voltage. In one example, the data layers <b>30</b> may include a metal-insulation transition (MIT) material, which has a resistance that changes according to an applied voltage. In another example, the data layer <b>30</b> may include a transition metal oxide such as a vanadium oxide, an aluminum oxide, a bismuth oxide, a titanium oxide, a niobium oxide, a nickel oxide, a copper oxide, zinc oxide, a tin oxide, a zirconium oxide, a silicon oxide, a hafnium oxide, a cobalt oxide, an iron oxide, combinations thereof or the like. In a more specific example, the data layer <b>30</b> may include V<sub>2</sub>O<sub>5</sub>, VO<sub>2</sub>, VO, or combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Alternatively, the data layers <b>30</b> may include a phase change resistance material having a high-resistance state and a low-resistance state according to a crystalline state of the phase-change resistance material, or a calcogenide compound. The above-described materials of the data layers <b>30</b> are only examples and example embodiments are not limited thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">When the data layers <b>30</b> are conductive layers, a diode junction may be formed between the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and the vertical electrode <b>20</b>, thereby resulting in a rectification property there between. In this example, the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> may include first semiconductors of a first conductive type, whereas the vertical electrode <b>20</b> may include a second semiconductor of a second conductive type. The second conductive type may be different from the first conductive type. In one example, the first conductive type and the second conductive type may be n-type and p-type, respectively, or vice versa.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, an anti-fuse layer <b>40</b> may be optionally disposed at each intersecting region where the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and the vertical electrode <b>20</b> intersect each other. In the example embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, an anti-fuse layer <b>40</b> is interposed between each horizontal electrode <b>10</b> and corresponding data layer <b>30</b>. The vertical electrode <b>20</b> and the data layers <b>30</b> are electrically connected to each other.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In more detail with regard to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, each anti-fuse layer <b>40</b> is disposed to extend along the side wall of a corresponding one of the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> that faces the vertical electrode <b>20</b>. However, the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> may be disposed on the side walls of the vertical electrode <b>20</b>. The locations of the data layers <b>30</b> and the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> are only examples and example embodiments are not limited thereto. For example, the locations of the data layers <b>30</b> and the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> may be reversed. In one example, the data layers <b>30</b> and the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> may be adjacent to the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and the vertical electrode <b>20</b>, respectively. In this example, the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and the data layers <b>30</b> may be electrically connected to each other. The relative locations of the data layers <b>30</b> and the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> may also be applied to other example embodiments, which will be described in more detail below. Although not illustrated, a conductive layer including a conductive material (e.g., a metal) may be interposed between the data layers <b>30</b> and the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b>. The conductive layer may function as an electrode.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> may function as an anti-fuse. For example, each of the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> may include an insulating material of which insulating property is lost in response to an applied voltage. Accordingly, the non-volatile memory device may be used as a one-time programmable (OTP) memory because the insulating property of the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> material is not recovered. OTP memory may be used in products requiring relatively significant memory capacity. According to at least some example embodiments, the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> may include an oxide, a nitride, an oxy-nitride, or combinations thereof. The anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> may include a silicon oxide, a silicon nitride, a silicon oxy-nitride, or combinations thereof. Also, the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> may include a transition metal oxide, such as, an aluminum oxide, a tantalum oxide, a hafnium oxide, a lanthanum oxide, a bismuth oxide, a titanium oxide, a niobium oxide, a nickel oxide, a copper oxide, a zinc oxide, a tin oxide, a zirconium oxide, a cobalt oxide, an iron oxide, or combinations thereof. The anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> may be single layers including any one of the materials described above, multi-layer structures including a plurality of stacked single layers, or more complex layer structures including at least two of the above-described materials. The materials for forming the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> are only examples and example embodiments are not limited thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A through 2C</figref> are perspective views of unit cells of non-volatile memory devices according to other example embodiments of inventive concepts. The unit cells <b>1</b><i>a</i>, <b>1</b><i>b</i>, and <b>1</b><i>c </i>shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A through 2C</figref> are similar to the unit cell <b>1</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, and thus, some details thereof will not be repeated.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">According to the example embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, the unit cell <b>1</b><i>a </i>may include one or more patterned data layers <b>30</b><i>a </i>and one or more patterned anti-fuse layers <b>40</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, the unit cell <b>1</b><i>a </i>includes a patterned data layer <b>30</b><i>a </i>and a patterned anti-fuse layer <b>40</b><i>a </i>disposed at intersecting regions where horizontal electrodes <b>10</b><i>a </i>and vertical electrode <b>20</b><i>a </i>intersect each other. In this example, the width of the patterned data layer <b>30</b><i>a </i>and the patterned anti-fuse layer <b>40</b><i>a </i>are the same or substantially the same as the width of the vertical electrode <b>20</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">According to the example embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>, one or more of the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b><i>b </i>and the vertical electrode <b>20</b><i>b </i>included in the unit cell <b>1</b><i>b </i>may include trenches T. In this example, one or more of data layers <b>30</b><i>b </i>and anti-fuse layers <b>40</b><i>b </i>may be disposed in the trenches T.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">As shown specifically in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>, a trench is formed in each horizontal electrode <b>10</b><i>b</i>, and a data layer <b>30</b><i>b </i>and an anti-fuse layer <b>40</b><i>b </i>are disposed in each trench T. Although not illustrated, the vertical electrode <b>20</b><i>b </i>may include the trenches T and one or more of data layers <b>30</b><i>b </i>and anti-fuse layers <b>40</b><i>b </i>may be disposed in the trenches T.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Also, although not illustrated, both the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b><i>b </i>and the vertical electrode <b>20</b><i>b </i>may include trenches T. In this example, one of data layers <b>30</b><i>b </i>and anti-fuse layers <b>40</b><i>b </i>may be disposed in the trenches T of the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b><i>b</i>, and the other of the data layers <b>30</b><i>b </i>and anti-fuse layers <b>40</b><i>b </i>may be disposed in the trenches T of the vertical electrode <b>20</b><i>b</i>. In at least this example embodiment, the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b><i>b </i>and the vertical electrode <b>20</b><i>b </i>are electrically insulated from each other.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">According to the example embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2C</figref>, the unit cell <b>1</b><i>c </i>may include a data layer <b>30</b><i>c </i>and an anti-fuse layer <b>40</b><i>c </i>surrounding the vertical electrode <b>20</b><i>c</i>. Although not illustrated, the data layer <b>30</b><i>c </i>and the anti-fuse layer <b>40</b><i>c </i>may be disposed to surround each horizontal electrode <b>10</b><i>c. </i></p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">As shown specifically in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2C</figref>, a data layer <b>30</b><i>c </i>and an anti-fuse layer <b>40</b><i>c </i>surround the vertical electrode <b>20</b><i>c. </i></p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">As described above, the elements included in the unit cells <b>1</b>, <b>1</b><i>a</i>, <b>1</b><i>b</i>, and <b>1</b><i>c </i>described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 2C</figref> are only examples and inventive concepts are not limited thereto. Characteristics of the elements may be combined.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view of a non-volatile memory device according to an example embodiment of inventive concepts. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the non-volatile memory device <b>100</b> includes a plurality of the unit cells <b>1</b> arranged two-dimensionally. However, example embodiments are not limited thereto and the unit cells <b>1</b><i>a</i>, <b>1</b><i>b</i>, and <b>1</b><i>c </i>of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A through 2C</figref> or combinations thereof may be included in the non-volatile memory device <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">More specifically with regard to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the non-volatile memory device <b>100</b> includes a plurality of the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b>, a plurality of the vertical electrodes <b>20</b>, a plurality of data layers <b>30</b>, and a plurality of anti-fuse layers <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and the vertical electrodes <b>20</b> are disposed to cross each other. For example, the vertical electrodes <b>20</b> are disposed between pairs of horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> so as to be vertical relative to the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> or to cross each other by a given, desired or predetermined angle. The vertical electrodes <b>20</b> may be appropriately selected according to the number and length of the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b>. Also, the numbers of the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and the vertical electrodes <b>20</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> are only examples and example embodiments are not limited thereto. In addition, in the example embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and the vertical electrodes <b>20</b> are formed as a square pillar; however, example embodiments are not limited thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the data layers <b>30</b> are disposed at intersecting regions where the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and the vertical electrodes <b>20</b> intersect each other. For example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> data layers <b>30</b> are disposed to extend along the side walls of each horizontal electrode <b>10</b>. The illustrated data layers <b>30</b> are only examples and may have various forms as described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 2C</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> may be optionally interposed between the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and each corresponding data layer <b>30</b>. In the example embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> are also disposed to extend along the side walls of the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b>. The illustrated anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> are only examples and may have various forms as described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 2C</figref>. Also, as described above, the locations of the data layers <b>30</b> and the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> may be reversed.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The non-volatile memory device <b>100</b> according to at least this example embodiment includes a plurality of memory cells. In this example, the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> function as word lines and the vertical electrodes <b>20</b> function as bit lines. However, the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> may function as bit lines and the vertical electrodes <b>20</b> may function as word lines. Hereinafter, an example configuration and operation of the non-volatile memory device <b>100</b>, in which the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> function as word lines, is described in more detail.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> include first horizontal electrodes <b>11</b> and second horizontal electrodes <b>12</b> that are spaced apart from each other. The first horizontal electrodes <b>11</b> are electrically connected to a first word line <b>50</b><i>a</i>, whereas the second horizontal electrodes <b>12</b> are electrically connected to a second word line <b>50</b><i>b</i>. The first word line <b>50</b><i>a </i>and the second word line <b>50</b><i>b </i>are disposed at opposite sides of the first horizontal electrodes <b>11</b> and the second horizontal electrodes <b>12</b>. For example, the first word line <b>50</b><i>a </i>is connected to first ends of the first horizontal electrodes <b>11</b>, whereas the second word line <b>50</b><i>b </i>is connected to second ends of the second horizontal electrodes <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">In the non-volatile memory device <b>100</b>, one of the first horizontal electrode <b>11</b> and the second horizontal electrode <b>12</b>, the vertical electrode <b>20</b>, and the data layer <b>30</b> disposed there between may form a memory cell as described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 2C</figref>. The first horizontal electrodes <b>11</b> and the second horizontal electrodes <b>12</b> may be accessed through the first word line <b>50</b><i>a </i>and the second word line <b>50</b><i>b</i>, respectively. Accordingly, access to a memory cell may be achieved by selecting one of the first word line <b>50</b><i>a </i>and the second word line <b>50</b><i>b</i>, and the vertical electrode <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">In one example, a memory cell of the nonvolatile memory device <b>100</b> is programmed by applying a program voltage to the first word line <b>50</b><i>a </i>or the second word line <b>50</b><i>b</i>, and to the vertical electrode <b>20</b>. In this example, the program voltage is greater than a threshold voltage of the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> and the insulating properties of the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> are lost locally. In one example, when the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> are disposed relatively closely between the vertical electrode <b>20</b> and the first horizontal electrodes <b>11</b> or the second horizontal electrodes <b>12</b>, a concentration of electrical current causes the insulating properties of the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> to be lost locally in the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b>. Accordingly, the data layers <b>30</b> adjacent to the broken anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> are conductive, and thus, may be programmed.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">In another example, a memory cell is read by applying a reading voltage to the first word line <b>50</b><i>a </i>or the second word line <b>50</b><i>b</i>, and the vertical electrode <b>20</b>. In this example, the reading voltage is less than the program voltage and the threshold voltage of the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b>, but greater than a threshold voltage of the data layers <b>30</b>. Accordingly, an electrical current flows between the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and the vertical electrode <b>20</b> through the data layers <b>30</b> adjacent to the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> of which insulating properties are lost due to the program voltage, and thus, a memory cell is read.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a perspective view of a non-volatile memory device <b>200</b> having a stacked-layer structure according to another example embodiment of inventive concepts. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross-sectional diagram taken along line V-V&#x2032; in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. The non-volatile memory device <b>200</b> includes the unit cells <b>1</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and is similar to the non-volatile memory device <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. Thus, some details thereof will not be repeated. But, the non-volatile memory device <b>200</b> including the unit cell <b>1</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is only an example, and example embodiments are not limited thereto. The non-volatile memory device <b>200</b> may include any of the unit cells <b>1</b><i>a</i>, <b>1</b><i>b</i>, and <b>1</b><i>c </i>of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A through 2C</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, the non-volatile memory device <b>200</b> includes a plurality of the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b>, a plurality of the vertical electrodes <b>20</b>, and a plurality of data layers <b>30</b>. The plurality of horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> are formed of a plurality of stacked layers. The plurality of the vertical electrodes <b>20</b> are formed in a plurality of rows so as to intersect with the plurality of horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> at intersecting regions. The plurality of data layers <b>30</b> are disposed at the intersecting regions where the plurality of the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and the plurality of the vertical electrodes <b>20</b> intersect each other.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The non-volatile memory device <b>200</b> may optionally include an anti-fuse layer <b>40</b> interposed between each of the plurality of horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> and a corresponding data layer <b>30</b>. The example embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref> includes the optional anti-fuse layers <b>40</b>. As described above, alternatively, an anti-fuse layer <b>40</b> may be interposed between each of the plurality of vertical electrodes <b>20</b> and a corresponding data layer <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, the non-volatile memory device <b>200</b> is formed of a plurality of the non-volatile memory devices <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, which are stacked in a plurality of layers. More specifically, the non-volatile memory device <b>200</b> includes first conductive layers <b>13</b> and insulating layers <b>14</b> that are stacked alternately on one another. Accordingly, the plurality of the horizontal electrodes <b>10</b> (e.g., the first horizontal electrodes <b>11</b> and the second horizontal electrodes <b>12</b>) may be formed of the first conductive layers <b>13</b> and the insulating layers <b>14</b> interposed between the first conductive layers <b>13</b>, thereby forming a plurality of stacked layers. Similarly, the first word lines <b>50</b><i>a </i>and the second word lines <b>50</b><i>b </i>may be formed of the first conductive layers <b>13</b> and the insulating layers <b>14</b> interposed between the first conductive layers <b>13</b>, thereby forming a plurality of stacked layers. The first horizontal electrodes <b>11</b> and the second horizontal electrodes <b>12</b> in each layer may be separated from one another in the same or substantially the same manner as described above with regard to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. Similarly, the first word lines <b>50</b><i>a </i>and the second word lines <b>50</b><i>b </i>in each layer may also be separated from one another in the same or substantially the same manner as described above with regard to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, the vertical electrodes <b>20</b> extend across the stacked layers of the first horizontal electrodes <b>11</b> and the second horizontal electrodes <b>12</b>. Thus, the vertical electrodes <b>20</b> are shared by the stack of the first horizontal electrodes <b>11</b> and the second horizontal electrodes <b>12</b> disposed in each different layer.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The data layers <b>30</b> extend across the stacked layers of the first horizontal electrodes <b>11</b> and the second horizontal electrodes <b>12</b>. Further, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the data layers <b>30</b> further extend onto sidewalls of the first word lines <b>50</b><i>a </i>and the second word lines <b>50</b><i>b</i>. In one example, the data layers <b>30</b> are in the form of a square tube surrounding the outer walls of the vertical electrodes <b>20</b> in each row. As described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 2C</figref>, the data layers <b>30</b> may have various forms.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> extend across the stacked layers of the first horizontal electrodes <b>11</b> and the second horizontal electrodes <b>12</b>. The anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> further extend onto the sidewalls of the first word lines <b>50</b><i>a </i>and the second word lines <b>50</b><i>b</i>. In one example, the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> surround the data layers <b>30</b>, thereby having the form of a square tube surrounding the outer walls of the vertical electrodes <b>20</b> and/or the data layers <b>30</b> disposed in each row. As described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 2C</figref>, the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> may have various forms. Also, the locations of the data layers <b>30</b> and the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> may be reversed.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">Example operation of the non-volatile memory device <b>200</b> according to at least this example embodiment may be inferred from the operation of the non-volatile memory device <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. The capacity of the non-volatile memory device <b>200</b> according to at least this example embodiment may be increased relatively easily by increasing the number of the memory cells, for example, the number of first horizontal electrodes <b>11</b> and second horizontal electrodes <b>12</b> or the number of stacked layers. Accordingly, the non-volatile memory device <b>200</b> according to example embodiments may have relatively high integration in the same or substantially the same plane, and thus, may be more suitable as a relatively high-capacity and/or relatively highly integrated product.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a perspective view of a non-volatile memory device having a stacked-layer structure according to another example embodiment of inventive concepts. The non-volatile memory device <b>300</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is similar to the non-volatile memory device <b>200</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, and thus, some details thereof will not be repeated.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">Referring to the example embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, vertical electrodes <b>22</b> have a cylindrical form and data layers <b>32</b> are disposed to surround the vertical electrodes <b>22</b>. Accordingly, the data layers <b>32</b> fill gaps between the first horizontal electrodes <b>11</b> and the second horizontal electrodes <b>12</b>, and the vertical electrodes <b>22</b> are recessed into the data layers <b>32</b>. Also, as described above, anti-fuse layers <b>42</b> are formed between the data layers <b>32</b> and the first horizontal electrodes <b>11</b>, and between the data layers <b>32</b> and the second horizontal electrodes <b>12</b>. The locations of the data layers <b>32</b> and the anti-fuse layers <b>42</b> may be reversed.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A through 7G</figref> are perspective views illustrating a method of manufacturing a non-volatile memory device according to an example embodiment of inventive concepts.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</figref>, a plurality of the first conductive layers <b>13</b> and a plurality of the insulating layers <b>14</b> are stacked alternately on one another. The first conductive layers <b>13</b> may be formed of, for example, semiconductor layers such as epitaxial layers or polysilicon layers, or a metal. Example metals include tungsten (W), aluminum (Al), copper (Cu), molybdenum (Mo), titanium (Ti), tantalum (Ta), ruthenium (Ru), platinum (Pt), palladium (Pd), nickel (Ni), gold (Au), silver (Ag), beryllium (Be), bismuth (Bi), hafnium (Hf), indium (In), manganese (Mn), molybdenum (Mo), lead (Pb), rhodium (Rh), rhenium (Re), tellium (Te), zinc (Zn), zirconium (Zr), cobalt (Co), iridium (Ir), an alloy thereof, an oxide thereof, a nitride thereof, a silicide thereof, or combinations thereof. The first conductive layers <b>13</b> may be doped with first conductive type impurities, for example, n-type impurities or p-type impurities.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</figref>, a plurality of trenches <b>15</b> are formed in the first conductive layers <b>13</b> and the insulating layers <b>14</b>. The trenches <b>15</b> may be formed using a photolithography process and/or an etching process. Portions of the first conductive layers <b>13</b> disposed in a plurality of rows along the sidewalls of the trenches <b>15</b> are identified as the first and second horizontal electrodes <b>11</b> and <b>12</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7F</figref>. Moreover, portions of the first conductive layers <b>13</b> disposed along the ends of the trenches <b>15</b> are identified as the first and second word lines <b>50</b><i>a </i>and <b>50</b><i>b </i>in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7F</figref>. Therefore, an appropriate number of the trenches <b>15</b> are formed according to the widths and number of the first and second horizontal electrodes <b>11</b> and <b>12</b> and first and second word lines <b>50</b><i>a </i>and <b>50</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7C</figref>, an anti-fuse layer <b>40</b> is formed in each trench <b>15</b>. In this example, each anti-fuse layer <b>40</b> is formed to extend across the inner sidewalls of the first conductive layers <b>13</b> and has a given, desired or predetermined thickness so as to partially (e.g., not to completely) fill the trenches <b>15</b>. The anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> may be oxide layers, nitride layers, oxy-nitride layers, or combinations of the layers and may include a material for forming an anti-fuse.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7C</figref>, a data layer <b>30</b> is formed on each anti-fuse layer <b>40</b> in each trench <b>15</b>. In this example, the data layers <b>30</b> extend across the inner sidewalls of the first conductive layers <b>13</b> and have a given, desired or predetermined thickness to partially fill (e.g., not completely fill) the trenches <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7D</figref>, second conductive layers <b>16</b> are formed on the data layers <b>30</b> to fill the trenches <b>15</b>. The second conductive layers <b>16</b> form the vertical electrodes <b>20</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7E</figref>. The second conductive layers <b>16</b> may be formed of semiconductor layers such as epitaxial layers or polysilicon layers, or a metal, as described with respect to the first conductive layers <b>13</b>. The second conductive layers <b>16</b> may be formed of the same as, substantially the same as, or a different material from the first conductive layers <b>13</b>. Also, the second conductive layers <b>16</b> may be doped with second conductive type impurities, which are opposite to the first conductive type impurities of the first conductive layers <b>13</b>. The second conductive layers <b>16</b> may be formed by forming a semiconductor layer or a metal layer using chemical vapor deposition and planarizing the semiconductor layer or the metal layer. The planarization may be performed using an etchback process or chemical-mechanical polishing (CMP).</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7E</figref>, the second conductive layers <b>16</b> are patterned to form a plurality of the vertical electrodes <b>20</b>. The patterning may be performed using a photolithography process and/or an etching process. The plurality of the vertical electrodes <b>20</b> may be patterned to be electrically separated or insulated from each other.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7F</figref>, each of the first conductive layers <b>13</b> are appropriately separated to define the first and second horizontal electrodes <b>11</b> and <b>12</b> and the first and second word lines <b>50</b><i>a </i>and <b>50</b><i>b</i>. The first word line <b>50</b><i>a </i>is connected to the first horizontal electrodes <b>11</b>, but separated from the second horizontal electrodes <b>12</b>. The second word line <b>50</b><i>b </i>is connected to the second horizontal electrodes <b>12</b>, but separated from the first horizontal electrodes <b>11</b>. For example, the structure of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7F</figref> may be formed by cutting between the first horizontal electrodes <b>11</b> and the second word line <b>50</b><i>b</i>, and between the second horizontal electrodes <b>12</b> and the first word line <b>50</b><i>a </i>in the structure of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7E</figref>. The cutting may be performed using a photolithography process and/or an etching process.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7G</figref>, the first conductive layers <b>13</b> and the insulating layers <b>14</b> are patterned to have a stepped structure. In the stepped structure, the first conductive layers <b>13</b> are exposed. The patterning may be performed several times using a photolithography process and/or an etching process. The order of forming the stepped structure is only an example and example embodiments are not limited thereto. For example, forming of the stepped structure may be performed before, after or directly after forming the plurality of trenches <b>15</b> in the first conductive layers <b>13</b> and the insulating layers <b>14</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</figref>. Contacts <b>60</b>, which are electrically connected to the first conductive layers <b>13</b> exposed in each step of the stepped structure, are formed on the exposed parts of the first conductive layers <b>13</b>. The first and second word lines <b>50</b><i>a </i>and <b>50</b><i>b </i>and the first and second horizontal electrodes <b>11</b> and <b>12</b> are electrically connected to the outside (e.g., an external device or apparatus) by the contacts <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8A through 8E</figref> are perspective views illustrating a method of manufacturing the non-volatile memory device according to another example embodiment of inventive concepts. The manufacturing method according to at least this example embodiment is a similar to the manufacturing method illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A through 7G</figref>, and thus, some descriptions will not be repeated here. For example, a manufacturing operation illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</figref> may follow the manufacturing operations illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A and 7B</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</figref>, anti-fuse layers <b>42</b> are formed in the trenches <b>15</b>. Each anti-fuse layer <b>42</b> extends across the inner sidewalls of the first conductive layers <b>13</b> and has a given, desired or predetermined thickness to partially fill (e.g., not completely fill) the trenches <b>15</b>. Data layers <b>32</b> are formed on the anti-fuse layers <b>42</b> so as to completely fill the trenches <b>15</b>. The data layers <b>32</b> may be formed using, for example, a chemical vapour deposition method and a planarization process. The planarization process may be performed by using an etchback process or CMP.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8B</figref>, the data layers <b>32</b> are patterned to form a plurality of holes <b>35</b> in the data layers <b>32</b>. The holes <b>35</b> may be formed using a photolithography process and/or an etching process. In this example, the holes <b>35</b> have a circular or substantially circular form. However, example embodiments are not limited thereto and the holes <b>35</b> may have a polygonal or elliptical form.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8C</figref>, the vertical electrodes <b>22</b> are formed on the data layers <b>32</b>. In one example, the vertical electrodes <b>22</b> may be formed by filling conductive materials in the holes <b>35</b> and planarizing the holes <b>35</b> using chemical vapour deposition. The vertical electrodes <b>22</b> may include second conductive type impurities.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8D</figref>, each of the first conductive layers <b>13</b> are appropriately separated to define the first and second horizontal electrodes <b>11</b> and <b>12</b> and the first and second word lines <b>50</b><i>a </i>and <b>50</b><i>b</i>. The first word line <b>50</b><i>a </i>is connected to the first horizontal electrodes <b>11</b>, but separated from the second horizontal electrodes <b>12</b>. The second word line <b>50</b><i>b </i>is connected to the second horizontal electrodes <b>12</b>, but separated from the first horizontal electrodes <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8E</figref>, the first conductive layers <b>13</b> and the insulating layers <b>14</b> are patterned to have a stepped structure. In the stepped structure, the first conductive layers <b>13</b> are exposed. The patterning may be performed several times using a photolithography process and/or an etching process. The contacts <b>60</b>, which are electrically connected to the first conductive layers <b>13</b> exposed in each step of the stepped structure, are formed on the exposed parts of the first conductive layers <b>13</b>. The first and second word lines <b>50</b><i>a </i>and <b>50</b><i>b </i>and the first and second horizontal electrodes <b>11</b> and <b>12</b> are electrically connected to the outside (e.g., an external device or apparatus) by the contacts <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">According to the manufacturing methods shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A through 7G</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8A through 8E</figref>, memory cells having a stacked-layer structure may be formed simultaneously or concurrently. Therefore, manufacturing costs may be reduced by simplifying manufacturing operations.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">Hereinafter, an example operation of a non-volatile memory device according to an example embodiment of inventive concepts will be described. In this example, the data layers <b>30</b> included in the non-volatile memory device are formed of variable resistance materials. The data layers <b>30</b> and the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> included in the non-volatile memory device according to this example embodiment are connected to each other in series. When an external voltage is applied to the data layers <b>30</b> and the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b>, a voltage V<sub>D </sub>applied to the data layers <b>30</b> and a voltage V<sub>A </sub>applied to the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> are represented by Equation 1 shown below.
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>V</i><sub>D</sub><i>=V R</i><sub>D</sub>/(<i>R</i><sub>D</sub><i>+R</i><sub>A</sub>),<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>V</i><sub>A</sub><i>=V R</i><sub>A</sub>/(<i>R</i><sub>D</sub><i>+R</i><sub>A</sub>)&#x2003;&#x2003;[Equation 1]<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
In Equation 1, R<sub>D </sub>and R<sub>A </sub>are resistances of the data layers <b>30</b> and the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b>, respectively, and V is an applied external voltage.
</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">Also, the relationship between a breakdown voltage V<sub>AB </sub>and a program voltage V<sub>p </sub>of the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b>, the relationship between a threshold voltage V<sub>TH </sub>and a program voltage V<sub>p </sub>of the data layer <b>30</b>, and the relationship between the breakdown voltage V<sub>AB </sub>and the threshold voltage V<sub>TH </sub>of the data layer <b>30</b> are represented by Equation 2 shown below.
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>V</i><sub>AB</sub><i>&#x2266;V</i><sub>P</sub><i>R</i><sub>A</sub><i>/R</i><sub>D</sub><i>+R</i><sub>A</sub>),<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>V</i><sub>TH</sub><i>&#x3c;V</i><sub>P</sub><i>R</i><sub>D</sub>/(<i>R</i><sub>D</sub><i>+R</i><sub>A</sub>),<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>V<sub>TH</sub>&#x3c;V<sub>AB</sub>&#x2003;&#x2003;[Equation 2]<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">Also, the relationship between the threshold voltage V<sub>TH </sub>and a reading voltage V<sub>R </sub>of the data layer <b>30</b> is represented by Equation 3 shown below.
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>V</i><sub>R</sub>/2<i>&#x3c;V</i><sub>TH</sub><i>&#x3c;V</i><sub>R</sub>&#x2003;&#x2003;[Equation 3]<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">In Equation 3, the lower limit V<sub>R</sub>/2 and the upper limit V<sub>R </sub>of the threshold voltage V<sub>TH </sub>of the data layer <b>30</b> are in a 3-level reading operation. However, inventive concepts are not limited thereto. For example, in a 4-level reading operation, the lower limit and the upper limit of the threshold voltage V<sub>TH </sub>of the data layer <b>30</b> may be changed to V<sub>R</sub>/3 and 2V<sub>R</sub>/3, respectively, or 2V<sub>R</sub>/3 and V<sub>R</sub>, respectively. Thicknesses, types of material, contact areas, or forms of the data layer <b>30</b> and the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> may be selected to satisfy the equations above.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a view schematically illustrating an example operation of a non-volatile memory device according to an example embodiment of inventive concepts.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the unit cells described above are disposed in regions where word lines W/L and bit lines B/L intersect each other. A part of the unit cells may be programmed, for example, by applying a program voltage to the unit cells. According to at least this example embodiment, insulating properties of the anti-fuse layers are lost in response to the program voltage. In this example, as described above, the program voltage V<sub>P </sub>is greater than the breakdown voltage V<sub>AB </sub>of the anti-fuse layers. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, a first unit cell X, a second unit cell Y, and a third unit cell Z are programmed, whereas the other unit cells are not programmed.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">A reading voltage V is then applied to read the first unit cell X. In at least this example embodiment, a 3-level reading operation, in which half of the reading voltage V is applied to non-read unit cells, is illustrated. However, inventive concepts are not limited thereto. The reading voltage V is applied to the word line W/L and the bit line B/L, which pass by the first unit cell X. For example, voltages with magnitudes of &#x201c;V&#x201d; and &#x201c;0&#x201d; may be applied to the word line W/L and the bit line B/L, respectively, which pass by the first unit cell X. Also, half of the reading voltage V (e.g., a voltage with a magnitude of &#x201c;V/2&#x201d;) is applied to the word lines W/L and the bit lines B/L, which do not pass by the first unit cell X. Accordingly, magnitudes of voltage &#x201c;V/2&#x201d; and &#x201c;0&#x201d; are respectively applied to the word lines W/L and the bit lines B/L with respect to the second unit cell Y. As a result, a voltage of &#x201c;V/2&#x201d; is applied to the second unit cell Y. Also, voltages with magnitudes of &#x201c;V&#x201d; and V/2&#x201d; are respectively applied to the word lines W/L and the bit lines B/L with respect to the third unit cell Z. As a result, a voltage of &#x201c;V/2&#x201d; is applied to the third unit cell Z. Moreover, a voltage of &#x201c;V/2&#x201d; is applied to all word lines W/L and the bit lines B/L with respect to the unit cells that are not programmed. As a result, a voltage of &#x201c;0&#x201d; is applied to the unit cells that are not programmed. The insulating properties of the anti-fuse layers <b>40</b> are broken down because the first unit cell X, the second unit cell Y, and the third unit cell Z are programmed. However, as described above, as the data layers <b>30</b> have the threshold voltage V<sub>TH </sub>that is greater than 2/V, the data layers <b>30</b> function as conductive layers in the first unit cell X, whereas the data layers <b>30</b> function as insulating layers in the second unit cell Y and the third unit cell Z. Accordingly, a memory function is available in the first unit cell X.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a graph showing an example voltage-current characteristic of the data layers formed of variable resistance materials and included in the non-volatile memory device according to example embodiments of inventive concepts.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, before a voltage applied to the variable resistive materials reaches the threshold voltage V<sub>TH</sub>, a current is nearly 0 and there is little change of current due to an increase of voltage. In other words, for example, the variable resistive materials have insulating properties before the threshold voltage V<sub>TH </sub>is applied. When a voltage applied to the variable resistive materials reaches the threshold voltage V<sub>TH</sub>, a current is increased relatively significantly and the variable resistance materials have a conduction-insulation transition property or a metal-insulation transition (MIT) property. Accordingly, after the application of the threshold voltage V<sub>TH</sub>, the variable resistive materials have a conductive property. A flowing current corresponds to an applied current. Such a current-voltage characteristic is partially shown in transition metal oxides such as vanadium oxide, V<sub>2</sub>O<sub>5</sub>, VO<sub>2</sub>, and/or VO. For example, when the variable resistance materials include V<sub>2</sub>O<sub>5</sub>, an insulation characteristic shown before the threshold voltage V<sub>TH </sub>is relatively good (e.g., excellent) and the conduction-insulation transition characteristic is shown in a relatively narrow voltage range. When the applied voltage is removed, the variable resistance materials may again have an insulating property. Although not illustrated, when a voltage decreases from the threshold voltage V<sub>TH</sub>, a current-voltage characteristic of the variable resistive materials may form a hysteresis loop.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a block diagram of a card according to an example embodiment of inventive concepts.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, a controller <b>510</b> and a memory <b>520</b> are disposed to send/receive electric signals to/from each other. In one example, the memory <b>520</b> sends data to the controller <b>510</b> in response to a command from the controller <b>510</b>. The memory <b>520</b> may include the non-volatile memory device <b>100</b> according to an example embodiment of inventive concepts. The non-volatile memory devices according to the various example embodiments may be disposed to have a NAND or NOR architecture array corresponding to the logic gate design. Such NAND and NOR arrays are generally known in the art. The memory arrays disposed in a plurality of rows and columns may have one or more memory array bank (not shown). The memory <b>520</b> may include the memory array (not shown) or the memory array bank (not shown), all of which are known in the art. The memory card <b>5000</b> may further include conventional components or elements such as a conventional row decoder (not shown), a column decoder (not shown), input/output (I/O) buffers (now shown), and/or a control resistance materials (not shown) to drive the memory array bank (not shown), all of which are known in the art. The memory card <b>5000</b> may be used in memory devices, for example, a memory card such as a memory stick card, a smart media (SM) card, a secure digital (SD) card, a mini SD card, a multi media card (MMC), etc.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a block diagram of a system according to an example embodiment of inventive concepts.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, the system <b>6000</b> includes a controller <b>610</b>, an input/output device <b>620</b>, a memory <b>630</b>, and an interface <b>640</b>. The system <b>6000</b> may be a mobile system or a system that transmits and/or receives data. The mobile system may be a personal digital assistant (PDA), a portable computer, a web tablet, a wireless phone, a mobile phone, a digital music player, a memory card, etc. The controller <b>610</b> may execute a software program and control the system <b>6000</b>. The controller <b>610</b> may be a microprocessor, a digital signal processor, a microcontroller, or the like. The input/output device <b>630</b> may be used to input or output data of the system <b>6000</b>. The system <b>6000</b> is connected to an external apparatus, for example, a personal computer or a network, using the input/output device <b>620</b>, to send/receive data to/from the external apparatus. The input/output device <b>620</b> may be a keypad, a keyboard, a display, etc. The memory <b>630</b> may store codes and/or data for operating the controller <b>610</b> and/or may store data processed by the controller <b>610</b>. The memory <b>630</b> may include a non-volatile memory device according to one or more example embodiments of inventive concepts. The interface <b>640</b> may be a data transmission path between the system <b>6000</b> and an external apparatus. The controller <b>610</b>, the input/output device <b>620</b>, the memory <b>630</b>, and the interface <b>640</b> communicate with one another via a bus <b>650</b>. For example, the system <b>6000</b> may be used for, or incorporated into, a mobile phone, a MP3 player, a navigation system, a portable multimedia player (PMP), a solid state disk (SSD), a household appliance, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">The foregoing is illustrative of example embodiments and is not to be construed as limiting of inventive concepts. Although example embodiments have been described, those of ordinary skill in the art will readily appreciate that many modifications are possible in example embodiments without materially departing from the novel teachings and advantages of example embodiments. Accordingly, all such modifications are intended to be included within the scope of the claims. Example embodiments are defined by the following claims, with equivalents of the claims to be included therein.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A non-volatile memory device comprising:
<claim-text>at least one horizontal electrode being one of an n-type layer and a p-type layer, the at least one horizontal electrode disposed lengthwise in a horizontal direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one vertical electrode being one of the n-type layer and the p-type layer that is different from the at least one horizontal electrode, the at least one vertical electrode disposed lengthwise in a vertical direction perpendicular to the at least one horizontal electrode such that the at least one vertical electrode intersects the at least one horizontal electrode at an intersecting region;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one data layer disposed at the intersecting region, and having a conduction-insulation transition property; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one anti-fuse layer connected in series with the at least one data layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The non-volatile memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one data layer includes a transition metal oxide.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The non-volatile memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one data layer includes a vanadium oxide, an aluminum oxide, a bismuth oxide, a titanium oxide, a niobium oxide, a nickel oxide, a copper oxide, zinc oxide, a tin oxide, a zirconium oxide, a silicon oxide, a hafnium oxide, a cobalt oxide, an iron oxide, or combinations thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The non-volatile memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one data layer includes V.sub.20.sub.5, VO.sub.2, VO, or combinations thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The non-volatile memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one anti-fuse layer includes oxide layers, nitride layers, oxy-nitride layers, or combinations thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The non-volatile memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one data layer has a threshold voltage that is less than a breakdown voltage of the at least one anti-fuse layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The non-volatile memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one anti-fuse layer is interposed at the intersecting region between the at least one data layer and the at least one horizontal electrode.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The non-volatile memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one anti-fuse layer is interposed at the intersection region between the at least one data layer and the at least one vertical electrode.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The non-volatile memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of the at least one data layers and the at least one anti-fuse layers have a pattern at the intersecting region.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The non-volatile memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of the at least one horizontal electrode and the at least one vertical electrode include one or more trenches formed at the intersecting region, and wherein
<claim-text>at least one of the at least one data layer and the at least one anti-fuse layer are disposed in the one or more trenches.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The non-volatile memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of the at least one data layer and the at least one anti-fuse layer are disposed to surround the at least one vertical electrode.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The non-volatile memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one horizontal electrode and the at least one vertical electrode are disposed to cross each other at a right angle.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The non-volatile memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of the at least one horizontal electrode and the at least one vertical electrode include polysilicon, tungsten (W), aluminum (Al), copper (Cu), molybdenum (Mo), titanium (Ti), tantalum (Ta), ruthenium (Ru), platinum (Pt), palladium (Pd), nickel (Ni), gold (Au), silver (Ag), beryllium (Be), bismuth (Bi), hafnium (Hf), indium (In), manganese (Mn), molybdenum (Mo), lead (Pb), rhodium (Rh), rhenium (Re), tellium (Te), zinc (Zn), zirconium (Zr), cobalt (Co), iridium (Ir), platinum (Pt), an alloy thereof, an oxide thereof, a nitride thereof, a silicide thereof, or a combination thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The non-volatile memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one data layer has a width at least equal to a width of the at least one vertical electrode.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A non-volatile memory device comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of horizontal electrodes stacked in a plurality of layers, each of the plurality of horizontal electrodes being one of an n-type layer and a p-type laver, the plurality horizontal electrodes disposed lengthwise in a horizontal direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of vertical electrodes formed in a plurality of rows, each of the plurality of vertical electrodes being one of the n-type layer and the p-type layer that is different from an associated one of the plurality of horizontal electrodes, the plurality of vertical electrodes disposed lengthwise in a vertical direction perpendicular to the plurality of horizontal electrodes such that the plurality of vertical electrodes intersects with the plurality of horizontal electrodes at intersecting regions;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of data layers, each of the plurality of data layers being disposed at a corresponding intersecting region and having a conduction-insulation transition property; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of anti-fuse layers, each of the plurality of anti-fuse layers being connected in series with a corresponding data layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The non-volatile memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of data layers extend across stacked layers of the plurality of horizontal electrodes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The non-volatile memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of anti-fuse layers extend across stacked layers of the plurality of horizontal electrodes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The non-volatile memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein each of the plurality of horizontal electrodes includes a plurality of first horizontal electrodes and a plurality of second horizontal electrodes that are spaced apart from each other.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A non-volatile memory device comprising:
<claim-text>first conductive layers, each of the first conductive layers being one of an n-type layer and a p-type layer, the first conductive layers disposed lengthwise in a horizontal direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>second conductive layers configured to face the first conductive layers, each of the second conductive layers being one of the n-type layer and the p-type layer that is different from an associated one of the first conductive layers, the second conductive layers disposed lengthwise in a vertical direction perpendicular to the first conductive layers such that the second conductive layers intersect with the first conductive layers at intersecting regions;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of data layers, each of the plurality of data layers being interposed between the first and second conductive layers and having a conduction-insulation transition property; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of anti-fuse layers, each of the plurality of anti-fuse layers being interposed between the first and second conductive layers and being connected to the plurality of data layers.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The non-volatile memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one of anti-fuse layer has a width at least equal to the width of the at least one vertical electrode.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
