<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08627182-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08627182</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12643636</doc-number>
<date>20091221</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>1049</us-term-extension>
<disclaimer>
<text>This patent is subject to a terminal disclaimer.</text>
</disclaimer>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>M</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>714774</main-classification>
<further-classification>714817</further-classification>
<further-classification>375345</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e55">Impulse noise mitigation</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4068174</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Svelund</name>
<date>19780100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5311087</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Suganuma</name>
<date>19940500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5377276</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Terai et al.</name>
<date>19941200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5495229</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Balch et al.</name>
<date>19960200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>3405724</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5499189</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Seitz</name>
<date>19960300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>700286</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5657244</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Seitz</name>
<date>19970800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5703904</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Langberg</name>
<date>19971200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>375232</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5943637</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Okumura et al.</name>
<date>19990800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6920194</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Stopler et al.</name>
<date>20050700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>375349</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7274794</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Rasmussen</name>
<date>20070900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0043925</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Stopler et al.</name>
<date>20030300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>375254</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0078044</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Norrell et al.</name>
<date>20060400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>375222</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00013">
<othercit>International Search Report and Written Opinion of the International Searching Authority for International Application No. PCT/US06/42399, mailed on Dec. 15, 2008, 9 pages.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>714817</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>714774</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>375345</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11267591</doc-number>
<date>20051104</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7665012</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12643636</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20100098188</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20100422</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Starr</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas</first-name>
<address>
<city>Barrington</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Starr</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas</first-name>
<address>
<city>Barrington</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Toler Law Group, PC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>AT&#x26;T Intellectual Property I, L.P.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Atlanta</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Chaudry</last-name>
<first-name>M. Mujtaba K</first-name>
<department>2112</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Systems and methods to mitigate impulse noise are provided. A particular method includes providing a signal from a transmission source to a mitigator. The mitigator checks the signal for complex impulse noise comprising at least a first periodic impulse noise component correlated to a first portion of a sinusoid representing frequency of an alternating current power source associated with the transmission source and a second periodic impulse noise component correlated to a second portion of the sinusoid. The method further includes receiving noise mitigation instructions from the mitigator at the transmission source to compensate for the complex impulse noise.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="185.34mm" wi="172.89mm" file="US08627182-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="232.83mm" wi="177.63mm" file="US08627182-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="232.49mm" wi="128.27mm" file="US08627182-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="159.43mm" wi="159.34mm" file="US08627182-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="196.77mm" wi="172.04mm" file="US08627182-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="215.90mm" wi="158.83mm" file="US08627182-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CLAIM OF PRIORITY</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation application of and claims priority to U.S. patent application Ser. No. 11/267,591 filed Nov. 4, 2005, the contents of which are expressly incorporated herein by reference in their entirety.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to telecommunications, and in particular to methods, systems, and devices to mitigate impulse noise in telecommunications transmission media.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Digital transmission systems, such as digital subscriber lines (DSL), radio, and coaxial cable are subject to transmission errors due to noise induced into the transmission media. Some noise, such as crosstalk and radio frequency interference, is relatively constant. Other noise sources including light dimmers, power supplies, light flashers, and gas discharge lighting systems (e.g., fluorescent lighting systems) produce impulse noise. Impulse noise produces noise of a brief duration, and is often quite severe during the brief interval. Some sources of impulse noise produce periodic impulses. Impulse noise often has a high amplitude that can overwhelm most methods to mitigate noise.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">An impulse may occur during the rising edge of a sinusoid and a second impulse may occur during the falling edge. This causes a complex pattern involving two different intervals. Existing techniques do not fully address the impulse noise problems associated with complex periodic behavior such as patterns involving more than one repeating time period between impulses.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a high level process flow of a specific exemplary embodiment of a method of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a high level process flow of a specific exemplary alternative embodiment of a method of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic diagrammatic illustration of a specific embodiment of an impulse noise mitigation system of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagrammatic representation of a specific exemplary embodiment of a signal transmission network of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a block diagram of an illustrative embodiment of a general computer system.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In view of the foregoing, the present disclosure, through description of one or more various aspects, embodiments and/or specific features or sub-components, is intended to bring out one or more of the advantages that will be evident from the description. The terminology, examples, drawings and embodiments are illustrative and not intended to limit the scope of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The present disclosure addresses impulse noise mitigation that applies to many forms of digital transmission, for example DSL, radio, and coaxial cable transceivers. Digital transmission systems commonly employ three techniques to protect against noise (both constant noise and impulse noise): signal power, frequency band filtering, and error correcting codes. All of these techniques have drawbacks of substantially reducing the payload capacity of the transmission system. The techniques often fail to fully protect against impulse noise.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">To make the signal more powerful than the noise, the transmitted signal power may be increased beyond what would be necessary if there were no impulse noise. The power technique, however, may often be ineffective for impulse noise due to the high amplitude of impulse noise, and can add costs to the system. Certain portions of the frequency band may be blocked by filters at the receiver in an effort to block most of the noise. The filter technique may often be ineffective for impulse noise due to the wideband nature of impulse noise, and frequency filtering greatly reduces the payload capacity of the system. Error correcting codes including Trellis codes, Turbo codes, parity codes, Reed-Solomon codes, and Cyclic Redundancy Check (CRC) codes may be employed in a Forward Error Control (FEC) technique or in an Automatic Repeat Request (ARQ)&#x2014;such as used for the TCP-IP protocol.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Interleaving may be employed to help a FEC technique to address bursts of errors. Interleaving has the drawback of increasing signal latency. Interleaved FEC techniques may be effective for addressing small bursts of errors, but impulse noise can produce error bursts of duration so long that excessive FEC redundancy may be needed to overcome the errors. Thus, interleaved FEC techniques may have the drawbacks of adding latency and greatly reducing payload capacity when attempting to overcome long bursts of errors.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">A recent technique to mitigate periodic impulse noise tracks the recent history of intervals between episodes of impulse noise to predict when the next episode will occur. During the predicted episodes of impulse noise, two mitigation techniques may be employed to reduce noise: (1) increase FEC redundancy during the interval, or (2) reduce the amount of payload data. Both of these mitigation techniques greatly reduce the payload capacity (in the extreme case payload becomes zero), but the capacity reduction applies only during the brief predicted noise episodes.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The technique of increasing FEC redundancy combats impulse noise by using a high redundancy FEC technique with powerful error correcting abilities during the predicted noise episodes while using a different FEC technique with much less overhead during the quiet periods.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The payload-reduction technique combats impulse noise by reducing the number of data bits sent during the predicted noise interval to increase the signal-to-noise ratio during the predicted noise interval, and also reducing the number of data bits at risk. In the extreme, the number of data bits may be reduced to zero during the predicted noise interval to provide the ultimate error reduction&#x2014;at the cost of reduced payload capacity.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The prediction technique provides effective protection against periodic impulse noise with no added latency, and relatively little reduction in average payload capacity. The effectiveness of the technique generally relies on substantially accurate predictions of when future impulse intervals will occur. The technique involves the observation of the recent history of received noise impulses to determine a simple periodic interval between impulses.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The prediction technique measures the time period between past impulse noise events. It provides for the ability to track changes in the period between impulses, but the tracking is not precise. Due to practical limits on timing accuracy, and changes in the phase of the occurrences of periodic impulses, the prediction of future impulse intervals may not be exact. The technique does not necessarily directly synchronize the impulse with the power line frequency. Furthermore, the technique does not specifically address complex periodic behavior such as patterns involving more than one repeating time period between impulses.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Periodic impulse noise caused by power line related sources may occur precisely at certain points in the phase of the sinusoidal power line frequency. For example, many light dimmers turn the flow of current off and on at certain points in the sinusoidal power line frequency (60 Hz in the United States). Additionally, multiple impulse noise sources may be present that occur at different points during the phase of the power line frequency. For example, one impulse may occur during a point during the rising edge of the sinusoid and a second impulse may occur during the falling edge. The result is a complex pattern involving two different intervals.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Under the present disclosure, the time of the occurrence of an impulse noise interval is substantially correlated to the phase of the power line frequency (e.g., 60 Hz in the United States). The receiver observes the recent history of impulses noise to determine at which point in the phase of the power line frequency impulses occur. Impulses may be detected by CRC error check indications, or a sudden increase in received signal power (either wide-band power, or power in certain narrow frequency bands).</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In a particular embodiment, a method includes determining whether impulse noise of a cable carrying a digital signal is complex impulse noise. Complex impulse noise includes a plurality of impulse noise components. The method further includes determining whether the complex impulse noise is synchronized with a phase of an alternating current (AC) power line transmission. The method further includes identifying a first impulse noise component of the plurality of impulse noise components that is synchronized with the phase. The first impulse noise component is associated with a first noise source. The method further includes identifying a second impulse noise component of the plurality of impulse noise components that is synchronized with the phase. The second impulse noise component is associated with a second noise source. The method further includes determining a first duration of the first impulse noise component and a second duration of the second impulse noise component. The method further includes predicting a first time interval between occurrences of the first impulse component and a second time interval between occurrences of the second impulse component. The method also includes applying one or more noise mitigation techniques based on the first time interval and the first duration and based on the second time interval and the second duration.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In a particular embodiment, a method includes providing a signal from a transmission source to a mitigator. The mitigator checks the signal for complex impulse noise comprising at least a first periodic impulse noise component correlated to a first portion of a sinusoid representing frequency of an alternating current power source associated with the transmission source and a second periodic impulse noise component correlated to a second portion of the sinusoid. The method further includes receiving noise mitigation instructions from the mitigator at the transmission source to compensate for the complex impulse noise. The noise mitigation instructions to compensate for the first periodic impulse noise component include instructions to be repeatedly applied at a first time interval for a first duration. The noise mitigation instructions to compensate for the second periodic impulse noise component include instructions to be repeatedly applied at a second time interval for a second duration.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In a particular embodiment, a method includes determining whether a signal carried by a digital subscriber line includes complex impulse noise. Complex impulse noise includes at least a first periodic impulse component correlatable to a phase of an alternating power source that induces the first periodic impulse component in the signal due to a first noise source and a second periodic impulse component correlatable to the phase of the alternating power source that induces the second periodic impulse component in the signal due to a second noise source. The method further includes determining a first time interval and a first duration for the first periodic impulse component. The method further includes determining a second time interval and a second duration for the second periodic impulse component. The method also includes applying at least a first mitigation technique, based on the first time interval and the first duration, and a second mitigation technique, based on the second time interval and the second duration, to the signal to compensate for the complex impulse noise.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a high level process flow of a specific exemplary embodiment of a method of the present disclosure. The method of the embodiment involves detecting <b>110</b> impulses that generate impulse noise in a signal transmission medium, such as an ac power line. Noise data may be analyzed by a computer to determine <b>112</b> whether the impulses result in a simple periodic impulse sequence <b>113</b> or a complex impulse sequence <b>114</b>. A complex impulse sequence <b>114</b> may be produced, for example, by two or more independently periodic impulse sequences. In the case of complex impulse sequence <b>114</b>, the method may involve determining <b>116</b> whether the complex sequence may be correlated to the phase of the ac power line frequency. Such correlation may not always be attainable due to the complexity of the impulse sequence. In the case where the complex sequence is not correlated to the phase of the power line frequency, the method involves analyzing the complex sequence, selecting <b>122</b> one or more suitable noise mitigation measures to apply with respect to the noise, and applying the selected measure or measures with respect to the noise.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Continuing with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the method further involves correlating <b>120</b> the time that the impulse occurs to the frequency phase of the transmission medium in the case where the impulse noise results from a relatively simple periodic impulse sequence <b>113</b> or in the case where a complex impulse sequence may nevertheless be correlated <b>117</b> to the phase of the line frequency. The method then involves selecting <b>122</b> one or more noise mitigation measures or techniques and applying the selected noise mitigation technique or techniques <b>130</b> with respect to the noise. Signal transmission errors that might otherwise arise as a result of the periodic or complex impulse noise may thus be reduced by implementing any one or more suitable noise mitigation techniques known to those skilled in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a high level process flow of a specific exemplary alternative embodiment of a method of the present disclosure. Multiple power line cycles may be measured to: (1) determine if the noise impulses are periodic <b>210</b>, (2) if the noise impulses are at least approximately synchronized with the ac power line phase <b>220</b>, (3) perform averaging of the phase from several power line cycles <b>230</b>, (4) determine at least approximately the point of the power line phase where the periodic impulses occur <b>240</b>, and (5) determine at least the approximate duration of impulses when they occur <b>250</b>. Such measurements enable the accurate, or at least approximate, prediction of future periodic noise intervals <b>260</b>. Signal transmissions errors may be reduced by applying <b>270</b> any one or more of the noise mitigation techniques described herein or otherwise known to those skilled in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic diagrammatic illustration of a specific exemplary embodiment of a periodic impulse noise detection system of the present disclosure. The phase of ac power line <b>310</b> may be detected by directly connecting detector apparatus <b>330</b> to secondary winding <b>325</b> of ac power line transformer <b>320</b>, or alternatively measuring the 60 Hz, or in some places 50 Hz, signal induced <b>340</b> onto antenna <b>350</b>. Apparatus <b>330</b> may include a detector in communication with a remote impulse noise mitigator having a computer, microprocessor chip or board that receives data from the detector, processes the data to select one or more noise mitigation techniques, and applies the techniques to line <b>310</b>. Alternatively, apparatus <b>330</b> may include a detector and a noise mitigator integrated in apparatus <b>330</b> to operate as just described.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">With respect to the data processing performed by the noise mitigator of apparatus <b>330</b>, the processing may include analyzing the data to determine whether or not there is a complex impulse sequence such as may occur from two or more independently periodic impulse sequences. A complex impulse noise sequence may or may not be correlated (or correlatable) to the phase of ac power line <b>310</b> for the simple reason that the sequence is complex. Accordingly, in a case where the impulse noise is a consequence of a complex impulse sequence, apparatus <b>330</b> may select one or more noise mitigation techniques to apply to line <b>310</b> without correlating the impulses to the phase of line <b>310</b>, particularly when the sequence is sufficiently complex to defeat attempts to make the correlation.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">With respect to the selection by apparatus <b>330</b> of one or more noise mitigation techniques, apparatus <b>330</b> may select the use of different noise mitigation measures in distinct frequency bands. For example, for Very-High-Bit-Rate Digital Subscriber Line 2 (VDSL2), one selected measure may include the application of one selected degree of interleaving for information transmitted below 3.75 MHz and a different selected degree of interleaving for information transmitted above 3.75 MHz.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagrammatic representation of a specific exemplary embodiment of a signal transmission network of the present disclosure. Network <b>410</b> includes, but is not necessarily limited to, transmission medium <b>412</b> and a plurality of transmission nodes <b>414</b>, such as for example, landline towers or poles, or cellular towers. Network <b>410</b> further includes transformer <b>420</b> having secondary winding <b>422</b>. Detector or sensor <b>435</b>, connected to winding <b>422</b> detects impulse <b>440</b>. A computer, also referred to herein at times as a noise mitigator, <b>436</b>, processes data from detector <b>435</b> to determine whether the impulse noise is periodic or complex and whether the times of occurrences of the impulses may be correlated, at least approximately, to the phase of the frequency of the transmission medium, and applies impulse noise mitigation measures <b>438</b> with respect to the impulse noise.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Computer <b>436</b> may be remotely in communication with detector <b>435</b>, depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> under reference letter B or, additionally or alternatively, may be integrated with detector <b>435</b>, depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> under reference letter A, in the form of, for example, a programmable microprocessor chip or board <b>436</b> having machine-readable media to process data and execute programmed instructions encoded on the media. Accordingly, detector <b>435</b> and computer or processor <b>436</b>, whether remote or integrated, may be referred to collectively as a noise mitigation apparatus <b>430</b> such that apparatus <b>430</b> detects noise impulses, processes information related to the impulses and applies one or more mitigation techniques such as, for example, an error correcting code with respect to the noise.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The disclosure further contemplates the detection of multiple power line synchronized impulse noise sequences at different points in the power line phase. For example, one impulse may occur each time the power line sinusoid is at X degrees phase, and a second impulse may occur each time the power line sinusoid is at Y degrees phase.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The disclosure yet further contemplates a transmission system having multiple frequency bands, where each frequency band may be separately monitored for the effects of periodic impulse noise. In the event that some bands have little or no degradation during the impulse noise intervals, then error mitigation techniques apply only to those frequency bands that exceed a pre-selected or pre-defined noise threshold.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">While the disclosure addresses impulse noise that is substantially synchronized with the power line phase, the methods of the disclosure may also be combined with other noise mitigation techniques to simultaneously protect against multiple types of noise. For example, Trellis or Turbo coding may be employed at all times to protect against constant noise, while the methods described in this disclosure may be used to provide additional protection during the predicted impulse noise intervals. Also, the predictive periodic noise mitigation technique described above may be used simultaneously in combination with the methods and systems of the present disclosure to protect against periodic noise that is not synchronized to the power line frequency.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">A system of the disclosure may continuously monitor the pattern of noise impulses to detect changes in the phase, the appearance of additional impulse sequences, and the cessation of some or all periodic impulse sequences. Continuous monitoring may be of particular utility for tracking changes in the impulse noise so that the predicted noise intervals are based on recent environmental behavior. During the predicted impulse noise intervals two techniques may be used to protect against transmission errors: (1) increase FEC redundancy during the interval, or (2) reduce the amount of payload data (including possibly no data during the interval).</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The disclosure addresses the protection of digital transmission systems from errors caused by periodic impulse noise synchronous to the power line frequency. The protection is achieved without reducing payload capacity during the periods between the impulse noise episodes, and without increasing signal latency. Furthermore, the techniques of the disclosure protect against multiple simultaneous impulse noise producing phenomena.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In accordance with various embodiments of the present disclosure, the methods described herein are intended for operation as software programs running on a programmable machine such as a computer processor. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a diagrammatic representation of a machine in the form of a computer system <b>500</b> within which a set of instructions, when executed, may cause the machine to perform any one or more of the methodologies discussed herein. In some embodiments, the machine operates as a standalone device. In some embodiments, the machine may be connected (e.g., using a network) to other machines. In a networked deployment, the machine may operate in the capacity of a server or a client user machine in server-client user network environment, or as a peer machine in a peer-to-peer (or distributed) network environment. The machine may comprise a server computer, a client user computer, a digital signal processor (DSP), a microprocessor, a modem, a personal computer (PC), a tablet PC, a set-top box (STB), a Personal Digital Assistant (PDA), a cellular telephone, a mobile device, a palmtop computer, a laptop computer, a desktop computer, a personal digital assistant, a communications device, a wireless telephone, a land-line telephone, a control system, a camera, a scanner, a facsimile machine, a printer, a pager, a personal trusted device, a web appliance, a network router, switch or bridge, or any machine capable of executing a set of instructions (sequential or otherwise) that specify actions to be taken by that machine. It will be understood that a device of the present disclosure includes broadly any electronic device that provides voice, video or data communication. Further, while a single machine is illustrated, the term &#x201c;machine&#x201d; shall also be taken to include any collection of machines that individually or jointly execute a set (or multiple sets) of instructions to perform any one or more of the methodologies discussed herein.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The computer system <b>500</b> may include a processor <b>502</b> (e.g., a central processing unit (CPU), a graphics processing unit (GPU), or both), a main memory <b>504</b> and a static memory <b>506</b>, which communicate with each other via a bus <b>508</b>. The computer system <b>500</b> may further include a video display unit <b>510</b> (e.g., a liquid crystal display (LCD), a flat panel, a solid state display, or a cathode ray tube (CRT)). The computer system <b>500</b> may include an input device <b>512</b> (e.g., a keyboard), a cursor control device <b>514</b> (e.g., a mouse), a disk drive unit <b>516</b>, a signal generation device <b>518</b> (e.g., a speaker or remote control) and a network interface device <b>520</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The disk drive unit <b>516</b> may include a machine-readable medium <b>522</b> on which is stored one or more sets of instructions (e.g., software <b>524</b>) embodying any one or more of the methodologies or functions described herein, including those methods illustrated in herein above. The instructions <b>524</b> may also reside, completely or at least partially, within the main memory <b>504</b>, the static memory <b>506</b>, and/or within the processor <b>502</b> during execution thereof by the computer system <b>500</b>. The main memory <b>504</b> and the processor <b>502</b> also may constitute machine-readable media.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Dedicated hardware implementations including, but not limited to, application specific integrated circuits, programmable logic arrays and other hardware devices can likewise be constructed to implement the methods described herein. Applications that may include the apparatus and systems of various embodiments broadly include a variety of electronic and computer systems. Some embodiments implement functions in two or more specific interconnected hardware modules or devices with related control and data signals communicated between and through the modules, or as portions of an application-specific integrated circuit. Thus, the example system is applicable to software, firmware, and hardware implementations.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In accordance with various embodiments of the present disclosure, the methods described herein are intended for operation as software programs running on a computer processor. Furthermore, software implementations can include, but not limited to, distributed processing or component/object distributed processing, parallel processing, or virtual machine processing can also be constructed to implement the methods described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The present disclosure contemplates a machine readable medium containing instructions <b>524</b>, or that which receives and executes instructions <b>524</b> from a propagated signal so that a device connected to a network environment <b>526</b> can send or receive voice, video or data, and to communicate over the network <b>526</b> using the instructions <b>524</b>. The instructions <b>524</b> may further be transmitted or received over a network <b>526</b> via the network interface device <b>520</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">While the machine-readable medium <b>522</b> is shown in an example embodiment to be a single medium, the term &#x201c;machine-readable medium&#x201d; should be taken to include a single medium or multiple media (e.g., a centralized or distributed database, and/or associated caches and servers) that store the one or more sets of instructions. The term &#x201c;machine-readable medium&#x201d; shall also be taken to include any medium that is capable of storing or encoding a set of instructions for execution by the machine and that cause the machine to perform any one or more of the methodologies of the present disclosure. Dedicated hardware implementations including, but not limited to, application specific integrated circuits, programmable logic arrays and other hardware devices can likewise be constructed to implement the methods described herein. Furthermore, alternative software implementations including, but not limited to, distributed processing or component/object distributed processing, parallel processing, or virtual machine processing can also be constructed to implement the methods described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">It should also be noted that the software implementations of the present disclosure as described herein are optionally stored on a tangible storage medium, such as: a magnetic medium such as a disk or tape; a magneto-optical or optical medium such as a disk; or a solid state medium such as a memory card or other package that houses one or more read-only (non-volatile) memories, random access memories, or other re-writable (volatile) memories. The disclosure is considered to include a storage medium as listed herein and including art-recognized equivalents and successor media, in which the software implementations herein are stored.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Those skilled in the art will recognize that the present disclosure extends to machine-readable media (&#x201c;MRM&#x201d;) contain instructions for execution by a programmable machine such as a computer. MRM is broadly defined to include any kind of computer memory such as floppy disks, conventional hard disks, CD-ROMs, Flash ROMS, nonvolatile ROM, RAM, Storage Media, email attachments, solid state media, magnetic media, and signals containing instructions, together with processors to execute the instructions.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The term &#x201c;machine-readable medium&#x201d; shall accordingly be taken to further include, but not be limited to: solid-state memories such as a memory card or other package that houses one or more read-only (non-volatile) memories, random access memories, or other re-writable (volatile) memories; magneto-optical or optical medium such as a disk or tape. Accordingly, the disclosure is considered to include any one or more of a machine-readable medium, as listed herein and including art-recognized equivalents and successor media, in which the software implementations herein are stored.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Although the present specification describes components and functions implemented in the embodiments with reference to particular standards and protocols, the disclosure is not limited to such standards and protocols. Each of the standards for Internet and other packet switched network transmission (e.g., ATM, TCP/IP, UDP/IP, HTML, HTTP) represent examples of the state of the art. Such standards are periodically superseded by faster or more efficient equivalents having essentially the same functions. Accordingly, replacement standards and protocols having the same functions are considered equivalents.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The illustrations of embodiments described herein are intended to provide a general understanding of the structure of various embodiments, and they are not intended to serve as a complete description of all the elements and features of apparatus and systems that might make use of the structures described herein. Many other embodiments will be apparent to those of skill in the art upon reviewing the above description. Other embodiments may be utilized and derived therefrom, such that structural and logical substitutions and changes may be made without departing from the scope of this disclosure. Figures are merely representational and may not be drawn to scale. Certain proportions thereof may be exaggerated, while others may be minimized. Accordingly, the specification and drawings are to be regarded in an illustrative rather than a restrictive sense.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Such embodiments of the inventive subject matter may be referred to herein, individually and/or collectively, by the term &#x201c;disclosure&#x201d; merely for convenience and without intending to voluntarily limit the scope of this application to any single invention or inventive concept if more than one is in fact disclosed. Thus, although specific embodiments have been illustrated and described herein, it should be appreciated that any arrangement calculated to achieve the same purpose may be substituted for the specific embodiments shown. This disclosure is intended to cover any and all adaptations or variations of various embodiments. Combinations of the above embodiments, and other embodiments not specifically described herein, will be apparent to those of skill in the art upon reviewing the above description.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The Abstract of the Disclosure is provided with the understanding that it will not be used to interpret or limit the scope or meaning of the claims. In addition, in the foregoing Detailed Description, various features may be grouped together or described in a single embodiment for the purpose of streamlining the disclosure. This disclosure is not to be interpreted as reflecting an intention that the claimed embodiments require more features than are expressly recited in each claim. Rather, as the following claims reflect, inventive subject matter may be directed to less than all of the features of any of the disclosed embodiments. Thus, the following claims are incorporated into the Detailed Description, with each claim standing on its own as defining separately claimed subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The above-disclosed subject matter is to be considered illustrative, and not restrictive, and the appended claims are intended to cover all such modifications, enhancements, and other embodiments, which fall within the scope of the present invention. Thus, to the maximum extent allowed by law, the scope of the present invention is to be determined by the broadest permissible interpretation of the following claims and their equivalents, and shall not be restricted or limited by the foregoing detailed description.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method, comprising:
<claim-text>determining whether impulse noise of a cable carrying a digital signal is complex impulse noise, wherein the complex impulse noise includes a plurality of impulse noise components;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining whether the complex impulse noise is synchronized with a phase of an alternating current power line transmission;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying a first impulse noise component of the plurality of impulse noise components that is synchronized with the phase, wherein the first impulse noise component is associated with a first noise source;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying a second impulse noise component of the plurality of impulse noise components that is synchronized with the phase, wherein the second impulse noise component is associated with a second noise source;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a first duration of the first impulse noise component and a second duration of the second impulse noise component;</claim-text>
<claim-text>predicting a first time interval between occurrences of the first impulse component and a second time interval between occurrences of the second impulse component; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a noise mitigation technique based on the first time interval and the first duration and based on the second time interval and the second duration.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising stopping application of the noise mitigation technique based on the first time interval and the first duration when the first component of the plurality of impulse noise components no longer is part of the complex impulse noise.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first noise source comprises a light dimmer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first noise source comprises gas discharge lighting.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first duration is an average duration of the first impulse noise component over a first plurality of cycles of the phase, and wherein the second duration is an average duration of the second impulse noise component over a second plurality of cycles of the phase.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the first time interval is an average time interval between occurrences of the first impulse component over the first plurality of cycles of the phase and wherein the second impulse component is an average time interval between occurrences of the second impulse component over the second plurality of cycles of the phase.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the noise mitigation technique includes reducing an amount of payload data at a start of each repeating first time interval for the first duration.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein no data is transmitted during each repeating first time interval.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the noise mitigation technique includes increasing forward error correction redundancy during the first duration beginning at each time interval.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A method, comprising:
<claim-text>providing a signal from a transmission source to a mitigator, wherein the mitigator checks the signal for complex impulse noise comprising a first periodic impulse noise component correlated to a first portion of a sinusoid representing frequency of an alternating current power source associated with the transmission source and a second periodic impulse noise component correlated to a second portion of the sinusoid; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving noise mitigation instructions from the mitigator at the transmission source to compensate for the first periodic impulse noise component and for the second periodic impulse noise component, wherein the noise mitigation instructions to compensate for the first periodic impulse noise component include instructions to be repeatedly applied at a first time interval for a first duration, and wherein the noise mitigation instructions to compensate for the second periodic impulse noise component include instructions to be repeatedly applied at a second time interval for a second duration.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising receiving noise mitigation instructions to compensate for constant noise.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising receiving noise mitigation instructions to compensate for impulse noise that does not correlate to the sinusoid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the noise mitigation instructions to compensate for the first periodic impulse noise component include instructions to increase forward error correction redundancy during the first duration beginning at each first time interval.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the noise mitigation instructions to compensate for the first periodic impulse noise component include instructions to reduce an amount of payload data during the first duration beginning at each first time interval.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the first time interval is an average position on the sinusoid of a beginning of the first periodic impulse noise component taken over a plurality of cycles of the alternating current power source, and where the first duration is an average duration of the first periodic impulse noise component over the plurality of cycles.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A method, comprising:
<claim-text>determining whether a signal carried by a digital subscriber line includes complex impulse noise, wherein the complex impulse noise includes a first periodic impulse component correlatable to a phase of an alternating power source that induces the first periodic impulse component in the signal due to a first noise source, and a second periodic impulse component correlatable to the phase of the alternating power source that induces the second periodic impulse component in the signal due to a second noise source;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a first time interval and a first duration for the first periodic impulse component;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a second time interval and a second duration for the second periodic impulse component; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a first mitigation technique, based on the first time interval and the first duration, and a second mitigation technique, based on the second time interval and the second duration, to the signal to compensate for the complex impulse noise.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, further comprising receiving noise mitigation instructions to compensate for constant noise.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, further comprising receiving noise mitigation instructions to compensate for impulse noise that does not correlate to the phase of the alternating power source.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the first mitigation technique comprises reducing an amount of payload data in the signal during the first duration beginning at each first time interval.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the first mitigation technique comprises increasing forward error correction redundancy during the first duration beginning at each first time interval. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
