<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624444-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624444</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13491246</doc-number>
<date>20120607</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>51</main-group>
<subgroup>34</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>307154</main-classification>
<further-classification>307132 R</further-classification>
<further-classification>122 1422</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Energy saving switch for and process for conserving energy while operating a water heater</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>1993926</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Gauger</name>
<date>19350300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>13762411</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2266244</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Osterheld</name>
<date>19411200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4016402</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Scott</name>
<date>19770400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>392464</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4166944</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Scott</name>
<date>19790900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4413775</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Scott</name>
<date>19831100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>236 20 R</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4535931</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Bartok et al.</name>
<date>19850800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4549160</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>McGhee</name>
<date>19851000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4692051</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Stansbury, Jr. et al.</name>
<date>19870900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5103078</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Boykin et al.</name>
<date>19920400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5816491</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Berkeley et al.</name>
<date>19981000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6375087</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Day et al.</name>
<date>20020400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6920843</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Wilson</name>
<date>20050700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8022647</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Davis et al.</name>
<date>20110900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0051819</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Isaacson</name>
<date>20070300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00015">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0062248</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Subramanian</name>
<date>20110300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>18</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>307139</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>307140</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>307143</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>307132 R</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>307132 E</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>307132 M</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>307154</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>122 142</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>122 1421</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>122 1422</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>236 20 R</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>15</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130327843</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20131212</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Monetti</last-name>
<first-name>Robert</first-name>
<address>
<city>Newbury Park</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Monetti</last-name>
<first-name>Robert</first-name>
<address>
<city>Newbury Park</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Kelly &#x26; Kelley, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Fleming</last-name>
<first-name>Fritz M</first-name>
<department>2836</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A process for conserving energy while operating a water heater includes the steps of programming a system controller with at least one time interval and assigning a target temperature, comparing the current time to the programmed time interval and the current water temperature setting for the water heater against the target temperature, and heating the water as long as the current time is within the time interval and the water temperature setting is less than the target temperature. An energy saving switch includes a programmable logic controller, geared control shafts, a motor, a control lever, and a mating cuff. Together, these members control the water heater thermostat control valve to ensure that hot water is available only during the times of day when it is required.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="193.04mm" wi="152.32mm" file="US08624444-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="254.59mm" wi="215.31mm" file="US08624444-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="235.71mm" wi="210.57mm" file="US08624444-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="259.59mm" wi="205.23mm" file="US08624444-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="264.92mm" wi="214.97mm" file="US08624444-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="268.05mm" wi="212.43mm" file="US08624444-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="254.59mm" wi="215.31mm" file="US08624444-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="264.58mm" wi="215.31mm" file="US08624444-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="270.26mm" wi="215.56mm" file="US08624444-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">Virtually all homes in the United States and other developed countries include a system for providing heated water. Traditional hot water systems include a tank for storing and heating water.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">These systems often include a large tank encased in insulation and positioned with a heating element. The tank also includes an external thermostat control valve for manipulating the temperature of the water in the tank. The heating element heats the stored water in the tank to the temperature set on the thermostat control valve. Once the water is heated to the desired temperature, the heating element stops heating the water. If the water temperature falls below the desired temperature, the heating element turns on again to heat the water. This cycle continues indefinitely so that hot water is always available.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">These traditional water heating systems fail to take into account the changing demand for hot water in a normal household on an hourly basis throughout the day. For example, in the morning more hot water is needed for showers, breakfast preparation and cleanup, and other household chores. In the mid-morning through the afternoon, the demand for hot water decreases as household members go to work and to school. Then later in the afternoon, hot water demand increases again for dinner preparation and cleanup, evening bathing, and more household chores. This means that in a 24 hour cycle, a normal household may only require hot water for only a fraction of that time.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Frugal homeowners quickly realize that keeping water heated during time periods when there is little demand for hot water is wasteful and expensive. Indeed, the U.S. Department of Energy estimates that water heating accounts for 14%-25% of energy consumption in a typical household. Homeowners with gas powered water heaters may attempt to combat the expense of keeping water heated all day by utilizing the thermostat control valve that is accessible on all gas powered water heaters. In an attempt to save money, a homeowner may turn down the temperature of his gas powered water heater during the time intervals when he knows that hot water will not be required. But this method of saving energy and money is problematic. The homeowner may forget to turn the water temperature back up after the water in the tank has been left to cool all day or night with no hot water available for morning showers and cleanup. Typical gas powered water heaters take 40 minutes to an hour to heat a tank of water. This means that the homeowner may be left without hot water when the demand once again arises. Additionally, when adjusting the temperature control dial on a water heater, a homeowner may turn the heat setting too high or too low. If the water temperature is too hot, there is a risk of scalding when extremely hot water is dispensed through the house's plumbing. If the water temperature is too low, the homeowner may not be able to effectively and comfortably bathe or do other household chores.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Several patents and patent applications teach inventions for automatically controlling water heaters. U.S. Pat. No. 2,266,244 to Osterheld teaches a manually adjustable time delay that is installed on electric water heaters. The Osterheld time delay requires a temperature probe be inserted into the water tank of an electric water heater. The Osterheld invention causes a delay in the energization of the electric heater beyond the start of an off-peak period so that water is not heated when the demand for hot water is low. (Osterheld, Col. 2, Lines 1-8) The Osterheld invention is directed to controlling electrical current to a water heater and not gas. Additionally, Osterheld does not teach a time delay that requires no alterations to the existing water heater.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">U.S. Publication No. 2007/0051819 to Isaacson teaches a water heater with programmable low temperature mode. This is an apparatus for gas heated water heaters and requires a temperature probe be installed into the water tank of the water heater to monitor the temperature of the water. The Isaacson water heater has a high temperature mode and a low temperature mode. In low temperature mode, the temperature of the water is kept in a certain range of temperatures. In the high temperature mode, the water is heated above the low temperature mode range of temperatures. Isaacson does not teach an energy saving switch that can be installed with minimal effort on an existing water heater.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">U.S. Pat. No. 6,920,843 to Wilson teaches a programmable water heater that can be programmed to provide hot water at different times of day. The Wilson programmable timer is powered by a solenoid rather than by typical wall current. As with Isaacson, Wilson does not teach an energy saving switch that can be installed with minimal effort on an existing water heater.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">U.S. Publication No. 2011/0062248 to Subramanian teaches a programmable water heater thermostat controller that attaches over the temperature control unit of an existing gas or electric water heater. The Subramanian thermostat controller can be programmed to turn the water heater on and off at different times of day. It controls the water heater temperature by clamping the water heater thermostat control between two rollers that work together to rotate the thermostat control in one direction or the other. This clamping action is problematic because over time, the rollers may slip on the thermostat control or fail to rotate the thermostat control at all as the thermostat control stiffens with age and wear. The Subramanian thermostat controller is also installed in such a way that the water heater owner cannot manually override the controller in order to manipulate the thermostat control freely.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In light of the prior art, there is a need for a process for heating water to a target temperature during a given time interval. There is also a need for an energy saving switch that that utilizes this process and can be mounted on an existing water heater and securely connected to the thermostat control valve of the water heater in such a way that there will be no rotational slipping. Additionally, a need exists for such a switch that can be manually overridden if needed while remaining mounted on a water heater with no additional modifications to the water heater.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The present invention includes a process for conserving energy while operating a water heater and an energy saving switch for a water heater that embodies this process.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The process for conserving energy while operating a water heater comprises the steps of: programming a system controller with at least one time interval; assigning a target temperature for the water in the water heater to the time interval; comparing the current time to the time interval to determine if the current time is within the time interval; heating the water in the water heater if the current time is within the time interval and the target temperature has not yet been reached. The process may also include ceasing to heat the water in the water heater if the current time is outside the time interval or if the current temperature of the water in the water heater is greater than or equal to the target temperature. This can be accomplished automatically or via a manual over-ride. The system controller may also be programmed with more than one time interval if hot water is needed during multiple times of the day. Every time interval in the claimed process has a start time and an end time, wherein the step of heating the water in the water heater occurs after the start time and before the end time.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The energy saving switch for a water heater that embodies the claimed process comprises: a programmable system controller; a geared output escapement shaft with a proximal end and a distal end; a sprag wheel attached to the proximal end of the geared output escapement shaft; a motor powered by the programmable system controller and connected to the sprag wheel wherein the motor rotates the sprag wheel which in turn rotates the geared output escapement shaft; an adjustable control lever; a geared input control shaft with a proximal end and a distal end, wherein the adjustable control lever is mounted to the proximal end and the distal end is angularly connected with the distal end of the geared output escapement shaft; and a mating cuff configured about the distal end of the geared output escapement shaft. The programmable system controller may include: a programmable logic circuit configured with a power input connection, a data input connection, and an output connection; means for inputting instructions into the programmable logic circuit via the data input connection; and means for storing the instructions input into the programmable logic circuit. The programmable logic circuit may further include a back-up power source and a remote control. The motor is powered via the output connection of the programmable system controller. The motor is also connected to the proximal end of the geared output escapement shaft by a drive shaft connector.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The sprag wheel, located at the proximal end of the geared output escapement shaft, allows for the motor to continue rotating even if the geared output escapement shaft is locked. The sprag wheel is comprised of an inner disc with a planar first side. The planar first side includes a radial cavity to accept a compression spring and ball. The opposite second side of the inner disc is fitted with a shaft connector that is connected to the motor. The proximal end of the geared output escapement shaft is formed into a cup shape with an inner diameter that includes an axial notch. When the sprag wheel's inner disc rotates in either direction inside the inner diameter of the proximal end of the geared output escapement shaft, the ball ended compression spring will engage the axial notch of the geared output escapement shaft. With the compression spring and ball thus engaged, the geared output escapement shaft will rotate until it reaches a predetermined stop. At that point, the compression spring and ball will extend into the radial cavity and the sprag wheel will continue to be rotated by the motor for the allotted time set by the program.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The energy saving switch may also include a stop block mounted to the energy saving switch adjacent to the adjustable control lever such that the stop block prevents the adjustable control lever from rotating past a predetermined point.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The mating cuff of the energy saving switch may include: a circular outer cuff, mounted to the exterior of the energy saving switch about the distal end of the geared output shaft, having a curved inner surface and fitted with apertures along the circumference; curved inner clamps, having a convex side and threaded apertures wherein the convex side of the curved inner clamps corresponds with the curved inner surface of the circular outer cuff; and clamp screws, wherein the clamp screws are long enough to pass through both the apertures of the circular outer cuff and the threaded apertures of the curved inner clamps. The mating cuff is positioned over the circular collar of the thermostat control valve such that the circular collar is in between the circular outer cuff and the curved inner clamps. When the clamp screws are tightened, the convex side of the curved inner clamps tightens against the circular collar of the thermostat control valve, thereby creating a means by which the energy saving switch can be clamped onto the collar of a thermostat control valve.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Other features and advantages of the present invention will become apparent from the following more detailed description, taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, which illustrate, by way of example, the principles of the invention.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The accompanying drawings illustrate the invention. In such drawings:</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a flow chart illustrating the process of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view of the present invention mounted on a water heater;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a top view of the present invention illustrating the input keyboard for the system controller;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a side view of the present invention illustrating the control lever, temperature dial, and stop block of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a side view of the present invention illustrating the movement of the control lever in relation to the stop block as well as the mating cuff of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a top internal view of the present invention illustrating the geared input shaft, the geared output shaft, the sprag wheel, and the motor;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a top internal view of the present invention illustrating the compression spring and ball of the sprag wheel;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is an exploded view of the present invention illustrating the placement of the parts of the mating cuff, the parts of the control lever and temperature dial, and the parts of the sprag wheel;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a side internal view of the control lever;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is an exploded view of the mating cuff of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a perspective view of the mating cuff of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a head-on view of the mating cuff of the present invention before it is tightened onto the collar of a water heater temperature control dial;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a head-on view of the mating cuff of the present invention as it is partially tightened onto the collar of a water heater temperature control valve;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is a head-on view of the mating cuff of the present invention when it is fully engaged with the collar of a water heater temperature control valve; and</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is a system schematic illustrating the connections between the different parts of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The present invention is directed to a process and apparatus for conserving energy while operating a water heater. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a flow chart illustrating the claimed process.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The claimed process begins in box <b>100</b> by inputting a time interval and a target temperature. The time interval has a start time and an end time. The claimed process can have one time interval or many time intervals, either per day or per week. A time interval can be set to occur once a day, or once a week, or once on a given date. In the step represented by box <b>100</b>, a user can create a schedule of time intervals such that heated water is available at the various times of day that the user needs hot water. Box <b>100</b> also includes inputting a maximum target temperature for the time interval. The maximum target temperature is the point which the water is not to be heated beyond during the given time interval. By setting the maximum target temperature, the user ensures that the water will not be over-heated during the heating time interval. For example, if the user's household includes small children, the maximum target temperature can be set a little lower than normal in order to guard against scalding.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Box <b>110</b> represents the beginning of a continual cycle. If the current time is before the start time, then the start time has not been reached. This loop continues until the current time is equal to the start time. Once the start time of the time interval has been reached, then the process moves to box <b>120</b> where the water heater is turned on. In the preferred embodiment of the present invention, the water heater is turned on by increasing the temperature setting of the water heater thermostat control valve. Until the start time of a time interval is reached, the water heater thermostat control valve is set to its lowest setting. In most water heaters, the lowest setting is &#x201c;Vacation&#x201d;. With the dial turned to &#x201c;Vacation&#x201d;, the heating element of the water heater is not shut all the way off. Rather it is turned low, so that the water in the water heater tank is kept at a low temperature (approximately 45 degrees Fahrenheit in many cases, or the ambient temperature if the ambient temperature is higher than 45 degrees). When the water heater is turned on, as in box <b>120</b>, the flow of gas or electricity to the heating element is turned on and the heating element burns. This means that the temperature of the water inside the water heater tank is increased. The water heater remains on as long as the conditions in boxes <b>130</b> and <b>140</b> remain false. Once either one of the conditions in boxes <b>130</b> and <b>140</b> become true, the process moves to box <b>150</b> and the water heater shuts off.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In box <b>130</b>, the current time is compared to the start time and the end time as defined by the current time interval. If the current time is after the start time, but before the end time, then the time interval is not complete and this condition is false. In box <b>140</b>, the current temperature setting of the water heater is compared to the maximum target temperature set for the current time interval. If the current temperature setting is less than the maximum target temperature then the maximum target temperature has not been reached and this condition is false. The water heater remains on as long as both conditions in boxes <b>130</b> and <b>140</b> remain false. The water heater is shut off as in box <b>150</b> when either the time interval is complete or the target temperature is reached, or both the time interval is complete and the maximum target temperature is reached.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In a preferred embodiment, water heater shut off, as in box <b>150</b>, is accomplished by rotating the water heater thermostat control valve back down to its lowest setting. The water heater remains in this state until the start time of the next time interval is reached again in box <b>110</b>. At that point, the water heater turns on in box <b>120</b>, and the process begins again.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates a preferred embodiment of the claimed energy saving switch. The energy saving switch <b>200</b> is shown mounted on the thermostat control valve <b>250</b> of a water heater <b>240</b>. The energy saving switch <b>200</b> has means for inputting information <b>210</b>. In the preferred embodiment, the means for inputting information <b>210</b> is a keyboard that allows the user to input time intervals and other system settings. The energy saving switch <b>200</b> also features a control lever <b>220</b> and a stop block <b>230</b>. The control lever <b>220</b> also features a temperature dial <b>260</b> that indicates different heat settings. The control lever <b>220</b> and the stop block <b>230</b> work in conjunction to allow the user to set the maximum target temperature for the desired time interval. The operation of the control lever <b>200</b> and the stop block <b>230</b> are shown in more detail in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows the top face of the energy saving switch <b>200</b> featuring means for inputting information <b>210</b>, the control lever <b>220</b>, the stop block <b>230</b>, and the temperature dial <b>260</b>. The means for inputting information <b>210</b> may also be located elsewhere in wireless connection with the energy saving switch <b>200</b>. In that case, the means for inputting information may be operated by remote control, or via the Internet, or another type of wireless device. In the preferred embodiment, the means for inputting information <b>210</b> is a keyboard with a plurality of labeled keys. In the preferred embodiment, there are keys for inputting days of the week, start times, and end times. There is also an on/off switch and a manual override. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> also shows the mating cuff <b>300</b>. The mating cuff <b>300</b> is illustrated in more detail in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10-14</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a side view of the energy saving switch <b>200</b> showing the control lever <b>220</b>, the stop block <b>230</b> and the temperature dial <b>260</b>. The temperature dial <b>260</b> is the same dial the water heater is installed with. When the energy saving switch <b>200</b> is mounted on the water heater temperature control valve, the temperature dial <b>260</b> is removed from the water heater and attached to the energy saving switch <b>200</b>. This allows the energy saving switch <b>200</b> to be calibrated more precisely to the water heater that it is mounted on.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The movement of the control lever <b>220</b> of the energy saving switch <b>200</b> is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. When the user is setting the energy saving switch with a time interval and target temperature, he positions the control lever <b>220</b> at the desired target temperature along the temperature dial <b>260</b>. For example, if the user wants the water temperature in the water heater to be warm in between 4:30 P.M. and 7:30 P.M., he will input those times into the process controller, then he will position the control lever <b>220</b> so that it is next to &#x201c;WARM&#x201d; as indicated by the temperature dial <b>260</b>. When 4:30 P.M. occurs, the control lever <b>220</b> rotates along directional line <b>500</b>. As the control lever <b>220</b> rotates along directional line <b>500</b>, the modulating detent <b>520</b> simultaneously rotates along directional line <b>530</b> thereby rotating the thermostat control valve <b>250</b> and increasing the temperature of the water in the water heater <b>240</b>. The control lever <b>220</b> moves along directional line <b>500</b> until it contacts the stop block <b>230</b>. Once the control lever <b>220</b> contacts the stop block <b>230</b>, the control lever <b>220</b> can rotate no further in the direction indicated by line <b>500</b>. The stop block <b>230</b> prevents the control lever <b>220</b> from over rotating, which thereby prevents the water in the water heater <b>240</b> from heating to temperatures above a predetermined point, i.e., a maximum temperature. When the time interval ends, the control lever <b>220</b> rotates in the opposite direction until the water in the water heater is no longer being heated.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In an alternate embodiment, a step controller is used rather than a motor <b>630</b> with a timed rotation. A step controller can be programmed with rotational distances so that a target temperature during a given time interval can be achieved by the pre-programmed step controller rotating the modulating detent <b>520</b> a known number of degrees. In this alternate embodiment, the control lever <b>220</b> and stop block <b>230</b> become a safety measure to provide a point past which the thermostat control valve <b>250</b> cannot be rotated, should the step controller malfunction.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The internal operations of the preferred embodiment are illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6-8</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates how the geared input control shaft <b>600</b> and the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b> work together to rotate the modulating detent <b>520</b> when it is connected to the thermostat control valve <b>250</b> of the water heater <b>240</b>. The modulating detent <b>520</b> forms a positive connection with the thermostat control valve <b>250</b> such that the thermostat control valve <b>250</b> is locked into the energy saving switch <b>200</b>. The connection between the modulating detent <b>520</b> and the thermostat control valve <b>250</b> is not frictional, but rather is made by a positive engagement that ensures that the modulating detent <b>520</b> and the thermostat control valve <b>250</b> rotate in concert.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Both the geared input control shaft <b>600</b> and the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b> have a proximal and a distal end. The proximal end of the geared input control shaft <b>600</b> is connected to the control lever <b>220</b>. The proximal end of the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b> is formed into a cup shape with an inner diameter that includes an axial notch <b>760</b>. A sprag wheel <b>730</b> is fitted within the inner diameter and connects to a motor <b>630</b>. The geared input control shaft <b>600</b> and the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b> are angularly connected at their distal ends via interlocking teeth <b>640</b> on their respective, angularly positioned gears. The interlocking teeth <b>640</b> allow for the geared input control shaft <b>600</b> and the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b> to simultaneously rotate in opposite directions, even though they are mounted at a 90 degree angle to each other.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows the preferred placement of the programmable logic controller <b>700</b>. The programmable logic controller <b>700</b> is preferably a computer circuit board with a power input connection, a data input connection, programmable logic, computer memory, and an output connection. The power input connection (not shown) is connected to the programmable logic controller <b>700</b>. The power input connection (not shown) may be connected to a standard power outlet. The power input connection can also be connected to a back-up power source (not shown). The back-up power source is an on-board battery. This allows the energy saving switch <b>200</b> to maintain current time settings in the programmable logic controller during periods of household power outage. The output connection <b>710</b> is connected to the motor <b>630</b>. The programmable logic controller <b>700</b> preferably includes computer memory to store instructions and programmable logic to process instructions. Depending on the processed instructions, the output connection <b>710</b> selectively powers the motor <b>630</b>, and changes the rotational direction of the motor <b>630</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> also illustrates the sprag wheel <b>730</b> of the preferred embodiment. The sprag wheel <b>730</b> has a proximal and a distal end. The distal end of the sprag wheel <b>730</b> is a disc featuring a radial cavity <b>770</b> on the circumference of the disc which accepts a compression spring <b>740</b> and a ball <b>750</b>. The proximal end of the sprag wheel <b>730</b> has a recess to accept and attach to the motor <b>630</b>. The proximal end of the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b> has a cup shaped recess featuring an axial notch <b>760</b> on the inner circumference of the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b>. The axial notch <b>760</b> in the geared escapement shaft <b>610</b> will accept the ball <b>750</b>, which is retained therein by the compression spring <b>740</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In operation, the sprag wheel <b>730</b> allows the motor <b>630</b> to continue rotating once the control lever <b>220</b> is blocked by the stop block <b>230</b>. For example, when a user sets the desired maximum target temperature for a given time interval, he rotates the control lever <b>220</b> to the desired maximum target temperature on the temperature dial <b>260</b>. When the time interval begins, the motor <b>630</b> starts to rotate the control lever <b>220</b> toward the stop block <b>230</b>. When the maximum target temperature is reached, the control lever <b>220</b> is in contact with the stop block <b>230</b>, and can no longer rotate. Once the control lever <b>220</b> is blocked by the stop block <b>230</b>, the geared input control shaft <b>600</b> can no longer rotate. The inter locking teeth <b>640</b> of the geared input control shaft <b>600</b> and the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b> lock the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b> from rotating further. At this point, the members of the energy saving switch <b>200</b> are locked, but the motor <b>630</b> does not stop. Rather, the motor <b>630</b> continues to rotate because the sprag wheel <b>730</b> has disengaged from the axial notch <b>760</b> of the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b>. The motor <b>630</b> will continue to rotate for a programmed period of time.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In an alternate embodiment, a step controller is utilized rather than a motor <b>630</b> with a timed rotation. A step controller is programmed with rotational distances so the control lever <b>220</b> is no longer needed to set the desired target water temperature for a given time interval. In this alternate embodiment, a time interval begins and the step controller rotates the geared output control shaft <b>610</b> a certain number of degrees. When the thermostat control valve <b>250</b> has been rotated to the appropriate temperature setting, the step controller stops rotating the geared output control shaft <b>610</b>. In this embodiment, the sprag wheel <b>730</b> is not utilized because the step controller is programmed to stop after a given number of rotations. If the step controller has been mis-programmed, or has malfunctioned, the control lever <b>220</b> and stop block <b>230</b> serve to prevent the thermostat control valve <b>250</b> from being over-rotated, producing water that is too hot for home use. If the step controller over-rotates the geared output control shaft <b>610</b> and the geared output control shaft <b>610</b> is locked by the control lever <b>220</b> and stop block <b>230</b>, the sprag wheel <b>730</b> will keep the step controller from burning out.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In the preferred embodiment with a rotating motor <b>630</b>, the sprag wheel <b>730</b> allows for the motor <b>630</b> to rotate for a specified period of time, even though the rest of the energy saving switch <b>200</b> is locked. The compression spring <b>740</b> and ball <b>750</b> located within the radial cavity <b>770</b> of the sprag wheel <b>730</b>, and is tensioned such that it allows the sprag wheel <b>730</b> to rotate within the proximal end of the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b>, even while the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b> is locked. When the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b> is locked, the compression spring <b>740</b> no longer has enough compression to cause the ball <b>750</b> to remain in the axial notch <b>760</b> of the proximal end of the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b>. As the sprag wheel <b>730</b> continues to be rotated by the motor <b>630</b>, the compression spring <b>740</b> and ball <b>750</b> compress into the radial cavity <b>770</b> of the sprag wheel <b>730</b>. This allows the motor <b>630</b> to continue rotating for a specified period of time. This remains true even though the geared input control shaft <b>600</b> and the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b> are locked.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">When the time interval ends, the programmable logic controller <b>700</b> changes the rotational direction of the motor <b>630</b>. As the sprag wheel <b>730</b> makes a rotation in the opposite direction, the compression spring <b>740</b> and ball <b>750</b> line up with the axial notch <b>760</b> in the proximal end of the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b>. At this point, the compression spring <b>740</b> expands, pushing the ball <b>750</b> into the axial notch <b>760</b> of the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b>. With the compression spring <b>740</b> thus expanded and pressing the ball <b>750</b> into the axial notch <b>760</b>, the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b>, geared input control shaft <b>600</b>, and control lever <b>220</b> can freely rotate in the opposite direction. These members continue to operate in this direction until the thermostat valve <b>250</b> can no longer be rotated. At this point, the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b> will stop and the sprag wheel <b>730</b> allows the motor <b>630</b> to continue operating in the opposite direction for a specified period of time. Once the time period ends, the motor <b>630</b> will stop.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In an alternate embodiment of the present invention, a step controller is used to power the rotation of the geared input control shaft <b>600</b> and the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b>. Having a step controller rather than a continuous motor would negate the need for a sprag wheel <b>730</b>, as in the preferred embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is an exploded view of the energy saving switch <b>200</b> of the present invention. The sprag wheel <b>730</b>, as described above, is formed on the proximal end of the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b>. The distal end of the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b> is angularly connected with the distal end of the input control shaft <b>600</b>. The distal end of the geared output escapement shaft <b>610</b> also comprises the modulating detent <b>520</b>. The modulating detent <b>520</b> is formed to connect with the thermostat control valve <b>250</b> such that when the modulating detent <b>520</b> is rotated, the thermostat control valve <b>250</b> is rotated also. The proximal end of the input control shaft <b>600</b> comprises the control lever <b>220</b> and is fitted with the temperature dial <b>260</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> also includes an exploded view of the mating cuff <b>300</b>. The mating cuff <b>300</b> serves to attach the energy saving switch <b>200</b> to the water heater <b>240</b>, and to support the energy saving switch <b>200</b> in a position perpendicular to the water heater <b>240</b>. The mating cuff <b>300</b> is formed to the exterior of the energy saving switch <b>200</b>, and is circularly placed about the modulating detent <b>520</b>. The mating cuff <b>300</b> comprises a circular outer cuff <b>310</b>, curved inner clamps <b>320</b>, and a plurality of clamp screws <b>330</b>. The operation of the mating cuff <b>300</b> is illustrated more particularly in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10-14</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a side cut-away view of the control lever <b>220</b>. This view illustrates the spring-loaded retractable member <b>900</b> and the geared inner wheel <b>910</b>. In operation, when the user sets the target temperature for a given time interval, he retracts the spring-loaded retractable member <b>900</b> and positions the control lever at the desired temperature indicated on the temperature dial <b>260</b>. He then releases the spring-loaded retractable member <b>900</b>. When released, the spring-loaded retractable member <b>900</b> engages with the geared inner wheel <b>910</b> such that the geared input control shaft <b>600</b>, the control lever <b>200</b>, and the temperature dial <b>260</b> all rotate together. If the spring-loaded retractable member <b>900</b> is not engaged with the geared inner wheel <b>910</b>, only the geared input control shaft <b>600</b> and the temperature dial <b>260</b> will rotate together while the control lever <b>220</b> remains free. The control lever <b>220</b> and the sprag wheel <b>730</b> allow the user to manually override the programming of the energy saving switch <b>200</b> if necessary. When the user wishes to manually adjust the water heater thermostat control valve <b>250</b> off schedule, he simply rotates the control lever <b>220</b> toward the stop block <b>230</b>. The control lever <b>220</b> will stay at the position the user has put it in until the next time interval begins and ends.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10-14</figref> illustrate the operation of the mating cuff <b>300</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is an exploded view of the mating cuff <b>300</b>. The circular outer cuff <b>310</b> is fitted with a plurality of apertures <b>340</b>. The curved inner clamps <b>320</b> are also fitted with matching apertures <b>340</b>. In use, the clamp screws <b>330</b> fit through the apertures <b>340</b> on both the circular outer cuff <b>310</b> and the curved inner clamps <b>320</b> and serve to tighten and hold the curved inner clamps <b>320</b> in place. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> shows how the circular outer cuff <b>310</b> fits around the thermostat control valve collar <b>510</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, the curved inner clamps <b>320</b> are tightened against the inner face of the thermostat control valve collar <b>510</b> and held in place by the clamp screws <b>330</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The tightening of the curved inner clamps <b>320</b> against the inner surface of the thermostat control valve collar <b>510</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12-14</figref>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, the mating cuff <b>300</b> is shown disassembled. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, the clamp screws <b>330</b> have been inserted through the apertures <b>340</b> of the circular outer cuff <b>310</b>, and the curved inner clamps <b>320</b>. As the clamp screws <b>330</b> are tightened, the curved inner clamps <b>320</b> are tightened against the inner surface of the thermostat control valve collar <b>510</b> forming a close fit as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref>. With the clamp screws <b>330</b> tightened, the mating cuff <b>300</b>, and the energy saving switch <b>200</b> are held in place against the water heater <b>240</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is a system schematic illustrating connections between the members of the energy saving switch <b>200</b>. The programmable logic controller <b>1500</b> is powered by external DC power supply <b>1560</b>, 110/120 VAC house current <b>1570</b>, with an on-board battery backup <b>1670</b>. The on-board battery backup <b>1670</b> is present to maintain current time and system settings in the programmable logic controller <b>1500</b> during periods of household power outage. The programmable logic controller <b>1500</b> is connected to an input keyboard <b>1510</b> that is used to schedule time intervals for water heating according to days of the week, date, week, time on, and time off as in <b>1520</b>. The programmable logic controller <b>1500</b> can also be initiated remotely via the remote control <b>1530</b>. The remote control <b>1530</b> can be used to turn on the water heater for a programmed period of time, as in <b>1540</b> by overriding the scheduling that the programmable logic controller <b>1500</b> has been programmed with. The remote control <b>1530</b> can also be used to return the energy saving switch <b>200</b> to its normal cycle.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Once the programmable logic controller <b>1500</b> initiates a water heating cycle (due to a programmed time interval being reached, or due to a manual override via the remote control <b>1530</b> or the input keyboard <b>1510</b>) the programmable logic controller <b>1500</b> powers the motor <b>1550</b>. The motor is connected to the sprag wheel <b>1580</b>. The sprag wheel <b>1580</b> is connected to the geared output escapement shaft <b>1590</b>. The sprag wheel <b>1580</b> allows the motor <b>1550</b> to rotate the geared output escapement shaft <b>1590</b> and the geared input control shaft <b>1610</b> as long as the geared input control shaft <b>1610</b> is not locked. If the geared input control shaft <b>1610</b> is locked, the sprag wheel <b>1580</b> allows the motor to continue rotating for a programmed period of time while the geared input control shaft <b>1610</b> and geared output escapement shaft <b>1590</b> remain locked.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The geared input control shaft <b>1610</b> is angularly connected to the geared output escapement shaft <b>1590</b>. The geared output escapement shaft <b>1590</b> comprises a modulating detent <b>1620</b> at its distal end. The modulating detent <b>1620</b> is formed to securely connect with the thermostat control valve <b>1630</b> of the water heater. Thus when the modulating detent <b>1620</b> is rotated, the thermostat control valve <b>1630</b> is rotated as well. The thermostat control valve <b>1630</b> controls the gas supply <b>1640</b> to feed the burner <b>1650</b> of the water heater.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Although several embodiments have been described in some detail for purposes of illustration, various modifications may be made without departing from the scope and spirit of the invention. Accordingly, the invention is not to be limited, except by the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An energy saving switch for a water heater, comprising:
<claim-text>a programmable logic controller;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a geared output escapement shaft with a proximal end and a distal end;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a motor powered by the programmable logic controller and connected to the proximal end of the geared output escapement shaft wherein the motor rotates the geared output escapement shaft;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an adjustable control lever;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a geared input control shaft with a proximal end and a distal end, wherein the adjustable control lever is mounted to the proximal end and the distal end is angularly connected with the distal end of the geared output escapement shaft; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating cuff configured about the distal end of the geared output escapement shaft.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The energy saving switch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the programmable logic controller comprises:
<claim-text>a programmable logic circuit configured with a power input connection, a data input connection, and an output connection;</claim-text>
<claim-text>means for inputting instructions into the programmable logic circuit via the data input connection; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>means for storing the instructions input into the programmable logic circuit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The energy saving switch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the programmable logic controller further comprises:
<claim-text>an independent power back-up configured to connect to the power input connection; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>means for remotely inputting instructions into the programmable logic circuit via the data input connection.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The energy saving switch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the independent power back-up is an on-board battery.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The energy saving switch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the means for inputting instructions is a keyboard.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The energy saving switch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the means for storing instructions is computer memory.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The energy saving switch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the motor is powered via the output connection of the programmable logic controller, and wherein the motor is connected to the proximal end of the geared output escapement shaft by a drive shaft connector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The energy saving switch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the motor and the geared output escapement shaft are both configured for bi-directional rotation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The energy saving switch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a sprag wheel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The energy saving switch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the sprag wheel is substantially coextensive with the proximal end of the geared output escapement shaft and the motor, and the proximal end of the geared output escapement shaft comprises a cup-shaped recess with an inner diameter having an axial notch.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The energy saving switch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the sprag wheel comprises:
<claim-text>an inner disc, having a planar first side and an opposite second side, a radial cavity disposed on the first side and a drive shaft connector mounted on the second side, wherein the shaft connector is connected to the motor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a compression spring and ball partially disposed within the radial cavity such that the compression spring and ball expand into the axial notch of the inner diameter of the proximal end of the geared output escapement shaft when the sprag wheel is rotated within the inner diameter.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The energy saving switch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the ball-ended compression spring is tensioned within the radial cavity and axial notch such that the inner disc of the sprag wheel and the geared output escapement shaft rotate in concert.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The energy saving switch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the compression spring and ball compress completely into the radial cavity of the sprag wheel when the geared output escapement shaft locks such that the compression spring and ball no longer extend into the axial notch of the inner diameter of the proximal end of the geared output escapement shaft and the sprag wheel remains rotatable.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The energy saving switch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the control lever is affixed with a temperature dial.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The energy saving switch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the angular connection between the geared input control shaft and the geared output escapement shaft is configured by interlocking the respective gears at a ninety degree angle.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The energy saving switch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a stop block mounted to the energy saving switch adjacent to the adjustable control lever such that the stop block prevents the adjustable control lever from rotating past a predetermined point.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The energy saving switch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the mating cuff is comprised of:
<claim-text>a circular outer cuff, mounted to the exterior of the energy saving switch about the distal end of the geared output shaft, having a curved inner surface and fitted with threaded apertures along the circumference;</claim-text>
<claim-text>curved inner clamps, having a convex side and threaded apertures wherein the convex side of the curved inner clamps corresponds with the curved inner surface of the circular outer cuff; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>clamp screws, wherein the clamp screws are long enough to pass through the apertures of the circular outer cuff and be threaded into the apertures of the curved inner clamps.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The energy saving switch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein tightening the clamp screws of the mating cuff causes the convex side of the curved inner clamps to tighten against the curved inner surface of the circular outer cuff thereby creating a means by which the energy saving switch can be clamped onto the collar of a thermostat control valve. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
