<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626780-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626780</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12830970</doc-number>
<date>20100706</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>98137208 A</doc-number>
<date>20091103</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>387</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>17</main-group>
<subgroup>30</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>707758</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Multimedia playing system, apparatus for identifing a file and, method thereof</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0153293</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hsu et al.</name>
<date>20060700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0294058</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Zabback et al.</name>
<date>20061200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>707  2</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0038318</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Sakata</name>
<date>20070200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>700 94</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0076959</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Bressan</name>
<date>20070400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0118480</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ueda et al.</name>
<date>20070500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>705 59</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0235724</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Sassenscheidt et al.</name>
<date>20080900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0260244</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kaftory et al.</name>
<date>20081000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>382165</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>2007/40197</doc-number>
<date>20071000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>2007/40214</doc-number>
<date>20071000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>28</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>11</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110102604</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110505</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chien</last-name>
<first-name>Chun-Chin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Teng</last-name>
<first-name>Sheng-Shan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chien</last-name>
<first-name>Chun-Chin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Teng</last-name>
<first-name>Sheng-Shan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Muncy, Geissler, Olds &#x26; Lowe, PLLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Delta Electronics, Inc.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan Hsien</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Perveen</last-name>
<first-name>Rehana</first-name>
<department>2155</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Khong</last-name>
<first-name>Alexander</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A multimedia playing system, an apparatus for identifying a file, and a method thereof are provided. The multimedia playing system comprises a display device, a sensing device, and an identification device. The display device is configured to display the file and has a predetermined area. A plurality of color tags adapted to be displayed on the predetermined area is attached to the file. The sensing device continuously senses the predetermined area to generate a sensed datum. The identification device is connected to the sensing device and receives the sensed data from the sensing device to determine a sensed color code representing each of the sensed data. The identification device further forms a sensed sequence by the sensed color codes and determines a piece of display information corresponding to the sensed sequence.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="198.04mm" wi="158.83mm" file="US08626780-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="188.81mm" wi="121.50mm" file="US08626780-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="198.88mm" wi="158.58mm" file="US08626780-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="204.47mm" wi="156.46mm" file="US08626780-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="181.36mm" wi="116.67mm" file="US08626780-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="201.51mm" wi="75.10mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626780-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority to Taiwan Patent Application No. 098137208 filed on Nov. 3, 2009.</p>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCES TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Not applicable.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The present invention provides a multimedia playing system, an apparatus for identifying a file, and a method thereof. In particular, the present invention provides an apparatus for identifying a file played on a display device of the multimedia playing system, the multimedia playing system, and a method thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">2. Descriptions of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Liquid crystal display (LCD) technologies have been developed and found wider application over recent years. Aside from application in products such as personal computers, household television sets, and handheld apparatuses, LCD systems have also gradually been applied to the public media sector; for example, advertisements may be played using multimedia files on LCD systems in airports, rapid transit vehicles, department stores, hypermarkets, and other places. Accordingly, many manufacturers have placed greater efforts in searching the LCD system market for more applications of the LCD systems.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">To ensure that a multimedia file is correctly played on the display device of an LCD system at a predetermined time point or that the multimedia file is correctly played according to the scheduled contents, some manufacturers currently monitor the display device by directly capturing frames by means of a charge coupled device (CCD) and obtaining the information of the multimedia files by means of an image analysis software. However, because the CCD must be installed at a distance of at least 3&#x2dc;5 meters from the display device to monitor the whole frame and the captured frames must be transmitted back to a remote host for image analysis, this kind of arrangement leads to high complexity and high costs.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to the above descriptions, it is important to provide a solution capable of reducing both the complexity and cost necessary for monitoring an LCD system and expanding the application of LCD systems in the public media sector to improve the convenience in use and provide more diversified services.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">An objective of the present invention is to provide a multimedia playing system. The multimedia playing system comprises a display device, a sensing device, and an identification device. The display device is configured to play a file and has a predetermined area. A plurality of color tags are attached to the file, the color tags are adapted to be displayed on the predetermined area, and each of the color tags corresponds to a color code. The sensing device is disposed to face the predetermined area and configured to continuously sense the predetermined area to generate a sensed datum. The identification device is connected to the sensing device and configured to store a color pattern, wherein the color pattern records at least one predetermined color sequence. The at least one predetermined color sequence corresponds to a piece of the playing information of the file and is composed of the color codes. The identification device is further configured to receive the sensed data from the sensing device to determine a sensed color code representing each of the sensed data, wherein each of the sensed color codes is one of the color codes. The identification device is further configured to store the sensed color code into a queue register until an amount of the sensed color codes stored in the queue register is equal to a predetermined quantity. A sensed color sequence is formed by the sensed color codes. The identification device is further configured to determine the piece of playing information corresponding to the sensed color sequence by comparing the sensed color sequence with the at least one predetermined color sequence.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Another objective of the present invention is to provide an apparatus for identifying a file played on a display device. The apparatus is adapted for the multimedia playing system described above. The display device has a predetermined area. A plurality of color tags is attached to the file, the color tags are adapted to be displayed on the predetermined area, and each of the color tags corresponds to a color code. The apparatus comprises a storage module, a transmission module, a queue register, and a process module. The storage module is configured to store a color pattern, wherein the color pattern records at least one predetermined color sequence. The at least one predetermined color sequence corresponds to a piece of playing information from the file and is composed of the color codes. The transmission module is configured to continuously receive a sensed datum from a sensing device, wherein the sensing device generates the sensed data by sensing the predetermined area. The process module is configured to continuously determine a sensed color code representing the sensed datum, wherein the sensed color code is one of the color codes. The process module is further configured to continuously store the sensed color code into the queue register until an amount of the sensed color codes stored in the queen register is equal to a predetermined quantity. A sensed color sequence is formed by the sensed color codes. The process module is further configured to determine the piece of playing information corresponding to the sensed color sequence by comparing the sensed color sequence with the at least one predetermined color sequence.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Yet a further objective of the present invention is to provide a method for identifying a file played on a display device. The method is adapted for the apparatus to identify a file described above. The display device has a predetermined area. A plurality of color tags is attached to the file, the color tags are adapted to be displayed on the predetermined area, and each of the color tags corresponds to a color code. The method is used with a color pattern, and the color pattern records at least one predetermined color sequence. The at least one predetermined color sequence corresponds to a piece of playing information of the file and is composed of the color codes. The method comprises the following steps: (a) receiving a sensed datum from a sensing device, wherein the sensing device generates the sensed data by sensing the predetermined area; (b) determining a sensed color code representing the sensed datum; (c) storing the sensed color code into a queue register; (d) iterating steps (a), (b), and (c) until an amount of the sensed color codes stored in the queue register is equal to a predetermined quantity, and a sensed color sequence is formed by the sensed color codes stored in the queue register; and (e) determining the piece of playing information corresponding to the sensed color sequence by comparing the sensed color sequence with the at least one predetermined color sequence.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The multimedia playing system of the present invention is adapted for an LCD display system. Because the multimedia playing system is able to obtain information of the file without the use of a CCD, the complexity and cost necessary for monitoring of the LCD system are significantly reduced, and thus, may be used conveniently to provide more diversified services.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The detailed technology and preferred embodiments implemented for the subject invention are described in the following paragraphs accompanying the appended drawings for people skilled in this field to well appreciate the features of the claimed invention.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view of a multimedia playing system of the first embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a flowchart of a method for identifying a multimedia file, which is adapted for the multimedia playing system of the first embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A-3H</figref> are schematic views of an example of the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic view of another example of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The following embodiments are only provided to illustrate rather than to limit the present invention. It should be appreciated that in the following embodiments and the attached drawings, elements unrelated to the present invention are omitted from depiction; and dimensional relationships among the individual elements in the attached drawings are illustrated only for ease of understanding, but not to limit the actual scale.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a schematic view of a multimedia playing system <b>1</b> according to a first embodiment of the present invention. The multimedia playing system <b>1</b> comprises a display device <b>11</b>, a sensing device <b>13</b>, and an identification device <b>15</b>. The display device <b>11</b> is configured to play a file, which may be a multimedia file, for example, an advertisement or a movie. The display device <b>11</b> may be an LCD or a plasma display panel. The display device <b>11</b> has a predetermined area <b>11</b><i>a</i>, and a plurality of color tags adapted to be displayed on the predetermined area <b>11</b><i>a </i>is attached to the multimedia file. Each of the color tags corresponds to a color code. For example, the color tags may comprise a red tag, a blue tag, and a green tag. The red tag corresponds to a red code, the blue tag corresponds to a blue code, and the green tag corresponds to a green code. The sensing device <b>13</b> is disposed facing the predetermined area and configured to continuously sense the predetermined area <b>11</b><i>a </i>to generate a sensed datum <b>102</b> according to a sensing result. The sensed datum <b>102</b> may comprise a red composition datum, a green composition datum, and a blue composition datum.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The identification device <b>15</b> may be connected to the sensing device <b>13</b> either wirelessly or in a wired way. The identification device <b>15</b> comprises a transmission module <b>15</b><i>a</i>, a process module <b>15</b><i>b</i>, a queue register <b>15</b><i>c</i>, and a storage module <b>15</b><i>d</i>. The transmission module <b>15</b><i>a </i>is configured to receive the sensed datum <b>102</b> from the sensing device <b>13</b>. The storage module <b>15</b><i>d </i>is configured to store a color pattern which records a predetermined color sequence <b>108</b>. The predetermined color sequence <b>108</b> corresponds to a piece of playing information of the multimedia file and is composed of the color codes. For example, the predetermined color sequence <b>108</b> may be a red code, a blue code, a green code, a permutation of two codes or even a permutation of three codes. In other words, the predetermined color sequence <b>108</b> may be a permutation of more than one color code in which a color code may appear repeatedly in the permutation provided that adjacent color codes are not identical to each other; for example, &#x201c;red&#x201d;, &#x201c;red, blue&#x201d;, &#x201c;red, blue, green&#x201d; and, &#x201c;red, blue, green, blue&#x201d; are all permissible permutations of the color codes.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Additionally, the storage module <b>15</b><i>d </i>is further configured to store a red composition definition, a green composition definition and, a blue composition definition. The process module <b>15</b><i>b </i>is further configured to determine each of the sensed color codes <b>104</b> representing the sensed data <b>102</b> respectively by comparing the red composition datum, the green composition datum, and the blue composition datum of the sensed data <b>102</b> with the red composition definition, the green composition definition, and the blue composition definition. Then, the process module <b>15</b><i>b </i>is further configured to determine whether the sensed color code <b>104</b> representing the sensed datum is one of the color codes. If the sensed color code <b>104</b> is one of the color codes, it will be stored into the queue register <b>15</b><i>c</i>. Otherwise, if the sensed color code <b>104</b> is not one of the color codes, it will be discarded. It shall be noted that the process module <b>15</b><i>b </i>also determines whether the sensed color code <b>104</b> is identical to a prior sensed color code stored in the queue register <b>15</b><i>c</i>. If the answer is &#x201c;yes&#x201d;, the process module <b>15</b><i>b </i>will delete the prior sensed color code stored in the queue register <b>15</b><i>c </i>and store the sensed color code <b>104</b> (i.e., the latest sensed color code that is determined) into the queue register <b>15</b><i>c. </i></p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In more details, the process module <b>15</b><i>b </i>continuously receives the sensed data <b>102</b> and determines the sensed color codes <b>104</b> representing the sensed data <b>102</b>. When an amount of the sensed color codes <b>104</b> stored in the queue register <b>15</b><i>c </i>is equal to a predetermined quantity, the process module <b>15</b><i>b </i>will compose the sensed color codes <b>104</b> into a sensed color sequence <b>106</b> so that by comparing the sensed color sequence <b>106</b> with the predetermined color sequence <b>108</b>, the piece of playing information corresponding to the sensed color sequence <b>106</b> can be determined. Meanwhile, the process module <b>15</b><i>b </i>will also clear the sensed color codes <b>104</b> that have formed the sensed color sequence <b>106</b> from the queue register <b>15</b><i>c </i>to make room for storage of new sensed color codes <b>104</b>. The piece of playing information may correspond to the start of playing the multimedia file, the end of playing the multimedia file, or any predetermined time point during the playing process. Thereby, a frame displayed on the display device may be monitored only according to the playing information representing the different color sequences. For example, if the multimedia file is an advertisement, then, by using the color sequence, the advertisement may be correctly monitored and played on the display device at a predetermined time point and the playing time of the advertisement on the display device may be calculated.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The second embodiment of the present invention is a method for identifying a multimedia file played on a display device, which is adapted for the identification device <b>15</b> described in the first embodiment. A flowchart of the method is depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. It shall be appreciated that in this embodiment, the display device has a predetermined area, and a plurality of color tags adapted to be displayed on the predetermined area is attached to the multimedia file. Each of the color tags corresponds to a color code, and the method is used with a color pattern that records a predetermined color sequence. The predetermined color sequence corresponds to a piece of playing information of the multimedia file and is composed of the color codes.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The method for identifying a multimedia file that is played on a display device is described as follows. Initially, step <b>201</b> is executed to receive a sensed datum from a sensing device. Then, step <b>202</b> is executed to determine the sensed color code representing the sensed datum by comparing the red composition datum, the green composition datum, and the blue composition datum with the red composition definition, the green composition definition, and the blue composition definition. Next, step <b>203</b> is executed to determine whether the sensed color code representing the sensed datum is one of the color codes. If the answer is &#x201c;yes&#x201d;, then step <b>205</b> is executed to determine whether the sensed color code is identical to a prior sensed color code stored in the queue register. Otherwise, if the answer of step <b>205</b> is &#x201c;no&#x201d;, then step <b>207</b> is executed to store the sensed color code into the queue register. Afterwards, step <b>211</b> is executed to determine whether an amount of the sensed color codes stored in the queue register is equal to a predetermined quantity. If the amount has reached the predetermined quantity, then step <b>213</b> is executed to form a sensed color sequence by the sensed color codes stored in the queue register. Finally, step <b>215</b> is executed to determine a piece of playing information corresponding to the sensed color sequence, and step <b>217</b> is executed to, according to the piece of playing information corresponding to the sensed color sequence, determine that the multimedia file is correctly played on the display device.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">On the other hand, if it is determined in step <b>203</b> that the sensed color code representing the sensed datum is not one of the color codes, then step <b>204</b> is executed to discard the sensed color code. If it is determined in step <b>205</b> that the sensed color code is identical to the prior sensed color code stored in the queue register, then step <b>209</b> is executed to delete the prior sensed color code stored in the queue register and to store the sensed color code (i.e., the latest sensed color code that is determined) into a queue register.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">It shall be noted that steps <b>201</b> to <b>205</b> are iteratively executed to receive a new sensed datum and determine a new sensed color code representing the new sensed datum. Steps <b>207</b> and <b>209</b> will be executed in response to step <b>205</b>. In other words, if it is determined in step <b>211</b> that an amount of the sensed color codes stored in the queue register has not reached the predetermined quantity, step <b>211</b> will be iterated until the amount of sensed color codes stored in the queue register reaches the predetermined quantity, and then steps <b>213</b>, <b>215</b>, and <b>217</b> are executed in response to step <b>211</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Hereinbelow, the present invention will be illustrated with reference to examples thereof. Here, it is assumed that the color codes stored in the storage module are red, blue, and green, so the color tags attached to the multimedia file may be a red tag <b>31</b>, a blue tag <b>33</b>, and a green tag <b>35</b>. It is also assumed that the predetermined color sequence consists of a predetermined quantity of color tags, and here, consists of three color tags. In reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A-3H</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> shows that the three color tags, including the red tag <b>31</b>, the blue tag <b>33</b>, and the green tag <b>35</b>, appear at different time points. The sensing device senses the color tags at time points t<sub>1</sub>&#x2dc;t<sub>7</sub>, which are equally separated, respectively to generate sensed data. At time point t<sub>1</sub>, the process module determines that the sensed color code <b>31</b><i>a </i>representing the sensed datum is a red code, and then stores the sensed color code <b>31</b><i>a </i>into the queue register, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>. At time point t<sub>2</sub>, the process module determines that the sensed color code <b>31</b><i>b </i>representing the sensed datum is also a red code; however, because the sensed color code <b>31</b><i>b </i>is identical to the prior sensed color code <b>31</b><i>a </i>stored in the queue register, the process module must delete the sensed color code <b>31</b><i>a </i>from the queue register and, instead, store the sensed color code <b>31</b><i>b </i>into the queue register, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref>. At time point t<sub>3</sub>, because no color tag exists at this time point, the process module determines that the sensed color code representing the sensed datum is not one of the color codes and, thus, discards the sensed color code, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3D</figref>. In this case, the queue register still has the sensed color code <b>31</b><i>b </i>stored therein; i.e., the status of the queue register is identical to that shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref>. Subsequently, at time points t<sub>4 </sub>and t<sub>5</sub>, the process module determines, respectively, that the sensed color code <b>33</b><i>a </i>representing a sensed datum and the sensed color code <b>33</b><i>b </i>representing a sensed datum are both blue codes, so the process module deletes the sensed color code <b>33</b><i>a </i>stored in the register at time point t<sub>4 </sub>from the register and stores the sensed color code <b>33</b><i>b </i>into the register instead, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3E-3F</figref>. Likewise, at time points t<sub>6 </sub>and t<sub>7</sub>, the process module determines, respectively, that the sensed color code <b>35</b><i>a </i>representing a sensed datum and the sensed color code <b>35</b><i>b </i>representing a sensed datum are both green codes, so the process module deletes the sensed color code <b>35</b><i>a </i>stored in the register at time point t<sub>4 </sub>from the register and stores the sensed color code <b>35</b><i>b </i>into the register instead, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3G-3H</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates another example to exemplify how the present invention uses color tags to obtain a piece of playing information represented by the color tags. Initially, it is assumed that color codes stored in the storage module are red, blue, and green, so the color tags attached to the multimedia file may be a red tag <b>31</b>, a blue tag <b>33</b>, and a green tag <b>35</b>. It is also assumed that the predetermined color sequence consists of a predetermined quantity of color tags, and here, consists of three color tags. Here, the color sequence of &#x201c;red tag <b>31</b>, blue tag <b>33</b>, green tag <b>35</b>&#x201d; is used to represent the start of playing a multimedia file, and the color sequence of &#x201c;blue tag <b>33</b>, red tag <b>31</b>, green tag <b>35</b>&#x201d; is used to represent the end of playing the multimedia file. Then, from the color sequence of &#x201c;red tag <b>31</b>, blue tag <b>33</b>, green tag <b>35</b>&#x201d;, a duration T<sub>1 </sub>in which the color sequence appears is obtained. Finally, from the color sequence of &#x201c;blue tag <b>33</b>, red tag <b>31</b>, green tag <b>35</b>&#x201d;, a duration T<sub>2 </sub>from the end of the color sequence of &#x201c;red tag <b>31</b>, blue tag <b>33</b>, green tag <b>35</b>&#x201d; to the end of the color sequence of &#x201c;blue tag <b>33</b>, red tag <b>31</b>, green tag <b>35</b>&#x201d; is obtained. Accordingly, by attaching these two color sequences to the multimedia file, the duration in which the multimedia file is played on the display device can be calculated to be approximately T<sub>1</sub>+T<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In summary, the multimedia playing system of the present invention may be effectively applied to an LCD system. By attaching color tags to a multimedia file and by using a sensing device to sense the color tags instead of conventionally using a CCD to monitor the frame, both the complexity and cost necessary for monitoring the system are significantly reduced. Furthermore, because both the complexity and cost are reduced, the multimedia playing system of the present invention may make the LCD system more convenient to use, thereby providing more diversified services.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The above disclosure is related to the detailed technical contents and inventive features thereof. People skilled in this field may proceed with a variety of modifications and replacements based on the disclosures and suggestions of the invention as described without departing from the characteristics thereof. Nevertheless, although such modifications and replacements are not fully disclosed in the above descriptions, they have substantially been covered in the following claims as appended.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method for identifying a file played on a display device, the display device having a predetermined area, a plurality of color tags being attached to the file, the color tags being adapted to be displayed on the predetermined area, each of the color tags corresponding to a color code, the method being used with a color pattern, the color pattern recording at least one predetermined color sequence, the at least one predetermined color sequence corresponding to a piece of playing information of the file and being composed of the color codes, the method comprising the following steps of:
<claim-text>(a) receiving a sensed datum from a sensing device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) determining a sensed color code representing the sensed datum, wherein the sensed color code is one of the color codes;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) storing the sensed color code into a queue register;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) iterating steps (a), (b), and (c) until an amount of the sensed color codes stored in the queue register is equal to a predetermined quantity, and a sensed color sequence being formed by the sensed color codes stored in the queue register; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) determining the piece of playing information corresponding to the sensed color sequence by comparing the sensed color sequence with the at least one predetermined color sequence;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the sensing device generates the sensed data by sensing the predetermined area.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising the following steps of:
<claim-text>(f) determining that the sensed color code is not one of the color codes; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(g) discarding the sensed color code based on the determination result of the step (f).</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one predetermined color sequence is composed of the predetermined quantity of the color codes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of the sensed data comprises a red composition datum, a green composition datum, and a blue composition datum.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the method is used with a red composition definition, a green composition definition, and a blue composition definition, the step (b) determines the sensed color code representing the sensed datum by comparing the red composition datum, the green composition datum, and the blue composition datum with the red composition definition, the green composition definition, and the blue composition definition.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising the following steps of:
<claim-text>determining that the sensed color code is identical to a prior sensed color code stored in the queue register after the step (b); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>deleting the prior sensed color code stored in the queue register.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the piece of playing information corresponding to the at least one predetermined color sequence represents one of a message of starting a play and a message of ending a play.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, further comprising the following steps of:
<claim-text>calculating a playing time of the file played on the display device according to the piece of playing information corresponding to the sensed color sequence.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising the following steps of:
<claim-text>determining that the file is correctly played on the display device according to the piece of playing information corresponding to the sensed color sequence.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. An apparatus for identifying a file played on a display device, the display device having a predetermined area, a plurality of color tags being attached to the file, the color tags being adapted to be displayed on the predetermined area, each of the color tags corresponding to a color code, the apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a storage module, being configured to store a color pattern, the color pattern recording at least one predetermined color sequence, the at least one predetermined color sequence corresponding to a piece of playing information of the file and being composed of the color codes;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transmission module, being configured to continuously receive a sensed datum from a sensing device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a queue register; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a process module, being configured to continuously determine a sensed color code representing the sensed datum, the sensed color code being one of the color codes, the process module being further configured to continuously store the sensed color code into the queue register until an amount of the sensed color codes stored in the queen register is equal to a predetermined quantity, a sensed color sequence being formed by the sensed color codes, and the process module being further configured to determine the piece of playing information corresponding to the sensed color sequence by comparing the sensed color sequence with the at least one predetermined color sequence;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the sensing device generates the sensed data by sensing the predetermined area.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the process module is further configured to determine that the sensed color code is not one of the color codes and discard the sensed color code based on the determination of the sensed color code being not one of the color codes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one predetermined color sequence is composed of the predetermined quantity of the color codes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein each of the sensed data comprises a red composition datum, a green composition datum, and a blue composition datum.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the storage module is further configured to store a red composition definition, a green composition definition, and a blue composition definition, the process module determines the sensed color code representing the sensed datum by comparing the red composition datum, the green composition datum, and the blue composition datum with the red composition definition, the green composition definition, and the blue composition definition.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the process module is further configured to determine that the sensed color code is identical to a prior sensed color code stored in the queue register and delete the prior sensed color code stored in the queue register after determining the sensed color code representing the sensed datum.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the piece of playing information corresponding to the predetermined color sequence represents one of a message of starting a play and a message of ending a play.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the process module is further configured to calculate a playing time of the file played on the display device according to the piece of playing information corresponding to the sensed color sequence.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the process module is further configured to determine that the file is correctly played on the display device according to the piece of playing information corresponding to the sensed color sequence.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A multimedia playing system, comprising:
<claim-text>a display device, having a predetermined area and being configured to play a file, a plurality of color tags being attached to the file, the color tags being adapted to be displayed on the predetermined area, each of the color tags corresponding to a color code;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensing device, being disposed to face the predetermined area and configured to continuously sense the predetermined area to generate a sensed datum; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an identification device, being connected to the sensing device and configured to store a color pattern, the color pattern recording at least one predetermined color sequence, the at least one predetermined color sequence corresponding to a piece of playing information of the file and being composed of the color codes, the identification device being further configured to receive the sensed data from the sensing device, the identification device being further configured to determine a sensed color code representing each of the sensed data, each of the sensed color codes being one of the color codes, the identification device being further configured to store the sensed color code into a queue register until an amount of the sensed color codes stored in the queue register is equal to a predetermined quantity, a sensed color sequence being formed by the sensed color codes, the identification device being further configured to determine the piece of playing information corresponding to the sensed color sequence by comparing the sensed color sequence with the at least one predetermined color sequence.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The multimedia playing system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the identification device is further configured to determine that the sensed color code is not one of the color codes and discard the sensed color code based on the determination of the sensed color code being not one of the color codes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The multimedia playing system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one predetermined color sequence is composed of the predetermined quantity of the color codes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The multimedia playing system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein each of the sensed data comprises a red composition datum, a green composition datum, and a blue composition datum.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. The multimedia playing system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, wherein the identification device is further configured to store a red composition definition, a green composition definition, and a blue composition definition the identification device determines the sensed color code representing the sensed datum by comparing the red composition datum, the green composition datum, and the blue composition datum with the red composition definition, the green composition definition, and the blue composition definition.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. The multimedia playing system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the identification device is further configured to determine that the sensed color code is identical to a prior sensed color code stored in the queue register and delete the prior sensed color code stored in the queue register after determining the sensed color code representing the sensed datum.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text>25. The multimedia playing system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the identification device is further configured to calculate a playing time of the file played on the display device according to the piece of playing information corresponding to the sensed color sequence.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text>26. The multimedia playing system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the identification device is further configured to determine that the file is correctly played on the display device according to the piece of playing information corresponding to the sensed color sequence.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text>27. The multimedia playing system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the piece of playing information corresponding to the predetermined color sequence represents one of a message of starting a play and a message of ending a play.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text>28. The multimedia playing system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the identification device is connected to the sensing device by one of a wireless way and a wired way. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
