<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08627438-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08627438</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13228192</doc-number>
<date>20110908</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>125</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>17</main-group>
<subgroup>30</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>726  9</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Passwordless strong authentication using trusted devices</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0067828</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Bychkov</name>
<date>20070300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>726  3</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00002">
<othercit>RSA securities &#x201c;Enhancing One-Time Passwords for Protection Against Real-Time Phishing Attacks&#x201d;, 2004. RSA Security Inc. pp. 1-10.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>32</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>726  9</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>7</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bhimanaik</last-name>
<first-name>Bharath Kumar</first-name>
<address>
<city>Bellevue</city>
<state>WA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bhimanaik</last-name>
<first-name>Bharath Kumar</first-name>
<address>
<city>Bellevue</city>
<state>WA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Thomas | Horstemeyer, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Amazon Technologies, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Reno</city>
<state>NV</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Zand</last-name>
<first-name>Kambiz</first-name>
<department>2434</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Getachew</last-name>
<first-name>Abiy</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A code for accessing an online resource having a customer account associated therewith is presented via a secondary device, and authentication data indicative of the code that was presented is received from a primary device. The primary device is identified as a trusted device associated with the customer account responsive to receiving the authentication data therefrom, and the secondary device is authenticated for access to the online resource responsive to identification of the primary device as the trusted device associated with the customer account.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="173.91mm" wi="277.71mm" file="US08627438-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="286.85mm" wi="179.32mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627438-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="239.18mm" wi="186.01mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627438-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="284.73mm" wi="187.03mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627438-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="264.75mm" wi="176.53mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627438-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="183.56mm" wi="132.08mm" file="US08627438-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="201.76mm" wi="127.51mm" file="US08627438-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="287.87mm" wi="189.82mm" file="US08627438-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">Consumers may use computer network systems, such as the Internet, to access a variety of data, applications, and services, generally referred to herein as online resources. The methodology employed to reliably verify the identity of a consumer or other user of a computer network system prior to allowing the user access to system resources is generally referred to as authentication. For example, the user may send a username and password to a remote server in order to authenticate the user for access to the resources provided thereby. Cryptography can be used to preserve the confidentiality of the transmitted username and password when authenticating the user.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">However, such password-based authentication can be somewhat cumbersome to the user. For example, as each online resource typically requires its users to have unique usernames, a user may be unable to use the same username to access multiple online resources if that username is already in use by another user of any of the online resources. As such, a user may be required to remember several different usernames in order to access different online resources, as well as to keep track of which username was used to set up the account for each online resource. Likewise, each online resource may have different rules as to the types of character strings that may be used as passwords. For example, some websites may require a password to have more than a particular number of characters (e.g. more than 6 characters), others may require a password to be a combination of alphabetic and numeric characters, and still others may require a password to include at least one special character (such as !, @, #, $, %, &#x26;, etc.). Thus, in addition to remembering different usernames, a user may also be required to remember several different passwords in order to access different online resources, as well as to keep track of which username-password pair applies to each account.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The use of usernames and passwords for authentication may also present problems from a security perspective. For example, password-based authentication may be vulnerable to keystroke logging applications (where a hidden application records the keystrokes of a user) or phishing attacks (where a user is tricked into revealing his username and password by a masquerading entity). Also, should a user's password for an online resource be compromised by the above or other security issues, the user may be required to create and remember yet another password, thereby compounding the above-mentioned problems associated with remembering and keeping track of different usernames and password combinations for different accounts.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram of systems, devices, methods and computer program products for authenticating a customer of an account-based online resource using a trusted device, according to various embodiments described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram illustrating authentication of a customer of an account-based online resource using a trusted device, according to some embodiments described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a block diagram illustrating authentication of a customer of an account-based online resource using a trusted device, according to further embodiments described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates a screenshot of an example user interface for authenticating a customer of an account-based online resource using a trusted device according to various embodiments described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a flowchart of operations that may be performed to authenticate a customer of an account-based online resource using a trusted device according to some embodiments described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flowchart of operations that may be performed to authenticate a customer of an account-based online resource using a trusted device according to further embodiments described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a flowchart of operations that may be performed to authenticate a customer of an account-based online resource using a trusted device according to still further embodiments described herein.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Various embodiments described herein provide methods, systems, and devices for providing alternate and more secure ways for authenticating customers to access online resources, instead of (or in addition to) entry of a username and password. As used herein, an online resource may refer to any content that is accessible via a network, such as web-based or cloud-based data, applications, and services. Examples of online resources may include, but are not limited to, web-based or cloud based data storage services, social networking applications, shopping services, microblogging accounts, payment services, multimedia content delivery services (such as online magazine, music, video, etc.) and financial services (such as credit/banking services).</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In particular, embodiments described herein allow customers to sign-in or login to one or more accounts associated with online applications or services using a trusted device (such as a mobile phone, a smartphone, a tablet, or other portable electronic terminal) that has been previously registered or linked to the account(s). For example, a visible code may be displayed on a desktop computer alongside (or instead of) a password-based sign-in window that is typically used to access a customer account for a web-based service. A mobile phone that has been previously registered with the same customer account can scan the displayed code using its camera, and can send the scanned code to a web server that provides the web-based service. In response to receiving the scanned code, the web server can identify the mobile phone as being associated with the customer account based on the prior registration, and can thereby authenticate the desktop computer for access to the web-based service based on recognition of the scanned code. Thus, the desktop computer may be automatically signed-in to the web-based service based on recognition of the mobile phone as a trusted device, without requiring the customer to enter his username and password.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Online resources that can be accessed in accordance with embodiments described herein may be accessible using a web browser executing on a computer, as well as with native applications executing on non-traditional computing devices, such as televisions or external set-top boxes connected to a television. Embodiments described herein therefore allow an unregistered device (or a device that is otherwise unknown to an online application or service) to access a customer account responsive to receiving authenticating information from a trusted device that has been previously registered with (or is otherwise already associated with) the customer account. Accordingly, embodiments described herein may reduce demands on the customer (e.g., for remembering usernames and passwords) as well as obviate many security risks as compared to traditional password-based authentication methods.</p>
<p id="h-0004" num="0000">Overall Architecture for Using a Trusted Device to Authenticate Another Device</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram of systems, devices, methods, and computer program products for authenticating a customer for access to account-based online resources using a trusted device, according to various embodiments described herein. As used herein, the term &#x201c;account-based online resource&#x201d; may refer to network-accessible data, applications, services, or combinations thereof that require a customer account or subscription to access the content or services provided thereby. Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a communications environment or system <b>100</b> may include a mobile electronic device <b>110</b> and another electronic device <b>120</b> that are accessible to a user <b>101</b> and are configured for communication via a network <b>140</b>. The mobile device <b>110</b> (also referred to herein as a &#x201c;primary device&#x201d; associated with the user <b>101</b>) may be a wireless communication terminal, such as a cellular telephone, smartphone, electronic book reader, tablet, or other portable electronic terminal that is configured to access the network <b>140</b> over a wireless connection, for example, via a base station transceiver <b>108</b>. The electronic device <b>120</b> (also referred to herein as a &#x201c;secondary device&#x201d; accessible to the user <b>101</b>) may be a wired or wireless communication terminal, such as a desktop computer, laptop computer, smartphone, tablet, network-ready television, set-top box, and the like, and may be configured to access the network <b>140</b> via a wired or wireless connection. The secondary device <b>120</b> may be configured to access the network using a web browser or a native application executing thereon. In some embodiments, the mobile device <b>110</b> may have a physical size or form factor that enables it to be easily carried or transported by a user <b>101</b>, while the electronic device <b>120</b> may have a larger physical size or form factor than the mobile device <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The devices <b>110</b> and <b>120</b> are configured to access online resources, including web-based or cloud-based data, applications, and services, via the network <b>140</b>. The network <b>140</b> may represent one or more of a local area network (LAN), a wide area network (WAN), an Intranet or other private network that may not be accessible by the general public, or a global network, such as the Internet or other publicly accessible network. The network <b>140</b> provides communication between the devices <b>110</b> and <b>120</b> and one or more online resource providers <b>150</b> (such as web servers) configured to provide the aforementioned online data, applications, or services. The online resource provider <b>150</b> may include a network transceiver, processor, memory, and or other circuitry configured to coordinate and manage operations for delivering online resources to the devices <b>110</b> and <b>120</b> via the network <b>140</b>. While illustrated as a single entity in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, it will be understood that, in some embodiments, the online resource provider <b>150</b> may represent one or more physical or virtual servers that are configured to deliver online resources to the devices <b>110</b> and <b>120</b>. Examples of the online resources provided by the online resource provider <b>150</b> may include, but are not limited to, web-based or cloud based data storage services, social networking applications, shopping services, microblogging accounts, payment services, multimedia content delivery services (for delivery of online magazines, music, video, etc.) and financial services (such as credit/banking services).</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The online resource provider <b>150</b> may require a subscription or customer account in order to access each of the different online resources provided thereby. As such, the system <b>100</b> also includes a customer account store <b>135</b> that contains customer account information for one or more customers, such as the user <b>101</b>. The customer account store <b>135</b> may be embodied in nonvolatile memory, such as flash, magnetic, or optical rewritable nonvolatile memory. The customer account information stored in the customer account store <b>135</b> may include a listing of customer accounts and online resources to which the accounts correspond. The customer accounts may include information identifying each user or customer that has registered for each online resource, such as the customer's name, mailing address, e-mail address, phone number, payment. The customer account information may also include information that may be used to verify or authenticate the customer to access the account. For example, for each customer account, the customer account information may include a username and a password selected by the customer to access the account. However, as noted above, such password-based authentication may be cumbersome for a customer, and may also be vulnerable from a security standpoint.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In accordance with some embodiments described herein, the customer account information stored in the customer account store <b>135</b> further includes registration information identifying a trusted device associated with each account. For example, the user <b>101</b> may download and execute an application on the primary device <b>110</b> that allows the user to register or otherwise link the primary device <b>110</b> to one or more of the user's accounts for different online resources. The primary device <b>110</b> may transmit this registration information to a server associated with an online resource (such as the online resource provider <b>150</b> that delivers the online resource or an authentication server <b>130</b>, as discussed below) in the form of a registration request that identifies the user <b>101</b> and the users' customer account. In response, the online resource provider <b>150</b> may register the primary device <b>110</b> as a trusted device associated with the customer account, and may store an indication of this association in the customer account store <b>135</b>. For example, the customer account store <b>135</b> may include a lookup table including a key values and parameters indicative of a plurality of customer accounts for each online resource, and one or more trusted devices associated each customer account.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the system further includes an authentication server <b>130</b> configured to authenticate electronic devices (such as the devices <b>110</b> and <b>120</b>) to access the online resource(s) provided by the online resource provider <b>150</b>. The authentication server <b>130</b> may include a network transceiver, processor, memory, and or other circuitry configured to coordinate and manage authentication operations via the network <b>140</b>. In particular, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the authentication server <b>130</b> includes a code generator <b>131</b> and an authentication module <b>133</b>. The code generator <b>131</b> and the authentication module <b>133</b> may be embodied in hardware and/or in software that runs on a processor, such as a commercially available or custom microprocessor.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The code generator <b>131</b> is configured to provide a code that may be used to access an online resource having an associated customer account. The code may be any unique identifier, such as a randomly generated character string, and may be represented by a one-dimensional or multi-dimensional machine-readable code, such as a QR code, in some embodiments. The code may be generated in response to detecting an attempt by the secondary device <b>120</b> to access the online content provided by the online resource provider <b>150</b>. For example, the code generator <b>131</b> may generate the code in response to receiving a request to access an online resource provided by the online resource provider <b>150</b> using a trusted device. In other embodiments, the code generator <b>131</b> may retrieve or select the code from a code store <b>145</b> that stores a plurality of previously-generated codes. The code provided by the code generator <b>131</b> may also include addressing information for the authentication server <b>130</b>, such as an IP address or network ID. The authentication server <b>130</b> also includes a network transceiver <b>132</b> that is configured to transmit or issue the code provided by the code generator <b>131</b> to the online resource provider <b>150</b> for presentation via the secondary device <b>120</b>, for example, in response to detecting the attempt by the secondary device <b>120</b> to access the online resource. The code store <b>145</b> may also store information listing currently or previously issued codes, the authentication status of each issued code, and the online resource to which each issued code corresponds, thereby allowing re-use of codes.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">As described in greater detail below with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, the secondary device <b>120</b> may display or otherwise present the code received from the transceiver <b>132</b> to provide a method for authentication of the secondary device <b>120</b> using the primary device <b>110</b>, without receiving a username or password from the secondary device <b>120</b>. More particularly, the primary device <b>110</b> may scan or otherwise record in the code presented by the secondary device <b>120</b>, and may transmit authentication data indicative of the code to the authentication server <b>130</b> using the network ID, IP address, or other information identifying the authentication server <b>130</b> that is included in the code. The authentication data may identify the primary device <b>110</b>, and may indicate that the code previously provided to the secondary device <b>120</b> was recorded by the primary device <b>110</b>. In some embodiments, the primary device <b>110</b> may locally scan or capture a code displayed by the secondary device <b>120</b> (via the screen of the secondary device <b>120</b>) or transmitted by the secondary device <b>120</b> (via Bluetooth or near-field communication), and may send the captured code or authentication data derived from the captured code to the authentication server <b>130</b>. For example, upon registration, the authentication server <b>130</b> may assign and transmit to the primary device <b>110</b> a particular encryption key for use in future authentication operations. As such, after scanning the code presented by the secondary device, the primary device <b>110</b> may derive a security value from the scanned code, may use the assigned key to encrypt or &#x201c;sign&#x201d; the security value to provide the authentication data, and may transmit the authentication data to the authentication server <b>130</b>, which may recognize that the code was locally scanned by the primary device <b>110</b> based on the &#x201c;signature&#x201d; present in the authentication data.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The authentication data received from the primary device <b>110</b> can be used by the authentication server <b>130</b> to authenticate the secondary device <b>120</b> for access to a customer accounts associated with the online content provided by the online resource provider <b>150</b>. In particular, in response to receiving the authentication data from the mobile device <b>110</b> via the transceiver <b>132</b>, the authentication module <b>133</b> is configured to access the customer account store <b>135</b> in order to identify the primary device <b>110</b> as a trusted device associated with the customer account. In particular, based on information in the authentication data identifying the primary device <b>110</b>, the authentication module <b>133</b> accesses a lookup table stored in the customer account store <b>135</b>, where the lookup table includes key values and parameters indicating the trusted device(s) that have been previously registered with each customer account for the desired online resource. As such, the authentication module <b>133</b> may identify the primary device <b>110</b> as a trusted device associated with a particular customer account based on a prior registration event linking or otherwise associating the primary device with the customer account. In some embodiments, the registration event may occur prior to or concurrently with receiving the authentication data from the primary device <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In response to identifying the primary device <b>110</b> as a trusted device associated with the customer account, the authentication server <b>130</b> may authenticate the secondary device <b>120</b> for access to the desired online resource. For example, the authentication module <b>133</b> may provide an indication to the online resource provider <b>150</b> that the secondary device <b>120</b> is permitted access to the online resource responsive to receiving the authentication data from the primary device <b>110</b>. In particular, the authentication module <b>133</b> may mark the security value from the code that was presented by the secondary device <b>120</b> as being authenticated, and may store an indication thereof in the customer account store <b>135</b> or in the code store <b>145</b>. Upon verifying authentication of the secondary device <b>120</b>, the online resource provider <b>150</b> may automatically log the secondary device <b>120</b> into the customer account associated with the online resource provided thereby. Accordingly, embodiments described herein may allow for authentication of the secondary device <b>120</b> without receiving customer identification information, such as a username and password, from the secondary device <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In some embodiments, the system <b>100</b> may be further configured to allow for multi-factor authentication of the secondary device <b>120</b> via the primary device <b>110</b>. For example, responsive to receiving the authentication data indicative of the code presented by the secondary device <b>120</b>, the authentication server <b>130</b> may instruct the primary device <b>110</b> or the secondary device <b>120</b> to display a prompt for additional authentication data. In particular, as customer accounts associated with some online resources hosted by the online resource provider <b>150</b> (such as banking or other financial services) may contain more sensitive information than others (such as streaming video services), the authentication server <b>130</b> may request additional authentication data in order to authenticate the secondary device <b>120</b> for access to more sensitive accounts. Likewise, the user <b>101</b> may associate multiple devices having different levels of trust with a particular customer account in the customer account store <b>135</b>, and the online resource provider <b>150</b> may require additional authentication data from devices having a lower level of trust. For example, if the primary device <b>110</b> is registered as a trusted device with the user's corporate account, the user <b>101</b> may also register a personal device (such as a personal mobile phone) with the corporate account; however, additional authentication data may be required from the personal device to authenticate the secondary device <b>120</b> for access to the corporate account, based on its lower level of trust relative to the primary device <b>110</b>. The additional authentication data may be requested, for example, in the form of a username and password, a personal identification number (PIN) or even a physical authentication token, in addition to the data indicative of the code displayed by the secondary device <b>120</b>. As such, for accounts associated with more sensitive online content (or for devices having a lower level of trust), the authentication server <b>130</b> may be configured to permit the secondary device <b>120</b> to access an account hosted by the online resource provider <b>150</b> only in response to receiving both the initial authentication data (indicative of the code presented by the secondary device <b>120</b>) and the additional authentication data discussed above.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Embodiments described herein may also be used to facilitate transactions with a point-of-sale (POS) terminal, such as those used in retail stores or even in parking meters. For example, the secondary device <b>120</b> may be a network-accessible parking meter configured to present the code described herein to the primary device <b>110</b>. The primary device <b>110</b> can thereby record and transmit the code to the authentication server <b>130</b> to authenticate the parking meter <b>120</b> to access the user's account for a parking service. Once logged-in to the user's account, the user <b>101</b> may use the parking meter <b>120</b> to charge the parking fees to the user's account, without entering customer identification information into the parking meter.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Although <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates an example communications environment <b>100</b> in accordance with some embodiments, it will be understood that the present disclosure is not limited to such a configuration but is intended to encompass any configuration capable of carrying out the operations described herein. For example, although primarily discussed above with reference to a single authentication server <b>130</b> and a single online resource provider <b>150</b>, some embodiments may include a plurality of distributed network elements that collectively perform the operations described herein to provide for passwordless authentication of a customer using a trusted device. Likewise, while illustrated as separate entities, it will be understood that the operations performed by the online resource provider <b>150</b> and the authentication server <b>130</b> may be performed by a single entity in some embodiments. More generally, various functionality described herein with reference to separate functional elements may be combined within a single functional element and, vice versa, functionality described herein in single functional elements can be carried out by a plurality of separate functional elements.</p>
<p id="h-0005" num="0000">Use Case Example&#x2014;Consumer Access to Website Via PC</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates authentication of a personal computer <b>220</b> for access to an online resource using a trusted mobile device according to some embodiments described herein. The mobile device <b>210</b> may be a mobile terminal, smartphone, electronic book reader, or tablet, in some embodiments. Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a user (such as the user <b>101</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) may download and launch a mobile device application <b>215</b> using the mobile device <b>210</b>. The mobile device application <b>215</b> may present a user interface <b>212</b> via a display <b>209</b> of the mobile device <b>210</b>. The user interface <b>212</b> may provide one or more on-screen prompts that allow the user to register or link the mobile device <b>210</b> with a particular customer account for a web-based shopping service (for example, as provided by the online resource provider <b>150</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). The data associating the mobile device <b>210</b> with the customer account for the shopping service may be stored, for example, in a customer account data store (such as the customer account store <b>135</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Using a web browser <b>219</b> executing on the personal computer <b>220</b>, the user may attempt to access the web-based shopping service (illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> as a fictitious service called &#x201c;WebShopping.com&#x201d;) provided by a online resource provider. The user interface <b>250</b> of the shopping service includes two options for authentication: a manual sign-in area <b>225</b><i>a </i>(where the user can enter a username and password), and an automatic sign-in area <b>225</b><i>b </i>(where the user can sign-in using a trusted device). The automatic sign-in area <b>225</b><i>b </i>of the user interface <b>250</b> also displays a QR code <b>205</b><i>a </i>for use in the automatic sign-in process. The QR code <b>205</b><i>a </i>may represent a unique or randomly generated security token (such as a pseudo-random number (PRN) sequence) that is provided by an authentication server <b>230</b> in response to detecting the attempt by the personal computer <b>220</b> to access the online shopping service. In some embodiments, the QR code <b>205</b><i>a </i>may be generated and displayed responsive to receiving a request from the personal computer <b>220</b> expressing a desire to access the online shopping service without entry of customer identification. information. For example, the user interface <b>250</b> may include an option or on-screen button (or other user activated interface) <b>229</b> for signing-in using the automatic sign-in process instead of manual sign-in process. Responsive to selection of this button <b>229</b>, the browser <b>219</b> (or the online resource provider) may transmit a request to the authentication server <b>230</b>, and the authentication server <b>230</b> may generate and transmit the code <b>205</b><i>a </i>to the online resource provider for display by the browser <b>219</b> in the automatic sign-in area <b>225</b><i>b </i>of the user interface <b>250</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, once the QR code <b>205</b><i>a </i>is displayed on the personal computer <b>220</b> in the automatic sign-in area <b>225</b><i>b</i>, the user can launch the mobile device application <b>215</b> on the mobile device <b>210</b>, and can scan the displayed QR code <b>205</b><i>a </i>using a camera <b>207</b> of the mobile device <b>210</b>. In some embodiments, the user interface <b>250</b> may display on-screen directions prompting the user to scan the displayed QR code <b>205</b><i>a </i>using a trusted device that is registered with the user's account for the online shopping service. An indication <b>205</b><i>b </i>of the QR code can be displayed in the user interface <b>212</b> of the mobile device <b>210</b> responsive to scanning the code <b>205</b><i>a </i>using the camera <b>207</b>. The user interface <b>212</b> of the mobile device application <b>215</b> may also display a button <b>211</b> asking the user to confirm that the code has been scanned for the automatic sign-in process. Additional options may also be presented via the user interfaces <b>212</b> or <b>250</b>, such as options to limit or extend the duration of time for which the personal computer <b>220</b> is authenticated to access the online shopping service.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In response to selection of the button <b>211</b>, the mobile device application <b>215</b> transmits authentication data to the authentication server <b>230</b>, for example, based on addressing information (such as a network ID or IP address) included in the QR code <b>205</b><i>a</i>. The authentication data is generated by the mobile device <b>210</b> from the security token included in the QR code <b>205</b><i>a</i>. For example, the authentication data may be generated by the mobile device <b>210</b> by encrypting the security token presented in the QR code <b>205</b><i>a </i>using an encryption key previously provided to the mobile device <b>210</b> by the authentication server <b>230</b> (for example, during the registration process). The authentication data therefore includes information that identifies the mobile device <b>210</b> and indicates that the QR code <b>205</b><i>a </i>displayed on the personal computer <b>220</b> was scanned by the mobile device <b>210</b> based on the encryption of the authentication data with the assigned key.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Upon receiving the authentication data, the authentication server <b>230</b> verifies that the mobile device <b>210</b> is a trusted device associated with the customer account, for example, by accessing a lookup table in a customer account data store (such as the customer account store <b>135</b>). Once the mobile device <b>210</b> has been identified as a trusted device, the authentication server <b>230</b> marks the token provided in the QR code <b>205</b><i>a </i>as authenticated, and may store an indication of the same in the customer account data store or in a code data store (such as the code store <b>145</b>). The online resource provider repeatedly queries the appropriate data store or otherwise verifies with the authentication server <b>230</b> that the code <b>205</b><i>a </i>has been authenticated, and in response, transmits cookies to the web browser <b>219</b> to set up a session or authentication state. As such, the personal computer <b>220</b> is authenticated and automatically signed-in to the customer account of the online shopping service based on prior registration of the mobile device <b>210</b> as a trusted device for the customer account, without entry of a username or password.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In some embodiments, the user interface <b>212</b> of the mobile device application <b>215</b> also provides an option or on-screen button <b>235</b> for revoking the access of the personal computer <b>220</b> to the online shopping service. In particular, upon selection of the button <b>235</b>, the mobile device <b>210</b> may transmit a notification to the authentication server <b>230</b> indicating a desire to revoke the access of the personal computer <b>220</b>, and the authentication server <b>230</b> may thereafter deny the personal computer <b>220</b> access to the online shopping service, for example, by automatically logging out the personal computer <b>220</b> from the customer account in response to the notification. Also, the authentication server <b>230</b> may transmit an alert message to the mobile device <b>210</b> in the event that a problem or security issue with the customer account is detected. For example, the online resource provider or the authentication server <b>230</b> may detect an attempt to access the customer account by another device while the personal computer <b>220</b> is signed-in to the customer account. The alert <b>234</b> may be displayed via the user interface <b>212</b> of the mobile device application <b>215</b>, and the mobile device <b>210</b> may transmit a message to revoke all access to the customer account responsive to selection of the button <b>235</b>. It will be understood that, although illustrated by way of example as being performed by the mobile device application <b>215</b>, the operations for revoking the access of the personal computer <b>220</b> may be presented via and performed by other devices as well. For example, in some embodiments, the option <b>235</b> to revoke the access of the personal computer <b>220</b> may be presented via the browser <b>219</b> executing on the personal computer <b>220</b>; thus, the notification to revoke access may be received from the personal computer <b>220</b> itself. Likewise, a user may login to his account using another computer, such as a home desktop computer (whether by manual sign-in or trusted device sign-in), and the notification to revoke the access of the personal computer <b>220</b> may be received from the desktop computer responsive to presentation of the option <b>235</b> thereby.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Embodiments described herein may also be used in conjunction with third-party online resource providers. For example, once the personal computer <b>220</b> has been authenticated for access to the customer's WebShopping.com account, the personal computer <b>220</b> may be used to browse AwfulBuy.com, another fictitious web-based shopping service. The online resource provider hosting the AwfulBuy.com site may request a code or token from the online resource provider hosting the WebShopping.com site, and the online resource provider hosting the WebShopping.com site may send the token or code to the online resource provider hosting the AwfulBuy.com site indicating that the personal computer <b>220</b> has been authenticated to access the customer's WebShopping.com account. As such, the customer's WebShopping.com account may be used to shop AwfulBuy.com without providing customer identification information to the online resource provider hosting the AwfulBuy.com site.</p>
<p id="h-0006" num="0000">Use Case Example&#x2014;Consumer Access to Online Streaming Via TV/STB</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates authentication of a set-top box (STB) <b>320</b><i>a </i>for access to an online resource using a trusted mobile device according to some embodiments described herein. The STB <b>320</b><i>a </i>may be configured to stream audio and video from an online resource provider, and may be connected to an external display <b>320</b><i>b</i>, such as monitor or television. The mobile device <b>310</b> may be a mobile terminal, smartphone, electronic book reader, or tablet, in some embodiments. Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a user (such as the user <b>101</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) may download and launch a mobile device application <b>315</b> using the mobile device <b>310</b>. The mobile device application <b>315</b> may present a user interface <b>312</b> via a display <b>309</b> of the mobile device <b>310</b>. The user interface <b>312</b> may provide one or more on-screen prompts that allow the user to register or link the mobile device <b>310</b> with a particular customer account for cloud-based streaming entertainment service (for example, as provided by the online resource provider <b>150</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). The data associating the mobile device <b>310</b> with the customer account for the streaming service may be stored, for example, in a customer account data store (such as the customer account store <b>135</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Using a native application <b>319</b> executing on the STB <b>320</b><i>a</i>, the user may attempt to access the cloud-based streaming entertainment service (illustrated herein as a fictitious service called &#x201c;CloudFlix&#x201d;) provided by an online resource provider. The user interface <b>350</b> of the streaming service includes two options for authentication: a manual sign-in area <b>325</b><i>a </i>(where the user can enter a username and password), and an automatic sign-in area <b>325</b><i>b </i>(where the user can sign-in using a trusted device). The automatic sign-in area <b>325</b><i>b </i>of the user interface <b>350</b> also displays a QR code <b>305</b><i>a </i>for use in the automatic sign-in process. The QR code <b>305</b><i>a </i>may represent a unique or randomly generated security token that is provided by an authentication server <b>330</b> in response to detecting the attempt by the STB <b>320</b><i>a </i>to access the streaming service. In some embodiments, the QR code <b>305</b><i>a </i>may be generated and displayed responsive to receiving a request from the STB <b>320</b><i>a </i>indicating a desire to access the service without entry of customer identification information. For example, the user interface <b>350</b> may display an option or on-screen button <b>329</b> for signing-in using the automatic sign-in process instead of the manual sign-in process. Responsive to selection of this option <b>329</b>, the native application <b>319</b> may transmit a request to the authentication server <b>330</b>, and the authentication server <b>330</b> may generate and transmit the QR code <b>305</b><i>a </i>to the online resource provider for display by the native application <b>319</b> in the automatic sign-in area <b>325</b><i>b </i>of the user interface <b>350</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, once the QR code <b>305</b><i>a </i>is displayed in the automatic sign-in area <b>325</b><i>b</i>, the user can launch the mobile device application <b>315</b> on the mobile device <b>310</b>, and can scan the displayed QR code <b>305</b><i>a </i>using a camera <b>307</b> of the mobile device <b>310</b>. In some embodiments, the user interface <b>350</b> may display on-screen directions prompting the user to scan the displayed QR code <b>305</b><i>a </i>using a trusted device that is registered with the user's account for the cloud-based streaming service. An indication <b>305</b><i>b </i>of the QR code may be displayed by the user interface <b>312</b> responsive to scanning the QR code <b>305</b><i>a </i>using the camera <b>307</b>. The user interface <b>312</b> of the mobile device application <b>315</b> may also display a button <b>311</b> asking the user to confirm that the code has been scanned for the automatic sign-in process. Additional options may also be presented via the user interfaces <b>312</b> or <b>350</b>, such as options to limit or extend the duration of time for which the STB <b>320</b><i>a </i>will be authenticated to access the online streaming service.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In response to selection of the button <b>311</b>, the mobile device application <b>315</b> transmits authentication data to the authentication server <b>330</b>, for example, based on contact information (such as a network ID or IP address) included in the QR code <b>305</b><i>a</i>. The authentication data is generated by the mobile device <b>310</b> from the security token included in the QR code <b>305</b><i>a</i>. For example, the authentication data may be generated by the mobile device <b>310</b> by encrypting the security token presented in the QR code <b>305</b><i>a </i>using an encryption key previously provided to the mobile device <b>310</b> by the authentication server <b>330</b> (for example, during the registration process). The authentication data can therefore include information that identifies the mobile device <b>310</b> and indicates that the QR code <b>305</b><i>a </i>presented via the display <b>320</b><i>b </i>was locally scanned by the mobile device <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Upon receiving the authentication data, the authentication server <b>330</b> verifies that the mobile device <b>310</b> is a trusted device associated with the customer account, for example, by accessing a lookup table in the customer account data store (such as the customer account store <b>135</b>). Once the mobile device <b>310</b> has been identified as a trusted device, the authentication server <b>330</b> marks the token provided in the QR code <b>305</b><i>a </i>as authenticated, and may store an indication of the same in a customer account data store or a code data store (such as the code store <b>145</b>). The online resource provider repeatedly queries or otherwise verifies with the authentication server <b>330</b> that the code <b>305</b><i>a </i>has been authenticated, and in response, links the native application <b>319</b> executing on the STB <b>320</b><i>a </i>to the customer account. As such, the STB <b>320</b><i>a </i>is authenticated and automatically signed-in to the customer account of the online streaming service based on the prior registration of the mobile device <b>310</b> as a trusted device for the customer account, and without requiring entry of a username and password, which may be especially cumbersome in the context of non-traditional computing devices such as the STB <b>320</b><i>a</i>. The mobile device application <b>315</b> (or an application executing on another device) may also be used to revoke the authentication of the STB <b>320</b><i>a </i>at any time responsive to selection of a button <b>335</b>, as similarly discussed above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Although illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref> with reference to graphical codes presented as images by secondary devices <b>220</b> and <b>320</b><i>a</i>, it will be understood that the codes presented by the secondary devices <b>220</b> and <b>320</b><i>a </i>are not so limited, but rather, can include any unique identifier that can be presented by a secondary devices, including audible codes or codes presented via short-range communication (such as Bluetooth or NFC). Also, while illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> as separate devices, it will be understood that some or all of the functionality of the STB <b>320</b><i>a </i>may be included or implemented within the display <b>320</b><i>b </i>in some embodiments. More generally, the various functionality described with reference to separate functional elements may be combined within a single functional element, and vice versa.</p>
<p id="h-0007" num="0000">Example User Interface for an Online Resource</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a screenshot illustrating an example user interface for authenticating a customer of an account-based online resource using a trusted device in accordance with some embodiments disclosed herein. The online resource may be accessed over a network, such as the network <b>140</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, using a web browser, a downloadable client application, or a native application executing on a secondary electronic device, such as the electronic devices <b>120</b>, <b>220</b>, or <b>320</b><i>a/b </i>of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, <b>2</b>, or <b>3</b>. Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a user interface <b>400</b> of a web-based online resource (illustrated herein as a fictitious online shopping service called &#x201c;WebShopping.com&#x201d;) includes a banner area <b>450</b> along an upper portion of the user interface <b>400</b> indicating the name of the service, and a manual sign-in area <b>425</b><i>a</i>. The manual sign-in area <b>425</b><i>a </i>displays fields <b>426</b> and <b>427</b> for entering a username and password, respectively, and a &#x201c;sign-in&#x201d; button <b>428</b> that a user can click (after entry of a username and password in the fields <b>426</b> and <b>427</b>) to authenticate the user for access to the website. As such, the user interface <b>400</b> allows for authentication of a user to access the online resource by traditional password-based authentication.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the user interface <b>400</b> further includes an automatic sign-in area <b>425</b><i>b</i>. The automatic sign-in area <b>425</b><i>b </i>allows for authentication using a trusted device (such as the mobile devices <b>110</b>, <b>210</b>, or <b>310</b> described herein) by displaying a machine-readable code <b>405</b> (illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> as a QR code) representing a security token. The code <b>405</b> can be scanned by a camera of a trusted device and transmitted to an authentication server, as described in detail above, to authenticate the secondary electronic device that is currently displaying the user interface <b>400</b> for access to the shopping service. In some embodiments, the code <b>405</b> may be generated and displayed on the user interface <b>400</b> responsive to clicking a button <b>431</b> indicating a desire to sign-in to the service without entry of customer identification information. For example, in response to clicking the button <b>431</b>, a request to access WebShopping.com using a trusted device (e.g., without entry of a username and password in fields <b>426</b> and <b>427</b>) may be transmitted to an authentication server (such as the authentication server <b>130</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>), which may generate and transmit the code <b>405</b> for display in the automatic sign-in area <b>425</b><i>b </i>of the user interface <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The automatic sign-in area <b>425</b><i>b </i>also displays a button <b>429</b> that allows a user to set a duration of validity for the authentication of the secondary device on which the user interface <b>400</b> is displayed. In particular, by clicking on the button <b>429</b>, the user interface <b>400</b> allows a user to enter an indication of a duration of time for which the present session or access to the online resource will be allowed. In some embodiments, the option <b>429</b> for setting the duration of validity for authentication of the secondary device may be provided via the trusted device, either in addition to or instead of via the user interface <b>400</b>. The automatic sign-in area <b>425</b><i>b </i>further includes a &#x201c;click when ready&#x201d; button <b>430</b> that allows a user to notify a server (such as the authentication server <b>130</b> or the online resource provider <b>150</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) that the displayed code <b>405</b> has been scanned by the trusted device and has been sent to the server. For example, in response to clicking the button <b>430</b>, a notification may be sent to a online resource provider (such as the online resource provider <b>150</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>), which may prompt the online resource provider to verify with the authentication server that the security token included in the displayed code <b>405</b> has been authenticated. In other embodiments, however, the user interface <b>400</b> may not include the button <b>430</b>, and the online resource provider may periodically (or at predetermined times) check with the authentication server to verify that the security token has been authenticated. As such, the user interface <b>400</b> may allow a user having a trusted device to access the WebShopping.com shopping service using the automatic sign-in area <b>425</b><i>b </i>only, without requiring entry of a username and password in fields <b>426</b> and <b>427</b>. However, in other embodiments, the user interface <b>400</b> may be configured for multi-factor authentication, for example, by requiring authentication using both the manual and automatic sign-in areas <b>425</b><i>a </i>and <b>425</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Although illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> with reference to two sign-in areas <b>425</b><i>a </i>and <b>425</b><i>b</i>, it will be understood that user interfaces in accordance with some embodiments may include additional or fewer sign-in areas. For example, in some embodiments, only the manual sign-in area <b>425</b><i>a </i>may be initially displayed, and a user may have to click an on-screen button to display the automatic sign-in area <b>425</b><i>b</i>, or vice versa. The user interface <b>400</b> may also be configured to remember the user's preferred sign-in method, and display only the manual sign-in area <b>425</b><i>a </i>or the automatic sign-in area <b>425</b><i>b </i>in accordance therewith. Also, in instances where the mobile device or the online content to be accessed are associated with a higher level of security, the user interface <b>400</b> may display one or more additional sign-in areas (with each requiring a different type of authentication) to provide multi-factor authentication. Furthermore, while illustrated as a QR code, it will be understood that the code <b>405</b> displayed in the automatic sign-in area <b>425</b><i>b </i>may be displayed as a different type of graphical code, such as a one-dimensional barcode, an alphanumeric sequence, or the like. Also, in some embodiments, the code <b>405</b> may not be displayed at all, but rather, may be an audible code or a code transmitted using short-range communication, such as Bluetooth or NFC. More generally, it will be understood that the user interface <b>400</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is provided for illustrative purposes only, and that user interfaces in accordance with embodiments described herein may include any and all variations that provide the functionality described herein.</p>
<p id="h-0008" num="0000">Mobile Device Application Operations</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a flowchart of operations for authenticating a customer of an account-based online resource using a trusted device in accordance with some embodiments. The operations of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> may be performed by the primary device <b>110</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> or the mobile device applications <b>215</b> or <b>315</b> when executed by a processor of the mobile devices <b>210</b> or <b>310</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> or <b>3</b>. Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, a mobile device is registered as a trusted device associated with customer account for an online resource at block <b>505</b>. For example, the mobile device may download a software application from an online application store, and may register or link the mobile device with one or more user accounts for online resources by following on-screen directions presented by the downloaded application.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">At block <b>510</b>, the mobile device is used to record a code presented by another electronic device (e.g., a secondary device) for accessing the online resource. For example, a user of the mobile device may launch the downloaded mobile application, and may scan a graphical code that is displayed by the other electronic device, for example, using a camera of the mobile device. In other embodiments, the code presented by the other electronic device may an audible code or a code transmitted using short-range communications (such as Bluetooth or near-field communication (NFC)), and may be recorded by the mobile device using a microphone or a short-range receiver. The other electronic device may be a desktop or laptop computer, a network-ready television, or a set-top box configured to link a television to a network, such as the Internet. The other electronic device may provide a larger display for accessing the online resource than the mobile device. As such, the other electronic device may be less portable than the mobile device, but may be easier to use when accessing the online resource than the mobile device, for example, due to the larger screen size.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">At block <b>515</b>, authentication data indicative of the code that was presented by the other electronic device is transmitted from the mobile device to an authentication server (such as the authentication server <b>130</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) in order to authenticate the other electronic device for access to the online resource. The authentication data may be generated by the mobile device based on the code that was recorded at block <b>510</b>. For example, a mobile device may derive a numerical sequence from the code displayed by the other electronic device, encrypt the numerical sequence using an encryption key assigned to the mobile device by the authentication server during the registration process at block <b>505</b>, and transmit the encrypted numerical sequence to the authentication server as the authentication data. The authentication data may thereby contain an indication that the code was locally recorded by the mobile electronic device, based on the encryption using the assigned key. The authentication server may therefore authenticate the other electronic device for access to the online resource without receiving a password from the other electronic device, as described in greater detail below.</p>
<p id="h-0009" num="0000">Authentication Server Operations</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flowchart of operations for authenticating a customer of an account-based online resource using a trusted device in accordance with some embodiments. The operations of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> may be performed by the authentication server <b>130</b>, <b>230</b>, or <b>330</b> described herein. Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, a code for accessing an online resource having an associated customer account is presented via a secondary device at block <b>605</b>. The code may be, for example, a graphical code, an audible code, or a code transmitted using Bluetooth or near field communication (NFC), and may represent a security token, such as a pseudo-random number (PRN) sequence. As such, the code may be presented via a display of the secondary device, a speaker of the secondary device, or a transmitter of the secondary device. The code may also indicate addressing information for an authentication server that is to perform the authentication of the secondary device, such as the authentication server <b>130</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The secondary device may be a desktop or laptop computer, a network-ready television, or a set top box configured to connect a television to a network, such as the Internet.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">At block <b>610</b>, data indicative of the code that was presented via the secondary device is received from a primary device, for example, at the authentication server specified by the code. The primary device may be a mobile terminal, such as a smart phone, a tablet, an electronic book reader, or other portable electronic device. The data received from the primary device may indicate that the code displayed by the secondary device was locally captured or otherwise recorded by the primary device. For example, the data received from the primary device may be an encrypted value generated from a numerical sequence indicated by the code presented by the secondary device. Based on the received authentication data, the primary device is identified as a trusted device associated with the customer account at block <b>615</b>, for example, based on a prior registration event stored in a customer account data store.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">At block <b>620</b>, the secondary device is authenticated for access to the online resource in response to identifying the primary device as the trusted device associated with the customer account. For example, in response to identifying the primary device as a trusted device based on the prior registration event, the security token presented in the graphical code may be marked as authenticated by an authentication server, such as the authentication server <b>130</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. An indication of the authentication of the code may be stored in a data store, such as the code store <b>145</b>. An online resource provider, such as the online resource provider <b>150</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, may subsequently verify with the authentication server or the appropriate data store that the security token has been authenticated, and may thereby automatically sign-in the secondary device to the online resource. As such, the secondary device may be authenticated to access the customer account associated with the online resource without receiving a username or password from the secondary device, based on the trust associated with the primary device.</p>
<p id="h-0010" num="0000">Detailed Server Operations</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a flowchart of further operations for authenticating a customer of an account-based online resource using a trusted device in accordance with some embodiments. In some embodiments, the operations of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> may be performed by the authentication server <b>130</b> and the online resource provider <b>150</b> described herein. Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, a mobile device (e.g., a primary device) is registered as a trusted device associated with a customer account for an online resource at block <b>705</b>. For example, a registration request including information identifying the customer account may be received from the mobile device (along with information authenticating the user of the mobile device for access to the account, such as a username and password), and the mobile device may be registered or otherwise linked with the customer account in response to the registration request. The registration information linking the mobile device to the customer account may be stored in a data store, such as the customer account store <b>135</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">At block <b>710</b>, an attempt to access the online resource by an electronic device different from the trusted device (e.g., a secondary device) is detected. For example, a message may be received from a web browser or native application executing on the other electronic device indicating that a user of the other electronic device wishes to access the online resource. In some embodiments, the message may be received as a request to access the online resource without entry of any customer identification information (such as a username and password). For example, a user of the other electronic device may click or otherwise select a &#x201c;sign-in without entry of a password&#x201d; button displayed via a user interface of the other electronic device, and the request may be transmitted in response to the user action.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In response to detecting the attempt to access the online resource, a graphical code including a security token therein is provided for display by the electronic device at block <b>715</b>. The graphical code may represent a unique identifier, and may be generated responsive to receiving the request to access the online resource without entry of customer identification information. The graphical code may be a one-dimensional or multi-dimensional machine-readable code representing a random alphanumeric character string in some embodiments. The graphical code may also include information identifying the authentication server that is to perform the authentication of the other electronic device. After the graphical code has been displayed by the other electronic device, authentication data is received from the mobile device at block <b>725</b>. The authentication data indicates that the graphical code displayed by be other electronic device was recorded or otherwise captured by the mobile device. For example, the authentication data may be an encrypted value generated from the code displayed by the other electronic device using an encryption key assigned to the mobile device during the registration at block <b>705</b>. The authentication data may thereby include information indicating that code was locally recorded by the mobile device, and may be received at the authentication server based on the information identifying the authentication server provided in the graphical code.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Based on the received authentication data and the registration data stored in the data store, it is determined whether the mobile device is a trusted device associated with the customer account at block <b>730</b>. For example, the authentication data may include information identifying the mobile device, and a lookup table stored in the data store may be accessed to identify the mobile device as a trusted device for the customer account. If the mobile device is not identified as a trusted device at block <b>730</b>, the other electronic device is denied access to the online resource at block <b>780</b>. In some embodiments, the other electronic device may re-prompt the user to enter a username and password at this time, e.g., so as to revert to traditional password-based authentication upon failure of the automatic trusted device-based authentication.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">However, if the mobile device is identified as a trusted device at block <b>730</b>, it is determined at block <b>740</b> whether any additional authentication factors are needed. In particular, depending on the level of security associated with the customer account to be accessed, more than one authenticating factor may be required. For example, the number of authentication factors required to access a user's bank account may be greater than that required to access a user's streaming music or movie accounts. Likewise, the number of required authenticating factors may depend on a level of trust associated with the mobile device. For example, a personal mobile phone may require more instances of authentication data to access a business or corporate account than a mobile phone issued by the business or corporation. If it is determined at block <b>740</b> that additional authentication factors are needed, a prompt for additional authentication data is provided via a display of the mobile device or a display of the other electronic device at block <b>745</b>. If it is determined that the additional authentication data has not been received at block <b>750</b>, the mobile device is denied access to the online resource at block <b>780</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">If, however it is determined that no additional authentication factors are needed at block <b>740</b>, or if the additional authentication data is received at block <b>750</b>, the security token presented in the graphical code displayed by the other electronic device is marked as authenticated at block <b>755</b> in response to identifying the mobile device as a trusted device. Authentication of the security token is thereby detected at block <b>760</b>. For example, the authentication of the security token may be detected by the online resource provider (such as the online resource provider <b>150</b>) by periodically checking or otherwise verifying the status of the security token with the authentication server (such as the authentication server <b>130</b>). In response to detecting authentication of the security token at block <b>760</b>, the other electronic device is automatically signed-in the to the online resource without receiving a username or password associated with the customer account at block <b>765</b>. For example, the online resource provider may transmit a cookie including an authentication state to the web browser executing on the other electronic device to sign-in the device to the online resource.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">At block <b>770</b>, it is determined whether a duration of validity of the authentication of the other electronic device has expired. For example, an indication of a duration of time (for which access to the online resource is permitted) may be received from the mobile device (or from the other electronic device), and it may be determined whether the authentication has expired based on a timer. In addition or alternatively, a notification may be received from the mobile device revoking the access of the other electronic device to the online resource. Should either event occur, the other electronic device is denied access to the online resource at block <b>780</b>. As such, the trusted, primary mobile device may retain some control of access to the customer account by the other, secondary device even after access to the account has been granted.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Accordingly, embodiments described herein provide methods, systems, devices, and computer program products that allow a secondary device to access a customer account responsive to receiving authenticating information from a primary, trusted device that is already associated with the customer account, without requiring customer identification information from the secondary device. Thus, these embodiments can reduce or eliminate problems that may be associated with password-based authentication, from both a convenience and a security standpoint.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Various embodiments have been described fully herein with reference to the accompanying figures, in which various embodiments are shown. This disclosure may, however, be embodied in many alternate forms and should not be construed as limited to the embodiments set forth herein.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Accordingly, while the disclosure is susceptible to various modifications and alternative forms, specific embodiments thereof are shown by way of example in the drawings and were described in detail herein. It should be understood, however, that there is no intent to limit the disclosure to the particular forms disclosed, but on the contrary, the disclosure is to cover all modifications, equivalents, and alternatives falling within the spirit and scope of the disclosure as defined by the claims. Like numbers refer to like elements throughout the description of the figures.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The terminology used herein is for the purpose of describing particular embodiments only and is not intended to be limiting of the disclosure. As used herein, the singular forms &#x201c;a&#x201d;, &#x201c;an&#x201d; and &#x201c;the&#x201d; are intended to include the plural forms as well, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise. It will be further understood that the terms &#x201c;comprises,&#x201d; &#x201c;comprising,&#x201d; &#x201c;includes,&#x201d; &#x201c;including,&#x201d; &#x201c;have,&#x201d; &#x201c;having&#x201d; or variants thereof when used herein, specify the presence of stated features, integers, steps, operations, elements, and/or components, but do not preclude the presence or addition of one or more other features, integers, steps, operations, elements, components, and/or groups thereof. Moreover, when an element/step is referred to as being &#x201c;responsive&#x201d; to another element/step (and variants thereof), it can be directly responsive to the other element/step, or intervening elements/steps may be present. In contrast, when an element/step is referred to as being &#x201c;directly responsive&#x201d; to another element/step (and variants thereof), there are no intervening elements/steps present.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">It will be understood that, although the terms first, second, etc. may be used herein to describe various elements, these elements should not be limited by these terms. These terms are only used to distinguish one element from another. For example, a first element could be termed a second element, and, similarly, a second element could be termed a first element without departing from the teachings of the disclosure. Moreover, although some of the diagrams include arrows on communication paths to show a primary direction of communication, it is to be understood that communication may occur in the opposite direction to the depicted arrows.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Various embodiments are described herein with reference to block diagrams and/or flowchart illustrations of computer-implemented methods, apparatus (systems and/or devices) and/or computer program products. It is understood that a block of the block diagrams and/or flowchart illustrations, and combinations of blocks in the block diagrams and/or flowchart illustrations, can be implemented by computer program instructions that are performed by one or more computer circuits. These computer program instructions may be provided to a processor circuit of a general purpose computer circuit, special purpose computer circuit, and/or other programmable data processing circuit to produce a machine, such that the instructions, which execute via the processor of the computer and/or other programmable data processing apparatus, transform and control transistors, values stored in memory locations, and other hardware components within such circuitry to implement the functions/acts specified in the block diagrams and/or flowchart block or blocks, and thereby create means (functionality) and/or structure for implementing the functions/acts specified in the block diagrams and/or flowchart block(s)</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">These computer program instructions may also be stored in a computer-readable medium that can direct a computer or other programmable data processing apparatus to function in a particular manner, such that the instructions stored in the computer-readable medium produce an article of manufacture including instructions which implement the functions/acts specified in the block diagrams and/or flowchart block or blocks.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">A tangible, non-transitory computer-readable medium may include an electronic, magnetic, optical, electromagnetic, or semiconductor data storage system, apparatus, or device. More specific examples of the computer-readable medium would include the following: a portable computer diskette, a random access memory (RAM) circuit, a read-only memory (ROM) circuit, an erasable programmable read-only memory (EPROM or Flash memory) circuit, a portable compact disc read-only memory (CD-ROM), and a portable digital video disc read-only memory (DVD/Blu-Ray).</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The computer program instructions may also be loaded onto a computer and/or other programmable data processing apparatus to cause a series of operational steps to be performed on the computer and/or other programmable apparatus to produce a computer-implemented process such that the instructions which execute on the computer or other programmable apparatus provide steps for implementing the functions/acts specified in the block diagrams and/or flowchart block or blocks.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Accordingly, the present disclosure may be embodied in hardware and/or in software (including firmware, resident software, micro-code, etc.) that runs on a processor such as a digital signal processor, which may collectively be referred to as &#x201c;circuitry,&#x201d; &#x201c;a module,&#x201d; &#x201c;an engine,&#x201d; or variants thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">It should also be noted that in some alternate implementations, the functions/acts noted in the blocks may occur out of the order noted in the flowcharts. For example, two blocks shown in succession may in fact be executed substantially concurrently or the blocks may sometimes be executed in the reverse order, depending upon the functionality/acts involved. Moreover, the functionality of a given block of the flowcharts and/or block diagrams may be separated into multiple blocks and/or the functionality of two or more blocks of the flowcharts and/or block diagrams may be at least partially integrated. Finally, other blocks may be added/inserted between the blocks that are illustrated.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Unless otherwise defined, all terms used herein have the same meaning as commonly understood by one of ordinary skill in the art to which this invention belongs. As used herein, the terms &#x201c;present&#x201d; or &#x201c;provide&#x201d; may refer to operations for transmitting data from one device to another, or to operations for displaying the data on an electronic device for viewing by a user. As used herein, a &#x201c;wireless communication terminal&#x201d; includes, but is not limited to, a device that is configured to receive/transmit communication signals via a wireless interface with, for example, a cellular network, a wireless local area network (WLAN), a satellite network, and/or another communication terminal. A wireless communication terminal may also be referred to as a &#x201c;mobile terminal.&#x201d; Examples of wireless communication devices include, but are not limited to, a satellite or cellular radiotelephone or &#x201c;smartphone&#x201d; that can include a radiotelephone, Internet/intranet access, Web browser, and/or a global positioning system (GPS) receiver; and a conventional laptop and/or palmtop computer or other appliance that includes a radio transceiver.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">Many different embodiments have been disclosed herein, in connection with the above description and the drawings. It will be understood that it would be unduly repetitious and obfuscating to literally describe and illustrate every combination and subcombination of these embodiments. Accordingly, the present specification, including the drawings, shall be construed to constitute a complete written description of all combinations and subcombinations of the embodiments described herein, and of the manner and process of making and using them, and shall support claims to any such combination or subcombination.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">In the drawings and specification, there have been disclosed embodiments of the disclosure and, although specific terms are employed, they are used in a generic and descriptive sense only and not for purposes of limitation, the scope of the disclosure being set forth in the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>That which is claimed:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A computer-implemented method of authenticating a customer using a trusted device, the method comprising: registering a mobile device as a trusted device associated with a customer account for an online resource; detecting an attempt to access the online resource by an electronic device different from the trusted device; providing a graphical code for display by the electronic device responsive to detecting the attempt, the graphical code including a security token therein; receiving authentication data from the mobile device, the authentication data indicating that the graphical code was captured by the mobile device; identifying the mobile device as the trusted device associated with the customer account responsive to receiving the authentication data from the mobile device and based on the registering the mobile device as a trusted device; marking the security token included in the graphical code as authenticated responsive to identifying the mobile device as the trusted device associated with the customer account; detecting authentication of the security token displayed by the electronic device; and automatically signing-in the electronic device to the customer account for the online resource responsive to detecting the authentication of the security token and without receiving a username or password associated with the customer account therefrom, wherein at least one of the registering, detecting the attempt to access, providing, receiving, identifying, marking, detecting the authentication, and automatically signing-in is performed using at least one hardware processor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein detecting authentication of the security token comprises:
<claim-text>querying a data store to verify that the security token has been authenticated,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the querying is performed repeatedly or in response to receiving a notification indicating that the trusted device has transmitted the authenticating data.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the electronic device includes a web browser executing thereon, and wherein automatically signing-in the electronic device to the customer account for the online resource comprises:
<claim-text>transmitting a cookie including a session identifier to the web browser responsive to detecting the authentication of the security token displayed by the electronic device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the electronic device is connected to a television and includes a native application executing thereon, and wherein automatically signing-in the electronic device to the customer account for the online resource comprises:
<claim-text>linking the native application executing on the electronic device to the customer account responsive to detecting the authentication of the security token displayed by the electronic device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A computer-implemented method of authenticating a customer, the method comprising: presenting, via a secondary device, a code for accessing an online resource having a customer account associated therewith; receiving, from a primary device, authentication data indicative of the code that was presented via the secondary device, wherein the code is captured by the primary device from a display of the secondary device; identifying the primary device as a trusted device associated with the customer account responsive to receiving the authentication data from the Mobil device; and authenticating the secondary device for access to the online resource responsive to identifying the primary device as the trusted device associated with the customer account, wherein at least one of the presenting, receiving, identifying, and authenticating is performed using at least one hardware processor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein identifying the primary device comprises:
<claim-text>identifying the primary device as the trusted device based on a registration event associating the primary device with the customer account for the online resource,</claim-text>
<claim-text>and wherein authenticating the secondary device comprises:
<claim-text>providing an indication that the secondary device is permitted to access the online resource responsive to identifying the primary device as the trusted device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the code includes a security token therein, and wherein providing an indication that the secondary device is permitted to access the online resource comprises marking the security token in the code presented via the secondary device as authenticated.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the registration event occurs prior to or concurrently with receiving the authentication data from the primary device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the authentication data received from the primary device indicates that the code presented via the secondary device was locally captured and recorded by the primary device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>automatically logging-in the secondary device to the customer account associated with the online resource responsive to authenticating the secondary device and without receiving customer identification information therefrom.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein presenting the code comprises:
<claim-text>receiving a request to access the online resource without entry of customer identification information via the secondary device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting the code for presentation via the secondary device responsive to receiving the request.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the code comprises an identifier that is randomly generated responsive to receiving the request to access the online resource without entry of the customer identification information.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the code includes information identifying an authentication server that performs the authenticating, and wherein receiving the authentication data from the primary device comprises:
<claim-text>receiving the authentication data at the authentication server based on the information included in the code.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>receiving, from the primary device or the secondary device, an indication of a duration of time for which the access to the online resource via the secondary device will be valid; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>denying the secondary device access to the online resource upon expiration of the duration of time.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>receiving, from the primary device, a notification revoking the access of the secondary device to the online resource; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>denying the secondary device access to the online resource responsive to receiving the notification from the primary device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>providing a prompt for additional authentication data via the primary device or via the secondary device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the additional authentication data from the primary device or the secondary device responsive to providing the prompt,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein authenticating the secondary device for access to the online resource is performed responsive to receiving both the authentication data and the additional authentication data.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the primary device is associated with multiple customer accounts for different online resources having respective security levels associated therewith, and further comprising:
<claim-text>detecting an attempt to access one of the online resources by the secondary device,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the prompt for the additional authentication data is selectively provided based on the security level associated with the one of the online resources.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the primary device comprises one of a plurality of trusted devices associated with the customer account, wherein the primary device is associated with a lower level of trust than a tertiary device associated with the customer account, and wherein the prompt for the additional authentication data is not provided to the tertiary device to authenticate the secondary device for access to the online resource.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A server for authenticating a customer, the server comprising:
<claim-text>a code generator configured to provide a code for accessing an online resource having a customer account associated therewith;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transceiver configured to transmit the code for presentation by a secondary device responsive to detecting an attempt to access the online resource by the secondary device, and to receive authentication data from a primary device responsive to transmitting the code, wherein the authentication data indicates that the code presented by the secondary device was recorded by the primary device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an authentication module configured to access a customer account store to identify the primary device as a trusted device associated with the customer account responsive to receiving the authentication data from the primary device, and to authenticate the secondary device for access to the online resource responsive to identifying the primary device as the trusted device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The server of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the authentication module is configured to identify the primary device as the trusted device associated with the customer account based on a registration event stored in the customer account store, and wherein the authentication module is configured to provide an indication that the secondary device is permitted to access the online resource responsive to identification of the primary device as the trusted device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The server of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, wherein the code includes a security token therein, and wherein the authentication module is configured to mark the security token as authenticated responsive to identifying the primary device as the trusted device and store an indicia thereof in a code store as the indication that the secondary device is permitted to access the online resource.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The server of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the authentication data received from the primary device indicates that the code presented via the secondary device was locally recorded by the primary device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. The server of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the code generator is configured to randomly generate the code responsive to receiving a request to access the online resource without entry of customer identification information via the secondary device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. The server of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the code includes addressing information for the server, and wherein the authentication module receives the authentication data from the primary device based on the addressing information included in the code.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text>25. The server of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the transceiver is configured to receive, from the primary device or the secondary device, an indication of a duration of time for which the access to the online resource via the secondary device will be valid, and wherein the authentication module is configured to deny the secondary device access to the online resource upon expiration of the duration of time.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text>26. The server of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the transceiver is configured to receive, from the primary device, a notification revoking the access of the secondary device to the online resource, and wherein the authentication module is configured to deny the secondary device access to the online resource responsive to receiving the notification from the primary device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text>27. The server of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the authentication module is configured to provide a prompt for additional authentication data via the primary device or via the secondary device, wherein the transceiver is configured to receive the additional authentication data from the primary device or the secondary device responsive to providing the prompt, and wherein the authentication module is configured to authenticate the secondary device for access to the online resource responsive to receiving both the authentication data and the additional authentication data.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text>28. The server of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00027">claim 27</claim-ref>, wherein the authentication module is configured to selectively provide the prompt for additional authentication data based on a level of security associated with the online resource or based on a level of trust associated with the primary device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029" num="00029">
<claim-text>29. A computer program product for authenticating a customer, the computer program product comprising a non-transitory computer-readable storage medium having computer-readable program code therein that, when executed by a processor, is configured to:
<claim-text>register a mobile device including the processor therein as a trusted device associated with a customer account for an online resource;</claim-text>
<claim-text>record a code for accessing the online resource, wherein the code is presented by an electronic device different than the mobile device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmit authentication data indicative of the code that was presented by the electronic device to an authentication server, the authentication data indicating that the code was recorded by the trusted device to authenticate the electronic device for access to the online resource.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030" num="00030">
<claim-text>30. The computer program product of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00029">claim 29</claim-ref>, wherein the code is recorded using a camera of the mobile device, and wherein the computer-readable program code is further configured to:
<claim-text>derive, from the code recorded by the trusted device, addressing information for the authentication server and a security value provided therein;</claim-text>
<claim-text>encrypt the security value using a predetermined encryption algorithm assigned to the mobile device responsive to registering thereof; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmit the authentication data including the encrypted security value to the authentication server using the addressing information.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031" num="00031">
<claim-text>31. The computer program product of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00029">claim 29</claim-ref>, wherein the computer-readable program code is further configured to:
<claim-text>provide a prompt for entry of a duration of time for which the access to the online resource via the electronic device will be valid; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmit an indication of the duration of time to the authentication server.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032" num="00032">
<claim-text>32. The computer program product of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00029">claim 29</claim-ref>, wherein the computer-readable program code is further configured to:
<claim-text>receive a request for additional authentication data based on a level of trust associated with the mobile device or a level of security associated with the online resource;</claim-text>
<claim-text>provide a prompt for the additional authentication data responsive to the request;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receive the additional authentication data via a user interface responsive to the prompt; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmit the additional authentication data to the authentication server, wherein both the authentication data indicative of the code and the additional authentication data are used to authenticate the electronic device for access to the online resource. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
