<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623754-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623754</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13560280</doc-number>
<date>20120727</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>21</main-group>
<subgroup>44</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438613</main-classification>
<further-classification>257737</further-classification>
<further-classification>257E23021</further-classification>
<further-classification>257E23069</further-classification>
<further-classification>257E21509</further-classification>
<further-classification>257673</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Repairing anomalous stiff pillar bumps</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5929521</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Wark et al.</name>
<date>19990700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257737</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8198131</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Weng et al.</name>
<date>20120600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438107</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0141889</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Chen et al.</name>
<date>20030700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>324765</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>24</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-exemplary-claim>14</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-exemplary-claim>20</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-exemplary-claim>23</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257737</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257673</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E21021</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E23069</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E21509</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438613</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>15</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>35</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ryan</last-name>
<first-name>Vivian W.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Berne</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Geisler</last-name>
<first-name>Holm</first-name>
<address>
<city>Dresden</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Breuer</last-name>
<first-name>Dirk</first-name>
<address>
<city>Dresden</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ryan</last-name>
<first-name>Vivian W.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Berne</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Geisler</last-name>
<first-name>Holm</first-name>
<address>
<city>Dresden</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Breuer</last-name>
<first-name>Dirk</first-name>
<address>
<city>Dresden</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Williams, Morgan &#x26; Amerson, P.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>GLOBALFOUNDRIES Inc.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Grand Cayman</city>
<country>KY</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Karimy</last-name>
<first-name>Timor</first-name>
<department>2894</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Generally, the subject matter disclosed herein relates to repairing anomalous stiff pillar bumps that may be detected above a metallization system of a semiconductor chip or wafer. One illustrative method disclosed herein includes, among other things, forming a pillar bump above a metallization system of a semiconductor chip, and forming a plurality of notches in the pillar bump, wherein the plurality of notches are adapted to adjust a flexibility of the pillar bump when the pillar bump is exposed to a lateral force.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="109.47mm" wi="302.34mm" file="US08623754-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="181.78mm" wi="175.94mm" file="US08623754-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="270.43mm" wi="188.89mm" file="US08623754-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="246.72mm" wi="180.26mm" file="US08623754-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="260.43mm" wi="177.97mm" file="US08623754-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="254.42mm" wi="171.96mm" file="US08623754-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="251.46mm" wi="160.02mm" file="US08623754-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="255.10mm" wi="168.99mm" file="US08623754-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="235.97mm" wi="170.86mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623754-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="243.50mm" wi="178.99mm" file="US08623754-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="241.72mm" wi="158.16mm" file="US08623754-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="234.10mm" wi="178.82mm" file="US08623754-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="242.06mm" wi="172.97mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623754-20140107-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="235.71mm" wi="173.48mm" file="US08623754-20140107-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00014" num="00014">
<img id="EMI-D00014" he="229.79mm" wi="176.78mm" file="US08623754-20140107-D00014.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00015" num="00015">
<img id="EMI-D00015" he="157.14mm" wi="182.54mm" file="US08623754-20140107-D00015.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Disclosure</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Generally, the present disclosure relates to sophisticated semiconductor devices, and, more particularly, to methods and systems for testing and evaluating the metallization layers of a back-end-of-line (BEOL) metallization system and the pillar bumps that may be formed thereabove.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In modern ultra-high density integrated circuits, device features have been steadily decreasing in size to enhance the performance of the semiconductor device and the overall functionality of the circuit. In addition to an increase in the speed of operation due to reduced signal propagation times, reduced feature sizes allow an increase in the number of functional elements in the circuit in order to extend its functionality. Moreover, even as overall device sizes have dramatically decreased, the manufacturers of advanced semiconductor devices remain under constant pressure to reduce both costs and manufacturing times so as to remain economically competitive.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In the manufacture of many sophisticated integrated circuits, it is usually necessary to provide electrical connections between the various semiconductor chips making up a microelectronic device. Depending on the type of chip and the overall device design requirements, these electrical connections may be accomplished in a variety of ways, such as, for example, by wirebonding, tape automated bonding (TAB), flip-chip bonding, and the like. In recent years, the use of flip-chip technology, wherein semiconductor chips are attached to carrier substrates, or to other chips, by means of solder balls formed from so-called solder bumps, has become an important aspect of the semiconductor processing industry.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In flip-chip technology, solder balls are formed on a contact layer of at least one of the chips that is to be connected, such as, for example, on a dielectric passivation layer formed above the last metallization layer of a semiconductor chip that includes a plurality of integrated circuits. Similarly, adequately sized and appropriately located bond pads are formed on another chip, such as, for example, a carrier package substrate, such that each bond pad corresponds to a respective solder ball formed on the semiconductor chip. The two units, i.e., the semiconductor chip and carrier substrate, are then electrically connected by &#x201c;flipping&#x201d; the semiconductor chip, bringing the solder balls into physical contact with the bond pads, and performing a so-called Controlled Collapse Chip Connection (C4) solder bump &#x201c;reflow&#x201d; process at high-temperature, so that each solder ball on the semiconductor chip melts and bonds to a corresponding bond pad on the carrier substrate. Typically, hundreds of solder bumps may be distributed over the entire chip area, thereby providing, for example, the I/O capability required for modern semiconductor chips that usually include complex circuitry, such as microprocessors, storage circuits, three-dimensional (3D) chips, and the like, and/or a plurality of integrated circuits forming a complete complex circuit system.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">As semiconductor devices have gradually been reduced in size over successive design technology node generations, pillar bumps made up of more highly conductive materials, such as copper, gold, silver and/or alloys thereof, have replaced solder bumps in at least some flip-chip and 3D chip applications. Pillar bumps offer several advantages over more traditional solder bump connections, including higher interconnect densities, improved electrical and thermal performance, a greater standoff between the chip and the substrate, easier underfilling after the bonding operation, greater device reliability, and the like. During a typical high temperature C4 solder bump reflow process, solder bumps will generally collapse and spread out to some degree, thereby changing shape and size during the bonding process. Pillar bumps, on the other hand, which may only have relatively small solder caps for bonding to the corresponding bonding pads, substantially retain their shape and dimensional stability during the reflow process, due in most part to the higher melting temperatures of a typical pillar bump material, such as copper and the like, as compared to that of a typical solder material. This improvement in dimensional stability in turn permits the fabrication of pillar bumps based on much tighter bump pitches than would commonly be used for solder bumps, and an some cases much finer redistribution wiring patterns, thus leading to higher interconnect densities.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">As noted above, pillar bumps sometimes have a small solder cap, which may be used to bond the pillar bumps to respective bond pads on a corresponding carrier substrate during a high temperature reflow process. Typically, the carrier substrate material is an organic laminate, which has a coefficient of thermal expansion (CTE) that may be on the order of anywhere from 4-8 times greater than that of the semiconductor chip, which, in many cases, is made up primarily of silicon and silicon-based materials. Accordingly, due to the CTE mismatch between the semiconductor chip and the carrier substrate (i.e., silicon vs. organic laminate), the carrier substrate will grow more than the semiconductor chip when exposed to the reflow temperature, and as a consequence, thermal interaction stresses will be imposed on the chip/substrate package as the package cools and the solder caps solidify. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref><i>a</i>-<b>1</b><i>d</i>, which schematically illustrate at least some of the possible chip packaging thermal interaction effects that may occur during this process, will now be described.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>a </i>schematically illustrates a chip package <b>100</b>, which includes a carrier substrate <b>101</b> and a semiconductor chip <b>102</b>. The semiconductor chip <b>102</b> typically includes a plurality of pillar bumps <b>103</b>, which are formed above a metallization system <b>104</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>d</i>) of the chip <b>102</b>. In at least some cases, the pillar bumps <b>103</b> include solder caps <b>103</b>C, which generally facilitate the bonding operation between the pillar bumps <b>103</b> and corresponding bond pads (not shown) on the carrier substrate <b>101</b>. During the chip packaging assembly process, the semiconductor chip <b>102</b> is inverted, or &#x201c;flipped,&#x201d; and brought into contact the carrier substrate <b>101</b>, after which the chip package <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>a </i>is exposed to a reflow process <b>120</b> at a reflow temperature that exceeds the melting temperature of the material making up the solder caps <b>103</b>C. Depending on the specific solder alloy used to form the solder caps <b>103</b>C, the reflow temperature may be upwards of 200&#xb0;-265&#xb0; C. During the reflow process <b>120</b>, when the material of the solder caps <b>103</b>C is in a liquid phase, both the carrier substrate <b>101</b> and the semiconductor chip <b>102</b> are able to thermally &#x201c;grow&#x201d; in a substantially unrestrained manner, based on the coefficient of thermal expansion of each respective component. As such, both the carrier substrate <b>101</b> and the semiconductor chip <b>102</b> remain in an essentially flat, non-deformed condition, although each will grow by a different amount due to their different CTE's.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>b</i>, on the other hand, schematically illustrates the chip package <b>100</b> during a cool-down phase, when a thermal interaction begins to take place between the carrier substrate <b>101</b> and the semiconductor chip <b>102</b>. As the chip package <b>100</b> cools, the solder caps <b>103</b>C solidify and mechanically join the pillar bumps <b>103</b> on the semiconductor chip <b>102</b> to the bond pads on the carrier package substrate <b>101</b>. As the chip package <b>100</b> continues to cool after solder cap <b>103</b>C solidification, the CTE mismatch between the materials of the carrier substrate <b>101</b> and the semiconductor chip <b>102</b> cause the substrate <b>101</b> to shrink at a greater rate than the chip <b>102</b>. Typically, this difference in thermal expansion/contraction is accommodated by a combination of out-of-plane deformation of both the carrier substrate <b>101</b> and the semiconductor chip <b>102</b>, and some amount of shear deformation of the pillar bumps <b>103</b>. This out-of-plane deformation induces shear and bending forces <b>101</b>F, <b>101</b>M in the carrier substrate <b>101</b>, as well as shear and bending forces <b>102</b>F, <b>102</b>M in the semiconductor chip <b>102</b>. Other localized effects may occur in the semiconductor chip <b>102</b> in areas immediately surrounding the pillar bumps <b>103</b>, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>d </i>and described below.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>c </i>schematically illustrates a plan view of the semiconductor chip <b>102</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref><i>a</i>-<b>1</b><i>b</i>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>c</i>, the semiconductor chip <b>102</b> has a center <b>102</b>C located at the intersection of an first chip centerline <b>102</b>X and a second chip centerline <b>102</b>Y of the chip <b>102</b>. Additionally, a plurality of pillar bumps <b>103</b> may be distributed over the surface of the semiconductor chip <b>102</b>. It should be noted, however, that while the pillar bumps <b>103</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>c </i>are depicted as being randomly positioned, it should be appreciated that the relative positions of the pillar bumps <b>103</b> are illustrative only, as the bumps <b>103</b> may generally be distributed in a substantially uniform or homogeneous fashion, at least locally, over the surface of the semiconductor chip <b>102</b>. Furthermore, the schematically depicted shear force <b>102</b>F that may be induced in semiconductor chip <b>102</b> as a result of the thermal interaction between the chip <b>102</b> and the carrier substrate <b>101</b> (see, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>b</i>) will generally be oriented from the periphery <b>102</b>P of the semiconductor chip <b>102</b> toward, or in the general direction of, the center <b>102</b>C, as indicated by the arrows shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>c. </i></p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>d </i>schematically illustrates an area of the semiconductor chip <b>102</b> surrounding an individual pillar bump <b>103</b>A after cool-down of the chip package <b>100</b>. For simplicity, the semiconductor chip <b>102</b> has been inverted relative to the chip packaging configurations illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref><i>a</i>-<b>1</b><i>b</i>, and the carrier substrate <b>101</b> is not shown. Furthermore, only the uppermost metallization layers <b>104</b>A, <b>104</b>B and <b>104</b>C of a metallization system <b>104</b> of the semiconductor chip <b>102</b> are shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>d</i>, and any metallization layers below layer <b>104</b>C, device layers, or substrate layers of the chip <b>102</b> have not been depicted. The semiconductor chip <b>102</b> may include a passivation layer <b>106</b> formed above the last metallization layer <b>104</b>A, an underbump metallization (UBM) layer <b>105</b>U formed in and above an opening in the passivation layer <b>106</b>, and a pillar bump <b>103</b>A formed above the UBM layer <b>105</b>U. In some cases, the pillar bump <b>103</b>A may facilitate the creation of an electrical connection between the carrier substrate <b>101</b> (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>d</i>) and one or more semiconductor devices (not shown) formed in the device level (not shown) of the semiconductor chip <b>102</b>. However, in other cases, the pillar bump <b>103</b>A may be a &#x201c;dummy bump&#x201d; that does not provide an electrical connection to chip circuitry (not shown), but wherein the &#x201c;dummy bump&#x201d; is included so as to provide the substantially uniform or homogeneous bump distribution previously noted.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">When the pillar bump <b>103</b>A is intended to provide an electrical connection to chip circuitry (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>d</i>), the UBM layer <b>105</b>U and the pillar bump <b>103</b>A may be formed above a bond pad <b>105</b>, which may be used to facilitate an electrical connection to an underlying contact structure <b>107</b>. Both the bond pad <b>105</b> and the contact structure <b>107</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>d </i>are outlined with dotted lines, indicating that these elements may or may not be present below the pillar bump <b>103</b>A. As noted previously, the bond pad <b>105</b> (when present) may be in contact with the contact structure <b>107</b> so as to facilitate the electrical connection of the pillar bump <b>103</b>A to an integrated circuit (not shown) formed in the device level (not shown) below the metallization system <b>104</b>. For illustrative purposes only, the contact structure <b>107</b> (when present) may include, for example, a contact via <b>107</b>B formed in the metallization layer <b>104</b>B, a conductive line <b>107</b>C and a contact via <b>107</b>D in the metallization layer <b>104</b>C, and the like, whereas other configurations may also be used.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">As noted above, during the cool-down phase, the out-of-plane deformation of the chip package <b>100</b> that is caused by the thermal interaction of the semiconductor chip <b>102</b> and the carrier substrate <b>101</b> will typically induce shear and bending forces <b>102</b>F, <b>102</b>M in the chip <b>102</b>. These shear and bending forces <b>102</b>F, <b>102</b>M will result in localized loads acting on each pillar bump <b>103</b>, such as a shear load <b>103</b>S, a tensile or uplift load <b>103</b>T and bending moment <b>103</b>M across the pillar bump <b>103</b>A. However, since the material of the pillar bump <b>103</b> is, in general, very robust, and typically has a stiffness that exceeds that of at least some of the materials that make up the semiconductor chip <b>102</b>&#x2014;and in particular, the dielectric materials included in the metallization system <b>104</b>&#x2014;relatively little deformation energy will be absorbed by plastic deformation of the pillar bump <b>103</b>A during the chip packaging thermal interaction. Instead, the majority of the loads <b>103</b>S, <b>103</b>T and <b>103</b>M will be translated through the pillar bump <b>103</b>A and into the metallization layers, such as layers <b>104</b>A-<b>104</b>C, underlying the pillar bump <b>103</b>A. These translated loads will generally have the highest magnitude in an area of the metallization system <b>104</b> that is below the edges <b>113</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>d </i>as a dotted line) of the pillar bump <b>103</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Under the conditions outlined above, highly localized stresses may develop in one or more of the metallization layers of the metallization system <b>104</b>, such as a tensile stress <b>108</b>T on one side of the pillar bump <b>103</b>A and a compressive stress <b>108</b>C on the opposite side of the pillar bump <b>103</b>A. Furthermore, if the stresses <b>108</b>T and/or <b>108</b>C are of a high enough magnitude, a local failure of one or more of the metallization layers may occur below the pillar bump <b>103</b>A. Typically, a failure of a given metallization layer having a substantially homogeneous material system will manifest as a delamination or a crack <b>109</b>, and will normally occur where the loads are highest&#x2014;i.e., near the edges <b>113</b> of the pillar bump <b>103</b>A, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>d</i>. In other cases, such as those utilizing a substantially inhomogeneous material system having locally varying fracture energies, the crack <b>109</b> may only occur in a single metallization layer, such as the layer <b>104</b>C shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>d</i>, whereas in other cases, and depending on many factors, the crack <b>109</b> may propagate either deeper or shallower into the underlying metallization system <b>104</b>, e.g., spreading from one metallization layer to another.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Delamination failures and cracks, such as the crack <b>108</b>, that may occur in a metallization layer below a pillar bump, such as the pillar bump <b>103</b>A shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>d</i>, are sometimes subject to premature failure, as the crack <b>108</b> may prevent the pillar bump <b>103</b>A from making a good electrical connection to the contact structure <b>107</b> therebelow. However, since the delamination/crack defects described above do not occur until the chip packaging assembly stage of semiconductor chip manufacture, the defects will generally not be detectable until a final quality inspection is performed. In some cases, after the flip-chip operation has been completed, the chip package <b>100</b> may be subjected to acoustic testing, such as C-mode acoustic microscopy (CSAM). Cracks <b>109</b> that may be present in the metallization system <b>104</b> of the semiconductor chip <b>102</b> below the pillar bumps <b>103</b> will have a characteristic appearance during the CSAM inspection process that is recognizably different from that of pillar bumps <b>103</b> that do not have such cracks <b>109</b> therebelow. Such pillar bumps are sometimes referred to as &#x201c;white bumps,&#x201d; &#x201c;white spots,&#x201d; or &#x201c;ghost bumps,&#x201d; since this is how the difference in the acoustic signal in the CSAM images was first visualized. White bump defects may impose a costly downside to the overall chip manufacturing process, as they do not occur, and hence cannot be detected, until a significant material and manufacturing investment in the chip has already occurred. Furthermore, in those instances where the assembled chip package <b>100</b> is not subjected to CSAM inspection, undetected white bump defects may lead to reduced overall device reliability.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Additionally, the development and use of dielectric materials having a dielectric constant (or k-value) of approximately 3.5 or lower&#x2014;which are often referred to as &#x201c;low-k dielectric materials&#x201d;&#x2014;has led to an increased incidence of white bumps. Typically, low-k dielectric materials have lower mechanical strength, mechanical modulus, and adhesion strength than do some of the more commonly used dielectric materials having higher k-values, such as silicon dioxide, silicon nitride, silicon oxynitride, and the like. As metallization systems utilize more, and sometimes thicker, metallization layers that are made up of low-k dielectric materials, there is a greater likelihood that the lower strength low-k materials will rupture when exposed to the loads that are imposed on the metallization layers underlying the pillar bumps, thus leading to delaminations and cracks&#x2014;i.e., white bump defects. In particular, cracks tend to occur, or at least initiate, in the low-k metallization layers that are closest to the upper surface of the a semiconductor chip&#x2014;i.e., closest to the last metallization layer&#x2014;as the deformation energy is typically greatest near the upper surface, while in many cases decreasing in lower metallization levels. Furthermore, it appears that the type of white bump problems described above may sometimes even be further exacerbated in metallization layers comprised of ultra-low-k (ULK) materials having k-values of approximately 2.7 or lower, which in some cases may have even lower-strength mechanical properties than that of some low-k materials.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In some prior art semiconductor chips, the detrimental effects associated with white bump defects can sometimes be minimized by reducing the number of critical and/or sensitive circuit elements that are positioned in those areas of a metallization system that are below and/or adjacent to pillar bumps that are formed in those regions of a chip where white bumps are more likely to occur. For example, the size of a body&#x2014;i.e., its length or width&#x2014;is one factor that may have a significant influence on the total amount of thermal expansion that body undergoes when exposed to an elevated temperature. As such, the points of greatest thermal interaction&#x2014;and commensurately highest out-of-plane loads&#x2014;may occur in those areas of the semiconductor chip which are farthest from a neutral center, or centerline, of the chip, such as the periphery of the chip, such as the periphery <b>102</b>P and in particular, those areas near the corners <b>102</b>E of the chip (see, e.g., <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>c</i>). Accordingly, during the design and layout of a given semiconductor chip, it is sometimes feasible to position critical circuit elements and to route at least some conductive elements away from those areas of the chip that are typically exposed to greatest amount of differential thermal expansion between the semiconductor chip and the carrier substrate, e.g., near the edges and corners of the chip.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">However, simply adjusting the layout of the various circuit elements as described above does not always address all of the problems that may often be related to white bumps, which can sometimes occur in regions of a semiconductor chip that would not normally be associated with the highest thermal interaction and out-of-plane loads. For example, in some cases, a certain area of a particular low-k or ULK material layer of a given back-end-of-line (BEOL) metallization system may display mechanical properties that are uncharacteristically lower than may normally be expected of that specific material. Such lower mechanical properties may be due to any one of several different factors, including variation and/or drifting in the material deposition parameters, cleanliness, contamination, and/or microscratching issues associated with a given tool or wafer, and the like. Furthermore, such adjusted layout configurations often tend to give up valuable chip real estate, which can sometimes limit the type of applications for which the resulting chips may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Accordingly, and in view of the foregoing, there is a need to implement new strategies to address the design and manufacturing issues associated with the detrimental effects that white bump occurrences can often have on a semiconductor chip during the typical chip packaging operations. The present disclosure relates to various testing methods and mitigation strategies that are directed to avoiding, or at least minimizing, the effects of one or more of the problems identified above.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The following presents a simplified summary of the present disclosure in order to provide a basic understanding of some aspects disclosed herein. This summary is not an exhaustive overview of the disclosure, nor is it intended to identify key or critical elements of the subject matter disclosed here. Its sole purpose is to present some concepts in a simplified form as a prelude to the more detailed description that is discussed later.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Generally, the subject matter disclosed herein relates to repairing anomalous stiff pillar bumps that may be detected above a metallization system of a semiconductor chip or wafer. One illustrative method disclosed herein includes, among other things, forming a pillar bump above a metallization system of a semiconductor chip, and forming a plurality of notches in the pillar bump, wherein the plurality of notches are adapted to adjust a flexibility of the pillar bump when the pillar bump is exposed to a lateral force.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Another illustrative embodiment of the present disclosure is a method that includes positioning a pillar bump support device in contact with a first side of a pillar bump formed above a metallization system of a semiconductor chip, positioning a pillar bump repair device adjacent to a second side of the pillar bump, and forming a first notch on the second side of the pillar bump with the pillar bump repair device, wherein forming the first notch includes imposing a force on the second side with the pillar bump repair device. The method further includes, among other things, supporting the pillar bump with the pillar bump support device while forming the first notch, wherein supporting the pillar bump includes resisting, with the pillar bump support device, the force being imposed on the second side of the pillar bump by actuation of said pillar bump repair device.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">A further illustrative embodiment of the present disclosure includes a device that is made up of, among other things, a plurality of pillar bumps formed above a metallization system of a semiconductor chip, and a plurality of first notches formed on a first side of at least one of the plurality of pillar bumps, wherein each of the plurality of first notches is positioned along the first side in a substantially vertical alignment.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Also included in the presently disclosed subject matter is a pillar bump support device having a pillar bump contact surface that is adapted to contact an outer surface of a pillar bump formed above a metallization system of a semiconductor chip, wherein the pillar bump support device is adapted to substantially support the pillar bump when a force is imposed on the pillar bump during a pillar bump repair process.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The disclosure may be understood by reference to the following description taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, in which like reference numerals identify like elements, and in which:</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref><i>a</i>-<b>1</b><i>b </i>schematically illustrate a flip-chip packaging operation of a prior art semiconductor chip and a carrier substrate;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> <i>c </i>schematically illustrates a plan view of the prior art semiconductor chip of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref><i>a</i>-<b>1</b><i>b; </i></p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> <i>d </i>schematically illustrates out-of-plane loading on a representative pillar bump and underlying metallization system of a prior art semiconductor chip after the flip-chip packaging operation of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref><i>a</i>-<b>1</b><i>b; </i></p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> schematically depicts an illustrative test configuration disclosed herein that may be used for lateral force testing of pillar bumps formed above a metallization system of a semiconductor chip or wafer;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> graphically illustrates comparative curves representing the behavioral interaction between pillar bumps and an underlying metallization system of a semiconductor chip or wafer when tested to crack failure using fast-speed and slow-speed lateral force tests and the illustrative test configuration of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> disclosed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref><i>a</i>-<b>4</b><i>b </i>are photomicrographs showing crack morphology of cracks in the metallization systems of representative semiconductor chips that occurred as a result of a flip-chip bonding operation;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref><i>c</i>-<b>4</b><i>d </i>are photomicrographs showing the crack morphology of cracks in the metallization systems of representative semiconductor chips that occurred as a result of a slow-speed bump test to crack failure using the illustrative testing configuration of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> disclosed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref><i>e</i>-<b>4</b><i>h </i>are photomicrographs showing the crack morphology of cracks in the metallization systems of representative semiconductor chips that occurred as a result of a fast-speed bump test to crack failure using the illustrative testing configuration of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> disclosed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> graphically illustrates comparative curves representing the behavioral interaction between anomalous stiff or typical compliant pillar bumps, and an underlying metallization system of a semiconductor chip or wafer when tested to crack failure using slow-speed lateral force tests and the illustrative test configuration of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> disclosed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6</figref><i>a </i>and <b>6</b><i>b </i>schematically depict test configurations according to some illustrative embodiments disclosed herein that may be used for testing and locating anomalous stiff pillar bumps formed above a metallization system of a semiconductor chip or wafer;</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7</figref><i>a</i>-<b>7</b><i>e </i>schematically show various views of an illustrative system and method that may be used to repair anomalous stiff pillar bumps in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> graphically depicts the comparative difference between a curve that represents the typical behavioral interaction of pillar bumps that are formed above a metallization system of a semiconductor chip or wafer, and a curve that represents the behavioral interaction of pillar bumps that are formed above anomalous weak sites in a metallization system when tested to crack failure using slow-speed lateral force tests and the illustrative test configuration of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> disclosed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9</figref><i>a </i>and <b>9</b><i>b </i>schematically depict test configurations according to some illustrative embodiments disclosed herein that may be used for testing pillar bumps formed above a metallization system of a semiconductor chip or wafer so as to locate anomalous weak sites in the underlying metallization system; and</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9</figref><i>c</i>-<b>9</b><i>l </i>schematically depicts various embodiments of illustrative test probe tips that may be used for testing pillar bumps in accordance with one or more of the testing configurations illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9</figref><i>a </i>and <b>9</b><i>b. </i></p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">While the subject matter disclosed herein is susceptible to various modifications and alternative forms, specific embodiments thereof have been shown by way of example in the drawings and are herein described in detail. It should be understood, however, that the description herein of specific embodiments is not intended to limit the invention to the particular forms disclosed, but on the contrary, the intention is to cover all modifications, equivalents, and alternatives falling within the spirit and scope of the invention as defined by the appended claims.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Various illustrative embodiments of the present subject matter are described below. In the interest of clarity, not all features of an actual implementation are described in this specification. It will of course be appreciated that in the development of any such actual embodiment, numerous implementation-specific decisions must be made to achieve the developers' specific goals, such as compliance with system-related and business-related constraints, which will vary from one implementation to another. Moreover, it will be appreciated that such a development effort might be complex and time-consuming, but would nevertheless be a routine undertaking for those of ordinary skill in the art having the benefit of this disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The present subject matter will now be described with reference to the attached figures. Various structures and devices are schematically depicted in the drawings for purposes of explanation only and so as to not obscure the present disclosure with details that are well known to those skilled in the art. Nevertheless, the attached drawings are included to describe and explain illustrative examples of the present disclosure. The words and phrases used herein should be understood and interpreted to have a meaning consistent with the understanding of those words and phrases by those skilled in the relevant art. No special definition of a term or phrase, i.e., a definition that is different from the ordinary and customary meaning as understood by those skilled in the art, is intended to be implied by consistent usage of the term or phrase herein. To the extent that a term or phrase is intended to have a special meaning, i.e., a meaning other than that understood by skilled artisans, such a special definition will be expressly set forth in the specification in a definitional manner that directly and unequivocally provides the special definition for the term or phrase.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In general, the subject matter of the present disclosure is directed to various methods and systems that may be employed to test and evaluate the metallization layers of a so-called back-end-of-line (BEOL) metallization system and the pillar bumps that may be formed thereabove. In certain embodiments disclosed herein, lateral force tests may be performed on each of a plurality of pillar bumps formed above a representative BEOL metallization system so as to simulate the type of out-of-plane loads that may be imposed on the pillar bumps as a result of chip packaging thermal interaction during a flip-chip assembly process. For example, each lateral force test may be performed until a failure occurs in the metallization layers underlying the tested pillar bump, e.g., until a crack is induced. In some embodiments, the crack may be representative of the type of crack failures that occur as a result of thermal interaction during chip packaging, such as the crack <b>109</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>d</i>. Furthermore, relevant testing data may be gathered during the lateral force tests, and thereafter evaluated so as to determine the behavioral interaction between the pillar bumps and the underlying metallization layers when exposed to loads such as those that may be generated during flip-chip assembly. From this, a statistical assessment may be performed so as to establish a typical behavioral interaction curve for a given pillar bump/metallization system configuration that may be indicative of how that configuration would normally be expected to react when exposed to out-of-plane loads.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In at least some embodiments of the present disclosure, a typical behavioral interaction curve for a given pillar bump/metallization system configuration may be used in a comparative fashion for a variety of evaluation purposes when testing additional products that may be formed based on similar configuration parameters. For example, in certain embodiments a behavioral interaction curve may be used to locate and characterize processing and/or material-related issues that may be associated with anomalous pillar bumps and/or the underlying metallization layers. In other embodiments, a typical behavioral interaction curve may be used to evaluate the overall robustness of a given chip design and layout, which may be influenced by parameters such as: number of metallization layers; dielectric material types, strengths and thicknesses; size, configuration and relative positioning of conductive elements; and/or size, configuration and positioning of pillar bumps relative to underlying features. In still other embodiments, a behavioral interaction curve may also be used as a quality assurance tool to evaluate tool performance and/or drift (i.e., changes in materials or deposition parameters) in the processes that may be used to form low-k dielectric materials, ultra-low k (ULK) dielectric materials, and/or pillar bumps. In yet further embodiments, a typical behavioral interaction curve may also be used to evaluate new materials for advanced device generations, such low-k and/or ULK dielectric materials, which may have substantially reduced mechanical strength, and therefore be more susceptible to thermal interaction induced crack-like failures.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">It should be understood that, unless otherwise specifically indicated, any relative positional or directional terms that may be used in the descriptions below&#x2014;such as &#x201c;upper,&#x201d; &#x201c;lower,&#x201d; &#x201c;on,&#x201d; &#x201c;adjacent to,&#x201d; &#x201c;above,&#x201d; &#x201c;below,&#x201d; &#x201c;over,&#x201d; &#x201c;under,&#x201d; &#x201c;top,&#x201d; &#x201c;bottom,&#x201d; &#x201c;vertical,&#x201d; &#x201c;horizontal,&#x201d; and the like&#x2014;should be construed in light of that term's normal and everyday meaning relative to the depiction of the components or elements in the referenced figures. For example, referring to the schematic cross-section of the semiconductor chip <b>102</b> depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>d</i>, it should be understood that the passivation layer <b>106</b> is formed &#x201c;above&#x201d; the last metallization layer <b>104</b>A, and the conductive bond pad <b>105</b> is positioned &#x201c;below&#x201d; or &#x201c;under&#x201d; the pillar bump <b>103</b>A. Similarly, it should also be noted that the passivation layer <b>106</b> may be positioned &#x201c;on&#x201d; the last metallization layer <b>104</b>A in those embodiments wherein no other layers or structures are interposed therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> schematically depicts one illustrative embodiment of a novel test configuration that may be used for testing the behavioral interaction between a representative pillar bump <b>203</b> and an underlying metallization system <b>204</b> of a wafer or semiconductor chip <b>202</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the pillar bump <b>203</b> may be formed above the metallization system <b>204</b>, which may include a plurality of metallization layers and conductive features, such as bond pads, contact vias and conductive lines, which for simplicity are not illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. See, e.g., <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>d</i>, described in additional detail above. In some embodiments, the pillar bump <b>203</b> may be made up of any one of a number of well-known and highly conductive metals, such as copper, gold, silver and the like, or alloys thereof. Furthermore, it should be appreciated that the pillar bump <b>203</b> may represent one of a plurality of pillar bumps that are each formed above and generally distributed over an upper surface of the semiconductor chip <b>202</b>, some of which may be tested so as to established a typical behavioral interaction curve, as will be described in further detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">As noted above, the metallization system <b>204</b> may include a plurality of various metallization layers (not shown), each of which may be made up of one or more respective dielectric materials, and include a plurality of conductive features (not shown), such as contract vias and/or conductive lines and the like, which may be positioned and arranged within each of the various metallization layers as may be required to define an overall circuit layout of the semiconductor chip <b>202</b>. Depending on the specific design of the semiconductor chip <b>202</b>, one or more of the respective metallization layers may include a low-k and/or ULK dielectric material.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In accordance with the presently disclosed subject matter, the behavioral interaction of the pillar bump <b>203</b> and the metallization system <b>204</b> may be tested and evaluated using a lateral force test. In certain illustrative embodiments, a test probe <b>220</b> may be moved at a constant speed along a path <b>221</b> that is substantially parallel to the plane <b>223</b> of the metallization system <b>204</b> so as to contact the pillar bump <b>203</b>. When the test probe <b>220</b> contacts the pillar bump <b>203</b>, an indentation or notch <b>224</b> may be formed in the pillar bump <b>203</b> as the test probe <b>220</b> continues to move at a constant speed and pushes on the pillar bump <b>203</b>. As a result of the constant speed movement of the test probe <b>220</b>, a force <b>220</b>F is imposed on the pillar bump <b>203</b>, which can be measured and recorded over the duration of the test. In some embodiments, the resulting force <b>220</b>F imposed on the pillar bump <b>203</b> by the test probe <b>220</b> may approximately represent the type of loading that is sometimes induced on a given pillar bump during the thermal interaction of flip-chip packaging. Furthermore, the force <b>220</b>F on the pillar bump <b>203</b> may in turn induce a shear load <b>220</b>S and an overturning moment <b>220</b>M at an interface <b>240</b> between the pillar bump <b>203</b> and the metallization system <b>204</b>, thereby resulting in localized tensile and compressive stresses <b>208</b>T and <b>208</b>C in the metallization system <b>204</b> in substantially the same manner as previously described above with respect to the pillar bump <b>103</b>A shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>d</i>, thereby approximating a stress field in the metallization system <b>204</b> that can result in white bump occurrences.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In some exemplary embodiments of the present disclosure, the lateral force test described above may be continued on the pillar bump <b>203</b> until a load and/or displacement induced failure occurs proximate to the pillar bump <b>203</b> in the underlying metallization system <b>204</b>&#x2014;e.g., until a crack occurs in one or more of the metallization layers (not shown) of the metallization system <b>204</b>, such as the crack <b>109</b> described and illustrated with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>d </i>above. Additionally, test data related to the resulting force <b>220</b>F and the total distance moved by the probe <b>220</b> throughout the duration of the lateral force test may be recorded, which may then be used to generate a behavioral interaction curve for the tested pillar bump <b>203</b> and metallization system <b>204</b>. Furthermore, additional lateral force tests may be performed on each of a plurality of other similarly configured pillar bumps, which may then be used to create a typical behavioral interaction curve for a given pillar bump and metallization system configuration, examples of which are illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> and described below.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> graphically depicts typical force/distance behavioral interaction curves that represent data obtained during lateral force testing of a plurality of pillar bumps formed above a metallization system of a semiconductor chip or wafer when tested to crack failure using the illustrative test configuration of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, as described above. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, both of the force/distance curves <b>301</b> and <b>302</b> essentially plot a distance <b>320</b>D that is traveled by a test probe (such as the test probe <b>220</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) against a force <b>320</b>F that is generated by the test probe on a representative typical pillar bump (such as the pillar bump <b>203</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) throughout the duration of a lateral force test. However, curve <b>301</b> represents test data that is obtained by moving the test probe at a constant speed during the lateral force tests that is different than the constant test probe speed used to generate curve <b>302</b>, as will be further described below.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">As may be known by those having ordinary skill in the art, a constant test probe speed that is greater than approximately 10 &#x3bc;m/sec (micrometers, or microns, per second) and ranging up to as high as about 10 &#x3bc;m/sec has been used in prior art test schemes to evaluate the behavior of at least some pillar bump/metallization system configurations. The force/distance curve <b>301</b> represents a typical behavioral interaction of a given pillar bump/metallization system that has been tested using such a known constant test probe speed, i.e., ranging from approximately 1-10 &#x3bc;m/sec. The force/distance curve <b>302</b>, on the other hand, represents a typical behavioral interaction of a pillar bump/metallization system having a substantially similar configuration as that used to generate the fast speed test curve <b>301</b>, wherein however the lateral force tests have been performed using a much slower constant probe speed. More specifically, the force/distance curve <b>302</b> may be based on a constant test probe speed that is less than the typical minimum prior art test probe speed of approximately 1 &#x3bc;m/sec, and in certain embodiments may even be less than approximately 0.1 &#x3bc;m/sec&#x2014;or about 10-100 times slower than the typical prior art lateral force test. For comparative purposes, a lateral force test that is performed in the range of approximately 1-10 &#x3bc;m/sec (e.g., the tests represented by curve <b>301</b>) is hereinafter referred to as a &#x201c;fast speed test,&#x201d; wherein a test that may be performed at less than approximately 0.1 &#x3bc;m/sec (e.g., the tests represented by curve <b>302</b>) is hereinafter referred to as a &#x201c;slow speed test.&#x201d; Accordingly, it should be appreciated that a slow speed test may be performed at a constant test probe speed that may be at least 1 to 2 orders of magnitude slower, i.e., at least 10 to 100 times slower, than that of a typical fast speed test.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The fast speed curve <b>301</b> can generally be characterized as having four distinct response regions: <b>301</b>A, <b>301</b>B, <b>301</b>C and <b>301</b>D. The first region <b>301</b>A of curve <b>301</b> illustrates the initial behavioral response of the pillar bump/metallization system immediately after the pillar bump has been contacted by the lateral force test probe. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the first region <b>301</b>A shows a substantially non-linear force/distance response, wherein the distance <b>320</b>D (horizontal axis of the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> graph) traveled by the test probe increases at a greater rate than the force <b>320</b>F (vertical axis of the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> graph) imposed on the pillar bump by the test probe, which may be the result of some degree of strain hardening of the pillar bump during the initial bump deformation.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The second region <b>301</b>B of curve <b>301</b> illustrates a substantially linear force/distance response, during which time the distance <b>320</b>D traveled by the test probe and the force <b>320</b>F imposed on the pillar bump both increase at a substantially constant rate. Thereafter, as illustrated by the third region <b>301</b>C, the force/distance response of the pillar bump/metallization system again displays a substantially non-linear characteristic, which may be indicative of an acceleration of the microcracking failure that is occurring in the low-k and/or ULK dielectric materials making up the metallization system. Accordingly, the distance <b>320</b>D traveled by the test probe once again increases at a greater rate than the force <b>320</b>F imposed on the pillar bump as both the force <b>320</b>F and the distance <b>320</b>D traveled both move toward creating an eventual macroscopic crack failure, indicated by point <b>331</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The fourth region <b>301</b>D of curve <b>301</b> illustrates the behavioral response of the pillar bump/metallization system to the fast speed test after crack failure at point <b>331</b> has occurred. The post-crack force/distance response illustrated by the fourth region <b>301</b>D may also be characterized as being substantially linear in nature, wherein the force <b>320</b>F on the pillar bump drops quickly as the crack widens and propagates through the metallization system. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the crack point <b>331</b> occurs after a force <b>320</b>F having a magnitude <b>321</b> has been imposed on the pillar bump, and the test probe has traveled a total distance <b>320</b>D of magnitude <b>311</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the force/distance curve <b>302</b>, which represents the behavioral interaction of the pillar bump/metallization system when exposed to the slow speed test disclosed herein, has a similar overall configuration as the fast speed curve <b>301</b>, and furthermore displays similarly characterized curve regions <b>302</b>A, <b>302</b>B, <b>302</b>C and <b>302</b>D. More specifically, the first region <b>302</b>A of curve <b>302</b> is substantially non-linear, indicating that the distance <b>320</b>D traveled by the test probe increases at a greater rate than the force <b>320</b>F imposed on the pillar bump. The second region <b>302</b>B shows a substantially linear force/distance response such that both the distance <b>320</b>D and force <b>320</b>F increase at relatively constant rates, whereas the third region <b>302</b>C is again non-linear, as is the case with the third region <b>301</b>C of the fast test curve <b>301</b>. After a crack has occurred (identified as point <b>332</b>), the post-crack fourth region <b>302</b>D of the slow speed curve <b>302</b> again displays a substantially linear characteristic, wherein the force <b>320</b>F on the pillar bump drops precipitously versus the distance <b>320</b>D traveled by the test probe as the crack widens as propagates through metallization system.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">It should be noted, however, that while the general configuration and characteristics of the various regions of the fast speed and slow speed test curves <b>301</b> and <b>302</b> have a substantially similar shape and appearance, test curve <b>302</b> indicates that a crack will occur at both a lower force <b>320</b>F and a shorter distance <b>320</b>D traveled during the slow speed lateral force tests (represented by curve <b>302</b>), as disclosed herein, when compared to the fast speed tests (represented by curve <b>301</b>). More specifically, a crack occurs during the slow speed tests of curve <b>302</b> (see, crack point <b>332</b>) after a force <b>320</b>F having a magnitude <b>322</b> has been imposed on the pillar bump. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the force <b>322</b> is less by an amount <b>323</b> than the force <b>321</b> necessary to create a crack during the fast speed tests of curve <b>301</b> (see, crack point <b>331</b>). In one example, the force <b>322</b> may be approximately 10-35% less than the force <b>321</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Similarly, the slow speed tests of curve <b>302</b> show that the total distance <b>320</b>D traveled by the test probe during prior to the initiation of a crack has a magnitude <b>312</b>, which is less by an amount <b>313</b> than the corresponding distance <b>311</b> needed to create a crack during the fast speed tests of curve <b>301</b>. In one example, the distance <b>312</b> may be about 5-30% less than the distance <b>311</b>. Accordingly, when used as a predictive and/or comparative tool for evaluating data associated with lateral force tests that may be performed on similar pillar bump/metallization system configurations, the fast speed test curve <b>301</b> would indicate that a given system configuration may generally be more robust, i.e., able to resist higher loads and/or greater lateral movement during chip packaging interaction, than would be indicated by the slow speed test curve <b>302</b>. However, at least some qualitative and quantitative evidence indicates that slow speed tests may be more a representative predictor of crack-related product failures in actual flip-chip packages, as will be discussed in further detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref><i>a</i>-<b>4</b><i>h </i>are scanning electron microscope (SEM) photographs of illustrative crack failures in BEOL metallization layers below the pillar bumps of various representative semiconductor chips. More specifically, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref><i>a </i>and <b>4</b><i>b </i>are SEM photographs of actual product cracks <b>409</b> that have occurred during a typical flip-chip bonding and assembly process. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref><i>a </i>and <b>4</b><i>b</i>, the cracks <b>409</b> display a substantially grainy or pebbly morphology, which is often typical of the appearance of the type of cracks that occur as a result of the thermal interaction between the semiconductor chip and a carrier package substrate, as previously described.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref><i>c</i>-<b>4</b><i>f </i>are SEM photographs of illustrative cracks <b>419</b> in the BEOL metallization layers below pillar bumps of representative semiconductor chips that have been created during fast speed lateral force tests, such as those represented by test curve <b>301</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> and described above. As can be seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref><i>c</i>-<b>4</b><i>f</i>, the cracks <b>419</b> created during fast speed lateral force tests display a substantially smooth crack morphology, which is significantly different from the pebbly crack morphology seen in the cracks <b>409</b> that have occurred in actual semiconductor chips during flip-chip assembly. This difference in crack morphology between the cracks <b>409</b> induced in actual failed products and the cracks <b>419</b> created during fast speed lateral force tests provides at least some evidence that the fast speed test cracks <b>419</b> may not accurately represent the real-world conditions that occur during the flip-chip bonding and assembly process that lead to the initiation and propagation of white bump cracks in actual products, such as the illustrative cracks <b>409</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref><i>a </i>and <b>4</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">On the other hand, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref><i>g </i>and <b>4</b><i>h </i>are SEM photographs showing cracks <b>429</b> that have been created in the BEOL metallization layers of representative semiconductor chips during a slow speed lateral force test disclosed herein, such as the tests represented by the curve <b>302</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref><i>g </i>and <b>4</b><i>h</i>, the cracks <b>429</b> display a substantially grainy or pebbly appearance&#x2014;i.e., a morphology that is substantially similar to the morphology of the bonding and assembly-related cracks <b>409</b> seen in actual real-world products, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref><i>a </i>and <b>4</b><i>b</i>. This similarity in crack morphology may indicate that slow speed lateral force tests disclosed herein more accurately represent the conditions that arise in actual semiconductor chips during the flip-chip process, as compared to the fast speed tests lateral force tests previously described, which may result in the substantially smoother crack morphology seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref><i>c</i>-<b>4</b><i>f</i>. Additionally, strain rate calculations that are performed on actual products during the reflow process in the regime where crack failures would typically be expected to initiate in the BEOL metallization layers indicate that the rate of strain during reflow is slower than that which occurs during a typical fast speed lateral force test, yet provides reasonably good correlation to the rate of strain that occurs during slow speed tests.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">As noted above, lateral force tests using a constant test probe speed in the range of approximately 1-10 &#x3bc;m/sec&#x2014;i.e., fast speed tests&#x2014;have generally been performed in prior art testing schemes when evaluating and characterizing the behavioral interaction of pillar bumps with their underlying metallization systems. Furthermore, as may be appreciated by a person of ordinary skill in the art after a complete reading of the present disclosure, the amount of time that is required to perform fast speed lateral force tests is much shorter than the amount of time that may be required to perform the corresponding slow speed tests&#x2014;each of which may take as much as 10 to 100 times longer to perform, since the constant test probe speed used during the slow speed tests disclosed herein is less than 0.1 &#x3bc;m/sec. When hundreds, or even thousands, of lateral force tests are performed so as to characterize the behavioral interaction of a given pillar bump/metallization system configuration, and hundreds or even thousands more tests are performed during chip quality assurance assessments, or to evaluate different dielectric materials or chip configurations, use of the typical fast speed test may result in an overall reduction in the amount of time needed to perform a given set of tests. However, in many instances, the perceived economic benefits that may be associated with the reduced amount of time used to perform the prior art fast speed tests is significantly outweighed by the additional correlational accuracy provided by the novel slow speed tests of the present disclosure. Thus, contrary to traditional manufacturing and inspection operations, where manufacturers are constantly pressured to perform operations faster so as to reduce cost, by performing the more time-consuming slow speed test disclosed herein, unexpected benefits may be achieved.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">As the above discussion shows, fast speed lateral force testing is generally not as representative of real-world chip packaging interaction effects as are the novel slow speed testing methods disclosed herein. For example, the fast speed tests may give a misleading impression that a given pillar bump/metallization system configuration can withstand a higher load prior to crack initiation than it may actually be capable of resisting. Accordingly, when a typical behavioral response curve is generated using prior art fast speed lateral force tests, such as the test curve <b>301</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> above, and that typical behavioral response curve is used to perform an evaluation of a specific semiconductor chip BEOL metallization system layout, the fast speed test curve may indicate that the chip layout is more robust under chip packaging thermal interaction forces than it actually is. As such, an overly optimistic design margin may be attributed to the design when in fact the design margins may be significantly lower, or even completely nonexistent. In such cases, force/distance behavioral interaction curves that are based on the novel slow speed lateral force tests disclosed herein may be substantially more accurate, thus providing the requisite design margins, as well as fostering a greater overall reliability in the chip evaluation process.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">In some illustrative embodiments of the present disclosure, a typical force/distance behavioral interaction curve, such as the curve <b>302</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, may be used in a comparative fashion in conjunction with additional lateral force testing to evaluate and characterize atypical, or anomalous, behavioral interactions between a given BEOL metallization system configuration and the pillar bumps formed thereabove. For example, random statistical testing may be performed on a plurality of pillar bumps formed above a metallization system of a semiconductor chip or wafer using the slow speed testing techniques described herein. In certain embodiments, the force/distance curves generated for some specific tests may display an unexpectedly different response to the lateral force test than might otherwise have been predicted by the typical behavioral interaction curve for a similarly configured pillar bump/metallization system. This is turn may thereby indicate the presence of one or more material, configuration, and/or design related anomalies, which may be associated either with the pillar bump, the underlying metallization system, or some combination thereof, as will be described in further detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">In some instances, one or more of the BEOL metallization layers making up a given metallization system may be abnormally and/or unexpectedly weaker than would normally be anticipated for a typical system having a similar configuration. Such weak areas within the metallization system may be attributable to any one or more of several different factors, including a drift in process deposition parameters, processing tool malfunction and/or cleanliness, substrate cleanliness, bonding or adhesion issues between adjacent layers and/or conductive elements, and the like. In other cases, anomalous weak areas in a given BEOL metallization system may be attributable to the specific layout of the various circuit elements in those areas, such as closely spaced conductive elements within a given metallization layer, and/or the relative positioning or alignment of circuit elements between successive metallization layers. In still other cases, the anomalies may be related to one or more aspects of the pillar bump, such as the type of material, adhesion, and/or processing issues described above.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In certain cases, the material of a particular pillar bump may be somewhat harder and/or stronger than might normally be expected for a typical pillar bump that is made up of that same type of material. As a result, the overall stiffness of such a pillar bump may be increased relative to that of a typical pillar bump, which, due to its lower hardness and/or material strength, may be somewhat more flexible or compliant when exposed to certain lateral loading schemes. Under such circumstances, the behavioral interaction between a metallization system and a pillar bump that may be made up of a harder and/or stronger material may display a substantially different behavioral interaction curve under a lateral force test relative to that of the typical pillar bumps described above. For descriptive purposes, these pillar bumps that may be made up of a material that is otherwise harder and/or stronger than that of the typical pillar bumps described above may hereinafter be referred to as &#x201c;stiff&#x201d; pillar bumps, whereas typical pillar bumps may also be referred to as &#x201c;compliant&#x201d; pillar bumps.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">In some cases, such anomalous stiff pillar bumps may be formed during the pillar bump process such that the pillar bump includes one or more metal grains which have an otherwise anomalous or imperfect crystalline grain structure. For example, in those illustrative embodiments wherein the pillar bumps of a semiconductor chip are made up of copper or a copper alloy, the elastic and plastic behavior of the copper pillar bumps may depend on the actual texture of the bumps. As noted above, in some cases, this texture could cause some of the copper pillar bumps to be stiffer than a more typical compliant pillar bump with respect to certain loading schemes that are applied to the bumps during lateral load tests&#x2014;i.e., resulting in a stiff pillar bump, as previously described. Such anomalous stiff pillar bumps may generally be less likely to deflect and/or deform under a given load than would a more typical compliant pillar bump, whether that given load is an out-of-plane thermal interaction load during a flip-chip bonding and assembly process, or a lateral load imposed on the pillar bump during a slow speed lateral load test. Accordingly, since stiff pillar bumps may be less likely to deform under a lateral load, they may also be more likely to be associated with crack-induced failures of a chip's metallization system, since a greater amount of the load on the stiff pillar bump is driven into the weaker underlying metallization layers.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> graphically illustrates comparative pillar bump/metallization system interaction curves <b>501</b> and <b>502</b>, which represent the behavioral interaction of anomalous stiff pillar bumps and typical compliant pillar bumps, respectively, when tested to crack failure using the illustrative test configuration of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, curve <b>502</b>, which represents the typical behavioral interaction between compliant pillar bumps and an underlying metallization system, has a configuration that is substantially the same as the typical force/distance curve <b>302</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. More specifically, the compliant pillar bump curve <b>502</b> displays an initial non-linear strain-hardening region <b>502</b>A (correlating to region <b>302</b>A), a second substantially linear region <b>502</b>B (correlating to region <b>302</b>B), a third non-linear region <b>502</b>C (correlating to region <b>302</b>C), a crack point <b>532</b> (correlating to crack point <b>332</b>), and a substantially linear post-crack region <b>502</b>D (correlating to region <b>302</b>D). Furthermore, it should be understood that the crack point <b>532</b> occurs at a force level <b>522</b> having substantially the same magnitude as the force level <b>322</b> of curve <b>302</b>, and at a total distance traveled <b>512</b> having substantially the same magnitude as the distance <b>312</b> of curve <b>302</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">Curve <b>501</b>, which represents the typical behavioral interaction between stiff pillar bumps and an underlying metallization system, has a configuration that is similar to some aspects of the force/distance curve <b>502</b>, but different, however, than some other aspects of curve <b>502</b>. For example, the stiff pillar bump curve <b>501</b> has a substantially linear region <b>501</b>B which has substantially the same slope as the second substantially linear region <b>502</b>B of curve <b>502</b>, and a region <b>501</b>C having substantially the same non-linear configuration as the third non-linear region <b>502</b>C of curve <b>502</b>. Furthermore, curve <b>501</b> displays a crack point <b>531</b> this is at a force level that is substantially the same as the force level <b>522</b> of curve <b>502</b>, as well has a substantially linear post-crack region <b>501</b>D which has substantially the same slope as the post-crack region <b>502</b>D of curve <b>502</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">On the other hand, the stiff pillar bump curve <b>501</b> does not display a substantially non-linear initial curve region that would be comparable to the non-linear region <b>502</b>A of the compliant pillar bump curve <b>502</b>. This may be indicative that the initial strain-hardening effect shown in region <b>502</b>A (and region <b>302</b>A of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) that influences the force/distance response of compliant pillar bumps does not generally occur with the stiff pillar bumps. Accordingly, since there is no non-linear strain-hardening effects occurring during the initial part of the lateral force tests represented by curve <b>501</b>, a stiff pillar bump/metallization system may reach its maximum load carrying level <b>522</b> more quickly than does a similarly configured compliant pillar bump/metallization system. More specifically, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, curve <b>501</b> shows that a crack is created in the stiff pillar bump system at a maximum distance traveled <b>511</b> that is less than the distance <b>512</b> that is required to initiate a crack in the compliant pillar bump system by an amount <b>513</b>, as shown by curve <b>502</b>. Therefore, the data represented by the stiff pillar bump curve <b>501</b> indicates that as a given chip package cools and shrinks after the chip reflow process, white bump crack failures will be more likely to occur in those areas of the metallization system that surround or are near anomalous stiff pillar bumps.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">In certain illustrative embodiments, the slow speed lateral force tests disclosed herein may be performed on specific semiconductor chips prior to flip-chip packaging so as to detect the presence of anomalous stiff pillar bumps, which, as described above, may be more likely than typical compliant pillar bumps to lead to the occurrence of white bump crack failures in an underlying metallization system. However, in accordance with the present disclosure, adjustments may be made to the slow speed lateral force testing methodology so that the pillar bumps in general are not tested to failure, i.e., so that the presence of stiff pillar bumps is merely detected, but without creating a crack in the underlying metallization system during the test.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref><i>a </i>schematically depicts one illustrative embodiment of the present disclosure wherein a slow speed lateral force test may be used to detect the presence of anomalous stiff pillar bumps formed above a metallization system <b>604</b> of a semiconductor chip or wafer <b>602</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref><i>a</i>, a test probe <b>620</b> may be used to impose a force <b>620</b>F on a pillar bump <b>603</b>, which may represent one of a plurality of pillar bumps <b>603</b> of the semiconductor chip <b>602</b>. In certain embodiments, the test probe <b>620</b> may be moved along a path <b>621</b> at a constant speed in accordance with the previously described slow speed testing methodology&#x2014;i.e., at a test probe speed that is less than approximately 0.1 &#x3bc;m/sec&#x2014;so as to generate the force <b>620</b>F on the respective pillar bump <b>603</b>. Furthermore, in order to avoid inadvertently inducing a crack in the metallization system <b>604</b> underlying the pillar bump <b>603</b> during the slow speed lateral force test shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref><i>a</i>, the probe <b>620</b> may be moved along a path that is not substantially parallel to the plane <b>623</b> of the metallization system <b>604</b>, as may have been used to generate the typical behavioral interaction curves <b>301</b> and <b>302</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, as well as the curves <b>501</b> and <b>502</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. Instead, and for the reasons outlined below, the path <b>621</b> along which the test probe <b>620</b> may be moved during the test may be angled downward toward the pillar bump <b>603</b> and the metallization system <b>604</b> at a substantially non-zero angle <b>622</b> relative to the plane <b>623</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">It should be appreciated that when the force <b>620</b>F is imposed on the pillar bump <b>603</b> with the probe <b>620</b> at the substantially non-zero angle <b>622</b>, only a first portion of the force vector <b>620</b>F translates to a shear load <b>620</b>S and an overturning moment <b>620</b>M at the interface <b>640</b> between the pillar bump <b>603</b> and the metallization system <b>604</b>. On the other hand, a second portion of the force vector <b>620</b>F imposed on the pillar bump <b>603</b> translates to a compressive load <b>620</b>C at the interface <b>640</b>. Accordingly, with the overturning moment <b>620</b>M being reduced from what would typically be the case when the lateral force is imposed along a substantially parallel path relative to the metallization system (see, e.g., the path <b>212</b> of the force <b>220</b>F relative to the plane <b>223</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>), together with the additional compressive load portion <b>620</b>C, the localized tensile stress <b>608</b>T in the metallization system <b>604</b> may, at least during an initial part of the lateral force test, remain below a stress level that might induce a crack.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">In certain embodiments of the present disclosure, the force/distance behavioral interaction of the pillar bump <b>603</b> and the metallization system <b>604</b> may be evaluated and/or plotted during the lateral force test. Furthermore, in at least some illustrative embodiments, the specific behavioral interaction of a given tested pillar bump <b>603</b> may be compared on a real-time basis to the known behavioral interaction curves for anomalous stiff pillar bumps and typical compliant pillar bumps, e.g., the behavioral interaction of pre-characterized typical populations, such as may be represented by the comparative behavioral interaction curves <b>501</b> and <b>502</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. Moreover, since stiff pillar bumps have been shown to display a substantially linear response from the very beginning of a lateral force test (see, e.g., region <b>501</b>B of curve <b>501</b>), as compared to the substantially non-linear initial response of compliant pillar bumps (see, e.g., region <b>502</b>A of curve <b>502</b>), it is possible to quickly assess whether or not a given pillar bump <b>603</b> may be an anomalous stiff pillar bump. In some embodiments, slow speed lateral force testing of the pillar bump/metallization system may then continue at least until a statistically significant and/or predetermined quantity of pillar bumps <b>603</b> have been tested, at least in the critical areas of the semiconductor chip <b>602</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">In at least some embodiments, the modified slow speed lateral force testing of pillar bumps <b>603</b> that is used to detect stiff pillar bumps as described above may be performed with the semiconductor chip <b>602</b> mounted on a test fixture (not shown) such that the plane <b>623</b> of the metallization system <b>604</b> is in a substantially horizontal orientation, as is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref><i>a</i>, and wherein the test probe <b>620</b> is moved along the path <b>621</b> at a downwardly oriented angle <b>622</b> relative to the horizontal plane. In certain embodiments, the angle <b>622</b> may range between about 5&#xb0; and 45&#xb0;, wherein the specific angle <b>622</b> used may depend on the level of overturning moment <b>620</b>M to which the metallization system <b>604</b> can be safely exposed without inducing a crack. Furthermore, it should be appreciated that, due to the angle <b>622</b> of the path <b>621</b> along which the test probe <b>620</b> is moved during the modified lateral force tests, the notch <b>624</b> created in the tested pillar bump <b>603</b> may have a substantially asymmetric configuration or appearance, thereby readily distinguishing the angled pillar bump tests that may be used to detect stiff pillar bumps.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">In other embodiments, the semiconductor chip <b>602</b> may be mounted on a test fixture (not shown) as described above, wherein however the test fixture and chip <b>602</b> may be rotated such that the plane <b>623</b> of the metallization system <b>604</b> is at an angle <b>622</b> relative to horizontal, as is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref><i>b</i>. During the lateral force tests, the test probe <b>620</b> may then be moved along a path <b>621</b> that is substantially aligned with the horizontal plane, thereby inducing the same relative magnitudes of loads <b>620</b>S, <b>620</b>C and overturning moment <b>620</b>M at the interface <b>640</b> as is described with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref><i>a </i>above. Accordingly, the same reduced relative level of local tensile stress <b>608</b>T may be induced in the metallization system <b>604</b> during the angled lateral force tests illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref><i>b</i>, thus substantially avoiding the creation of cracks.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">In some embodiments disclosed herein, when the modified lateral force testing method illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6</figref><i>a </i>and <b>6</b><i>b </i>is used to detect anomalous stiff pillar bumps without inducing crack failures in the underlying metallization system of a semiconductor chip, it may be possible to take at least some remedial steps to salvage a chip that contains stiff pillar bumps without having to resort to completely scrapping the chip. Such an approach may be of particular importance in those cases where the semiconductor chip in question may have a relatively greater cost than normal, and/or may be intended for use in more robust, critical, specialized, and/or high end applications. For example, as noted above, a stiff pillar bump may be more likely to lead to crack failures in the underlying metallization system than would a typical compliant pillar bump, due at least in part to the shorter total amount of pillar bump displacement that may be required to induce a load of sufficient magnitude to induce a crack. See, i.e., the comparative behavioral interaction curves <b>501</b> and <b>502</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, showing that a displacement distance <b>511</b> (curve <b>501</b>) is generally required to induce a crack in the metallization system below a typical stiff pillar bump, whereas a greater distance <b>512</b> (curve <b>502</b>) is generally required to induce a crack below a typical compliant pillar bump. Accordingly, an analysis may be performed to evaluate the specific locations on the semiconductor chip where stiff pillar bumps may be located, and a determination made as to whether or not those specific locations may be expected to undergo an amount of differential thermal expansion during chip packaging interaction that would be sufficiently likely to cause crack failures in the underlying metallization system.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">On one hand, if any stiff pillar bumps are positioned at specific points on the chip where subsequent white bump failures may be less likely to occur, a risk assessment may be performed to determine whether or not it may be feasible to use the chip as-is. On the other hand, if one or more stiff pillar bumps are located in those regions of the chip where white bump failures are more likely to occur, such as at or near the corners of the chip, additional analysis and/or remedial action may be warranted, as will be further described below.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">In those cases where stiff pillar bumps may be located in the regions of a semiconductor chip where white bump defects are more likely to occur, an analysis of the chip's circuit layout below and surrounding the specific points where stiff pillar bumps are positioned may be performed to determine whether those areas of the chip contain sensitive circuit elements that may be adversely affected should a white bump crack occur in the surrounding metallization layers. If not, a further risk assessment may be performed to determine the feasibility of using the chip as-is. However, even if sensitive circuit elements may be present in the areas of the chip below a stiff pillar bump, it may still be possible to use the chip in a less demanding application that may not require an overly robust chip design. Additionally, in at least some illustrative embodiments of the present disclosure, some stiff pillar bumps may be repaired by modifying the flexibility of the pillar bumps as described with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7</figref><i>a</i>-<b>7</b><i>e </i>below, so that the chip might still be used as originally intended, or at least in an application requiring less stringent adherence to the original circuit design layout requirements.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">Once a stiff pillar bump has been detected above the metallization system of a semiconductor chip, the stiff pillar bump may be repaired by increasing the pillar bump's flexibility, so that at least some of the out-of-plane loads imposed on the repaired pillar bump during chip packaging thermal interaction may be absorbed by deformation of the bump. This in turn may reduce the magnitude of the loads that are transmitted through the pillar bump's bonding pad (see, e.g., <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>d</i>) and the corresponding level of local tensile stresses that are induced in the underlying metallization system. Accordingly, the likelihood that a crack may occur in one or more of the metallization layers during flip-chip packaging may be thereby reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>a </i>schematically depicts one embodiment of an illustrative method that may be used for repairing stiff pillar bumps according the present disclosure. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>a</i>, a pillar bump repair device <b>720</b> may be used to form a plurality of strain-relieving notches along one side <b>703</b>A of a respective stiff pillar bump <b>703</b>, such as the notches <b>725</b><i>a</i>-<i>d</i>, which may provide a degree of spring-like flexibility to the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b>. The strain-relieving notches <b>725</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>may be formed by contacting the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b> with the tip <b>720</b>P of the pillar bump repair device <b>720</b>, thereby imposing a force <b>720</b>F that is sufficiently high enough to locally deform the bump <b>703</b> at the location of each notch <b>725</b><i>a</i>-<i>d</i>. In some illustrative embodiments, the pillar bump repair device <b>720</b> may be moved along a path <b>721</b> that is substantially parallel to the plane <b>723</b> of the metallization system <b>704</b>, although it should be appreciated that a non-parallel path may also be used, depending on the degree of additional pillar bump flexibility required.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">In certain disclosed embodiments, the path <b>721</b> of the pillar bump repair device <b>720</b> may be substantially aligned with a radial vector <b>702</b>V that points toward the approximate center <b>702</b>C of the semiconductor chip <b>702</b> (see, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>c</i>), so that the stress-relieving notches <b>725</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>may be oriented along the path of the greatest out-of-plane loads imposed on the chip <b>702</b> during flip-chip packaging. See, e.g., the force vectors <b>102</b>F illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>c </i>and described above. The stress-relieving notches <b>725</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>that are formed in accordance with the steps outlined above may therefore be positioned along the side <b>703</b>A of the stiff pillar bump that is oriented substantially away from the approximate center <b>702</b>C of the semiconductor chip <b>702</b>, and substantially toward the periphery of the chip <b>702</b> (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>a</i>), which corresponds to the tensile load side of the pillar bump <b>703</b>. See, e.g., the local tensile stress <b>208</b>T shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. Moreover, in at least some embodiments, the notches <b>725</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>may be positioned along the side <b>703</b>A in a substantially vertical alignment. Accordingly, the notches <b>725</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>may hereinafter be referred to as tensile strain-relieving notches, as they may tend to provide additional bump flexibility on the tensile load side of the pillar bump <b>703</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">The actual quantity of tensile strain-relieving notches formed along the side <b>703</b>A of the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b>, as well as the depth of each respective notch, may depend on the degree of additional flexibility that may be required for the repaired pillar bump in question. For example, stiff pillar bumps that are positioned in areas of a semiconductor chip where a greater amount of differential thermal expansion occurs, such as locations that are the farthest distance from the center of the chip (see, e.g., the corner regions <b>102</b>E of the chip <b>102</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>c</i>) may require a greater degree of additional pillar bump flexibility, and therefore may have more and/or deeper strain-relieving notches. Similarly, stiff pillar bumps that may be positioned above or near areas of the metallization system containing sensitive or critical circuit elements may also require greater added flexibility so as to reduce the likelihood that cracks may occur in those areas, thus necessitating more and/or deeper notches.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>b </i>schematically illustrates another exemplary method for increasing the flexibility of the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b> depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>a</i>, wherein additional strain-relieving notches, such as the notches <b>726</b><i>a</i>-<i>c</i>, may be formed on an opposite side <b>703</b>B of the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b> from the first side <b>703</b>A where the initial strain-relieving notches <b>725</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>may have been formed, as described above. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>b</i>, the notches <b>726</b><i>a</i>-<i>c </i>may be formed by moving the pillar bump repair device <b>720</b> substantially along the same path <b>721</b> as described with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>a </i>above so as to impart a force <b>720</b>F that locally deforms the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b> at the location of each additional notch <b>726</b><i>a</i>-<i>c</i>. However, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>b</i>, the pillar bump repair device <b>720</b> is moved in an opposite direction relative to the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b> so that the tip <b>720</b>P contacts the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b> on an opposite side <b>703</b>B from the side <b>703</b>A. Therefore, in at least some embodiments, the stress-relieving notches <b>726</b><i>a</i>-<i>c </i>may be oriented substantially toward the approximate center <b>702</b>C of the semiconductor chip <b>702</b> (see, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>c</i>), and away from the periphery of the chip <b>702</b> (not shown), which corresponds to the compressive load side of the pillar bump <b>703</b>. See, e.g., the local compressive stress <b>208</b>C shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. Moreover, as with the notches <b>725</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>above, in certain illustrative embodiments, the notches <b>726</b><i>a</i>-<i>c </i>may also be positioned along the side <b>703</b>B of the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b> in a substantially vertical alignment. Accordingly, the notches <b>726</b><i>a</i>-<i>c </i>may hereinafter be referred to as compressive strain-relieving notches, as they may tend to provide additional bump flexibility on the compressive load side of the pillar bump <b>703</b>. Furthermore, and as noted above, the actual quantity and depth of the compressive strain-relieving notches formed on the side <b>703</b>B oriented toward the approximate center <b>702</b>C of the semiconductor chip <b>702</b>, such as the notches <b>726</b><i>a</i>-<i>c</i>, may be adjusted as required for the desired final flexibility of the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b> after the above described repair modifications have been performed.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">In some illustrative embodiments, the position of one or more of the above described strain-relieving notches and the depth to which the notches are formed may be limited by one or more of the specific design parameters associated with a given pillar bump. For example, the presence of the strain-relieving notches described herein may reduce, to at least some degree, the cross-sectional area of a repaired pillar bump. As such, in certain embodiments the notch depths may be limited so as to avoid increasing the current density in a repaired pillar bump, thereby avoid, or at least minimize, any electromigration effects that may result from the reduced cross-sectional area. Similarly, the proximity of a given strain-relieving notch to the top or bottom end of the repaired pillar bump may also be limited for the same reasons, as the current density in the pillar bump may be highest in those areas.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>c </i>schematically depicts a plan view of the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7</figref><i>a </i>and <b>7</b><i>b</i>, illustrating further illustrative embodiments of the stiff pillar bump repair methods disclosed herein. In certain embodiments, a pillar bump support device <b>730</b>, such as a collar-shaped support device and the like, may be used to substantially prevent the force <b>720</b>F used to form each strain-relieving notch in the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b> from causing the type of pillar bump displacement that commonly occurs during the lateral force testing of pillar bumps. See, e.g., the force/distance curves <b>301</b> and <b>302</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, and the force/distance curves <b>501</b> and <b>502</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">In operation, the pillar bump support device <b>730</b> may be positioned adjacent to a stiff pillar bump <b>703</b> so that a contact surface <b>730</b>S of the pillar bump support device <b>730</b> is substantially in contact with at least a portion of the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b>. In certain embodiments, the pillar bump support device <b>730</b> may be held in place during the pillar bump repair process by an appropriate tool (not shown) on the opposite side of the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b> from where the strain-relieving notches are being formed with the pillar bump repair device <b>720</b>. For example, when the tensile strain-relieving notches <b>725</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>are being formed along the side <b>703</b>A of the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b> that is oriented away from the approximate center <b>702</b>C of the semiconductor chip <b>702</b>, the pillar bump support device <b>730</b> may be positioned on the opposite side <b>703</b>B of the pillar bump <b>703</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>c</i>. Similarly, when the compressive strain-relieving notches <b>726</b><i>a</i>-<i>c </i>are being formed along the side <b>703</b>B of the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b> that is oriented toward the center approximate <b>702</b>C, the pillar bump support device <b>730</b> may be positioned on the opposite side <b>703</b>A. In this way, the notch-creating force <b>720</b>F will generally not be transmitted into the underlying metallization system <b>704</b> (see, e.g., <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</figref>, <b>6</b><i>a</i>. and <b>6</b><i>b</i>), but will instead be resisted by a reaction force <b>730</b>F that is imposed on the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b> by the pillar bump support device <b>730</b>. Accordingly, the repair system shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>c </i>will substantially be in force equilibrium during the above-described pillar bump repair process, and the possibility that cracks may be created in the metallization system <b>704</b> by the force <b>720</b>F may be substantially avoided.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">In some embodiments, at least a portion of the pillar bump support device <b>730</b> may have a shape that substantially conforms to the shape of the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b>, so that it may thereby provide adequate support during the pillar bump repair processes described herein. For example, when the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b> has a substantially cylindrical shape as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>c</i>, the portion of the pillar bump support device <b>730</b> that is adapted to contact the pillar bump <b>703</b> may have a substantially similar cylindrical shape. In such embodiments, the pillar bump support device <b>730</b> may be, for example, a portion of a hollow cylinder, such as half of a hollow cylinder, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>c</i>. However, it should be appreciated that the half hollow cylinder configuration shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>c </i>is illustrative only, as other configurations or shapes may also be used, so long as they provide the requisite degree of support, as described above. Furthermore, the pillar bump support device <b>730</b> may also be made up of any suitable material that may be capable of providing an appropriate degree of support, and substantially without creating any additional surface damage to the repaired pillar bump <b>703</b>. By way of example only, the pillar bump support device <b>730</b> may be made of a resilient gasket-like material, such as rubber and the like, although it should be understood that other materials, both harder and softer, may also be used within the spirit and scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">In certain embodiments, the pillar bump repair device <b>720</b> used to form the stress-relieving notches <b>725</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>and/or <b>726</b><i>a</i>-<i>c </i>may be, for example, a test probe, such as the test probes <b>220</b> or <b>620</b> described herein that may typically be used for performing lateral force tests. In other embodiments, the pillar bump repair device <b>720</b> may be a specialized tool such that the tip <b>720</b>P has a specific tip contour, as will be further described with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7</figref><i>d </i>and <b>7</b><i>e below. </i></p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">During the above-described pillar bump repair process, the material of the pillar bump surrounding the inside tip of any given strain-relieving notch, such as the inside tips <b>725</b>P and/or <b>726</b>P shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7</figref><i>a </i>and <b>7</b><i>b</i>, may become strain hardened as a respective notch indention is formed. Furthermore, as the shape of the tip <b>720</b>P on the pillar bump repair device <b>720</b> approaches a sharper point, the amount of strain hardening induced during the notch deformation process may increase. As noted above, the test probe that is used to perform lateral force tests for detecting stiff pillar bumps (such as the test probe <b>620</b> shown in in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6</figref><i>a </i>and <b>6</b><i>b</i>) may sometimes also be used to form the strain-relieving notches during the pillar bump repair process. However, in those illustrative embodiments wherein the test probe used to detect stiff pillar bumps may have a substantially pointed tip <b>720</b>P, a pillar bump repair device having a tip <b>720</b>P that does not induce such a great degree of strain hardening during notch formation may instead be used during the pillar bump repair process, as described below.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>d </i>is a close-up view of the tensile strain-relieving notches <b>725</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>formed in the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7</figref><i>a </i>and <b>7</b><i>b</i>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>d</i>, the tip <b>720</b>P of the pillar bump repair device <b>720</b> may have a radiused contour <b>720</b>R, which may then be used to form one or more of the notches <b>725</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>with an inside notch tip <b>725</b>P having a radiused contour <b>725</b>R that is substantially the same as the radius <b>720</b>R. The radius-tipped notches <b>725</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>may therefore cause a lower overall degree of strain hardening in the surrounding material of the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b>, thereby increasing to some degree the amount of flexibility that is added to the pillar bump <b>703</b> by virtue of the above-described pillar bump repair process. Furthermore, it should be understood that when strain-relieving notches are also formed on an opposite of the stiff pillar bump <b>703</b>, such as the compressive strain-relieving notches <b>726</b><i>a</i>-<i>c </i>shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7</figref><i>b </i>and <b>7</b><i>c</i>, the pillar bump repair device <b>720</b> having a tip <b>720</b>P with a radiused contour <b>720</b>R may also be used so as to reduce the degree of material strain hardening that may be caused in those locations during notch formation.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">In other illustrative embodiments disclosed herein, the pillar bump repair device <b>720</b> having a tip <b>720</b>P with a radiused contour <b>720</b>R may also be used to reduce the degree of strain hardening that may have been induced in the area surrounding any notch that may have been formed using a test probe having a substantially sharp-pointed tip. For example, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>e</i>, the radiused-tipped pillar bump repair device <b>720</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>d </i>may be used to adjust the profile a previously formed notch <b>724</b> having a substantially sharp-pointed inside notch tip <b>724</b>T, so that the adjusted profile of the notch <b>727</b> may have an inside notch tip <b>727</b>P with a radiused contour <b>727</b>R that substantially matches the radiused contour <b>720</b>R of the tip <b>720</b>P on the pillar bump repair device <b>720</b>. Furthermore, in at least some embodiments, the profile of any notches formed in a given pillar bump when lateral force testing is being used to detect the presence of stiff pillar bumps, such as the notches <b>624</b> in the pillar bumps <b>603</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6</figref><i>a </i>and <b>6</b><i>b</i>, may adjusted in a similar fashion by using a radius-tipped pillar bump repair device, such as the device <b>720</b> having a tip <b>720</b>P with a radiused contour <b>720</b>R.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> graphically illustrates comparative pillar bump/metallization system behavioral interaction curves <b>801</b> and <b>802</b>, wherein curve <b>801</b> depicts a behavioral interaction curve of pillar bumps that have been formed above anomalous weak sites in the BEOL metallization system of a semiconductor chip or wafer, whereas curve <b>802</b> depicts a typical comparative behavioral interaction curve of a representative pillar bump/metallization system configuration. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, comparative behavioral interaction curve <b>802</b> has a configuration that is substantially the same as the typical comparative force/distance behavioral interaction curves <b>302</b> and <b>502</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 5</figref>, respectively. More specifically, curve <b>802</b> displays an initial non-linear, e.g., strain-hardening, region <b>802</b>A (correlating to regions <b>302</b>A/<b>502</b>A), a second substantially linear region <b>802</b>B (correlating to regions <b>302</b>B/<b>502</b>B), a third non-linear region <b>802</b>C (correlating to regions <b>302</b>C/<b>502</b>C), a crack point <b>832</b> (correlating to crack points <b>332</b>/<b>532</b>), and a substantially linear post-crack region <b>802</b>D (correlating to regions <b>302</b>D/<b>502</b>D). Furthermore, it should be understood that the crack point <b>832</b> occurs at a force level <b>822</b> having substantially the same magnitude as the force levels <b>322</b>/<b>522</b> of curves <b>302</b>/<b>502</b>, and at a total distance traveled <b>812</b> having substantially the same magnitude as the distances <b>312</b>/<b>512</b> of curves <b>302</b>/<b>502</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">Curve <b>801</b>, which, as noted above, depicts the representative behavioral interaction of pillar bumps that have been formed above anomalous weak sites of a BEOL metallization system, has a configuration that is similar to some aspects of the typical force/distance curve <b>802</b>, but different, however, than some other aspects of curve <b>802</b>. For example, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, curve <b>801</b> has a substantially non-linear initial <b>801</b>A that closely follows the shape of the initial non-linear region <b>802</b>A of the typical comparative force/distance behavioral interaction curve <b>802</b>. Additionally, curve <b>801</b> has a linear region <b>801</b>B which has substantially the same slope as the second substantially linear region <b>802</b>B of curve <b>802</b>, and furthermore closely follows curve <b>802</b> up to an approximate transition point <b>861</b>, which is indicative of a lateral force <b>820</b>F on a representative pillar bump having a magnitude <b>851</b> and a distance traveled <b>820</b>D having a magnitude <b>841</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">However, after having reached the end of the substantially linear response region <b>801</b>B at the approximate transition point <b>861</b>, curve <b>801</b> transitions into a substantially non-linear response region <b>801</b>C, which has a substantially similar non-linear configuration as the third non-linear region <b>802</b>C of curve <b>802</b>, albeit occurring in a lower range of force <b>820</b>F and a shorter range of distance traveled <b>820</b>D. For example, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the comparative behavioral interaction curve <b>802</b> displays an approximate linear to non-linear transition point <b>862</b> between regions <b>802</b>B and <b>802</b>C that occurs at a lateral force magnitude <b>852</b>, which is greater by an amount <b>853</b> than the lateral force magnitude <b>851</b> for the transition point <b>861</b> of curve <b>801</b>. In one example, the force <b>852</b> may be approximately 10-50% greater than the force <b>851</b>. Furthermore, the transition point <b>862</b> also occurs at a distance traveled <b>842</b> that is greater than the distance traveled <b>841</b> shown for curve <b>801</b> at the transition point <b>861</b> by an amount <b>843</b>. In one example, the distance <b>842</b> may be approximately 5-35% greater than the distance <b>841</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">Curve <b>801</b> further indicates that a crack will eventually occur at anomalous weak BEOL sites at a force level <b>820</b>F and distance traveled <b>820</b>D that are both lower than the respective values indicated for the typical pillar bump/metallization system configuration depicted by curve <b>802</b>. More specifically, curve <b>801</b> displays a crack point <b>831</b> that occurs at a force level <b>820</b>F having a magnitude <b>821</b> that is lower by an amount <b>823</b> than the magnitude <b>822</b> of the force level <b>820</b>F that is required to initiate a crack in the typical pillar bump/metallization system configuration as indicated by crack point <b>832</b>. Similarly, accordingly to curve <b>801</b>, the total distance traveled <b>820</b>D to initiate a crack in the weak BEOL metallization system during lateral force tests has a magnitude <b>811</b>, which is less than the corresponding magnitude <b>812</b> of curve <b>802</b> by an amount <b>813</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">Accordingly, a comparison of the force/distance response curves <b>801</b> and <b>802</b> provides evidence that a system configuration that is made up of typical pillar bump (e.g., a compliant pillar bump as previously described) will generally display, at least up to a point, a common force/distance behavioral interaction response, irrespective of whether or not the pillar bump is located near or above an anomalous weak BEOL metallization system site. However, when the tested pillar bump is positioned above or near an aforementioned anomalously weak BEOL site, the behavioral interaction curve of the tested pillar bump will transition from a substantially linear response to a substantially non-linear at a lower lateral force level and distance traveled than would normally be expected for a typical pillar bump/metallization system configuration. This type of pillar bump/metallization system behavioral interaction may therefore be used in some instances to perform additional lateral force tests on representative semiconductor chips or wafers so as to detect the presence of anomalous weak BEOL sites in a given metallization system.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">In certain illustrative embodiments, slow speed lateral force tests as disclosed herein may be performed on the pillar bumps of specific semiconductor chips prior to flip-chip packaging so as to detect the presence of anomalous weak BEOL sites in an underlying metallization system, which, as described above, may be more likely to lead to the occurrence of white bump crack failures. However, as with the above-described lateral force tests that may be used to detect the presence of anomalous stiff pillar bumps (see, e.g., <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6</figref><i>a </i>and <b>6</b><i>b </i>and the corresponding description), adjustments may be made to the slow speed lateral force testing scheme so that the pillar bumps are not tested to failure, i.e., so that the presence of weak BEOL sites is merely detected, but without creating a crack in the underlying metallization system during the test.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref><i>a </i>schematically depicts one illustrative embodiment of the present disclosure wherein a slow speed lateral force test may be used to detect the presence of anomalous stiff pillar bumps formed above a metallization system <b>904</b> of a semiconductor chip or wafer <b>902</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref><i>a</i>, a test probe <b>920</b> may be used to impose a force <b>920</b>F on a pillar bump <b>903</b>, which may represent one of a plurality of pillar bumps <b>903</b> of the semiconductor chip <b>902</b>. In certain embodiments, the test probe <b>920</b> may be moved along a path <b>921</b> at a constant speed in accordance with the previously described slow speed testing methodology&#x2014;i.e., at a test probe speed that is less than approximately 0.1 &#x3bc;m/sec&#x2014;so as to generate the force <b>920</b>F on the respective pillar bump <b>903</b>. Furthermore, in order to enhance the ability to detect weak BEOL sites in the metallization system <b>904</b> underlying the pillar bump <b>903</b> during the slow speed lateral force test shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref><i>a</i>, the probe <b>920</b> may not be moved along a path that is substantially parallel to the plane <b>923</b> of the metallization system <b>904</b>, as may have been used to generate the typical behavioral interaction curves <b>301</b> and <b>302</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, as well as the curves <b>801</b> and <b>802</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>. Instead, and for the reasons outlined below, the path <b>921</b> along which test probe <b>920</b> is moved during the test may be angled at a substantially non-zero angle <b>922</b> relative to the plane <b>923</b> so that the tip <b>920</b>P of the test probe <b>920</b> contacts the pillar bump <b>903</b> at a generally upward tilt.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">It should be understood that when the force <b>920</b>F is imposed on the pillar bump <b>903</b> with the probe <b>920</b> at the substantially non-zero angle <b>922</b>, only a first portion of the force vector <b>920</b>F translates to a shear load <b>920</b>S and an overturning moment <b>920</b>M at the interface <b>940</b> between the pillar bump <b>903</b> and the metallization system <b>904</b>. On the other hand, a second portion of the force vector <b>920</b>F imposed on the pillar bump <b>903</b> translates to a tensile load <b>920</b>T at the interface <b>940</b>. In this load configuration, the total uplift load on the pillar bump <b>903</b> due to the combination of the overturning moment <b>920</b>M and the additional tensile load portion <b>920</b>T, the localized tensile stress <b>908</b>T in the metallization system <b>904</b> may be higher than what would typically be expected, compared to the load configuration that would typically occur when the lateral force is imposed along a substantially parallel path relative to the metallization system (see, e.g., the path <b>212</b> of the force <b>220</b>F relative to the plane <b>223</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). In this way, when the tested pillar bump <b>903</b> is positioned above or near an anomalously weak BEOL site in the metallization system <b>904</b>, the transition point from a substantially linear to a substantially non-linear behavioral response, such as the transition point <b>861</b> between the regions <b>802</b>B and <b>802</b>C of comparative behavioral interaction curve <b>802</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, would be expected to occur more quickly than might otherwise be the case, thereby enhancing weak site detection.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">In certain embodiments of the present disclosure, the force/distance behavioral interaction of the pillar bump <b>903</b> and the metallization system <b>904</b> may be evaluated and/or plotted during the lateral force test. Furthermore, in at least some illustrative embodiments, the specific behavioral interaction of a given tested pillar bump <b>903</b> may be compared on a real-time basis to the known behavioral interaction curves for pillar bumps formed above anomalous weak BEOL sites and the typical pillar bump/metallization system, e.g., the behavioral interaction of pre-characterized typical populations, such as may be represented by the comparative behavioral interaction curves <b>801</b> and <b>802</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>. Moreover, since pillar bumps formed above weak BEOL sites have been shown to display a quicker transition from a substantially linear response to a substantially non-linear response during a lateral force test (see, e.g., transition point <b>861</b> of curve <b>801</b>) as compared to the same transition in a typical pillar bump/metallization system configuration (see, e.g., the approximate transition point <b>862</b> of curve <b>802</b>), it is possible to quickly assess whether or not a given pillar bump <b>903</b> may be formed above an anomalously weak site within the BEOL metallization system <b>904</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">For example, when the force <b>920</b>F imposed on the pillar bump <b>903</b>, or the distance traveled by the test probe <b>920</b> during the lateral force tests, passes a level that is known to cause an early linear to non-linear behavioral response transition in tests performed on pillar bumps formed above weak BEOL sites (see, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>), it may be indicative that the tested pillar bump <b>903</b> is not located above or near an anomalous weak BEOL site. On the other hand, an early linear/non-linear transition during the later force test may be indicative of a weak site in the BEOL metallization system <b>904</b> below the pillar bump <b>903</b>. Irrespective of whether or not a weak BEOL site has been detected during the lateral force test described above, once the force <b>920</b>F or the distance traveled by the test probe <b>920</b> has passed the range within which the linear/non-linear transition point is generally known to occur, the test may be discontinued prior to inducing a crack in the underlying metallization system. Furthermore, it should be appreciated that in certain illustrative embodiments, a suitable lateral support device, such as the pillar bump support device <b>730</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>c </i>and described above, may be used to reduce the magnitude of the bending load imposed on the pillar bump <b>903</b> during the above-described tests, thus reducing the likelihood that cracks may occur.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">In at least some embodiments, the modified slow speed lateral force testing of pillar bumps <b>903</b> that is used to detect stiff pillar bumps as described above may be performed with the semiconductor chip <b>902</b> mounted on a test fixture (not shown) such that the plane <b>923</b> of the metallization system <b>904</b> is in a substantially horizontal orientation, as is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref><i>a</i>, and wherein the test probe <b>920</b> is moved along the path <b>921</b> at an angle <b>922</b> that is angled upward relative to the horizontal plane. In certain embodiments, the angle <b>922</b> may range between about 5&#xb0; and 45&#xb0;, wherein the specific angle <b>922</b> used may depend on the degree of weak BEOL site detection enhancement that may be desired for the specific semiconductor chip <b>902</b> and metallization system <b>904</b> being tested. Furthermore, it should be appreciated that, due to the angle <b>922</b> of the path <b>921</b> along which the test probe <b>920</b> is moved during the modified lateral force tests, the notch <b>924</b> created in the tested pillar bump <b>903</b> may have a substantially asymmetric configuration or appearance, thereby readily distinguishing the angled pillar bump tests that may be used to detect anomalous weak BEOL sites.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">In other embodiments, the semiconductor chip <b>902</b> may be mounted on a test fixture (not shown) as previously described, wherein however the test fixture and chip <b>902</b> may be rotated such that the plane <b>923</b> of the metallization system <b>904</b> is at an angle <b>922</b> relative to horizontal, as is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref><i>b</i>. During the lateral force tests, the test probe <b>920</b> may then be moved along a path <b>921</b> that is substantially aligned with the horizontal plane, thereby inducing the same relative magnitudes of loads <b>920</b>S, <b>920</b>T and overturning moment <b>920</b>M at the interface <b>940</b> as is described with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref><i>a </i>above. Accordingly, the same enhanced level of local tensile stress <b>908</b>T may be induced in the metallization system <b>904</b> during the angled lateral force tests illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref><i>b</i>, thus substantially enhancing the detection of anomalously weak BEOL sites in the metallization system <b>904</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">In some embodiments, slow speed lateral force testing of the pillar bump/metallization system as disclosed herein may then continue at least until a statistically significant and/or predetermined quantity of pillar bumps <b>903</b> have been tested, at least in those areas of the semiconductor chip <b>902</b> that may be of interest, depending on the specific reasons for performing the tests. For example, in certain illustrative embodiments, the above-described weak BEOL site detection testing may be used to evaluate the robustness of a specific metallization system layout. Depending on the outcome of the weak site detection testing, the specific chip layout may be used for the intended application as-is, the layout may be adjusted as required so as to eliminate and/or design around some or all of the detected weak sites, or the specific layout may be categorized for less robust applications and thereafter used as-is in less critical or less demanding applications.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">In certain other embodiments, testing for anomalous weak BEOL sites may be used to evaluate the performance of specific dielectric materials in a given metallization system configuration, or to evaluate the relative performance of new dielectric materials for use in highly scaled new device generations. In still other embodiments, weak site testing may be used as a quality control tool to pre-test dies for flip-chip bonding and assembly readiness, to evaluate process excursions and/or process drift in the back end of line manufacturing stages, or to evaluate the overall health of the manufacturing line (e.g., tool and/or substrate cleanliness, and the like).</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">Due to the generally upward tilt of the angle <b>922</b> at which the test probe <b>920</b> contacts the pillar bump <b>903</b> relative the plane <b>923</b> of the metallization system <b>904</b> during the testing for anomalous weak BEOL sites as described above, the tip <b>920</b>P of the test probe <b>920</b> may sometimes move or slide across the outer surface <b>903</b>S of the pillar bump <b>903</b> before the notch <b>924</b> begins being formed. Accordingly, in some illustrative embodiments of the present disclosure, the tip <b>920</b>P of the test probe <b>920</b> may be adapted so that it grabs or digs into the surface <b>903</b>S of the pillar bump <b>903</b> rather than sliding across the surface <b>903</b>S as described above, thereby providing a more consistently repeatable detection test for weak BEOL sites that may be present in the metallization system <b>904</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9</figref><i>c</i>-<b>9</b><i>l </i>depicts various illustrative embodiments of test probe tips <b>920</b>P that may be used for testing pillar bumps <b>903</b> in accordance with one or more of the testing configurations illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9</figref><i>a </i>and <b>9</b><i>b</i>, as will be described in further detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref><i>c </i>is a side elevation view of one embodiment of a tip <b>920</b>P of an illustrative test probe <b>920</b>, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref><i>d </i>shows the plan view of the test probe <b>920</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref><i>c </i>along the view &#x201c;<b>9</b><i>d</i>-<b>9</b><i>d</i>.&#x201d; As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9</figref><i>c </i>and <b>9</b><i>d</i>, the tip <b>920</b>P of the test probe <b>920</b> may have a tapered top surface <b>950</b> defining an included angle <b>950</b>A so that the tip <b>920</b>P forms a chisel-like wedge shape <b>960</b>W. In at least some embodiments, the included angle <b>950</b>A may range on the order of 30-40&#xb0;, although other angles may also be used. Furthermore, in certain embodiments, the included angle <b>950</b>A may be adjusted as required so as to provide the requisite degree of tip sharpness, e.g., so that the wedge shape <b>960</b>W of the tip <b>920</b>P grabs or digs into the surface <b>903</b>S of the tested pillar bump <b>903</b> (see, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9</figref><i>a </i>and <b>9</b><i>b</i>) substantially without moving or slipping. Moreover, the included angle <b>950</b>A may also be adjusted based on the specific materials of the test probe <b>920</b> and the pillar bumps <b>903</b> so to minimize the amount of undue deformation or other damage to the wedge shape <b>960</b>W during repeated pillar bump testing.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9</figref><i>e </i>and <b>9</b><i>f </i>depict another illustrative embodiment of a test probe <b>920</b> having a tip <b>920</b>P that forms a wedge shape <b>960</b>W, wherein the tip <b>920</b>P may also have a tapered bottom surface <b>951</b>, which together with the tapered top surface <b>950</b> forms the included angle <b>950</b>A. In certain embodiments, the included angle <b>950</b>A may be approximately 30-40&#xb0;, although the included angle <b>950</b>A may be adjusted to other specific angles as may be required so as to provide the requisite degree of tip sharpness, and/or to minimize the amount of undue deformation or other damage to the wedge shape <b>960</b>W during repeated pillar bump testing, as previously described.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9</figref><i>g </i>and <b>9</b><i>h </i>depict yet another illustrative test probe <b>920</b> having a tip <b>920</b>P that is substantially similar to the tip configuration shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9</figref><i>e </i>and <b>9</b><i>f</i>&#x2014;i.e., with tapered top and bottom surfaces <b>950</b> and <b>951</b> forming a wedge shape <b>960</b>W, and wherein the tip <b>920</b>P also includes a plurality of vertically oriented serrations <b>970</b>V. As shown in the plan view of the test probe <b>920</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref><i>f</i>, the vertically oriented serrations <b>970</b>V may, in at least some embodiments, extend across the full width of the wedge shape <b>960</b>W. In other embodiments (not shown), the serrations <b>970</b>V may be substantially centrally located on the tip <b>920</b>P with un-serrated portions of the wedge shape <b>960</b>W near each side, or vice versa, wherein the serrations <b>970</b> are grouped near either side of the tip <b>920</b>P with an un-serrated central portion. Furthermore, as with the included angle <b>950</b>A of the top and bottom surfaces <b>950</b> forming the wedge shape <b>970</b>W, the size and shape of the vertically oriented serrations <b>970</b>V may be adjusted as required so as to reduce the likelihood that the tip <b>920</b>P may slip during its initial contact with the sides <b>903</b>S of the tested pillar bump <b>903</b>&#x2014;e.g., so that the tip <b>920</b>P may more firmly engage with or grip the pillar bump <b>903</b>&#x2014;while also substantially reducing the likelihood of deformation and/or damage to the serrations <b>970</b>V.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9</figref><i>i </i>and <b>9</b><i>j </i>show yet another illustrative configuration of a test probe <b>920</b> having a tip <b>920</b>P that may be used to substantially reduce the likelihood that the test probe <b>920</b> does not slip when the tip <b>920</b>P initially engages the surface <b>9035</b> of a respective tested pillar bump <b>903</b>. In some embodiments, the tip may have top and bottom tapered surfaces <b>950</b> having an included angle <b>950</b>A as previously described with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9</figref><i>c</i>-<b>9</b><i>f </i>above. However, as shown in the illustrative embodiment depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9</figref><i>i </i>and <b>9</b><i>j</i>, the tip <b>920</b>P may have a substantially truncated or flat surface <b>960</b>F that includes a plurality of substantially horizontally oriented serrations <b>970</b>H. Furthermore, in certain embodiments, the tip <b>920</b>P of test probe <b>920</b> may also have tapered side surfaces <b>952</b> having an included angle <b>952</b>A, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref><i>j</i>. Depending on the parameters associated with the specific weak BEOL site testing, such as pillar bump materials, test probe materials, metallization system configuration, and the like, the included angle <b>952</b>A may range from approximately 20-40&#xb0;, although it should be understood that other angles may also be used, as previously described with respect to the included angle <b>950</b>A described above. It should also be appreciated that any of the previously disclosed embodiments described above, such as the embodiments illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9</figref><i>c</i>-<b>9</b><i>g</i>, may similarly have tapered side surfaces <b>951</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref><i>j</i>. Also as previously described, the included angles <b>950</b>A and <b>952</b>A and the number and size of horizontally oriented serrations <b>970</b>H may be adjusted as required based on the various pillar bump parameters and testing requirements.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9</figref><i>k </i>and <b>9</b><i>l </i>depict a further illustrative embodiment of a test probe <b>920</b>, wherein the tip <b>920</b>P of the test probe <b>920</b> may have a substantially flat surface <b>960</b>F. In certain embodiments, the substantially flat surface <b>960</b>F may be serrated in both the vertical and horizontal directions, such that the tip <b>920</b>P is made up of a plurality of teeth <b>970</b>T having a substantially pyramidal shape, and which may be adapted to grab or dig into the surface <b>903</b>S of a tested pillar bump <b>903</b> (see, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9</figref><i>a </i>and <b>9</b><i>b</i>), rather than slide across the surface <b>903</b>S as described above. Furthermore, it should also be appreciated that the double-serrated/pyramidal teeth configuration illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9</figref><i>k </i>and <b>9</b><i>l </i>may also be used, for example, on the truncated or flat surface <b>960</b>F of the illustrative embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9</figref><i>i </i>and <b>9</b><i>j </i>and described above.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">As a result of the forgoing descriptions, the present disclosure provides various methods and systems that may be employed to test and evaluate the metallization layers of a BEOL metallization system and the pillar bumps formed thereabove.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">The particular embodiments disclosed above are illustrative only, as the invention may be modified and practiced in different but equivalent manners apparent to those skilled in the art having the benefit of the teachings herein. For example, the process steps set forth above may be performed in a different order. Furthermore, no limitations are intended to the details of construction or design herein shown, other than as described in the claims below. It is therefore evident that the particular embodiments disclosed above may be altered or modified and all such variations are considered within the scope and spirit of the invention. Accordingly, the protection sought herein is as set forth in the claims below.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method, comprising:
<claim-text>forming pillar bump above a metallization system of a semiconductor chip; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a plurality of notches in said pillar bump, wherein forming each one of said plurality of notches comprises contacting a lateral side of said pillar bump with a notch-forming tool and imposing a substantially lateral force on said pillar bump with said tool, said plurality of notches being adapted to adjust a flexibility of said pillar bump when said pillar bump is exposed to a chip packaging interaction force.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein forming said plurality of notches comprises positioning each of said plurality of notches along said lateral side of said pillar bump in a substantially vertical alignment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein forming said plurality of notches comprises positioning each of said plurality of notches along a lateral side of said pillar bump that is oriented substantially away from a center of said semiconductor chip.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein forming said plurality of notches comprises forming at least three notches.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein forming said plurality of notches comprises forming an asymmetrically shaped notch.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein forming said plurality of notches comprises forming at least one of said plurality of notches with a tool having a radiused tip.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein forming said plurality of notches comprises forming at least one of said plurality of notches with a first tool having a first tool profile so as to form said at least one of said plurality of notches with a first notch profile, and using a second tool having a second tool profile to adjust a profile of said at least one of said plurality of notches from said first notch profile to a second notch profile.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein forming said at least one of said plurality of notches with said first tool comprises performing a lateral force test on said pillar bump with a test probe having said first tool profile.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein forming said plurality of notches comprises forming at least two first notches along a first lateral side of said pillar bump and forming at least one second notch on a second lateral side of said pillar bump, said second lateral side being on a substantially opposite side of said pillar bump from said first lateral side.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further comprising positioning each of said at least two first notches on said pillar bump so that said first lateral side is oriented substantially away from a center of said semiconductor chip and positioning said at least one second notch on said pillar bump so that said second lateral side is oriented substantially toward said center of said semiconductor chip.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising supporting said pillar bump with a pillar bump support device while forming said plurality of notches.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein supporting said pillar bump with a pillar bump support device comprises positioning said pillar bump support device to be in contact with a first lateral side of said pillar bump while forming one of said plurality of notches on a second lateral side of said pillar bump with said tool, said pillar bump support device being adapted to resist said substantially lateral force imposed on said pillar bump by said tool while forming said one of said plurality of notches.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising, after forming said plurality of notches in said pillar bump, performing a flip-chip operation to attach said semiconductor chip to a carrier substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A method, comprising:
<claim-text>positioning a pillar bump support device in contact with a first lateral side of a pillar bump formed above a metallization system of a semiconductor chip;</claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning a pillar bump repair device adjacent to a second lateral side of said pillar bump;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first notch on said second lateral side of said pillar bump with said pillar bump repair device, wherein forming said first notch comprises imposing a substantially laterally oriented force on said second lateral side with said pillar bump repair device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>supporting said pillar bump with said pillar bump support device while forming said first notch, wherein supporting said pillar bump comprises resisting, with said pillar bump support device, said substantially laterally oriented force being imposed on said second lateral side of said pillar bump by actuation of said pillar bump repair device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein positioning said pillar bump repair device adjacent to said second lateral side comprises positioning said pillar bump repair device adjacent to an opposite side of said pillar bump from said first lateral side.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein forming said first notch on said second lateral side of said pillar bump comprises forming said first notch on a lateral side of said pillar bump that is oriented substantially away from a center of said semiconductor chip.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, further comprising forming at least one second notch on said second lateral side of pillar bump with said pillar bump repair device while supporting said pillar bump with said pillar bump support device, wherein said at least one second notch is substantially vertically aligned with said first notch.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>positioning said pillar bump support device in contact with said second lateral side of said pillar bump;</claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning said pillar bump repair device adjacent to said first lateral side of said pillar bump;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming at least one further notch on said first lateral side of said pillar bump with said pillar bump repair device by imposing a further substantially laterally oriented force on said first lateral side with said pillar bump repair device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>supporting said pillar bump with said pillar bump support device while forming said at least one further notch by resisting, with said pillar bump support collar, said force imposed on said first lateral side of said pillar bump.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, further comprising, after forming said first notch in said pillar bump, performing a flip-chip operation to attach said semiconductor chip to a carrier substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. A method, comprising:
<claim-text>forming pillar bump above a metallization system of a semiconductor chip; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a plurality of notches in said pillar bump, wherein forming at least one of said plurality of notches comprises using a first tool having a first tool profile to form said at least one of said plurality of notches with a first notch profile and using a second tool having a second tool profile to adjust a profile of said at least one of said plurality of notches from said first notch profile to a second notch profile, said plurality of notches being adapted to adjust a flexibility of said pillar bump when said pillar bump is exposed to a lateral force.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, wherein forming said at least one of said plurality of notches with said first tool comprises performing a lateral force test on said pillar bump with a test probe having said first tool profile.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. A method, comprising:
<claim-text>forming pillar bump above a metallization system of a semiconductor chip;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a plurality of notches in said pillar bump, wherein said plurality of notches are adapted to adjust a flexibility of said pillar bump when said pillar bump is exposed to a lateral force; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>supporting said pillar bump with a pillar bump support device while forming said plurality of notches, wherein supporting said pillar bump comprises positioning said pillar bump support device to be in contact with a first side of said pillar bump while forming each of said plurality of notches on a second side of said pillar bump, said pillar bump support device being adapted to resist a force imposed on said pillar bump by a tool that is used to form each of said plurality of notches.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. A method, comprising:
<claim-text>positioning a pillar bump support device in contact with a first side of a pillar bump formed above a metallization system of a semiconductor chip;</claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning a pillar bump repair device adjacent to a second side of said pillar bump that is oriented substantially away from a center of said semiconductor chip;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first notch on said second side of said pillar bump with said pillar bump repair device, wherein forming said first notch comprises imposing a force on said second side with said pillar bump repair device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>supporting said pillar bump with said pillar bump support device while forming said first notch, wherein supporting said pillar bump comprises resisting, with said pillar bump support device, said force being imposed on said second side of said pillar bump by actuation of said pillar bump repair device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00023">claim 23</claim-ref>, wherein said first side of said pillar bump is laterally opposite of said second side. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
