<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622603-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622603</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13656811</doc-number>
<date>20121022</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>101123522 A</doc-number>
<date>20120629</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>21</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362619</main-classification>
<further-classification>362600</further-classification>
<further-classification>362613</further-classification>
<further-classification>362615</further-classification>
<further-classification>362617</further-classification>
<further-classification>362621</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e61">Backlight module</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0254260</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Li</name>
<date>20051100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0126361</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Chang et al.</name>
<date>20060600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0139967</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Peng</name>
<date>20070600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362617</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>M268608</doc-number>
<date>20050600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>I251701</doc-number>
<date>20060300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>200641470</doc-number>
<date>20061200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>M306335</doc-number>
<date>20070200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>200725080</doc-number>
<date>20070700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>201017286</doc-number>
<date>20100500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-cpc-text>G02F 1/335</classification-cpc-text>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>10</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362600-622</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>9</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kuan</last-name>
<first-name>Yu-Chieh</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsin-Chu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liu</last-name>
<first-name>Yung-Chih</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsin-Chu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kuan</last-name>
<first-name>Yu-Chieh</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsin-Chu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liu</last-name>
<first-name>Yung-Chih</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsin-Chu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>WPAT, PC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>King</last-name>
<first-name>Justin</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>AU Optronics Corp.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Hsin-Chu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Raleigh</last-name>
<first-name>Donald</first-name>
<department>2879</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A backlight module includes a light source, a light guide plate and at least one optical film. The light source has a plurality of light emitting devices. The light guide plate includes a light entrance portion, a main body portion and at least one positioning structure. The light entrance portion has a top surface and a light entrance surface. The light source is disposed corresponding to the light entrance surface. The top surface is adjacently connected to the light entrance surface. The main body is connected to the light entrance portion and has a first light extraction surface connecting the top surface. The positioning structure is disposed on the top surface and corresponding to an interval between two adjacent light emitting devices, and has an accommodating space. The optical film is disposed above the light guide plate and has at least one protruding portion disposed in the accommodating space.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="171.79mm" wi="169.16mm" file="US08622603-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="197.53mm" wi="173.74mm" file="US08622603-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="184.91mm" wi="177.55mm" file="US08622603-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="248.67mm" wi="169.16mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622603-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="197.87mm" wi="174.07mm" file="US08622603-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="185.25mm" wi="178.99mm" file="US08622603-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="248.33mm" wi="161.46mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622603-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="201.08mm" wi="173.06mm" file="US08622603-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="242.40mm" wi="165.69mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622603-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="202.44mm" wi="177.21mm" file="US08622603-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to a backlight module, and more particularly to a backlight module having a positioning structure for optical films.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">While electronic industry keeps developing, liquid crystal displays (LCDs) have become the mainstream of present market. Since the LCD panel is not a self-emitting device, a backlight module is needed to provide light to the LCD panel, thus achieving the purpose of image displaying.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">According to some requirements coming from the market, the design trend of bezel for LCD module is towards narrower and the LCD module keeps enlarging its size and widening its viewing angle. Such requirements have to be taken into the consideration on designing of the components in the backlight module. For example, in order to install optical films to the backlight module, positioning structures (such as fixing corners) are disposed on the frame of the backlight module for fixing and positioning the optical films, and avoiding the displacement of the optical films which leads to downgrade of the optical performance.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">However, the above mentioned fixing corners on the frame are usually located at two sides of the LCD module. When the backlight module is illuminating, shadows are formed by the fixing corners on the two sides of the screen of the LCD module. Such shadows directly affect the displaying quality of the LCD module.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The present invention provides a backlight module including a light source, a light guide plate and at least one optical film. The light source has a plurality of light emitting devices. The light guide plate includes a light entrance portion, a main body portion and at least one positioning structure. The light entrance portion has a top surface and a light entrance surface. The light source is disposed corresponding to the light entrance surface. The top surface is adjacently connected to the light entrance surface. The main body portion is connected to the light entrance portion and has a first light extraction surface, and the first light extraction surface is connected to the top surface. The at least one positioning structure is disposed on the top surface of the light entrance portion. The positioning structure is disposed corresponding to an interval between two adjacent light emitting devices. The positioning structure has an accommodating space. The at least one optical film is disposed above the light guide plate. The optical film has at least one protruding portion disposed in the accommodating space.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The present invention will become more readily apparent to those ordinarily skilled in the art after reviewing the following detailed description and accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a top view of a backlight module according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a magnified view of an area circled by dashed line Z in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a cross sectional view along a line A-A in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a three-dimensional view showing the structure of the backlight module according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> is a top view of the backlight module according to another embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref> is a top view showing each one of the optical films in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref> is a top view of the backlight module according to another embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref> is a cross sectional view along a line K-K in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a top view of the backlight module according to another embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The present invention will now be described more specifically with reference to the following embodiments. It is to be noted that the following descriptions of preferred embodiments of this invention are presented herein for purpose of illustration and description only. It is not intended to be exhaustive or to be limited to the precise form disclosed.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, which is a top view of a backlight module according to an embodiment of the present invention. As <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows, the backlight module <b>1</b> includes a light source <b>10</b>, a light guide plate <b>11</b> and at least one optical film <b>12</b>. The light source <b>10</b> has a plurality of light emitting devices <b>100</b>. The light guide plate <b>11</b> includes a light entrance portion <b>110</b>, a main body portion <b>111</b> and at least one positioning structure <b>112</b>. The light entrance portion <b>110</b> has a top surface <b>1101</b> and a light entrance surface <b>1102</b>. The light source <b>10</b> is disposed corresponding to the light entrance surface <b>1102</b>. The top surface <b>1101</b> is adjacently connected to the light entrance surface <b>1102</b>. The main body portion <b>111</b> is connected to the light entrance portion <b>110</b>. The main body portion <b>111</b> has a first light extraction surface <b>1110</b>. The first light extraction surface <b>1110</b> is connected to the top surface <b>1101</b> of the light entrance portion <b>110</b>. The positioning structure <b>112</b> is arranged on the top surface <b>1101</b> of the light entrance portion <b>110</b>. The positioning structure <b>112</b> is disposed corresponding to an interval between two adjacent ones of the light emitting devices <b>100</b>. The positioning structure <b>112</b> has an accommodating space <b>1120</b>. The optical film <b>12</b> is disposed above the light guide plate <b>11</b>. The optical film <b>12</b> has at least one protruding portion <b>120</b>. The protruding portion <b>120</b> is disposed in the accommodating space <b>1120</b> of the positioning structure <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In this embodiment of the backlight module <b>1</b>, since the positioning structure <b>112</b> is disposed corresponding to the interval between the two adjacent ones of the light emitting devices <b>100</b>, the structure design has an advantage that the positioning structure <b>112</b> does not block the light emitted from the light emitting device <b>100</b>, thus avoiding the shadows formed by the positioning structure <b>112</b> blocking the light emitted from the light emitting device <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Following the mentioned above, as <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows, the optical film <b>12</b> of this embodiment further has a base plate <b>121</b>. The base plate <b>121</b> has a second light extraction surface <b>122</b> and a side surface <b>123</b> connecting to the second light extraction surface <b>122</b>. The protruding portion <b>120</b> of the optical film <b>12</b> is, for example, located at the side surface <b>123</b>, but not limited thereto in the present invention. Besides, the number of the protruding portions <b>120</b> of the optical film <b>12</b> is four in this figure. For accommodating the protruding portions <b>120</b>, the number of the positioning structures <b>112</b> is also four in this figure, but not limited thereto in the present invention. The increase and decrease of the number of the positioning structures <b>112</b> depend on the number of the protruding portions <b>120</b>. In other words, if the number of the protruding portion <b>120</b> is one, then the number of the positioning structure <b>112</b> is also one.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, which is a magnified view of an area circled by dashed line Z in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. As <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows, the positioning structure <b>112</b> further has a first surface <b>1121</b>, a second surface <b>1122</b> and a third surface <b>1123</b>. The second surface <b>1122</b> and the third surface <b>1123</b> respectively extend from two ends of the first surface <b>1121</b> and along the direction toward the main body portion <b>111</b> of the light guide plate <b>11</b>. The first surface <b>1121</b>, the second surface <b>1122</b> and the third surface <b>1123</b> of the positioning structure <b>112</b> define the accommodating space <b>1120</b>. As <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows, in this embodiment, the first surface <b>1121</b>, the second surface <b>1122</b> and the third surface <b>1123</b> of the positioning structure <b>112</b> are, for example, in a U-shaped arrangement.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, which is a cross sectional view along a line A-A in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. As <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows, in this embodiment of the backlight module <b>1</b>, the light entrance portion <b>110</b> further has a bottom surface <b>1103</b> opposite to the top surface <b>1101</b>. The distance between the bottom surface <b>1103</b> and the top surface <b>1101</b> for example gradually decreases along the direction E away from the light entrance surface <b>1102</b>. For example, as <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows, the distance between a point B on the top surface <b>1101</b> of the light entrance portion <b>110</b> and the bottom surface <b>1103</b> of the light entrance portion <b>110</b> is D<b>1</b>, and the distance between a point C on the top surface <b>1101</b> of the light entrance portion <b>110</b> and the bottom surface <b>1103</b> of the light entrance portion <b>110</b> is D<b>2</b>. As can be clearly seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the distance D<b>1</b> between the top surface <b>1101</b> of the light entrance portion <b>110</b> and the bottom surface <b>1103</b> is greater than the distance D<b>2</b>. The distance D<b>1</b> between the top surface <b>1101</b> of the light entrance portion <b>110</b> and the bottom surface <b>1103</b> gradually decreases to the distance D<b>2</b> along the direction E away from the light entrance surface <b>1102</b>. More specifically, the top surface <b>1101</b> of the light entrance portion <b>110</b> is, for example, an inclined surface. The shape of the light entrance portion <b>110</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is merely one of the embodiments of the present invention, and not limited thereto in the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Please refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> again. As <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows, the positioning structures <b>112</b> of this embodiment, for example, protrude from the top surface <b>1101</b> of the light entrance portion <b>110</b>. As <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows, the width of the positioning structure <b>112</b> gradually decreases along the direction E away from the light entrance surface <b>1102</b>. For example, as <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows, the length of the line segment I-J represents the first width W<b>1</b> of the positioning structure <b>112</b> and the length of the line segment G-H represents the second width W<b>2</b> of the positioning structure <b>112</b>. As can be clearly seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the first width W<b>1</b> of the positioning structure <b>112</b> is greater than the second width W<b>2</b>. The first width W<b>1</b> of the positioning structure <b>112</b> gradually decreases to the width W<b>2</b> along the direction E away from the light entrance surface <b>1102</b>. The shape of the positioning structure <b>112</b> is merely one of the embodiments of the present invention, and not limited thereto in the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In order to more clearly show the structure of every components of the backlight module <b>1</b> and the positioning relationship thereof in this embodiment, the structure of the backlight module <b>1</b> of this embodiment can be referred to a three dimensional view in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. It should be mentioned that in this figure, in order to clearly demonstrate the outer appearance of the positioning structure <b>112</b> and the positioning relationship between the positioning structure <b>112</b> and the other components, the optical film <b>12</b> is omitted. The connecting relationship between the optical film <b>12</b> and the positioning structure <b>112</b> can be specifically described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and other embodiments below.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> is a top view of the backlight module according to another embodiment of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref> is top view showing each one of the optical films in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>. The backlight module <b>1</b><i>a </i>of this embodiment is similar to the backlight module <b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The difference is that, as shows in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>, the backlight module <b>1</b><i>a </i>of this embodiment includes a plurality of optical films <b>12</b><i>a</i>, <b>12</b><i>b</i>, and <b>12</b><i>c</i>. The dimensions of the optical films <b>12</b><i>a</i>, <b>12</b><i>b</i>, and <b>12</b><i>c </i>are, for example, substantially the same. The optical films <b>12</b><i>a</i>, <b>12</b><i>b</i>, and <b>12</b><i>c </i>have protruding portions <b>120</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>b</i>, and <b>120</b><i>c</i>, respectively. As <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> shows, the backlight module <b>1</b><i>a </i>of this embodiment includes positioning structures <b>112</b><i>a</i>, <b>112</b><i>b</i>, and <b>112</b><i>c</i>. The optical films <b>12</b><i>a</i>, <b>12</b><i>b</i>, <b>12</b><i>c </i>are sequentially stacked from bottom to top on the light extraction surface <b>1110</b> of the light guide plate <b>11</b> (the optical film <b>12</b><i>c </i>is the top optical film). The protruding portion <b>120</b><i>a </i>of the optical film <b>12</b><i>a </i>is disposed in the accommodating space <b>1120</b><i>a </i>of the positioning structure <b>112</b><i>a</i>. The protruding portion <b>120</b><i>b </i>of the optical film <b>12</b><i>b </i>is disposed in the accommodating space <b>1120</b><i>b </i>of the positioning structure <b>112</b><i>b</i>. The protruding portion <b>120</b><i>c </i>of the optical film <b>12</b><i>c </i>is disposed in the accommodating space <b>1120</b><i>c </i>of the positioning structure <b>112</b><i>c</i>. In other words, the accommodating space of one of the positioning structures <b>112</b><i>a</i>, <b>112</b><i>b </i>and <b>112</b><i>c </i>only accommodates the protruding portion of one of the optical films <b>12</b><i>a</i>, <b>12</b><i>b </i>and <b>12</b><i>c</i>. Therefore, after the optical films <b>12</b><i>a</i>, <b>12</b><i>b </i>and <b>12</b><i>c </i>are sequentially stacked, it can be clearly recognized that the protruding portions <b>120</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>b </i>and <b>120</b><i>c </i>of the optical films <b>12</b><i>a</i>, <b>12</b><i>b </i>and <b>12</b><i>c </i>are respectively and securely fixed by the positioning structures <b>112</b><i>a</i>, <b>112</b><i>b </i>and <b>112</b><i>c</i>. There is not any one of the optical films which is neglected to be fixed. The other components in this figure are the same as <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows and thus not repeated herein.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref> is a top view of the backlight module according to another embodiment of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref> is a cross sectional view along a line K-K in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref>. As <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref> shows, the backlight module <b>1</b><i>b </i>of the embodiment is similar to the backlight module <b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The difference is that the positioning structure <b>112</b><i>d </i>of the backlight module <b>1</b><i>b </i>further has a fourth surface <b>1124</b>. The fourth surface <b>1124</b> is connected to the first surface <b>1121</b>, the second surface <b>1122</b> and the third surface <b>1123</b> (the second surface <b>1122</b> and the third surface <b>1123</b> shown as <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). The fourth surface <b>1124</b> overlaps the protruding portion <b>120</b> of the optical film <b>12</b>. The advantage of the fourth surface <b>1124</b> of the positioning structure <b>112</b><i>d </i>of this embodiment is that when the protruding portion <b>120</b> of the optical film <b>12</b> is disposed in the accommodating space <b>1120</b> of the positioning structure <b>112</b><i>d</i>, since the fourth surface <b>1124</b> overlaps the protruding portion <b>120</b> of the optical film <b>12</b>, the optical film <b>12</b> is more firmly fixed on the first light extraction surface <b>1110</b> of the light guide plate <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, which is a top view of the backlight module according to another embodiment of the present invention. As <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows, the backlight module <b>1</b><i>c </i>is similar to the backlight module <b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The difference is that the light guide plate <b>11</b><i>c </i>of the backlight module <b>1</b><i>c </i>further includes a plurality of protruding structures <b>13</b>. The protruding structures <b>13</b> are disposed on the light entrance surface <b>1102</b> of the light entrance portion <b>110</b>. Each one of the light emitting devices <b>100</b> of the light source <b>10</b> is located between two adjacent ones of the protruding structures <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In conclusion, the backlight module disclosed by the embodiments of the present invention, in which the light guide plate has at least one positioning structure. The positioning structure is disposed on the top surface of the light entrance portion of the light guide plate, and the positioning structure is disposed corresponding to the interval between two adjacent ones of the light emitting devices. Under this structural design, the protruding portions of the optical films can be directly disposed in the accommodating spaces of the positioning structures. There is no need to dispose a position structure on the frame for fixing the optical film. Moreover, since the positioning structure is disposed corresponding to the interval between two adjacent ones of the light emitting devices, the positioning structures do not block the light emitted from the light emitting devices. Therefore, the shadows formed by the positioning structure on the frame can be avoided, the function of the alignment in assembly can be remained and the displacement of the optical films can be avoided.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">While the invention has been described in terms of what is presently considered to be the most practical and preferred embodiments, it is to be understood that the invention needs not be limited to the disclosed embodiment. On the contrary, it is intended to cover various modifications and similar arrangements included within the spirit and scope of the appended claims which are to be accorded with the broadest interpretation so as to encompass all such modifications and similar structures.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A backlight module, comprising:
<claim-text>a light source having a plurality of light emitting devices;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light guide plate comprising:
<claim-text>a light entrance portion having a top surface and a light entrance surface, wherein the light source is disposed corresponding to the light entrance surface, and the top surface is adjacently connected to the light entrance surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a main body portion connected to the light entrance portion and having a first light extraction surface, the first light extraction surface being connected to the top surface; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one positioning structure disposed on the top surface of the light entrance portion, the positioning structure being disposed corresponding to an interval between two adjacent ones of the light emitting devices, the positioning structure having an accommodating space; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one optical film disposed above the light guide plate, the optical film having at least one protruding portion, the protruding portion being disposed in the accommodating space.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The backlight module according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the positioning structure further has a first surface, a second surface and a third surface, the second surface and the third surface respectively extend from two sides of the first surface and along the direction toward the main body portion, and the first surface, the second surface and the third surface define the accommodating space.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The backlight module according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the positioning structure further has a fourth surface connected to the first surface, the second surface and the third surface, and the fourth surface overlaps the protruding portion of the optical film.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The backlight module according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the first surface, the second surface and the third surface are in a U-shaped arrangement.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The backlight module according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the optical film further has a base plate, the base plate has a second light extraction surface and a side surface connecting to the second light extraction surface, and the protruding portion of the optical films is located at the side surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The backlight module according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the numbers of the at least one optical film and the at least one positioning structure are respectively plural, and the accommodating space of each one of the positioning structures only accommodates the protruding portion of one of the optical films.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The backlight module according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the numbers of the at least one protruding portion of the optical film and the at least one positioning structure are respectively plural, and the protruding portions of the optical film are respectively disposed in the accommodating spaces of the positioning structures.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The backlight module according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the light guide plate further includes a plurality of protruding structures disposed on the light entrance surface of the light entrance portion, and each one of the light emitting devices is located between two adjacent ones of the protruding structures.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The backlight module according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the light entrance portion further includes a bottom surface opposite to the top surface, and the distance between the top surface and the bottom surface gradually decreases along a direction away from the light entrance surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The backlight module according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the positioning structure protrudes from the top surface of the light entrance portion, and the width of the positioning structure gradually decreases along the direction away from the light entrance surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
