<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625559-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625559</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13217457</doc-number>
<date>20110825</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>139</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20090101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>W</subclass>
<main-group>4</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>370338</main-classification>
<further-classification>455103</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">System and method for enhancing personal device communication capabilities using modified battery module</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6456036</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Thandiwe</name>
<date>20020900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>320106</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0068034</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Silvester</name>
<date>20030400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>37943312</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0083058</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Mayer</name>
<date>20030500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>455422</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0263117</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kogan et al.</name>
<date>20041200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>320114</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0206627</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Wright</name>
<date>20080800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>429 93</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0111501</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Tang et al.</name>
<date>20090400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>455522</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0161257</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Cornett et al.</name>
<date>20100600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>702 63</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0329181</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lan</name>
<date>20101200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>370328</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>16</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>13</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>61376849</doc-number>
<date>20100825</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120051347</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120301</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kumar</last-name>
<first-name>Prem Jothipragasam</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Diego</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>O'Neil</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas</first-name>
<address>
<city>La Jolla</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hughes</last-name>
<first-name>Robbin David</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Diego</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kumar</last-name>
<first-name>Prem Jothipragasam</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Diego</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>O'Neil</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas</first-name>
<address>
<city>La Jolla</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hughes</last-name>
<first-name>Robbin David</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Diego</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Shah</last-name>
<first-name>Chirag</first-name>
<department>2477</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Pancholi</last-name>
<first-name>Rina</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">One or more embodiments of the present invention disclose a system and method for enhancing the communication capabilities of a personal electronic device by modifying its existing battery module, adding communication circuitry to the modified module, and providing for the personal device to communicate in a Wireless Wide Area Network (WWAN) via this modified battery module. The system and method consists of a personal device's existing battery pack modified to contain one or more wireless communication circuits, the wireless communication circuitry included in the modified battery module, and the method by which the personal device will communicate to the WWAN using the modified battery module. The system can also be used to re-distribute WWAN communication from the modified battery module, to one or more external personal devices, using near-field communications.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="177.46mm" wi="226.48mm" file="US08625559-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="140.89mm" wi="188.13mm" file="US08625559-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="231.73mm" wi="173.99mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625559-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="235.37mm" wi="180.93mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625559-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="214.12mm" wi="173.06mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625559-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="228.68mm" wi="175.43mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625559-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="226.65mm" wi="176.70mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625559-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present application is based on, and claims priority from, U.S. Provisional Application No. 61/376,849, filed Aug. 25, 2011, the disclosure of which is hereby incorporated by referenced herein in its entirety.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Currently, personal devices are manufactured and sold containing a finite set of wireless communication methods. This set can be null, that is, the personal device has no communication capability, or it can have a limited number of communication methods.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">However, after time of sale, the user may require an additional or newly fielded communication method which was beyond the capability of the personal device at the time of sale.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Or, it may be found that the existing communication capability of the personal device does not provide adequate connectivity, or subjects the user or network carrier to roaming charges or other expensive fees. In either case, to overcome these limitations, the user currently must purchase an entirely new personal device containing the required additional communication methods.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">One or more embodiments are illustrated by way of example, and not by limitation, in the figures of the accompanying drawings, wherein elements having the same reference numeral designations represent like elements throughout and wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a high-level functional block diagram of a personal device containing an unmodified battery module assembly;</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a high-level functional block diagram of a personal device containing a battery module assembly which has been modified to include communication circuitry, according to an embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a high-level functional block diagram of a personal device with modified battery, according to an embodiment of the invention, illustrating one method by which the personal device may use the modified battery to communicate with the WWAN;</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a decision-flow diagram of processing in a personal device with modified battery, according to an embodiment of the invention, illustrating one method by which the personal device may decide to use the modified battery to communicate with the WWAN;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a decision-flow diagram of processing in a personal device with modified battery, according to another embodiment of the invention, illustrating another method by which the personal device may decide to use the modified battery to communicate with the WWAN; and</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a high-level functional block diagram of a personal device with modified battery, according to one embodiment of the invention, illustrating one method by which the modified battery in the hosting personal device, may be used to redistribute the communication with the WWAN, to one or multiple external personal devices, using near-field communication.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">One or more embodiments of the present invention provide a way to update or extend the communication capability of the personal device without the user or carrier having to purchase an entirely new personal device.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Using one or more embodiments, a user may purchase, or be provided by a carrier, a modified battery pack containing the additional communication method. The personal device then uses the circuitry contained in the modified battery pack to communicate to the WWAN, instead of or in addition to its current capability.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">For instance, when a new communication method such as 4<sup>th</sup>-Generation (4 G) Wireless is fielded by the carrier, the existing personal device containing only2<sup>nd-</sup>Generation or 3<sup>rd-</sup>Gen Wireless capability need not be rendered obsolete. Instead, a modified battery pack containing 4 G Wireless communication circuitry may be inserted in the existing personal device, such that the personal device now can utilize 4 G Wireless communication capability. The same method can be used to provide a 4 G Wireless device with second generation or third generation WWAN capabilities, where the WWAN modem in the battery pack adds to the WWAN capabilities of the device.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> depicts a high-level functional block diagram of a personal device <b>100</b> in which an embodiment of the present invention may be incorporated. The personal device is portable, meaning it is powered by a battery module <b>104</b> containing control and charging circuitry <b>105</b>, with the majority of the battery volume of the assembly taken up by energy storage cells <b>106</b> using chemical technology such as Lithium-Ion or Nickel-Cadmium, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In portable personal devices, the battery assembly usually forms a removable module <b>104</b> contained within a distinct battery compartment <b>102</b>. The battery module usually can be removed either by hand manipulation, or using simple tools. The reason for this modularity is that the battery assembly sometimes requires replacement. The storage cells or control circuitry may fail, may need updating to increase capacity, or may need replacing to reduce weight and size through technology improvements.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The personal device may have been manufactured containing a set of one or more methods of communication <b>103</b> with the Internet, Wireless WWAN, or other personal devices. Examples of communication methods built into the personal device at time of manufacture include (1) Telecommunications Industry Association (TIA) standard Ev-DO, revisions 0, A, and B; (2) Third-Generation Partnership Project (3GPP) standard UMTS and its variations High-Speed Packet Data (HSPA); (3) 3rd Generation Partnership Project 2 (3GPP2) standard IS-2000; (4) Groupe Special Mobile standard Global System for Mobile Communications (GSM) and its variation Enhanced Data rates for GSM Evolution (EDGE); (5) Bluetooth; and (6) Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) 802.11 Wireless LAN (aka &#x201c;WiFi&#x201d;).</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The set of communication capabilities <b>103</b> built into the personal device during manufacture and at time of sale, are usually fixed, that is, the electronics implementing these communication capabilities are not removable and cannot be replaced or upgraded easily.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">After time of sale, the user may require an additional or newly-fielded communication method which was beyond the capability of the personal device at the time of sale. Or, it may be found that the existing communication capability <b>103</b> of the personal device does not provide adequate connectivity, or subjects the user or network carrier to roaming charges or other expensive fees.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">To overcome these limitations without the invention described in one or more embodiments of this disclosure, the user currently must purchase an entirely new personal device containing the required additional communication methods.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">For instance, if an owner of a personal device containing only EvDO (a &#x201c;3rd-Generation&#x201d; wireless Internet access technology) needs to access the Internet using the newly-fielded Long-Term-Evolution (LTE) standard, there is currently no easy way for the owner of the personal device to accomplish this, unless an entirely-new personal device containing hardware which implements the LTE standard is purchased.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">This can be costly for the user, and wasteful of otherwise useful personal device hardware. The personal device may contain a high-cost and high-performance display, keypad, memory, audio and video camera hardware, and be in perfect working order for some communication uses. But for want of the set of newly-required communication capabilities, the entire device may be rendered obsolete and in need of replacement.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> depicts a high-level functional block diagram of a personal device <b>200</b> as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, but in which an embodiment of the present invention has been incorporated. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the removable battery assembly <b>204</b> has been modified to incorporate an additional set of communication methods (<b>207</b>, <b>208</b>) using circuitry (<b>207</b>, <b>208</b>, <b>209</b>, <b>210</b>) designed to fit within the volume footprint of the battery assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The additional communication circuitry (<b>207</b>, <b>208</b>) inserted into the battery assembly may include Radio Frequency (RF) power amplifiers (PA), low-noise receiver amplifiers (LNA), frequency down-converters and digitizing hardware, baseband processing microprocessors and other discrete circuitry, and antennas (<b>209</b>, <b>210</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the set of communication methods (<b>207</b>, <b>208</b>) include circuits designed to implement near-field communication <b>208</b> between the modified battery module and hosting personal device, as well as circuits designed to implement various WWAN standards <b>209</b>. Examples of WWAN standards implemented by the modified battery <b>200</b> may include 3GPP Long-Term Evolution (LTE) and TIA standard EvDO. Examples of near-field communication implemented by the modified battery <b>200</b> may include Bluetooth or 802.11 Wireless LAN.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The additional communication circuitry (<b>207</b>, <b>208</b>, <b>209</b>, <b>210</b>) inserted into the battery assembly is powered by the battery cells <b>206</b> and control circuitry <b>205</b>, as is the hosting personal device. To accommodate the additional communication circuitry (<b>207</b>, <b>208</b>, <b>209</b>, <b>210</b>), the battery's chemical cell <b>206</b> size has been reduced, resulting in somewhat reduced battery capacity and resulting increased frequency of charging the personal device required.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> depicts a high-level functional block diagram of a personal device <b>300</b> as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, but illustrating how one embodiment of the present invention has been incorporated and is used by the hosting personal device.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Following <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, in one example embodiment, the personal device connects to the modified battery module using IEEE 802.11 Wireless LAN <b>320</b>. The modified battery module communicates to the WWAN <b>310</b> using Long-Term Evolution (LTE), which in this example the personal device <b>300</b> did not support at time of manufacture. In this embodiment, the modified battery effectively presents a WiFi &#x201c;hotspot&#x201d; for the personal device to initiate and continue a TCP/IP data connection to the Internet using the LTE WWAN.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Also following <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, in another example embodiment, the personal device connects to the modified battery module using Bluetooth Near Field Communication (NFC) <b>300</b>. The modified battery module communicates to the WWAN <b>310</b> using 1X-CDMA2000. In this example, the personal station only supports GSM circuit-switched calls. In this embodiment, the modified battery effectively presents a way for the personal device to initiate and continue a circuit-switched telephone connection. In this example, the personal station avoids expensive roaming charges over a non-Home GSM network when there is a Home CDMA2000 network available to use.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> depicts a high-level decision-tree diagram <b>400</b> illustrating how, in one embodiment of the present invention, the personal device and modified battery pair as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>2</b> and <b>3</b>, may decide when to use either the host device's communication circuitry, or the modified battery's communication circuitry, to provide service to the user.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Following <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, in one example embodiment, when the personal device is powered on <b>401</b>, the personal device and modified battery both attempt to acquire service <b>402</b>. Subsequently, the personal device acquires Service A, while the modified battery acquires Service B. Service A and B may be one of a set of communication methods such as, but not limited to: No Service, CDMA-2000, GSM/EDGE, EvDO, UMTS/HSPA, LTE, or other wireless communication technology.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">After both personal device and modified battery acquire service, software implementing decision criteria (<b>404</b>, <b>405</b>), contained within either the personal device, or modified battery, or both, makes note of the signal strength and roam status of both Service A and Service B.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In the first decision criteria evaluation <b>404</b>, if Service A's roam status is TRUE (Roaming on non-Home system) or signal strength is weak, a further decision criteria <b>405</b> is evaluated, that is, if Service B's roam status is TRUE (Roaming on non-Home system) signal strength is weak.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, if Roam status of Service A is FALSE (in Home system not roaming), and if Service A's signal strength is strong (not weak), the personal device will use Service A to provide service to the user (action block <b>407</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Also in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, if Roam status of Service B is TRUE (Roaming on non-Home system), or if Service B's signal strength is weak (not strong), the personal device will still use Service A to provide service to the user (action block <b>407</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Finally, in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, if Roam status of Service A is TRUE (Roaming on non-Home system) or if Service A's signal strength is weak (not strong), AND, if the Roam status of Service B is FALSE (in Home system not roaming), and if Service B's signal strength is strong (not weak), the personal device will use Service B to provide service to the user (action block <b>406</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> depicts a high-level decision-tree diagram <b>500</b> illustrating, in another embodiment of the present invention, how a personal device and modified battery pair as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>2</b> and <b>3</b>, may decide when to use either the host device's communication circuitry, or the modified battery's communication circuitry, to provide service to the user.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Following <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, in another example embodiment, when the personal device is powered on <b>501</b>, the personal device and modified battery both attempt to acquire service. Subsequently, the personal device acquires Service A, while the modified battery acquires Service B (<b>502</b>). Service A and B may be one of a set of communication methods such as, but not limited to: No Service, CDMA-2000, GSM/EDGE, EvDO, UMTS/HSPA, LTE, or other wireless communication technology.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">After both personal device and modified battery acquire service <b>502</b>, software implementing decision criteria (<b>504</b>, <b>505</b>), contained within either the personal device, or modified battery, or both, makes note of the relative preference (to user or carrier), and instantaneous data performance inherent in both Service A and Service B (<b>503</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Then, in a first decision criterion <b>504</b> if Service B uses a technology which is preferred to Service A, a further decision criteria <b>505</b> is evaluated, that is, the instantaneous data service performance adequacy (such as serving data rate capability for example) of Service B relative to some minimum performance criterion.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> depicts a high-level functional block diagram of a personal device <b>600</b> as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, but illustrating one method by which the modified battery in the hosting personal device, may be used to redistribute the communication with the WWAN, to one or multiple external devices, using near-field communication.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Following <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, in one example embodiment, the personal device connects to the modified battery module using IEEE 802.11 Wireless LAN or Bluetooth <b>620</b>. The modified battery module communicates to the WWAN <b>610</b> using Long-Term Evolution (LTE), which in this example the personal device <b>600</b> did not support at time of manufacture. In this embodiment, the modified battery effectively presents a WiFi or Bluetooth &#x201c;hotspot&#x201d; for both the hosting personal device <b>600</b>, and one or multiple external personal devices <b>630</b>, to initiate and continue a TCP/IP data connection to the Internet using the LTE WWAN.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A modified removable battery module inserted into a portable personal device, the modified removable battery module comprising:
<claim-text>a set of modified battery cells each of said cells having a corresponding control and a charging circuit, wherein the corresponding control and the charging circuit are physically located on the modified removable battery module;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an additional set of communication circuitry physically located on the modified removable battery module comprising:
<claim-text>a communication processing device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first communication interface coupled with said communication processing device, the first communication interface arranged to communicate with the portable personal device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a memory coupled with said communication processing device and configured to store instructions i of a communication device control system; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second communication interface coupled with said communication processing device, the second communication interface is configured to communicate with a wireless wide area communication network; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>an enclosure housing sized to fit within a battery compartment of the portable personal device and configured to receive the set of modified battery cells, the corresponding control, the charging circuit, and the additional set of communication circuitry;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the communication device control system decides when to use a communication interface of the portable personal device outside the modified removable battery module and the second communication interface of the modified removable battery module to provide a network service to a user of the portable personal device based on a decision criteria.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The modified removable battery module as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second communication interface is a cellular-based communication network.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The modified removable battery module as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first communication interface is a near field communication interface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The modified removable battery module as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the near field communication interface comprises at least one of BLUETOOTH, and 802.11 Wireless LAN (WiFi), wherein said modified removable battery module is configured to initiate and continue a circuit switched telephone connection.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The modified removable battery module comprising the added communication circuitry as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the modified removable battery module is sized to fit within the battery compartment of the portable personal device resulting in increased frequency of charging of said portable personal device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The modified removable battery module comprising the added communication circuitry as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the modified removable battery module is designed to provide power to acquire services, to at least one of the portable personal device, and to the communication circuitry added to the modified removable battery module.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The communication device control system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said system is further configured to control allocation of one or more components of a communication service with the portable personal device via the first communication interface physically located on the modified removable battery module.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The communication device control system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said modified removable battery module is configured to enable at least one of a Wi-Fi hotspot and Blue-tooth hotspot to continue a data connection between a first communication interface physically located on the modified removable battery module and a communication interface of the portable personal device outside the modified removable battery.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The modified removable battery module as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the additional set of communication circuitry is configured to increase frequency of charging of said portable personal device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The modified removable battery module as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said module is configured to initiate and continue a circuit switched telephone connection.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The modified removable battery module as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said the decision criteria comprises to determine instantaneous data performance in a service carrier.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The modified removable battery module as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said the decision criteria comprises to rate performance adequacy of a service carrier.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A method of managing communication between a portable personal device, and a communication device control system physically located on a modified removable battery module, the method comprising:
<claim-text>allocating communication connections, by said modified removable battery module in the communication device control system, between a first communication interface physically located on the modified removable battery module and a communication interface of the portable personal device outside the modified removable battery, based on at least one of a user preference or the communication device control system attribute or the portable personal device system attribute; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>deciding when to use a communication interface of said portable personal device outside the modified removable battery module and a communication interface physically located on said modified removable battery module to provide service to a user of the portable personal device,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the modified battery module is inserted into the portable personal device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising: the modified removable battery module using a set of criterion to decide when to use a communication interface of said portable personal device outside the modified removable battery module and a communication interface physically located on said modified removable battery module to provide service to a user of the portable personal device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the set of criterion comprises wireless communication network availability, wireless communication network cost, performance characteristics, and inherent characteristics of the communication capabilities of the portable personal device and the modified removable battery module inserted into the portable personal device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the modified removable battery module in the portable personal device, redistributes the communication between a first communication interface physically located on the modified removable battery module and a communication interface of the portable personal device outside the modified removable battery with Wireless Wide Area Network (WWAN), to one or multiple external personal devices, using near-field communication. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
