<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624554-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624554</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13228151</doc-number>
<date>20110908</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>323</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>M</subclass>
<main-group>10</main-group>
<subgroup>46</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>320114</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Solar bracelet</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3910257</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Fletcher et al.</name>
<date>19751000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>600483</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8459825</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Trzecieski</name>
<date>20130600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362157</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0251888</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Douglas</name>
<date>20091000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362103</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0308725</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Trzecieski</name>
<date>20101200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>315 32</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>18</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>320101</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>320107</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>320112</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>320114</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>320115</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362103</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362104</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>136243</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>136245</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>136251</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>136291</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>61487051</doc-number>
<date>20110517</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120293107</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121122</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ajagbe</last-name>
<first-name>Adebowale</first-name>
<address>
<city>Detroit</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ajagbe</last-name>
<first-name>Adebowale</first-name>
<address>
<city>Detroit</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Gifford, Krass, Sprinkle, Anderson &#x26; Citkowski, P.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chau</last-name>
<first-name>John</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Tso</last-name>
<first-name>Edward</first-name>
<department>2859</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A device configured to be worn around the wrist of a user and operable to charge an electrical device is provided. The device includes a cover and a band. The band is adapted to be worn around a wrist of a user. The cover may be adapted to mount onto the band. The band having a storage space configured for holding electrical components operable to store and discharge electrical power, such as a battery. The device further includes an output operable to connect the battery to an electrical device so as to charge the electrical device.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="130.56mm" wi="283.55mm" file="US08624554-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="240.79mm" wi="169.50mm" file="US08624554-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="236.98mm" wi="178.56mm" file="US08624554-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Application 61/487,051 filed on May 17, 2011, the disclosure of which is incorporated by reference herein in its entirety.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The invention relates to a device worn on the wrist of a user operable to harness solar energy and other renewable energy sources by which passive or active use of the device is operable to store energy for later use with an electrical device such as a cellular phone.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The use of solar energy to charge a cellular phone is currently known and used. However, such devices are stand-alone stationary devices such as a docking station. The docking station is operable to connect the cellular phone so as to charge the cellular phone. Accordingly, it remains desirable to have a device which may be worn as part of the user's outfit and is conveniently located so as to allow the user to operate a cellular phone while charging the cellular phone simultaneously while on the go.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">According to one aspect of the invention, a device having solar cells and a battery for storing solar power. The device further includes a cover and a band. The band is adapted to be worn around a wrist of a user. The cover may be adapted to mount onto the band. The band includes a storage space configured for holding electrical components operable to store and discharge electrical power.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The device includes a battery adapted to store and discharge electrical power, and at least one solar cell operable to transform light into electrical power. The solar cell is in electrical communication with the battery and operable to charge the battery. The device may further include an electrical circuit operable to control the charge and discharge of electricity to and from the battery.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The storage space may further contain an electrical chord and a mechanism operable to retract the electrical chord. The electrical chord may include an end portion adapted to engage power input of an electrical device, such as a cellular phone.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In a first preferred embodiment, the cover encircles the band. The cover includes a plurality of solar cells. The solar cells are electrically wired to the battery so as to charge the battery. Electrical power from the solar cells may be filtered through an electrical circuit operable to control charging of the battery. The electrical circuit may also control the discharging of the electrical power stored in the battery.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The covers may be decorated with design and indicia. The solar cells may be colored so as to present an aesthetically pleasing accessory for wear with an outfit. The covers may be removed from the band so as to allow the user to change covers according to the user's choice. In one embodiment, the device may include a fastening device such as a clasp, operable to secure the cover with respect to the band.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The device may further include an electrical energy generating mechanism operable to transform movement into electrical energy, such as an auxiliary device. Specifically, the auxiliary device converts the swaying of a user's arm into electricity. The auxiliary device may also be wired to the battery so as to charge the battery.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The band includes in first surface and a second surface. The first surface of the band is covered by the cover, and the second surface of the band is exposed to the wrist of a user when worn. The storage space is disposed between the first and second surfaces. The storage space may including mounting portions operable to hold various electrical components such as the battery, the electrical circuit, electrical chord, and mechanism for retracting the electrical chord.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In a second preferred embodiment, the band includes a base portion, and the cover is adapted to be disposed over the base portion. The cover includes a display. The base portion is configured to house electrical components operable to tell time. The time is shown on the display.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The battery is also stored on the base portion and covered by the cover. The outer surface of the cover includes at least one solar cell. The solar cell is electrically wired to the battery so as to charge the battery. Electrical power from the solar cells may be filtered through an electrical circuit operable to control charging of the battery. The electrical circuit may also control the discharging of the electrical power stored in the battery.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Advantages of the present invention will be readily appreciated as the same become understood by reference to the following detailed description when considered in connection with the accompanying drawings wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view showing a first preferred embodiment of the device worn on the wrist of a user holding a cellular phone;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exploded view of the device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a view of the device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> having a cover hingedly mounted onto a band; and</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a perspective view of the second preferred embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">With reference now to the figures, a device <b>10</b> configured to be worn around the wrist of a user and operable to charge an electrical device <b>12</b> is provided. The device <b>10</b> includes a cover <b>14</b> and a band <b>16</b>. The band <b>16</b> is adapted to be worn around a wrist of a user. The cover <b>14</b> may be adapted to mount onto the band <b>16</b>. The band <b>16</b> includes a storage space <b>18</b> configured for holding electrical components operable to store and discharge electrical power, such as a battery <b>20</b>. The device <b>10</b> further includes an output <b>22</b> operable to connect the battery <b>20</b> to an electrical device <b>12</b> so as to charge the electrical device <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Referring first to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-2</figref>, an illustration of a first preferred embodiment of the device <b>10</b> is provided. The band <b>16</b> is a circular member adapted to be worn on the wrist of a user. The band <b>16</b> may be formed from a rigid and durable material such as gold, silver or a hardened plastic. Alternatively, the band <b>16</b> may be formed from an expandable material such as rubber.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The cover <b>14</b> encircles the band <b>16</b> and is adapted to be mounted onto the band <b>16</b>. The cover <b>14</b> includes a plurality of solar cells <b>24</b>. The solar cells <b>24</b> are electrically wired to a battery <b>20</b>. The battery <b>20</b> is operable to store and discharge electrical power. The solar cells <b>24</b> as operable to collect solar energy and transform the solar energy into electricity so as to charge the battery <b>20</b>. Electrical power from the solar cells <b>24</b> may be filtered through an electrical circuit <b>26</b> operable to control charging of the battery <b>20</b>. The electrical circuit <b>26</b> may also control the discharging of the electrical power stored in the battery <b>20</b>. The battery <b>20</b> may be a rechargeable battery <b>20</b> such as a lithium ion battery <b>20</b> or any other battery <b>20</b> currently known and used in the art for storing electrical power.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The device <b>10</b> may use a plurality of covers <b>14</b>, each cover <b>14</b> may be decorated with design and indicia. The solar cells <b>24</b> may be colored so as to present an aesthetically pleasing accessory for wear with an outfit. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, the solar cells <b>24</b> alternate between decorative panels <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The covers <b>14</b> may be removed from the band <b>16</b> so as to allow the user to change covers <b>14</b> according to the user's choice. In one embodiment, the device <b>10</b> may include a fastening device <b>30</b> operable to secure the cover <b>14</b> with respect to the band <b>16</b>. Specifically, the fastening device <b>30</b> is a male member <b>32</b> formed of an electric conducting material. The solar cells <b>24</b> are wired to the male member <b>32</b>. The fastening device <b>30</b> is operable to engage a female member <b>34</b> so as to provide electrical connection between the solar cells <b>24</b> and the battery <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The band <b>16</b> includes in first surface <b>36</b><i>a </i>and a second surface <b>36</b><i>b</i>. The first surface <b>36</b><i>a </i>of the band <b>16</b> is covered by the cover <b>14</b>, and the second surface <b>36</b><i>b </i>of the band <b>16</b> is exposed to the wrist of a user when worn. The storage space <b>18</b> is disposed between the first and second surfaces <b>36</b><i>a</i>, <b>36</b><i>b</i>. The storage space <b>18</b> may include mounting portions <b>38</b> to hold various electrical components such as the battery <b>20</b>, and the electric circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the storage space <b>18</b> may further house the output <b>22</b>. The output <b>22</b> may be exposed on the second surface <b>36</b><i>b </i>of the band <b>16</b>. The second surface <b>36</b><i>b </i>of the band <b>16</b> includes a detent <b>40</b> so as to keep the output <b>22</b> behind the second surface <b>36</b><i>b </i>of the band <b>16</b> with respect to the user's wrist. The output <b>22</b> is an adapter <b>42</b> electrically connected to the battery <b>20</b>. Thus, a user may mount a micro-USB chord or the like to the adapter <b>42</b> so as to charge the electrical device <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">It should be appreciated that the cover <b>14</b> may be adapted to mount onto the band <b>16</b> in other ways. With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the cover <b>14</b> includes a hinge. A fastener is mounted onto the hinge and exposed to the first surface <b>36</b><i>a </i>of the band <b>16</b>. The fastener is a male member <b>32</b> formed of an electric conducting material. The solar cells <b>24</b> are wired to the male member <b>32</b>. The fastening device <b>30</b> is operable to engage a female member <b>34</b> so as to provide electrical connection between the solar cells <b>24</b> and the battery <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The output <b>22</b> may include an electrical chord <b>44</b> and a mechanism <b>46</b> operable to retract the electrical chord <b>44</b>. The electrical chord <b>44</b> may include an end portion <b>48</b> adapted to engage power input <b>50</b> of an electrical device <b>12</b>, such as a cellular phone. One end of the electrical chord <b>44</b> is wired to the battery <b>20</b> and the other end of the electrical chord <b>44</b> includes an adapter <b>42</b> configured to engage the power input <b>50</b> of an electrical device <b>12</b>. Any such adapters <b>42</b> currently known and used in the art may be adapted for use herein, illustratively include a micro-USB port <b>52</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The bracelet may further include an auxiliary electric device <b>54</b>, operable to transform the swaying motion of an arm into electricity. For instance, such technology is currently known and used and disclosed in WO/2005/100787 which is incorporated herein by reference. The auxiliary device <b>10</b> may also be wired to the battery <b>20</b> so as to charge the battery <b>20</b>. The electric circuitry may be further operable to step down electrical power generated by the auxiliary device <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The cord may be pulled and connected to a cellular phone so as to charge the cellular phone. Such connectors are currently known and used and illustratively include a micro-USB port <b>52</b>. Accordingly, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the user may wear the bracelet as a fashion accessory and may power the cellular phone while holding the cellular phone in his or her hand.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a second preferred embodiment of the present invention is provided. In a second preferred embodiment, the band <b>16</b> includes a base portion <b>56</b>, and the cover <b>14</b> is adapted to be disposed over the base portion <b>56</b>. The cover <b>14</b> includes a display <b>58</b>. The base portion <b>56</b> is configured to house electrical components operable to tell time. The time is shown on the display <b>58</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The battery <b>20</b> is also stored on the base portion <b>56</b> and covered by the cover <b>14</b>. The outer surface <b>60</b> of the cover <b>14</b> includes at least one solar cell <b>24</b>. The solar cell <b>24</b> is electrically wired to the battery <b>20</b> so as to charge the battery <b>20</b>. Electrical power from the solar cells <b>24</b> may be filtered through an electrical circuit <b>26</b> operable to control charging of the battery <b>20</b>. The electrical circuit <b>26</b> may also control the discharging of the electrical power stored in the battery <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The cover <b>14</b> includes four side walls extending generally orthogonal to a face plate <b>62</b>. The display <b>58</b> is mounted to the faceplate. An outer surface <b>60</b> of the cover <b>14</b> includes a detent <b>40</b>, the output <b>22</b> is exposed on the outer surface <b>60</b> of the cover <b>14</b> and within the detent <b>40</b> so as to be behind the outer surface <b>60</b> of the cover <b>14</b>. Specifically, the detent <b>40</b> is disposed on one of the sidewalls of the cover <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The output <b>22</b> is an adapter <b>42</b> configured to engage an electrical chord <b>44</b> operable to connect to the power input <b>50</b> of an electrical device <b>12</b>. Thus a user may simply attach an electrical chord <b>44</b> with the appropriate USB connection between the adapter <b>42</b> and the electrical device <b>12</b> such as a cellular phone to charge the cellular phone.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Accordingly, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the user may wear the watch as a fashion accessory and may power the cellular phone while holding the cellular phone in his or her hand.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The invention has been described in an illustrative manner. It is therefore to be understood that the terminology used is intended to be in the nature of words of description rather than limitation. Many modifications and variations of the invention are possible in light of the above teachings without varying from the scope and spirit of the invention described herein.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A device for charging an electrical device, the device configured to be worn around a wrist of a user, the device comprising:
<claim-text>a band adapted to be worn around the wrist, the band having a storage space configured for holding components;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cover having an outer surface exposed to the environment, the cover adapted to mount onto the band;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a battery;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one solar cell disposed on the outer surface of the cover, the at least one solar cell electrically wired to the battery; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an output operable to connect the battery to the electrical device so as to charge the electrical device while the user holds the electrical device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The device as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further including an electrical circuit operable to control discharging and charging of the battery.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The device as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, the cover may be decorated with design and indicia so as to present an aesthetically pleasing accessory for wear with an outfit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The device as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, including a plurality of covers, each of the plurality of covers are removably attached to the band so as to allow the user to change the cover with a different covers.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The device as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, further including a fastening device, operable to secure and release the cover to and from the band.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The device as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, further including a female member disposed on the band, the female member in electrical connection with the battery, the fastening device is a male member electrically connected to the solar cell, the male member configured to engage the female member so as to secure the cover to the band and transmit electricity from the solar cell to the battery.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The device as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the band includes in first surface and a second surface, the first surface of the band is covered by the cover, and the second surface of the band is exposed to the wrist of a user when worn, the band further including at least one mounting portion disposed on the first surface of the band, the one of the at least one mounting portions configured to hold the battery, and another of the at least one mounting portions is configured to hold the electric circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The device as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the output includes a electrical chord and a mechanism operable to retract the electrical chord, the electrical chord and mechanism stored within the storage space, the electrical chord having an end portion adapted to engage a power input of an electrical device, the other end of the electrical chord is wired to the battery.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The device as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the end portion includes an adapter configured to engage an electrical chord operable to connect to the power input of an electrical device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The device as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref> wherein the adapter is a micro-USB port.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The device as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the second surface of the band includes a detent, the output is exposed on the second surface of the band and within the detent so as to be behind the second surface of the band with respect to the user's wrist.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The device as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, further including an auxiliary electric device operable to transform the swaying motion of an arm into electricity, the auxiliary device is wired to the battery so as to charge the battery.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The device as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the electric circuitry may be further operable to step down electrical power generated by the auxiliary device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The device as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the cover includes a hinge operable to displace one end of the cover with respect to an opposite end of the cover, the hinge having a fastening device operable to secure the cover to the band.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The device as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, further including a female member disposed on the band, the female member in electrical connection with the battery, the fastening device is a male member electrically connected to the solar cell, the male member configured to engage the female member so as to secure the cover to the band and transmit electricity from the solar cell to the battery.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The device as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the band includes a base portion, the cover includes a display and the cover is adapted to be disposed over the base portion, the device further includes electrical components operable to tell time, the electrical components contained between the cover and the base portion, time is shown on the display.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The device as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the outer surface of the cover includes a detent, the output is exposed on the outer surface of the cover and within the detent so as to be behind the outer surface of the cover.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The device as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the output is an adapter configured to engage a electrical chord operable to connect to the power input of an electrical device. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
