<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622189-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622189</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13256554</doc-number>
<date>20090319</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>30</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>07</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>194206</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Banknote recognition and counting machine and money counting method</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4830742</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Takesako</name>
<date>19890500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>209534</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6179704</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Suzuki</name>
<date>20010100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7980394</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Otsuka</name>
<date>20110700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>209534</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0182330</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Chiles</name>
<date>20060800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>382135</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0283685</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Cousin</name>
<date>20061200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>194217</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0069007</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Molbak</name>
<date>20070300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>235379</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>63-286993</doc-number>
<date>19881100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2007-065776</doc-number>
<date>20070300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00009">
<othercit>European Search Report (Application No. 09841872.6&#x2014;PCT/JP2009/055470) (7 pages&#x2014;dated Jun. 2, 2013).</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>8</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>194206</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>194215</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>194216</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>194217</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>209534</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>235379</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120006646</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120112</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Morino</last-name>
<first-name>Hajime</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kasukabe</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Numata</last-name>
<first-name>Toshio</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kawasaki</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Matsuura</last-name>
<first-name>Shinji</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo-To</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Morino</last-name>
<first-name>Hajime</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kasukabe</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Numata</last-name>
<first-name>Toshio</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kawasaki</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Matsuura</last-name>
<first-name>Shinji</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo-To</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Renner, Kener, Greieve, Bobak, Taylor &#x26; Weber</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Glory Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Himeji-Shi, Hyogo-Ken</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Beauchaine</last-name>
<first-name>Mark</first-name>
<department>3653</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/JP2009/055470</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20090319</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20110914</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2010/106667</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20100923</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">In a banknote recognition and counting machine (<b>10</b>), information concerning a count result on coins is inputted through an input unit (<b>32, 53</b>), and then the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit (<b>32, 53</b>) is sent to a control unit (<b>50</b>). Thereafter, information concerning a count result on one or more banknotes counted by a recognition and counting unit (<b>24</b>) and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit are outputted, through an output unit (<b>32</b>p, <b>34, 52, 38</b>).</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="173.91mm" wi="183.64mm" file="US08622189-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="246.89mm" wi="171.53mm" file="US08622189-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="177.72mm" wi="161.46mm" file="US08622189-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="246.30mm" wi="142.92mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622189-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="191.18mm" wi="182.54mm" file="US08622189-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="237.15mm" wi="151.13mm" file="US08622189-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="246.55mm" wi="179.41mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622189-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="129.96mm" wi="134.54mm" file="US08622189-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is the National Stage of International Application No. PCT/JP2009/055470, filed on Mar. 19, 2009.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a banknote recognition and counting machine adapted for recognizing and counting one or more banknotes, and also relates to a money counting method for counting money by using the banknote recognition and counting machine.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND ART</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In the past, various types of machines have been used as the banknote recognition and counting machine adapted for recognizing and counting the banknotes. In general, the banknote recognition and counting machine includes a casing, a placing unit adapted for placing thereon the banknotes and feeding such placed banknotes, one by one, into the casing, a recognition and counting unit provided in the casing and adapted for recognizing and counting the banknotes, respectively fed into the casing from the placing unit, and a stacking unit adapted for stacking therein the banknotes that have been recognized and counted by the recognition and counting unit and then fed to the stacking unit. Further, a control unit is provided to this banknote recognition and counting machine, such that a count result on the banknotes is sent to this control unit from the recognition and counting unit. In this case, information concerning a recognition result on the banknotes recognized by the recognition and counting unit is outputted by an output unit. For instance, a printer is used as the output unit, and the information concerning the recognition result on the banknotes recognized by the recognition and counting unit, more specifically, the number of the banknotes for each denomination of money or total amount of money of the banknotes, respectively recognized by the recognition and counting unit, is printed by this printer.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Further, in the case of outputting a count result on coins as well as outputting the count result on the banknotes, an external machine or device, such as a personal computer or the like, is provided. Namely, in this case, the banknote recognition and counting machine adapted for recognizing and counting the banknotes and a coin recognition and counting machine adapted for recognizing and counting the coins are respectively connected with the external machine, and the information concerning the count result on the banknotes is sent to the external machine from the banknote recognition and counting machine, while the information concerning the count result on the coins is sent to the same external machine from the coin recognition and counting machine. Thus, the information concerning the count result on the banknotes and the information concerning the count result on the coins are respectively outputted from the same external machine.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In addition, as another approach for outputting the count result on the coins as well as outputting the count result on the banknotes, one method, as disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 7,269,279B or JP6-36207B2, has been known. More specifically, in the U.S. Pat. No. 7,269,279B, a money handling machine, which is adapted for counting the banknotes by using a banknote counting unit as well as adapted for counting the coins by measuring the mass of the coins by using a coin balance, is disclosed. Meanwhile, in the JP6-36207B2, a money deposit machine, which includes the banknote recognition and counting machine and coin recognition and counting machine and is thus adapted for counting the banknotes by using the banknote recognition and counting machine as well as adapted for counting the coins by using the coin recognition and counting machine, is disclosed.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DISCLOSURE OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">However, in the case of employing the method, in which the external machine, such as the personal computer or the like, is provided for outputting the count result on the coins as well as outputting the count result on the banknotes, and in which the banknote recognition and counting machine adapted for recognizing and counting the banknotes and the coin recognition and counting machine adapted for recognizing and counting the coins are respectively connected with the external machine, there is a need for providing the external machine, such as the personal computer or the like. Therefore, the entire production cost may be unduly increased.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">More specifically, in the case of the money deposit machine disclosed in the above JP6-36207B2, each of the information concerning the recognition result on the banknotes and the information concerning the recognition result on the coins is sent to a teller's machine provided separately from the money deposit machine, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> provided in the JP6-36207B2. Then, the information concerning each recognition result on the banknotes and coins is outputted on a display unit or printing unit of the teller's machine. Accordingly, for this money deposit machine disclosed in the JP6-36207B2, it is necessary to provide the external machine composed of the teller's machine, leading to rather increase of the entire production cost.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Meanwhile, for the money handling machine disclosed in the U.S. Pat. No. 7,269,279B, it is necessary to provide the coin balance for counting the coins, thus requiring an additional cost for installing this coin balance. Further, in the case of counting both of the banknotes and coins, the number of the banknotes is usually larger than the number of the coins. In other words, the number of the coins to be counted is usually quite small, as compared with the number of the banknotes to be counted. Therefore, it is rather inefficient to provide the coin balance, for separately counting such a small number of coins. Besides, the coins often include many denominations of money. Therefore, before the coin balance is used for counting such coins, it is necessary to once sort the coins, by hand, leading to rather deterioration of the working efficiency.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The present invention was made in light of such problems. Therefore, it is an object of this invention to provide a banknote recognition and counting machine that can output both of the information concerning the count result on the banknotes and the information concerning the count result on the coins, without the need for providing the external machine, such as the personal computer or the like. It is another object of this invention to provide a money counting method that can be used for outputting both of the information concerning the count result on the banknotes and the information concerning the count result on the coins, by using the banknote recognition and counting machine of this invention.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">A banknote recognition and counting machine according to the present invention is configured to recognize and count banknotes and includes: a casing; a recognition and counting unit provided in the casing and configured to recognize and count one or more banknotes, put from the outside into the casing; a control unit connected with the recognition and counting unit and configured to receive a count result on one or more banknotes, sent from the recognition and counting unit; an input unit connected with the control unit and configured to allow information concerning a count result on coins to be inputted, the information concerning the count result on the coins, that has been inputted through the input unit, being sent to the control unit; and an output unit connected with the control unit and configured to output information concerning the count result on one or more banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to such a banknote recognition and counting machine, the information concerning the count result on the coins is inputted through the input unit, and then the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit is sent to the control unit. Thereafter, the information concerning the count result on the banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit are respectively outputted from the output unit. Therefore, the count result on the banknotes can be outputted, as well as the count result on the coins can be outputted, by using the banknote recognition and counting machine provided for recognizing and counting the banknotes. As such, both of the information concerning the count result on the banknotes and the information concerning the count result on the coins can be outputted, without the need for providing the external machine, such as the personal computer or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In the banknote recognition and counting machine according to the present invention, the input unit may include an operation unit provided to an outer surface of the casing and configured to send a command to the control unit.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Alternatively, the input unit may include a coin interface unit, that is connected, for communication, with a coin recognition and counting machine configured to recognize and count the coins, the coin interface unit receiving the information concerning the count result on the coins sent from the coin recognition and counting machine.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In the banknote recognition and counting machine according to the present invention, the output unit may be configured to output information concerning the total of the count result on one or more banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit and the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In this case, the output unit may be configured to output information concerning the total amount of money and/or information concerning the total number of money by denomination, in the total of the count result on one or more banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit and the count result on the coins, inputted through the input unit.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In the banknote recognition and counting machine according to the present invention, the input unit may be capable of allowing the information concerning a manually-obtained count result on one or more banknotes that cannot be recognized by the recognition and counting unit, to be inputted, in addition to the information concerning the count result on the coins.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In the banknote recognition and counting machine according to the present invention, the banknote recognition and counting machine further including a memory unit connected with the control unit and configured to store therein the information concerning the count result on one or more banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In this case, the memory unit may include a first memory part configured to store therein the information concerning the count result on one or more banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit, and a second memory part configured to store therein the information concerning the count result on the coins, inputted through the input unit.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In the banknote recognition and counting machine according to the present invention, the output unit may include any one of: a display unit configured to display the information concerning the count result on one or more banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit; a printing unit configured to print the information concerning the count result on one or more banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit; an external interface unit connected, for communication, with an external machine and configured to send the information concerning the count result on one or more banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit, to the external machine; and a storage-medium writing unit configured to write the information concerning the count result on one or more banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit, in an external storage medium.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The money counting method of this invention is adapted for counting money by using a banknote recognition and counting machine configured to recognize and count banknotes, and includes: recognizing and counting one or more banknotes, put from the outside into a casing of the banknote recognition and counting machine, by using a recognition and counting unit; inputting information concerning a count result on coins, through an input unit; and outputting information concerning a count result on one or more banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit, through an output unit.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">According to this money counting method, the banknotes, respectively put from the outside into the casing of the banknote recognition and counting machine, are recognized and counted by the recognition and counting unit, and the information concerning the count result on the coins is inputted through the input unit, and then the information concerning the count result on the banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit are outputted through the output unit. Therefore, this method can be used for outputting both of the information concerning the count result on the banknotes and the information concerning the count result on the coins, by using the banknote recognition and counting machine adapted for recognizing and counting the banknotes, without the need for providing the external machine, such as the personal computer or the like.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> is a perspective view provided for showing external appearance of the banknote recognition and counting machine related to one embodiment of the present invention, when a shutter is evacuated from an opening provided in a front face of the stacking unit.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> is another perspective view provided for showing the external appearance of the banknote recognition and counting machine related to the embodiment of the present invention, when the shutter closes the opening provided in the front face of the stacking unit.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a diagram schematically illustrating the internal construction of the banknote recognition and counting machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A and 1B</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram illustrating details of an operation/display unit of the banknote recognition and counting machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and so on.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a block diagram illustrating a control system of the banknote recognition and counting machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and so on.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a flow chart for illustrating the operation for outputting the recognition result on the banknotes as well as outputting the recognition result on the coins, by using the banknote recognition and counting machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and so on.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6(</figref><i>a</i>) through <b>6</b>(<i>f</i>) respectively illustrate display contents on the display unit when the operation, as illustrated in the flow chart of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, is performed in the banknote recognition and counting machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and so on.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates contents printed by the printing unit when the operation, as illustrated in the flow chart of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, is performed in the banknote recognition and counting machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and so on.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Hereinafter, one embodiment of the present invention will be described, with reference to the drawings. As used herein, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 7</figref> are provided for respectively illustrating the banknote recognition and counting machine related to the embodiment. Of these drawings, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A and 1B</figref> respectively illustrate one perspective view of the banknote recognition and counting machine related to this embodiment. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> schematically illustrates the internal construction of the banknote recognition and counting machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A and 1B</figref>, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates the details of the operation/display unit of the banknote recognition and counting machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and so on. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates one exemplary control system of the banknote recognition and counting machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and so on. The flow chart of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates the operation for outputting the recognition result on the banknotes as well as outputting the recognition result on the coins, by using the banknote recognition and counting machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and so on. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6(</figref><i>a</i>) through <b>6</b>(<i>f</i>) are respectively provided for illustrating the display contents on the display unit when the operation, as illustrated in the flow chart of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, is performed in the banknote recognition and counting machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and so on. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates the contents printed by the printing unit when the operation, as illustrated in the flow chart of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, is performed in the banknote recognition and counting machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and so on.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A</figref>, <b>1</b>B and <b>2</b>, a banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b> includes a casing <b>12</b> and a placing unit <b>14</b> adapted for placing thereon a plurality of banknotes P to be respectively counted, in a stacked condition. Further, this banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b> includes a feeding unit <b>16</b> adapted for feeding each banknote P located at the lowermost layer of the banknotes P placed on the placing unit <b>14</b> in the stacked condition, one by one, into the casing <b>12</b>, and a transport unit <b>22</b> adapted for transporting the banknotes P, respectively fed into the casing <b>12</b> by the feeding unit <b>16</b>, one by one. In addition, a recognition and counting unit <b>24</b> adapted for recognizing and counting the banknotes P respectively fed into the casing <b>12</b> from the placing unit <b>14</b> is provided to the transport unit <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The feeding unit <b>16</b> includes a kicker roller <b>16</b><i>a </i>provided to be in contact with the surface of the banknote P located at the lowermost layer of the banknotes P placed on the placing unit <b>14</b> in the stacked condition, and a feed roller <b>16</b><i>b </i>located on the downstream side, in the feeding direction of the banknotes P, relative to the kicker roller <b>16</b><i>a</i>, and adapted for feeding the banknotes P, respectively kicked out by the kicker roller <b>16</b><i>a</i>, into the casing <b>12</b>. Further, a gate roller (or reverse rotation roller) <b>16</b><i>c </i>is provided to be opposed to the feed roller <b>16</b><i>b</i>, with a gate part provided between the feed roller <b>16</b><i>b </i>and the gate roller <b>16</b><i>c</i>. Thus, each banknote P kicked out by the kicker roller <b>16</b><i>a </i>is passed through the gate part and then fed out, one by one, toward the transport unit <b>22</b> in the casing <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the transport unit <b>22</b> is bifurcated into two transport paths, at a point located on the downstream side relative to the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b>, and one of the two transport paths is connected with a stacking unit <b>26</b>, while the other transport path is connected with a reject unit <b>30</b>. With this configuration, the banknotes P that have been respectively recognized and counted by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b> can be selectively fed to the stacking unit <b>26</b> or reject unit <b>30</b>. An opening is provided in the front face of the stacking unit <b>26</b> (i.e., the face of the stacking unit <b>26</b> depicted on the right side in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>), such that the operator can take out the banknotes P respectively stacked in the stacking unit <b>26</b>, via this opening. Further, another opening is provided in the front face of the reject unit <b>30</b>, such that the operator can take out the banknotes P&#x2032; respectively stacked in the reject unit <b>30</b>, via this opening.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Further, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a diversion unit <b>31</b>, including a diverter and a drive unit (not shown) for driving the diverter, is provided at the point where the transport unit <b>22</b> is bifurcated into the two transport paths. Due to this diversion unit <b>31</b>, each banknote P that has been fed from the upstream side of the diversion unit <b>31</b> can be selectively fed to either one of the two bifurcated transport paths.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">A stacking wheel mechanism <b>28</b> is provided on the back face side of the stacking unit <b>26</b> in the casing <b>12</b> (i.e., in a position located on the left side in the stacking unit <b>26</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). This stacking wheel mechanism <b>28</b> is composed of a stacking wheel <b>28</b><i>a </i>and a drive unit (not shown) for driving the stacking wheel <b>28</b><i>a</i>. This stacking wheel <b>28</b><i>a </i>is provided to be rotated in a clockwise direction (i.e., the direction indicated by an arrow depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) about a shaft extending in a substantially horizontal direction orthogonal to the sheet of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. In this stacking wheel <b>28</b><i>a</i>, a plurality of vanes <b>28</b><i>b </i>are provided to extend outward, from an outer circumferential face of the wheel <b>28</b><i>a</i>, in a direction reverse to the rotation direction of the wheel <b>28</b><i>a </i>(i.e., the anticlockwise direction in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). More specifically, such vanes <b>28</b><i>b </i>are arranged on the outer circumferential face of the stacking wheel <b>28</b><i>a</i>, at an equal interval, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The stacking wheel <b>28</b><i>a </i>of the stacking wheel mechanism <b>28</b> is provided to be constantly rotated, by the driving unit, in the clockwise direction, as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, during the operation of the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b>, thereby to receive the banknotes P, respectively fed from the transport unit <b>22</b>, one by one. More specifically, the stacking wheel <b>28</b><i>a </i>can serve to receive each banknote P fed from the transport unit <b>22</b> between the two vanes <b>28</b><i>b </i>thereof, and then feed the banknote P received between the two vanes <b>28</b><i>a </i>into the stacking unit <b>26</b>. In this way, the banknotes P can be fed to the stacking unit <b>26</b>, one by one, from the stacking wheel <b>28</b><i>a</i>, as such the plurality of banknotes P can be stacked in the stacking unit <b>26</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1B</figref>, <b>2</b> and so on, a shutter <b>40</b> is provided to close the opening provided in the front face of the stacking unit <b>26</b>, such that the opening in the front face of the stacking unit <b>26</b> can be selectively closed by the shutter <b>40</b>. By means of a shutter drive unit (not shown) for driving the shutter <b>40</b>, the shutter <b>40</b> can be moved, between an opening position, as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>, in which the shutter <b>40</b> is evacuated from the opening in the front face of the stacking unit <b>26</b> in order to open the opening, and a closing position, as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref>, for closing the opening in the front face of the stacking unit <b>26</b>. Namely, when the shutter <b>40</b> is located in the opening position as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>, the shutter <b>40</b> is evacuated from the opening in the front face of the stacking unit <b>26</b> and thus the opening is opened, thereby allowing the operator to access the banknotes P respectively stacked in the stacking unit <b>26</b>. Meanwhile, when the shutter <b>40</b> is located in the closing position as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref>, the opening in the front face of the stacking unit <b>26</b> is closed by the shutter <b>40</b>, thus preventing the operator from accessing the banknotes P respectively stacked in the stacking unit <b>26</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the shutter <b>40</b> located in the opening position is depicted by a solid line, while the shutter <b>40</b> located in the closing position is depicted by a two-dot chain line.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">With the provision of the shutter <b>40</b> as described above, when the opening in the front face of the stacking unit <b>26</b> is closed by the shutter <b>40</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref>, the risk that the dust may be blown out toward the operator with the rotation of the stacking wheel <b>28</b><i>a </i>of the stacking wheel mechanism <b>28</b> can be effectively suppressed. Further, by closing the opening in the front face of the stacking unit <b>26</b> by the shutter <b>40</b>, unwanted leakage of a sound generated from the interior of the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b> toward the outside during the operation of this machine <b>10</b> can be successfully prevented.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Further, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, various sensors are provided to the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b>. Specifically, to the placing unit <b>14</b>, a placing-unit-residue banknote detection sensor <b>62</b> composed of a reflection-type optical sensor is provided for detecting whether or not there are some banknotes P remaining on the placing unit <b>14</b>. Further, a diversion timing sensor <b>64</b> composed of an optical sensor is provided on the upstream side relative to the diversion unit <b>31</b> in the transport unit <b>22</b>. In this case, the diverter of the diversion unit <b>31</b> can be optionally moved to either one of a first position for feeding each banknote P to the stacking unit <b>26</b> and a second position for feeding each banknote P to the reject unit <b>30</b> (in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the diverter of the diversion unit <b>31</b> is located in the position for feeding each banknote P to the stacking unit <b>26</b>), at each timing on which the banknote P is detected by the diversion timing sensor <b>64</b>. Thus, each banknote P transported by the transport unit <b>22</b> and then detected by the diversion timing sensor <b>64</b> is selectively fed to either one of the two transport paths by the diversion unit <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Additionally, a banknote tracking detection sensor <b>66</b> is provided to the transport path located on the side of the stacking unit <b>26</b>, among the two transport paths bifurcated at the point where the diversion unit <b>31</b> is located. This banknote tracking detection sensor <b>66</b> is composed of a proper optical sensor adapted for detecting each banknote P fed to the transport path arranged on the side of the stacking unit <b>26</b>. Namely, with the provision of this banknote tracking detection sensor <b>66</b>, each banknote P that has been fed, by the diversion unit <b>31</b>, to the transport path arranged on the side of the stacking unit <b>26</b> can be detected. Further, in the stacking unit <b>26</b>, a stacking-unit banknote detection sensor <b>68</b> is provided. This stacking-unit banknote detection sensor <b>68</b> is composed of another optical sensor adapted for detecting whether or not there are some banknotes P stacked in the stacking unit <b>26</b>. In addition, a reject-unit banknote detection sensor <b>70</b> is provided in the reject unit <b>30</b>. This reject-unit banknote detection sensor <b>70</b> is composed of another proper optical sensor adapted for detecting whether or not there are some reject banknotes P&#x2032; stacked in the reject unit <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Further, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b> includes a control unit <b>50</b>. This control unit <b>50</b> can serve to control each component of the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b>. More specifically, this control unit <b>50</b> is connected with each of the feeding unit <b>16</b>, transport unit <b>22</b>, recognition and counting unit <b>24</b>, stacking unit <b>26</b> including the stacking-wheel drive mechanism <b>28</b>, diversion unit <b>31</b> and the like. In this case, the recognition and counting result on each banknote P recognized by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b> is sent to the control unit <b>50</b>, while the control unit <b>50</b> sends an instruction signal to each of the feeding unit <b>16</b>, transport unit <b>22</b>, stacking unit <b>26</b>, diversion unit <b>31</b> and the like, in order to control such components. Further, the control unit <b>50</b> is connected with each of the placing-unit-residue banknote detection sensor <b>62</b>, diversion timing sensor <b>64</b>, banknote tracking detection sensor <b>66</b>, stacking-unit banknote detection sensor <b>68</b> and reject-unit banknote detection sensor <b>70</b>, in order to receive each detection result of such sensors <b>62</b> to <b>70</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Further, the control unit <b>50</b> is connected with an operation/display unit <b>32</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and so on, the operation/display unit <b>32</b> is provided to a front face of the casing <b>12</b>. In this case, the condition (or process condition) under which the banknotes P are handled or processed in the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b>, more specifically the information on the number for each denomination of money, total amount of money or the like of the banknotes P counted by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b>, can be displayed on the operation/display unit <b>32</b>. Additionally, the operator can input various commands to the control unit <b>50</b> via the operation/display unit <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Now, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, more specific construction of the operation/display unit <b>32</b> will be described. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the operation/display unit <b>32</b> has a laterally elongated and substantially rectangular shape, and includes a display unit <b>32</b><i>p </i>composed of, for example, an LCD or the like, and provided at a laterally central part of the operation/display unit <b>32</b>. In this case, the display unit <b>32</b><i>p </i>can serve to display the process condition for the banknotes P in the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b>, more specifically the information on the operational mode of the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b>, information on the number for each denomination of money, total amount of money or the like of the banknotes P counted by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b>, error information and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">On the right side of the display unit <b>32</b><i>p </i>in the operation/display unit <b>32</b>, a SHUTTE (shutter) key <b>32</b><i>a</i>, a SHIFT key <b>32</b><i>b</i>, a START/STOP key <b>32</b><i>c</i>, a C (clear) key <b>32</b><i>d </i>and an ACCEPT key <b>32</b><i>e </i>are provided, respectively. Further, on the left side of the display unit <b>32</b><i>p </i>in the operation/display unit <b>32</b>, a MENU key <b>32</b><i>f</i>, another START/STOP key <b>32</b><i>g</i>, another C (clear) key <b>32</b><i>h </i>and another ACCEPT key <b>32</b><i>i </i>are provided, respectively. Additionally, in a right adjacent portion relative to the display unit <b>32</b><i>p</i>, an F1 (a first function) key <b>32</b><i>j</i>, an F2 (a second function) key <b>32</b><i>k</i>, an F3 (a third function) key <b>321</b> and an F4 (a fourth function) key <b>32</b><i>m </i>are vertically arranged, in this order from the top. Furthermore, in a lower portion of the operation/display unit <b>32</b>, a reject lamp <b>32</b><i>s</i>, an ADD (addition) lamp <b>32</b><i>t</i>, a RIGHT (right-side) lamp <b>32</b><i>u</i>, another ADD lamp <b>32</b><i>v </i>and a LEFT (left-side) lamp <b>32</b><i>w </i>are provided, respectively. It is noted that the respective function keys (i.e., the F1 key <b>32</b><i>j </i>to F4 key <b>32</b><i>m</i>) are provided to be selectively pushed down, upon performing various commands respectively displayed in a left adjacent portion in the display unit <b>32</b><i>p. </i></p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">For instance, when the operator pushes down the SHUTTE key <b>32</b><i>a </i>of the operation/display unit <b>32</b>, the shutter <b>40</b> is moved from the opening position as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> to the closing position as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> or moved from the closing position as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> to the opening position as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>, by the shutter drive unit (not shown). In this manner, each time the SHUTTE key <b>32</b> is pushed down, the opening and closing operation of the shutter <b>40</b> is performed.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Further, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a printing unit <b>34</b> composed of, for example, a printer, is connected with the control unit <b>50</b> of the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b>. This printing unit <b>34</b> may be provided to the casing <b>12</b> of the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b>, or otherwise may be provided separately from the casing <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Further, a memory unit <b>36</b> is connected with the control unit <b>50</b> of the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b>. This memory unit <b>36</b> is composed of, for example, a flash memory, hard disk or the like, and is provided in the casing <b>12</b>. In this case, the memory unit <b>36</b> serves to store therein information on the number for each denomination of money, total amount of money or the like of the banknotes P counted by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b>. In addition, an external interface <b>52</b> and a coin interface <b>53</b> are respectively connected with the control unit <b>50</b>. Thus, the control unit <b>50</b> can transmit or receive a signal relative to a higher-ranking machine, such as a host computer or the like, via the external interface <b>52</b>. Further, the control unit <b>50</b> can transmit or receive the signal relative to the coin recognition and counting machine provided for recognizing and counting the coins, via the coin interface <b>53</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Further, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a storage-medium writing unit <b>38</b> adapted for writing various kinds of information in a storage medium provided separately from the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b> is connected with the control unit <b>50</b> of the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b>. In this case, the storage medium is composed of a publicly known medium or device, such as a floppy disk, a USB memory, a CD-ROM, a DVD or the like. This storage medium is detachably attached to the storage-medium writing unit <b>38</b>. For instance, the storage-medium writing unit <b>38</b> is composed of a floppy disk drive, a USB memory drive, a CD-ROM drive, a DVD drive or the like. This storage-medium writing unit <b>38</b> may be provided to the casing <b>12</b> of the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b>, or otherwise may be provided separately from the casing <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Now, the operation of the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b> constructed as described above will be discussed. It is noted that the operation of the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b> as will be described below is performed by controlling each component of this machine <b>10</b> under the control of the control unit <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">First, a basic operation (i.e., a counting operation for the banknotes) of the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b> will be described.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">First of all, the operator places the banknotes P to be respectively counted, on the placing unit <b>14</b>, in the stacked condition. Thereafter, when the operator pushes down the START/STOP key <b>32</b><i>c </i>or <b>32</b><i>g </i>in the operation/display unit <b>32</b> and gives a command for starting the counting process for the banknotes P to the control unit <b>50</b>, the banknotes P respectively placed in the stacked condition on the placing unit <b>14</b> are fed to the transport unit <b>22</b> in the casing <b>12</b>, one by one, successively, by the feeding unit <b>16</b>, from the banknote P located at the lowermost layer, and then transported by the transport unit <b>22</b>. During this operation, the recognition process about the denomination of money, authenticity, fitness and the like of each banknote P and the counting process for the banknotes P are respectively performed by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b>. Then, the recognition result and count result on the banknotes P obtained by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b> are respectively sent to the control unit <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In this case, each banknote P judged, as the genuine banknote, by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b> is further transported by the transport unit <b>22</b> and fed to the stacking unit <b>26</b> by the diversion unit <b>31</b>. During this operation, each banknotes P is fed, one by one, from the transport unit <b>22</b>, to the stacking wheel <b>28</b><i>a</i>. This stacking wheel <b>28</b><i>a </i>receives each banknote P fed from the transport unit <b>22</b> between the two vanes <b>28</b><i>b </i>thereof, and then feeds this banknote P received between the two vanes <b>28</b><i>b </i>into the stacking unit <b>26</b>. In this way, the banknotes P can be arranged in the stacking unit <b>26</b>, by the stacking wheel <b>28</b><i>a</i>. Since the opening is provided in the front face of the stacking unit <b>26</b>, the operator can take out such banknotes P respectively stacked in the stacking unit <b>26</b>, via the opening.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Meanwhile, each banknotes P&#x2032; not judged to be genuine by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b> is further transported by the transport unit <b>22</b> and fed to the reject unit <b>30</b> by the diversion unit <b>31</b>. Since the opening is provided in the front face of the reject unit <b>30</b>, the operator can take out such banknotes P&#x2032; respectively stacked in the reject unit <b>30</b>, via the opening.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Next, the case of outputting the count result on the banknotes as well as outputting the count result on the coins, by using the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b> provided for recognizing and counting the banknotes, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 4</figref>, will be described.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Namely, in the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b> of this embodiment, the information concerning the count result on the banknotes P counted by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b> can be fed to the control unit <b>50</b>, as well as the information concerning the count result on the coins can be fed to the control unit <b>50</b> through the input unit. As used herein, the term &#x201c;input unit&#x201d; means the operation/display unit <b>32</b>, coin interface <b>53</b> or the like. It is noted that a specific aspect for inputting the information to the control unit <b>50</b>, by using such components, will be described later. Further, as used herein, the &#x201c;count result on the coins&#x201d; means a result obtained when the operator manually counts the coins, or result obtained by recognizing and counting the coins, by using the coin recognition and counting machine provided separately from the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b>. Then, the information concerning the count result on the banknotes P counted by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b> and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted to the control unit <b>50</b> can be outputted, respectively, from the output unit. As used herein, the term &#x201c;output unit&#x201d; means the display unit <b>32</b><i>p </i>of the operation/display unit <b>32</b>, printing unit <b>34</b>, external interface <b>52</b>, storage-medium writing unit <b>38</b> or the like. It is noted that a specific aspect for outputting the information, by using such components, will be described later.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Now, referring to the flow chart of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> as well as to the illustrations of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref>, the operation for outputting the count result on the banknotes as well as outputting the count result on the coins, by using the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b> provided for recognizing and counting the banknotes, will be described in more detail.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">First, the operator places the banknotes P to be respectively counted, on the placing unit <b>14</b>, in the stacked condition. Then, the recognition and counting process for the banknotes P is performed in the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b>. More specifically, the banknotes P, respectively placed in the stacked condition on the placing unit <b>14</b>, are fed, one by one, to the transport unit <b>22</b> in the casing <b>12</b>, by the feeding unit <b>16</b>, and then the recognition process about the denomination of money, authenticity, fitness and the like of each banknote P and the counting process for the banknotes P are respectively performed by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b> (STEP <b>1</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>). Thereafter, the recognition result and count result on the banknotes P, respectively recognized and counted by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b>, are respectively sent to the control unit <b>50</b>. In this case, each banknote P judged as the genuine banknote, based on the recognition result sent from the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b>, is further transported by the transport unit <b>22</b> and fed to the stacking unit <b>26</b> by the diversion unit <b>31</b>. Meanwhile, each banknote P&#x2032; not judged as the genuine banknote, based on the recognition result sent from the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b>, is further transported by the transport unit <b>22</b> and fed to the reject unit <b>30</b> by the diversion unit <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Once the recognition and counting process for the banknotes P is performed, as described above, in the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b>, the count result on the banknotes, respectively judged as the genuine banknotes (i.e., the information on the total amount of money, e.g., 1,250 euros, of the counted banknotes P as well as on the number (PCS), e.g., 5 PCS, of the same banknotes P) and the country, from which such banknotes P are issued (this country may include a union of a plurality of countries, such as euro-zone countries (EUR) or the like), is displayed as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6(</figref><i>a</i>). In each of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6(</figref><i>a</i>) through <b>6</b>(<i>f</i>), four function keys, i.e., an F1 (first function) key <b>32</b><i>j</i>, an F2 (second function) key <b>32</b><i>k</i>, an F3 (third function) key <b>32</b><i>l </i>and an F4 (fourth function) key <b>32</b><i>m</i>, are shown, for reference, in a right-adjacent section relative to the display unit <b>32</b><i>p</i>. Further, in each of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6(</figref><i>a</i>) through <b>6</b>(<i>f</i>), various commands (e.g., MODE, MANUAL, DISPLAY, BATCH, arrows respectively indicating the upward direction and downward direction, and the like) are shown, respectively, in a left-adjacent portion, relative to the F1 key <b>32</b><i>j </i>to F4 key <b>32</b><i>m</i>, in the display unit <b>32</b><i>p</i>. In this case, each of such commands will be performed, when one of the four function keys <b>32</b><i>j </i>to <b>32</b><i>m </i>is pushed down.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Thereafter, the control unit <b>50</b> judges whether or not the input operation for the manually-obtained count result on the banknotes P is selected (STEP <b>2</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>). Specifically, in the case some banknotes P&#x2032; are fed to the reject unit <b>30</b>, the operator manually performs the counting process, for the banknotes or the like other than the counterfeit banknotes among the banknotes P&#x2032; fed to the reject unit <b>30</b>, more specifically, for the banknotes not respectively judged as the genuine banknote because of transport errors or recognition errors, and then inputs the manually-obtained count result on such banknotes to the control unit <b>50</b>, via the operation/display unit <b>32</b> (STEP <b>3</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>). More specifically, in the case a screen as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6(</figref><i>a</i>) is displayed on the display unit <b>32</b><i>p</i>, when the operator pushes down the F2 key <b>32</b><i>k </i>in order to select a manual mode, the display on the display unit <b>32</b><i>p </i>is changed into the screen as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6(</figref><i>b</i>). In this case, upon the judgment whether or not the manually-obtained count result on the banknotes is inputted to the control unit <b>50</b>, as shown in the STEP <b>2</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, when the operator pushes down the F2 key <b>32</b><i>k </i>to select the manual mode, the control unit <b>50</b> judges that an input operation for the manually-obtained count result on the banknotes has been selected.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Further, in the case the screen as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6(</figref><i>b</i>) is displayed on the display unit <b>32</b><i>p</i>, when the operator pushes down the F1 key <b>32</b><i>j </i>or F2 key <b>32</b><i>k </i>in the operation/display unit <b>32</b>, a cursor is moved upward or downward. Namely, with this operation, the cursor will be moved to a display point for displaying any one of related denominations (e.g., 500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5 (euros)). Thereafter, when the operator pushes down the F3 key <b>321</b>, the manually-obtained count result on the banknotes P can be added, for each denomination of money, to the count result on the banknotes P obtained by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b>, i.e., the number of the banknotes P for each denomination of money. Meanwhile, when the operator pushes down the F4 key <b>32</b><i>m </i>in the operation/display unit <b>32</b>, the number of the banknotes P, for each denomination of money, displayed on the screen shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6(</figref><i>b</i>) is decreased. In this way, the information concerning the manually-obtained count result on the banknotes P is inputted to the control unit <b>50</b>, via the operation/display unit <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Once the information concerning the manually-obtained count result on the banknotes P is inputted to the control unit <b>50</b>, via the operation/display unit <b>32</b>, the control unit <b>50</b> will judge whether or not the count result on the coins is inputted (STEP <b>4</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>). As a result, when the control unit <b>50</b> judges that the count result on the coins is inputted to the control unit <b>50</b> (e.g., in such a case that the operator has manually performed the counting process for the coins, or the like), the operator will input the information concerning the manually-obtained count result on the coins to the control unit <b>50</b>, via the operation/display unit <b>32</b> (STEP <b>5</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>). More specifically, in the case the screen as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6(</figref><i>b</i>) is displayed on the display unit <b>32</b><i>p</i>, when the operator pushes down the F1 key <b>32</b><i>j</i>, while pushing down the SHIFT key <b>32</b><i>b </i>(at this time, when the SHIFT key <b>32</b><i>b </i>is pushed down, an indication of &#x201c;COIN&#x201d; is displayed, in a left-adjacent point relative to the F1 key <b>32</b><i>j</i>), and then selects an input mode for inputting the count result on the coins, the display on the display unit <b>32</b><i>p </i>is changed into the screen as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6(</figref><i>c</i>). Namely, upon the judgment on whether or not the count result on the coins is inputted to the control unit <b>50</b>, as shown in the STEP <b>4</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, when the operator pushes down the F1 key <b>32</b><i>j</i>, while pushing down the SHIFT key <b>32</b><i>b</i>, and then selects the input mode for inputting the count result on the coins, the control unit <b>50</b> judges that the input operation for inputting the count result on the coins has been selected.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Further, in the case the screen as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6(</figref><i>c</i>) is displayed on the display unit <b>32</b><i>p</i>, when the operator pushes down the F1 key <b>32</b><i>j </i>or F2 key <b>32</b><i>k </i>in the operation/display unit <b>32</b>, a cursor is moved upward or downward. Namely, with this operation, the cursor will be moved to the display point for displaying any one of the related denominations (i.e., 1, 0.5, 0.2, 0.1, 0.05, 0.02, 0.01 (euros)). Thereafter, when the operator pushes down the F3 key <b>321</b> in the operation/display unit <b>32</b>, the manually-obtained count result on the coins can be increased, for each denomination of money. Meanwhile, when the operator pushes down the F4 key <b>32</b><i>m </i>in the operation/display unit <b>32</b>, the number of the coins, for each denomination of money, displayed in the screen shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6(</figref><i>c</i>) is decreased. In this way, the information concerning the manually-obtained count result on the coins is inputted to the control unit <b>50</b>, via the operation/display unit <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">It is noted that the method for inputting the information concerning the count result on the coins to the control unit <b>50</b> is not limited to such an aspect as described above. For instance, in place of using the method in which the operator manually performs the counting process for the coins and then inputs the manually-obtained count result on the coins to the control unit <b>50</b> via the operation/display unit <b>32</b>, the coin recognition and counting machine adapted for recognizing and counting the coins may be connected with the coin interface <b>53</b> of the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b>, such that the information concerning the count result on the coins counted by the coin recognition and counting machine can be inputted to the control unit <b>50</b> via the coin interface <b>53</b>. In this case, the need for the operator to perform the operation, via the operation/display unit <b>32</b>, while watching this display unit <b>32</b><i>p</i>, can be eliminated.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Thereafter, when the operator pushes down the ACCEPT key <b>32</b><i>e </i>or <b>32</b><i>i </i>in the operation/display unit <b>32</b>, a message or indication of &#x201c;ACCEPTED&#x201d; is displayed on the display unit <b>32</b><i>p</i>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6(</figref><i>d</i>). Thus, one transaction is accepted in the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b> (&#x201c;YES&#x201d; in the STEP <b>6</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5)</figref>. Then, the count result on the banknotes P counted by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b>, the manually-obtained count result on the banknotes P inputted via the operation/display unit <b>32</b>, and the count result on the coins inputted via the operation/display unit <b>32</b> or the like are respectively outputted (STEP <b>7</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>). During this operation, the information concerning the total of the count result on the banknotes P and the count result on the coins may be outputted. In this case, in the total sum of the count result on the banknotes P and the count result on the coins, the information concerning the total amount of money and/or information concerning the number of such money (i.e., the banknotes P and coins) for each denomination thereof is outputted. However, in place of outputting the information concerning the total of the count result on the banknotes P and the count result on the coins, the count result on the banknotes P and the count result on the coins may be outputted, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">In short, the information concerning the count result on the banknotes P and/or coins is displayed on the display unit <b>32</b><i>p </i>of the operation/display unit <b>32</b>. More specifically, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6(</figref><i>e</i>), the number of the banknotes P for each denomination of money and the total amount of money of the banknotes P and coins (T. TOTAL (TRANSACTION TOTAL): 1,250.52 euros) are displayed, respectively. Thereafter, in the state the screen as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6(</figref><i>e</i>) is displayed on the display unit <b>32</b><i>p</i>, when the F1 key <b>32</b><i>j </i>is pushed down in order to switch the screens, the display on the display unit <b>32</b><i>p </i>is changed into the screen as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6(</figref><i>f</i>). Thus, the number of the coins for each denomination of money and the total amount of money of the banknotes P and coins are displayed, respectively. In this case, in addition to the display of the information concerning the count result on the banknotes P or coins on the display unit <b>32</b><i>p</i>, or in place of the display of the information concerning the count result on the banknotes P or coins on the display unit <b>32</b><i>p</i>, the information concerning the count result on the banknotes P or coins may be printed on the printing unit <b>34</b>, such as the printer or the like. In this case, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the number for each denomination of money and total amount of money of the banknotes P, the number for each denomination of money and total amount of money of the coins, and the total amount of money of the banknotes P and coins are printed, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">Further, the information concerning the count result on the banknotes P or coins may be sent to the higher-ranking machine, such as the host computer or the like, via the external interface <b>52</b>. In addition, the information concerning the count result on the banknotes P or coins may be stored in the memory unit <b>36</b>. In this case, the memory unit <b>36</b> is composed of a first memory part <b>36</b><i>a </i>adapted for storing therein the information concerning the count result on the banknotes P respectively counted by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b>, and a second memory part <b>36</b><i>b </i>adapted for storing therein the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted via the operation/display unit <b>32</b> or the like. Namely, in this case, the information concerning the count results on the banknotes P and coins is stored, separately, in the corresponding memory unit parts <b>36</b><i>a</i>, <b>36</b><i>b</i>. For instance, two hard disks or the like are provided in the casing <b>12</b>, and one hard disk is provided as the first memory part <b>36</b><i>a</i>, and the other hard disk is provided as the second memory part <b>36</b><i>b</i>. Further, the information concerning the count result on the banknotes P or coins may be written in the storage medium by the storage-medium writing unit <b>38</b>, when this storage medium is inserted in the storage-medium writing unit <b>38</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">In this way, once the information concerning the count result on the banknotes P or coins is outputted by the display unit <b>32</b><i>p</i>, printing unit <b>34</b>, external interface <b>52</b>, storage-medium writing unit <b>38</b> or the like, a series of operations in the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b> is ended.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">If required, in the series of operations in the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b> as shown in the flow chart of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the step (STEP <b>2</b>) for judging whether or not the manually-obtained count result on the banknotes is inputted, and the step (STEP <b>3</b>) for inputting the information concerning the manually-obtained recognition result on the banknotes P via the operation/display unit <b>32</b> may be omitted respectively. In this case, however, once the recognition and counting process for the banknotes P is performed by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b>, only the information concerning the count result on the coins will be inputted to the control unit <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">As stated above, according to the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b> of this embodiment, the information concerning the count result on the coins is inputted through the input unit, and then the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit is sent to the control unit <b>50</b>. Thereafter, the information concerning the count result on the banknotes P counted by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b> and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit are respectively outputted from the output unit. Further, according to the money counting method of this embodiment, the recognition and counting process is performed, for the banknotes P respectively put from the outside into the casing <b>12</b> of the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b>, by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b>, while the information concerning the count result on the coins is inputted through the input unit. Then, the information concerning the count result on the banknotes P counted by the recognition and count unit <b>24</b> and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit are respectively outputted through the output unit. Thus, according to this banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b> and/or money counting method, the count result on the banknotes P can be outputted, as well as the count result on the coins can be outputted, by using the banknote recognition and counting machine <b>10</b> provided for recognizing and counting the banknotes P. As such, both of the information concerning the count result on the banknotes P and the information concerning the count result on the coins can be outputted, without the need for providing the external machine, such as the personal computer or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">For instance, the input unit is composed of the operation/display unit <b>32</b> provided to an outer face of the casing <b>12</b> and adapted for allowing a necessary command to be inputted to the control unit. Alternatively, the input unit may be composed of the coin interface <b>53</b>, which is connected, for communication, with the coin recognition and counting machine provided for recognizing and counting the coins, and is adapted for receiving the information concerning the count result on the coins from the coin recognition and counting machine. Further, as the input unit, any other suitable unit than the operation/display unit <b>32</b> or coin interface <b>53</b> may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">The output unit is composed of the display unit <b>32</b><i>p </i>adapted for displaying the information concerning the count result on the banknotes P counted by the recognition and count unit <b>24</b> and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit, or composed of the printing unit <b>34</b>, such as the printer or the like, adapted for printing the information concerning the count result on the banknotes P counted by the recognition and count unit <b>24</b> and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit. Otherwise, the output unit may be composed of the external interface <b>52</b> connected, for communication, with the external machine and adapted for sending the information concerning the count result on the banknotes P counted by the recognition and count unit <b>24</b> and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit, to the higher-ranking machine. Further, the output unit may be composed of the storage-medium writing unit <b>38</b> adapted for writing the information concerning the count result on the banknotes P counted by the recognition and count unit <b>24</b> and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit, in the external storage medium. In addition, as the output unit, any other suitable unit than the display unit <b>32</b><i>p</i>, printing unit <b>34</b>, external interface <b>52</b> and storage-medium writing unit <b>38</b> may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">Further, the output unit may be provided for outputting the information concerning the total of the count result on the banknotes P counted by the recognition and count unit <b>24</b> and the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit. In this case, the output unit may be provided for outputting the information concerning the total amount of money (see &#x201c;1,250,52 euros&#x201d; shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6(</figref><i>e</i>), <b>6</b>(<i>f</i>) and <b>7</b>) or information concerning the total number of the money for the each denomination of money (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7)</figref>, in the information concerning the total of the count result on the banknotes P counted by the recognition and count unit <b>24</b> and the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit. Alternatively, in place of outputting the information concerning the total of the count result on the banknotes P counted by the recognition and count unit <b>24</b> and the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit, the output unit may be provided for outputting the count result on the banknotes P counted by the recognition and count unit <b>24</b> and the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit, separately from each other.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">Further, as shown in the STEP <b>2</b> and STEP <b>3</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the input unit, such as the operation/display unit <b>32</b> or the like, may be provided for allowing the information concerning the manually-obtained count result on the banknotes P&#x2032; that cannot be recognized by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b>, to be inputted, in addition to the information concerning the count result on the coins.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">Further, the memory unit <b>36</b> may store therein the information concerning the count result on the banknotes P counted by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b> and the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit. In this case, the memory unit <b>36</b> is composed of the first memory part <b>36</b><i>a </i>adapted for storing therein the information concerning the count result on the banknotes P respectively counted by the recognition and counting unit <b>24</b>, and the second memory part <b>36</b><i>b </i>adapted for storing therein the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A banknote recognition and counting machine configured to recognize and count one or more banknotes, the machine comprising:
<claim-text>a casing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a recognition and counting unit provided in the casing and configured to recognize and count one or more banknotes, put from the outside into the casing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control unit connected with the recognition and counting unit and configured to receive a count result on one or more banknotes, sent from the recognition and counting unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an input unit connected with the control unit and configured to allow information concerning a count result on coins to be inputted, the information concerning the count result on the coins, that has been inputted through the input unit, being sent to the control unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an output unit connected with the control unit and configured to output information concerning the count result on one or more banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the input unit is an operation unit, from which an operator sends a command to the control unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the count result on the coins is manually obtained such that the operation unit sends the manually-obtained count result on coins to the control unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The banknote recognition and counting machine according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the output unit is configured to output information concerning the total of the count result on one or more banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit and the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The banknote recognition and counting machine according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the output unit is configured to output information concerning the total amount of money and/or information concerning the total number of money by denomination, in the total of the count result on one or more banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit and the count result on the coins, inputted through the input unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The banknote recognition and counting machine according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the input unit is capable of allowing the information concerning a manually-obtained count result on one or more banknotes that cannot be recognized by the recognition and counting unit, to be inputted, in addition to the information concerning the count result on the coins.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The banknote recognition and counting machine according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a memory unit connected with the control unit and configured to store therein the information concerning the count result on one or more banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The banknote recognition and counting machine according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the memory unit includes a first memory part configured to store therein the information concerning the count result on one or more banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit, and a second memory part configured to store therein the information concerning the count result on the coins, inputted through the input unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The banknote recognition and counting machine according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the output unit includes any one of: a display unit configured to display the information concerning the count result on one or more banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit; a printing unit configured to print the information concerning the count result on one or more banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit; an external interface unit connected, for communication, with an external machine and configured to send the information concerning the count result on one or more banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit, to the external machine; and a storage-medium writing unit configured to write the information concerning the count result on one or more banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the input unit, in an external storage medium.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A money counting method for counting money by using a banknote recognition and counting machine configured to recognize and count one or more banknotes, the method comprising:
<claim-text>recognizing and counting one or more banknotes, put from the outside into a casing of the banknote recognition and counting machine, by using a recognition and counting unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>inputting information concerning a count result on coins, through an operation unit, from which an operator sends a command; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>outputting information concerning a count result on one or more banknotes counted by the recognition and counting unit and the information concerning the count result on the coins inputted through the operation unit, through an output unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the count result on the coins is manually obtained, such that the operation unit sends the manually-obtained count result on coins to a control unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
