<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624501-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624501</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12963209</doc-number>
<date>20101208</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>470</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>24</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>31511151</main-classification>
<further-classification>315352</further-classification>
<further-classification>315354</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Measuring and controlling parameters of a plasma generator</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6150628</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Smith et al.</name>
<date>20001100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>21912154</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6388226</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Smith et al.</name>
<date>20020500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>21912157</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6486431</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Smith et al.</name>
<date>20021100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>21912157</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6559408</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Smith et al.</name>
<date>20030500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>21912157</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7541558</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Smith et al.</name>
<date>20090600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>21912141</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7569790</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Holber et al.</name>
<date>20090800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>21912141</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0150386</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Gonzalez et al.</name>
<date>20040800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0086699</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Holber et al.</name>
<date>20060400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0088655</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Collins et al.</name>
<date>20060400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0179948</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Nagarkatti et al.</name>
<date>20080700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0218324</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Or et al.</name>
<date>20090900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO-2006/078340</doc-number>
<kind>A2</kind>
<date>20060700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00013">
<othercit>International Search Report for PCT/US2011/057814, Dec. 30, 2011, 12 pages.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>31</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>31511151</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>315344</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>315352</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>315354</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>15634548</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>15634549</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120146508</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120614</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nagarkatti</last-name>
<first-name>Siddharth P.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Acton</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Shajii</last-name>
<first-name>Ali</first-name>
<address>
<city>Weston</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Benzerrouk</last-name>
<first-name>Souheil</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hudson</city>
<state>NH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nagarkatti</last-name>
<first-name>Siddharth P.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Acton</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Shajii</last-name>
<first-name>Ali</first-name>
<address>
<city>Weston</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Benzerrouk</last-name>
<first-name>Souheil</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hudson</city>
<state>NH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Proskauer Rose LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>MKS Instruments, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Andover</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Tran</last-name>
<first-name>Thuy Vinh</first-name>
<department>2821</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Methods, systems, and computer program products are described for measuring and controlling parameters of a plasma generator. A current in a primary winding of a transformer or inductive element that generates a plasma is measured. A voltage across a secondary winding of the transformer or inductive element is measured. Based on the current of the primary winding and the voltage across the secondary winding, a parameter of the plasma is determined. The parameter includes a resistance value associated with the plasma, a power value associated with the plasma, or both.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="173.31mm" wi="123.95mm" file="US08624501-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="165.78mm" wi="138.60mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624501-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="182.12mm" wi="68.07mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624501-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="193.89mm" wi="122.94mm" file="US08624501-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The description generally relates to measuring and controlling parameters of a plasma generator.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Plasma discharges can be used to excite gases to produce activated gases containing ions, free radicals, atoms and molecules. Activated gases are used in numerous industrial and scientific applications including processing solid materials such as semiconductor wafers, powders, and other gases.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Plasma can be generated in various ways including DC discharge, RF discharge, and microwave discharge. RF discharges produce high energy ions and, therefore, are often used to generate plasmas for applications where the material being processed comes into contact with the plasma. RF discharges can be achieved by electrostatically or inductively coupling energy from a power supply to a plasma. Inductively-coupled plasma generators typically employ complex power delivery systems. In addition, precision instrumentation is usually required to ascertain and/or control the power reaching the plasma.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Various approaches exist for ascertaining and/or controlling power reaching the plasma in an inductively-coupled plasma generator. For example, some approaches estimate plasma power using input voltage supplied to the plasma and/or current in the primary winding of the transformer for generating plasma. Existing approaches for determining parameters of plasmas produced in inductively-coupled plasma generators typically focus on either the primary-side or the secondary-side coils of the inductive element. One problem with existing approaches is a failure to provide direct or precise measurements of power delivered to the plasma, in part due to the distance of the measurement equipment from the inductive element and/or the presence of intervening elements. Another potential problem is failure of existing techniques to accurately estimate or characterize plasma resistance, due in part, again, to the distance of the measurement equipment from the inductive-element. Because plasma power and plasma resistance can be used to accurately and efficiently control power delivery to the plasma, ensure repeatability of the process for plasma generation, and diagnose process-related issues, better techniques for measuring and controlling functionality of plasma generators are needed.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Because plasma power and plasma resistance can be used to accurately and efficiently control power delivery to the plasma, ensure repeatability of the process for plasma generation, and/or diagnose process-related issues, improved techniques for accurately and precisely measuring and controlling parameters or functionality of a plasma generator are desirable. The concepts described herein control parameters of a plasma generator based on electrical parameters or properties of the plasma produced, such as plasma resistance and plasma power. Advantageously, using plasma-related parameters to control functionality of plasma generators enhances the accuracy and/or precision with which plasma is produced and promotes repeatability of the process for operating a plasma generator.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">One advantage of the described implementation that is realized results from positioning measurement equipment and sensors close to the inductive element, on both the primary side and the secondary side. Such a configuration allows more precise measurements and/or more accurate characterizations of the plasma behavior or properties. This advantage is achieved, in part, because the techniques involved do not characterize the plasma or its behavior with respect to the secondary-side of the inductive element based on measurements made only on the primary side of the inductive element, or vice versa (e.g., characterizing primary-side behavior of the plasma based only on secondary-side measurements). Instead, the present technique measures electrical parameters of both the primary and secondary side of the inductive element to model and characterize the generated plasma, e.g., to determine plasma resistance and/or plasma power.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In one aspect, there is a method. The method involves measuring a current of a primary winding of a transformer or other inductive element that generates a plasma and measuring a voltage across a secondary winding of the transformer. The method also involves determining a parameter of the plasma based on the current of the primary winding and the voltage across the secondary winding. The parameter includes a resistance value associated with the plasma, a power value associated with the plasma, or both.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Another aspect features a method for controlling a toroidal plasma. The method involves measuring a current of a primary winding of a transformer that generates the toroidal plasma and measuring a voltage across a secondary winding of the transformer. The method involves measuring an input voltage supplied to the transformer and estimating a power value of the plasma based on the current of the primary winding and the voltage across the secondary winding. The method involves regulating a power delivered to the plasma based on the estimated power value.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In another aspect, there is a system. The system includes a first module configured to measure a current of a primary winding of a transformer that generates a toroidal plasma and a voltage across a secondary winding of the transformer. The system includes a second module in communication with the first module, the second module configured to determine a parameter of the toroidal plasma based on the current of the primary winding and the voltage across the secondary winding. The parameter includes a resistance value associated with the plasma, a power value associated with the plasma, or both.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Yet another aspect relates to a toroidal plasma generator. The toroidal plasma generator includes a plasma chamber and a transformer or other inductive element having a magnetic core surrounding a portion of the plasma chamber and a primary winding. The toroidal plasma generator includes a power supply in electrical communication with the primary winding. The power supply supplies a current to the primary winding, and the supplied current induces a toroidal plasma in the plasma chamber. The toroidal plasma generator further includes a module for estimating a parameter of the toroidal plasma by measuring the current of the primary winding and a voltage across a secondary winding of the transformer. The parameter includes a resistance value associated with the toroidal plasma, a power value associated with the toroidal plasma, or both.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Another aspect involves a computer program product tangibly embodied in an information carrier. The information carrier is a non-transitory, computer-readable storage medium. The computer program product includes instructions operable to cause data processing apparatus to receive a measured value for a current of a primary winding of a transformer used to generate a plasma in a plasma chamber and a measured value for a voltage across a secondary winding of the transformer. The computer program product includes instructions operable to cause data processing apparatus to determine a parameter of the plasma based on the current of the primary winding and the voltage across the secondary winding according to a model of the plasma that relates the current of the primary winding to the current in the secondary winding and the voltage across the secondary winding. The parameter includes a resistance value associated with the plasma, a power value associated with the plasma, or both.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Any of the aspects above can include one or more of the following features in one or more embodiments. In some embodiments, the parameter of the plasma is determined based on a model of the plasma that relates the current of the primary winding to the current in the secondary winding and the voltage across the secondary winding. In some embodiments, the model of the plasma is updated based on measured values of the current of the primary winding and the voltage across the secondary winding. An iterative filter can be used to estimate the parameter of the plasma based on the model of the plasma. An example of an iterative filter is a Kalman filter.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Some embodiments involve determining a root-mean-square (RMS) equivalent of the current of the primary winding. Determining the RMS equivalent of the current of the primary winding can involve several steps, such as using a rectifier to rectify the current in the primary winding, using a differential amplifier in cooperation with a filter to compute an average of the rectified primary current, using a converter to sample the average primary current, and using a processor module to convert the sampled primary current to the RMS equivalent current of the primary winding.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Some embodiments involve determining an RMS equivalent of the voltage across the secondary winding. Determining the RMS equivalent of the voltage across the secondary winding can involve several steps, such as using a rectifier to rectify the voltage in the secondary winding, using a differential amplifier in cooperation with a filter to compute an average of the rectified secondary voltage, using a converter to sample the average secondary voltage and using a processor module to convert the sampled secondary voltage to the RMS equivalent voltage of the secondary winding.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In some embodiments, determining the parameter of the plasma includes the steps of estimating an RMS current of the secondary winding and an RMS voltage of the secondary winding, and estimating a phase between the estimated RMS current of the secondary winding and the RMS voltage of the secondary winding. Determining the parameter of the plasma can involve the steps of estimating the power value based on the estimated RMS current of the secondary winding, the RMS voltage of the secondary winding and the phase, and estimating the resistance value based on the RMS voltage of the secondary winding and the estimated power value. Determining the parameter of the plasma can involve repeating the above-recited steps until an error associated with estimating the resistance value satisfies a predetermined criterion such as, for example, when a difference between an estimated resistance value of the present iteration and an estimated resistance value of the previous iteration is below a threshold.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The RMS current of the secondary winding can be estimated based on an RMS current of the primary winding and a correction factor computed based on the resistance value, a core inductance value, and an angular frequency. Phase values can estimated based on the resistance value, a plasma inductance value, and a frequency.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Some embodiments feature regulation of the power delivered to the plasma based on a determined power value. Regulating the power delivered to the plasma can involve, for example, computing a difference between a predetermined power setpoint and the determined power value and determining a new power value based on the difference. The power is regulated, in some implementations, in a feedback loop.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In some embodiments, an input voltage supplied to the plasma is measured and used to compensate for input-line voltage ripple. Compensating for input-line voltage ripple can involve adjusting a switching frequency to regulate the power supplied to the plasma. Some examples involve monitoring at least one of the power value and the resistance value to detect an unsafe operating condition associated with a toroidal plasma chamber. A deviation of at least one of the power value and the resistance value from a predetermined value can be detected.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">These and other features will be more fully understood by reference to the following description and drawings, which are illustrative and not necessarily to scale.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an exemplary toroidal plasma generator.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an exemplary circuit for measuring and computing electrical parameters of the primary or secondary winding of a transformer.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an exemplary circuit for computing electrical parameters related to a plasma.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an exemplary toroidal plasma generator <b>100</b>. The plasma generator <b>100</b> includes a switching power supply <b>104</b>. The switching power supply <b>104</b> includes a voltage supply <b>108</b> coupled to and/or in electrical communication with a switching circuit <b>112</b>. The plasma generator <b>100</b> includes an ignition control circuit <b>116</b> and a power transformer <b>120</b> for coupling electromagnetic energy into a plasma <b>124</b>. The power transformer <b>120</b> (e.g., an inductive element) is in electrical communication with circuits <b>128</b> and <b>132</b> for measuring electrical parameters of the power transformer <b>120</b>. The circuits <b>128</b> and <b>132</b> can be physical circuits implemented in hardware or logical circuits implemented in software, or a combination of these. A third circuit <b>136</b> communicates with the circuits <b>128</b> and <b>132</b> to compute certain parameters about the power transformer <b>120</b>, the plasma <b>124</b>, or of the plasma generator <b>100</b>. The plasma generator <b>100</b> includes a control circuit <b>140</b> configured to accept electrical parameters (or values thereof) from circuit <b>128</b>, circuit <b>132</b>, and/or circuit <b>136</b> and, based on these inputs, regulates certain operations of the plasma generator <b>100</b> by adjusting various operational parameters to achieve desired properties of or in the plasma <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The power transformer <b>120</b> includes a primary coil <b>144</b>, a secondary winding <b>148</b>, a high permeability magnetic core <b>150</b>, and a plasma chamber <b>158</b>. The plasma chamber <b>158</b> allows the plasma <b>124</b> to form a secondary circuit (not shown) of the transformer <b>120</b>. The power transformer <b>120</b> can include additional magnetic cores (not shown) and primary coils (not shown) that form additional secondary circuits (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The plasma chamber <b>158</b> can be formed from a metallic material such as aluminum or a refractory metal, or can be formed from a dielectric material such as quartz. One or more sides <b>160</b> of the plasma chamber <b>158</b> can be exposed to a process chamber <b>162</b> to allow charged particles generated by the plasma <b>124</b> to be in contact with a material to be processed (not shown). A sample holder <b>166</b> can be positioned in the process chamber <b>162</b> to support the material to be processed. The material to be processed can be biased relative to the potential of the plasma <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The voltage supply <b>108</b> can be a line voltage supply or a bus voltage supply. The switching circuit <b>112</b> includes one or more switching semiconductor devices <b>170</b> such as, for example, switching transistors. The one or more switching semiconductor devices <b>170</b> can be switching transistors. The switching circuit <b>112</b> can be a solid state switching circuit. An output <b>174</b> of the switching circuit <b>112</b> can be coupled to the primary winding <b>144</b> of the transformer <b>120</b> and/or in electrical communication therewith.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The plasma generator <b>100</b> can include a means (not shown) for generating free charges that provides an initial ionization event for igniting a plasma in the plasma chamber <b>158</b>. In some embodiments, the ignition control circuit <b>116</b> controls and/or influences the initial ionization event. The initial ionization event can be a short, high voltage pulse that is applied to the plasma chamber <b>158</b>. In some embodiments, the pulse has a voltage of approximately 500-10,000 volts and can last approximately 0.1 to 10 microseconds. A noble gas such as argon can be inserted into the plasma chamber <b>158</b> to induce the voltage required to ignite the plasma <b>124</b>. Ultraviolet radiation can also be used to generate the free charges in the plasma chamber <b>158</b> that provide the initial ionization event for igniting the plasma <b>124</b> in the plasma chamber <b>158</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In some embodiments, the switching power supply <b>104</b> generates the short, high voltage electric pulse and applies it across the primary winding <b>144</b> of the transformer <b>120</b>. This excitation voltage induces a high voltage current in the primary winding <b>144</b>, thereby generating an alternating magnetic field through the magnetic core (not shown) across a path of the gas in the plasma chamber <b>158</b>. As a result, current is induced within the gas of the plasma chamber <b>158</b>, causing its ignition into a plasma <b>124</b>. In some embodiments, a second transformer primary in the form of a winding <b>178</b> is introduced to assist ignition. The secondary primary winding <b>178</b> wraps about a portion of the magnetic core (not shown) of the transformer <b>120</b>. When the power supply <b>102</b> applies the short, high voltage electric pulse across the primary winding <b>144</b>, a current is induced within the secondary primary winding <b>178</b> according to a turn ratio. A lead of the secondary primary winding <b>178</b> is connected to one or more ignition electrodes (not shown) arranged about or within the plasma chamber <b>158</b>. During plasma ignition, the voltage on the lead is applied to the ignition electrodes that capacitively couple energy to the gas flowing within the plasma chamber <b>158</b> to ignite and sustain a plasma. Other techniques for causing the initial ionization event that ignites a plasma also exist. For example, in some embodiments, the short, high voltage electric pulse is applied to an electrode <b>182</b> that is capacitively coupled to the plasma chamber <b>158</b> by a dielectric material (not shown). In some embodiments, the plasma chamber <b>158</b> is exposed to ultraviolet radiation from an ultraviolet light source <b>186</b> that is optically coupled to the plasma chamber <b>158</b>. The ultraviolet radiation causes the initial ionization event that ignites the plasma. In any of these embodiments, the ignition control circuit <b>116</b> can control the application or parameters of electric pulses to the ignition elements (<b>178</b>, <b>182</b>, <b>186</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In some embodiments, the ignition control circuit <b>116</b> increases the voltage of the primary winding <b>144</b> of the transformer <b>120</b> above its normal operating voltage prior to and/or during ignition and energizes the electrode <b>178</b> to provide initial ionization events to assist ignition. The ignition control circuit <b>116</b> can also control the current of the switching power supply <b>104</b> to protect circuit components in the switching circuit <b>112</b> and/or in the switching semiconductor devices <b>170</b> of the switching power supply <b>104</b>, such as one or more MOSFETs, MOSFET drivers, charge resistors and discharge resistors. The ignition control circuit <b>116</b> can include a resonance capacitor <b>190</b> and a switching device <b>194</b>. The resonance capacitor <b>190</b> is in electrical communication with the primary winding <b>144</b> and the switching power supply <b>104</b>. The switching device <b>194</b> switches the resonance capacitor <b>190</b> on or off from the primary winding <b>144</b> and the switching power supply <b>104</b>. The switching device <b>194</b> can be a mechanical switch or a solid-state switch.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The resonance capacitor <b>190</b> is connected in series with the primary winding <b>144</b> and the switching power supply <b>250</b>. Prior to and during the ignition of the plasma <b>124</b>, the control circuit <b>140</b> causes the switching device <b>194</b> to switch in the resonance capacitor <b>190</b> so that a resonant circuit is formed at the switching frequency of the switching power supply <b>104</b>. The resonant circuit increases the voltage on the primary winding to a resonance voltage that can be between 1 to 10 times higher than the normal operating voltage supplied by the switching power supply <b>104</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In operation, a gas is bled into the plasma chamber <b>158</b> of the transformer <b>120</b> until a pressure substantially between 1 millitorr and 100 millitorr is reached. The gas can comprise a noble gas, a reactive gas or a mixture of at least one noble gas and at least one reactive gas. The switching circuit <b>112</b> supplies a current to the primary winding <b>144</b> that induces a potential inside the plasma chamber <b>158</b>. The magnitude of the induced potential depends on the magnetic field produced by the core <b>150</b> and the frequency at which the switching semiconductor devices <b>170</b> operate according to Faraday's law of induction. An ionization event that forms the plasma can be initiated in the chamber <b>158</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Once the gas is ionized, the plasma <b>124</b> is formed which completes a secondary circuit (not shown) of the transformer <b>120</b>. The electric field of the plasma can be substantially between 1-100 Volts/centimeter. If primarily noble gases are present in the plasma chamber <b>158</b>, the electric fields in the plasma <b>124</b> can be as low as 1 Volt/centimeter. If electronegative gases are present in the chamber <b>158</b>, the electric fields in the plasma <b>124</b> are considerably higher.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In some embodiments, the circuit <b>128</b> measures electrical parameters of the primary winding <b>144</b> of the transformer <b>120</b> and the circuit <b>132</b> measures electrical parameters of the secondary winding <b>148</b>. Exemplary electrical parameters of the primary winding <b>144</b> include the current driving the primary winding <b>144</b>, the voltage across the primary winding <b>144</b>, and the bus or line voltage supply generated by the voltage supply <b>108</b>. Exemplary electrical parameters of the secondary winding <b>148</b> include the current in the secondary winding <b>148</b> and the voltage across the secondary winding <b>148</b>. The circuits <b>128</b> and <b>132</b> can also include means for processing and converting the measured electrical parameters to forms suitable for use by other components of the plasma generator <b>100</b>. For example, the circuits <b>128</b> and <b>132</b> can convert or calculate raw voltage, resistance, or current values into root-mean-square (RMS) voltage, resistance, or current values. The computation circuit <b>136</b> uses electrical parameters measured from the primary and secondary windings <b>144</b>, <b>148</b> (and communicated, respectively, by the circuits <b>128</b> and <b>132</b>) to estimate parameters and/or properties associated with the plasma, such as plasma resistance and plasma power. Other parameters characterizing the plasma can also be determined or calculated based on the measured values.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The plasma generator <b>100</b> includes the control circuit <b>140</b> for regulating operation of the plasma generator <b>100</b>. The control circuit <b>140</b> includes a controller module <b>196</b> and a summation module <b>198</b>, at least one of which implements routines or processes to determine and/or realize desired parameters/properties for the plasma <b>124</b>. The control circuit <b>140</b> can be implemented on one or more processors.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an exemplary configuration <b>200</b> describing the general flow for calculating properties of the inductive element of an inductively-coupled plasma generator. The configuration <b>200</b> can be used in cooperation with the circuit <b>128</b> in communication with the primary winding <b>144</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The circuit <b>128</b> measures and processes electrical parameters of the primary winding <b>144</b> of the transformer <b>120</b>. The configuration <b>200</b> can be used in cooperation with the circuit <b>132</b> for measuring and processing electrical parameters of the secondary winding <b>148</b>. In some embodiments, circuit <b>128</b> (in the configuration <b>200</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) measures a sinusoidal current in the primary winding <b>144</b> and converts the measured current to a form suitable for use by the computation circuit <b>136</b>. In some embodiments, circuit <b>132</b> (in the configuration <b>200</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) measures a sinusoidal voltage in the secondary winding <b>148</b> and converts the measured voltage to a form suitable for use by the computation circuit <b>136</b>. The configuration <b>200</b> includes a measuring device <b>204</b> in electrical communication with a rectifier element <b>208</b>. An output of the rectifier element <b>208</b> is coupled to and/or in electrical communication with a differential amplifier element <b>212</b> and a filter element <b>216</b> which, in turn, communicate with an analog-to-digital converter element <b>220</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In some embodiments, the measuring device <b>204</b> is a sensor to measure current in the primary winding <b>144</b>. The resulting current measurement is converted to a rectified current with or by the rectifier element <b>208</b>. The rectifier element <b>208</b> can be, for example, a full-wave rectifier. The rectified current is supplied to and processed by the differential amplifier element <b>212</b> and the filter element <b>216</b> to generate an average current. In some embodiments, the filter element <b>216</b> is a Sallen-key filter. The analog-to-digital converter element <b>220</b> then samples the average current to generate a sampled average current of the primary winding <b>144</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In some embodiments, the measuring device <b>204</b> is an ohmic divider to measure voltage across the secondary winding <b>148</b>. The measured voltage is converted to a rectified voltage with the rectifier element <b>208</b>. In some embodiments, the rectifier element <b>208</b> is a full-wave rectifier. The rectified voltage is supplied to and processed by the differential amplifier element <b>212</b> and the filter element <b>216</b> to generate an average voltage. In some embodiments, the filter element <b>216</b> is a Sallen-key filter. The analog-to-digital converter <b>220</b> element then samples the average voltage to generate a sampled average voltage across the secondary winding <b>148</b>. The configuration <b>200</b> (or elements <b>208</b>, <b>212</b>, <b>216</b>, or <b>220</b> thereof) can be implemented on one or more processors regardless of whether the configuration <b>200</b> cooperates with the circuit <b>128</b>, the circuit <b>132</b>, or both.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an exemplary computation circuit <b>300</b> illustrating a general flow for determining parameters of a plasma in an inductively-coupled plasma generator. The computation circuit <b>300</b> can be used, for example, in cooperation with the computation circuit <b>136</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> for computing plasma resistance and/or plasma power based on electrical parameters or values of the primary winding <b>144</b> and secondary winding <b>148</b> of the power transformer <b>120</b>. An input <b>304</b> of the computation circuit <b>300</b> can be the sampled average current in the primary winding determined by circuit <b>128</b> (e.g., calculated as discussed with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). Another input <b>308</b> can be the sampled average voltage across the secondary winding determined by circuit <b>132</b> (e.g., calculated as discussed with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In some embodiments, the computation circuit <b>300</b> implements mathematical algorithms that model aspects or features of the plasma. For example, the electrical properties of a plasma can be modeled by, e.g., relating the current in the primary winding <b>144</b> of the transformer <b>120</b> to the current and/or voltage of the secondary winding <b>148</b> of the transformer <b>120</b>. Electrical parameters of a plasma, such as plasma resistance and plasma power, can be estimated based on the current and/or voltage of the secondary winding <b>148</b> as they relate to the current in the primary winding <b>144</b>. Moreover, the measured parameters of the plasma can be used or incorporated to update or refine the model, based on observed properties or parameters measured during operation.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates an exemplary technique for determining parameters or properties of a plasma based on a model of the function of a plasma and for updating features of the model based on the determined parameters or properties. Input <b>304</b> is provided to module <b>312</b>. In some embodiments, module <b>312</b> converts the sampled average current in the primary winding (I<sub>p</sub><sub><sub2>&#x2014;</sub2></sub><sub>avg</sub>) provided by input <b>304</b> to an equivalent root-mean-square (RMS) value (I<sub>p</sub><sub><sub2>&#x2014;</sub2></sub><sub>RMS</sub>) based on the following equation:</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">
<maths id="MATH-US-00001" num="00001">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <msub>
    <mi>I</mi>
    <mi>p_RMS</mi>
  </msub>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mrow>
    <mfrac>
      <mi>&#x3c0;</mi>
      <mrow>
        <mn>2</mn>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <msqrt>
          <mn>2</mn>
        </msqrt>
      </mrow>
    </mfrac>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <mrow>
      <msub>
        <mi>I</mi>
        <mi>P_avg</mi>
      </msub>
      <mo>.</mo>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">An output of module <b>312</b> is communicated to module <b>318</b>. In some embodiments, module <b>318</b> computes an RMS current of the secondary winding (I<sub>s</sub><sub><sub2>&#x2014;hd RMS</sub2></sub>) based on the estimated RMS current of the primary winding (I<sub>p</sub><sub><sub2>&#x2014;</sub2></sub><sub>RMS</sub>) provided by module <b>312</b> using the following equation:</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">
<maths id="MATH-US-00002" num="00002">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <mrow>
    <msub>
      <mi>I</mi>
      <mi>s_RMS</mi>
    </msub>
    <mo>=</mo>
    <mrow>
      <mfrac>
        <mi>kN</mi>
        <msqrt>
          <mrow>
            <mn>1</mn>
            <mo>+</mo>
            <msup>
              <mi>&#x25b;</mi>
              <mn>2</mn>
            </msup>
          </mrow>
        </msqrt>
      </mfrac>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <msub>
        <mi>I</mi>
        <mi>p_RMS</mi>
      </msub>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
  <mo>,</mo>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
where k is a coupling coefficient of the transformer <b>120</b>, N represents the number of turns of the primary coil <b>144</b> around the transformer core <b>150</b> and &#x2208; is a plasma resistance correction factor. In some embodiments, N is 2. The above equation relates the current in the primary winding <b>144</b> to the current in the secondary winding <b>148</b>.
</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In some embodiments, the plasma resistance correction factor (&#x2208;) is computed by module <b>322</b> as follows:</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">
<maths id="MATH-US-00003" num="00003">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <mrow>
    <mi>&#x25b;</mi>
    <mo>=</mo>
    <mfrac>
      <msub>
        <mi>R</mi>
        <mi>plasma</mi>
      </msub>
      <mrow>
        <mi>&#x3c9;</mi>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <mstyle>
          <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
        </mstyle>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <msub>
          <mi>L</mi>
          <mn>0</mn>
        </msub>
      </mrow>
    </mfrac>
  </mrow>
  <mo>,</mo>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
where L<sub>0 </sub>is a inductance of the core <b>150</b>, &#x3c9; is an angular frequency, and R<sub>plasma </sub>is a plasma resistance. The core inductance (L<sub>0</sub>) can be a system constant that is measured a priori. The core inductance (L<sub>0</sub>) can also be determined dynamically during the computational process. The plasma resistance (R<sub>plasma</sub>) is computed at module <b>334</b>, explained in more detail below.
</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Input <b>308</b> is provided to module <b>314</b>. In some embodiments, module <b>314</b> converts the sampled average voltage across the secondary winding (V<sub>s</sub><sub><sub2>&#x2014;</sub2></sub><sub>avg</sub>) provided by input <b>308</b> to an equivalent RMS value (V<sub>s</sub><sub><sub2>&#x2014;</sub2></sub><sub>RMS</sub>) using the following equation:</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">
<maths id="MATH-US-00004" num="00004">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <msub>
    <mi>V</mi>
    <mi>s_RMS</mi>
  </msub>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mrow>
    <mfrac>
      <mi>&#x3c0;</mi>
      <mrow>
        <mn>2</mn>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <msqrt>
          <mn>2</mn>
        </msqrt>
      </mrow>
    </mfrac>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <mrow>
      <msub>
        <mi>V</mi>
        <mi>s_avg</mi>
      </msub>
      <mo>.</mo>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Module <b>326</b> estimates a phase (&#x3c6;) between the voltage across the secondary winding <b>148</b> and the current in the secondary winding <b>148</b> using the following equation:</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">
<maths id="MATH-US-00005" num="00005">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <mrow>
    <mi>&#x3d5;</mi>
    <mo>=</mo>
    <mrow>
      <msup>
        <mi>tan</mi>
        <mrow>
          <mo>-</mo>
          <mn>1</mn>
        </mrow>
      </msup>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mo>{</mo>
        <mfrac>
          <mrow>
            <mn>2</mn>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mi>&#x3c0;</mi>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mi>f</mi>
            <mo>*</mo>
            <msub>
              <mi>L</mi>
              <mi>plasma</mi>
            </msub>
          </mrow>
          <msub>
            <mi>R</mi>
            <mi>plasma</mi>
          </msub>
        </mfrac>
        <mo>}</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
  <mo>,</mo>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
where f is a frequency of the processor on which circuit <b>300</b> is implemented, L<sub>plasma </sub>is a plasma inductance and R<sub>plasma </sub>is the plasma resistance. In some embodiments, at least one of the frequency (f) and the plasma inductance (L<sub>plasma</sub>) is known a priori. In some embodiments, at least one of the frequency (f) and plasma inductance (L<sub>plasma</sub>) is determined dynamically (or iteratively, via the computation of the plasma parameters). The plasma resistance (R<sub>plasma</sub>) can be computed at module <b>334</b>, explained in more detail below.
</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Outputs from modules <b>314</b>, <b>318</b> and <b>326</b> are provided to module <b>330</b> to compute a value for the power delivered to the plasma (P<sub>plasma</sub>) using the following equation:
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>P</i><sub>plasma</sub><i>=V</i><sub>s</sub><sub><sub2>&#x2014;</sub2></sub><sub>RMS</sub><i>I</i><sub>s</sub><sub><sub2>&#x2014;</sub2></sub><sub>RMS </sub>cos(&#x3c6;),<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
where V<sub>s</sub><sub><sub2>&#x2014;hd RMS </sub2></sub>is the RMS voltage across the secondary winding <b>148</b> obtained from module <b>314</b>, I<sub>s</sub><sub><sub2>&#x2014;</sub2></sub><sub>RMS </sub>is the RMS current in the secondary winding <b>148</b> obtained from module <b>318</b>, and &#x3c6; is the angle between the RMS voltage and the RMS current obtained from module <b>326</b>.
</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Outputs of modules <b>314</b> and <b>330</b> are provided to module <b>334</b> that estimates the plasma resistance (R<sub>plasma</sub>) using the following differential equation:</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">
<maths id="MATH-US-00006" num="00006">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <mrow>
    <mfrac>
      <mrow>
        <mo>&#x2146;</mo>
        <msub>
          <mi>R</mi>
          <mi>plasma</mi>
        </msub>
      </mrow>
      <mrow>
        <mo>&#x2146;</mo>
        <mi>t</mi>
      </mrow>
    </mfrac>
    <mo>=</mo>
    <mrow>
      <mfrac>
        <mn>1</mn>
        <mi>&#x3c4;</mi>
      </mfrac>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mo>{</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mfrac>
            <msubsup>
              <mi>V</mi>
              <mi>s_RMS</mi>
              <mn>2</mn>
            </msubsup>
            <msub>
              <mi>P</mi>
              <mi>plasma</mi>
            </msub>
          </mfrac>
          <mo>-</mo>
          <msub>
            <mi>R</mi>
            <mi>plasma</mi>
          </msub>
        </mrow>
        <mo>}</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
  <mo>,</mo>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
where V<sub>s</sub><sub><sub2>&#x2014;</sub2></sub><sub>RMS </sub>is the RMS voltage across the secondary winding <b>148</b> obtained from module <b>314</b>, P<sub>plasma </sub>is the plasma power obtained from module <b>330</b>, and &#x3c4; is a time constant associated with an iterative filter used to estimate the value of plasma resistance (R<sub>plasma</sub>) by solving the differential equation. The filter for solving the differential equation can be a Kalman filter. The filter (or an operator) can select an initial estimate of the plasma resistance (R<sub>plasma</sub>) to affect or optimize convergence of the iterative process. For example, the initial value of the plasma resistance
</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">
<maths id="MATH-US-00007" num="00007">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <mrow>
    <mo>(</mo>
    <msub>
      <mi>R</mi>
      <mi>plasma</mi>
    </msub>
    <mo>)</mo>
  </mrow>
  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
  <mstyle>
    <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
  </mstyle>
  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
  <mi>can</mi>
  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
  <mstyle>
    <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
  </mstyle>
  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
  <mi>be</mi>
  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
  <mstyle>
    <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
  </mstyle>
  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
  <mrow>
    <mfrac>
      <msub>
        <mi>V</mi>
        <mi>s_RMS</mi>
      </msub>
      <msub>
        <mi>I</mi>
        <mi>s_RMS</mi>
      </msub>
    </mfrac>
    <mo>.</mo>
  </mrow>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
In some embodiments, computation in modules <b>318</b>-<b>334</b> is iteratively repeated until the process converges at which point an error associated with estimating the resistance value satisfies a predetermined criterion. An example of a predetermined criterion is when the difference between an estimated resistance value in the present iteration and an estimated resistance value in the previous iteration is below a threshold.
</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">At least a portion of modules <b>304</b>-<b>334</b> of the computation circuit <b>300</b> implement mathematical algorithms to estimate plasma-related properties, such as, for example, plasma power and/or plasma resistance. The computation circuit <b>300</b> can be implemented on one or more processors. In some embodiments, the computation circuit <b>300</b> is implemented on a digital signal processor.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, control circuit <b>140</b> can regulate operation of the plasma generator <b>100</b> based on computations and/or measurements obtained from at least one of the computation circuit <b>136</b>, the circuit <b>128</b> for measuring and processing electrical parameters of the primary winding <b>144</b>, and the circuit <b>132</b> for measuring and processing electrical parameters of the secondary winding <b>148</b>. In some embodiments, the control circuit <b>104</b> regulates ignition voltage prior to and/or during plasma ignition based on the voltage across the secondary winding <b>148</b> measured by the circuit <b>132</b>. In some embodiments, the control circuit <b>104</b> regulates power supplied to the plasma load <b>124</b> after plasma ignition based on the plasma power computed at the circuit <b>136</b>. In some embodiments, the control circuit <b>104</b> regulates current driving the plasma load <b>124</b> after plasma ignition based on the current in the secondary winding <b>148</b> computed by the circuit <b>136</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In some embodiments, after ignition of the plasma <b>124</b>, the power delivered to the plasma <b>124</b> is regulated using a feedback loop comprising the computation circuit <b>136</b>, the control circuit <b>140</b>, and the switching power supply <b>104</b>. More specifically, the control circuit <b>140</b> uses the plasma power estimated by the computation circuit <b>136</b> to adjust operation of the switching power supply <b>104</b>, thereby controlling power delivered to the plasma load <b>124</b>. In some embodiments, after ignition of the plasma <b>124</b>, the power delivered to the plasma <b>124</b> is regulated using a feed-forward loop comprising the voltage supply <b>108</b>, the control circuit <b>140</b>, and the switching circuit <b>112</b>. The control circuit <b>140</b> can use the voltage generated by the voltage supply <b>108</b> to adjust operating parameters of the switching circuit <b>112</b>, such as to compensate for input line voltage ripple, which in turn controls power delivery to the plasma load <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In some embodiments, after ignition of the plasma <b>124</b>, the current driving the plasma load <b>124</b> is regulated using a feedback loop that includes the computation circuit <b>136</b>, the control circuit <b>140</b> and the switching power supply <b>104</b>. For example, the control circuit <b>140</b> uses the current in the secondary winding estimated by the computation circuit <b>136</b> to adjust operation of the switching power supply <b>104</b>, thereby controlling current driving the plasma load <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Prior to and/or during ignition of the plasma <b>124</b>, ignition voltage can be regulated using a feedback loop that includes the circuit <b>132</b> for measuring electrical parameters of the secondary winding, the control circuit <b>140</b>, and the switching power supply <b>104</b>. For example, the control circuit <b>140</b> uses the voltage across the secondary winding measured by the circuit <b>132</b> to adjust operation of the switching power supply <b>104</b> prior to and/or during ignition of the plasma load <b>124</b> to control the ignition voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">After plasma ignition, to facilitate control of power delivered to the plasma <b>124</b> with the control circuit <b>104</b>, the summation module <b>198</b> accepts as an input an estimation of the power delivered to the plasma load (P<sub>plasma</sub>) computed by the computation circuit <b>136</b>. An operator or the controller module <b>196</b> provides a power setpoint signal (P<sub>sp</sub>) to the summation module <b>198</b> that defines a desired power at the plasma load <b>124</b>. The summation module <b>198</b> then calculates a power offset (e) as the difference between the power setpoint signal (P<sub>sp</sub>) and the estimated plasma power (P<sub>plasma</sub>) based on the following:
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>e=P</i><sub>sp</sub><i>&#x2212;P</i><sub>plasma</sub>,<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
If the power offset is zero, the plasma generator is deemed to be operating under acceptable (or optimal) conditions and no adjustment to achieve the desired power at the plasma load occurs. If the power offset is not zero, the controller module <b>196</b> operates to minimize the offset.
</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The controller module <b>196</b> receives the power offset value as an output from the summation module <b>198</b> and attempts to minimize the offset by calculating a value and then directing a corrective action to adjust the operation of the switching power supply <b>104</b>. The controller module <b>196</b> can be a state-space controller, an adaptive controller, or a fuzzy-logic controller. In some embodiments, the controller module <b>408</b> is a proportional-integral-derivative (PID) controller that uses a PID algorithm to compute the necessary corrective action. The &#x201c;proportional&#x201d; value of the PID algorithm predicts, determines or is associated with the reaction of the controller module <b>196</b> to the current offset. The &#x201c;integral&#x201d; value of the PID algorithm predicts, determines or is associated with the reaction of the controller module <b>196</b> based on the sum of recent offsets. The &#x201c;derivative&#x201d; value of the PID algorithm predicts, determines or is associated with the reaction of the controller module <b>196</b> based on the rate at which the offset has changed. The PID algorithm can optionally include an additional term that predicts, determines or is associated with the reaction of the controller module <b>196</b> as a function of the input voltage to compensate for input-line voltage ripple. The controller module <b>196</b> uses a weighted sum of these four actions to adjust the plasma-generation process based on the following equation:</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">
<maths id="MATH-US-00008" num="00008">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <mrow>
    <msub>
      <mi>f</mi>
      <mi>control</mi>
    </msub>
    <mo>=</mo>
    <mrow>
      <mrow>
        <msub>
          <mi>k</mi>
          <mi>p</mi>
        </msub>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <mi>e</mi>
      </mrow>
      <mo>+</mo>
      <mrow>
        <msub>
          <mi>k</mi>
          <mi>i</mi>
        </msub>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mo>&#x222b;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mi>e</mi>
            <mo>&#xb7;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>&#x2146;</mo>
              <mi>&#x3c4;</mi>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
      <mo>+</mo>
      <mrow>
        <msub>
          <mi>k</mi>
          <mi>d</mi>
        </msub>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <mfrac>
          <mrow>
            <mo>&#x2146;</mo>
            <mi>e</mi>
          </mrow>
          <mrow>
            <mo>&#x2146;</mo>
            <mi>t</mi>
          </mrow>
        </mfrac>
      </mrow>
      <mo>+</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mi>f</mi>
        <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mo>(</mo>
          <msub>
            <mi>V</mi>
            <mi>in</mi>
          </msub>
          <mo>)</mo>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
  <mo>,</mo>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
where k<sub>p </sub>is the value of the scalar constant for the &#x201c;proportional&#x201d; component of the PID control algorithm, k<sub>i </sub>is the value of the scalar constant for the &#x201c;integral&#x201d; component of the PID control algorithm, k<sub>d </sub>is the value of the scalar constant for the &#x201c;derivative&#x201d; component of the PID control algorithm, and e is the power offset obtained from the output of summation module <b>198</b>. In addition, V<sub>in </sub>is the input voltage generated by the voltage supply <b>108</b>. In general, by tuning the three scalar constants (k) and the optional input voltage function of the PID algorithm, the controller module <b>196</b> can provide control action designed for user-desired process requirements.
</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">After plasma ignition, to facilitate control of the current delivered to the plasma <b>124</b> with the control circuit <b>104</b>, the summation module <b>198</b> accepts as an input an estimation of the current in the secondary winding (I<sub>s</sub>) computed by the computation circuit <b>136</b>. An operator or the controller module <b>196</b> provides a current setpoint signal (I<sub>sp</sub>) to the summation module <b>198</b> that defines a desired current for the plasma load <b>124</b>. The summation module <b>198</b> then calculates a current offset (e<sub>i</sub>) as the difference between the current setpoint signal (I<sub>sp</sub>) and the estimated current in the secondary winding (I<sub>s</sub>) based on the following equation:
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>e</i><sub>i</sub><i>=I</i><sub>sp</sub><i>&#x2212;I</i><sub>s</sub>.<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
If the current offset is zero, the plasma generator <b>100</b> is deemed to be operating under acceptable (or optimal) conditions and no adjustment to achieve the desired current for the plasma load <b>124</b> occurs. If the current offset is not zero, the controller module <b>196</b> operates to minimize the offset.
</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The controller module <b>196</b> receives the current offset value as an output from the summation module <b>198</b> and attempts to minimize the offset by calculating a value and then directing a corrective action to adjust the operation of the switching power supply <b>104</b>. The controller module <b>196</b> can be a state-space controller, an adaptive controller, or a fuzzy-logic controller. In some embodiments, the controller module <b>196</b> is a PID controller that uses a weighted sum of the &#x201c;proportional&#x201d; value, the &#x201c;integral&#x201d; value and the &#x201c;derivative&#x201d; value of the PID algorithm to control current driving the plasma load <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Prior to and/or during plasma ignition, to facilitate control of the ignition voltage with the control circuit <b>104</b>, the summation module <b>198</b> accepts as an input a voltage across the secondary winding <b>148</b> (V<sub>s</sub>) measured by the circuit <b>132</b>. An operator or the controller module <b>196</b> provides a voltage setpoint signal (V<sub>sp</sub>) to the summation module <b>198</b> that defines a desired ignition voltage to be achieved prior to and/or during ignition. The summation module <b>198</b> then calculates a voltage offset (e<sub>v</sub>) as the difference between the voltage setpoint signal (V<sub>sp</sub>) and the measured voltage across the secondary winding <b>148</b> (V<sub>s</sub>) based on the following equation:
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>e</i><sub>v</sub><i>=V</i><sub>sp</sub><i>&#x2212;V</i><sub>s</sub>.<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
If the voltage offset is zero, the plasma generator <b>100</b> is deemed to be operating under acceptable (or optimal) conditions and no adjustment to achieve the desired ignition voltage occurs. If the voltage offset is not zero, the controller module <b>196</b> operates to minimize the offset.
</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The controller module <b>196</b> receives the voltage offset value as an output from the summation module <b>198</b> and attempts to minimize the offset by calculating a value and then directing a corrective action to adjust the operation of the switching power supply <b>104</b>. The controller module <b>196</b> can be a state-space controller, an adaptive controller, or a fuzzy-logic controller. In some embodiments, the controller module <b>408</b> is a PID controller that uses a weighted sum of the &#x201c;proportional&#x201d; value, the &#x201c;integral&#x201d; value and the &#x201c;derivative&#x201d; value of the PID algorithm to control ignition voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The controller module <b>196</b> outputs one or more signals to adjust the operation of the switching power supply <b>104</b> which, in turn, controls the power, voltage and/or current delivered to the plasma load <b>124</b>. In some embodiments, the controller module <b>196</b> facilitates control by adjusting the duty cycle of the switching power supply <b>104</b> while keeping the switching frequency fixed or relatively constant. In some embodiments, the controller module <b>196</b> facilitates control by adjusting the switching frequency of the switching power supply <b>104</b> while keeping the duty cycle fixed. In some embodiments, the controller module <b>196</b> facilitates control by adjusting the switching frequency and the duty cycle of the switching power supply <b>104</b> substantially simultaneously. In some embodiments, the switching frequency is adjusted within the range of 270 kHz and 480 kHz.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">In an exemplary implementation, the electrical parameters associated with the primary winding <b>144</b>, the secondary winding <b>148</b> and the plasma <b>124</b> are used to monitor the operation of the plasma generator <b>100</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. For example, the electrical parameters can be used to characterize process performance. Hence, these parameters can be monitored to ensure that the plasma generator <b>100</b> is being operated within specified or desired operating ranges and conditions. In addition, the electrical parameters can be used for diagnostic purposes. For example, certain process parameters such as voltage across the primary winding <b>144</b> and secondary winding <b>148</b>, current in the primary winding <b>144</b> and secondary winding <b>148</b>, plasma <b>124</b> power, plasma <b>124</b> resistance and frequency can be stored and/or tracked. In some embodiments, analysis of such historical data is used to monitor the health or performance of the plasma generator <b>100</b> by detecting deviations between the current operational parameters and the historical trend corresponding to the respective parameters. In addition, historical information can be used to detect the location and timing of faults in the operational process and to determine causes of these faults. Furthermore, the electrical parameters can be used to ensure repeatability of the plasma-generation process so that consistent operational standard is maintained.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The above-described techniques can be implemented in digital electronic circuitry, or in computer hardware, firmware, software, or in combinations of them. The implementation can be as a computer program product, e.g., a computer program tangibly embodied in an information carrier, e.g., in a machine-readable storage device or in a propagated signal, for execution by, or to control the operation of, data processing apparatus, e.g., a programmable processor, a computer, or multiple computers. A computer program can be written in any form of programming language, including compiled or interpreted languages, and it can be deployed in any form, including as a stand-alone program or as a module, component, subroutine, or other unit suitable for use in a computing environment. A computer program can be deployed to be executed on one computer or on multiple computers at one site or distributed across multiple sites and interconnected by a communication network.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">Processors suitable for the execution of a computer program include, by way of example, both general and special purpose microprocessors, and any one or more processors of any kind of digital computer. Generally, a processor receives instructions and data from a read-only memory or a random access memory or both. The essential elements of a computer are a processor for executing instructions and one or more memory devices for storing instructions and data. Generally, a computer will also include, or be operatively coupled to receive data from or transfer data to, or both, one or more mass storage devices for storing data, e.g., magnetic, magneto-optical disks, or optical disks. Data transmission and instructions can also occur over a communications network. Information carriers suitable for embodying computer program instructions and data include all forms of non-volatile memory, including by way of example semiconductor memory devices, e.g., EPROM, EEPROM, and flash memory devices; magnetic disks, e.g., internal hard disks or removable disks; magneto-optical disks; and CD-ROM and DVD-ROM disks. The processor and the memory can be supplemented by, or incorporated in special purpose logic circuitry.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The terms &#x201c;module&#x201d; and &#x201c;function,&#x201d; as used herein, mean, but are not limited to, a software or hardware component which performs certain tasks. A module may advantageously be configured to reside on addressable storage medium and configured to execute on one or more processors. A module may be fully or partially implemented with a general purpose integrated circuit (IC), a field programmable gate array (FPGA), or an application-specific integrated circuit (ASIC). Thus, a module may include, by way of example, components, such as software components, object-oriented software components, class components and task components, processes, functions, attributes, procedures, subroutines, segments of program code, drivers, firmware, microcode, circuitry, data, databases, data structures, tables, arrays, and variables. The functionality provided for in the components and modules may be combined into fewer components and modules or further separated into additional components and modules.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">To provide for interaction with a user, the above described techniques can be implemented on a computer having a display device, e.g., a CRT (cathode ray tube) or LCD (liquid crystal display) monitor or touchscreen display, for displaying information to the user and a keyboard and a pointing device, e.g., a mouse or a trackball, by which the user can provide input to the computer (e.g., interact with a user interface element). Other kinds of devices can be used to provide for interaction with a user as well; for example, feedback provided to the user can be any form of sensory feedback, e.g., visual feedback, auditory feedback, or tactile feedback; and input from the user can be received in any form, including acoustic, speech, or tactile input.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">The above described techniques can be implemented in a distributed computing system that includes a back-end component, e.g., as a data server, and/or a middleware component, e.g., an application server, and/or a front-end component, e.g., a client computer having a graphical user interface and/or a Web browser through which a user can interact with an example implementation, or any combination of such back-end, middleware, or front-end components.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The technology has been described in terms of particular embodiments. The alternatives described herein are examples for illustration only and not to limit the alternatives in any way. The steps of the technology can be performed in a different order and still achieve desirable results. Other embodiments are within the scope of the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00001" nb-file="US08624501-20140107-M00001.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00001" he="6.69mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624501-20140107-M00001.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00002" nb-file="US08624501-20140107-M00002.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00002" he="7.03mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624501-20140107-M00002.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00003" nb-file="US08624501-20140107-M00003.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00003" he="6.35mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624501-20140107-M00003.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00004" nb-file="US08624501-20140107-M00004.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00004" he="6.69mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624501-20140107-M00004.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00005" nb-file="US08624501-20140107-M00005.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00005" he="7.03mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624501-20140107-M00005.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00006" nb-file="US08624501-20140107-M00006.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00006" he="7.79mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624501-20140107-M00006.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00007" nb-file="US08624501-20140107-M00007.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00007" he="6.69mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624501-20140107-M00007.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00008" nb-file="US08624501-20140107-M00008.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00008" he="6.35mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624501-20140107-M00008.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method comprising:
<claim-text>measuring a current of a primary winding of a transformer that generates a plasma;</claim-text>
<claim-text>measuring a voltage across a secondary winding of the transformer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a parameter of the plasma comprising a resistance value associated with the plasma, or a power value associated with the plasma, or both, wherein determining the parameter of the plasma comprises:
<claim-text>estimating a current in the secondary winding based on the current of the primary winding; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>estimating the parameter based on the current in the secondary winding and the voltage across the secondary winding.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising updating the parameter of the plasma based on measured values of the current of the primary winding and the voltage across the secondary winding.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising determining a root-mean-square (RMS) equivalent of the current of the primary winding and determining an RMS equivalent of the voltage across the secondary winding.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein determining the RMS equivalent of the current of the primary winding comprises:
<claim-text>rectifying the current in the primary winding;</claim-text>
<claim-text>computing an average of the rectified primary current;</claim-text>
<claim-text>sampling the average of the rectified primary current; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>converting the sampled average of the rectified primary current to the RMS equivalent current of the primary winding.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein determining the RMS equivalent of the voltage across the secondary winding comprises:
<claim-text>rectifying the voltage in the secondary winding;</claim-text>
<claim-text>computing an average of the rectified secondary voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>sampling the average of the rectified secondary voltage; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>converting the sampled average of the rectified secondary voltage to the RMS equivalent voltage of the secondary winding.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein determining the parameter of the plasma comprises the steps of:
<claim-text>(a) estimating an RMS current of the secondary winding and an RMS voltage of the secondary winding;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) estimating a phase between the estimated RMS current of the secondary winding and the RMS voltage of the secondary winding;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) estimating the power value based on the estimated RMS current of the secondary winding, the RMS voltage of the secondary winding and the phase;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) estimating the resistance value based on the RMS voltage of the secondary winding and the estimated power value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) repeating steps (a) through (d) until an error associated with estimating the resistance value satisfies a predetermined criterion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the RMS current of the secondary winding is estimated based on an RMS current of the primary winding and a correction factor computed based on the resistance value, a core inductance value, and an angular frequency.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the phase is estimated based on the resistance value, a plasma inductance value, and a frequency.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising regulating power delivered to the plasma based on the determined power value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein regulating the power delivered to the plasma comprises the steps of:
<claim-text>computing a difference between a predetermined power setpoint and the determined power value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a new power value based on the difference.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the power is regulated in a feedback loop.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising measuring an input voltage supplied to the plasma and compensating for input-line voltage ripple based on the input voltage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein compensating for input-line voltage ripple comprises adjusting a switching frequency to regulate the power supplied to the plasma.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising monitoring at least one of the power value and the resistance value to detect an unsafe operating condition associated with a toroidal plasma chamber.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising detecting a deviation of at least one of the power value and the resistance value from a predetermined value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A method for controlling a toroidal plasma, the method comprising:
<claim-text>measuring a current of a primary winding of a transformer that generates the toroidal plasma;</claim-text>
<claim-text>measuring a voltage across a secondary winding of the transformer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>measuring an input voltage supplied to the transformer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>estimating a power value of the plasma comprising: i) determining a current in the secondary winding using the current of the primary winding and ii) estimating the power value based on the current in the secondary winding and the voltage across the secondary winding; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>regulating a power delivered to the plasma based on the estimated power value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein regulating the power delivered to the plasma comprises the steps of:
<claim-text>computing a difference between a predetermined power setpoint and the estimated power value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a new power value based on the difference.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the power is regulated in a feedback loop.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, further comprising compensating for input-line voltage ripple based on the measured input voltage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein compensating for input-line voltage ripple comprises adjusting a switching frequency based on the measured input voltage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. A toroidal plasma generator, comprising:
<claim-text>a plasma chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transformer having a magnetic core surrounding a portion of the plasma chamber and a primary winding;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a power supply in electrical communication with the primary winding, the power supply supplying a current to the primary winding, and the supplied current inducing a toroidal plasma in the plasma chamber; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a module for estimating a parameter of the toroidal plasma by i) measuring the current of the primary winding and a voltage across a secondary winding of the transformer, ii) determining a current in the secondary winding based on the current of the primary winding; and iii) estimating the parameter based on the current in the secondary winding and the voltage across the secondary winding, the parameter comprising a resistance value associated with the toroidal plasma, or a power value associated with the toroidal plasma, or both.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. A system comprising:
<claim-text>a first module configured to measure a current of a primary winding of a transformer that generates a toroidal plasma and a voltage across a secondary winding of the transformer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second module in communication with the first module, the second module configured to determine a parameter of the toroidal plasma comprising a resistance value associated with the plasma, or a power value associated with the plasma, or both, wherein the parameter is determined by i) determining a current in the secondary winding based on the current of the primary winding; and ii) estimating the parameter based on the current in the secondary winding and the voltage across the secondary winding.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, further comprising a third module configured to determine an RMS equivalent of the current of the primary winding and an RMS equivalent of the voltage across the secondary winding.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00023">claim 23</claim-ref>, wherein the third module comprises:
<claim-text>a rectifier configured to rectify the current in the primary winding;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a differential amplifier in cooperation with a filter configured to compute an average of the rectified primary current;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a converter configured to sample the average of the rectified primary current; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a processor module configured to convert the sampled average of the rectified primary current to the RMS equivalent current of the primary winding.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text>25. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00023">claim 23</claim-ref>, wherein the third module comprises:
<claim-text>a rectifier configured to rectify the voltage across the secondary winding;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a differential amplifier in cooperation with a filter configured to compute an average of the rectified secondary voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a converter configured to sample the average of the rectified secondary voltage; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a processor module configured to convert the sampled average of the rectified secondary voltage to the RMS equivalent voltage of the secondary winding.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text>26. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, wherein the second module includes an iterative filter configured to estimate the parameter of the plasma based on a model of the plasma that relates the current of the primary winding to the voltage across the secondary winding.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text>27. A computer program product, tangibly embodied in a non-transitory information carrier, the computer program product including instructions being operable to cause a data processing apparatus to:
<claim-text>receive a measured value of a current of a primary winding of a transformer used to generate a plasma in a plasma chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receive a measured value of a voltage across a secondary winding of the transformer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determine a parameter of the plasma comprising a resistance value associated with the plasma, or a power value associated with the plasma, or both, wherein the parameter is determined by i) determining a current in the secondary winding based on the current of the primary winding and ii) estimating the parameter based on the current in the secondary winding and the voltage across the secondary winding.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text>28. A method comprising:
<claim-text>measuring a current of a primary winding of a transformer that generates a plasma;</claim-text>
<claim-text>measuring a voltage across a secondary winding of the transformer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a parameter of the plasma based on i) an RMS equivalent of the current of the primary winding and ii) an RMS equivalent of the voltage across the secondary winding, the parameter comprising a resistance value associated with the plasma, or a power value associated with the plasma, or both.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029" num="00029">
<claim-text>29. A method for controlling a toroidal plasma, the method comprising:
<claim-text>measuring a current of a primary winding of a transformer that generates the toroidal plasma;</claim-text>
<claim-text>measuring a voltage across a secondary winding of the transformer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>measuring an input voltage supplied to the transformer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>estimating a power value of the plasma based on an RMS equivalent of the current of the primary winding and an RMS equivalent of the voltage across the secondary winding; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>regulating a power delivered to the plasma based on the estimated power value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030" num="00030">
<claim-text>30. A system comprising:
<claim-text>a first module configured to measure a current of a primary winding of a transformer that generates a toroidal plasma and a voltage across a secondary winding of the transformer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second module in communication with the first module, the second module configured to determine a parameter of the toroidal plasma based on i) an RMS equivalent of the current of the primary winding and ii) an RMS equivalent of the voltage across the secondary winding, the parameter comprising a resistance value associated with the plasma, or a power value associated with the plasma, or both.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031" num="00031">
<claim-text>31. A computer program product, tangibly embodied in a non-transitory information carrier, the computer program product including instructions being operable to cause a data processing apparatus to:
<claim-text>receive a measured value of a current of a primary winding of a transformer used to generate a plasma in a plasma chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receive a measured value of a voltage across a secondary winding of the transformer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determine a parameter of the plasma according to a model relating the parameter of the plasma to i) an RMS equivalent of the current of the primary winding and ii) an RMS equivalent of the voltage across the secondary winding, the parameter comprising a resistance value associated with the plasma, or a power value associated with the plasma, or both.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
