<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625213-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625213</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13077576</doc-number>
<date>20110331</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>280</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>11</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>360 25</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Automated cluster size measurement</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5652054</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kikitsu et al.</name>
<date>19970700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>428328</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6849349</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Klemmer et al.</name>
<date>20050200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7407685</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Watanbe et al.</name>
<date>20080800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7494726</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Watanabe et al.</name>
<date>20090200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7579095</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Ichihara et al.</name>
<date>20090800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7892663</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Nakagawa et al.</name>
<date>20110200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0219631</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Takahashi et al.</name>
<date>20031100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>428695</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>11</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>14</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Jury</last-name>
<first-name>Jason Charles</first-name>
<address>
<city>Minneapolis</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wu</last-name>
<first-name>Xiaowei</first-name>
<address>
<city>Pleasanton</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Asselin</last-name>
<first-name>Pierre</first-name>
<address>
<city>Edina</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Jury</last-name>
<first-name>Jason Charles</first-name>
<address>
<city>Minneapolis</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wu</last-name>
<first-name>Xiaowei</first-name>
<address>
<city>Pleasanton</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Asselin</last-name>
<first-name>Pierre</first-name>
<address>
<city>Edina</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Seagate Technology LLC</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Cupertino</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Negron</last-name>
<first-name>Daniell L</first-name>
<department>2688</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A cluster size measurement method includes writing a first pattern of a first size of a first number of magnetic clusters. A second pattern of a second size of a second number of magnetic clusters is written, wherein the second plurality of clusters includes clusters of the first number of clusters and a switched cluster. A cluster size of the switched cluster is automatically determined by contrasting the first size and the second size.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="201.51mm" wi="151.21mm" file="US08625213-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="238.25mm" wi="150.28mm" file="US08625213-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="231.99mm" wi="155.53mm" file="US08625213-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="226.99mm" wi="150.28mm" file="US08625213-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="224.37mm" wi="109.73mm" file="US08625213-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="217.42mm" wi="163.75mm" file="US08625213-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="223.35mm" wi="160.10mm" file="US08625213-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="191.77mm" wi="151.89mm" file="US08625213-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="226.31mm" wi="152.57mm" file="US08625213-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="144.95mm" wi="161.12mm" file="US08625213-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="214.12mm" wi="176.61mm" file="US08625213-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="106.09mm" wi="156.21mm" file="US08625213-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">Embodiments according to the present invention generally relate to magnetic media.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">In magnetic recording media, for example as used in hard disk drives, information is written to and read from magnetic elements that represent digital bits. The minimum size that can be written to is called a cluster, and cluster size defines media recording density. Clusters may vary in size. Bits may include a plurality of magnetic clusters, e.g. seven to fifty clusters may equal one bit.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Just as magnetic clusters are the smallest building blocks for magnetic patterns written to a medium, the physical grains are the smallest physical building blocks. In present media, grains are polycrystalline units consisting of a single chemical composition (e.g. CoCr), separated by a boundary consisting of a different composition. Clusters may contain one physical grain or a number of grains. Grains behave like conversations at a party. A few loner grains may remain by themselves, or more interesting grains may group together in larger numbers. Therefore a single grain may be a cluster, or a number of grains may group together and form a cluster. Individual grains may be visually analyzed using microscopic instruments. However, the microscopic instruments that are capable of sensing magnetic fields (for example, transition electron microscopy) have great difficulty observing magnetic clusters in recording media. Other methods such as magnetic force microscopy suffer from poor spatial resolution, and cannot directly observe magnetic clusters.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Embodiments of the present invention are illustrated by way of example, and not by way of limitation, in the figures of the accompanying drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a magnified plan view of a portion of a magnetic recording media, according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a magnified plan view of a portion of the magnetic recording media after further processing, according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> is a magnified plan view of a portion of the magnetic recording media showing the change between <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref> is a magnified plan view of a portion of the magnetic recording media illustrating the magnetic fields of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a graphical depiction of a method of measuring cluster size, according to another embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> is a graphical depiction of a method of measuring cluster size, according to another embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref> is another graphical depiction of a method of measuring cluster size, according to another embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</figref> is a histogram of cluster sizes, according to another embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> depicts a flowchart of a process of automatically determining cluster size, according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> depicts a flowchart of a process of automatically calculating cluster size according to some embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a block diagram of an example of a general purpose computer system within which a cluster size measurement system in accordance with the present invention can be implemented.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a data storage device in which embodiments of the present invention can be implemented to measure cluster size.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a simplified cross-sectional view of a perpendicular magnetic recording medium, which may be used in the data storage device.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a simplified cross-sectional view of a portion of the perpendicular magnetic recording medium with a head unit.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Reference will now be made in detail to embodiments, examples of which are illustrated in the accompanying drawings. While the embodiments will be described in conjunction with the drawings, it will be understood that they are not intended to limit the embodiments. On the contrary, the embodiments are intended to cover alternatives, modifications and equivalents. Furthermore, in the following detailed description, numerous specific details are set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding. However, it will be recognized by one of ordinary skill in the art that the embodiments may be practiced without these specific details. In other instances, well-known methods, procedures, components, and circuits have not been described in detail as not to unnecessarily obscure aspects of the embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">For expository purposes, the term &#x201c;horizontal&#x201d; as used herein refers to a plane parallel to the plane or surface of a substrate, regardless of its orientation. The term &#x201c;vertical&#x201d; refers to a direction perpendicular to the horizontal as just defined. Terms such as &#x201c;above,&#x201d; &#x201c;below,&#x201d; &#x201c;bottom,&#x201d; &#x201c;top,&#x201d; &#x201c;side,&#x201d; &#x201c;higher,&#x201d; &#x201c;lower,&#x201d; &#x201c;upper,&#x201d; &#x201c;over,&#x201d; and &#x201c;under&#x201d; are referred to with respect to the horizontal plane.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a magnified plan view of a portion of a magnetic recording media <b>100</b>, according to an embodiment of the present invention. Embodiments of the present invention provide methods and systems for automatically measuring cluster size. In an embodiment, various overlapping patterns are written to a recording medium. During the writing of the patterns, a first pattern is partially overwritten by a second pattern, and each pattern is mapped after being written. The difference between the two patterns may be used to estimate individual magnetic cluster sizes that comprise the underlying medium.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The magnetic recording media <b>100</b> includes magnetic clusters <b>102</b>. The magnetic clusters <b>102</b> are comprised of one or more physical grains (not shown). Physical grains may be visualized using microscopic instruments. A number of magnetic clusters <b>102</b> may form a digital bit (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>), e.g. &#x201c;0&#x201d; or &#x201c;1&#x201d;. For example, in some embodiments seven to fifty clusters may form a bit. Unlike physical grains, magnetic clusters <b>102</b> may not be seen easily using microscopic instruments.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">A first pattern <b>104</b> has been written to the magnetic clusters <b>102</b>. The first pattern <b>104</b> includes first clusters <b>106</b> with a first magnetic orientation, and second clusters <b>108</b> with a second magnetic orientation. After writing, the first pattern <b>104</b> is read back and mapped, creating a first media map <b>110</b>. In an embodiment, a disk drive device (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>) may be used to write and read the first pattern <b>104</b>. However in some embodiments, any device capable of reading and writing to the magnetic recording media <b>100</b> may be used (e.g. spin stand or non-drive test system).</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The first media map <b>110</b> is a map of the collective magnetic orientations of the magnetic clusters <b>102</b>. Because individual clusters may not be seen, the first media map <b>110</b> is generated as a result of reading the first pattern <b>104</b>. The first media map <b>110</b> illustrates first magnetic oriented area <b>112</b> of the first clusters <b>106</b>, and second magnetic oriented area <b>114</b> of the second clusters <b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Line <b>116</b> illustrates a boundary where, for example, a device writing to the magnetic recording media <b>100</b> stopped writing the first magnetic oriented area <b>112</b> and started writing the second magnetic oriented area <b>114</b>. In some embodiments, a disk drive may have first oriented all of the magnetic clusters <b>102</b> to a first direction in a first pass. The disk drive may have then oriented a portion of the clusters beginning at the line <b>116</b> to a second direction in a second pass, thus forming the first magnetic oriented area <b>112</b> and the second magnetic oriented area <b>114</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The magnetic clusters <b>102</b> may not exactly align to the ideal straight line that matches line <b>116</b>. In addition, physical grains do not orient in different directions within a cluster. Therefore, an individual cluster has a uniform orientation. As a result, portions of the first magnetic oriented area <b>112</b> and portions of the second magnetic oriented area <b>114</b> may extend somewhat on either side of the line <b>116</b>, forming a first jagged transition line <b>118</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a magnified plan view of a portion of the magnetic recording media <b>100</b> after further processing, according to an embodiment of the present invention. A second pattern <b>204</b> has been written to the magnetic clusters <b>102</b>. The second pattern <b>204</b> includes first clusters <b>206</b> with the first magnetic orientation, and second clusters <b>208</b> with the second magnetic orientation. After writing, the second pattern <b>204</b> is read back and mapped, creating a second media map <b>210</b>. In an embodiment, the disk drive device (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>) may be used to write and read the second pattern <b>204</b>. However in some embodiments, any device capable of reading and writing to the magnetic recording media <b>100</b> may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The second media map <b>210</b> is a map of the collective magnetic orientations of the magnetic clusters <b>102</b>. Because individual clusters may not be seen, the second media map <b>210</b> is generated as a result of reading the second pattern <b>204</b>. The second media map <b>210</b> illustrates first magnetic oriented area <b>212</b> of the first clusters <b>206</b>, and second magnetic oriented area <b>214</b> of the second clusters <b>208</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The second media map <b>210</b> has been formed by slightly moving the line <b>116</b>, e.g. by 0.5 nm. Therefore, in an embodiment, a disk drive (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>) has changed the shape of the first magnetic oriented area <b>112</b> of the first pattern <b>104</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) and the second magnetic oriented area <b>114</b> of the first pattern <b>104</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) by writing the second pattern <b>204</b> offset from the first pattern <b>104</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>), e.g. by 0.5 nm. As a result, a second jagged transition line <b>218</b> has been formed. In some embodiments, the second pattern <b>204</b> is moved in a downtrack direction from the first pattern <b>104</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In some embodiments, the second pattern <b>204</b> may be nearly identical to the first pattern <b>104</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>), and no detectable differences may exist between the first media map <b>110</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) and the second media map <b>210</b>. Thus, in an embodiment, the difference between the two patterns is increased very gradually. As a result, in various embodiments, the second pattern <b>204</b> is moved a distance less than a cluster size.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> is a magnified plan view of a portion of the magnetic recording media <b>100</b> showing the change between the first pattern <b>104</b> and the second pattern <b>204</b>, according to an embodiment of the present invention. In an embodiment, the size of a transition cluster <b>304</b> is determined by contrasting the first pattern <b>104</b> and the second pattern <b>204</b>. For example, a difference operation may be taken between the first pattern <b>104</b> and the second pattern <b>204</b>, thus producing the size of the transition cluster <b>304</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Magnetic information that is recorded to the magnetic recording media <b>100</b> should conform to the granularity of the magnetic recording media <b>100</b>. The granularity determines the unique form of the magnetic information. Thus, attempts to record magnetic information that have more spatial variation than the granularity can support, may result in difficulties when trying to read back from the magnetic recording media <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The orientation and size of the magnetic clusters <b>102</b> may be somewhat random. Thus, the granularity of the magnetic recording media <b>100</b> may be random. An equation for relating features in a two-dimensional readback map, e.g. the first magnetic oriented area <b>112</b> and the second magnetic oriented area <b>114</b>, and an underlying cluster area is:</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">
<maths id="MATH-US-00001" num="00001">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <msub>
    <mi>A</mi>
    <mi>c</mi>
  </msub>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mrow>
    <mfrac>
      <mn>1</mn>
      <msub>
        <mi>V</mi>
        <mn>0</mn>
      </msub>
    </mfrac>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <mrow>
      <mo>&#x222b;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mo>&#x222b;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>&#x3b4;</mi>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mi>V</mi>
            <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>
              <mrow>
                <msup>
                  <mi>x</mi>
                  <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
                </msup>
                <mo>,</mo>
                <msup>
                  <mi>y</mi>
                  <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
                </msup>
              </mrow>
              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mo>&#x2146;</mo>
            <msup>
              <mi>x</mi>
              <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
            </msup>
          </mrow>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mo>&#x2146;</mo>
            <msup>
              <mi>y</mi>
              <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
            </msup>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
wherein A<sub>c</sub>=an area of a switched cluster, V<sub>0</sub>=a zero-to-peak readback voltage, &#x3b4;V=a two-dimensional cluster readback map, x&#x2032;=down-track coordinate (direction), y&#x2032;=cross-track coordinate (direction), dx&#x2032;=down-track variable of integration, and dy&#x2032;=cross-track variable of integration.
</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In some embodiments, the zero-to-peak readback voltage V<sub>0 </sub>is used to normalize the expression, e.g. to yield a meaningful &#x201c;area&#x201d; quantity rather than an &#x201c;area-voltage&#x201d; quantity. The equation above indicates that the (normalized) integral of the cluster voltage signal is proportional to the cluster area. The zero-to-peak readback voltage can be observed in normal magnetic recording operation. However, the feature readback map &#x3b4;V may be observed as the difference between the readback maps of two states of the recording medium, where the difference in the states is the orientation of a magnetic cluster.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref> is a magnified plan view of a portion of the magnetic recording media illustrating the magnetic fields of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, according to an embodiment of the present invention. In an embodiment, a device reading the first media map <b>110</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) may generate a first magnetic readback map <b>360</b>. For example, a disk drive may read the first magnetic oriented area <b>112</b> and the second magnetic oriented area <b>114</b> as the first magnetic readback map <b>360</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">After the second pattern <b>204</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) has been written, the device may read the second media map <b>210</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) as a second magnetic readback map <b>362</b>. For example, the disk drive may read the first magnetic oriented area <b>212</b> and the second magnetic oriented area <b>214</b> as the second magnetic readback map <b>362</b>. A difference operation, e.g. the above equation, may then be taken between the first magnetic readback map <b>360</b> and the second magnetic readback map <b>362</b>, thus producing a third magnetic readback map <b>364</b> corresponding to the transition cluster <b>304</b>. The third magnetic readback map <b>364</b> then is used in the above equation as &#x3b4;V to yield the corresponding area of the transition cluster <b>304</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a graphical depiction <b>400</b> of an automated method of measuring cluster size in a crosstrack direction, according to another embodiment of the present invention. In the graphical depiction <b>400</b>, cluster size is measured by comparing tracks on their sides. Thus, as tracks are written in a downtrack direction, changes along their edges are compared in a crosstrack direction. The changes then indicate cluster size. In an embodiment, the disk drive device (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>) may be used to write and read the tracks. However in some embodiments, any device capable of reading and writing the tracks may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In a first step <b>432</b>, tracks <b>434</b> are erased, e.g. AC erased, in a downtrack direction <b>436</b> out to +10 and &#x2212;10 tracks on either side, e.g. crosstrack, of a first track <b>438</b>. In a second step <b>440</b>, the tracks <b>434</b> are erased, e.g. DC erased, out to +2 and &#x2212;2 tracks on either side, e.g. crosstrack, of the first track <b>438</b>. In a third step <b>442</b>, a first offset track <b>444</b> is written at a +0.5 track offset, e.g. crosstrack, from the first track <b>438</b>. In a fourth step <b>446</b>, a second offset track <b>448</b> is erased, e.g. DC erased, at a &#x2212;0.5 track offset, e.g. crosstrack, from the first track <b>438</b>. In a fifth step <b>450</b>, readbacks are captured many times, e.g. 200 averages, at &#x2212;0.4, &#x2212;0.2, 0.0, +0.2, and +0.4 track offsets, e.g. crosstrack, from the first track <b>438</b>. This first application of step <b>450</b> yields the first magnetic readback map. Another application of steps <b>446</b> and <b>450</b> yields the second magnetic readback map. The difference between these maps yields a third magnetic readback map that consists of well-separated magnetic clusters. The cluster area integral equation above is applied to each instance of magnetic clusters observed in the third map, to yield their corresponding cluster area. In some embodiments the fourth step <b>446</b> and the fifth step <b>450</b> are repeated many times.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> is a graphical depiction <b>500</b> of an automated method of measuring cluster size in a downtrack direction, according to another embodiment of the present invention. In the graphical depiction <b>500</b>, cluster size is measured by writing a first pattern with a head field of, for example, a hard drive. The head field is stepped along the downtrack direction and a second pattern is written. The size of the first pattern and the size of the second pattern are contrasted to determine cluster size along the downtrack direction. In an embodiment, the disk drive device (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>) may be used to write and read the patterns. However in some embodiments, any device capable of reading and writing to the patterns may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">A first pattern <b>504</b> is written to a track <b>534</b> by a magnetic recording device (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>), e.g. a recording head of a disk drive (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>). The magnetic recording device (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>) is stepped, e.g. 2 nm, in a downtrack direction <b>536</b>. A second pattern <b>505</b> is written to the track <b>534</b> by the magnetic recording device (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>). The size of the first pattern <b>504</b> and the size of the second pattern <b>505</b> are contrasted, e.g. subtracted, leaving one or more clusters <b>502</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In some embodiments the magnetic recording device (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>) is repeatedly stepped along in the downtrack direction <b>536</b>. After each step, pattern sizes are compared, and cluster sizes are recorded. In various embodiments, a distribution of a number of cluster sizes may be recorded and used to, for example, determine average cluster size, numbers of cluster sizes, frequency of cluster sizes, etc. Numbers of cluster sizes may also be used to create a histogram (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</figref>) of cluster sizes on a particular media. Various media with different properties will have differing distributions of cluster sizes, creating unique distribution shapes when graphed on a histogram.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref> is a plan view <b>570</b> of a portion of a magnetic recording device, e.g. recording head, according to another embodiment of the present invention. The plan view <b>570</b> illustrates an example of a device, e.g. disk drive, performing the automated method of measuring cluster size in a downtrack direction (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>). In a first step <b>572</b>, first footprints <b>574</b> of a recording device, e.g. disk drive head, are recorded on a DC erased background <b>576</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In a second step <b>578</b>, second footprints <b>580</b> are recorded at least partially overlying the first footprints <b>574</b>. For example in an embodiment, second footprints <b>580</b> are recorded overlying first footprints at a distance &#x394;x on either side of first footprints <b>574</b>, at distance 0 overlying first footprints <b>574</b>, and at distance 2&#x394;x from first footprints <b>574</b>. In a third step <b>582</b>, a difference <b>584</b> is taken between the footprint images and the size of clusters <b>586</b> are calculated.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</figref> is a histogram <b>590</b> of cluster sizes, according to an embodiment of the present invention. Cluster sizes may not be uniform. Therefore, a number of cluster sizes may be recorded and analyzed, for example in the histogram <b>590</b>, as a distribution of cluster diameters. For example, in the histogram <b>590</b> cluster diameters <b>592</b> may be listed in the x-axis and cluster counts <b>594</b> may be listed in the y-axis. Thus, in some embodiments a magnetic recording media may be processed many times to produce a number of cluster measurements. As a result, the histogram <b>590</b> of cluster diameters <b>592</b> illustrates a more accurate representation of the magnetic recording media.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> depicts a flowchart <b>600</b> of an automated process of determining cluster size, according to an embodiment of the present invention. In block <b>602</b>, a first pattern is written of a first size of a first number of magnetic clusters. For example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> the first pattern is written to the magnetic recording media. The first pattern includes clusters with a first orientation and clusters with a second orientation.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In block <b>604</b>, a second pattern is written of a second size of a second number of magnetic clusters. In some embodiments, the second number of clusters includes clusters of the first number of clusters and a switched cluster. For example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> the second pattern is written to the magnetic recording media. The second pattern is written over the first pattern and includes the clusters from the first pattern. Most of the clusters maintain the first orientation and the second orientation. However, one of the clusters, a switched cluster (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>), has switched orientation from the second orientation to the first orientation. Therefore, the size and shape of the first pattern and the second pattern changes.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In block <b>606</b>, a cluster size of the switched cluster is determined by contrasting the first size and the second size. For example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> the difference between the first pattern and the second pattern is highlighted as the switched cluster. Thus, the switched cluster is the area of difference between the first pattern and the second pattern.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In an embodiment, the first size is associated with a first cluster map and the second size is associated with a second cluster map. The contrasting includes taking a difference between the first cluster map and the second cluster map. An area under the difference is integrated, and the area is normalized to a peak amplitude to determine a normalized area. The normalized area is determined to be the cluster size. For example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> the contrasting included determining an area of the switched cluster A<sub>c </sub>wherein,</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">
<maths id="MATH-US-00002" num="00002">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <mrow>
    <msub>
      <mi>A</mi>
      <mi>c</mi>
    </msub>
    <mo>=</mo>
    <mrow>
      <mfrac>
        <mn>1</mn>
        <msub>
          <mi>V</mi>
          <mn>0</mn>
        </msub>
      </mfrac>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mo>&#x222b;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mo>&#x222b;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mi>&#x3b4;</mi>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mi>V</mi>
              <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <msup>
                    <mi>x</mi>
                    <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
                  </msup>
                  <mo>,</mo>
                  <msup>
                    <mi>y</mi>
                    <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
                  </msup>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>&#x2146;</mo>
              <msup>
                <mi>x</mi>
                <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
              </msup>
            </mrow>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>&#x2146;</mo>
              <msup>
                <mi>y</mi>
                <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
              </msup>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
  <mo>,</mo>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
and wherein V<sub>0</sub>=zero-to-peak readback voltage, &#x3b4;V=two-dimensional cluster readback map, x&#x2032;=down-track coordinate (direction), y&#x2032;=cross-track coordinate (direction), dx&#x2032;=down-track variable of integration, and dy&#x2032;=cross-track variable of integration.
</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In a further embodiment, the second pattern is substantially similar to the first pattern. For example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> the only difference between the two patterns is the size of the switched cluster. In some embodiments, the first and second patterns are magnetic patterns. For example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> a magnetic write head writes magnetic information to a magnetic recording medium. In various embodiments, the cluster size is a minimum size to which information can be written. For example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> magnetic grains have grouped together to form clusters. As a cluster, the magnetic grains have the same magnetic alignment and switch alignments together in response to external magnetic fields, e.g. a write head.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> depicts a flowchart <b>700</b> of an automated process of calculating cluster size according to some embodiments of the present invention. In a block <b>702</b>, a first number of clusters is magnetically oriented in a first direction. For example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> first clusters with a first magnetic orientation are written to the magnetic recording media.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In a block <b>704</b>, the first number of clusters and a second number of clusters are mapped to form a first magnetic map. In some embodiments, the second number of clusters is magnetically oriented in a different direction from the first number of clusters, and the second number of magnetic clusters includes a transition cluster. For example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> second clusters with a second magnetic orientation on the magnetic recording media are oriented in a different direction from the first clusters with the first magnetic orientation. The first clusters and the second clusters form the first magnetic map of the magnetic recording media.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In a block <b>706</b>, a third number of clusters is magnetically oriented in the first direction. In some embodiments, the third number of clusters includes the first number of clusters and the transition cluster. For example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> the second pattern is written to the magnetic recording media. Most of the clusters maintain the first orientation and the second orientation. However, one of the clusters, a switched cluster (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>), has switched orientation from the second orientation to the first orientation.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">In a block <b>708</b>, the third number of clusters and the second number of clusters is mapped to form a second magnetic map. For example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> the second pattern forms a second magnetic map of clusters oriented in the first magnetic direction and the second magnetic direction.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In a block <b>710</b>, the first magnetic map and the second magnetic map are compared to determine a size of the transition cluster. For example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> the difference between the first pattern and the second pattern is highlighted as the switched cluster. Thus, the switched cluster is the area of difference between the first pattern and the second pattern.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In an embodiment, the comparing includes taking a difference between the first magnetic map and the second magnetic map. An area under the difference is integrated, and the area is normalized to a peak amplitude to determine a normalized area. The normalized area is determined to be the size of the transition cluster. For example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> the determining included determining an area of the transition cluster A<sub>c </sub>wherein,</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">
<maths id="MATH-US-00003" num="00003">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <mrow>
    <msub>
      <mi>A</mi>
      <mi>c</mi>
    </msub>
    <mo>=</mo>
    <mrow>
      <mfrac>
        <mn>1</mn>
        <msub>
          <mi>V</mi>
          <mn>0</mn>
        </msub>
      </mfrac>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mo>&#x222b;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mo>&#x222b;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mi>&#x3b4;</mi>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mi>V</mi>
              <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <msup>
                    <mi>x</mi>
                    <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
                  </msup>
                  <mo>,</mo>
                  <msup>
                    <mi>y</mi>
                    <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
                  </msup>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>&#x2146;</mo>
              <msup>
                <mi>x</mi>
                <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
              </msup>
            </mrow>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>&#x2146;</mo>
              <msup>
                <mi>y</mi>
                <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
              </msup>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
  <mo>,</mo>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
and wherein V<sub>0</sub>=zero-to-peak readback voltage, &#x3b4;V=two-dimensional cluster readback map, x&#x2032;=down-track coordinate (direction), y&#x2032;=cross-track coordinate (direction), dx&#x2032;=down-track variable of integration, and dy&#x2032;=cross-track variable of integration.
</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">In some embodiments, magnetically orienting the first number of clusters in a first direction includes magnetically orienting a first number of clusters in a first direction on a magnetic recording media. For example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> the clusters are written to a portion of a magnetic recording media, e.g. a perpendicular magnetic recording medium (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">In various embodiments, the transition cluster is located at a cross track boundary between the second number of clusters and the third number of clusters. For example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> tracks are written in a downtrack direction, and changes along their edges are compared in a cross track direction. The changes indicate the size of one or more transition clusters along the cross track boundary.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">In an embodiment, each cluster within the first number of clusters, the second number of clusters, and the third number of clusters is a minimum size to which information can be magnetically written. For example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> magnetic grains have grouped together to form clusters. As a cluster, the magnetic grains have the same magnetic alignment and switch alignments together in response to external magnetic fields, e.g. a write head.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Methods and media structures are described herein, which embodiments of the present invention as described above, may measure cluster size. It is appreciated that magnetic recording media as discussed herein may be utilized with a variety of systems including disc drive memory systems, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a block diagram of an example of a general purpose computer system <b>800</b> within which a cluster measurement system in accordance with the present invention can be implemented. In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the system includes a host central processing unit (CPU) <b>802</b> coupled to a graphics processing unit (GPU) <b>804</b> via a bus <b>806</b>. One or more CPUs as well as one or more GPUs may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Both the CPU <b>802</b> and the GPU <b>804</b> are coupled to memory <b>808</b>. In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the memory <b>808</b> may be a shared memory, whereby the memory stores instructions and data for both the CPU <b>802</b> and the GPU <b>804</b>. Alternatively, there may be separate memories dedicated to the CPU <b>802</b> and GPU <b>804</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">In an embodiment, the memory <b>808</b> includes instructions for the cluster measurement system in accordance with the present invention. The instructions control a coupled magnetic read/write device <b>814</b>. In an embodiment, the coupled magnetic read/write device <b>814</b> may be a hard disk drive.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The system <b>800</b> also includes a user interface <b>812</b> that, in one implementation, includes an on-screen cursor control device, displayed on a coupled display <b>810</b>. The user interface may include a keyboard, a mouse, a joystick, game controller, and/or a touch screen device (a touchpad).</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Generally speaking, the system <b>800</b> includes the basic components of a computer system platform that implements functionality in accordance with embodiments of the present invention. The system <b>800</b> can be implemented as, for example, any of a number of different types of computer systems (e.g., servers, laptops, desktops, and notebooks).</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">Magnetic storage media are widely used in various applications, particularly in the computer industry for data storage and retrieval applications, as well as for storage of audio and video signals. Perpendicular magnetic recording media, for example hard disc drive storage devices, include recording media with a perpendicular anisotropy in the magnetic layer. In perpendicular magnetic recording media, residual magnetization is formed in a direction perpendicular to the surface of the magnetic medium, typically by a layer of a magnetic material on a substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">A perpendicular recording disc drive head typically includes a trailing write pole, and a leading return or opposing pole magnetically coupled to the write pole. In addition, an electrically conductive magnetizing coil surrounds the yoke of the write pole. During operation, the recording head flies above the magnetic recording medium by a distance referred to as the fly height. To write to the magnetic recording medium, the magnetic recording medium is moved past the recording head so that the recording head follows the tracks of the magnetic recording medium, with the magnetic recording medium first passing under the return pole and then passing under the write pole. Current is passed through the coil to create magnetic flux within the write pole. The magnetic flux passes from the write pole tip, through the hard magnetic recording track, into the soft underlayer, and across to the return pole. In addition to providing a return path for the magnetic flux, the soft underlayer produces magnetic charge images of the magnetic recording layer, increasing the magnetic flux and increasing the playback signal. The current can be reversed, thereby reversing the magnetic field and reorienting the magnetic dipoles.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The perpendicular recording medium is a continuous layer of discrete, contiguous magnetic crystals or domains. Within the continuous magnetic layer, discrete information is stored in individual bits. The individual bits are magnetically oriented positively or negatively, to store binary information. Areal density is a function of the number of the individual bits on the recording medium. As areal densities increase, the amount of information stored on the recording medium also increases. Manufacturers strive to satisfy the ever-increasing consumer demand for higher capacity hard drives by increasing the areal density.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">High density perpendicular recording media use carefully balanced magnetic properties. These carefully balanced magnetic properties include sufficiently high anisotropy (perpendicular magnetic orientation) to ensure thermal stability, resist erasure, and function effectively with modern disc drive head designs; and grain-to-grain uniformity of magnetic properties sufficient to maintain thermal stability and to minimize the switching field distribution (SFD).</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">As recording densities increase, smaller grain structures help to maintain the number of magnetic particles in a bit at a similar value. But smaller grain structures are easier to erase, requiring higher anisotropy to maintain thermal stability, and making writability worse. Further, when individual storage bits within magnetic layers of magnetic recording media are reduced in size, they store less energy making it easier for the bits to lose information. Also, as individual weaker bits are placed closer together, it is easier for continuous read/write processes and operating environments to create interference within and between the bits. This interference disrupts the read/write operations, resulting in data loss.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The magnetic layers may be designed as an ordered array of uniform islands, each island storing an individual bit. This is referred to as bit patterned media. By eliminating the continuous magnetic layer and restricting the bits to discrete magnetic islands, interference is reduced and areal densities are increased. However, high areal density bit patterned media (e.g., &#x3e;500 Gbpsi) demands high anisotropy of the magnetic material in the islands.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a data storage device in which embodiments of the present invention can be implemented to measure cluster size. In addition, embodiments of the present invention can be implemented in a number of devices including, for example, spin-stands and non-drive test systems.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a plan view of a disc drive <b>900</b>. The disc drive <b>900</b> generally includes a base plate <b>902</b> and a cover (not shown) that may be disposed on the base plate <b>902</b> to define an enclosed housing for various disc drive components. The disc drive <b>900</b> includes one or more data storage discs <b>904</b> of computer-readable data storage media. Typically, both of the major surfaces of each data storage disc <b>904</b> include a plurality of concentrically disposed tracks for data storage purposes. Each data storage disc <b>904</b> is mounted on a hub or spindle <b>906</b>, which in turn is rotatably interconnected with the base plate <b>902</b> and/or cover. Multiple data storage discs <b>904</b> are typically mounted in vertically spaced and parallel relation on the spindle <b>906</b>. A spindle motor <b>908</b> rotates the data storage discs <b>904</b> at an appropriate rate.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The disc drive <b>900</b> also includes an actuator arm assembly <b>910</b> that pivots about a pivot bearing <b>912</b>, which in turn is rotatably supported by the base plate <b>902</b> and/or cover. The actuator arm assembly <b>910</b> includes one or more individual rigid actuator arms <b>914</b> that extend out from near the pivot bearing <b>912</b>. Multiple actuator arms <b>914</b> are typically disposed in vertically spaced relation, with one actuator arm <b>914</b> being provided for each major data storage surface of each data storage disc <b>904</b> of the disc drive <b>900</b>. Other types of actuator arm assembly configurations could be utilized as well, such as an &#x201c;E&#x201d; block having one or more rigid actuator arm tips or the like that cantilever from a common structure. Movement of the actuator arm assembly <b>910</b> is provided by an actuator arm drive assembly, such as a voice coil motor <b>916</b> or the like. The voice coil motor <b>916</b> is a magnetic assembly that controls the operation of the actuator arm assembly <b>910</b> under the direction of control electronics <b>918</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">A load beam or suspension <b>920</b> is attached to the free end of each actuator arm <b>914</b> and cantilevers therefrom. Typically, the suspension <b>920</b> is biased generally toward its corresponding data storage disc <b>904</b> by a spring-like force. A slider <b>922</b> is disposed at or near the free end of each suspension <b>920</b>. What is commonly referred to as the read/write head (e.g., transducer) is appropriately mounted as a head unit (not shown) under the slider <b>922</b> and is used in disc drive read/write operations. The head unit under the slider <b>922</b> may utilize various types of read sensor technologies such as anisotropic magnetoresistive (AMR), giant magnetoresistive (GMR), tunneling magnetoresistive (TuMR), other magnetoresistive technologies, or other suitable technologies.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">The head unit under the slider <b>922</b> is connected to a preamplifier <b>926</b>, which is interconnected with the control electronics <b>918</b> of the disc drive <b>900</b> by a flex cable <b>928</b> that is typically mounted on the actuator arm assembly <b>910</b>. Signals are exchanged between the head unit and its corresponding data storage disc <b>904</b> for disc drive read/write operations. In this regard, the voice coil motor <b>916</b> is utilized to pivot the actuator arm assembly <b>910</b> to simultaneously move the slider <b>922</b> along a path <b>930</b> and across the corresponding data storage disc <b>904</b> to position the head unit at the appropriate position on the data storage disc <b>904</b> for disc drive read/write operations.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">When the disc drive <b>900</b> is not in operation, the actuator arm assembly <b>910</b> is pivoted to a &#x201c;parked position&#x201d; to dispose each slider <b>922</b> generally at or beyond a perimeter of its corresponding data storage disc <b>904</b>, but in any case in vertically spaced relation to its corresponding data storage disc <b>904</b>. In this regard, the disc drive <b>900</b> includes a ramp assembly <b>932</b> that is disposed beyond a perimeter of the data storage disc <b>904</b> to both move the corresponding slider <b>922</b> vertically away from its corresponding data storage disc <b>904</b> and to also exert somewhat of a retaining force on the actuator arm assembly <b>910</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a simplified cross-sectional view of a perpendicular magnetic recording medium <b>1000</b>, which may be used for the data storage disc <b>904</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>). The perpendicular magnetic recording medium <b>1000</b> is an apparatus including multiple layers established upon a substrate <b>1002</b>. A seed layer <b>1008</b> is a layer that is established overlying the substrate. A base layer <b>1010</b> is a layer that is established overlying the seed layer <b>1008</b>. Perpendicular magnetic recording islands <b>1012</b> are recording areas that may be established in the base layer <b>1010</b> and on the seed layer <b>1008</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">The substrate <b>1002</b> can be fabricated from materials known to those skilled in the art to be useful for magnetic recording media for hard disc storage devices. For example, the substrate <b>1002</b> may be fabricated from aluminum (Al) coated with a layer of nickel phosphorous (NiP). However, it will be appreciated that the substrate <b>1002</b> can also be fabricated from other materials such as glass and glass-containing materials, including glass-ceramics. The substrate <b>1002</b> may have a smooth surface upon which the remaining layers can be deposited.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">In a further embodiment, a buffer layer <b>1004</b> is established overlying the substrate <b>1002</b>, a soft underlayer <b>1006</b> is established overlying the buffer layer <b>1004</b>, and the seed layer <b>1008</b> is overlying the soft underlayer <b>1006</b>. The buffer layer <b>1004</b> can be established from elements such as Tantalum (Ta). The soft underlayer <b>1006</b> can be established from soft magnetic materials such as CoZrNb, CoZrTa, FeCoB and FeTaC. The soft underlayer <b>1006</b> can be formed with a high permeability and a low coercivity. For example, in an embodiment the soft underlayer <b>1006</b> has a coercivity of not greater than about 10 oersteds (Oe) and a magnetic permeability of at least about 50. The soft underlayer <b>1006</b> may comprise a single soft underlayer or multiple soft underlayers, and may be separated by spacers. If multiple soft underlayers are present, the soft underlayers can be fabricated from the same soft magnetic material or from different soft magnetic materials.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">In the embodiment illustrated, the seed layer <b>1008</b> is disposed on the soft underlayer <b>1006</b>. The seed layer <b>1008</b> can be established, for example, by physical vapor deposition (PVD) or chemical vapor deposition (CVD) from noble metal materials such as, for example, Ru, Ir, Pd, Pt, Os, Rh, Au, Ag or other alloys. The use of these materials results in desired growth properties of the perpendicular magnetic recording islands <b>1012</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">The perpendicular magnetic recording islands <b>1012</b> as described herein may be formed within the base layer <b>1010</b> and on the seed layer <b>1008</b>. The perpendicular magnetic recording islands <b>1012</b> can be established to have an easy magnetization axis (e.g., the C-axis) that is oriented perpendicular to the surface of the perpendicular magnetic recording medium <b>1000</b>. Useful materials for the perpendicular magnetic recording islands <b>1012</b> include cobalt-based alloys with a hexagonal close packed (hcp) structure. Cobalt can be alloyed with elements such as chromium (Cr), platinum (Pt), boron (B), niobium (Nb), tungsten (W) and tantalum (Ta).</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">The perpendicular magnetic recording medium <b>1000</b> can also include a protective layer (not shown) on top of the perpendicular magnetic recording islands <b>1012</b> and/or the base layer <b>1010</b>, such as a protective carbon layer, and a lubricant layer disposed over the protective layer. These layers are adapted to reduce damage from the read/write head interactions with the recording medium during start/stop operations.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a simplified cross-sectional view of a portion of the perpendicular magnetic recording medium <b>1000</b> with a head unit <b>1100</b>. During the writing process, a perpendicular write head <b>1102</b> flies or floats above the perpendicular magnetic recording medium <b>1000</b>. The perpendicular write head <b>1102</b> includes a write pole <b>1104</b> coupled to an auxiliary pole <b>1106</b>. The arrows shown indicate the path of a magnetic flux <b>1108</b>, which emanates from the write pole <b>1104</b> of the perpendicular write head <b>1102</b>, entering and passing through at least one perpendicular magnetic recording island <b>1012</b> in the region below the write pole <b>1104</b>, and entering and traveling within the soft underlayer <b>1006</b> for a distance. The magnetically soft underlayer <b>1006</b> serves to guide magnetic flux emanating from the head unit <b>1100</b> through the recording island <b>1012</b>, and enhances writability. As the magnetic flux <b>1108</b> travels towards and returns to the auxiliary pole <b>1106</b>, the magnetic flux <b>1108</b> disperses.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">The magnetic flux <b>1108</b> is concentrated at the write pole <b>1104</b>, and causes the perpendicular magnetic recording island <b>1012</b> under the write pole <b>1104</b> to magnetically align according to the input from the write pole <b>1104</b>. As the magnetic flux <b>1108</b> returns to the auxiliary pole <b>1106</b> and disperses, the magnetic flux <b>1108</b> may again encounter one or more perpendicular magnetic recording islands <b>1012</b>. However, the magnetic flux <b>1108</b> is no longer concentrated and passes through the perpendicular magnetic recording islands <b>1012</b>, without detrimentally affecting the magnetic alignment of the perpendicular magnetic recording islands <b>1012</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">The foregoing description, for purpose of explanation, has been described with reference to specific embodiments. However, the illustrative discussions above are not intended to be exhaustive or to limit the invention to the precise forms disclosed. Many modifications and variations are possible in view of the above teachings.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00001" nb-file="US08625213-20140107-M00001.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00001" he="6.35mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08625213-20140107-M00001.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00002" nb-file="US08625213-20140107-M00002.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00002" he="6.35mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08625213-20140107-M00002.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00003" nb-file="US08625213-20140107-M00003.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00003" he="6.35mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08625213-20140107-M00003.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00004" nb-file="US08625213-20140107-M00004.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00004" he="6.35mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08625213-20140107-M00004.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00005" nb-file="US08625213-20140107-M00005.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00005" he="6.35mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08625213-20140107-M00005.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00006" nb-file="US08625213-20140107-M00006.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00006" he="6.35mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08625213-20140107-M00006.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method comprising:
<claim-text>writing a first pattern of a first size of a first plurality of magnetic clusters;</claim-text>
<claim-text>writing a second pattern of a second size of a second plurality of magnetic clusters, wherein said second plurality of clusters includes clusters of said first plurality of clusters and a switched cluster; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>automatically determining a cluster size of said switched cluster by contrasting said first size and said second size.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>:
<claim-text>wherein said first size is associated with a first cluster map and said second size is associated with a second cluster map, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said contrasting comprises:
<claim-text>taking a difference between said first cluster map and said second cluster map;</claim-text>
<claim-text>integrating an area under said difference; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>normalizing said area to a peak amplitude to determine a normalized area, wherein said normalized area is determined to be said cluster size.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said contrasting comprises determining an area of said switched cluster (Ac) wherein,</claim-text>
<claim-text>
<maths id="MATH-US-00004" num="00004">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <mrow>
    <msub>
      <mi>A</mi>
      <mi>c</mi>
    </msub>
    <mo>=</mo>
    <mrow>
      <mfrac>
        <mn>1</mn>
        <msub>
          <mi>V</mi>
          <mn>0</mn>
        </msub>
      </mfrac>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mo>&#x222b;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mo>&#x222b;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mo>&#x2146;</mo>
              <msup>
                <mi>x</mi>
                <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
              </msup>
            </mrow>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>&#x2146;</mo>
              <msup>
                <mi>y</mi>
                <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
              </msup>
            </mrow>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mi>&#x3b4;</mi>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mi>V</mi>
              <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <msup>
                    <mi>x</mi>
                    <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
                  </msup>
                  <mo>,</mo>
                  <msup>
                    <mi>y</mi>
                    <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
                  </msup>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
  <mo>,</mo>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>and wherein V<sub>0</sub>=zero-to-peak readback voltage, &#x3b4;V=two-dimensional cluster readback map, x&#x2032;=down-track coordinate (direction), y&#x2032;=cross-track coordinate (direction), dx&#x2032;=down-track variable of integration, and dy&#x2032;=cross-track variable of integration.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said second pattern is substantially similar to said first pattern, and wherein said first and second patterns are magnetic patterns.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising repeating said writing said first pattern, writing said second pattern, and said automatically determining cluster size n times, and compiling a cluster size distribution.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said cluster size is a minimum size to which a bit of recorded information can be stored.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>writing a third pattern of a third size of a third plurality of magnetic clusters, wherein said third plurality of magnetic clusters includes clusters of said second plurality of magnetic clusters and a second switched cluster;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a second cluster size of said second switched cluster; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>recording a distribution of a plurality of cluster sizes, wherein said distribution includes said cluster size and said second cluster size.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A non-transitory computer readable medium having stored thereon, computer executable instructions that, if executed by a processor causes the processor to perform a method comprising:
<claim-text>writing a first pattern with a magnetic field to a first plurality of magnetic clusters, wherein said first pattern is a magnetic pattern;</claim-text>
<claim-text>moving said magnetic field in a downtrack direction a distance less than a cluster size;</claim-text>
<claim-text>writing a second pattern with said magnetic field to a second plurality of magnetic clusters, wherein said second plurality of clusters includes clusters of said first plurality of clusters and a switched cluster, and wherein said second pattern is a magnetic pattern; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>automatically determining a cluster size of said switched cluster.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The non-transitory computer readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>:
<claim-text>wherein said first pattern is associated with a first cluster map and said second pattern is a second cluster map, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said determining comprises:
<claim-text>taking a difference between said first cluster map and said second cluster map;</claim-text>
<claim-text>integrating an area under said difference; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>normalizing said area to a peak amplitude to determine a normalized area, wherein said normalized area is determined to be said cluster size.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The non-transitory computer readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> wherein said determining comprises measuring an area of said switched cluster (Ac) wherein,</claim-text>
<claim-text>
<maths id="MATH-US-00005" num="00005">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <mrow>
    <msub>
      <mi>A</mi>
      <mi>c</mi>
    </msub>
    <mo>=</mo>
    <mrow>
      <mfrac>
        <mn>1</mn>
        <msub>
          <mi>V</mi>
          <mn>0</mn>
        </msub>
      </mfrac>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mo>&#x222b;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mo>&#x222b;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mo>&#x2146;</mo>
              <msup>
                <mi>x</mi>
                <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
              </msup>
            </mrow>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>&#x2146;</mo>
              <msup>
                <mi>y</mi>
                <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
              </msup>
            </mrow>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mi>&#x3b4;</mi>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mi>V</mi>
              <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <msup>
                    <mi>x</mi>
                    <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
                  </msup>
                  <mo>,</mo>
                  <msup>
                    <mi>y</mi>
                    <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
                  </msup>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
  <mo>,</mo>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>and wherein V<sub>0</sub>=zero-to-peak readback voltage, &#x3b4;V=two-dimensional cluster readback map, x&#x2032;=down-track coordinate (direction), y&#x2032;=cross-track coordinate (direction), dx&#x2032;=down-track variable of integration, and dy&#x2032;=cross-track variable of integration.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The non-transitory computer readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> wherein said second pattern is substantially similar to said first pattern.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The non-transitory computer readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, said method further comprises repeating said writing said first pattern, writing said second pattern, and said automatically determining cluster size n times, and compiling a cluster size distribution.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The non-transitory computer readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> wherein said cluster size is a minimum size to which a bit of recorded information can be stored.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The non-transitory computer readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, said method further comprises:
<claim-text>writing a third pattern to a third plurality of magnetic clusters, wherein said third pattern is a magnetic pattern, and wherein said third plurality of magnetic clusters includes clusters of said second plurality of magnetic clusters and a second switched cluster;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a second cluster size of said second switched cluster; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>recording a distribution of a plurality of cluster sizes, wherein said distribution includes said cluster size and said second cluster size.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A method comprising:
<claim-text>magnetically orienting a first plurality of clusters in a first direction;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>mapping said first plurality of clusters and a second plurality of clusters to form a first magnetic map, wherein said second plurality of clusters is magnetically oriented in a different direction from said first plurality of clusters, and wherein said second plurality of magnetic clusters includes a transition cluster;
<claim-text>magnetically orienting a third plurality of clusters in said first direction, wherein said third plurality of clusters includes said first plurality of clusters and said transition cluster;</claim-text>
<claim-text>mapping said third plurality of clusters and said second plurality of clusters to form a second magnetic map; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>comparing said first magnetic map and said second magnetic map to automatically determine a size of said transition cluster.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref> wherein said comparing comprises:
<claim-text>taking a difference between said first magnetic map and said second magnetic map;</claim-text>
<claim-text>integrating an area under said difference; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>normalizing said area to a peak amplitude to determine a normalized area, wherein said normalized area is said size of said transition cluster.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref> wherein said determining comprises measuring an area of said transition cluster (Ac) wherein,</claim-text>
<claim-text>
<maths id="MATH-US-00006" num="00006">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <mrow>
    <msub>
      <mi>A</mi>
      <mi>c</mi>
    </msub>
    <mo>=</mo>
    <mrow>
      <mfrac>
        <mn>1</mn>
        <msub>
          <mi>V</mi>
          <mn>0</mn>
        </msub>
      </mfrac>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mo>&#x222b;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mo>&#x222b;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mo>&#x2146;</mo>
              <msup>
                <mi>x</mi>
                <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
              </msup>
            </mrow>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>&#x2146;</mo>
              <msup>
                <mi>y</mi>
                <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
              </msup>
            </mrow>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mi>&#x3b4;</mi>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mi>V</mi>
              <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <msup>
                    <mi>x</mi>
                    <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
                  </msup>
                  <mo>,</mo>
                  <msup>
                    <mi>y</mi>
                    <mi>&#x2032;</mi>
                  </msup>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
  <mo>,</mo>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>and wherein V<sub>0</sub>=zero-to-peak readback voltage, &#x3b4;V=two-dimensional cluster readback map, x&#x2032;=down-track coordinate (direction), y&#x2032;=cross-track coordinate (direction), dx&#x2032;=down-track variable of integration, and dy&#x2032;=cross-track variable of integration.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref> wherein magnetically orienting a first plurality of clusters in a first direction comprises magnetically orienting a first plurality of clusters in a first direction on a magnetic recording media.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref> wherein said transition cluster is located at a cross track boundary between said second plurality of clusters and said third plurality of clusters.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref> wherein each cluster within said first plurality of clusters, said second plurality of clusters, and said third plurality of clusters is a minimum size to which a bit of recorded information can be stored. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
