<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622477-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622477</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13024960</doc-number>
<date>20110210</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>310</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>54</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>29741135</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Adjustable armrest for a seating unit</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5484187</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Doerner et al.</name>
<date>19960100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2974113</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6059366</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hu</name>
<date>20000500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>29741135</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6948775</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Tsai</name>
<date>20050900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>29741137</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6974189</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Machael et al.</name>
<date>20051200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7011371</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Tsai</name>
<date>20060300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7159947</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Lee</name>
<date>20070100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>29741137</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7201449</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Tsai</name>
<date>20070400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7306288</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Hu et al.</name>
<date>20071200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7367628</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Tsai</name>
<date>20080500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>29741135</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7559609</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Tsai</name>
<date>20090700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>29741135</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7648207</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Lai</name>
<date>20100100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7661763</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Tsai</name>
<date>20100200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2002/0070598</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Perl</name>
<date>20020600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>29741135</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0025378</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lin</name>
<date>20030200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>29741135</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00015">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0219671</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Huang</name>
<date>20100900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>29741137</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00016">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0248543</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hitchcock et al.</name>
<date>20111000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>29741136</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>13</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>29741135</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>29741137</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>29741138</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120205958</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120816</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Colasanti</last-name>
<first-name>John Albert</first-name>
<address>
<city>Coopersville</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kooistra</last-name>
<first-name>Brett William</first-name>
<address>
<city>Grand Haven</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Colasanti</last-name>
<first-name>John Albert</first-name>
<address>
<city>Coopersville</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kooistra</last-name>
<first-name>Brett William</first-name>
<address>
<city>Grand Haven</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Shook Hardy &#x26; Bacon LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>L &#x26; P Property Management Company</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>South Gate</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Brown</last-name>
<first-name>Peter</first-name>
<department>3636</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An armrest assembly is provided for adjusting an armrest of a seating unit in three degrees of motion. The armrest assembly includes an angle-adjustment mechanism that allows the armrest to pivot and to translate forward, and a lift mechanism that enables vertical articulation of the armrest. The angle-adjustment assembly includes a pivot bracket with a downwardly disposed pin and a shuttle with an arcuate slot to receive the pin. The arcuate slot includes contoured walls that form detents for restricting movement of the pin, thereby restraining rotation of the shuttle, with respect to the pivot bracket, to predefined angular positions. The lift mechanism includes a rack with ride element(s) extending therefrom and locking teeth, and a control bar with track(s). An upward manual actuation of the control bar causes the track to shift laterally and retract the locking teeth, via interaction between the track(s) and ride element(s), respectively.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="268.82mm" wi="180.51mm" file="US08622477-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="264.24mm" wi="188.89mm" file="US08622477-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="108.88mm" wi="181.27mm" file="US08622477-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="212.51mm" wi="198.04mm" file="US08622477-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="267.29mm" wi="188.89mm" file="US08622477-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="170.60mm" wi="167.56mm" file="US08622477-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">None.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">STATEMENT REGARDING FEDERALLY SPONSORED RESEARCH OR DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">None.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Conventional seating units (e.g., office chairs) often include armrests for supporting an arm of an occupant and include a seat and a backrest to support the occupant's body in an essentially seated disposition. In some models of seating units, the armrests are configured to move vertically to cope with occupants that have differing arm lengths. However, the apparatuses presently provided to achieve this vertical movement include complex assemblies (e.g., including rotating shafts) that are difficult for the occupant to manipulate and complicated to assemble. Further, these seating units fail to incorporate additional apparatuses for adjusting the armrest in various other degrees of motion that would maximize the ergonomic fit to the occupant.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Accordingly, embodiments of the present invention relate broadly to an armrest assembly that is installed to a seating unit and designed adjust an armrest of the seating unit in three different degrees of motion. This armrest assembly includes various mechanisms to effectuate the degrees of adjustment, wherein the mechanisms are effortless to operate and simply built.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Accordingly, the present invention seeks to provide an improved seating feature, which can be integrated in essentially any type of seating unit, such as an office chair. The seating feature relates to an adjustable armrest that may be adjusted in three degrees of movement. One degree of movement pertains to vertically adjusting the armrest via a lift mechanism. The other degrees of movement pertain to angularly articulating and translatably sliding the armrest forward and rearward, with respect to a seat and/or backrest of the seating unit, via an angle-adjustment mechanism. As more fully discussed below, these mechanisms function in concert to provide an occupant of the seating unit an ergonomically optimized seating experience and to adapt to occupants of varying physical characteristics.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Initially, the lift mechanism includes an actuation lever, a support member, a rack, a control bar, and a biasing device (e.g., compression spring). In embodiments, the support member is coupled to the armrest of the seating unit via the angle-adjustment mechanism. Typically, the support member includes a ribbed portion comprising lateral bars extending therefrom. In addition, the support member may include an upper anchor for retaining a first end of the biasing device.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In an exemplary embodiment, the rack includes a series of locking teeth protruding outward therefrom. Also, the rack includes ride element(s) and a ribbed portion that slidably engages with the ribbed portion of the support member. This slidable engagement of the ribbed portions serves to impede vertical movement of the rack, but allows lateral shifting of the rack. The control bar includes a lower anchor to retains a second end of the compression device and track(s) that receive the ride elements, respectively. In operation, the control bar is configured to shift longitudinally, under the manual actuation of an occupant of the seating unit, with respect to the support member.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The anchoring of the biasing device, as discussed above, allows the biasing device to impart a sustained downward force on control bar with respect to the support member. When the manual actuation of the occupant involves an upward force on the control bar (e.g., pressing on the actuation lever inserted into the control bar) that overcomes the downward force of the biasing device, the control bar is vertically raised with respect to the support member. This raise of the control bar, in turn, causes the rack to laterally shift with respect to the support member. In an exemplary embodiment, the lateral shift of the rack is guided by an interaction between the ride element(s) and the track(s), respectively. Once the control bar is fully raised, the rack assumes a retracted condition that disengages the locking teeth. The disengagement promotes vertical manipulation of the armrest to a precisely adjusted location that meets ergonomic preferences of the occupant.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">After the precisely adjusted location is arrived upon, the occupant of the seating unit may elect to establish the armrest in that location. This may be achieved by diminishing the upward force on the control bar (e.g., releasing pressure on the actuation lever) below the downward force of the biasing device. At this point, under the influence of the biasing device, the control bar is lowered with respect to the support member. This lowering of the control bar, in turn, causes the rack to laterally shift with respect to the support member. Once the control bar is fully lowered, the rack assumes an extended condition that engages the locking teeth. The engagement prevents unintentional vertical movement of the armrest and supports an arm of the occupant when resting on the armrest of the seating unit.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Generally, the angle-adjustment mechanism includes a shuttle, a compressive device, a detent key, a rail, and a pivot bracket. Typically, the angle-adjustment mechanism is coupled to a mounting plate, a pivot pin for securing the pivot bracket to the mounting plate, and a moveable housing. In embodiments, the angle-adjustment mechanism enables two degrees of articulation of the armrest. Specifically, the angle-adjustment mechanism may allow the armrest to translate fore and aft with respect to the seating unit, while facilitating selective pivotal adjustment of the armrest. As such, the occupant may employ the angle-adjustment mechanism to easily and conveniently adjust the armrest, while seated in the seating unit, to satisfy his or her ergonomic preferences.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Initially, the moveable housing is assembled to the armrest of the seating unit. The moveable housing includes a lower plate and a plurality of walls extending upward from the lower plate. In an exemplary embodiment, the lower plate includes an elongate slot formed therein. The mounting plate includes an upwardly disposed post element that, at least, partially extends through the elongate slot. The pivot bracket of the angle-adjustment assembly may be attached to the post element, as mentioned above. In addition, the pivot bracket includes a bushing, an arm radially extending from the bushing, and a pin downwardly disposed from the arm. The shuttle is rotatably coupled to the bushing of the pivot bracket. Further, the shuttle includes an arcuate slot for receiving the pin of the pivot bracket.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In an exemplary embodiment, the arcuate slot includes section(s) that are configured with a width that is undersized with respect to a thickness of the pin. That is, an interference is designed into an interaction between the arcuate slot and the pin. This interference acts to restrain any free rotation of the shuttle with respect to the pivot bracket. Typically, the arcuate slot includes a distal wall and a proximal wall with respect to the bushing. In one instance, the undersized sections of the arcuate slot, with respect to the pin, represent contours on the distal and proximal walls that form a set of detents. In operation, the set of detents define a plurality of predefined angular positions of the armrest. In another instance, the undersized sections of the arcuate slot represent substantially smooth surfaces on the distal and proximal walls, such that a continuous range of angular positions is provided by the arcuate slot. The continuous range of angular position is made possible, in part, upon the shuttle being composed of a flexible material. In this way, the interference created between the undersized width of the arcuate slot and the thickness of the pin results in a compression of the distal and proximal walls against the pin.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">With respect to the fore-and-aft translation of the angle-adjustment mechanism, the shuttle may include a cavity bored therein, where the compressive device (e.g., compression spring) is received within the cavity. In embodiments, one end of the compressive device may be held in place by a chamber wall of the cavity, while an opposed end of the compressive device may be coupled to the detent key causing a resistive force between the detent key and rail. In operation, upon applying a lateral force to the moveable house the occupant overcomes the resistive force causing fore-aft movement and forcing the detent key across the rail.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The rail may be removably installed to the moveable housing and may be reversible to accomplish differing feels during translational movement of the angle-adjustment mechanism. Generally, the rail may be fabricated with at least one face, where the face of the rail physically interfaces with the detent key to restrain translation of the moveable housing with respect to the mounting plate. In one instance, the face includes contours that form a set of detents, which define a plurality of predefined translational positions of the moveable housing with respect to the mounting plate. In another instance, the face includes a substantially smooth surface, such that a continuous range of transitional positions is provided by the rail. In an exemplary embodiment, the rail is composed of a flexible material that assists the physical interface, or contact, between the detent key and the substantially smooth surface of the rail in frictionally holding the shuttle in a particular transitional position.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">This Summary is provided to introduce a selection of concepts in a simplified form that are further described below in the Detailed Description. This Summary is not intended to identify key features or essential features of the claimed subject matter, nor is it intended to be used as an aid in determining the scope of the claimed subject matter. The present invention is defined by the claims.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWING</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Illustrative embodiments of the present invention are described in detail below with reference to the attached drawing figures, which are incorporated by reference herein. In the accompanying drawings, which form a part of the specification and which are to be read in conjunction therewith, and in which like reference numerals are used to indicate like parts in the various views:</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagrammatic perspective view of seating unit that has an armrest assembly installed thereto, in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is diagrammatic perspective view of the armrest assembly with a cut-away section to expose locking teeth of a rack, in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an exploded view of an angle-adjustment mechanism, in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagrammatic perspective view of the angle-adjustment mechanism, in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an elevation view of the angle-adjustment assembly installed to a moveable housing, in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is an exploded view of a lift mechanism, in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a diagrammatic perspective view of the lift mechanism adjusted to a retracted condition, in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a view similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, but illustrating the lift mechanism adjusted to an extended condition, in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is an elevation view of the armrest assembly with a cut-away section to expose the locking teeth engaged to a locking block, in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The subject matter of the present invention is described with specificity herein to meet statutory requirements. However, the description itself is not intended to limit the scope of this patent. Rather, the inventors have contemplated that the claimed subject matter might also be embodied in other ways, to include different steps or varying components/materials similar to the ones described in this document, in conjunction with other present or future technologies.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Generally, embodiments of the present invention relate to an armrest mechanism for adjusting an armrest of a seating unit along three degrees of motion. As used herein, the phrase &#x201c;seating units&#x201d; is not meant to be limited to office chairs similar to the type illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. Instead, seating units refer broadly to any style of furniture designed to support a user's body in an essentially seated disposition. As such, seating units may include recliners, incliners, sofas, love seats, sectionals, theater seating, traditional chairs, chairs with a moveable seat portion, and other such furniture pieces. Further, a user occupying the seating unit may be described as an occupant, while a user adjusting the armrest mechanism may be described as an operator. However, it should be noted that the terms &#x201c;operator&#x201d; and &#x201c;occupant&#x201d; both generally relate to a person within proximity of the seating unit, and hereinafter are used interchangeably.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The armrest assembly includes an angle-adjustment mechanism and a lift mechanism to effectuate the three degrees of motion described above. These mechanisms involve a plurality of interconnected components that are arranged to actuate (e.g., slide and/or rotate with respect to one another) and control movement of the armrest between a variety of vertical, translational, and angular positions. Typically, in order to accomplish this actuation of the armrest, the components are coupled together. It is understood and appreciated that these couplings between these components can take a variety of configurations, such as pivot pins, bearings, traditional mounting hardware, rivets, bolt and nut combinations, or any other suitable fasteners that are well-known in the furniture-manufacturing industry. Further, the shapes of the components may vary from the illustrated components in the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-9</figref>, as may the locations of certain couplings. It will be understood that when a linkage is referred to as being pivotably &#x201c;coupled&#x201d; to, &#x201c;interconnected&#x201d; with, &#x201c;mounted&#x201d; to, &#x201c;attached&#x201d; on, etc., another component, it is contemplated that the components may be in direct contact with each other, or other elements, such as intervening elements/components/mechanisms, may also be present.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Further, the discussion herein focuses on a single armrest assembly. However, in an exemplary configuration, a pair of armrest are provided on a single seating unit, where movement of the pair of armrests is controlled independently by a pair of armrest assemblies, respectively (one of which is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> and indicated by reference numeral <b>100</b>). Because a rack provided within each of the armrest assemblies is substantially centrally located, each of the pair of armrest assemblies may be substantially similar in design. This is true even when the pair of armrest assemblies is incorporated within both right- and left-side arms, respectively, of the seating unit. As such, the ensuing discussion will focus on only one of the armrest assemblies, with the content being equally applied to the other substantially similar armrest assembly incorporated in a complimentary arm of the seating unit. It should be noted, that this centrally located rack, in combination with the compact design of the lift mechanism, allows the lift mechanism to be housed in varying types of arms, thereby minimizing the investment to manufacture specific arms with customized styling for accepting the lift mechanisms.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Turning to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, an exemplary seating unit <b>10</b> having adjustable armrests will now be described according to embodiments of the present invention. Initially, the seating unit <b>10</b> (e.g., office chair) includes a base <b>60</b>, a pedestal <b>70</b>, a seat pan <b>40</b>, a seat <b>30</b>, a backrest <b>20</b>, and control lever(s) <b>50</b> for invoking adjustment of the seat <b>30</b> and the backrest <b>20</b>. As illustrated, the base <b>60</b> is designed with a hub-and-spoke configuration with castors <b>65</b> connected to each of the spokes, respectively. Further, the castors <b>65</b> are located intermediately between the base <b>60</b> and an underlying surface (not shown) to facilitate mobilizing the seating unit <b>10</b>. The pedestal <b>70</b> may include a lower end rotatably coupled to the base <b>60</b> and an upper end pivotably coupled to the seat pan <b>40</b>. The seat pan <b>40</b> serves to support the seat <b>30</b>, as well as an occupant thereof. Further, the seat pan <b>40</b> may be attached to the armrest assemblies <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, one of the armrest assemblies <b>100</b> will now be described in general. As shown, the illustrative armrest assembly <b>100</b> includes an armrest <b>125</b> for supporting an arm of an occupant of the seating unit <b>10</b>, a support <b>110</b>, a moveable housing <b>120</b> assembled to the armrest <b>125</b>, a sleeve <b>130</b>, and an actuation lever <b>210</b> of the lift mechanism. In embodiments, the armrest assembly <b>100</b> is configured with a substantially vertical section <b>112</b> and a substantially horizontal section <b>111</b> joined by an angled, or L-shaped, portion <b>117</b>. The substantially vertical section <b>112</b> section may be formed as a hollow column that includes an interior surface (see cut-away section of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 9</figref>). In embodiments, the interior surface holds a locking block (see reference numeral <b>119</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>) extending inward from the interior surface of the support <b>110</b>. In operation, as discussed more fully below, locking teeth on a rack selectively engage with the locking block when a control bar of the adjustment mechanism is shifted downward. Further, the interior surface may be employed to substantially encapsulate and support the adjustment assembly. In other words, the adjustment assembly is telescopically mounted to the interior surface of the substantially vertical section <b>112</b> of the support <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The substantially horizontal section <b>111</b> of the support <b>110</b> includes a mounting surface <b>115</b> that assembles the armrest assembly <b>100</b> to the seat pan <b>40</b> of the seating unit <b>10</b>. In embodiments, the mounting surface <b>115</b> may include a pattern of apertures <b>116</b> capable of mounting to a plurality of dissimilar-shaped seat pans, thereby incorporating adaptability into the design of the support <b>110</b>. Further, the mounting surface <b>115</b> is capable of accepting and mating to various spacers in order to lower the adjustment assembly <b>100</b> with respect to the seat <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The sleeve <b>130</b> is coupled to, and adjustable in accordance with, the lift assembly. In one instance, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, fasteners <b>145</b> that couple a mounting plate <b>140</b> to a support member <b>220</b> of the lift mechanism are employed to couple the sleeve <b>130</b> to the lift mechanism as well. Further, the sleeve <b>130</b> functions as a housing that covers and protects the lift mechanism. Even further, the sleeve <b>130</b> may assume various profiles that provide an aesthetic component to the armrest assembly <b>100</b>. As depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, an upper portion of the sleeve <b>130</b> may include an aperture formed therein to allow the actuation lever <b>210</b> to extend outward through the sleeve <b>130</b>. As such, the occupant is provided access to the actuation lever <b>210</b>, allowing the occupant to manually actuate the lift mechanism.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Turning to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref>, components of the angle-adjustment mechanism <b>300</b> will now be discussed, in accordance with embodiments of the present invention. Generally, the angle-adjustment mechanism <b>300</b> includes a rail <b>310</b>, a pivot bracket <b>320</b>, a shuttle <b>330</b>, a detent key <b>340</b>, and a compressive device <b>350</b>. Typically, the angle-adjustment mechanism <b>300</b> is coupled to the mounting plate <b>140</b>. In one instance, a pivot pin <b>360</b> may be provided for securing the pivot bracket <b>320</b> to a post element <b>141</b> extending upward from the mounting plate <b>140</b>. As illustrated, the pivot pin <b>360</b> is received into a bore that is axially aligned with a downward-disposed bushing <b>325</b> of the pivot bracket <b>320</b> and is received into a vertical cavity <b>142</b> bored into the post element <b>141</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Generally, the angle-adjustment mechanism <b>300</b> also is coupled to the moveable housing <b>120</b>. In one embodiment, the moveable housing <b>120</b> includes a beam <b>128</b> with fins <b>126</b> formed therein, a lower plate <b>123</b>, and walls <b>122</b> attached to the lower plate <b>123</b>. The walls <b>122</b> may include four adjoining plates that extend upwardly from the lower plate <b>123</b> and form a perimeter around the lower plate <b>123</b>. This perimeter may act to partially enclose the angle-adjustment mechanism <b>300</b>, as well as assemble to the armrest <b>125</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The walls <b>122</b> may include an inner surface <b>121</b> that guides fore-and-aft translation of the moveable housing <b>120</b> with respect to the shuttle <b>330</b>. In an exemplary embodiment, the lower plate <b>123</b> includes an elongate slot <b>124</b> formed therein. The post element <b>141</b> of the mounting plate <b>140</b> may extend through the elongate slot <b>124</b>, in effect, helping to guide the fore-and-aft translation of the moveable housing <b>120</b> with respect to the mounting plate <b>140</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Typically, the pivot bracket <b>320</b> of the angle-adjustment mechanism <b>300</b> may be securely coupled to the post element <b>141</b>, as mentioned above. In addition, the pivot bracket <b>320</b> includes the bushing <b>325</b>, a base plate <b>322</b> from which the bushing <b>325</b> is downwardly disposed, an arm <b>323</b> radially extending from the base plate <b>322</b>, and a pin <b>324</b> downwardly disposed from the arm <b>323</b>. Generally, the pivot bracket <b>320</b> is composed of a hard material, such as plastic. In an particular case, the plastic may be polyacetal or any other thermoplastic material used in precision parts, where the thermoplastic material offers a high level of stiffness, low friction, and excellent dimensional stability.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In an exemplary embodiment, the shuttle <b>330</b> includes a base plate <b>334</b>, a centrally positioned bushing <b>333</b> with a bore formed therein, a raised housing <b>332</b> with a cavity <b>337</b> bored therein, and an arcuate slot <b>331</b> that has a distal wall <b>338</b> and a proximal wall <b>339</b>, with respect to the bushing <b>333</b>. In one configuration, the arcuate slot <b>331</b> includes a cutout <b>336</b> in the distal wall <b>338</b>, where the cutout <b>336</b> divides the distal wall <b>338</b> into a pair of fingers <b>335</b>, or wings. When the shuttle <b>330</b> is composed of a flexible material, one or both of the fingers <b>335</b> may deflect elastically upon the pin <b>324</b> of the pivot bracket <b>320</b> transitioning within the arcuate slot <b>331</b>, as discussed more fully with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The arcuate slot <b>331</b> generally includes section(s) that are configured with a width that is undersized with respect to a thickness of the pin <b>324</b>. That is, an interference is designed into an interaction between the arcuate slot <b>331</b> and the pin <b>324</b>. This interference acts to restrain any free rotation of the shuttle <b>330</b> (in conjuncture with the moveable housing <b>120</b>), with respect to the pivot bracket <b>320</b>. In one instance, the undersized sections of the arcuate slot <b>331</b>, with respect to the pin <b>324</b>, represent concave and convex contours on the distal wall <b>338</b> and/or the proximal wall <b>339</b>, where the contours form a set of detents. In other instances, the contours include notches, grooves, slits, or other textures machined into one or more of the walls <b>338</b> and <b>339</b>. In operation, the set of detents define a plurality of predefined angular positions of the armrest, such as B and B&#x2032; of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. When the pin <b>324</b> is moved between angular positions within the set of detents, one or both of the fingers <b>335</b> may deflect elastically to allow rotation of the shuttle <b>330</b>. However, the fingers <b>335</b> collapse upon the pin <b>324</b> and hold it firmly in a targeted angular position upon the occupant reducing a rotational force applied to the armrest <b>125</b> and, by extension, to the shuttle <b>330</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In another instance, the undersized sections of the arcuate slot <b>331</b> each represent a substantially smooth surface on the distal wall <b>338</b> and/or the proximal wall <b>339</b>. In this way, a continuous range of angular positions is provided by the arcuate slot <b>331</b>. The continuous range of angular position is made possible, in part, when the shuttle <b>330</b> is composed of a flexible material (e.g., nylon) that may be elastically compressed. The flexible material will naturally apply a restoring force to push outwardly at a point of compression. Accordingly, the restoring force seizes the pin <b>324</b> between the walls <b>338</b> and <b>339</b> at the point of interference and temporarily holds the shuttle <b>330</b> in an angular position with respect to the pivot bracket <b>320</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Although various different configurations of the arcuate slot <b>331</b> have been described, it should be understood and appreciated that other types of suitable configurations of an &#x201c;arcuate slot&#x201d; may be used, and that embodiments of the present invention are not limited to the specific designs of the arcuate slot <b>331</b> described herein. For instance, the arcuate slot <b>331</b> may comprise a single pivoting spring arm that is formed upon removing one side wall connecting the distal wall <b>338</b> and the proximal wall <b>339</b>. In another instance, there are no cut-outs within walls of the actuate slot <b>331</b>, such the arcuate slot <b>331</b> represents a completely closed loop. In operation, the embodiment with a closed arcuate slot <b>331</b> includes a relatively thin distal wall <b>338</b> that flexes inward (to capture the pin <b>324</b>) and outward (to allow translation of the pin <b>324</b>), thereby providing a type of spring tension on the pin <b>324</b>. As such, embodiments of the present invention contemplate a wide variety of configurations of the arcuate slot <b>331</b>; thus, the arcuate slot <b>331</b> should not be construed as being limited to a particular design, but may encompass any slot, aperture, groove, fingers, etc., that act to selectively hold in tension a pin while allowing the pin to translate upon a user applying a threshold amount of angular force (moment) to the armrest.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">With respect to the fore-and-aft translation of the angle-adjustment mechanism <b>300</b>, the raised housing <b>332</b> of the shuttle <b>330</b> may include a laterally oriented cavity <b>337</b> bored therein. As depicted in the cut-away section of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the compressive device <b>350</b> (e.g., compression spring, deformable tube, and the like) is received within the cavity <b>337</b>. In embodiments, one end <b>352</b> of the compressive device <b>350</b> may be held in place by a chamber wall of the cavity <b>337</b>, while an opposed end <b>351</b> of the compressive device <b>350</b> may be coupled to the detent key <b>340</b>, thus, spring-loading the detent key <b>340</b> in an outwardly biased direction. In operation, upon applying a directional force to the detent key <b>340</b>, which overcomes a resistance inherent to the compressive device <b>350</b>, the detent key <b>340</b> is configured to traverse an opening of the cavity <b>337</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The rail <b>310</b> may be removably installed to the fins <b>126</b> of the moveable housing <b>120</b> and may be reversible to accomplish differing feels during translational movement of the angle-adjustment mechanism <b>300</b>. Generally, the rail <b>310</b> may be fabricated with a number of faces <b>311</b> and <b>312</b>, where each face of the rail <b>310</b> physically interfaces with the detent key <b>340</b> to restrain translation of the moveable housing <b>120</b> with respect to the mounting plate <b>140</b>. In one instance, the face <b>311</b> includes contours that form a set of detents <b>313</b>, which define a plurality of predefined translational positions of the moveable housing <b>120</b>, such as transitional positions A (detent <b>313</b>) and A&#x2032; (detent <b>313</b>&#x2032;) of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. In another instance, the face <b>312</b> includes a substantially smooth surface. In this instance, a continuous range of transitional positions may be provided by the smooth-surfaced face <b>312</b> of the rail <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In an exemplary embodiment, the rail <b>310</b> is composed of a flexible material that assists the physical interface, or contact, between the detent key <b>340</b> and the smooth-surfaced face <b>312</b> of the rail <b>310</b> in frictionally holding the shuttle <b>330</b> in a particular transitional position. The flexible material may comprise a soft-durometer rubber or any other material that permits slight compressions/deflections for inhibiting the detent key <b>340</b> from freely sliding over a face of the rail <b>310</b>. As such, the flexible material within the rail <b>310</b> imposes a rubbing action against the detent key <b>340</b>. Further, a variety of interchangeable rails <b>310</b> that have differing levels of flexibility, or stiffness, may be provided with the armrest assembly <b>100</b> to furnish the occupant a selection of break-away forces for invoking fore-and-aft translation of the armrest <b>125</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, operation of the angle-adjustment mechanism <b>300</b> will now be discussed, in accordance with embodiments of the present invention. As discussed above, the angle-adjustment mechanism <b>300</b> enables two degrees of articulation of the armrest <b>125</b>. In embodiments, the angle-adjustment mechanism <b>300</b> may allow the armrest to translate fore and aft with respect to the seating unit. The fore-and-aft translation may be restrained by detents <b>313</b> in the face <b>311</b> of the rail <b>310</b>. In this way, the detents <b>313</b> and <b>313</b>&#x2032; define translational positions A and A&#x2032;, respectively. Further, the angle-adjustment mechanism <b>300</b> may allow the occupant to selectively, pivotably adjustment of the armrest <b>125</b>. In embodiments, the angle-adjustment mechanism <b>300</b> may allow the armrest to pivotably adjust upon sliding the pin <b>324</b> over the detents on the walls <b>338</b> and <b>339</b> of the arcuate slot <b>331</b> formed in the shuttle <b>330</b>. In this way, the pivotably adjustment may be restrained by detents, such that the detents that define angular positions B and B&#x2032;, where B&#x2032; is angularly offset in comparison with position B. As such, the occupant may employ the single angle-adjustment mechanism <b>300</b> to easily and conveniently translate and pivot the armrest <b>125</b>, while seated in the seating unit, to satisfy his or her ergonomic preferences.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Turning to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6-9</figref>, the configuration of the lift mechanism <b>200</b> will now be discussed. Initially, the lift mechanism <b>200</b> includes an actuation lever <b>210</b>, a support member <b>220</b>, an internal locking rack <b>240</b>, a control bar <b>250</b>, and a biasing device <b>230</b> (e.g., compression spring). As discussed above, the support member <b>220</b> is coupled to the mounting plate <b>140</b> via fasteners <b>145</b>. In embodiments, an upper portion <b>222</b> of the support member <b>220</b> is provided with mating pads <b>223</b> with a pattern of holes <b>224</b> formed (e.g., drilled of molded) therein. The holes are configured to receive the fasteners <b>145</b>. Once assembled via the fasteners <b>145</b>, the mating pads <b>223</b> are held tightly against a lower surface of the mounting plate <b>140</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Typically, the support member <b>220</b> includes a ribbed portion <b>226</b> comprising lateral bars <b>225</b> extending therefrom. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the lateral bars <b>225</b> are evenly spaced, substantially parallel, rectangular protrusions that are aligned on a single surface of the support member <b>220</b>. In addition, the support member <b>220</b> may include an upper anchor <b>227</b> for retaining a first end <b>231</b> of the biasing device <b>230</b> (e.g., compressive device <b>350</b>, helical spring, or any other device that imparts a constant and uniform directional force when compressed). In one instance, the upper anchor <b>227</b> is configured as a downwardly disposed pin that may be inserted into an opening of the biasing device <b>230</b>, thereby retaining the first end <b>231</b>. Further, the support member may include a knob <b>228</b> with a cap. In one instance, the knob <b>228</b> extends from a lower portion of the support member <b>220</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In an exemplary embodiment, the rack <b>240</b> includes a series of locking teeth <b>241</b> protruding outward therefrom. In one instance, the locking teeth <b>241</b>, represent tooth-like protrusions extending outward from an elongate engagement portion of the rack <b>240</b>. Further, the locking teeth <b>241</b> may represent a series of selectively engageable protrusions with vertically aligned openings, or recesses, therebetween. When vertically aligned, the locking teeth <b>241</b> may engage with complimenting protrusions (e.g., locking block <b>119</b>) extending inward from an interior surface of the support <b>110</b>, thereby supporting the armrest <b>125</b> in one of a set of predefined longitudinal positions.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">As mentioned above, the individual locking teeth <b>241</b> are symmetrical and can be used in both left- and right-side configurations of the armrest assembly <b>100</b>. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</figref>, a spine <b>249</b> is provided to reduce flexibility in the locking teeth <b>241</b> while increasing the overall surface area of engagement with the locking block <b>119</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>. In a specific model of the lift mechanism <b>200</b>, the locking teeth <b>241</b> are arranged and designed based on a length of travel (e.g., 3 inches of vertical range of movement) and on a number of positions (e.g., 8-10) within the length of travel.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Also, the rack <b>240</b> may include ride element(s) <b>244</b>. These ride element(s) <b>244</b> may extend outward from the rack <b>240</b> and may, in embodiments, be configured as diamond-shaped wedges. Further, the ride element(s) <b>244</b> may be shaped to fit and travel within track(s) <b>255</b> formed into the control bar <b>250</b>. In operation, the tracks(s) <b>255</b> slide upward and downward, which guides the ride element(s) <b>244</b> and, by extension, the rack <b>240</b> to shift laterally.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The rack <b>240</b> may further include a ribbed portion with lateral bars <b>242</b>. In embodiments, the lateral bars <b>242</b> may be positioned on an upper portion <b>247</b> and/or a lower portion <b>246</b> of the rack <b>240</b>, where gap between the portions <b>246</b> and <b>247</b> receives the biasing device <b>230</b> such that the biasing device <b>230</b> is integral to the lift mechanism <b>200</b>. The lateral bars <b>242</b> may be shaped and positioned to compliment the lateral bars <b>225</b> extending from the support member <b>220</b>. Accordingly, the lateral bars <b>242</b> of the rack <b>240</b> slidably engage with the ribbed portion <b>226</b> of the support member <b>220</b>. In operation, this slidable engagement serves to impede vertical movement of the rack <b>240</b>, but allows lateral shifting of the rack <b>240</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The control bar <b>250</b> includes a lower anchor <b>254</b> to retain a second end <b>232</b> of the biasing device <b>230</b>. In one instance, the lower anchor <b>254</b> is configured as an upwardly disposed pin that may be inserted into an opening of the biasing device <b>230</b>, thereby retaining the second end <b>232</b>. The control bar <b>250</b> may also include the track(s) <b>255</b> that receive the ride element(s) <b>244</b>, respectively. The tracks(s) <b>255</b> may be configured with a substantially vertical region <b>257</b> and a diagonal region <b>256</b> that acts as a ramp to laterally shift the rack <b>240</b>. Further, the control bar <b>250</b> may include an opening <b>251</b> in its upper portion and a pair of prongs <b>252</b> with a slot <b>253</b> therebetween in its lower portion. Generally the knob <b>228</b> is captured within the slot <b>253</b>, thereby guiding the vertical movement of the control bar <b>250</b> with respect to the support member <b>220</b>. In operation, the control bar <b>250</b> is configured to shift longitudinally under the manual actuation of an operator of the seating unit.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In an exemplary embodiment, the occupant's manual actuation for vertically adjusting the armrest <b>125</b> is directed to the actuation lever <b>210</b>. The actuation lever <b>210</b> includes a knob portion <b>212</b> for receiving the occupant's interaction and a pair of hooked prongs <b>211</b> that assemble to the opening <b>251</b> of the control bar <b>250</b>. In one instance, the prongs <b>211</b> snap into place upon insertion into the opening <b>215</b> and temporarily attach the actuation lever <b>210</b> to the control bar <b>250</b>. In an exemplary embodiment, the prongs <b>211</b> are adapted to assemble with and secure to either side of the opening <b>251</b>. In this way, the lift mechanism <b>200</b> may housed by either the right-side support <b>110</b> or the left-side support <b>110</b> while still providing an outwardly directed actuation lever <b>210</b> on each of the supports <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The operation of the lift mechanism <b>200</b> will now be described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</figref>. Initially, the biasing device <b>230</b> imparts a sustained downward force on the control bar <b>250</b> with respect to the support member <b>220</b>. When the manual actuation of the occupant involves an upward force on the control bar <b>250</b> (e.g., pushing up on the actuation lever <b>210</b> mated with the control bar <b>250</b>) that overcomes the downward force of the biasing device <b>230</b>, the control bar <b>250</b> is vertically raised with respect to the support member <b>220</b>. This raise of the control bar <b>250</b>, in turn, causes the rack <b>240</b> (sandwiched between the control bar <b>250</b> and the support member <b>220</b>) to laterally shift with respect to the support member <b>220</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In an exemplary embodiment, the lateral shift of the rack <b>240</b> is guided by an interaction between the ride element(s) <b>244</b> and the track(s) <b>255</b>, respectively. For example, when the lift mechanism <b>200</b> is in the extended condition (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>), the diagonal region <b>256</b> of the track(s) <b>255</b> acts as a ramp to pull inward the ride element(s) <b>244</b> and retract the rack <b>240</b> while the control bar <b>250</b> is moved upward. Once the control bar <b>250</b> is fully raised, the ride element(s) <b>244</b> are moved to the substantially vertical region <b>257</b> of the track(s) <b>255</b>. Also, when fully raised, the rack <b>240</b> assumes a retracted condition (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>) that disengages the locking teeth <b>241</b> from the locking block <b>119</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>. The disengagement promotes vertical manipulation of the armrest <b>125</b> to a precisely adjusted location that meets ergonomic preferences of the occupant.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">After the precisely adjusted location is arrived upon, the occupant of the seating unit may elect to establish the armrest <b>125</b> in that location. This may be achieved by diminishing the upward force on the control bar <b>250</b> (e.g., releasing the actuation level <b>210</b>) below the downward force exerted by the biasing device <b>230</b>. At this point, under the influence of the biasing device <b>230</b>, the control bar <b>250</b> is automatically lowered with respect to the support member <b>220</b>. This lowering of the control bar <b>250</b>, in turn, causes the rack <b>240</b> to laterally shift outward with respect to the support member <b>220</b>. This outward lateral shift is effectuated by the slidable engagement of the track(s) <b>255</b> and the ride element(s) <b>244</b> in a procedure reverse in operation to the inward pull described above. Once the control bar <b>250</b> is fully lowered, the rack <b>240</b> assumes the extended condition that engages the locking teeth <b>241</b> with the locking block <b>119</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>. The engagement prevents unintended vertical movement of the armrest <b>125</b> and supports an arm of the occupant when resting on the armrest <b>125</b> of the seating unit.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">It should be understood that the construction of the armrest assembly <b>100</b> lends itself to enable easy assembly to, and disassembly from, the seat and/or backrest. Specifically, the design of the mounting surface <b>115</b> on the support <b>110</b> may allow for use of quick-disconnect hardware, such as a knock-down fastener. Accordingly, rapid disconnection of components of the seating unit <b>10</b> prior to shipping, or rapid connection upon receipt, is facilitated.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The present invention has been described in relation to particular embodiments, which are intended in all respects to be illustrative rather than restrictive. Alternative embodiments will become apparent to those skilled in the art to which the present invention pertains without departing from its scope.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">It will be seen from the foregoing that this invention is one well adapted to attain the ends and objects set forth above, and to attain other advantages, which are obvious and inherent in the device. It will be understood that certain features and subcombinations are of utility and may be employed without reference to other features and subcombinations. This is contemplated by and within the scope of the claims. It will be appreciated by persons skilled in the art that the present invention is not limited to what has been particularly shown and described hereinabove. Rather, all matter herein set forth or shown in the accompanying drawings is to be interpreted as illustrative and not limiting.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An armrest assembly provided for a seating unit, the armrest assembly comprising:
<claim-text>an armrest for supporting an arm of an occupant of the seating unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a support fixedly mounted to a seat pan of the seating unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a moveable housing having a lower plate and a plurality of walls attached to the lower plate, wherein the lower plate includes an elongate slot formed therein, and wherein the armrest is assembled to the moveable housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mounting plate having an upwardly disposed post element that, at least, partially extends through the elongate slot, wherein the mounting plate is moveably coupled to the support; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an angle-adjustment mechanism for enabling two degrees of articulation of the armrest, the angle-adjustment mechanism comprising:
<claim-text>(a) a pivot bracket attached to the post element, wherein the pivot bracket includes a bushing, an arm radially extending from the bushing, and a pin downwardly disposed from the arm; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a shuttle rotatably coupled to the bushing, wherein the shuttle includes an arcuate slot for receiving the pin, wherein one or more sections of the arcuate slot are configured with a width that is undersized with respect to a thickness of the pin, thereby restraining rotation of the shuttle with respect to the pivot bracket.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The armrest assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the arcuate slot includes a distal wall and a proximal wall with respect to the bushing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The armrest assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the one or more sections of the arcuate slot that are configured with the undersized width represent contours on the distal and proximal walls that form a set of detents, wherein the set of detents define a plurality of predefined angular positions of the armrest.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The armrest assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein a cutout is provided in the distal wall or the proximal wall of the arcuate slot.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The armrest assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the shuttle is composed of a flexible material such that the distal wall or the proximal wall deflect elastically upon translating the pin within the arcuate slot.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The armrest assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the one or more sections of the arcuate slot that are configured with the undersized width comprise substantially smooth surfaces on the distal and proximal walls such that a continuous range of angular positions is provided by the arcuate slot.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The armrest assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the shuttle is composed of a flexible material such that an interference created between the undersized width of the arcuate slot and the thickness of the pin results in a compression of the distal and proximal walls against the pin.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The armrest assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the shuttle includes a cavity, and wherein the angle-adjustment mechanism further comprises:
<claim-text>a compressive device having a first end and a second end, wherein the first end is received within the cavity;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a detent key coupled to the second end of the compressive device, wherein, upon applying a directional force to the detent key that overcomes a resistance inherent to the compressive device, the detent key is configured to traverse an opening of the cavity; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a rail having at least one face, which physically interfaces with the detect key to restrain fore-and-aft translation of the moveable housing with respect to the mounting plate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The armrest assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the armrest assembly is removably installed to the moveable housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The armrest assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one face includes contours that form a set of detents, and wherein the set of detents on the rail define a plurality of predefined translational positions of the moveable housing with respect to the mounting plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The armrest assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the rail is composed of a flexible material, and wherein the physical interface represents contact between the detent key and the substantially smooth surface such that the rail frictionally holds the shuttle in a particular transitional position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The armrest assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the angle-adjustment mechanism further comprises a pivot pin that couples the pivot bracket to the post element of the mounting plate, wherein the pivot pin is received by an aperture through the bushing of the pivot bracket.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The armrest assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one face includes a substantially smooth surface such that a continuous range of transitional positions is provided by the rail. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
