<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624149-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624149</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13348281</doc-number>
<date>20120111</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>179</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>23</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>10</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>34</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>21912148</main-classification>
<further-classification>2191215</further-classification>
<further-classification>21912151</further-classification>
<further-classification>219 75</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Plasma torch with reversible baffle</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3667371</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Russell</name>
<date>19720600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>126299 D</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4207925</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Nelson</name>
<date>19800600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>138 44</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5275735</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Stearns</name>
<date>19940100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>210628</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5680014</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Miyamoto et al.</name>
<date>19971000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>31511141</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8258423</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Severance et al.</name>
<date>20120900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>21912148</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>17</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>21912136</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>21912148</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>21912149</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2191215</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>21912151</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>219 74</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>219 75</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>21913742</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-cpc-text>H05H 1/34</classification-cpc-text>
<classification-cpc-text>B23K 10/00</classification-cpc-text>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130175244</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130711</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Griffin</last-name>
<first-name>David Charles</first-name>
<address>
<city>Florence</city>
<state>SC</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Diehl</last-name>
<first-name>Gregory William</first-name>
<address>
<city>Florence</city>
<state>SC</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Martin</last-name>
<first-name>Christopher Reed</first-name>
<address>
<city>Florence</city>
<state>SC</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Griffin</last-name>
<first-name>David Charles</first-name>
<address>
<city>Florence</city>
<state>SC</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Diehl</last-name>
<first-name>Gregory William</first-name>
<address>
<city>Florence</city>
<state>SC</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Martin</last-name>
<first-name>Christopher Reed</first-name>
<address>
<city>Florence</city>
<state>SC</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Kacvinsky Daisak PLLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>The ESAB Group, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Florence</city>
<state>SC</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Paschall</last-name>
<first-name>Mark</first-name>
<department>3742</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A plasma arc torch includes an annular baffle defining distinct faces A, B, C, and D. Faces A and C are opposite from each other, and faces B and D are opposite from each other. First passages for fluid flow extend between the faces A and C, and second passages extend between the faces B and D. The baffle is installable in an annular space between an inner wall and an outer wall, in either of two orientations. In a first orientation, the first passages are open to fluid flow and the second passages are closed by engagement of the inner and outer walls with the faces B and D, and in a second orientation, flipped over relative to the first orientation, the second passages are open to fluid flow and the first passages are closed by engagement of the inner and outer walls with the faces A and C.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="171.20mm" wi="102.45mm" file="US08624149-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="203.54mm" wi="135.21mm" file="US08624149-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="197.95mm" wi="168.83mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624149-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="168.83mm" wi="156.80mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624149-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="205.57mm" wi="185.93mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624149-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="255.27mm" wi="183.39mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624149-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="251.88mm" wi="148.93mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624149-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present application relates to plasma arc torches.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Plasma torches are commonly used for cutting, welding, or marking metal work pieces. In general, plasma torches employ an electrode to generate an electric arc within the torch. A high-velocity gas is flowed through the torch, and the electric arc ionizes the gas, creating a plasma. The high-velocity stream of ionized gas, or plasma, is delivered through a nozzle of the torch towards the work piece that is to be operated upon. The plasma serves to conduct electricity from the torch to the work piece. In this way, the plasma heats the work piece, melting the metal in the desired location.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Baffles are commonly used in plasma arc torches to control the flow of gasses or liquids. Baffles can be used, for example, to throttle the flow and/or to impart swirl to the flow. Swirl-inducing baffles are generally referred to as swirl baffles, or alternatively as diffusers.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A common type of swirl baffle is an annular ring having flow passages extending between the radially inner and outer surfaces of the ring. The passages extend non-radially, i.e., with a tangential component of direction, so that swirl is imparted to the fluid flowing through the passages. Some swirl baffles of this type have a configuration that allows them to be inadvertently installed upside down relative to the proper orientation. When the swirl baffle is incorrectly installed upside down, the swirl direction imparted by the baffle is the opposite of the intended direction. This can cause problems in some cases, such as when a downstream component's design is such that it works properly only when it receives swirl of a particular sense.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Embodiments of the present invention described herein address the above-noted issue, and some embodiments provide additional/different functionalities that can be advantageous in plasma arc torches and processes.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In one exemplary embodiment, a plasma arc torch is described, comprising a main torch body, an electrode, and a nozzle, a generally annular fluid flow passage being defined within the torch between a radially inner wall and a radially outer wall for flow of a fluid therethrough. The torch further comprises a generally annular baffle disposed in the generally annular fluid flow passage and engaging the radially inner and radially outer walls thereof. The baffle defines distinct faces A, B, C, and D, a set of first passages extending between the faces A and C, and a set of second passages extending between the faces B and D.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The faces of the baffle and the radially inner and outer walls of the annular fluid flow passage are configured to cooperate such that in a first orientation of the baffle the first passages are open to fluid flow and the second passages are closed to fluid flow by engagement of the radially inner and outer walls with the faces B and D. In a second orientation of the baffle, flipped over relative to the first orientation, the second passages are open to fluid flow and the first passages are closed to fluid flow by engagement of the radially inner and outer walls with the faces A and C.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The annular flow passage and baffle as described above can be configured in any of various ways to achieve various objectives. For example, in one embodiment, the first passages are configured to provide a first flow characteristic to the fluid flowing therethrough, and the second passages are configured to provide a second flow characteristic to the fluid flowing therethrough, the first and second flow characteristics differing from each other. The flow characteristic can be, for example, flow rate. Thus, when the baffle is installed in the first orientation, a first flow rate can be imparted by the baffle. When the baffle is flipped over and installed in the second orientation, the baffle can impart a second flow rate that is higher or lower than the first flow rate.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Alternatively the flow characteristic can be swirl magnitude and/or swirl direction. Thus, in another embodiment, the first passages are configured to impart swirl of a first magnitude and a first direction to the fluid flowing therethrough, and the second passages are configured to impart swirl of a second magnitude and a second direction to the fluid flowing therethrough. Various baffle configurations are possible. As one example, the baffle passages can be configured such that the first and second directions of the swirl are the same. That is, with the baffle installed in either of its two possible orientations (right side up or upside down), the resulting swirl direction is the same. The first and second magnitudes of the swirl can also be the same, such that the baffle is completely reversible without affecting performance in any way. In this manner, it is impossible to inadvertently install the baffle in a way that will adversely affect the torch operation.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Alternatively, it is possible to configure the passages so that the swirl is greater in one orientation than in the other, which may be useful in cases where it is desirable to use the same torch for different processes having different optimum swirl levels.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The baffle can be configured in various other ways. For example, each of the first passages can comprise a surface groove extending between the faces A and C, and each of the second passages can comprise a surface groove extending between the faces B and D.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Alternatively, each of the first passages can comprise a hole extending between the faces A and C, and each of the second passages can comprise a hole extending between the faces B and D.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In some embodiments, each of the faces A, B, C, and D of the baffle can be substantially conical, and the radially inner and outer walls of the generally annular fluid flow passage can define substantially conical surfaces, the substantially conical faces of the baffle engaging the substantially conical surfaces of the walls so as to radially center the baffle with respect to the walls. This can also serve to radially locate other components. For example, the inner wall of the annular fluid flow passage can be part of an inner component (e.g., a primary nozzle) and the outer wall can be part of an outer component (e.g., a secondary or shield nozzle) that surrounds the inner component. The conical surfaces of these components and the baffle can serve to radially center all of them with respect to one another.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The radial centering of the baffle relative to the torch components defining the generally annular fluid flow passage has utility more generally with any baffle, including those that do not have two sets of passages. In accordance with one embodiment of the invention, a plasma arc torch comprises a main torch body, an electrode, and a nozzle, a generally annular fluid flow passage being defined between a radially inner wall and a radially outer wall for flow of a fluid therethrough, the torch further comprising a generally annular baffle disposed in the generally annular fluid flow passage and engaging the radially inner and radially outer walls thereof, the baffle defining flow passages therethrough, and wherein each of the radially inner and outer walls of the generally annular fluid flow passage defines a substantially conical surface, and the baffle defines an inner conical surface and an outer conical surface, the inner and outer conical surfaces of the baffle respectively engaging the substantially conical surfaces of the inner and outer walls of the generally annular fluid flow passage so as to radially center the baffle with respect to the walls.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Additional embodiments of the invention and/or advantages achievable thereby are described herein or would be obvious to persons of ordinary skill in the art.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWING(S)</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Having thus described the invention in general terms, reference will now be made to the accompanying drawings, which are not necessarily drawn to scale, and wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a cross-sectional view of a plasma arc torch in accordance with one embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> is an enlarged portion of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view of a baffle used in the torch of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a top view of the baffle;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a side view of the baffle;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a bottom view of the baffle;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a top view of a baffle in accordance with another embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a side view of the baffle of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a bottom view of the baffle of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Embodiments of the present invention now will be described more fully hereinafter with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which some but not all embodiments are shown. Indeed, the invention may be embodied in many different forms and should not be construed as limited to the embodiments set forth herein; rather, these embodiments are provided so that this disclosure will satisfy applicable legal requirements. Like reference numerals refer to like elements throughout.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">A plasma torch <b>10</b> in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The torch includes a main torch body <b>12</b> having a central bore <b>14</b> through which an electrode assembly <b>16</b> extends. The electrode assembly <b>16</b> comprises an electrode holder <b>18</b> having an outer tubular member <b>18</b><i>a </i>and an inner tubular member <b>18</b><i>b </i>between which an annular space <b>19</b> is defined. The inner tubular member <b>18</b><i>b </i>comprises a coolant tube whose upper end is externally threaded for engaging internal threads in the outer tubular member <b>18</b><i>a</i>. The lower end of the coolant tube <b>18</b><i>b </i>is internally threaded for receiving an externally threaded nipple of an electrode <b>20</b>. The electrode <b>20</b> has a front face in which an emissive element <b>22</b> is embedded. The emissive element <b>22</b> is operable to emit an electric arc when a voltage potential difference is created between the electrode <b>20</b> and another member to which the arc extends. Coolant supplied into the coolant tube <b>18</b><i>b </i>circulates around the back (interior) side of the electrode <b>20</b> to cool the electrode.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The torch <b>10</b> further includes a primary nozzle <b>24</b> that surrounds the electrode <b>20</b> and is electrically isolated from the electrode. An annular gas flow passage <b>26</b> is defined between the nozzle <b>24</b> and the electrode <b>20</b>. Gas is fed to the passage <b>26</b> via a gas supply passage <b>28</b> defined in the torch. The nozzle <b>24</b> defines an orifice <b>30</b> through which the gas is discharged toward a workpiece. A swirl baffle <b>32</b> disposed between the nozzle <b>24</b> and the electrode assembly <b>16</b> imparts swirl to the gas flowing from the passage <b>28</b> into the passage <b>26</b>, so that the gas discharged from the nozzle orifice <b>30</b> is a swirling jet that surrounds the electric arc emitted from the emissive element <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">A secondary nozzle, or shield, <b>40</b> surrounds the primary nozzle <b>24</b> and there is an annular fluid flow passage <b>42</b> between them. The shield <b>40</b> defines an orifice <b>44</b> for discharge of shield fluid toward the workpiece. A secondary or shield fluid is supplied to the passage <b>42</b> from a shield fluid supply passage <b>46</b> defined in the torch. The shield fluid can be a gas or can be a liquid such as water, depending on the intended application of the torch.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">A baffle <b>50</b> is disposed in the annular passage <b>42</b> between the nozzle <b>24</b> and the shield <b>40</b>. The baffle <b>50</b> is generally annular and defines passages for flow of the shield fluid. With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A</figref>, <b>2</b>, <b>3</b>, <b>4</b>, and <b>5</b>, the baffle <b>50</b> includes four distinct faces A, B, C, and D, each of which is substantially conical in the illustrated embodiment. The faces A and C lie opposite each other, and the faces B and D lie opposite each other. Faces A and D face generally radially inwardly, and faces B and D face generally radially outwardly.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The nozzle <b>24</b> defines a substantially conical wall <b>25</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>) and the shield <b>40</b> defines a substantially conical wall <b>41</b> opposite from the wall <b>25</b>. The nozzle wall <b>25</b> is configured to lie flat against the face A of the baffle, and the shield wall <b>41</b> is configured to lie flat against the face C of the baffle. Additionally, the baffle is configured to be reversible in orientation (i.e., flipped over relative to the orientation shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>). In the flipped-over orientation, the nozzle wall <b>25</b> lies flat against the face D and the shield wall <b>41</b> lies flat against the face C.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 through 5</figref>, the baffle <b>50</b> defines a set of first passages <b>52</b> that extend between the faces A and C, and a set of second passages <b>54</b> that extend between the faces B and D. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-5</figref>, the first passages <b>52</b> comprise surface grooves formed in the face B and of sufficient depth to extend partially into the faces A and C. Similarly, the second passages <b>54</b> comprise surface grooves formed in the face C and of sufficient depth to extend partially into the faces B and D.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">When the baffle <b>50</b> in installed in the orientation shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>, the nozzle wall <b>25</b> and shield wall <b>41</b> close off the first passages <b>52</b>, but the second passages <b>54</b> are open for fluid flow. If the baffle is flipped over to its opposite orientation, then the walls <b>25</b> and <b>41</b> close off the second passages <b>54</b>, but the first passages <b>52</b> are open for fluid flow.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">This reversibility of the baffle <b>50</b> can be employed for various effects or advantages. One such advantage, possessed by the illustrated baffle <b>50</b>, is the ability to install the baffle in either of its two possible orientations without changing the manner in which the baffle affects the flow of fluid through it. That is, the baffle is &#x201c;fool-proof&#x201d; such that it cannot be inadvertently installed in the &#x201c;wrong&#x201d; orientation. In this regard, the baffle <b>50</b> is illustrated as being configured to impart swirl to the fluid passing through the passages that are active. The passages <b>52</b> and the passages <b>54</b> are configured to be identical in size and orientation when either one set or the other is the active set. Thus, in the first orientation as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>, the second passages <b>54</b> are active and impart swirl of a predetermined direction and magnitude (where &#x201c;direction&#x201d; is either clockwise or counterclockwise, and &#x201c;magnitude&#x201d; is the absolute value of the swirl angle with respect to axial). In the second orientation (flipped over relative to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>), the first passages <b>52</b> are active and impart the very same direction and magnitude of swirl.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">With respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 through 8</figref>, a baffle <b>150</b> in accordance with another embodiment is illustrated. The baffle <b>150</b> is similar in overall configuration to the previously described baffle, and thus has distinct faces A, B, C, and D arranged as in the prior embodiment. In this embodiment, however, the first passages <b>152</b> are holes rather than surface grooves, and they extend between the faces A and C. Likewise, the second passages <b>154</b> are holes rather than surface grooves, and they extend between the faces B and D. A further difference relative to the prior embodiment is that the first passages <b>152</b> and the second passages <b>154</b> are not configured to produce identical flow results. Instead, the first passages <b>152</b> are of smaller cross-sectional flow area than the second passages <b>154</b>. The advantage of this configuration is that the baffle <b>150</b> allows the user to adjust the level of shield fluid delivered through the shield orifice <b>44</b>. If in a particular process a relatively low shield fluid flow rate is desired, the baffle can be installed in the orientation in which the first (smaller) passages <b>152</b> are the active ones. If in another process a higher shield fluid flow rate is desired, then the baffle can be flipped over so the second (larger) passages <b>154</b> are the active ones.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">It will also be clear from the foregoing that the two sets of passages can be configured to vary other fluid flow characteristics instead of or in addition to the flow rate. For example, the passages may be configured so that in the first orientation the baffle provides swirl at a relatively low swirl angle, and in the second orientation the baffle provides swirl at a relatively higher swirl angle.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">While the baffles <b>50</b> and <b>150</b> illustrated herein are configured to produce swirl, it will be recognized that the invention is applicable to other situations where swirl may not be required or desired. Thus, the passages in the baffle can be oriented to produce flow without swirl. In this case, the baffle can be &#x201c;fool-proof&#x201d; as previously described, such that both sets of passages produce identical flow results. Alternatively, the baffle can have differently configured sets of passages so as to provide a flow-adjusting function depending on its orientation.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Many modifications and other embodiments of the invention set forth herein will come to mind to one skilled in the art to which this invention pertains having the benefit of the teachings presented in the foregoing descriptions and the associated drawings. For example, while the illustrated and described baffles <b>50</b>, <b>150</b> have four conical faces A, B, C, and D, baffles in accordance with the invention can have one or more faces that are not conical (e.g., cylindrical). Therefore, it is to be understood that the invention is not to be limited to the specific embodiments disclosed and that modifications and other embodiments are intended to be included within the scope of the appended claims. Although specific terms are employed herein, they are used in a generic and descriptive sense only and not for purposes of limitation.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A plasma arc torch comprising a main torch body, an electrode, and a nozzle, a generally annular fluid flow passage being defined between a radially inner wall and a radially outer wall for flow of a fluid therethrough, the torch further comprising a generally annular baffle disposed in the generally annular fluid flow passage and engaging the radially inner and radially outer walls thereof, wherein:
<claim-text>the baffle defines distinct faces A, B, C, and D, the faces A and C being generally opposite from each other and the faces B and D being generally opposite from each other, a set of first passages extending between the faces A and C, and a set of second passages extending between the faces B and D, and the faces of the baffle and the radially inner and outer walls of the annular fluid flow passage being configured to cooperate such that:</claim-text>
<claim-text>in a first orientation of the baffle the first passages are open to fluid flow and the second passages are closed to fluid flow by engagement of the radially inner and outer walls with the faces B and D, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>in a second orientation of the baffle, flipped over relative to the first orientation, the second passages are open to fluid flow and the first passages are closed to fluid flow by engagement of the radially inner and outer walls with the faces A and C.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The plasma arc torch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of the first passages comprises a hole extending between the faces A and C, and each of the second passages comprises a hole extending between the faces B and D.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The plasma arc torch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of the first passages comprises a surface groove extending between the faces A and C, and each of the second passages comprises a surface groove extending between the faces B and D.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The plasma arc torch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first passages are configured to provide a first flow characteristic to the fluid flowing therethrough, and the second passages are configured to provide a second flow characteristic to the fluid flowing therethrough, the first and second flow characteristics differing from each other.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The plasma arc torch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first passages are configured to impart swirl of a first magnitude and a first direction to the fluid flowing therethrough, and the second passages are configured to impart swirl of a second magnitude and a second direction to the fluid flowing therethrough.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The plasma arc torch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second directions of the swirl are the same.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The plasma arc torch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second magnitudes of the swirl are the same.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The plasma arc torch of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of the faces A, B, C, and D of the baffle is substantially conical, and the radially inner and outer walls of the generally annular fluid flow passage define substantially conical surfaces, the substantially conical faces of the baffle engaging the substantially conical surfaces of the walls so as to radially center the baffle with respect to the walls.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A baffle for a plasma arc torch, the baffle being generally annular and defining distinct faces A, B, C, and D, wherein faces A and C are generally opposite from each other and faces B and D are generally opposite from each other, the baffle defining a set of first passages extending between faces A and C and a set of second passages extending between faces B and D.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The baffle of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein each of the first passages comprises a hole extending between the faces A and C, and each of the second passages comprises a hole extending between the faces B and D.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The baffle of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein each of the first passages comprises a surface groove extending between the faces A and C, and each of the second passages comprises a surface groove extending between the faces B and D.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The baffle of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the first passages are configured to provide a first flow characteristic to a fluid flowing therethrough, and the second passages are configured to provide a second flow characteristic to a fluid flowing therethrough, the first and second flow characteristics differing from each other.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The baffle of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the first passages are configured to impart swirl of a first magnitude and a first direction to a fluid flowing therethrough, and the second passages are configured to impart swirl of a second magnitude and a second direction to a fluid flowing therethrough.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The baffle of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second directions of the swirl are the same.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The baffle of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second magnitudes of the swirl are the same.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The baffle of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein each of the faces A, B, C, and D of the baffle is substantially conical.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. A plasma arc torch comprising a main torch body, an electrode, and a nozzle, a generally annular fluid flow passage being defined between a radially inner wall and a radially outer wall for flow of a fluid therethrough, the torch further comprising a generally annular baffle disposed in the generally annular fluid flow passage and engaging the radially inner and radially outer walls thereof, the baffle defining flow passages therethrough, and wherein:
<claim-text>each of the radially inner and outer walls of the generally annular fluid flow passage defines a substantially conical surface, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the baffle defines an inner conical surface and an outer conical surface, the inner and outer conical surfaces of the baffle respectively engaging the substantially conical surfaces of the inner and outer walls of the generally annular fluid flow passage so as to radially center the baffle with respect to the walls. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
