<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622342-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622342</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13162931</doc-number>
<date>20110617</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>311</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>64</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>41</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>244 58</main-classification>
<further-classification>244 55</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">On-board aircraft auxiliary power systems having dual auxiliary power units</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2777301</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kuhn</name>
<date>19570100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4077202</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Schutze</name>
<date>19780300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4759178</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Joy</name>
<date>19880700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5480107</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Bacon</name>
<date>19960100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>244 55</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5855340</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Bacon</name>
<date>19990100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>244 53 R</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6247668</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Reysa et al.</name>
<date>20010600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>244 58</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6450447</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Konrad et al.</name>
<date>20020900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8286435</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Rensch</name>
<date>20121000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 60802</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0146344</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Saito et al.</name>
<date>20030800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>244 55</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0054739</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Perez et al.</name>
<date>20060300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>244 55</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>13</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>244 53 R</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>244 54</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>244 55</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>244 58</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>244 53 B</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60280</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120318913</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121220</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Filho</last-name>
<first-name>Aldemiro Lorenzini</first-name>
<address>
<city>S&#xe3;o Jos&#xe9; dos Campos</city>
<country>BR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>BR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Filho</last-name>
<first-name>Aldemiro Lorenzini</first-name>
<address>
<city>S&#xe3;o Jos&#xe9; dos Campos</city>
<country>BR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Nixon &#x26; Vanderhye P.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Embraer S.A.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>S&#xe3;o Jos&#xe9; dos Campos</city>
<country>BR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Collins</last-name>
<first-name>Timothy D</first-name>
<department>3644</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Stehle</last-name>
<first-name>Jamie S</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Aircraft are provided with a pair of auxiliary power units (APUs) adjacently mounted in parallel relative to one another within the tail cone section of the aircraft's fuselage. In some embodiments, the APUs are mounted generally vertically adjacent to one another. Alternatively, the APUs may be mounted generally horizontally adjacent to one another. The aircraft fuselage may include a pair of downwardly and outwardly oriented strakes adjacent the tail cone having lower edges which establish a maximum take-off pitch angle of the fuselage and define a spatial zone therebetween. The APUs are positioned within such a spatial zone defined between the strakes so that the maximum take-off pitch angle is not required to be changed when modifying an existing single APU aircraft with dual APUs.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="163.58mm" wi="261.70mm" file="US08622342-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="261.62mm" wi="164.85mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622342-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="215.90mm" wi="162.31mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622342-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="215.90mm" wi="178.31mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622342-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="215.90mm" wi="145.63mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622342-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The disclosed embodiments herein relate to on-board auxiliary power systems for aircraft in which dual auxiliary power units (APUs) are provided in a tail cone of the aircraft and operate in parallel so as to provide enhanced on-board electrical and/or pneumatic power.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Existing aircraft typically include two or more primary engines for propulsion. These aircraft also typically include at least one APU that provides electrical and/or pneumatic power in addition to or in lieu of the power provided by the primary engines. Accordingly, APUs can be used to provide power to the aircraft when the primary engines are not running, for example, when the aircraft is on the ground at an airport gate. The APUs can also provide temporary power to start the primary engines during normal operations, and/or temporary emergency power during an engine-out condition or other emergency condition during flight operations. Additionally, the APU can be used during flight to provide additional electrical and/or pneumatic power whenever the aircraft systems require an amount that exceeds the electrical and/or pneumatic power capability of the primary propulsion engines.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">There are certain instances when an existing certificated aircraft undergoes a design change so as to adapt the airframe to an entirely different purpose for which it was originally intended. For example, a civil transport aircraft may be subsequently adapted to perform military or police surveillance missions. Such aircraft modifications to a baseline aircraft are colloquially termed &#x201c;derivative aircraft&#x201d;. A derivative aircraft is thus often accompanied by a need to provide a substantial increase to the electrical power requirements due to the on-board presence of additional electrical and/or electronic equipment (e.g., on-board surveillance cameras, specialized radar, computers and associated equipment) carried by the aircraft to perform the missions for which it is designed. This increased electrical power requirement is often greater than the maximum electrical output for which the original APU was designed. The traditional solution to additional electrical power requirements is to replace the original APU with a larger APU having a correspondingly greater electrical power output capacity. However, such a larger APU will in turn usually require airframe space that is not readily available in the baseline (unmodified) aircraft, thereby requiring a major structural design change or even relocating the APU to another area within the airframe.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">It would therefore be especially desirable to provide a solution to the problems described above whereby increased electrical power output could be provided to accommodate an increased power requirement of a baseline aircraft without the need to relocate and/or replace the existing APU. It is towards fulfilling such needs that the present invention is directed.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF EXEMPLARY EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The present invention proposes the installation of two APUs in parallel in the aircraft tail cone to meet the increased electrical power demanded by equipment in a derivative aircraft. In preferred embodiments, the aircraft auxiliary power system is provided with dual APUs installed in parallel within the tail cone of the derivative aircraft with minimal impact on the original airframe design. In such a manner, the arrangement of the dual APUs can be accommodated within the tail cone of the derivative aircraft without substantial airframe modification of the baseline aircraft (e.g., without the need to modify the angle of takeoff in order to prevent tail strikes). As such, the necessary modifications in order to accommodate the dual APUs within the tail cone of the derivative aircraft can be achieved with minimal aerodynamic impact.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Therefore, according to preferred embodiments of the invention, an aircraft is provided which comprises a fuselage with a tail cone section, and a pair of auxiliary power units (APUs) adjacently mounted in parallel relative to one another within the tail cone section. In some embodiments, the APUs are mounted generally vertically adjacent to one another. A lower one of the APUs may thus be positioned forwardly of an upper one of the APUs.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">According to other embodiments, the aircraft will comprise an upwardly aft-angled bulkhead support ring, and support arms interconnecting the upper one of the APUs to the support ring. To support the second APU a support plate may be provided so as to rigidly connect a lower portion of the support ring such that a forward end of the support plate is connected to the lower portion of the support ring. Certain embodiments will include a support plate having upwardly and rearwardly directed support arms attached to the lower one of the APUs. The support arms may have a forward end attached to the rearward frame member of the aircraft and a rearward end attached to the lower one of the APUs. A rearward frame member may extend downwardly and forwardly from a lower region of the support ring.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Certain embodiments may be provided with a firewall plate positioned between the APUs. The firewall plate may be in the form of a generally U-shaped plate structure having downwardly directed lateral edge regions. An upper frame member may be attached generally at a center of the firewall plate.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In some preferred embodiments, the aircraft fuselage will include a pair of downwardly and outwardly oriented strakes adjacent the tail cone having lower edges which establish a maximum take-off pitch angle of the fuselage. The strakes will thus define a spatial zone therebetween. The APUs are positioned within such a spatial zone defined between the strakes.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The structure of the strakes may be provided by a series of inverted U-shaped strake frame members positioned about a lower one of the APUs. Horizontal strake frame members may also be provided and attached to the inverted U-shaped strake frame members.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to other embodiments, an aircraft is provided wherein the dual parallel APUs are mounted generally horizontally adjacent to one another.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">These and other aspects and advantages of the present invention will become more clear after careful consideration is given to the following detailed description of the preferred exemplary embodiments thereof.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF ACCOMPANYING DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The disclosed embodiments of the present invention will be better and more completely understood by referring to the following detailed description of exemplary non-limiting illustrative embodiments in conjunction with the drawings of which:</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> depicts a schematically a rear perspective view of an exemplary derivative aircraft which embodies a dual parallel APU arrangement in accordance with one aspect of this invention;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is detailed side elevation view of the tail cone region of the aircraft depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> having the aircraft skin partly removed for visual ease;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is rear perspective view of the parallel APU arrangement depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> and its associated airframe support structure; and</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> depicts schematically a rear perspective view of another exemplary derivative aircraft which embodies a dual parallel APU arrangement in accordance with another aspect of this invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Accompanying <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> depicts a rear perspective view of a derivative aircraft DA which is provided with an auxiliary power system <b>10</b> in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention. The derivative aircraft DA is depicted as including an elongate fuselage <b>12</b> terminating in a tail cone <b>12</b>-<b>1</b> in which the dual auxiliary power units (APUs) <b>14</b>, <b>16</b> are positioned in a vertically oriented side-by-side arrangement.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">As is conventional, the aircraft DA includes vertical horizontal stabilizers <b>17</b><i>a</i>, <b>17</b><i>b</i>, respectively. A pair of propulsion engines <b>18</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>18</b>-<b>2</b> are mounted laterally near the tail cone <b>12</b>-<b>1</b> on port and starboard sides of the fuselage. It is to be understood, that the depiction of the propulsion engines <b>18</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>18</b>-<b>2</b> near the tail cone <b>12</b>-<b>1</b> is exemplary only and thus the present invention may be embodiment in other aircraft configurations, e.g., where the propulsion engines are mounted under the port and starboard wings.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The derivative aircraft DA is also depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> as including port and starboard strakes <b>20</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>20</b>-<b>2</b>, respectively, oriented at the rear of the fuselage <b>12</b> adjacent to and laterally extending outwardly from the tail cone <b>12</b>-<b>1</b>. As is known, the strakes <b>20</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>20</b>-<b>2</b> are provided so as to enhance aerodynamic stability. The positioning of the strakes <b>20</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>20</b>-<b>2</b> near the tail cone <b>12</b>-<b>1</b> however also establishes the maximum rotation angle of the aircraft during take-off. That is, in order to prevent a tail-strike during take-off (which in the embodiment shown would be contact between the takeoff runway and the lowermost edges <b>20</b>-<b>1</b><i>a</i>, <b>20</b>-<b>2</b><i>a </i>of the strakes <b>20</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>20</b>-<b>2</b>, respectively), the pitch (rotation) angle of the fuselage is limited by pilot input to the pitch-axis control surfaces of the aircraft DA to a maximum allowable angle of attack (AOA) until the aircraft is airborne and vertically separated from the runway surface by sufficient altitude.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The APUs <b>14</b>, <b>16</b> are in and of themselves highly conventional JP-fueled turbine engines that turn a shaft associated with a generator and a compressor (not shown). The generator in turn generates electrical power while the compressor may be employed for other on-board systems (e.g., powering the aircraft's on-board hydraulics, air conditioning and the like). Most preferably, the APUs are connected to the fuel supply (typically in-wing mounted fuel cells) for the main propulsion engines <b>18</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>18</b>-<b>2</b>. When in use, the exhaust from the combustion of the fuel by the APUs is vented to ambient atmosphere by the exhaust opening <b>12</b>-<b>1</b><i>a </i>in the tail cone <b>12</b>-<b>1</b>. By way of background, the APUs <b>14</b>, <b>16</b> may embody the operational principles disclosed by U.S. Pat. Nos. 2,777,301; 4,077,202; 4,759,178 and 6,450,447, the entire content of each being expressly incorporated hereinto by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Accompanying <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref> depict in greater detail the manner in which the APUs <b>14</b>, <b>16</b> are accommodated within the tail cone <b>12</b>-<b>1</b> of the aircraft DA. Specifically, the position of the APU <b>14</b> within the aircraft DA remains unchanged as compared to its position in the unmodified baseline aircraft. That is, the APU <b>14</b> is physically attached to and supported by an upwardly aft-angled bulkhead support ring <b>22</b> by means of support arms <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>. A lower support bracket <b>28</b> is attached to the support ring <b>22</b> and includes upwardly and rearwardly directed support arms <b>30</b> attached to the APU <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In order to accommodate the mounting of the second APU <b>16</b>, a support plate <b>32</b> is attached to a lower portion of the support ring <b>22</b> and extends downwardly and rearwardly (relative to the aircraft fuselage <b>12</b>) to a lowermost extent defined by the lower edges <b>20</b>-<b>1</b><i>a</i>, <b>20</b>-<b>2</b><i>a </i>of the strakes <b>20</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>20</b>-<b>2</b>. The support plate <b>32</b> includes upwardly and rearwardly directed support arms <b>36</b> attached to the APU <b>16</b>. The downwardly and rearwardly directed support arm <b>42</b> has its forward end attached to the upper portion of the forward most frame <b>44</b> and the rearward end attached to the APU <b>16</b>. The forward most frame <b>44</b> extends downwardly and forwardly from the lower region of the support ring <b>22</b> and to the lowermost extent defined by the lower edges <b>20</b>-<b>1</b><i>a</i>, <b>20</b>-<b>2</b><i>a </i>of the strakes <b>20</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>20</b>-<b>2</b>, respectively. A pair of forward support brackets <b>34</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>34</b>-<b>2</b> are connected in series to a forward surface of the support plate <b>32</b>, the latter also being rigidly connected to the support ring <b>22</b>. The forward most support bracket <b>34</b>-<b>2</b> is connected to and carries a downwardly and rearwardly oriented support arm <b>38</b> having a terminal end fixed to a lower extent of the support plate <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">As can be seen from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, therefore, the various support structures are entirely contained within a spatial zone <b>40</b> defined between the strakes <b>20</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>20</b>-<b>2</b> and do not protrude downwardly beyond the plane defined by the lower edges <b>20</b>-<b>1</b><i>a</i>, <b>20</b>-<b>2</b><i>a </i>of the strakes <b>20</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>20</b>-<b>2</b>. Since the APUs are contained entirely within this spatial zone <b>40</b>, the maximum pitch angle to prevent a tail strike during take-off that had been established during certification of the baseline aircraft remains unchanged. As such, the modification of the baseline aircraft to include the dual APUs <b>14</b>, <b>16</b> in accordance with the present invention does not require modification of the derivative aircraft DA performance criteria.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a fire wall plate <b>46</b> is positioned between APUs <b>14</b> and <b>16</b>. The fire wall plate <b>46</b> is preferably in the form of an inverted U-shaped plate having downwardly directed lateral edge regions. A plurality of inverted U-shaped strake frame members <b>48</b>-<b>1</b> to <b>48</b>-<b>4</b> are positioned on and connected to the fire wall plate <b>46</b>. These inverted U-shaped strake frame members <b>48</b>-<b>1</b> to <b>48</b>-<b>4</b> form part of the structure of the strakes <b>20</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>20</b>-<b>2</b>. The upper frame <b>50</b> is positioned generally at the center of the fire wall plate <b>46</b> and is connected rigidly to the U-shaped strake frame members <b>48</b>-<b>1</b> to <b>48</b>-<b>4</b>. The structure of the strakes <b>20</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>20</b>-<b>2</b> also comprises horizontal strake frame members <b>52</b>-<b>1</b> to <b>52</b>-<b>4</b> which are rigidly connected substantially perpendicular to the inverted U-shaped strake frame members <b>48</b>-<b>1</b> to <b>48</b>-<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">An alternative embodiment of an auxiliary power system <b>10</b>&#x2032; having dual parallel APUs <b>14</b>&#x2032;, <b>16</b>&#x2032; is shown schematically in accompanying <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. As can be seen, unlike the embodiment described previously with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref> wherein the APUs <b>14</b>, <b>16</b> are oriented vertically adjacent in a side-by-side relationship to one another with the lower APU being positioned forwardly of the upper APU <b>16</b> due to the angular positioning of the support ring <b>22</b> and other support structures as described previously, the APUs <b>14</b>&#x2032;, <b>16</b>&#x2032; in the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> has both APUs adjacent to one another in a side-by-side relationship within a common horizontal plane. In the embodiment depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, relocation to the starboard side of the aircraft's centerline would be required for the original APU <b>14</b> supplied with the baseline aircraft so as to provide sufficient lateral space of the port side of the aircraft to accommodate the additional APU <b>16</b> in side-by-side relationship. A similar cantilevered mounting and support arrangement as with the original APU <b>14</b> could likewise be provided with the additional APU <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">While the invention has been described in connection with what is presently considered to be the most practical and preferred embodiment, it is to be understood that the invention is not to be limited to the disclosed embodiment, but on the contrary, is intended to cover various modifications and equivalent arrangements included within the spirit and scope thereof.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An aircraft comprising:
<claim-text>a fuselage with a tail cone section,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of auxiliary power units (APUs) mounted in a parallel generally vertically adjacent manner relative to one another within the tail cone section such that a lower one of the APUs is positioned forwardly of an upper one of the APUs,</claim-text>
<claim-text>an upwardly aft-angled bulkhead support ring, and support arms interconnecting the upper one of the APUs to the support ring, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a support plate rigidly connected to a lower portion of the support ring such that a forward end of the support plate is connected to a lower portion of the support ring.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. An aircraft as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the support plate includes upwardly and rearwardly directed support arms attached to the lower one of the APUs.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. An aircraft as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, further comprising a rearward frame member extending downwardly and forwardly from a lower region of the support ring.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. An aircraft as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the support arms have a forward end attached to the rearward frame member of the aircraft and a rearward end attached to the lower one of the APUs.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. An aircraft as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a firewall plate positioned between the APUs.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. An aircraft as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the firewall plate is an inverted U-shaped plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. An aircraft as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, further comprising an upper frame member attached generally at a center of the firewall plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. An aircraft as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a series of inverted U-shaped strake frame members positioned about a lower one of the APUs.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. An aircraft comprising:
<claim-text>a fuselage with a tail cone section,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of auxiliary power units (APUs) mounted in a parallel generally vertically adjacent manner relative to one another within the tail cone section</claim-text>
<claim-text>a series of inverted U-shaped strake frame members positioned about a lower one of the APUs, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>horizontal strake frame members attached to the inverted U-shaped strake frame members.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. An aircraft as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further comprising a firewall plate positioned between the APUs.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. An aircraft as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the firewall plate is an inverted U-shaped plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. An aircraft as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising an upper frame member attached generally at a center of the firewall plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. An aircraft as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the fuselage includes a pair of downwardly and outwardly oriented strakes adjacent the tail cone having lower edges which establish a maximum take-off pitch angle of the fuselage, wherein the strakes define a spatial zone therebetween, and wherein the APUs are positioned within the spatial zone defined between the strakes. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
