<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622288-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622288</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12737934</doc-number>
<date>20080903</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>2</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20120101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>Q</subclass>
<main-group>40</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>235379</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Money handling system</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6230928</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Hanna et al.</name>
<date>20010500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7954699</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Sanders et al.</name>
<date>20110600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>235379</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2002/0153414</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Stoutenburg et al.</name>
<date>20021000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>235380</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0083969</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Uchiyama et al.</name>
<date>20030500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>705 35</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0117061</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Angove et al.</name>
<date>20040600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0101723</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Uehara et al.</name>
<date>20090400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>235  7 A</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2003-263682</doc-number>
<date>20030900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
<classification-cpc-text>G07G 1/12</classification-cpc-text>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00008">
<othercit>European Search Report (Application No. 08809944.5&#x2014;PCT/JP2008/065889) (5 pages&#x2014;dated Aug. 11, 2012).</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>8</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>235379</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>235383</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>235381</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>12</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110153059</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110623</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Matsumoto</last-name>
<first-name>Yasuhiro</first-name>
<address>
<city>Himeji</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Matsumoto</last-name>
<first-name>Yasuhiro</first-name>
<address>
<city>Himeji</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Renner, Kenner, Grieve, Bobak, Taylor &#x26; Weber</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Glory Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Himeji-Shi, Hyogo-Ken</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Ahshik</first-name>
<department>2876</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/JP2008/065889</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20080903</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20110302</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2010/026631</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20100311</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A money handling system includes a money handling machine that has a money storage unit for storing money, and a money recycling unit for temporarily storing money taken from the exterior of the money handling machine after the money is recognized. The money recycling unit is adapted to feed the money temporarily stored therein to the money storage unit and/or to dispense the temporarily stored money to the exterior of the money handling machine. A wrapped-coin dispensing unit for storing wrapped coins and for dispensing the wrapped coins to the exterior of the money handling machine is also provided. Finally, a central control unit communicates with various components of the money handing machine, while being isolated therefrom.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="117.26mm" wi="151.81mm" file="US08622288-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="229.95mm" wi="174.58mm" file="US08622288-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="227.16mm" wi="160.95mm" file="US08622288-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="248.67mm" wi="188.81mm" file="US08622288-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="237.83mm" wi="175.85mm" file="US08622288-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="157.90mm" wi="185.50mm" file="US08622288-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="253.07mm" wi="181.02mm" file="US08622288-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="226.31mm" wi="152.57mm" file="US08622288-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This invention relates to a money handling system adapted for temporarily storing money, which is taken from the exterior to the interior of a casing and includes banknotes, coins and/or the like, in a recycling money storage unit, after recognizing the money, as well as adapted for feeding the money once stored in the recycling money storage unit to a money storage unit and/or dispensing the money to the exterior of the casing. It is noted that the term &#x201c;money&#x201d;, as used herein, may include banknotes and/or coins.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND ART</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">In the past, a money handling machine, which is adapted for depositing the money, such as sales proceeds or the like, in a store or the like, dispensing the money, such as changes or the like, and delivering the money to a designated collector, such as a staff or the like of an armored car company, in charge of collecting the sales proceeds or the like, has been known. This money handling machine includes a money storage unit configured for storing therein the money, and a money recycling unit configured for temporarily storing therein the money taken from the exterior to the interior of the casing of the machine, as well as adapted for feeding the money temporarily stored in this money recycling unit or money taken from the exterior to the interior of the casing, to the money storage unit, or otherwise dispensing such money to the exterior of the casing. In this case, the authority, under which the money stored in the money recycling unit (or money stored in an upper part of the money handling machine) is controlled, is separated from the authority, under which the money stored in the money storage unit (or money stored in a lower part of the money handling machine) is controlled. Namely, the former control authority is provided on the side of the store, which is hence suitable for performing a depositing process and/or dispensing process for the money, relative to the money handling machine, while the latter control authority is provided on the side of the designated collector collecting the banknote from the money handling machine. Therefore, each operation, for depositing, dispensing, delivering or the like, for the money stored in the upper part of the money handling machine, and/or access to deposit/dispense information and/or total amount data, in regard to the money stored in the upper part of the money handling machine, can be performed by only an operator authorized on the side of the store. Meanwhile, the money stored in the lower part of the money handling machine can be collected by only the designated collector.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">JP2003-141609A discloses a money deposit/dispense machine designed for use in the store or the like. Namely, this money deposit/dispense machine is generally installed in the store, and is adapted for depositing therein the sales proceeds of the store, as well as for dispensing therefrom the money, such as changes or the like, prepared for the store (i.e., a fund of the store). More specifically, in this money deposit/dispense machine, the control authority, under which the money to be stored, as the fund of the store, in a recycling storage unit and then dispensed, as the changes or the like, in the store, is controlled, is separated from the control authority, under which the sales proceeds of the store that will be transferred to a financial institution or the like, without being dispensed. In the case of dispensing the money prepared for the store (or fund of the store), the total amount of money to be dispensed is first inputted, and then the money corresponding to the inputted total amount of money is fed out from the recycling storage unit and dispensed from the money deposit/dispense machine. Meanwhile, the money, as the sales proceeds of the store, which is delivered to the armored car company or the like, will be collected by the armored car company. With this collecting process, money transfer data, on the money delivered to the armored car company or the like, is prepared to be sent to the financial institution or the like, by a host computer installed in the armored car company or the like, or by another host computer installed in the store. Thereafter, the money delivered to the armored car company or the like will be deposited in a bank count of the store. Further, money deposit/dispense data or the like, in regard to this money deposit/dispense machine, can be transmitted to the host computer of the armored car company or the like.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DISCLOSURE OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In the money deposit/dispense machine designed for use in the store and described in the above JP2003-141609A, loose banknotes and loose coins can be prepared as the fund of the store. Actually, however, it is also necessary to prepare wrapped coins, as the changes used in the store, in addition to the loose banknotes and loose coins. However, in the conventional money deposit/dispense machine as designed for use in the store, the wrapped coins cannot be prepared, as the changes or the like to be used in the store. Therefore, the operator on the side of the store should send an order to the armored car company or the like for such wrapped coins. For instance, for each day of the week, the operator on the side of the store sends information, by fax, to the armored car company or the like, about each denomination of the wrapped coins required and/or on the number or total amount of such wrapped coins for each denomination. Alternatively or additionally, the operator orders the wrapped coins from the armored car company or the like, based on the past ordering record. Of course, such wrapped coins should not be short of the number thereof, required for the fund of the store. Therefore, such wrapped coins may tend to be often provided, more than actually required, to the store from the armored car company or the like, leading to substantial degradation of the capital efficiency of the store.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The present invention was made in light of such circumstances. Therefore, it is an object of this invention to provide a money handling system, in which a wrapped-coin dispensing unit is provided to a money handling machine installed in the store, such that signal transmission and/or reception can be performed between the wrapped-coin dispensing unit and a central control unit, whereby, in this money handling system, the wrapped coins can be prepared, as the fund of the store, such as the changes or the like, in addition to the loose banknotes and/or loose coins.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The money handling system of the present invention is adapted for depositing and/or dispensing the money, and includes: a money handling machine including a money storage unit configured for storing therein the money, a money recycling unit adapted for temporarily storing the money taken from the exterior to the interior of the money handling machine, in a recycling money storage unit, after the money is recognized, as well as adapted for feeding the money once stored in the recycling money storage unit to the money storage unit and/or dispensing such money to the exterior of the money handling machine, a wrapped-coin dispensing unit adapted for storing wrapped coins, in a wrapped-coin storage unit, as well as adapted for dispensing the wrapped coins stored in the wrapped-coin storage unit to the exterior of the money handling machine, and a control unit adapted for controlling the money storage unit, money recycling unit and wrapped-coin dispensing unit; and a central control unit connected, for communication, with the money handling machine and capable of performing remote control of the money handling machine; and the central control unit is adapted for transmitting and receiving a signal relative to each of the money storage unit and wrapped-coin dispensing unit, in the money handling machine.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In the money handling system of the present invention, it is preferred that the money recycling unit is arranged to be controlled under a first control authority, while the money storage unit and wrapped-coin dispensing unit are respectively arranged to be controlled under a second control authority.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In the money handling system of the present invention, it is preferred that once the money stored in the recycling money storage unit of the money recycling unit is fed to the money storage unit, the control authority, under which such money is controlled, is changed from the first control authority to the second control authority, and then the total amount of money, corresponding to the money fed to the money storage unit, is deposited to an account of a financial institution related to the first control authority, and once the wrapped coins stored in the wrapped-coin storage unit of the wrapped-coin dispensing unit is dispensed to the exterior of the money handling machine, the control authority, under which such wrapped coins are controlled, is changed from the second control authority to the first control authority, and then the total amount of money, corresponding to such wrapped coins, is withdrawn from the account of the financial institution related to the first control authority.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In the money handling system of the present invention, it is preferred that the money handling system further comprises an operation unit adapted for allowing an operator to select a plurality of operation modes including a money exchange mode, and when the money exchange mode is selected via the operation unit, the control unit of the money handling machine serves to control the money storage unit to store therein the money deposited into the money handling machine, and then control the money recycling unit and/or wrapped-coin dispensing unit to dispense the exchange money, and finally transmit information on this money exchange process to the central control unit. Herein, as the exchange money, the wrapped coin and recycled banknote can be mentioned.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Alternatively, the money handling system may further comprise a operation unit adapted for allowing an operator to select a plurality of operation modes including a money exchange mode, when the money exchange mode is selected via the operation unit, the control unit of the money handling machine may serve to control the money storage unit to store therein the money deposited into the money handling machine, and then transmit information on this storage process to the central control unit, the central control unit may serve to determine whether or not the information on the storage process is appropriate, and when determining that the information on the storage process is appropriate, the central control unit transmits information on the money exchange process to the control unit of the money handling machine, and the control unit of the money handling machine may serve to control the money recycling unit and/or wrapped-coin dispensing unit to dispense the exchange money, based on the information on the money exchange process transmitted from the central control unit.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In the above money handling system, it is preferred that when the money exchange mode is selected via the operation unit, one or more denominations of exchange money and the number or total amount of money for each denomination of exchange money are inputted via the operation unit, and the control unit serves to control the money recycling unit and/or wrapped-coin dispensing unit to dispense the money of the inputted one or more denominations of exchange money, from the money handling machine, based on the inputted number or total amount of money.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Alternatively, the money handling system may further comprise an operator identification unit adapted for identifying information on the operator, a memory unit adapted for storing therein information on one or more money exchange patterns, provided for each operator and including one or more denominations of exchange money and the number or total amount of money for each denomination of exchange money regarding the money exchange process, and a selection unit configured for allowing the operator to select the one or more money exchange patterns stored in the memory, and once the information of the operator is identified by the operator identification unit, the control unit may serve to control the money recycling unit and/or wrapped-coin dispensing unit to dispense the money of one or more denominations of exchange money in one money exchange pattern selected by the operator via the selection unit, among the one or more money exchange patterns stored in the memory, from the money handling machine, based on the number or total amount of the money stored in the memory.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> is a block diagram illustrating general construction of a money handling system related to one embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> is a block diagram illustrating another construction of the money handling system related to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</figref> is a block diagram illustrating still another construction of the money handling system related to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1D</figref> is a block diagram illustrating still yet another construction of the money handling system related to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> is a diagram schematically illustrating construction of the money handling machine provided to the money handling system shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> or <b>1</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref> is a perspective view of the money handling machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> is a diagram schematically illustrating construction of a banknote handling machine provided to the money handling machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> or <b>2</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref> is a diagram schematically illustrating construction of a coin handling machine provided to the money handling machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> or <b>2</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref> is a diagram schematically illustrating construction of a wrapped-coin dispensing machine provided to the money handling machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> or <b>2</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a block diagram illustrating a control system provided for the money handling machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> or <b>2</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> is a diagram illustrating a series of operations for a money exchange process in the money handling machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> or <b>2</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref> is another diagram illustrating the series of operations for the money exchange process in the money handling machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> or <b>2</b>B.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Hereinafter, a money handling system of one exemplary embodiment of the present invention will be described with reference to the drawings. The money handling system related to this embodiment includes a money handling machine and a central control unit. This money handling machine includes a money storage unit arranged to be controlled on the side of the designated collector, a money recycling unit arranged to be controlled on the side of the store, and a wrapped-coin dispensing unit arranged to be controlled on the side of the designated collector. In this embodiment, the money storage unit, money recycling storage unit and wrapped-coin dispensing unit are respectively provided in one case of the money handling machine. Further, in this embodiment, commands and data can be transmitted and/or received between the central control unit and each of the money storage unit, money recycling unit and wrapped-coin dispensing unit. As such, the money handling machine can be operated and/or managed on the side of the central control unit, without any authorized operator being always present in each store where the money handling machine is installed.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The money handling machine related to this embodiment is adapted for performing a supplement process, a depositing process, a dispensing process, a delivery process, a mass delivery process, the money exchange process (including an exchange from large denomination to small denomination process and an exchange from small denomination to large denomination process), a checking process, a counting process and the like, about the money including the coins and banknotes. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 5</figref> are provided herein for respectively illustrating the construction of the money handling system related to one exemplary embodiment of the present invention. Of these drawings, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> shows one block diagram illustrating one exemplary construction of the money handling system of this embodiment, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> shows one block diagram illustrating another construction of the money handling system of this embodiment. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> schematically shows the construction of the money handling machine provided to the money handling system shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> or <b>1</b>B, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref> illustrates one exemplary perspective view of the money handling machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> schematically shows the construction of the banknote handling machine provided to the money handling machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> or <b>2</b>B, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref> schematically shows the construction of the coin handling machine provided to the money handling machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> or <b>2</b>B, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref> schematically shows the construction of the wrapped-coin dispensing machine provided to the money handling machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> or <b>2</b>B. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows one exemplary block diagram illustrating the control system provided for the money handling machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> or <b>2</b>B. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> (including <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A and 5B</figref>) is provided for illustrating the series of operations for the money exchange process in the money handling machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> or <b>2</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>, the money handling system of this embodiment includes a money handling machine <b>10</b> installed in the store, and a cash center <b>13</b> and a data center <b>14</b>, which are respectively provided on the outside of the store, while being respectively isolated from the money handling machine <b>10</b>. In addition, a central control unit is provided for each of the cash center <b>13</b> and data center <b>14</b>. In this embodiment, each of the cash center <b>13</b> and data center <b>14</b> can serve as the central control unit. Meanwhile, a controller <b>12</b> is provided to the money handling machine <b>10</b>. This controller <b>12</b> is connected, by wire or wireless communication, with the cash center <b>13</b>, and thus capable of receiving and transmitting a signal relative to the cash center <b>13</b>. Namely, this configuration can enable the remote control of the money handling machine <b>10</b> from the cash center <b>13</b> via the controller <b>12</b>. In this case, the controller <b>12</b> may be a communication control device or another proper terminal, which is connected, via a LAN or the like means, with the money handling machine <b>10</b>, or otherwise may be a communication unit or the like provided in the money handling machine <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Further, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>, the cash center <b>13</b> and data center <b>14</b> are connected, by wire or wireless communication, relative to each other, such that various data can be received and transmitted between the cash center <b>13</b> and the data center <b>14</b>. Therefore, the information, which has been transmitted to the cash center <b>13</b> from the money handling machine <b>10</b> via the controller <b>12</b>, in regard to the handling condition of money including the coins, banknotes and the like in the money handling machine <b>10</b>, can also be sent to the data center <b>14</b>. In the present invention, the central control unit is provided to each of the cash center <b>13</b> and data center <b>14</b>. However, the manner of providing the central control unit is not limited to this aspect. For instance, the central control unit may be provided to only the cash center <b>13</b>, or otherwise may be provided to only the data center <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Further, the construction of the money handling system of this embodiment is not limited to such an aspect as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>. For instance, the money handling system may be constructed as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref>. It is true that the construction of the money handling system shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> is substantially the same as the construction of the money handling system shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>, in that both of the two systems include the money handling machine <b>10</b>, together with the cash center <b>13</b> and data center <b>14</b>, which are respectively provided on the outside of the store, while being respectively isolated from the money handling machine <b>10</b>. However, a controller <b>17</b> provided to the money handling machine <b>10</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> has a further expanded function.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Namely, this controller <b>17</b> is connected, by wire or wireless communication, with each of the cash center <b>13</b> and data center <b>14</b>, and thus capable of receiving and transmitting the signal relative to both of the cash center <b>13</b> and data center <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In addition, still other functions can be provided to the controller <b>17</b> in the money handling system shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref>. For instance, this controller <b>17</b> can be further connected with a printer <b>17</b><i>a</i>, a card reader <b>17</b><i>b </i>and a scanner <b>17</b><i>c</i>. The printer <b>17</b><i>a </i>is provided for printing the information on the money including the coins, banknotes and the like, respectively handled by the money handling machine <b>10</b>. The card reader <b>17</b><i>b </i>can be connected to the money handling machine <b>10</b>, in addition to another card reader provided to the money handling machine <b>10</b>, and is configured for reading ID information of an ID card carried by each operator. With this configuration, each operator can be identified, based on the signal related to the ID information of the operator inputted to the controller <b>17</b>. The scanner <b>17</b><i>c </i>is configured to image a serial number, a bar-code or the like of each banknote. In this embodiment, the controller <b>17</b> may also serve as a router.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Furthermore, the controller <b>17</b> can also be connected with a personal computer <b>17</b><i>d </i>of the operator. In this case, the operator can operate the money handling machine <b>10</b> via the personal computer <b>17</b><i>d </i>connected with the controller <b>17</b>. In addition, this personal computer <b>17</b><i>d </i>can serve to receive and transmit the signal relative to the data center <b>14</b> that will be described later.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Now, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 through 4</figref>, the construction of the money handling machine <b>10</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A and 1B</figref> will be described in more detail.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</figref>, the money handling machine <b>10</b> includes a casing <b>11</b> having a substantially rectangular parallelepiped shape. In this casing <b>11</b>, a wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> is located on the left side, when seen from the front of the money handling machine <b>10</b>, while a banknote handling machine <b>20</b> is located on the right side, in an upper portion, when seen from the front of the money handling machine <b>10</b>, with a coin handling machine <b>30</b> located on the central, in the upper portion, when again seen from the front of the money handling machine <b>10</b>. Further, in the casing <b>11</b> of the money handling machine <b>10</b>, a money storage unit <b>40</b> configured for storing therein the coins and banknotes is provided below the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> and coin handling machine <b>30</b>. In this case, the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> and coin handling machine <b>30</b> are respectively arranged to be controlled under one control authority (that will be herein referred to as the &#x201c;first control authority&#x201d;) provided on the side of the store. Meanwhile, the money storage unit <b>40</b> and wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> are respectively arranged to be controlled under another control authority (that will be herein referred to as the &#x201c;second control authority&#x201d;) provided on the side of the designated collector.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Hereinafter, each component of the banknote handling machine <b>20</b>, coin handling machine <b>30</b>, money storage unit <b>40</b> and wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> will be described in detail.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">First of all, the construction of the money handling machine <b>20</b> will be described, with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A</figref>, <b>2</b>B and <b>3</b>A. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2B and 3A</figref>, the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> includes a banknote inlet <b>21</b> provided for taking the banknotes into the banknote handling machine <b>20</b>, a banknote reject slot <b>22</b> provided for rejecting the counterfeit banknotes, the banknotes or the like that cannot be recognized or the like, among the banknotes respectively taken in the banknote handling machine <b>20</b>, and a banknote return slot <b>23</b> provided for returning the banknotes that are not stored in the money storage unit <b>40</b>, among the banknotes respectively taken in the banknote handling machine <b>20</b>, to the exterior of the banknote handling machine <b>20</b>. Further, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, a transport unit <b>25</b> is provided in the banknote handling machine <b>20</b>. This transport unit <b>25</b> is adapted for transporting the banknotes respectively inserted through the banknote inlet <b>21</b>, in the banknote handling machine <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The banknote inlet <b>21</b> is configured such that one banknote or plurality of banknotes in a batch form can be collectively inserted therethrough, by the operator, in the long-edge orientation. Further, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>, a banknote stage <b>28</b> is provided to the banknote inlet <b>21</b>. When in a waiting position, this banknote stage <b>28</b> is lifted to prevent the operator from inserting the banknotes through the banknote inlet <b>21</b>. Meanwhile, when handling the banknotes, the banknote stage <b>28</b> takes a lowered position for allowing the operator to insert the banknote through the banknote inlet <b>21</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, the banknote inlet <b>21</b> is connected to the transport unit <b>25</b>, such that one banknote or plurality of banknotes in the batch form, respectively inserted through the banknote inlet <b>21</b>, can be transported, one by one, by the transport unit <b>25</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, the banknote reject slot <b>22</b> is also connected to the transport unit <b>25</b>, such that each banknote that has been recognized to be rejected, by a recognition unit (which will be described later), among the banknotes respectively taken in the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> via the banknote inlet <b>21</b>, can be transported to the banknote reject slot <b>22</b> by the transport unit <b>25</b>. Thus, the operator can take out such banknotes respectively fed to the banknote reject slot <b>22</b>. It is noted that this banknote reject slot <b>22</b> can also serve as an outlet for dispensing the changes or the like. Additionally, a cover (not shown) is provided to the banknote reject slot <b>22</b>. This cover is opened when waiting, while being closed when handling the banknotes or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Further, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, a banknote holding unit <b>29</b> is provided to the banknote return slot <b>23</b>, while being connected to the transport unit <b>25</b>. This banknote holding unit <b>29</b> is configured to receive the banknotes respectively transported thereto by the transport unit <b>25</b>. Further, a door <b>24</b> that can be opened and closed is provided to the banknote return slot <b>23</b>. When the banknotes held in the banknote holding unit <b>29</b> are returned, one side wall of the banknote holding unit <b>29</b> on the front face side of the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> is opened, thereby allowing the operator to take out the banknotes via the opened door <b>24</b>. In this case, the door <b>24</b> can be automatically opened, when the banknotes are brought into such a state that can allow the banknotes to be taken out from the banknote return slot <b>23</b>. In some cases, as will be described later, rather than being taken out, by the operator, from the banknote return slot <b>23</b>, the banknotes held in the banknote holding unit <b>29</b> are further fed to a banknote storage cassette <b>41</b> (which will be described later) arranged in the banknote storage unit <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The transport unit <b>25</b> can serve to transport the banknotes, one by one, in succession, in the banknote handling machine <b>20</b>. More specifically, the transport unit <b>25</b> is configured for transporting the banknotes along a transport path, while each banknote is held between a pair of belts. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, the transport path provided to the transport unit <b>25</b> is diverted at various points, with a diverter (not shown) provided at each diversion point of the transport path. For instance, each diverter is composed of a diverting nail, and is controlled by a control unit <b>15</b> that will be described later. Specifically, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, the transport unit <b>25</b> is provided for transporting each banknote inserted through the banknote inlet <b>21</b> to the banknote reject slot <b>22</b>, banknote holding unit <b>29</b> or recycling banknote storage unit <b>27</b> that will be described later. Further, the transport unit <b>25</b> can serve to transport each banknote temporarily stored in the recycling banknote storage unit <b>27</b> to the banknote reject slot <b>22</b> and/or banknote holding unit <b>29</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In addition, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, the recognition unit <b>26</b> is provided to the transport unit <b>25</b>. This recognition unit <b>26</b> can serve to recognize each banknote transported by the transport unit <b>25</b>, one by one, about the denomination, authenticity, fitness or the like thereof. More specifically, the recognition unit <b>26</b> includes magnetic sensors and/or optical sensors, each adapted for recognizing the banknotes, one by one, about the denomination, authenticity or the like thereof. In this case, the recognition result on each banknote recognized by the recognition unit <b>26</b> will be transmitted to the control unit <b>15</b> that will be described later.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In this embodiment, a plurality of (e.g., three) recycling banknote storage units <b>27</b> are arranged, in parallel, in the banknote handling machine <b>20</b>. In general, each of such recycling banknote storage units <b>27</b><i>a </i>to <b>27</b><i>c </i>is provided for each corresponding denomination of the banknotes. For instance, in the case Japanese banknotes are handled by the banknote handling machine <b>20</b>, one-thousand-yen banknotes, five-thousand-yen banknotes and ten-thousand-yen banknotes are stored in the recycling banknote storage units <b>27</b><i>a </i>to <b>27</b><i>c</i>, respectively. In some cases, two-thousand-yen banknotes and five-thousand-yen banknotes are stored, in a mixed state, in the recycling banknote storage unit <b>27</b><i>b</i>. Alternatively, in the case dollar banknotes (e.g., one-dollar banknotes, two-dollar banknotes, five-dollar banknotes, ten-dollar banknotes, twenty-dollar banknotes, fifty-dollar banknotes, one-hundred-dollar banknotes and the like) and/or yuan banknotes (e.g., one-yuan banknotes, five-yuan banknotes, ten-yuan banknotes, twenty-yuan banknotes, fifty-yuan banknotes, one-hundred-yuan banknotes and the like) are handled by the banknote handling machine <b>20</b>, more than three denominations are related to such banknotes or currency. Therefore, in this case, it is necessary to increase the number of the recycling banknote storage units <b>27</b> or otherwise to limit the denominations of the banknotes to be stored in the respective recycling banknote storage units <b>27</b>. Further, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, each recycling banknote storage unit <b>27</b> includes a drum <b>27</b><i>p </i>that can be rotated in both of forward and backward directions, with a pair of tapes being wound around the drum <b>27</b><i>p</i>. With this configuration, the banknotes fed to each recycling banknote storage unit <b>27</b> from the transport unit <b>25</b> will be wound around the corresponding drum <b>27</b><i>p</i>, successively, one by one, while being held between the pair of tapes.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">More specifically, each drum <b>27</b><i>p </i>is configured to be rotated in both of clockwise and anticlockwise directions in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, about one axis vertical to the sheet of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>. Each end of the pair of tapes is attached at the same point on the outer circumferential face of each drum <b>27</b><i>p</i>. Thus, such a pair of tapes can be wound together around each drum <b>27</b><i>p </i>when the drum <b>27</b><i>p </i>is rotated in the anticlockwise direction in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>. In this case, the operation of each drum <b>27</b><i>p </i>is controlled by the control unit <b>15</b> that will be described later. Thus, the banknotes fed to each recycling banknote storage unit <b>27</b> from the transport unit <b>25</b> can be wound, one by one, around each corresponding drum <b>27</b><i>p</i>, together with the pair of tapes, while being held between the pair of tapes, along with the rotation of the drum <b>27</b><i>p </i>in the anticlockwise direction in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>. In this way, the plurality of banknotes can be wound, one by one, with a proper interval, around each corresponding drum <b>27</b><i>p</i>. Meanwhile, when each drum <b>27</b><i>p </i>is rotated in the clockwise direction in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, the pair of tapes wound around this drum <b>27</b><i>p </i>will be released therefrom, and thus each banknote stored in the corresponding recycling banknote storage unit <b>27</b> will be fed to the transport unit <b>25</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">It is noted that each recycling banknote storage unit <b>27</b> is not limited to such an aspect as described above, in which this storage unit <b>27</b> is composed of the drum and pair of tapes, such that each banknote can be wound around the drum, together with the pair of tapes, while being held therebetween. For instance, each recycling banknote storage unit <b>27</b> may be provided as a stacker-type storage unit.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">As described above, the banknote holding unit <b>29</b> is provided in the banknote return slot <b>23</b>, while being connected to the transport unit <b>25</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>. This banknote holding unit <b>29</b> is configured to receive each banknote inserted through the banknote inlet <b>21</b> and/or receive each banknote once stored in each recycling banknote storage unit <b>27</b> and then fed thereto by the transport unit <b>25</b>. Further, this banknote holding unit <b>29</b> is configured to hold therein the plurality of banknotes, in the batch form, while such banknotes are respectively fed thereto from the transport unit <b>25</b>. As described above, when the banknotes held in the banknote holding unit <b>29</b> are returned, the side wall of the banknote holding unit <b>29</b> on the front face side of the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> is opened, thereby allowing the operator to take out the banknotes via the door <b>24</b>. In this case, the door <b>24</b> can be automatically opened, when the banknotes are brought into the state that can allow the banknotes to be taken out from the banknote return slot <b>23</b>. Meanwhile, when the banknotes are held in the banknote holding unit <b>29</b>, the banknotes are placed on a temporary holding plate. Further, when the banknotes held in the banknote holding unit <b>29</b> are fed to and stored in the banknote storage cassette <b>41</b>, a stage provided to the banknote storage cassette <b>41</b> is moved toward the banknotes placed on the temporary holding plate of the banknote holding unit <b>29</b>, and then lowered toward the banknote storage cassette <b>41</b> from the banknote holding unit <b>29</b>, with the banknotes transferred and placed on the stage. Thus, the banknotes can be stored in the banknote storage cassette <b>41</b>, such that the banknotes on the stage are pushed from above by a holding member.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Next, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A</figref>, <b>2</b>B and <b>3</b>B, the construction of the coin handling machine <b>30</b> will be described. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2B and 3B</figref>, the coin handling machine <b>30</b> includes a coin inlet <b>31</b> provided for taking the coins into the coin handling machine <b>30</b>, and a coin return slot <b>32</b> provided for rejecting the coins that cannot be recognized by a recognition unit <b>35</b><i>a </i>(which will be described later), among the coins respectively taken in the coin handling machine <b>30</b>; as well as for returning the coins that are not stored in the money storage unit <b>40</b>, among the coins respectively taken in the coin handling machine <b>30</b>, to the exterior of the coin handling machine <b>30</b>. Further, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, a transport unit <b>35</b> is provided in the coin handling machine <b>30</b>. This transport unit <b>35</b> is adapted for transporting the coins respectively inserted through the coin inlet <b>31</b>, in the coin handling machine <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The coin inlet <b>31</b> is configured such that one or more coins can be collectively inserted therethrough. Then, the coins respectively inserted through the coin inlet <b>31</b> are fed to the interior of the coin handling machine <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The coin return slot <b>32</b> is connected to a downstream end of the transport unit <b>35</b>, and is configured for accumulating therein the coins respectively transported from the transport unit <b>35</b>. Thus, the operator can take out the coins accumulated in the coin return slot <b>32</b>. As described above, this coin return slot <b>32</b> is provided for receiving the coins or the like that cannot be recognized by the recognition unit <b>35</b><i>a </i>(which will be described later), among the coins respectively taken in the coin handling machine <b>30</b>, as well as for receiving the coins that are not stored in the money storage unit <b>40</b>, among the coins respectively taken in the coin handling machine <b>30</b>. Thereafter, such coins will be returned to the exterior of the coin handling machine <b>30</b>, via the coin return slot <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, a coin feeding unit <b>33</b> is provided in the coin handling machine <b>30</b>. This coin feeding unit <b>33</b> is communicated with the coin inlet <b>31</b>, and is configured for temporarily accumulating therein the coins respectively inserted by the operator through the coin inlet <b>31</b>, as well as for feeding out such accumulated coins to the transport unit <b>35</b> that will be described later. Further, a rotary disk (not shown) adapted for feeding out the coins is provided to the coin feeding unit <b>33</b>, such that the coins can be fed out, one by one, by this rotary disk, toward the transport unit <b>35</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The transport unit <b>35</b> can serve to transport the coins, one by one, in succession, in the coin handling machine <b>30</b>. More specifically, this transport unit <b>35</b> can transport the coins, one by one, by using a coin transport belt (not shown), while each coin is standing on the belt, in a slightly oblique state, with an appropriate interval. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, an upstream end and the downstream end of the transport unit <b>35</b> are connected with the coin feeding unit <b>33</b> and coin return slot <b>32</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Further, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, the recognition unit <b>35</b><i>a </i>is provided to the transport unit <b>35</b>. The recognition unit <b>35</b><i>a </i>can serve to recognize the coins, one by one, while each coin is transported by the transport unit <b>35</b>. Specifically, this recognition unit <b>35</b><i>a </i>is configured for recognizing the denomination, authenticity or the like of each coin transported along the transport unit <b>35</b>. More specifically, the recognition unit <b>35</b><i>a </i>includes magnetic sensors and/or optical sensors, each adapted for recognizing the coins, one by one, about the denomination, authenticity or the like thereof. In this case, the recognition result on each coin recognized by the recognition unit <b>35</b><i>a </i>will be transmitted to the control unit <b>15</b> that will be described later.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In this embodiment, a plurality of (e.g., six) cylindrical recycling coin storage units <b>34</b> are arranged, in parallel, in the coin handling machine <b>30</b>, and each recycling coin storage unit <b>34</b> is configured for taking in and taking out the coins from the top thereof. Further, each recycling coin storage unit <b>34</b> is provided to extend in the vertical direction in the coin handling machine <b>30</b>. In general, each of such recycling banknote storage units <b>34</b><i>a </i>to <b>34</b><i>f </i>is provided for each corresponding denomination of the coins. For instance, in the case Japanese coins are handled by the coin handling machine <b>30</b>, one-yen coins, five-yen coins, ten-yen coins, fifty-yen coins, one-hundred-yen coins and five-hundred-yen coins are stored in the recycling coin storage units <b>34</b><i>a </i>to <b>34</b><i>f</i>, respectively. Alternatively, in the case US coins (e.g., one-cent coins, five-cent coins, ten-cent coins, twenty-five cent coins, fifty-cent coins, one-dollar coins and the like) and/or Chinese coins (e.g., one-fen coins, two-fen coins, five-fen coins, one-jiao coins, five-jiao coins, one-yuan coins and the like) are handled by the coin handling machine <b>30</b>, the recycling coin storage units <b>34</b> should be provided, in a number corresponding to the denominations of such coins or currency. In any case, the coins are stored, in a stacked condition, in each recycling coin storage unit <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, seven sorting holes <b>36</b> are provided, in a middle part of the transport unit <b>35</b>, while being arranged, with a given interval, from the coin feeding unit <b>33</b> toward the downstream side of the transport unit <b>35</b>. In this case, the sorting hole <b>36</b> (or overflowing sorting hole <b>36</b>) located on the most upstream side, among the seven sorting holes <b>36</b>, is provided for feeding the coins, directly, from the transport unit <b>35</b>, to a lateral transport unit <b>38</b> that will be described later. More specifically, this sorting hole <b>36</b> located on the most upstream side can serve to feed the coins, directly, onto the lateral transport unit <b>38</b>, when the recognition result on the coin recognized by the recognition unit <b>35</b><i>a </i>satisfies a predetermined condition (e.g., when a certain recycling coin storage unit <b>34</b> corresponding to the denomination of the coin recognized by the recognition unit <b>35</b><i>a </i>is completely filled with the coins). Meanwhile, each of the second to seventh sorting holes <b>36</b>, respectively arranged from the upstream side, is provided, corresponding to each of the recycling coin storage units <b>34</b><i>a </i>to <b>34</b><i>f. </i></p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, a coin escrow unit <b>39</b> for each denomination, which is adapted for escrowing (or temporarily holding) therein the coins, is provided to a top portion of each recycling coin storage unit <b>34</b> extending in the vertical direction. With this configuration, the coins, respectively, falling down from the transport unit <b>35</b> through each sorting hole <b>36</b>, are first escrowed in the coin escrow unit <b>39</b>. For example, this coin escrow unit <b>39</b> is configured for escrowing therein approximately ten coins, for each denomination. Thereafter, the coins respectively escrowed in this coin escrow unit <b>39</b> will be stored in each corresponding recycling coin storage unit <b>34</b>. Further, in this case, the coin escrow unit <b>39</b> includes a releasing member. Namely, due to this releasing member, the coins respectively escrowed in the coin escrow unit <b>39</b> for each denomination, can also be released onto the lateral transport unit <b>38</b> that will be described later.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Meanwhile, in the case the coins stored in each corresponding recycling coin storage unit <b>34</b> are taken out therefrom, a stage (not shown) provided at a bottom portion of the recycling coin storage unit <b>34</b> is lifted upward, and then the coins placed on the stage are fed toward the coin escrow unit <b>39</b> for each denomination. Thereafter, such coins fed to the coin escrow unit <b>39</b> are released onto the lateral transport unit <b>38</b> by the releasing member of the coin escrow unit <b>39</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Further, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, a coin holding unit <b>37</b><i>a </i>is provided in the coin handling machine <b>30</b>, with a chute <b>37</b><i>b </i>provided above the coin holding unit <b>37</b><i>a</i>. With this configuration, the coins fed to a top portion of the chute <b>37</b><i>b </i>from the lateral transport unit <b>38</b> that will be described later can be fed to the coin holding unit <b>37</b><i>a </i>through the chute <b>37</b><i>b</i>. Thereafter, the coins temporarily held in the coin holding unit <b>37</b><i>a </i>can be further fed to a coin storage cassette <b>42</b> (that will be described later) located in the money storage unit <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Additionally, in the coin handling machine <b>30</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, the lateral transport unit <b>38</b> having, for example, a circular belt <b>38</b><i>a </i>extending in a substantially horizontal direction, is provided in the vicinity of the recycling coin storage units <b>34</b> respectively extending in the vertical direction. The circular belt <b>38</b><i>a </i>is provided over two pulleys, each positioned at the same level. As such, the circular belt <b>38</b><i>a </i>can be circulated in either of the clockwise and anticlockwise directions in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, with the rotation of one of the two pulleys in either of the forward and backward directions. One end of the lateral transport unit <b>38</b> is positioned in the coin feeding unit <b>33</b>, while the other end of the lateral transport unit <b>38</b> is positioned in the vicinity of the top portion of the chute <b>37</b><i>b</i>. As described above, the circular belt <b>38</b><i>a </i>of the lateral transport unit <b>38</b> can be rotated in either of the forward and backward directions. Therefore, when the circular belt <b>38</b><i>a </i>is rotated in the anticlockwise direction in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, the coins present on the lateral transport unit <b>38</b> will be fed to the coin feeding unit <b>33</b>. Meanwhile, when the circular belt <b>38</b><i>a </i>is rotated in the clockwise direction in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, the coins present on the lateral transport unit <b>38</b> will be fed to the chute <b>37</b><i>b</i>, and thus eventually held in the coin holding unit <b>37</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Now, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</figref>, the construction of the money storage unit <b>40</b> will be described. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</figref>, the money storage unit <b>40</b> is provided in the lower part of the casing <b>11</b> of the money handling machine <b>10</b>. Further, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A and 3B</figref>, the money storage unit <b>40</b> includes the banknote storage cassette <b>41</b> provided for storing therein the banknotes and the coin storage cassette <b>42</b> provided for storing therein the coins. More specifically, the banknote storage cassette <b>41</b> is configured for storing therein the banknotes once held in the banknote holding unit <b>29</b> of the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>). Meanwhile, the coin storage cassette <b>42</b> is configured for storing therein the coins once held in the coin holding unit <b>37</b><i>a </i>of the coin handling machine <b>30</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>). With this configuration, each of the cassettes <b>41</b>, <b>42</b> of the money storage unit <b>40</b> can be drawn out, forward, from the casing <b>11</b>, by the designated collector in charge of collecting the sales proceeds, such as the staff or the like of the armored car company. In this manner, each cassette <b>41</b>, <b>42</b>, itself, can be collected by the designated collector.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Next, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A</figref>, <b>2</b>B and <b>3</b>C, the construction of the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> will be described. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2B and 3C</figref>, the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> includes a plurality of (e.g., seven) wrapped-coin storage cassettes (or wrapped-coin storage units) <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>g </i>provided in the casing <b>11</b>, each configured for storing therein the wrapped-coins, for each denomination. Then, this wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> can serve to dispense therefrom the wrapped coins stored in each of the wrapped-coin storage cassettes <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>g</i>, for each denomination, to the exterior of the casing <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">More specifically, the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> includes the plurality of (e.g., seven) wrapped-coin storage cassettes <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>g</i>, each configured for storing therein the wrapped-coins, for each denomination, and a wrapped-coin dispensing mechanism <b>53</b> configured for receiving the wrapped coins, respectively fed, one by one, from each of the wrapped-coin storage cassettes <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>g</i>. In this embodiment, the operator can fill, by hand, as needed, any one of the wrapped-coin storage cassettes <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>g </i>with the wrapped coins. More specifically, each storage cassette <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>g </i>is configured to store therein the plurality of wrapped coins, with the longitudinal direction of each wrapped coin being normal to the sheet of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref>. Namely, each circle as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref> denotes a cross section of each wrapped coin, which is stored in each storage cassette <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>g </i>and extending vertically to the sheet of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref>. Further, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref>, each storage cassette <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>g </i>is inclined, slightly downward, toward the wrapped-coin dispensing mechanism <b>53</b>. As such, each wrapped coin stored in each storage cassette <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>g </i>can be moved, by dead load (or its weight), toward the wrapped-coin dispensing mechanism <b>53</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">As described above, the wrapped-coin dispensing mechanism <b>53</b> is provided for receiving the wrapped coins, respectively fed, one by one, from each of the wrapped-coin storage cassettes <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>g</i>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref>, the wrapped-coin dispensing mechanism <b>53</b> can be lifted or lowered. As such, this wrapped-coin dispensing mechanism <b>53</b> can be moved to any suitable level corresponding to a right end of each storage cassette <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>g</i>, in order to receive the wrapped coins therefrom. More specifically, a timing belt (not shown) is provided, to the wrapped-coin dispensing mechanism <b>53</b>, such that the wrapped-coin dispensing mechanism <b>53</b> can be lifted or lowered by actuation of this timing belt.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In addition, a checking sensor <b>52</b> is provided for each storage cassette <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>g</i>, such that this checking sensor <b>52</b> can be moved, in a substantially lateral direction along the storage cassettes <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>g</i>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref>. In this way, the checking sensor <b>52</b> can serve to recognize each wrapped coin stored in each storage cassette <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>g</i>, about the denomination or the like thereof, as well as to check the number of the wrapped coins respectively stored in each storage cassette <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>g. </i></p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Further, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref>, a shutter <b>54</b> is located above the wrapped-coin dispensing mechanism <b>53</b>. This shutter <b>54</b> is usually closed, and it can be opened, when the operator sends a command for opening this shutter to the control unit <b>15</b> from an operation unit <b>45</b> and when the wrapped-coin dispensing mechanism <b>53</b> reaches the highest position thereof. Thus, the operator can take out the wrapped coins stored in the wrapped-coin dispensing mechanism <b>53</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Next, other various mechanisms provided in the money handling machine <b>10</b> will be described. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>, the operation unit <b>45</b> adapted for allowing the operator to input various commands to the control unit <b>15</b> (that will be described later) of the money handling machine <b>10</b>, and a display unit <b>44</b> adapted for displaying the handling condition of money or the like in the money handling machine <b>10</b> are respectively provided to a top face of the casing <b>11</b> of the money handling machine <b>10</b>. The operation unit <b>45</b> includes, for example, numeric keys, a confirmation key, a start key, a clear (or cancelling) key, a reset key and the like. Thus, by pushing such keys, the operator can input the various commands to the control unit <b>15</b> of the money handling machine <b>10</b>. For instance, the display unit <b>44</b> is composed of a liquid crystal display (LCD) device.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Further, a printer <b>43</b> adapted for printing the contents or the like of handling the money in the money handling machine <b>10</b>, and a card reader <b>46</b> adapted for checking the authority of the operator to operate the money handling machine <b>10</b> are respectively provided to a front face of the casing <b>11</b>. For instance, the card reader <b>46</b> can serve to read the ID information of the ID card carried by each operator.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">Now, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the control unit <b>15</b> adapted for controlling each component of the money handling machine <b>10</b> will be described. This control unit <b>15</b> is provided in the casing <b>11</b> of the money handling machine <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the control unit <b>15</b> is connected with each component of the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> (e.g., the transport unit <b>25</b>, recognition unit <b>26</b>, recycling banknote storage units <b>27</b>, banknote stage <b>28</b>, banknote holding unit <b>29</b>, door <b>24</b> and the like), each component of the coin handling machine <b>30</b> (e.g., the coin feeding unit <b>33</b>, transport unit <b>35</b>, recognition unit <b>35</b><i>a</i>, lateral transport unit <b>38</b>, recycling coin storage units <b>34</b> including the coin escrow unit <b>39</b> for each denomination, coin holding unit <b>37</b><i>a </i>and the like), money storage unit <b>40</b> and each component of the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> (e.g., the checking unit <b>52</b>, wrapped-coin dispensing mechanism <b>53</b>, and shutter <b>54</b>), as well as connected with the display unit <b>44</b>, operation unit <b>45</b>, printer <b>43</b>, card reader <b>46</b>, memory unit <b>47</b> and the like. Further, the control unit <b>15</b> is connected with the controller <b>12</b> (<b>17</b>) via an interface.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The control unit <b>15</b> is configured for receiving the recognition result on each banknote recognized by the recognition unit <b>26</b> of the banknote handling machine <b>20</b>, as well as for receiving the recognition result on each coin recognized by the recognition unit <b>35</b><i>a </i>of the coin handling machine <b>30</b>. Further, the control unit <b>15</b> can serve to receive the information, such as the ID information or the like on the operator, inputted via the operation unit <b>45</b> or read by the card reader <b>46</b> from each card. In addition, this control unit <b>15</b> is configured for receiving the information on the number of the wrapped coins stored in each wrapped-coin storage cassette <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>g </i>or the like checked by the checking sensor <b>52</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">When the money handling machine <b>10</b> is operated, the controller <b>15</b> checks the authority of the operator, based on the ID information on the operator, inputted from the operation unit <b>45</b> and/or card reader <b>46</b>. Further, the controller <b>15</b> can serve to control each component of the banknote handling machine <b>20</b>, coin handling machine <b>30</b> and/or wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b>, as well as to control the display unit <b>44</b>, printer <b>43</b> and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The cash center <b>13</b> or data center <b>14</b> is configured to transmit a command signal indicative of each process to be performed by the money handling machine <b>10</b>, to the money handling machine <b>10</b>, via the controller <b>12</b> (<b>17</b>). More specifically, the signal transmitted from the cash center <b>13</b> to the money handling machine <b>10</b> is related to at least one of a closing command, a delivery command, a collection by staff command, a depositing command, a dispensing command, a supplement command, a checking command, an exchange from large denomination to small denomination command, an exchange from small denomination to large denomination command, a counting command, a reset command, a confirmation command, a start command, an unlocking command and a program download command.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">Further, the cash center <b>13</b> or data center <b>14</b> is configured to receive a signal indicative of information on the handling condition of the money in the money handling machine <b>10</b>, from the money handling machine <b>10</b>, via the controller <b>12</b> (<b>17</b>). More specifically, the signal received by the data center <b>14</b> from the money handling machine <b>10</b> is related to at least one of closing data, delivery data, collection by staff data, total amount money data of the recycling money storage unit, depositing data, dispensing data, supplement data, checking data, exchange from large denomination to small denomination data, exchange from small denomination to large denomination data, counting data, total amount money data of the system, system data, failure data and program data.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">In this embodiment, the cash center <b>13</b> or data center <b>14</b> can serve to transmit and receive the signal relative to each of the banknote handling machine <b>20</b>, coin handling machine <b>30</b>, money storage unit <b>40</b> and wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b>, in the money handling machine <b>10</b>, via the controller <b>12</b> (<b>17</b>) and control unit <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">Next, the operation of the money handling machine <b>10</b> constructed as described above will be discussed.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The operation of the money handling machine <b>10</b> includes three modes, i.e., an interface confirmation mode, an operation mode and a maintenance mode. In this embodiment, the operator can select each of the interface confirmation mode, operation mode and maintenance mode, via the operation unit <b>45</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">The interface confirmation mode is provided for checking whether or not the money handling machine <b>10</b> is connected with a higher-ranking machine or the like via an interface <b>16</b>, in an initial state of the money handling machine <b>10</b> or when starting the money handling machine <b>10</b>. In this interface confirmation mode, if the money handling machine <b>10</b> is connected, for communication, with the higher-ranking machine or the like via the interface <b>16</b>, various setting data can be transmitted to the money handling machine <b>10</b> from the higher-ranking machine or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The operation mode includes two modes, i.e., an on-line mode in which the money handling machine <b>10</b> is connected, for communication, with the higher-ranking machine or the like, and an off-line mode in which the connection, for communication, between the money handling machine <b>10</b> and any external machine is shut off. Further, the on-line mode includes two modes, i.e., an opening-store mode and a closing-store mode. In the opening-store mode, the operator can perform the supplement process, depositing process, dispensing process, delivery process, mass delivery process, exchange from large denomination to small denomination process, exchange from small denomination to large denomination process, checking process, counting process and the like. Further, in the opening-store mode, each cassette <b>41</b>, <b>42</b>, itself, of the money storage unit <b>40</b> can be collected by the designated collector in charge of collecting the sales proceeds, such as the staff or the like of the armored car company. Meanwhile, in the closing-store mode, only the collection of each cassette <b>41</b>, <b>42</b> of the money storage unit <b>40</b> performed by the designated collector can be done. If required, such opening-store mode and closing-store mode may be switched from each other for specific time periods. Meanwhile, in the off-line mode, no information is transmitted to and from the higher-ranking machine, and the result of each process, e.g., the depositing process or the like, is stored in the memory unit <b>47</b> provided to the money handling machine <b>10</b>. In this case, the operator can select each of the aforementioned modes via the operation unit <b>45</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">During the maintenance mode, a person in charge of the maintenance for the money handling machine <b>10</b> serves to maintain the money handling machine <b>20</b>, coin handling machine <b>30</b> and/or wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> of the money handling machine <b>10</b>. Such maintenance may be carried out in a site or place where the money handling machine <b>10</b> is installed, or otherwise may be conducted after the money handling machine <b>10</b> is carried to a factory or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">Now, the supplement process, depositing process, dispensing process, delivery process, mass delivery process, exchange from large denomination to small denomination process, exchange from small denomination to large denomination process, checking process, counting process, and closing process and collection by staff process will be described, respectively. Each of these processes is performed by actuation of each component controlled by the control unit <b>15</b>. Further, as will be described later, each of the supplement process, depositing process, dispensing process, delivery process, mass delivery process, exchange from large denomination to small denomination process, exchange from small denomination to large denomination process, checking process, counting process, closing process and collection by staff process is performed, based on each corresponding command inputted to the control unit <b>15</b> by the operator via the operation unit <b>45</b>, or otherwise performed, in accordance with each corresponding command given to the control unit <b>15</b> from the cash center <b>13</b> or data center <b>14</b> via the controller <b>12</b> (<b>17</b>).</p>
<p id="h-0006" num="0000">(Supplement Process)</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">First of all, the supplement process for the banknotes and/or coins will be described in brief. The supplement process for the banknotes and/or coins is provided for supplementing each recycling banknote storage unit <b>27</b> of the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> with the banknotes for each denomination and/or supplementing each recycling coin storage unit <b>34</b> of the coin handling machine <b>30</b> with the coins for each denomination.</p>
<p id="h-0007" num="0000">(Depositing Process)</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">Next, the depositing process for the banknotes and/or coins will be described in brief. This depositing process includes two modes, i.e., a mode with the delivery process and another mode without the delivery process. The depositing process in the mode with the delivery process is provided for depositing the money into the money handling machine <b>10</b>, with the delivery process performed in succession to this depositing process. More specifically, in this mode, the banknotes are temporarily held in each corresponding recycling banknote storage unit <b>27</b>, and then held in the banknote holding unit <b>29</b>, and finally stored in the banknote storage cassette <b>41</b>. Further, in this mode, the coins are escrowed in the coin escrow unit <b>39</b> for each denomination, and then held in the coin holding unit <b>37</b><i>a</i>, and finally stored in the coin storage cassette <b>42</b>. Meanwhile, the depositing process in the mode without the delivery process is provided for only depositing the money into the money handling machine <b>10</b>. Namely, in this mode, if required after the depositing process, the delivery process (that will be described later) for delivering the money to the money storage unit <b>40</b> is performed, independently of the depositing process. In this embodiment, the mode with the delivery process or mode without the delivery process can be set during the installment of the money handling machine <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0008" num="0000">(Dispensing Process)</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">Next, the dispensing process for the banknotes and/or coins will be described in brief. The dispensing process for the banknotes and/or coins is provided for dispensing the banknotes stored in each recycling banknote storage unit <b>27</b> of the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> to the exterior of the banknote handling machine <b>20</b>, and/or dispensing the coins stored in each recycling coin storage unit <b>34</b> of the coin handling machine <b>30</b> to the exterior of the coin handling machine <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">In addition, as the dispensing process, another process for dispensing the wrapped coins stored in each storage cassette <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>g </i>of the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> to the exterior of this wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> can be mentioned. In the case the wrapped coins stored in each storage cassette <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>g </i>of the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> is dispensed from the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b>, the control authority, under which such wrapped coins are controlled, is changed from the second control authority (i.e., the control authority provided on the side of the designated collector) to the first control authority (i.e., the control authority provided on the side of the store). Further, in this case, the total amount of money corresponding to the wrapped coins dispensed from the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> is deposited into an account of the financial institution related to the designated collector, from another account of the financial institution related to the store. Namely, from a viewpoint of the store, while the cash of the wrapped coins is dispensed from the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b>, the total amount of money corresponding to such dispensed wrapped coins will be deducted from the account of the financial institution related to the store.</p>
<p id="h-0009" num="0000">(Delivery Process)</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">Next, the delivery process for the banknotes and/or coins will be described. Herein, the delivery process for the banknotes and/or coins is provided for delivering the banknotes stored in each recycling banknote storage unit <b>27</b> of the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> to the banknote storage cassette <b>41</b> of the money storage unit <b>40</b>, and/or delivering the coins stored in each recycling coin storage unit <b>34</b> of the coin handling machine <b>30</b> to the coin storage cassette <b>42</b> of the money storage unit <b>40</b>. Once the delivery process is performed, the control authority, under which the banknotes and/or coins, respectively fed from each recycling banknote storage unit <b>27</b> and/or each recycling coin storage unit <b>34</b> to the money storage unit <b>40</b>, are controlled, is changed from the first control authority (i.e., the control authority provided on the side of the store) to the second control authority (i.e., the control authority provided on the side of the designated collector). As a result, the total amount of money of the banknotes and/or coins, respectively stored in each recycling banknote storage unit <b>27</b> and/or each recycling coin storage unit <b>34</b>, is reduced by the total amount of money of the banknotes and/or coins, respectively subjected to the delivery process. Meanwhile, the total amount of money of the banknotes and/or coins, respectively stored in the banknote storage cassette <b>41</b> and/or coin storage cassette <b>42</b> of the money storage unit <b>40</b>, is increased by the total amount of money of the banknotes and/or coins, respectively subjected to the delivery process.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">In the delivery process as described above, once the banknotes and/or coins, respectively stored in each recycling banknote storage unit <b>27</b> and/or each recycling coin storage unit <b>34</b>, are fed to the money storage unit <b>40</b>, the total amount of money corresponding to such banknotes and/or coins will be deposited into the account of the financial institution related to the store, from the account of the financial institution related to the designated collector. Namely, from the viewpoint of the store, while the cash of the banknotes and/or coins fed to the money storage unit <b>40</b> is lost, the total amount of money corresponding to such banknotes and/or coins, respectively fed to the money storage unit <b>40</b>, will be deposited into the account of the financial institution related to the store.</p>
<p id="h-0010" num="0000">(Mass Delivery Process)</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">Now, the mass delivery process for the banknotes and/or coins will be described in brief. Herein, the mass delivery process for the banknotes and/or coins is provided for delivering the banknotes, in a relatively great amount, to the banknote storage cassette <b>41</b> of the money handling machine <b>40</b>, and/or delivering the coins, in a relatively great amount, to the coin storage cassette <b>42</b> of the money handling machine <b>40</b>. In this mass delivery process, similar to the aforementioned delivery process, the control authority, under which the banknotes and/or coins, respectively fed from the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> and/or coin handling machine <b>30</b> to the money storage unit <b>40</b>, are controlled, is changed from the first control authority (i.e., the control authority provided on the side of the store) to the second control authority (i.e., the control authority provided on the side of the designated collector). Again, in this case, the total amount of money corresponding to such banknotes and/or coins, respectively fed to the money storage unit <b>40</b>, will be deposited into the account of the financial institution related to the store, from the account of the financial institution related to the designated collector.</p>
<p id="h-0011" num="0000">(Exchange from Large Denomination to Small Denomination Process, and Exchange from Small Denomination to Large Denomination Process)</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">Next, the exchange from large denomination to small denomination process and the exchange from small denomination to large denomination process will be described. Herein, the exchange from large denomination to small denomination process and the exchange from small denomination to large denomination process are respectively provided for once taking the banknotes and/or coins into the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> and/or coin handling machine <b>30</b>, and then returning the banknotes and/or coins, which are respectively corresponding to the total amount of money of the banknotes and/or coins once taken in the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> and/or coin handling machine <b>30</b>, while being different in one or more denominations of money therefrom, to the exterior of the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> and/or coin handling machine <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">Further, the above exchange from large denomination to small denomination process and/or exchange from small denomination to large denomination process may be provided for first taking the banknotes and/or coins into the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> and/or coin handling machine <b>30</b>, and then dispensing the wrapped coins from the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b>. More specifically, the wrapped coins the amount of which is calculated by subtracting a charge for the service from the total amount of money of the banknotes and/or coins, respectively taken in the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> and/or coin handling machine <b>30</b>, or otherwise the wrapped coins the amount of which corresponds to the total amount of money of the banknotes and/or coins, respectively taken in the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> and/or coin handling machine <b>30</b>, are dispensed from the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b>. Further in this case, the banknotes temporarily stored in the recycling banknote storage units <b>27</b> of the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> may be dispensed from the banknote handling machine <b>20</b>, while the wrapped coins are dispensed from the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b>. Alternatively or additionally, the loose coins may be dispensed from the coin handling machine <b>30</b>, during the above exchange from large denomination to small denomination process and/or upon the exchange from small denomination to large denomination process.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">More specifically, once the command for performing such a money exchange process as described above is inputted to the control unit <b>15</b> by the operator via the operation unit <b>45</b>, or otherwise the command for performing the money exchange process is given to the control unit <b>15</b> from the cash center <b>13</b> or data center <b>14</b> via the controller <b>12</b> (<b>17</b>), the control unit <b>15</b> of the money handling machine <b>10</b> serves to deliver the banknotes and/or coins, respectively deposited in the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> and/or coin handling machine <b>30</b>, to the money storage unit <b>40</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>. In this case, the control authority, under which the banknotes and/or coins, respectively delivered from the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> and/or coin handling machine <b>30</b> to the money storage unit <b>40</b>, are controlled, is changed from the first control authority (i.e., the control authority provided on the side of the store) to the second control authority (i.e., the control authority provided on the side of the designated collector).</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">Thereafter, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>, the control unit <b>15</b> controls the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> to dispense therefrom the wrapped coins, as the exchange money. In this case, the control authority, under which the wrapped coins, respectively dispensed from the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b>, are controlled, is changed from the second control authority (i.e., the control authority provided on the side of the designated collector) to the first control authority (i.e., the control authority provided on the side of the store). Alternatively or additionally, while controlling the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> to dispense therefrom the wrapped coins, the control unit <b>15</b> may control the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> to dispense therefrom the banknotes temporarily stored in the recycling banknote storage units <b>27</b> of the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>). Further, the control unit <b>15</b> may serve to perform the dispensing process for dispensing the loose coins from the coin handling machine <b>30</b>. In any case, the control unit <b>15</b> will transmit the information on such a money exchange process to the cash center <b>13</b> and/or data center <b>14</b> via the controller <b>12</b> (<b>17</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">In the case of dispensing the wrapped coins from the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> in the above exchange from large denomination to small denomination process and/or exchange from small denomination to large denomination process, the following operation may be performed. For instance, when the command for performing the money exchange process is sent to the control unit <b>15</b> by the operator via the operation unit <b>45</b>, or when the command for performing the money exchange process is given to the control unit <b>15</b> from the cash center <b>13</b> or data center <b>14</b> via the controller <b>12</b> (<b>17</b>), the control unit <b>15</b> of the money handling machine <b>10</b> serves to deliver the banknotes and/or coins, respectively deposited in the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> and/or coin handling machine <b>30</b>, to the money storage unit <b>40</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>. In this case, the control authority, under which the banknotes and/or coins, respectively delivered from the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> and/or coin handling machine <b>30</b> to the money storage unit <b>40</b>, are controlled, is changed from the first control authority (i.e., the control authority provided on the side of the store) to the second control authority (i.e., the control authority provided on the side of the designated collector).</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">Thereafter, the control unit <b>15</b> will transmit the information on this delivery process (storage process) to the cash center <b>13</b> and/or data center <b>14</b> via the controller <b>12</b> (<b>17</b>). Then, the cash center <b>13</b> or data center <b>14</b> determines whether or not such information on the delivery process is appropriate. More specifically, the cash center <b>13</b> or data center <b>14</b> determines whether or not the total amount of money inputted by the operator via the operation unit <b>45</b> is coincident with the total amount of money actually delivered to the money storage unit <b>40</b>. If such information on the delivery process is determined to be appropriate, the cash center <b>13</b> or data center <b>14</b> will transmit information on this money exchange process to the control unit <b>15</b>. Then, the control unit <b>15</b> controls the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> to dispense therefrom the wrapped coins, as the exchange money, based on the information on the money exchange process transmitted thereto from the cash center <b>13</b> or data center <b>14</b>. In this case, the control authority, under which the wrapped coins dispensed from the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> are controlled, is changed from the second control authority (i.e., the control authority provided on the side of the designated collector) to the first control authority (i.e., the control authority provided on the side of the store). Alternatively or additionally, while controlling the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> to dispense therefrom the wrapped coins, the control unit <b>15</b> may serve to perform another dispensing process, by controlling the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> to dispense therefrom the banknotes temporarily stored in the recycling banknote storage units <b>27</b> of the banknote handling machine <b>20</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>). Further, the control unit <b>15</b> may control the coin handling machine <b>30</b> to dispense the loose coins therefrom.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">Further, in the above exchange from large denomination to small denomination process and/or exchange from small denomination to large denomination process, when the command for performing the money exchange process is sent to the control unit <b>15</b> by the operator via the operation unit <b>45</b>, or when the command for performing the money exchange process is given to the control unit <b>15</b> from the cash center <b>13</b> or data center <b>14</b> via the controller <b>12</b> (<b>17</b>), the information on one or more denominations of exchange money and the information on the number or total amount of money for each denomination of exchange money are also inputted to the control unit <b>15</b>. Then, the control unit <b>15</b> will control the money handling machine <b>10</b> to dispense therefrom the money of the inputted one or more denominations of exchange money, based on the inputted number or total amount of money. More specifically, the control unit <b>15</b> can serve to control the wrapped-coin handling machine <b>50</b> and/or banknote handling machine <b>20</b> to dispense therefrom the wrapped coins and/or banknotes of the inputted one or more denominations of exchange money, based on the inputted number or total amount of money.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">In the money handling machine <b>10</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the memory unit <b>47</b> is connected with the control unit <b>15</b>. This memory unit <b>47</b> can serve to store therein information on one or more money exchange patterns, provided for each operator and including the denomination or denominations of exchange money and the number or total amount of money for each denomination of exchange money regarding the money exchange process.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">With this configuration, once the information on the operator is identified by the card reader <b>46</b> after it reads the ID information of the ID card carried by this operator, the control unit <b>15</b> controls the display unit <b>44</b> to display thereon the money exchange pattern or patterns stored in the memory unit <b>47</b>. Otherwise, when identifying the information of each operator, a part of the body of the operator may be checked. In any case, once a certain money exchange pattern is selected by the operator via the operation unit <b>45</b> from the money exchange pattern or patterns displayed on the display unit <b>44</b>, the control unit <b>15</b> controls the money handling machine <b>10</b> to dispense therefrom the money of one or more denominations of exchange money in the selected money exchange pattern, based on the number or total amount of money stored in the memory unit <b>47</b>. More specifically, the control unit <b>15</b> can serve to control the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> and/or banknote handling machine <b>20</b> to dispense therefrom the wrapped coins and/or banknotes of one or more denominations of exchange money, (such one or more denominations are stored in the memory unit <b>47</b> and selected via the operation unit <b>45</b>), based on the number or total amount of money also stored in the memory unit <b>47</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">It is noted that the aforementioned memory unit, which is adapted for storing therein information on the one or more money exchange patterns, provided for each operator and including one or more denominations of exchange money and the number or total amount of money for each denomination of exchange money regarding the money exchange process, is not limited to one (i.e., the memory unit <b>47</b>) designed to be connected with the control unit <b>15</b> in the money handling machine <b>10</b>. For instance, a proper control means may be provided to the ID card carried by each operator.</p>
<p id="h-0012" num="0000">(Checking Process)</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">Now, the checking process for the banknotes and/or coins will be described in brief. The checking process for the banknotes is provided for first counting the banknotes present in the banknote handling machine <b>20</b>, and then ejecting such counted banknotes through the banknote reject slot <b>22</b> in order to check the number and/or total amount of money of such ejected banknotes, and finally depositing again such checked banknotes. Meanwhile, the checking process for the coins includes two checking modes, i.e., a normal checking mode and an automatic checking mode. The normal checking mode for the coins is provided for first counting the coins present in the coin handling machine <b>30</b>, and then ejecting such counted coins through the coin return slot <b>32</b> in order to check the number and/or total amount of money of such ejected coins, and finally depositing again such checked coins. The automatic checking mode is provided for once feeding the coins present in each recycling coin storage unit <b>34</b> onto the lateral transport unit <b>38</b>, and then feeding out the coins from the coin feeding unit <b>33</b> and transporting them by the transport unit <b>35</b>, and finally returning the coins to each recycling coin storage unit <b>34</b> via the escrow unit <b>39</b> for each denomination. In this case, the operator can select either of the former (or normal) checking mode or latter (or automatic) checking mode regarding the checking process for the coins, via the operation unit <b>45</b>, while watching the display unit <b>44</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0013" num="0000">(Counting Process)</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">Next, the counting process for the banknotes and/or coins will be described in brief. The counting process for the banknotes and/or coins is provided for counting the banknotes and/or coins at hand. More specifically, the counting process for the banknotes is provided for first feeding the banknotes into the banknote handling machine <b>20</b>, and then temporarily holding the normal banknotes in the banknote holding unit <b>29</b> and feeding abnormal banknotes to the banknote reject slot <b>22</b> in order to reject them, while counting the banknotes during such operations, and finally operating the door <b>24</b> to be automatically opened, thereby allowing the operator to take out the banknotes present in the banknote holding unit <b>29</b>. Meanwhile, the counting process for the coins is provided for first feeding the coins into the coin handling machine <b>30</b>, and then further feeding the normal coins to the lateral transport unit <b>38</b> through the overflowing sorting hole <b>36</b>, while feeding abnormal coins to the coin return slot <b>32</b> in order to remove such rejected coins, and after removing such rejected coins from the coin return slot <b>32</b>, finally feeding the coins fed to the lateral transport unit <b>38</b> to the coin return slot <b>32</b>, through the coin feeding unit <b>33</b> and transport unit <b>35</b>, thereby allowing the operator to take out the coins finally fed to the coin return slot <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0014" num="0000">(Closing Operation)</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">Next, the closing operation will be described in brief. When the closing command is inputted to the control unit <b>15</b> by the operator via the operation unit <b>45</b>, or when the closing command is sent to the control unit <b>15</b> from the cash center <b>13</b> or data center <b>14</b> via the controller <b>12</b> (<b>17</b>), the closing data, i.e., the data on the number of money for each denomination or data on the total amount of money or amount of money for each denomination, will be totalized, in regard to the banknotes stored in the banknote storage cassette <b>41</b> and the coins stored in the coin storage cassette <b>42</b>, due to the delivery process performed in a predetermined period of time, e.g., during a period of time between the previous closing process and the present closing process. Thereafter, the so-obtained closing data will be transmitted to the central control unit.</p>
<p id="h-0015" num="0000">(Collection by Staff Process)</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">Next, the collection by staff process will be described in brief. Once the command for the collection by staff process is sent to the control unit <b>15</b> by the operator via the operation unit <b>45</b>, the control unit <b>15</b> will unlock a door of the money storage unit <b>40</b>, thereby to allow the banknote storage cassette <b>41</b> and coin storage cassette <b>42</b> to be respectively taken out from the money storage unit <b>40</b>. In this state, the staff or the like being present on the side of the designated collector can take out each of the cassettes, while exchanging them with new cassettes. Thereafter, once the staff or the like closes the door, the collection by staff data, i.e., the data on the number of money for each denomination or data on the total amount of money or amount of money for each denomination, in regard to the collected banknotes and/or coins, will be transmitted to the central control unit.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">Each of the above processes, except for the delivery process included in the depositing process in the mode with the delivery process, can be started, when the operator selects one of such processes, inputs the command necessary for the process via the operation unit <b>45</b>, and then pushes the start key. Further, in regard to the supplement process or depositing process, if the confirmation key is pushed down during a predetermined period of time in which the clear key is allowed to be pushed down, the process can be confirmed to be completed.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">Alternatively, as described above, the cash center <b>13</b> or data center <b>14</b> can transmit at least one of the closing command, delivery command, collection by staff command, depositing command, dispensing command, supplement command, checking command, exchange from large denomination to small denomination command, exchange from small denomination to large denomination command, counting command, reset command, confirmation command, start command, unlocking command and program download command, to the money handling machine <b>10</b>. Such commands are respectively provided as an alternative to the operation of the operation unit <b>45</b> for each corresponding process.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">Meanwhile, the money handling machine <b>10</b> is configured to transmit the signal indicative of at least one of the closing data, delivery data, collection by staff data, total amount money data of the recycling money storage unit, depositing data, dispensing data, supplement data, checking data, exchange from large denomination to small denomination data, exchange from small denomination to large denomination data, counting data, total amount money data of the system, system data, failure data and program data, to the cash center <b>13</b> or data center <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">In this way, each of the information on the money handling machine <b>10</b> can be obtained, as needed, from the cash center <b>13</b> or data center <b>14</b>. Therefore, the money handling system can be operated, without any authorized operator being always present in the store. Further, the above data may include the date and time on which certain information is obtained, as well as include recognition information on the store and/or recognition information on the money handling machine. Thus, the information on the date and time on which certain data was obtained, as well as the information on the money handling machine from which the data was sent, and any other like information can be clarified. Additionally, with respect to the closing data, delivery data, collection by staff data, depositing data, dispensing data, supplement data, checking data, exchange from large denomination to small denomination data, exchange from small denomination to large denomination data, counting data and failure data, such data may include the information on the operator, such as the ID information thereof or the like, and/or information on the date and time on which a certain operation was performed by the operator. Thus, the information on the date, time and manner that the money was handled in the money handling machine <b>10</b>, the information on the person who performed the certain operation, as well as the information on the money handling machine <b>10</b> that handled the money, can be managed.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">In the above embodiment, the cash center <b>13</b> and data center <b>14</b> are respectively explained as the central control units having the same control authority. However, the cash center <b>13</b> may be arranged to be controlled under a different control authority than the control authority under which the data center <b>14</b> is controlled.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">More specifically, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</figref>, the cash center may be arranged to be controlled under the control authority provided on the side of the designated collector, and thus adapted for transmitting and receiving the data and/or command related to the money storage unit <b>40</b> and wrapped-coin dispensing unit <b>50</b>, respectively arranged to be controlled under the designated collector. Meanwhile, the data center <b>14</b> may be arranged to be controlled under the control authority provided on the side of the store, and hence adapted for transmitting and receiving the data and/or command related to the money recycling unit (i.e., the recycling banknote storage units <b>27</b> and/or recycling coin storage units <b>34</b>) arranged to be controlled on the side of the store. In this case, the data may be exchanged, as needed, between the cash center <b>13</b> and the data center <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">This configuration can securely prevent one part provided to the money handling system and arranged to be controlled under one control authority, from being unduly accessed by the people who do not have the one control authority, while operating the money handling system, even though such an authorized operator is not always present in the store.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">Further, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1D</figref>, the data center <b>14</b> may be adapted for receiving the data or the like related to the money recycling storage unit (i.e., the recycling banknote storage units <b>27</b> and recycling coin storage units <b>34</b>) from the money handling machine <b>10</b> and then transmitting such data to the cash center <b>13</b>, while the cash center <b>13</b> may be adapted for receiving the data transmitted from the data center <b>14</b> and then transmitting a certain command to the money handling machine <b>10</b>, based on such received data.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">With this configuration, even though a plurality of central control units are provided to the money handling system, this money handling system can be operated by only the authorized operator stationed at the cash center <b>13</b>, without any authorized operator being present in the store.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">As described above, according to the money handling system of this embodiment, the money handling machine <b>10</b> includes the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> configured for dispensing the wrapped coins to the exterior of the system. In this case, the wrapped-coin storage cassettes (or wrapped-coin storage units) <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>g </i>are respectively arranged in the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b>, such that the wrapped coins can be stored in each of such storage cassettes <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>g </i>and dispensed therefrom. The central control unit provided to the cash center <b>13</b> and/or data center <b>14</b> can serve to transmit and receive the signal relative to each of the money storage unit <b>40</b> and wrapped-coin dispensing unit <b>50</b> in the money handling machine <b>10</b>. Accordingly, such provision of the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b> to the money handling machine <b>10</b>, with the signal transmission and reception of the signal being enabled between the central control unit and the wrapped-coin dispensing machine <b>50</b>, can achieve adequate preparation of the wrapped coins, in addition to the loose banknotes and/or loose coins, as the fund of the store, such as the changes or the like, in the money handling system.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A money handling system for depositing and/or dispensing money, the system comprising:
<claim-text>a money handling machine including a money storage unit configured for storing therein the money, a money recycling unit adapted for temporarily storing the money taken from the exterior to the interior of the money handling machine, in a recycling money storage unit, after the money is recognized, as well as adapted for feeding the money once stored in the recycling money storage unit to the money storage unit and/or dispensing such money to the exterior of the money handling machine, a wrapped-coin dispensing unit adapted for storing wrapped coins, in a wrapped-coin storage unit, as well as adapted for dispensing the wrapped coins stored in the wrapped-coin storage unit to the exterior of the money handling machine, and a control unit adapted for controlling the money storage unit, the money recycling unit and the wrapped-coin dispensing unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a central control unit connected, for communication, with the money handling machine and capable of performing remote control of the money handling machine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the central control unit is adapted for transmitting and receiving a signal relative to each of the money storage unit and the wrapped-coin dispensing unit, in the money handling machine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the money recycling unit is arranged to be controlled under a first control authority, while the money storage unit and wrapped-coin dispensing unit are respectively arranged to be controlled under a second control authority.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The money handling system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein, once the money stored in the recycling money storage unit of the money recycling unit is fed to the money storage unit, the control authority, under which such money is controlled, is changed from the first control authority to the second control authority, and then the total amount of money, corresponding to the money fed to the money storage unit, is deposited to an account of a financial institution related to the first control authority, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>once the wrapped coins stored in the wrapped-coin storage unit of the wrapped-coin dispensing unit is dispensed to the exterior of the money handling machine, the control authority, under which such wrapped coins are controlled, is changed from the second control authority to the first control authority, and then the total amount of money, corresponding to such wrapped coins, is withdrawn from the account of the financial institution related to the first control authority.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The money handling system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the money handling system further comprises an operation unit adapted for allowing an operator to select a plurality of operation modes including a money exchange mode, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>when the money exchange mode is selected via the operation unit, the control unit of the money handling machine serves to control the money storage unit to store therein the money deposited into the money handling machine, and then control the money recycling unit and/or the wrapped-coin dispensing unit to dispense the exchange money, and finally transmit information on this money exchange process to the central control unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The money handling system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the money handling system further comprises an operation unit adapted for allowing an operator to select a plurality of operation modes including a money exchange mode,</claim-text>
<claim-text>when the money exchange mode is selected via the operation unit, the control unit of the money handling machine serves to control the money storage unit to store therein the money deposited into the money handling machine, and then transmits information on this storage process to the central control unit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the central control unit serves to determine whether or not the information on the storage process is appropriate, and when determining that the information on the storage process is appropriate, the central control unit transmits information on the money exchange process to the control unit of the money handling machine, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the control unit of the money handling machine serves to control the money recycling unit and/or wrapped-coin dispensing unit to dispense the exchange money, based on the information on the money exchange process transmitted from the central control unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The money handling system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein, when the money exchange mode is selected via the operation unit, one or more denominations of exchange money and the number or total amount of money for each denomination of exchange money are inputted via the operation unit, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the control unit serves to control the money recycling unit and/or wrapped-coin dispensing unit to dispense the money of the inputted one or more denominations of exchange money, from the money handling machine, based on the inputted number or total amount of money.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The money handling system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the money handling system further comprises an operator identification unit adapted for identifying information on the operator, a memory unit adapted for storing therein information on one or more money exchange patterns, provided for each operator and including one or more denominations of exchange money and the number or total amount of money for each denomination of exchange money regarding the money exchange process, and a selection unit configured for allowing the operator to select the one or more money exchange patterns stored in the memory unit, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>once the information of the operator is identified by the operator identification unit, the control unit serves to control the money recycling unit and/or wrapped-coin dispensing unit to dispense the money of one or more denominations of exchange money in one money exchange pattern selected by the operator via the selection unit, among the one or more money exchange patterns stored in the memory unit, from the money handling machine, based on the number or total amount of the money stored in the memory unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The money handling system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein, when the money exchange mode is selected via the operation unit, one or more denominations of exchange money and the number or total amount of money for each denomination of exchange money are inputted via the operation unit, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the control unit serves to control the money recycling unit and/or the wrapped-coin dispensing unit to dispense the money of the inputted one or more denominations of exchange money, from the money handling machine, based on the inputted number or total amount of money.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The money handling system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the money handling system further comprises an operator identification unit adapted for identifying information on the operator, a memory unit adapted for storing therein information on one or more money exchange patterns, provided for each operator and including one or more denominations of exchange money and the number or total amount of money for each denomination of exchange money regarding the money exchange process, and a selection unit configured for allowing the operator to select the one or more money exchange patterns stored in the memory unit, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>once the information of the operator is identified by the operator identification unit, the control unit serves to control the money recycling unit and/or wrapped-coin dispensing unit to dispense the money of one or more denominations of exchange money in one money exchange pattern selected by the operator via the selection unit, among the one or more money exchange patterns stored in the memory unit, from the money handling machine, based on the number or total amount of the money stored in the memory unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
