<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626110-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626110</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13591967</doc-number>
<date>20120822</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>SG</country>
<doc-number>201106089-4</doc-number>
<date>20110823</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>16</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4553432</main-classification>
<further-classification>455574</further-classification>
<further-classification>370311</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e61">Circuit arrangement and receiver including the circuit arrangement</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4491978</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Nagata et al.</name>
<date>19850100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4553431</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6654604</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Yokogawa et al.</name>
<date>20031100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>455424</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6825718</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kang et al.</name>
<date>20041100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>330 86</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6973334</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Katagishi et al.</name>
<date>20051200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4555501</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7536153</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Uda et al.</name>
<date>20090500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>455334</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00006">
<othercit>Pletcher, et al., A 2GHz 52 &#x3bc;W Wake-Up Receiver with -72dBm Sensitivity Using Uncertain-IF Architecture, 2008 IEEE Solid-State Circuits Conference Digest of Technical Papers, 524 (with supplement) (IEEESSCC 2008).</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00007">
<othercit>Proakis, et al., Digital Communications, 5th ed., 257 &#x26; 321, 2007.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00008">
<othercit>Lee, The Design of CMOS Radio-Frequency Integrated Circuits, 2nd ed., 15, 2004.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00009">
<othercit>Otis, et al., A 400 &#x3bc;W-RX, 1.6mW-TX Super-Regenerative Transceiver for Wireless Sensor Networks, 2005 IEEE Solid-State Circuits Conference Digest of Technical Papers, 396 (IEEESSCC 2005).</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00010">
<othercit>Curty, et al., Remotely Powered Addressable UHF RFID Integrated System, 40 IEEE J. Solid-State Circuits, 2193 (2005).</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00011">
<othercit>Jonsson, et al., RF Detector for On-Chip Amplitude Measurements, 40 Electronics Letters, 1239 (2004).</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00012">
<othercit>Shaeffer, et al., A 1.5-V, 1.5-GHz CMOS Low Noise Amplifier, 32 IEEE J. Solid-State Circuits, 745 (1997).</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00013">
<othercit>Cook, et al., Low-Power 2.4-GHz Transceiver With Passive RX Front-End and 400-mV Supply, 41 IEEE J. Solid-State Circuits, 2757 (2006).</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00014">
<othercit>Drago, et al., A 2.4GHz 830pJ/Bit Duty-Cycled Wake-Up Receiver with -82dBm Sensitivity for Crystal-Less Wireless Sensor Nodes, IEEE Solid-State Circuits Conference Digital Technical Papers, 224 (IEEESSCC 2010).</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00015">
<othercit>Huang, et al., A 2.4GHz/915MHz 51&#x3bc;W Wake-Up Receiver with Offset and Noise Suppression, IEEE Solid-State Circuits Conference Digital Technical Papers, 222 (IEEESSCC 2010).</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00016">
<othercit>ZarLink ZL70101 Data Sheet (Dec. 2009).</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>455334</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4553431</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4553432</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>455574</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>370311</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>12</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130049839</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130228</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cheng</last-name>
<first-name>Kuang-Wei</first-name>
<address>
<city>Singapore</city>
<country>SG</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>SG</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Je</last-name>
<first-name>Minkyu</first-name>
<address>
<city>Singapore</city>
<country>SG</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>SG</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cheng</last-name>
<first-name>Kuang-Wei</first-name>
<address>
<city>Singapore</city>
<country>SG</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Je</last-name>
<first-name>Minkyu</first-name>
<address>
<city>Singapore</city>
<country>SG</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Crockett, Esq.</last-name>
<first-name>K. David</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Syrengelas, Esq.</last-name>
<first-name>Niky Economy</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="03" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Crockett &#x26; Crockett, PC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Agency for Science, Technology and Research</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Singapore</city>
<country>SG</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Vuong</last-name>
<first-name>Quochien B</first-name>
<department>2648</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A circuit arrangement is provided. The circuit arrangement includes a first input terminal and a second input terminal, a first transistor and a second transistor coupled to each other and to the first input terminal and the second input terminal, each of the first transistor and the second transistor having a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal and a control terminal, an input matching circuit coupled to the first input terminal, the second input terminal, the first transistor and the second transistor, a first resistive element coupled between the control terminal and the second controlled terminal of the first transistor, a second resistive element coupled between the control terminal and the second controlled terminal of the second transistor, and an output terminal coupled to the second controlled terminals of the first transistor and the second transistor.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="140.97mm" wi="231.22mm" file="US08626110-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="211.75mm" wi="181.61mm" file="US08626110-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="201.85mm" wi="189.91mm" file="US08626110-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="222.67mm" wi="181.10mm" file="US08626110-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="230.46mm" wi="149.86mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626110-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="225.81mm" wi="155.53mm" file="US08626110-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="227.92mm" wi="165.44mm" file="US08626110-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="224.79mm" wi="161.29mm" file="US08626110-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="217.00mm" wi="192.02mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626110-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of priority of Singapore patent application No. 201106089-4, filed 23 Aug. 2011, the content of it being hereby incorporated by reference in its entirety for all purposes.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Various embodiments relate to a circuit arrangement, and a receiver including the circuit arrangement.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Reducing power consumption is always of the essence to ubiquitous wireless communication. For a low activity rate system, the natural method to take this advantage is duty-cycling turning on and off the device to reduce average power consumption so as to increase the battery life time by orders of magnitude. Following this trend, an always-on wake-up receiver (WuRx) <b>100</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, becomes a firm demand used to continuously monitor the radio link for communication requests, e.g. between an antenna <b>102</b> and a data receiver <b>104</b>, to power on the receiver <b>104</b> which is in deep sleep mode. As shown by the timing diagram <b>106</b>, the wake-up receiver (WuRx) <b>100</b> continuously monitors the radio link or channel for communication requests for the main receiver <b>104</b>, except during the period when there are communication requests for transmitting and receiving data, as shown by the timing diagrams <b>108</b>, <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">This auxiliary receiver, in the form of the wake-up receiver (WuRx) <b>100</b>, breaks the trade-off between latency and average power consumption with only one receiver existing. Because the WuRx <b>100</b> is continuously monitoring the channel, its active power consumption must be very low. For those transceiver architectures that offer high efficiency communication but suffer from long synchronization time, such as radio-frequency identification (RFID), ultra-wideband (UWB) and electronic toll collection (ETC), WuRx are good candidates for wake-up based synchronization.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The early days' receiver was very simple, such as AM receivers, and can be implemented with an antenna, radio-frequency (RF) amplification and a nonlinear envelope detector to demodulate the signal. There are no power hungry local oscillators and mixers, which are found on the RF signal path, altogether in the frequency conversion counterpart nowadays. The envelope detector, usually implemented with a diode, is a popular choice because of its low power consumption. Envelope detectors have the inherent disadvantage of their quadratic nonlinearity that means a factor two drop in efficiency. Each drop of 10 dB in the input RF amplitude will result in a drop of 20 dB in the demodulated amplitude. This nature limits the sensitivity of the detector and of the overall receiver, owing to the signal dependent gain of the envelope detector. Indeed, the detector is the bottleneck of the receiver's sensitivity since it attenuates low level input signal and adds excessive noise. Not only high gain amplification for sensitivity but also narrowband filtering at RF for selectivity are required to overcome this limitation. However, the addition of RF gain stage is expensive from a power perspective. For example, more than 80% of the total receiver power is consumed at the gain stages, by the low noise amplifier (LNA), followed by the antenna and the channel-select amplifiers. The power breakdown illustrates the critical problem that large amounts of power are required at the RF gain stage. This prohibits further reduction in power consumption if the gain stage at higher carrier frequency is mandatory in certain applications.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">There is another simple and low power wireless receiver candidate, a passive RFID tag, which does not even have a power supply. The RFID tag is inactive until it rectifies the remote RF energy from the reader to power up its own electronics and then to decode an incoming signal. In this way, the operation of the tag is very similar to the desired functionality of the WuRx. However, the rectifier has several drawbacks. The two main loss factors are from the threshold voltage of MOS diode and input parasitic capacitance of the rectifier. Hence, the communication range for the passive RFID tag is short, usually in the range of couples of centimeters, and the sensitivity is limited, at about &#x2212;25.7 dBm on a 300 ohms antenna in the 2.4 GHz band. Although the RFID tag receiver features attractively low power consumption, a practical WuRx design will require much improvement to overcome the above addressed sensitivity and selectivity limitation.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Therefore, simple RFID receivers design does not satisfy the requirement for WuRx due to its low sensitivity, while conventional frequency conversion architectures are inherently too complicated and limited by power consumption. Clearly, the feasibility of implementing a WuRx receiver at high frequencies with low power dissipation represents a significant challenge.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to an embodiment, a circuit arrangement is provided. The circuit arrangement may include a first input terminal and a second input terminal, a first transistor and a second transistor, each of the first transistor and the second transistor having a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal and a control terminal, the first controlled terminal of the first transistor being coupled to the first controlled terminal of the second transistor, the control terminal of the first transistor being coupled to the first input terminal, the control terminal of the second transistor being coupled to the second input terminal, and the second controlled terminal of the first transistor being coupled to the second controlled terminal of the second transistor, an input matching circuit coupled to the first input terminal, the second input terminal, the first transistor and the second transistor, a first resistive element coupled between the control terminal of the first transistor and the second controlled terminal of the first transistor, a second resistive element coupled between the control terminal of the second transistor and the second controlled terminal of the second transistor, and an output terminal coupled to the second controlled terminal of the first transistor and the second controlled terminal of the second transistor, wherein the input matching circuit includes a first inductor, a second inductor, a third inductor, a first capacitor and a second capacitor, wherein the first inductor is coupled between the first input terminal and the control terminal of the first transistor, wherein the second inductor is coupled between the first controlled terminal of the first transistor and the first controlled terminal of the second transistor, wherein the third inductor is coupled between the second input terminal and the control terminal of the second transistor, wherein the first capacitor is coupled between the control terminal of the first transistor and the first controlled terminal of the first transistor, and wherein the second capacitor is coupled between the control terminal of the second transistor and the first controlled terminal of the second transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to an embodiment, a circuit arrangement is provided. The circuit arrangement may include a first input terminal and a second input terminal, a first transistor and a second transistor, each of the first transistor and the second transistor having a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal and a control terminal, the first controlled terminal of the first transistor being coupled to the first controlled terminal of the second transistor, the control terminal of the first transistor being coupled to the first input terminal, the control terminal of the second transistor being coupled to the second input terminal, and the second controlled terminal of the first transistor being coupled to the second controlled terminal of the second transistor, a third transistor and a fourth transistor, each of the third transistor and the fourth transistor having a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal and a control terminal, the first controlled terminal of the third transistor being coupled to the first controlled terminal of the fourth transistor, the control terminal of the third transistor being coupled to the first input terminal, the control terminal of the fourth transistor being coupled to the second input terminal, and the second controlled terminal of the third transistor being coupled to the second controlled terminal of the fourth transistor, an input matching circuit coupled to the first input terminal, the second input terminal, the first transistor, the second transistor, the third transistor and the fourth transistor, a first resistive element coupled between the control terminal of the first transistor and the second controlled terminal of the first transistor, a second resistive element coupled between the control terminal of the second transistor and the second controlled terminal of the second transistor, a third resistive element coupled between the control terminal of the third transistor and the second controlled terminal of the third transistor, a fourth resistive element coupled between the control terminal of the fourth transistor and the second controlled terminal of the fourth transistor, a first output terminal coupled to the second controlled terminal of the first transistor and the second controlled terminal of the second transistor, and a second output terminal coupled to the second controlled terminal of the third transistor and the second controlled terminal of the fourth transistor, wherein the input matching circuit includes a first inductor, a second inductor, a third inductor, a first capacitor, a second capacitor, a third capacitor and a fourth capacitor, wherein the first inductor includes a first terminal coupled to the first input terminal, and a second terminal coupled to the control terminal of the first transistor and the control terminal of the third transistor, wherein the second inductor includes a first terminal coupled to the first controlled terminal of the first transistor, the first controlled terminal of the second transistor, the first controlled terminal of the third transistor and the first controlled terminal of the fourth transistor, wherein the third inductor includes a first terminal coupled to the control terminal of the second transistor and the control terminal of the fourth transistor, and a second terminal coupled to the second input terminal, wherein the first capacitor is coupled between the control terminal of the first transistor and the first controlled terminal of the first transistor, wherein the second capacitor is coupled between the control terminal of the second transistor and the first controlled terminal of the second transistor, wherein the third capacitor is coupled between the control terminal of the third transistor and the first controlled terminal of the third transistor, and wherein the fourth capacitor is coupled between the control terminal of the fourth transistor and the first controlled terminal of the fourth transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to an embodiment, a receiver including the circuit arrangement as described herein is provided.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In the drawings, like reference characters generally refer to the same parts throughout the different views. The drawings are not necessarily to scale, emphasis instead generally being placed upon illustrating the principles of the invention. In the following description, various embodiments of the invention are described with reference to the following drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a timing diagram of an always-on wake-up receiver (WuRx) of the prior art.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> shows a schematic block diagram of a circuit arrangement, according to various embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref> shows a schematic block diagram of a circuit arrangement, according to various embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a schematic block diagram of a wake-up receiver (WuRx), according to various embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a schematic of a circuit arrangement for a radio frequency (RF) detector, according to various embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows a plot of detector transfer curve illustrating the relationship between the output voltage V<sub>out </sub>and the input voltage V<sub>RF </sub>for different carrier frequencies, according to various embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows a plot of simulated S<b>11</b> and gain of an input matching circuit, according to various embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows a plot of simulated and calculated detector voltage conversion gain, k, according to various embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> shows a plot of simulated detector output noise, according to various embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> shows a plot of detector sensitivity, according to various embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> shows a plot of detector signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) as a function of input power for different carrier frequencies, according to various embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> shows a schematic of a circuit arrangement for a radio frequency (RF) detector, according to various embodiments.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The following detailed description refers to the accompanying drawings that show, by way of illustration, specific details and embodiments in which the invention may be practiced. These embodiments are described in sufficient detail to enable those skilled in the art to practice the invention. Other embodiments may be utilized and structural, logical, and electrical changes may be made without departing from the scope of the invention. The various embodiments are not necessarily mutually exclusive, as some embodiments can be combined with one or more other embodiments to form new embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Embodiments described in the context of one of the devices are analogously valid for the other device.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Features that are described in the context of an embodiment may correspondingly be applicable to the same or similar features in the other embodiments. Features that are described in the context of an embodiment may correspondingly be applicable to the other embodiments, even if not explicitly described in these other embodiments. Furthermore, additions and/or combinations and/or alternatives as described for a feature in the context of an embodiment may correspondingly be applicable to the same or similar feature in the other embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In the context of various embodiments, the phrase &#x201c;at least substantially&#x201d; may include &#x201c;exactly&#x201d; and a variance of +/&#x2212;5% thereof. As an example and not limitations, &#x201c;A is at least substantially same as B&#x201d; may encompass embodiments where A is exactly the same as B, or where A may be within a variance of +/&#x2212;5%, for example of a value, of B, or vice versa.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In the context of various embodiments, the term &#x201c;about&#x201d; or &#x201c;approximately&#x201d; as applied to a numeric value encompasses the exact value and a variance of +/&#x2212;5% of the value.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">As used herein, the term &#x201c;and/or&#x201d; includes any and all combinations of one or more of the associated listed items.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Various embodiments may provide an approach based on an envelope detector with improved sensitivity and selectivity, without or with reduced at least some of the disadvantages of the prior art.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Various embodiments may provide circuit arrangements for active radio frequency (RF) detectors (e.g. envelope detectors). Various embodiments also provide an architecture, including a circuit arrangement, for wake-up receivers. The architecture includes an RF detector. The architecture may also include a continuous-time oversampling sigma-delta analogue-to-digital converter (CT &#x3a3;&#x394; ADC).</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Various embodiments may provide an active radio frequency (RF) detector in an ultra-low power wake-up receiver (WuRx), for example for applications including electronic toll collection (ETC) systems. The receiver or transceiver may be utilized at the RF front-ends, employing a 5.8 GHz carrier frequency and an on-off keyed (OOK) modulation in wake-up requests. Other amplitude modulations such as amplitude-shift keying (ASK) may be employed. The receiver or transceiver may be designed for a sensitivity of about &#x2212;70 dBm, operating at data rates up to 100 kbps, with a power consumption within 10 &#x3bc;W. However, it should be appreciated that other specifications and implementations of the RF detector and the WuRx may be possible, depending on the applications. As a further example, the WuRx of various embodiments may be employed as a universal remote control for existing receivers. In addition, the WuRx of various embodiments may be employed in wireless sensor networks or wireless communication systems. It should be appreciated that the WuRx of various embodiments may be employed in various applications which require &#x3bc;W-class power consumption.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Although other modulation methods such as frequency or phase modulation may provide better link efficiency, amplitude modulations such as the OOK allows substantial simplification of the RF demodulation, resulting in large power savings compared to more complex methods. Where a forward error correction (FEC) based correlation is also employed, a better robustness of the wake-up link may be achieved with minimum power overhead.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> shows a schematic block diagram of a circuit arrangement <b>200</b>, according to various embodiments. The circuit arrangement <b>200</b> may be employed or included in a receiver, for example a wake-up receiver. The circuit arrangement <b>200</b> includes a first input terminal <b>202</b> (e.g. <b>406</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) and a second input terminal <b>204</b> (e.g. <b>408</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), a first transistor <b>206</b><i>a </i>(e.g. MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) and a second transistor <b>206</b><i>b </i>(e.g. MN<b>2</b> <b>402</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), each of the first transistor <b>206</b><i>a </i>and the second transistor <b>206</b><i>b </i>having a first controlled terminal <b>208</b>, a second controlled terminal <b>210</b> and a control terminal <b>212</b>, the first controlled terminal <b>208</b><i>a </i>(e.g. <b>424</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the first transistor <b>206</b><i>a </i>being coupled to the first controlled terminal <b>208</b><i>b </i>(e.g. <b>424</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the second transistor <b>206</b><i>b</i>, the control terminal <b>212</b><i>a </i>(e.g. <b>428</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the first transistor <b>206</b><i>a </i>being coupled to the first input terminal <b>202</b>, the control terminal <b>212</b><i>b </i>(e.g. <b>428</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the second transistor <b>206</b><i>b </i>being coupled to the second input terminal <b>204</b>, and the second controlled terminal <b>210</b><i>a </i>(e.g. <b>426</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the first transistor <b>206</b><i>a </i>being coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>210</b><i>b </i>(e.g. <b>426</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the second transistor <b>206</b><i>b</i>. The circuit arrangement <b>200</b> further includes an input matching circuit <b>214</b> coupled to the first input terminal <b>202</b>, the second input terminal <b>204</b>, the first transistor <b>206</b><i>a </i>and the second transistor <b>206</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The circuit arrangement <b>200</b> further includes a first resistive element <b>216</b> (e.g. Rf<b>1</b> <b>430</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) coupled between the control terminal <b>212</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>206</b><i>a </i>and the second controlled terminal <b>210</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>206</b><i>a</i>, a second resistive element <b>218</b> (e.g. Rf<b>2</b> <b>432</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) coupled between the control terminal <b>212</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>206</b><i>b </i>and the second controlled terminal <b>210</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>206</b><i>b</i>, and an output terminal <b>220</b> (e.g. <b>452</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>210</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>206</b><i>a </i>and the second controlled terminal <b>210</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>206</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The input matching circuit <b>214</b> of the circuit arrangement <b>200</b> includes a first inductor <b>222</b> (e.g. Lg<b>1</b> <b>410</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), a second inductor <b>224</b> (e.g. Ls <b>412</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), a third inductor <b>226</b> (e.g. Lg<b>2</b> <b>414</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), a first capacitor <b>228</b> (e.g. Cex<b>1</b> <b>416</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) and a second capacitor <b>230</b> (e.g. Cex<b>2</b> <b>418</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), wherein the first inductor <b>222</b> is coupled between the first input terminal <b>202</b> and the control terminal <b>212</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>206</b><i>a</i>, wherein the second inductor <b>224</b> is coupled between the first controlled terminal <b>208</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>206</b><i>a </i>and the first controlled terminal <b>208</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>206</b><i>b</i>, wherein the third inductor <b>226</b> is coupled between the second input terminal <b>204</b> and the control terminal <b>212</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>206</b><i>b</i>, wherein the first capacitor <b>228</b> is coupled between the control terminal <b>212</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>206</b><i>a </i>and the first controlled terminal <b>208</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>206</b><i>a</i>, and wherein the second capacitor <b>230</b> is coupled between the control terminal <b>212</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>206</b><i>b </i>and the first controlled terminal <b>208</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>206</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In other words, the circuit arrangement <b>200</b> includes a pair of input terminals (<b>202</b>, <b>204</b>), a pair of transistors (e.g. NMOS transistors) (<b>206</b><i>a</i>, <b>206</b><i>b</i>), an input matching circuit (<b>214</b>) (or LC network/circuit) coupled to the pair of input terminals and the pair of transistors, a pair of resistive elements (<b>216</b>, <b>218</b>) and an output terminal (<b>220</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Each of the pair of transistors includes a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal and a control terminal, where the first controlled terminals of the pair of transistors are coupled to each other, the second controlled terminals of the pair of transistors are coupled to each other, the control terminal of one of the transistors is coupled to one of the input terminals, and the control terminal of the other transistor is coupled to the other input terminal. One of the resistive elements is coupled to the control terminal and the second controlled terminal of one transistor, while the other resistive element is coupled to the control terminal and the second controlled terminal of the other transistor. The output terminal is coupled to the second controlled terminals of the pair of transistors.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The input matching circuit includes a first inductor coupled to one input terminal and the control terminal of one transistor, a second inductor coupled to the first controlled terminals of the pair of transistors, a third inductor coupled to the other input terminal and the control terminal of the other transistor, a first capacitor coupled to the control terminal and the first controlled terminal of one transistor, and a second capacitor coupled to the control terminal and the first controlled terminal of the other transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, the line represented as <b>235</b> is illustrated to show the relationship among the first controlled terminal <b>208</b><i>a</i>, the second controlled terminal <b>210</b><i>a </i>and the control terminal <b>212</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>206</b><i>a</i>, which may include electrical coupling and/or mechanical coupling, the line represented as <b>236</b> is illustrated to show the relationship among the first controlled terminal <b>208</b><i>b</i>, the second controlled terminal <b>210</b><i>b </i>and the control terminal <b>212</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>206</b><i>b</i>, which may include electrical coupling and/or mechanical coupling, the line represented as <b>237</b> is illustrated to show the relationship among the first inductor <b>222</b>, the second inductor <b>224</b>, the third inductor <b>226</b>, the first capacitor <b>228</b> and the second capacitor <b>230</b> of the input matching circuit <b>214</b>, which may include electrical coupling and/or mechanical coupling, while the line represented as <b>238</b> is illustrated to show the relationship among the first input terminal <b>202</b>, the second input terminal <b>204</b>, the first transistor <b>206</b><i>a</i>, the second transistor <b>206</b><i>b</i>, the input matching circuit <b>214</b>, the first resistive element <b>216</b>, the second resistive element <b>218</b> and the output terminal <b>220</b>, which may include electrical coupling and/or mechanical coupling.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In various embodiments, the circuit arrangement <b>200</b> may further include a third capacitor (e.g. C<b>1</b> <b>420</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) coupled in series with the first input terminal <b>202</b> and the first inductor <b>222</b> (e.g. coupled between the first input terminal <b>202</b> and the first inductor <b>222</b>), and a fourth capacitor (e.g. C<b>2</b> <b>422</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) coupled in series with the second input terminal <b>204</b> and the third inductor <b>226</b> (e.g. coupled between the second input terminal <b>204</b> and the third inductor <b>226</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In various embodiments, the first resistive element <b>216</b> (e.g. Rf<b>1</b> <b>430</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) may include a third transistor (e.g. MPR<b>1</b> <b>434</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) and a fourth transistor (e.g. MPR<b>2</b> <b>434</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), each of the third transistor and the fourth transistor having a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal, a control terminal and a bulk terminal, wherein the first controlled terminal (e.g. <b>436</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the third transistor is coupled to the first controlled terminal (e.g. <b>436</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the fourth transistor, wherein the second controlled terminal (e.g. <b>438</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the third transistor is coupled to the control terminal <b>212</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>206</b><i>a</i>, and the second controlled terminal (e.g. <b>438</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the fourth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>210</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>206</b><i>a</i>, wherein the bulk terminal (e.g. <b>441</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the third transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the third transistor, and the bulk terminal (e.g. <b>441</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the fourth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the fourth transistor, and wherein the control terminal (e.g. <b>440</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the third transistor is coupled to the control terminal (e.g. <b>440</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the fourth transistor, the first controlled terminal of the third transistor and the first controlled terminal of the fourth transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In various embodiments, the second resistive element <b>218</b> (e.g. Rf<b>2</b> <b>432</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) may include a fifth transistor (e.g. MPR<b>3</b> <b>442</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) and a sixth transistor (e.g. MPR<b>4</b> <b>442</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), each of the fifth transistor and the sixth transistor having a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal, a control terminal and a bulk terminal, wherein the first controlled terminal (e.g. <b>444</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the fifth transistor is coupled to the first controlled terminal (e.g. <b>444</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the sixth transistor, wherein the second controlled terminal (e.g. <b>446</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the fifth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>210</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>206</b><i>b</i>, and the second controlled terminal (e.g. <b>446</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the sixth transistor is coupled to the control terminal <b>212</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>206</b><i>b</i>, wherein the bulk terminal (e.g. <b>450</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the fifth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the fifth transistor, and the bulk terminal (e.g. <b>450</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the sixth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the sixth transistor, and wherein the control terminal (e.g. <b>448</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the fifth transistor is coupled to the control terminal (e.g. <b>448</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the sixth transistor, the first controlled terminal of the fifth transistor and the first controlled terminal of the sixth transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In various embodiments, the circuit arrangement <b>200</b> may further include a current mirror circuit coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>210</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>206</b><i>a</i>, the second controlled terminal <b>210</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>206</b><i>b</i>, and the output terminal <b>220</b>. The current mirror circuit may include a seventh transistor (e.g. MP<b>2</b> <b>462</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) and an eighth transistor (e.g. MP<b>1</b> <b>462</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), each of the seventh transistor and the eighth transistor having a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal and a control terminal, wherein the first controlled terminal (e.g. <b>464</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the seventh transistor and the first controlled terminal (e.g. <b>464</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the eighth transistor are coupled to a first voltage reference point (e.g. V<sub>1</sub>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), wherein the control terminal (e.g. <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the seventh transistor is coupled to the control terminal (e.g. <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the eighth transistor, wherein the second controlled terminal (e.g. <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the seventh transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>210</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>206</b><i>a</i>, the second controlled terminal <b>210</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>206</b><i>b </i>and the output terminal <b>220</b>, and wherein the second controlled terminal (e.g. <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the eighth transistor is coupled to the control terminal of the seventh transistor and the control terminal of the eighth transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In various embodiments, the circuit arrangement <b>200</b> may further include a current source (e.g. <b>470</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) having a first terminal and a second terminal, wherein the first terminal of the current source is coupled to the control terminal of the seventh transistor, the control terminal of the eighth transistor and the second controlled terminal of the eighth transistor, and the second terminal of the current source is coupled to a second voltage reference point (e.g. V<sub>2</sub>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In various embodiments, the circuit arrangement <b>200</b> may further include a fifth capacitor (e.g. Co <b>454</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) having a first terminal and a second terminal, wherein the first terminal of the fifth capacitor is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>210</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>206</b><i>a</i>, the second controlled terminal <b>210</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>206</b><i>b</i>, the output terminal <b>220</b> and the second controlled terminal of the seventh transistor, and the second terminal of the fifth capacitor is coupled to the second voltage reference point (e.g. V<sub>2</sub>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In various embodiments, the second inductor may be further coupled to the second voltage reference point.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In the context of various embodiments of the circuit arrangement <b>200</b>, the first voltage reference point may be a power supply line. In the context of various embodiments, the second voltage reference point may be a ground terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In the context of various embodiments, the circuit arrangement <b>200</b> may include, may be part of or may be an envelope detector. The envelope detector or RF detector may be part of a receiver (e.g. wake-up receiver).</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Various embodiments may provide a receiver including the circuit arrangement <b>200</b> as described above. The receiver may be or may include a wake-up receiver.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Various embodiments may provide a transceiver including the circuit arrangement <b>200</b> as described above. The transceiver may include a receiver (e.g. a wake-up receiver) having the circuit arrangement <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref> shows a schematic block diagram of a circuit arrangement <b>240</b>, according to various embodiments. The circuit arrangement <b>240</b> may be employed or included in a receiver, for example a wake-up receiver. The circuit arrangement <b>240</b> includes a first input terminal <b>242</b> (e.g. <b>1106</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) and a second input terminal <b>244</b> (e.g. <b>1108</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>), a first transistor <b>246</b><i>a </i>(e.g. MN<b>1</b> <b>1102</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) and a second transistor <b>246</b><i>b </i>(e.g. MN<b>2</b> <b>1102</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>), each of the first transistor <b>246</b><i>a </i>and the second transistor <b>246</b><i>b </i>having a first controlled terminal <b>248</b>, a second controlled terminal <b>250</b> and a control terminal <b>252</b>, the first controlled terminal <b>248</b><i>a </i>(e.g. <b>1118</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the first transistor <b>246</b><i>a </i>being coupled to the first controlled terminal <b>248</b><i>b </i>(e.g. <b>1118</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the second transistor <b>246</b><i>b</i>, the control terminal <b>252</b><i>a </i>(e.g. <b>1122</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the first transistor <b>246</b><i>a </i>being coupled to the first input terminal <b>242</b>, the control terminal <b>252</b><i>b </i>(e.g. <b>1122</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the second transistor <b>246</b><i>b </i>being coupled to the second input terminal <b>244</b>, and the second controlled terminal <b>250</b><i>a </i>(e.g. <b>1120</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the first transistor <b>246</b><i>a </i>being coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>250</b><i>b </i>(e.g. <b>1120</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the second transistor <b>246</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The circuit arrangement <b>240</b> further includes a third transistor <b>254</b><i>a </i>(e.g. MP<b>1</b> <b>1124</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) and a fourth transistor <b>254</b><i>b </i>(e.g. MP<b>2</b> <b>1124</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>), each of the third transistor <b>254</b><i>a </i>and the fourth transistor <b>254</b><i>b </i>having a first controlled terminal <b>256</b>, a second controlled terminal <b>258</b> and a control terminal <b>260</b>, the first controlled terminal <b>256</b><i>a </i>(e.g. <b>1126</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the third transistor <b>254</b><i>a </i>being coupled to the first controlled terminal <b>256</b><i>b </i>(e.g. <b>1126</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the fourth transistor <b>254</b><i>b</i>, the control terminal <b>260</b><i>a </i>(e.g. <b>1130</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the third transistor <b>254</b><i>a </i>being coupled to the first input terminal <b>242</b>, the control terminal <b>260</b><i>b </i>(e.g. <b>1130</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the fourth transistor <b>254</b><i>b </i>being coupled to the second input terminal <b>244</b>, and the second controlled terminal <b>258</b><i>a </i>(e.g. <b>1128</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the third transistor <b>254</b><i>a </i>being coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>258</b><i>b </i>(e.g. <b>1128</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the fourth transistor <b>254</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The circuit arrangement <b>240</b> further includes an input matching circuit <b>262</b> coupled to the first input terminal <b>242</b>, the second input terminal <b>244</b>, the first transistor <b>246</b><i>a</i>, the second transistor <b>246</b><i>b</i>, the third transistor <b>254</b><i>a </i>and the fourth transistor <b>254</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The circuit arrangement <b>240</b> further includes a first resistive element <b>264</b> (e.g. Rf<b>1</b> <b>1132</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) coupled between the control terminal <b>252</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>246</b><i>a </i>and the second controlled terminal <b>250</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>246</b><i>a</i>, a second resistive element <b>266</b> (e.g. Rf<b>2</b> <b>1134</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) coupled between the control terminal <b>252</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>246</b><i>b </i>and the second controlled terminal <b>250</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>246</b><i>b</i>, a third resistive element <b>268</b> (e.g. Rf<b>3</b> <b>1136</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) coupled between the control terminal <b>260</b><i>a </i>of the third transistor <b>254</b><i>a </i>and the second controlled terminal <b>258</b><i>a </i>of the third transistor <b>254</b><i>a</i>, a fourth resistive element <b>270</b> (e.g. Rf<b>4</b> <b>1138</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) coupled between the control terminal <b>260</b><i>b </i>of the fourth transistor <b>254</b><i>b </i>and the second controlled terminal <b>258</b><i>b </i>of the fourth transistor <b>254</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The circuit arrangement <b>240</b> further includes a first output terminal <b>272</b> (e.g. <b>1182</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>250</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>246</b><i>a </i>and the second controlled terminal <b>250</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>246</b><i>b</i>, and a second output terminal <b>274</b> (e.g. <b>1184</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>258</b><i>a </i>of the third transistor <b>254</b><i>a </i>and the second controlled terminal <b>258</b><i>b </i>of the fourth transistor <b>254</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The input matching circuit <b>262</b> of the circuit arrangement <b>240</b> includes a first inductor <b>276</b> (e.g. Lg<b>1</b> <b>1110</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>), a second inductor <b>278</b> (e.g. Ls <b>1111</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>), a third inductor <b>280</b> (e.g. Lg<b>2</b> <b>1112</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>), a first capacitor <b>282</b> (e.g. Cex<b>1</b> <b>1113</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>), a second capacitor <b>284</b> (e.g. Cex<b>2</b> <b>1114</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>), a third capacitor <b>286</b> (e.g. Cex<b>3</b> <b>1115</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) and a fourth capacitor <b>288</b> (e.g. Cex<b>4</b> <b>1116</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>), wherein the first inductor <b>276</b> includes a first terminal coupled to the first input terminal <b>242</b>, and a second terminal coupled to the control terminal <b>252</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>246</b><i>a </i>and the control terminal <b>260</b><i>a </i>of the third transistor <b>254</b><i>a</i>, wherein the second inductor <b>278</b> includes a first terminal coupled to the first controlled terminal <b>248</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>246</b><i>a</i>, the first controlled terminal <b>248</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>246</b><i>b</i>, the first controlled terminal <b>256</b><i>a </i>of the third transistor <b>254</b><i>a </i>and the first controlled terminal <b>256</b><i>b </i>of the fourth transistor <b>254</b><i>b</i>, wherein the third inductor <b>280</b> includes a first terminal coupled to the control terminal <b>252</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>246</b><i>b </i>and the control terminal <b>260</b><i>b </i>of the fourth transistor <b>254</b><i>b</i>, and a second terminal coupled to the second input terminal <b>244</b>, wherein the first capacitor <b>282</b> is coupled between the control terminal <b>252</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>246</b><i>a </i>and the first controlled terminal <b>248</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>246</b><i>a</i>, wherein the second capacitor <b>284</b> is coupled between the control terminal <b>252</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>246</b><i>b </i>and the first controlled terminal <b>248</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>246</b><i>b</i>, wherein the third capacitor <b>286</b> is coupled between the control terminal <b>260</b><i>a </i>of the third transistor <b>254</b><i>a </i>and the first controlled terminal <b>256</b><i>a </i>of the third transistor <b>254</b><i>a</i>, and wherein the fourth capacitor <b>288</b> is coupled between the control terminal <b>260</b><i>b </i>of the fourth transistor <b>254</b><i>b </i>and the first controlled terminal <b>256</b><i>b </i>of the fourth transistor <b>254</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">In other words, the circuit arrangement <b>240</b> includes a pair of input terminals (<b>242</b>, <b>244</b>), a first pair of transistors (e.g. NMOS transistors) (<b>246</b><i>a</i>, <b>246</b><i>b</i>), a second pair of transistors (e.g. PMOS transistors) (<b>254</b><i>a</i>, <b>254</b><i>b</i>), an input matching circuit (<b>262</b>) (or LC network/circuit) coupled to the pair of input terminals, the first pair of transistors and the second pair of transistors, four resistive elements (<b>264</b>, <b>266</b>, <b>268</b>, <b>270</b>) and a pair of output terminals (<b>272</b>, <b>274</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Each transistor of the first pair of transistors includes a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal and a control terminal, where the first controlled terminals of the first pair of transistors are coupled to each other, the second controlled terminals of the first pair of transistors are coupled to each other, the control terminal of one of the transistors is coupled to one of the input terminals, and the control terminal of the other transistor is coupled to the other input terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Each transistor of the second pair of transistors includes a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal and a control terminal, where the first controlled terminals of the second pair of transistors are coupled to each other, the second controlled terminals of the second pair of transistors are coupled to each other, the control terminal of one of the transistors is coupled to one of the input terminals, and the control terminal of the other transistor is coupled to the other input terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">A first resistive element of the four resistive elements is coupled to the control terminal and the second controlled terminal of one transistor of the first pair of transistors. A second resistive element coupled to the control terminal and the second controlled terminal of the other transistor of the first pair of transistors. A third resistive element is coupled to the control terminal and the second controlled terminal of one transistor of the second pair of transistors. A fourth resistive element is coupled to the control terminal and the second controlled terminal of the other transistor of the second pair of transistors.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">One of the output terminals is coupled to the second controlled terminals of the first pair of transistors, while the other output terminal is coupled to the second controlled terminals of the second pair of transistors.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The input matching circuit includes a first inductor coupled to one input terminal, the control terminal of one transistor of the first pair of transistors and the control terminal of one transistor of the second pair of transistors, a second inductor coupled to the first controlled terminals of the first and second pairs of transistors, a third inductor coupled to the other input terminal, the control terminal of the other transistor of the first pair of transistors and the control terminal of the other transistor of the second pair of transistors, a first capacitor coupled to the control terminal and the first controlled terminal of one transistor of the first pair of transistors, a second capacitor coupled to the control terminal and the first controlled terminal of the other transistor of the first pair of transistors, a third capacitor coupled to the control terminal and the first controlled terminal of one transistor of the second pair of transistors, and a fourth capacitor coupled to the control terminal and the first controlled terminal of the other transistor of the second pair of transistors.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>, the line represented as <b>290</b> is illustrated to show the relationship among the first controlled terminal <b>248</b><i>a</i>, the second controlled terminal <b>250</b><i>a </i>and the control terminal <b>252</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>246</b><i>a</i>, which may include electrical coupling and/or mechanical coupling, the line represented as <b>291</b> is illustrated to show the relationship among the first controlled terminal <b>248</b><i>b</i>, the second controlled terminal <b>250</b><i>b </i>and the control terminal <b>252</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>246</b><i>b</i>, which may include electrical coupling and/or mechanical coupling, the line represented as <b>292</b> is illustrated to show the relationship among the first controlled terminal <b>256</b><i>a</i>, the second controlled terminal <b>258</b><i>a </i>and the control terminal <b>260</b><i>a </i>of the third transistor <b>254</b><i>a</i>, which may include electrical coupling and/or mechanical coupling, the line represented as <b>293</b> is illustrated to show the relationship among the first controlled terminal <b>256</b><i>b</i>, the second controlled terminal <b>258</b><i>b </i>and the control terminal <b>260</b><i>b </i>of the fourth transistor <b>254</b><i>b</i>, which may include electrical coupling and/or mechanical coupling, the line represented as <b>294</b> is illustrated to show the relationship among the first inductor <b>276</b>, the second inductor <b>278</b>, the third inductor <b>280</b>, the first capacitor <b>282</b>, the second capacitor <b>284</b>, the third capacitor <b>286</b> and the fourth capacitor <b>288</b> of the input matching circuit <b>262</b>, which may include electrical coupling and/or mechanical coupling, while the line represented as <b>295</b> is illustrated to show the relationship among the first input terminal <b>242</b>, the second input terminal <b>244</b>, the first transistor <b>246</b><i>a</i>, the second transistor <b>246</b><i>b</i>, the third transistor <b>254</b><i>a</i>, the fourth transistor <b>254</b><i>b</i>, the input matching circuit <b>262</b>, the first resistive element <b>264</b>, the second resistive element <b>266</b>, the third resistive element <b>268</b>, the fourth resistive element <b>270</b>, the first output terminal <b>272</b> and the second output terminal <b>274</b>, which may include electrical coupling and/or mechanical coupling.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">In various embodiments, the input matching circuit <b>262</b> may further include a fifth capacitor (e.g. Cs <b>1117</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) having a first terminal and a second terminal, wherein the first terminal of the fifth capacitor is coupled to a second terminal of the second inductor <b>278</b> of the input matching circuit <b>262</b>, and the second terminal of the fifth capacitor is coupled to a first voltage reference point (e.g. V<sub>1</sub>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In various embodiments, the circuit arrangement <b>240</b> may further include a sixth capacitor (e.g. C<b>1</b> <b>1178</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) coupled in series with the first inductor <b>276</b> and the control terminal <b>252</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>246</b><i>a </i>(e.g. coupled between the second terminal of the first inductor <b>276</b> and the control terminal <b>252</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>246</b><i>a</i>), a seventh capacitor (e.g. C<b>2</b> <b>1179</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) coupled in series with the third inductor <b>280</b> and the control terminal <b>252</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>246</b><i>b </i>(e.g. coupled between the first terminal of the third inductor <b>280</b> and the control terminal <b>252</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>246</b><i>b</i>), an eighth capacitor (e.g. C<b>3</b> <b>1180</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) coupled in series with the first inductor <b>276</b> and the control terminal <b>260</b><i>a </i>of the third transistor <b>254</b><i>a </i>(e.g. coupled between the second terminal of the first inductor <b>276</b> and the control terminal <b>260</b><i>a </i>of the third transistor <b>254</b><i>a</i>), and a ninth capacitor (e.g. C<b>4</b> <b>1181</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) coupled in series with the third inductor <b>280</b> and the control terminal <b>260</b><i>b </i>of the fourth transistor <b>254</b><i>b </i>(e.g. coupled between the first terminal of the third inductor <b>280</b> and the control terminal <b>260</b><i>b </i>of the fourth transistor <b>254</b><i>b</i>).</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">In various embodiments, the first resistive element <b>264</b> (e.g. Rf<b>1</b> <b>1132</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) includes a fifth transistor (e.g. MPR<b>1</b> <b>1140</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) and a sixth transistor (e.g. MPR<b>2</b> <b>1140</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>), each of the fifth transistor and the sixth transistor having a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal, a control terminal and a bulk terminal, wherein the first controlled terminal (e.g. <b>1142</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the fifth transistor is coupled to the first controlled terminal (e.g. <b>1142</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the sixth transistor, wherein the second controlled terminal (e.g. <b>1144</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the fifth transistor is coupled to the control terminal <b>252</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>246</b><i>a</i>, and the second controlled terminal (e.g. <b>1144</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the sixth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>250</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>246</b><i>a</i>, wherein the control terminal (e.g. <b>1146</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the fifth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the fifth transistor, and the control terminal (e.g. <b>1146</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the sixth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the sixth transistor, and wherein the bulk terminal (e.g. <b>1147</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the fifth transistor is coupled to the bulk terminal (e.g. <b>1147</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the sixth transistor, the first controlled terminal of the fifth transistor and the first controlled terminal of the sixth transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">In various embodiments, the second resistive element <b>266</b> (e.g. Rf<b>2</b> <b>1134</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) includes a seventh transistor (e.g. MPR<b>3</b> <b>1148</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) and an eighth transistor (e.g. MPR<b>4</b> <b>1148</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>), each of the seventh transistor and the eighth transistor having a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal, a control terminal and a bulk terminal, wherein the first controlled terminal (e.g. <b>1150</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the seventh transistor is coupled to the first controlled terminal (e.g. <b>1150</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the eighth transistor, wherein the second controlled terminal (e.g. <b>1152</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the seventh transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>250</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>246</b><i>b</i>, and the second controlled terminal (e.g. <b>1152</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the eighth transistor is coupled to the control terminal <b>252</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>246</b><i>b</i>, wherein the control terminal (e.g. <b>1154</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the seventh transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the seventh transistor, and the control terminal (e.g. <b>1154</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the eighth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the eighth transistor, and wherein the bulk terminal (e.g. <b>1156</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the seventh transistor is coupled to the bulk terminal (e.g. <b>1156</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the eighth transistor, the first controlled terminal of the seventh transistor and the first controlled terminal of the eighth transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">In various embodiments, the third resistive element <b>268</b> (e.g. Rf<b>3</b> <b>1136</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) includes a ninth transistor (e.g. MPR<b>5</b> <b>1158</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) and a tenth transistor (e.g. MPR<b>6</b> <b>1158</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>), each of the ninth transistor and the tenth transistor having a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal, a control terminal and a bulk terminal, wherein the first controlled terminal (e.g. <b>1160</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the ninth transistor is coupled to the first controlled terminal (e.g. <b>1160</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the tenth transistor, wherein the second controlled terminal (e.g. <b>1162</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the ninth transistor is coupled to the control terminal <b>260</b><i>a </i>of the third transistor <b>254</b><i>a</i>, and the second controlled terminal (e.g. <b>1162</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the tenth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>258</b><i>a </i>of the third transistor <b>254</b><i>a</i>, wherein the control terminal (e.g. <b>1164</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the ninth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the ninth transistor, and the control terminal (e.g. <b>1164</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the tenth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the tenth transistor, and wherein the bulk terminal (e.g. <b>1166</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the ninth transistor is coupled to the bulk terminal (e.g. <b>1166</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the tenth transistor, the first controlled terminal of the ninth transistor and the first controlled terminal of the tenth transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">In various embodiments, the fourth resistive element <b>270</b> (e.g. Rf<b>4</b> <b>1138</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) includes an eleventh transistor (e.g. MPR<b>7</b> <b>1168</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) and a twelfth transistor (e.g. MPR<b>8</b> <b>1168</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>), each of the eleventh transistor and the twelfth transistor having a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal, a control terminal and a bulk terminal, wherein the first controlled terminal (e.g. <b>1170</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the eleventh transistor is coupled to the first controlled terminal (e.g. <b>1170</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the twelfth transistor, wherein the second controlled terminal (e.g. <b>1172</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the eleventh transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>258</b><i>b </i>of the fourth transistor <b>254</b><i>b</i>, and the second controlled terminal (e.g. <b>1172</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the twelfth transistor is coupled to the control terminal <b>260</b><i>b </i>of the fourth transistor <b>254</b><i>b</i>, wherein the control terminal (e.g. <b>1174</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the eleventh transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the eleventh transistor, and the control terminal (e.g. <b>1174</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the twelfth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the twelfth transistor, and wherein the bulk terminal (e.g. <b>1176</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the eleventh transistor is coupled to the bulk terminal (e.g. <b>1176</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the twelfth transistor, the first controlled terminal of the eleventh transistor and the first controlled terminal of the twelfth transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">In various embodiments, the circuit arrangement <b>240</b> may further include a current source (e.g. <b>1186</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) having a first terminal and a second terminal, wherein the first terminal of the current source is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>250</b><i>a </i>of the first transistor <b>246</b><i>a</i>, the second controlled terminal <b>250</b><i>b </i>of the second transistor <b>246</b><i>b </i>and the first output terminal <b>272</b>, and the second terminal of the current source is coupled to a second voltage reference point (e.g. V<sub>2</sub>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">In various embodiments, the circuit arrangement <b>240</b> may further include a tenth capacitor (e.g. Con <b>1188</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) having a first terminal and a second terminal, wherein the first terminal of the tenth capacitor is coupled to the first terminal of the current source and the first output terminal <b>272</b>, and the second terminal of the tenth capacitor is coupled to the first voltage reference point (e.g. V<sub>1</sub>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">In various embodiments, the circuit arrangement <b>240</b> may further include a resistor (e.g. R<sub>REF </sub><b>1190</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) having a first terminal and a second terminal, wherein the first terminal of the resistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>258</b><i>a </i>of the third transistor <b>254</b><i>a</i>, the second controlled terminal <b>258</b><i>b </i>of the fourth transistor <b>254</b><i>b </i>and the second output terminal <b>274</b>, and the second terminal of the resistor is coupled to a first voltage reference point (e.g. V<sub>1</sub>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">In various embodiments, the circuit arrangement <b>240</b> may further include an eleventh capacitor (e.g. Cop <b>1192</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) having a first terminal and a second terminal, wherein the first terminal of the eleventh capacitor is coupled to the first terminal of the resistor and the second output terminal <b>274</b>, and the second terminal of the eleventh capacitor is coupled to the first voltage reference point (e.g. V<sub>1</sub>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">In the context of various embodiments of the circuit arrangement <b>240</b>, the first voltage reference point may be a ground terminal. In the context of various embodiments, the second voltage reference point may be a power supply line.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">In the context of various embodiments, the circuit arrangement <b>240</b> may include, may be part of or may be an envelope detector. The envelope detector or RF detector may be part of a receiver (e.g. wake-up receiver).</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">Various embodiments may provide a receiver including the circuit arrangement <b>240</b> as described above. The receiver may be or may include a wake-up receiver.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">Various embodiments may provide a transceiver including the circuit arrangement <b>240</b> as described above. The transceiver may include a receiver (e.g. a wake-up receiver) having the circuit arrangement <b>240</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">In the context of various embodiments, each of the first transistor (e.g. <b>206</b><i>a</i>, <b>246</b><i>a</i>) and the second transistor (e.g. <b>206</b><i>b</i>, <b>246</b><i>b</i>) may be or may include an n-type metal oxide semiconductor field effect transistor (e.g. NMOS transistor).</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">In the context of various embodiments, each of the third transistor (e.g. <b>254</b><i>a</i>) and the fourth transistor (e.g. <b>254</b><i>b</i>) may be or may include a p-type metal oxide semiconductor field effect transistor (e.g. PMOS transistor).</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">In the context of various embodiments, each of the fifth transistor and the sixth transistor may be or may include a p-type metal oxide semiconductor field effect transistor (e.g. PMOS transistor).</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">In the context of various embodiments, each of the seventh transistor and the eighth transistor may be or may include a p-type metal oxide semiconductor field effect transistor (e.g. PMOS transistor).</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">In the context of various embodiments, each of the ninth transistor and the tenth transistor may be or may include a p-type metal oxide semiconductor field effect transistor (e.g. PMOS transistor).</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">In the context of various embodiments, each of the eleventh transistor and the twelfth transistor may be or may include a p-type metal oxide semiconductor field effect transistor (e.g. PMOS transistor).</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">In the context of various embodiments, the term &#x201c;transistor&#x201d; may include a field effect transistor (FET), such as one of a metal oxide semiconductor field effect transistor (MOSFET) (e.g. an n-channel MOS transistor (NMOS), a p-channel MOS transistor (PMOS)), a metal-insulator field effect transistor (MISFET) or a metal-semiconductor field effect transistor (MESFET).</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">In the context of various embodiments, the term &#x201c;controlled terminal&#x201d; may include or may mean a &#x201c;source/drain terminal&#x201d;, such that the term &#x201c;first controlled terminal&#x201d; may mean a &#x201c;first source/drain terminal&#x201d; and the term &#x201c;second controlled terminal&#x201d; may mean a &#x201c;second source/drain terminal&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">In the context of various embodiments, the terms &#x201c;controlled terminal&#x201d; or &#x201c;source/drain terminal&#x201d; of a transistor may refer to a source terminal or a drain terminal. As the source terminal and the drain terminal of a transistor are generally fabricated such that these terminals are geometrically symmetrical, these terminals may be collectively referred to as controlled terminals or source/drain terminals. In various embodiments, a particular controlled terminal or source/drain terminal may be a &#x201c;source&#x201d; terminal or a &#x201c;drain&#x201d; terminal depending on the voltage to be applied to that terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">In the context of various embodiments, the term &#x201c;control terminal&#x201d; may include or may mean a gate terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">In the context of various embodiments, the term &#x201c;bulk terminal&#x201d; may mean a substrate terminal for N-channel MOS transistors and a well terminal for P-channel MOS transistors.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">In the context of various embodiments, the term &#x201c;matching circuit&#x201d; may include or may mean an impedance matching circuit that at least substantially matches the impedance of one part of a circuit (e.g. a source) with the impedance of another part of the circuit (e.g. a load) so as to maximize the power transfer between the two parts of the circuit or minimize reflections from the load. The matching circuit may include one or more inductors (L) and/or one or more capacitors (C). Therefore, the matching circuit may be an LC circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">In the context of various embodiments, the term &#x201c;envelope detector&#x201d; may include or may mean a circuit that receives an input signal and provides an output which is the envelope of the input signal.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">In the context of various embodiments, the term &#x201c;current source&#x201d; may include, for example, a direct or indirect current source, or a current mirror, or a constant or variable current source, or a voltage bias.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">In the context of various embodiments, the term &#x201c;current mirror circuit&#x201d; may mean a circuit that serves as a current regulator, where the current flowing in one half or branch of the circuit is used to control the current flow in the other half or branch of the circuit. The current amplitude flowing through both halves or branches is at least substantially same.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">In the context of various embodiments, a reference to the term &#x201c;coupled&#x201d; with regard to two or more components may include a reference to &#x201c;directly coupled&#x201d; or &#x201c;indirectly coupled&#x201d;, e.g. including one or more other components (e.g. resistor and/or inductor and/or capacitor) connected therebetween the two or more components.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">In the context of various embodiments, the term &#x201c;coupled&#x201d; may include electrical coupling and/or mechanical coupling.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a schematic block diagram of a wake-up receiver (WuRx) <b>300</b>, according to various embodiments. The wake-up receiver (WuRx) <b>300</b> includes a bandpass filter <b>302</b>, an active radio frequency (RF) detector (e.g. amplitude detector or envelope detector) <b>304</b>, a programmable-gain amplifier (PGA) and a low pass filter (LPF), collectively shown by the block <b>306</b>, a continuous-time sigma-delta analogue-to-digital converter (CT &#x3a3;&#x394; ADC) <b>308</b> and a signal processing module or circuit <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">The wake-up receiver (WuRx) <b>300</b> may receive an on-off keying (OOK) input signal (e.g. a 5.8 GHz RF input signal) from an antenna (e.g. a 50&#x3a9; antenna) <b>312</b>, in which the input signal passes through the bandpass filter <b>302</b> for obtaining the desired RF band. The bandpass filter <b>302</b> is collaborated with the RF detector <b>304</b>, which may be co-design with an input matching network or circuit, in which the analog front-end or the RF detector <b>304</b> converts the OOK input signal directly into baseband signals. The baseband signals are amplified with programmable gain and lowpass filtered with variable bandwidth, by the PGA/LPF block <b>306</b>, and digitized by the CT &#x3a3;&#x394; ADC <b>308</b> to reduce noise of the circuit or system. The CT &#x3a3;&#x394; ADC <b>308</b> oversamples the wake-up request signals to increase the signal to noise ratio (SNR). The output of the ADC <b>308</b> is digitally processed by the signal processing circuit <b>310</b>, which may include a decimation filter and an error correction correlation receiver, to generate wake-up requests or signals. Therefore, the digital back-end processing is compliant with decimation filters.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a schematic of a circuit arrangement <b>400</b> for a radio frequency (RF) detector, according to various embodiments. The circuit arrangement <b>400</b> may be implemented, for example, for the active radio frequency (RF) detector (e.g. amplitude detector or envelope detector) <b>304</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>). The circuit arrangement <b>400</b> includes two parts: an amplitude detector based on the nonlinear behavior of MOS devices at the transition from weak to strong inversion, and an LC (inductor-capacitor) network for input matching. The LC network may also function as an RF filter (e.g. as the bandpass filter <b>302</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">The circuit arrangement <b>400</b> includes transistors (e.g. NMOS transistors) MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a </i>and MN<b>2</b> <b>402</b><i>b</i>, which form a pseudo-differential pair to sense differential inputs V<sub>RF+</sub> <b>404</b>, V<sub>RF&#x2212;</sub> <b>405</b>, received through a &#x201c;positive&#x201d; input terminal <b>406</b> and a &#x201c;negative&#x201d; input terminal <b>408</b>, which are robust to common mode noise, and which are matched to an antenna (e.g. <b>312</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) (not shown) with a matching circuit of an LC network having the inductors (L) Lg<b>1</b> <b>410</b>, Ls <b>412</b>, Lg<b>2</b> <b>414</b>, and the capacitors (C) Cex<b>1</b> <b>416</b> and Cex<b>2</b> <b>418</b>. The matching circuit is coupled to the input terminal <b>406</b>, the input terminal <b>408</b>, the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a </i>and the transistor MN<b>2</b> <b>402</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">The circuit arrangement <b>400</b> includes a capacitor C<b>1</b> <b>420</b> coupled in series with the input terminal <b>406</b> and the inductor Lg<b>1</b> <b>410</b> (e.g. coupled between the input terminal <b>406</b> and the inductor Lg<b>1</b> <b>410</b>), and a capacitor C<b>2</b> <b>422</b> coupled in series with the input terminal <b>408</b> and the inductor Lg<b>2</b> <b>414</b> (e.g. coupled between the second input terminal <b>204</b> and the third inductor <b>226</b> the input terminal <b>408</b> and the inductor Lg<b>2</b> <b>414</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">The transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a </i>includes a first controlled terminal (e.g. source terminal) <b>424</b><i>a</i>, a second controlled terminal (e.g. drain terminal) <b>426</b><i>a </i>and a control terminal (e.g. gate terminal) <b>428</b><i>a</i>, and the transistor MN<b>2</b> <b>402</b><i>b </i>includes a first controlled terminal (e.g. source terminal) <b>424</b><i>b</i>, a second controlled terminal (e.g. drain terminal) <b>426</b><i>b </i>and a control terminal (e.g. gate terminal) <b>428</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">The first controlled terminals <b>424</b><i>a</i>, <b>424</b><i>b </i>are coupled to each other. The second controlled terminals <b>426</b><i>a</i>, <b>426</b><i>b </i>are coupled to each other. The control terminal <b>428</b><i>a </i>is coupled to the input terminal <b>406</b> and the control terminal <b>428</b><i>b </i>is coupled to the input terminal <b>408</b>. The control terminal <b>428</b><i>a </i>is also coupled to the inductor Lg<b>1</b> <b>410</b> and the capacitor C<b>1</b> <b>420</b>. The control terminal <b>428</b><i>b </i>is also coupled to the inductor Lg<b>2</b> <b>414</b> and the capacitor C<b>2</b> <b>422</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the inductor Lg<b>1</b> <b>410</b> is coupled between the input terminal <b>406</b> and the control terminal <b>428</b><i>a</i>, the inductor Ls <b>412</b> is coupled between the first controlled terminals <b>424</b><i>a</i>, <b>424</b><i>b</i>, the inductor Lg<b>2</b> <b>414</b> is coupled between the input terminal <b>408</b> and the control terminal <b>428</b><i>b</i>, the capacitor Cex<b>1</b> <b>416</b> is coupled between the control terminal <b>428</b><i>a </i>and the first controlled terminal <b>424</b><i>a</i>, and the capacitor Cex<b>2</b> <b>418</b> is coupled between the control terminal <b>428</b><i>b </i>and the first controlled terminal <b>424</b><i>b</i>. The inductor Ls <b>412</b> is also coupled to a voltage reference point V<sub>2</sub>, which may be a ground terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">The circuit arrangement <b>400</b> further includes a resistive element Rf<b>1</b> <b>430</b> coupled between the control terminal <b>428</b><i>a </i>and the second controlled terminal <b>426</b><i>a</i>, and a resistive element Rf<b>2</b> <b>432</b> coupled between the control terminal <b>428</b><i>b </i>and the second controlled terminal <b>426</b><i>b</i>. The resistive element Rf<b>1</b> <b>430</b> and the resistive element Rf<b>2</b> <b>432</b> may be at least substantially same.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">The resistive element Rf<b>1</b> <b>430</b> includes transistors (e.g. PMOS transistors) MPR<b>1</b> <b>434</b><i>a </i>and MPR<b>2</b> <b>434</b><i>b</i>. The transistor MPR<b>1</b> <b>434</b><i>a </i>includes a first controlled terminal (e.g. source terminal) <b>436</b><i>a</i>, a second controlled terminal (e.g. drain terminal) <b>438</b><i>a</i>, a control terminal (e.g. gate terminal) <b>440</b><i>a</i>, and a bulk terminal <b>441</b><i>a</i>, and the transistor MPR<b>2</b> <b>434</b><i>b </i>includes a first controlled terminal (e.g. source terminal) <b>436</b><i>b</i>, a second controlled terminal (e.g. drain terminal) <b>438</b><i>b</i>, a control terminal (e.g. gate terminal) <b>440</b><i>b</i>, and a bulk terminal <b>441</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">The first controlled terminals <b>436</b><i>a</i>, <b>436</b><i>b </i>are coupled to each other. The second controlled terminal <b>438</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MPR<b>1</b> <b>434</b><i>a </i>is coupled to the control terminal <b>428</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a</i>. The second controlled terminal <b>438</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MPR<b>2</b> <b>434</b><i>b </i>is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>426</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a</i>. The bulk terminal <b>441</b><i>a </i>is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>438</b><i>a</i>. The bulk terminal <b>441</b><i>b </i>is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>438</b><i>b</i>. The control terminals <b>440</b><i>a</i>, <b>440</b><i>b </i>are coupled to each other and also coupled to the first controlled terminals <b>436</b><i>a</i>, <b>436</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">The resistive element Rf<b>2</b> <b>432</b> includes transistors (e.g. PMOS transistors) MPR<b>3</b> <b>442</b><i>a </i>and MPR<b>4</b> <b>442</b><i>b</i>. The transistor MPR<b>3</b> <b>442</b><i>a </i>includes a first controlled terminal (e.g. source terminal) <b>444</b><i>a</i>, a second controlled terminal (e.g. drain terminal) <b>446</b><i>a</i>, a control terminal (e.g. gate terminal) <b>448</b><i>a</i>, and a bulk terminal <b>450</b><i>a</i>, and the transistor MPR<b>4</b> <b>442</b><i>b </i>includes a first controlled terminal (e.g. source terminal) <b>444</b><i>b</i>, a second controlled terminal (e.g. drain terminal) <b>446</b><i>b</i>, a control terminal (e.g. gate terminal) <b>448</b><i>b</i>, and a bulk terminal <b>450</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">The first controlled terminals <b>444</b><i>a</i>, <b>444</b><i>b </i>are coupled to each other. The second controlled terminal <b>446</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MPR<b>3</b> <b>442</b><i>a </i>is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>426</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MN<b>2</b> <b>402</b><i>b</i>. The second controlled terminal <b>446</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MPR<b>4</b> <b>442</b><i>b </i>is coupled to the control terminal <b>428</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MN<b>2</b> <b>402</b><i>b</i>. The bulk terminal <b>450</b><i>a </i>is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>446</b><i>a</i>. The bulk terminal <b>450</b><i>b </i>is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>446</b><i>b</i>. The control terminals <b>448</b><i>a</i>, <b>448</b><i>b </i>are coupled to each other and also coupled to the first controlled terminals <b>444</b><i>a</i>, <b>444</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">It should be appreciated that any one or each of the resistive element Rf<b>1</b> <b>430</b> and resistive element Rf<b>2</b> <b>432</b> may also be at least substantially same, for example in terms of the arrangements of the PMOS transistors, as any one of the resistive element Rf<b>1</b> <b>1132</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>), the resistive element Rf<b>2</b> <b>1134</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>), the resistive element Rf<b>3</b> <b>1136</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) or the resistive element Rf<b>4</b> <b>1138</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) to be described later.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">The circuit arrangement <b>400</b> further includes an output terminal <b>452</b>, from which an output signal (e.g. a baseband signal) V<sub>out </sub><b>453</b> may be extracted, coupled to the second controlled terminals <b>426</b><i>a</i>, <b>426</b><i>b</i>. The circuit arrangement <b>400</b> may further include a capacitor Co <b>454</b>, wherein a first terminal of the capacitor Co <b>454</b> is coupled to the second controlled terminals <b>426</b><i>a</i>, <b>426</b><i>b</i>, and the output terminal <b>452</b>, and a second terminal of the capacitor Co <b>454</b> is coupled to a voltage reference point V<sub>2</sub>, which may be a ground terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111">The circuit arrangement <b>400</b> may further include a current mirror circuit <b>460</b> coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>426</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a</i>, the second controlled terminal <b>426</b><i>b </i>of the MN<b>2</b> <b>402</b><i>b</i>, and the output terminal <b>452</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">The current mirror circuit includes transistors (e.g. PMOS transistors) MP<b>2</b> <b>462</b><i>a </i>and MP<b>1</b> <b>462</b><i>b</i>. The transistor MP<b>2</b> <b>462</b><i>a </i>includes a first controlled terminal (e.g. source terminal) <b>464</b><i>a</i>, a second controlled terminal (e.g. drain terminal) <b>466</b><i>a</i>, and a control terminal (e.g. gate terminal) <b>468</b><i>a</i>, and the transistor MP<b>1</b> <b>462</b><i>b </i>includes a first controlled terminal (e.g. source terminal) <b>464</b><i>b</i>, a second controlled terminal (e.g. drain terminal) <b>466</b><i>b</i>, and a control terminal (e.g. gate terminal) <b>468</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">Each of the first controlled terminals <b>464</b><i>a</i>, <b>464</b><i>b </i>is coupled to a voltage reference point V<sub>1</sub>, which may be a power supply line. The control terminals <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b </i>are coupled to each other. The second controlled terminal <b>466</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MP<b>2</b> <b>462</b><i>a </i>is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>426</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a</i>, the second controlled terminal <b>426</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MN<b>2</b> <b>402</b><i>b </i>and the output terminal <b>452</b>. The second controlled terminal <b>466</b><i>a </i>is also coupled to the first terminal of the capacitor Co <b>454</b>. The second controlled terminal <b>466</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MP<b>1</b> <b>462</b><i>b </i>is coupled to the control terminals <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">The circuit arrangement <b>400</b> further includes a current source <b>470</b> providing a current I<sub>d</sub>, wherein a first terminal of the current source <b>470</b> is coupled to the control terminals <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b </i>and the second controlled terminal <b>466</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MP<b>1</b> <b>462</b><i>b</i>, and a second terminal of the current source <b>470</b> is coupled to a voltage reference point V<sub>2</sub>, which may be a ground terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">The gates or control terminals <b>428</b><i>a</i>, <b>428</b><i>b </i>of the transistors MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a </i>and MN<b>2</b> <b>402</b><i>b </i>are biased via the pseudo-resistors or resistive elements Rf<b>1</b> <b>430</b> and Rf<b>2</b> <b>432</b>, respectively. Such an arrangement may keep or maintain the average drain current of the of the transistors MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a </i>and MN<b>2</b> <b>402</b><i>b </i>equal to approximately half of the bias current, I<sub>d</sub>, of the current source <b>470</b>. The bias current I<sub>d </sub>may be chosen to be low, thereby maintaining the gate voltage just above the threshold voltage, V<sub>th</sub>, of the transistors MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a </i>and MN<b>2</b> <b>402</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116">The transistors MP<b>2</b> <b>462</b><i>a </i>and MP<b>1</b> <b>462</b><i>b </i>function to provide the bias current mirror, whereby the bias current I<sub>d </sub>provided by the current source <b>470</b> in a branch of the current mirror circuit <b>460</b> associated with the transistor MP<b>1</b> <b>462</b><i>b</i>, is mirrored or reproduced as substantially I<sub>d </sub>in another branch of the current mirror circuit <b>460</b> associated with the transistor MP<b>2</b> <b>462</b><i>a </i>to be supplied to the transistors MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a </i>and MN<b>2</b> <b>402</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0117">The capacitors C<b>1</b> <b>420</b> and C<b>2</b> <b>422</b> provide direct current (DC) blocking from the respective input terminals <b>406</b>, <b>408</b>, and therefore their capacitance should be large compared to the gate capacitance of the transistors MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a </i>and MN<b>2</b> <b>402</b><i>b </i>in order to obtain maximum voltage swing at the respective control terminals <b>428</b><i>a</i>, <b>428</b><i>b</i>. The capacitor Co <b>454</b> acts to sustain the output voltage and may work as part of the low pass filter (e.g. <b>306</b>) with an output resistance.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0118">The circuit arrangement <b>400</b> provides a single-ended output, via the output terminal <b>452</b>, so as to reduce the circuit complexity for low power considerations.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0119">In various embodiments, using the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a </i>as a non-limiting example, when the signal amplitude at the input terminal <b>406</b> is low, the DC behaviour of the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a </i>biased via the resistive element Rf<b>1</b> <b>430</b> is at least substantially similar to a diode connected NMOS. The output voltage V<sub>out </sub><b>453</b> is just above the threshold voltage. The DC biasing condition for the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a </i>is at least substantially similar to a zero V<sub>th </sub>(turn-on voltage) diode. Therefore, the circuit arrangement <b>400</b> or a detector including the circuit arrangement <b>400</b>, includes an equivalent zero-V<sub>th </sub>diode configuration, which may alleviate the threshold voltage loss that is present in conventional detectors.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0120">As the signal amplitude increases, the detector enters a strongly nonlinear regime. The transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a </i>conducts most current when the gate voltage is above a threshold voltage, V<sub>th</sub>. Since the drain current is limited by I<sub>d</sub>, the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a </i>discharges the capacitor Co <b>454</b> and lowers the gate voltage until the average drain current through the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a </i>is at least substantially equal to I<sub>d</sub>. If the drain current is large compared to the bias current I<sub>d </sub>when the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a </i>is conducting, the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a </i>only conducts in certain periods or durations. The output voltage V<sub>out </sub><b>453</b> then drops proportionally to the input peak amplitude, providing a detector gain of &#x2212;1 V/V. The detector output voltage V<sub>out </sub><b>453</b> may then be described according to</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0121">
<maths id="MATH-US-00001" num="00001">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <msub>
            <mi>V</mi>
            <mi>out</mi>
          </msub>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mrow>
            <msub>
              <mi>V</mi>
              <mi>th</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>+</mo>
            <msqrt>
              <mrow>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>I</mi>
                    <mi>d</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>&#xb7;</mo>
                  <mfrac>
                    <mn>2</mn>
                    <mrow>
                      <msub>
                        <mi>&#x3bc;</mi>
                        <mi>n</mi>
                      </msub>
                      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                      <msub>
                        <mi>C</mi>
                        <mi>ox</mi>
                      </msub>
                    </mrow>
                  </mfrac>
                  <mo>&#xb7;</mo>
                  <mfrac>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                    <mi>W</mi>
                  </mfrac>
                </mrow>
                <mo>-</mo>
                <mfrac>
                  <msup>
                    <mi>A</mi>
                    <mn>2</mn>
                  </msup>
                  <mn>2</mn>
                </mfrac>
              </mrow>
            </msqrt>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
        <mo>,</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Equation</mi>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>1</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
where A is the peak amplitude of a sinusoidal waveform input signal (e.g. input signal, V<sub>RF</sub>=A sin(&#x3c9;t)), W and L are the transistor width and length and &#x3bc;<sub>n </sub>(electron mobility), C<sub>ox </sub>(gate oxide capacitance per unit area) and V<sub>th </sub>(transistor threshold voltage) are process dependent device parameters.
</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0122">The currents in the transistors MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a </i>and MN<b>2</b> <b>402</b><i>b </i>may be limited and the detector gain may be slightly lower. In addition, the resistive elements Rf<b>1</b> <b>430</b> and Rf<b>2</b> <b>432</b> are chosen to be relatively large to provide DC biasing at the respective control terminals <b>428</b><i>a</i>, <b>428</b><i>b</i>, and a small AC gain from the respective gates or control terminals <b>428</b><i>a</i>, <b>428</b><i>b </i>to the respective drains or second controlled terminals <b>426</b><i>a</i>, <b>426</b><i>b</i>. For each of the resistive elements Rf<b>1</b> <b>430</b> and Rf<b>2</b> <b>432</b>, two diode connected PMOS in series, transistors MPR<b>1</b> <b>434</b><i>a</i>, MPR<b>2</b> <b>434</b><i>b </i>and transistors MPR<b>3</b> <b>442</b><i>a</i>, MPR<b>4</b> <b>442</b><i>b</i>, constitute pseudo resistors to serve as mega-ohms resistors without loading the output, and providing DC biasing at the control terminals (gate) <b>428</b><i>a</i>, <b>428</b><i>b</i>, with small parasitic effects (e.g. parasitic capacitance).</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0123">In general, the higher carrier frequency a detector uses, the more power burden it suffers in the RF gain amplification. A detector (e.g. envelope detector) employing the circuit arrangement <b>400</b> may be advantageously carrier frequency insensitive.</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0124"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows a plot <b>500</b> of detector transfer curve illustrating the relationship between the output voltage V<sub>out </sub>and the input voltage V<sub>RF </sub>for different carrier frequencies, according to various embodiments. The plot <b>500</b> shows the results for the carrier frequencies, Frf, of 0.1 GHz <b>502</b>, 1 GHz <b>504</b> and 5.8 GHz <b>506</b>. The plot <b>500</b> shows that V<sub>out </sub>is a function of only the amplitude of the input voltage V<sub>RF</sub>, and is independent of the carrier frequency, Frf. Therefore, RF detection by the detector of various embodiments is independent of the operating carrier frequency. The results show that the detector of various embodiments demonstrates its suitable applications in any carrier frequencies, for high sensitivity RF detection independent of the operating carrier frequencies or without carrier frequency limitation. However, this also means that the detector faces the challenges of non-selectivity.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0125">In order to provide good selectivity to out-of-band noise and interferences, a LC matching network or circuit of the inductors Lg<b>1</b> <b>410</b>, Ls <b>412</b>, Lg<b>2</b> <b>414</b>, and the capacitors Cex<b>1</b> <b>416</b> and Cex<b>2</b> <b>418</b> as described in the context of the circuit arrangement <b>400</b> may be provided. The capacitors Cex<b>1</b> <b>416</b> and Cex<b>2</b> <b>418</b> are added to provide additional design freedom. The LC matching network may supply a stable impedance match to a 50 ohms input source and also provides a narrow RF filter (e.g. <b>302</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) to remove out-of-band noise and interfering signals. The impedance, Z<sub>in</sub>, for the input matching network in the RF detector may be described according to</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0126">
<maths id="MATH-US-00002" num="00002">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <msub>
            <mi>Z</mi>
            <mi>in</mi>
          </msub>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mfrac>
              <mrow>
                <msub>
                  <mi>g</mi>
                  <mi>m</mi>
                </msub>
                <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                <msub>
                  <mi>L</mi>
                  <mi>s</mi>
                </msub>
              </mrow>
              <mrow>
                <msub>
                  <mi>C</mi>
                  <mi>ex</mi>
                </msub>
                <mo>+</mo>
                <msub>
                  <mi>C</mi>
                  <mi>gs</mi>
                </msub>
              </mrow>
            </mfrac>
            <mo>+</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mi>j</mi>
              <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mo>[</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <mi>&#x3c9;</mi>
                    <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
                    <mrow>
                      <mo>(</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <msub>
                          <mi>L</mi>
                          <mi>s</mi>
                        </msub>
                        <mo>+</mo>
                        <msub>
                          <mi>L</mi>
                          <mi>g</mi>
                        </msub>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>)</mo>
                    </mrow>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <mfrac>
                    <mn>1</mn>
                    <mrow>
                      <mi>&#x3c9;</mi>
                      <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <mo>(</mo>
                        <mrow>
                          <msub>
                            <mi>C</mi>
                            <mi>ex</mi>
                          </msub>
                          <mo>+</mo>
                          <msub>
                            <mi>C</mi>
                            <mi>gs</mi>
                          </msub>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>)</mo>
                      </mrow>
                    </mrow>
                  </mfrac>
                </mrow>
                <mo>]</mo>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
        <mo>,</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Equation</mi>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>2</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
where C<sub>gs </sub>and g<sub>m </sub>are the respective parasitic gate-to-source capacitance and the transconductance of the respective transistors MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a</i>, MN<b>2</b> <b>402</b><i>b. </i>
</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0127">An input match at the resonant frequency, &#x3c9;<sub>0</sub>, is achieved by equating the real part of Z<sub>in </sub>to the source impedance, R<sub>s</sub>, and the imaginary part to zero, as expressed respectively in Equations 3 and 4 below:</p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0128">
<maths id="MATH-US-00003" num="00003">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <msub>
            <mi>R</mi>
            <mi>s</mi>
          </msub>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mfrac>
            <mrow>
              <msub>
                <mi>g</mi>
                <mi>m</mi>
              </msub>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <msub>
                <mi>L</mi>
                <mi>s</mi>
              </msub>
            </mrow>
            <mrow>
              <msub>
                <mi>C</mi>
                <mi>ex</mi>
              </msub>
              <mo>+</mo>
              <msub>
                <mi>C</mi>
                <mi>gs</mi>
              </msub>
            </mrow>
          </mfrac>
        </mrow>
        <mo>,</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Equation</mi>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>3</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <msub>
          <mi>&#x3c9;</mi>
          <mn>0</mn>
        </msub>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mfrac>
            <mn>1</mn>
            <msqrt>
              <mrow>
                <mrow>
                  <mo>(</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>L</mi>
                      <mi>s</mi>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>+</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>L</mi>
                      <mi>g</mi>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>)</mo>
                </mrow>
                <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <mo>(</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>C</mi>
                      <mi>ex</mi>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>+</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>C</mi>
                      <mi>gs</mi>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>)</mo>
                </mrow>
              </mrow>
            </msqrt>
          </mfrac>
          <mo>.</mo>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Equation</mi>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>4</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0129"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows a plot <b>600</b> of simulated S<b>11</b> <b>602</b> and gain <b>604</b> of an input matching circuit, according to various embodiments, from an antenna to an input of the detector of various embodiments, including bonding wires and pad parasitic capacitance. The parameter S<b>11</b> refers to the return loss or the power reflected from the antenna. The detector input transistor (e.g. MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a</i>, MN<b>2</b> <b>402</b><i>b</i>) may be sensitive to voltage, and the impedance transformation additionally provides additional passive voltage gain, approximately 10 dB, based on the quality factor of the input matching circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0130">Another consideration is the output bandwidth, which is determined by the output pole. From large signal analysis, the output signal is the squared version of the input signal, and is filtered through the low pass filter formed by the detector output resistance and the capacitor Co (e.g. <b>454</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>). The bandwidth at the output is set by the pole at f<sub>p,det </sub>formed by the capacitor Co (e.g. <b>454</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) and the output impedance of the detector, which is approximately 1/g<sub>m</sub>, neglecting the body effect, and may be expressed as</p>
<p id="p-0132" num="0131">
<maths id="MATH-US-00004" num="00004">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <msub>
            <mi>f</mi>
            <mrow>
              <mi>p</mi>
              <mo>,</mo>
              <mi>det</mi>
            </mrow>
          </msub>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mfrac>
            <msub>
              <mi>g</mi>
              <mi>m</mi>
            </msub>
            <mrow>
              <mn>2</mn>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mi>&#x3c0;</mi>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mstyle>
                <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
              </mstyle>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <msub>
                <mi>C</mi>
                <mn>0</mn>
              </msub>
            </mrow>
          </mfrac>
        </mrow>
        <mo>,</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Equation</mi>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>5</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
where g<sub>m </sub>is the transconductance of the respective transistors MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a</i>, MN<b>2</b> <b>402</b><i>b. </i>
</p>
<p id="p-0133" num="0132">This pole is designed to be low enough to filter out any signal at the fundamental and higher harmonics, while still affording enough bandwidth to avoid or minimise attenuating the baseband signal. At the output port or terminal, only low frequency components may be observed. In various embodiments, for an OOK signal, the detected baseband waveform may be a square wave with a given baseband data rate, so the detector bandwidth should be high enough to avoid filtering this desired signal.</p>
<p id="p-0134" num="0133">Furthermore, in various embodiments, the transistors MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a</i>, MN<b>2</b> <b>402</b><i>b </i>may be sized larger in order to lower or minimise the flicker noise, if it becomes dominant in the overall receiver noise calculation.</p>
<p id="p-0135" num="0134">The conversion gain of the detector (e.g. envelope detector) of various embodiments will now be described. Due to the nonlinear nature of the envelope detector, there are challenges in analyzing the linear noise figure, NF. The following provides a non-limiting example to analyze the sensitivity of an envelope detection receiver.</p>
<p id="p-0136" num="0135">The first step is to determine the nonlinear response of the envelope detector. Firstly, the large signal drain current, I<sub>dc</sub>, of the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a </i>in saturation with an input signal V<sub>RF</sub>=A sin(&#x3c9;t) may be determined as described by:</p>
<p id="p-0137" num="0136">
<maths id="MATH-US-00005" num="00005">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <msub>
            <mi>I</mi>
            <mi>dc</mi>
          </msub>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <msup>
            <mrow>
              <mfrac>
                <mi>K</mi>
                <mn>2</mn>
              </mfrac>
              <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mo>[</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>V</mi>
                    <mi>out</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>+</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mi>QA</mi>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <mstyle>
                      <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
                    </mstyle>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <mi>sin</mi>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <mstyle>
                      <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
                    </mstyle>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <mrow>
                      <mo>(</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <mi>&#x3c9;</mi>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <mstyle>
                          <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                        </mstyle>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <mi>t</mi>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>)</mo>
                    </mrow>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>V</mi>
                    <mi>th</mi>
                  </msub>
                </mrow>
                <mo>]</mo>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
            <mn>2</mn>
          </msup>
        </mrow>
        <mo>,</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Equation</mi>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>6</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
where
</p>
<p id="p-0138" num="0137">
<maths id="MATH-US-00006" num="00006">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <mrow>
    <mi>K</mi>
    <mo>=</mo>
    <mrow>
      <msub>
        <mi>&#x3bc;</mi>
        <mi>n</mi>
      </msub>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <msub>
        <mi>C</mi>
        <mi>ox</mi>
      </msub>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <mfrac>
        <mi>W</mi>
        <mi>L</mi>
      </mfrac>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
  <mo>,</mo>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
which is a constant depending on the fabrication process and device size, W and L are the transistor (e.g. MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a</i>) width and length, &#x3bc;<sub>n </sub>and C<sub>ox </sub>are process dependent device parameters, V<sub>out </sub>is the detector output voltage, V<sub>th </sub>is the threshold voltage (e.g. of the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a</i>), Q is the quality factor of the input matching circuit, A and &#x3c9; are respectively the peak amplitude and frequency of the input signal V<sub>RF</sub>, and t is time.
</p>
<p id="p-0139" num="0138">Next, the DC output signal current, I<sub>d,Dc</sub>, and the high order harmonic term may be filtered by the detector output pole, providing a DC output current, I<sub>d,Dc</sub>, as described by:</p>
<p id="p-0140" num="0139">
<maths id="MATH-US-00007" num="00007">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <msub>
          <mi>I</mi>
          <mrow>
            <mi>d</mi>
            <mo>,</mo>
            <mi>DC</mi>
          </mrow>
        </msub>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mrow>
            <mfrac>
              <mi>K</mi>
              <mn>2</mn>
            </mfrac>
            <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>[</mo>
              <mrow>
                <msup>
                  <mrow>
                    <mo>(</mo>
                    <mrow>
                      <msub>
                        <mi>V</mi>
                        <mi>out</mi>
                      </msub>
                      <mo>-</mo>
                      <msub>
                        <mi>V</mi>
                        <mi>th</mi>
                      </msub>
                    </mrow>
                    <mo>)</mo>
                  </mrow>
                  <mn>2</mn>
                </msup>
                <mo>+</mo>
                <mfrac>
                  <mrow>
                    <msup>
                      <mi>Q</mi>
                      <mn>2</mn>
                    </msup>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <msup>
                      <mi>A</mi>
                      <mn>2</mn>
                    </msup>
                  </mrow>
                  <mn>2</mn>
                </mfrac>
              </mrow>
              <mo>]</mo>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
          <mo>.</mo>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Equation</mi>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>7</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0141" num="0140">By re-arranging the terms in Equation 7, the DC output voltage, V<sub>out</sub>, may be determined as</p>
<p id="p-0142" num="0141">
<maths id="MATH-US-00008" num="00008">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <msub>
            <mi>V</mi>
            <mi>out</mi>
          </msub>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mrow>
              <msub>
                <mi>V</mi>
                <mi>th</mi>
              </msub>
              <mo>+</mo>
              <msqrt>
                <mrow>
                  <mfrac>
                    <mrow>
                      <mn>2</mn>
                      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                      <msub>
                        <mi>I</mi>
                        <mrow>
                          <mi>d</mi>
                          <mo>,</mo>
                          <mi>DC</mi>
                        </mrow>
                      </msub>
                    </mrow>
                    <mi>K</mi>
                  </mfrac>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <mfrac>
                    <mrow>
                      <msup>
                        <mi>Q</mi>
                        <mn>2</mn>
                      </msup>
                      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                      <msup>
                        <mi>A</mi>
                        <mn>2</mn>
                      </msup>
                    </mrow>
                    <mn>2</mn>
                  </mfrac>
                </mrow>
              </msqrt>
            </mrow>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mi>kA</mi>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
        <mo>,</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Equation</mi>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>8</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
where k is the voltage conversion gain.
</p>
<p id="p-0143" num="0142">The voltage conversion gain, k, from the peak AC input amplitude A to output DC voltage V<sub>out </sub>may be determined by</p>
<p id="p-0144" num="0143">
<maths id="MATH-US-00009" num="00009">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mi>k</mi>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mfrac>
            <mrow>
              <mo>&#x2202;</mo>
              <msub>
                <mi>V</mi>
                <mi>out</mi>
              </msub>
            </mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mo>&#x2202;</mo>
              <mi>A</mi>
            </mrow>
          </mfrac>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mrow>
                <mo>-</mo>
                <mfrac>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                  <mn>2</mn>
                </mfrac>
              </mrow>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mfrac>
                <mrow>
                  <msup>
                    <mi>Q</mi>
                    <mn>2</mn>
                  </msup>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mi>A</mi>
                </mrow>
                <msqrt>
                  <mrow>
                    <mfrac>
                      <mrow>
                        <mn>2</mn>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <msub>
                          <mi>I</mi>
                          <mrow>
                            <mi>d</mi>
                            <mo>,</mo>
                            <mi>DC</mi>
                          </mrow>
                        </msub>
                      </mrow>
                      <mi>K</mi>
                    </mfrac>
                    <mo>-</mo>
                    <mfrac>
                      <mrow>
                        <msup>
                          <mi>Q</mi>
                          <mn>2</mn>
                        </msup>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <msup>
                          <mi>A</mi>
                          <mn>2</mn>
                        </msup>
                      </mrow>
                      <mn>2</mn>
                    </mfrac>
                  </mrow>
                </msqrt>
              </mfrac>
            </mrow>
            <mo>&#x2248;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mrow>
                <mo>-</mo>
                <mfrac>
                  <msqrt>
                    <mn>2</mn>
                  </msqrt>
                  <mn>4</mn>
                </mfrac>
              </mrow>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <msqrt>
                <mfrac>
                  <mi>K</mi>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>I</mi>
                    <mrow>
                      <mi>d</mi>
                      <mo>,</mo>
                      <mi>DC</mi>
                    </mrow>
                  </msub>
                </mfrac>
              </msqrt>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <msup>
                <mi>Q</mi>
                <mn>2</mn>
              </msup>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mi>A</mi>
                <mo>.</mo>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Equation</mi>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>9</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
Expanding k in a Taylor series and focusing on the first order term, the voltage conversion gain, k, as expressed in Equation 9, may be better approximated to get the design intuition.
</p>
<p id="p-0145" num="0144"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows a plot <b>700</b> of simulated detector voltage conversion gain, k <b>702</b> and calculated voltage conversion gain, k <b>704</b> (based on Equation 9), according to various embodiments, based on an example of a Chartered 0.18 &#x3bc;m CMOS with supply voltage, VDD=0.5V. The plot <b>700</b> illustrates that the calculated results <b>704</b> based on the simplified k of Equation 9 shows a good match with the simulation results <b>702</b> for small input voltage amplitudes (e.g. between 0 to 40 mV).</p>
<p id="p-0146" num="0145">The sensitivity of the detector (e.g. envelope detector) of various embodiments will now be described. The ultimate sensitivity may be determined by analyzing the noise contributions and gain factors to the detector output and calculating an effective noise figure, NF, that depends on the input signal power. The noise of the envelope detector itself, due to the transistors MN<b>1</b> (e.g. <b>402</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), MN<b>2</b> (e.g. <b>402</b><i>b</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), MP<b>2</b> (e.g. <b>462</b><i>a</i>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), and the resistive elements Rf<b>1</b> (e.g. <b>430</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), and Rf<b>2</b> (e.g. <b>432</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), appears directly at the output. This noise, N<sub>o,ED </sub>(V<sup>2</sup>/Hz), may be determined as described by</p>
<p id="p-0147" num="0146">
<maths id="MATH-US-00010" num="00010">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <msub>
            <mi>N</mi>
            <mrow>
              <mi>o</mi>
              <mo>,</mo>
              <mi>ED</mi>
            </mrow>
          </msub>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mn>2.</mn>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mfrac>
                <mrow>
                  <mn>4</mn>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mi>kT</mi>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mstyle>
                    <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                  </mstyle>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mi>&#x3b3;</mi>
                </mrow>
                <msub>
                  <mi>g</mi>
                  <mi>mn</mi>
                </msub>
              </mfrac>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                  <mo>+</mo>
                  <mfrac>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>g</mi>
                      <mi>mp</mi>
                    </msub>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>g</mi>
                      <mi>mn</mi>
                    </msub>
                  </mfrac>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
            <mo>+</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mn>2.</mn>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mfrac>
                <mrow>
                  <mn>4</mn>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mi>kT</mi>
                </mrow>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>R</mi>
                    <mi>f</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <msubsup>
                    <mi>g</mi>
                    <mi>mn</mi>
                    <mn>2</mn>
                  </msubsup>
                </mrow>
              </mfrac>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
        <mo>,</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Equation</mi>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>10</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
where k is the Boltzmann constant, T is temperature, &#x3b3; is the coefficient for MOSFET noise, g<sub>mn </sub>is the transconductance of the respective transistors MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a</i>, MN<b>2</b> <b>402</b><i>b</i>, g<sub>mp </sub>is the transconductance of the transistor MP<b>2</b> <b>462</b><i>a</i>, and R<sub>f </sub>is the resistance of the respective resistive elements Rf<b>1</b> <b>430</b>, Rf<b>2</b> <b>432</b>.
</p>
<p id="p-0148" num="0147"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> shows a plot <b>800</b> of simulated detector output noise <b>802</b> of the detector of various embodiments. The simulated noise may be integrated over the entire band and normalized to the detector bandwidth in order to approximate an equivalent brickwall noise density <b>804</b> in a 1 Hz bandwidth, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>. The equivalent noise density <b>804</b> may then be used in the noise factor calculation.</p>
<p id="p-0149" num="0148">The total noise factor, F, of the detector may then be expressed as</p>
<p id="p-0150" num="0149">
<maths id="MATH-US-00011" num="00011">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mi>F</mi>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mfrac>
            <mrow>
              <mrow>
                <msub>
                  <mi>N</mi>
                  <mi>RS</mi>
                </msub>
                <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                <msup>
                  <mi>k</mi>
                  <mn>2</mn>
                </msup>
              </mrow>
              <mo>+</mo>
              <msub>
                <mi>N</mi>
                <mrow>
                  <mi>o</mi>
                  <mo>,</mo>
                  <mi>ED</mi>
                </mrow>
              </msub>
            </mrow>
            <mrow>
              <msub>
                <mi>N</mi>
                <mi>RS</mi>
              </msub>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <msup>
                <mi>k</mi>
                <mn>2</mn>
              </msup>
            </mrow>
          </mfrac>
        </mrow>
        <mo>,</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Equation</mi>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>11</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
where N<sub>RS </sub>is the noise from the source resistance (=4kTR<sub>s</sub>, where k is the Boltzmann constant, T is temperature, and R<sub>s </sub>is the source resistance) and k is the conversion gain.
</p>
<p id="p-0151" num="0150">Due to the dependence of the conversion gain k on signal level, F increases with decreasing input power. Using NF=10 log F and the detector bandwidth BW<sub>det </sub>as a non-limiting example, the input-referred noise, P<sub>n,in</sub>, for the receiver in dBm may be determined by
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>P</i><sub>n,in</sub>=&#x2212;174+10 log(BW<sub>det</sub>)+<i>NF</i>&#x2003;&#x2003;(Equation 12).<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0152" num="0151">If the minimum signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) for reliable detection is SNR<sub>min</sub>, the minimum detectable signal, P<sub>mds</sub>, is the input power for which may be determined by
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>P</i><sub>mds</sub><i>=P</i><sub>n,in</sub>+SNR<sub>min</sub>&#x2003;&#x2003;(Equation 13).<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0153" num="0152">The relationship as described by Equation 13 may be visualized by plotting the noise power P<sub>n,in </sub>and (P<sub>in</sub>&#x2212;SNR<sub>min</sub>) versus P<sub>in</sub>, where P<sub>in </sub>is the input power, and locating the intersection.</p>
<p id="p-0154" num="0153"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> shows a plot <b>900</b> of detector sensitivity, according to various embodiments, for P<sub>n,in </sub><b>902</b> and P<sub>mds </sub><b>904</b>. For a value of 12 dB for SNR<sub>min </sub>(bit error rate, BER=10<sup>&#x2212;3 </sup>for OOK), P<sub>mds </sub>may be found to be approximately &#x2212;70 dBm, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0155" num="0154"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> shows a plot <b>1000</b> of detector signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) as a function of input power for different carrier frequencies, according to various embodiments. The plot <b>1000</b> shows the results for frequencies at about 2.4 GHz <b>1002</b> and about 5.8 GHz <b>1004</b>. Based on a bit error rate, BER=10<sup>&#x2212;3 </sup>for OOK (SNR=12 dB), the detector achieves a sensitivity of about &#x2212;65 dBm sensitivity at 2.4 GHz and about &#x2212;50 dBm at 5.8 GHz.</p>
<p id="p-0156" num="0155">The performance of the detector or wake-up receiver of various embodiments is summarised in Table 1. The RF detector of various embodiments may achieve high sensitivity and moderate selectivity, without RF gain amplifier stage, with a power consumption of about 10 &#x3bc;W or under.</p>
<p id="p-0157" num="0156">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00001" num="00001">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="35pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="182pt" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" rowsep="1">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>Parameter</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="35pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="56pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="126pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>Process</entry>
<entry>0.18 &#x3bc;m CMOS</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>Sensitivity (dBm)</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;70</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>Carrier frequency</entry>
<entry>5.8</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>(GHz)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>Data rate (KHz)</entry>
<entry>100</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>Voltage (V)</entry>
<entry>0.5</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>Power (&#x3bc;W)</entry>
<entry>10</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0158" num="0157"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> shows a schematic of a circuit arrangement <b>1100</b> for a radio frequency (RF) detector, according to various embodiments. The circuit arrangement <b>1100</b> may be implemented, for example, for the active radio frequency (RF) detector (e.g. amplitude detector or envelope detector) <b>304</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>). An RF detector employing the circuit arrangement <b>1100</b> may be a fully differential RF detector. The circuit arrangement <b>1100</b> includes two parts: an amplitude detector based on the nonlinear behavior of MOS devices at the transition from weak to strong inversion, and an LC (inductor-capacitor) network for input matching. The LC network may also function as a RF filter (e.g. as the bandpass filter <b>302</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0159" num="0158">The circuit arrangement <b>1100</b> includes transistors (e.g. NMOS transistors) MN<b>1</b> <b>1102</b><i>a </i>and MN<b>2</b> <b>1102</b><i>b</i>, and transistors (e.g. PMOS transistors) MP<b>1</b> <b>1124</b><i>a </i>and MP<b>2</b> <b>1124</b><i>b</i>, to provide fully-differential circuits to sense differential inputs V<sub>RF+</sub> <b>1104</b>, V<sub>RF&#x2212;</sub> <b>1105</b>, received through a &#x201c;positive&#x201d; input terminal <b>1106</b> and a &#x201c;negative&#x201d; input terminal <b>1108</b>, which are robust to common mode noise, and which are matched to an antenna (e.g. <b>312</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) (not shown) with a matching circuit of an LC network having the inductors (L) Lg<b>1</b> <b>1100</b>, Ls <b>1111</b>, Lg<b>2</b> <b>1112</b>, and the capacitors (C) Cex<b>1</b> <b>1113</b>, Cex<b>2</b> <b>1114</b>, Cex<b>3</b> <b>1115</b>, Cex<b>4</b> <b>1116</b>. The matching circuit is coupled to the input terminal <b>1106</b>, the input terminal <b>1108</b>, the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>1102</b><i>a</i>, the transistor MN<b>2</b> <b>1102</b><i>b</i>, the transistor MP<b>1</b> <b>1124</b><i>a </i>and the transistor MP<b>2</b> <b>1124</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0160" num="0159">The transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>1102</b><i>a </i>includes a first controlled terminal (e.g. source terminal) <b>1118</b><i>a</i>, a second controlled terminal (e.g. drain terminal) <b>1120</b><i>a </i>and a control terminal (e.g. gate terminal) <b>1122</b><i>a</i>, and the transistor MN<b>2</b> <b>1102</b><i>b </i>includes a first controlled terminal (e.g. source terminal) <b>1118</b><i>b</i>, a second controlled terminal (e.g. drain terminal) <b>1120</b><i>b </i>and a control terminal (e.g. gate terminal) <b>1122</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0161" num="0160">The first controlled terminals <b>1118</b><i>a</i>, <b>1118</b><i>b </i>are coupled to each other. The second controlled terminals <b>1120</b><i>a</i>, <b>1120</b><i>b </i>are coupled to each other. The control terminal <b>1122</b><i>a </i>is coupled to the input terminal <b>1106</b> and the control terminal <b>1122</b><i>b </i>is coupled to the input terminal <b>1108</b>. The control terminal <b>1122</b><i>a </i>is also coupled to the inductor Lg<b>1</b> <b>1110</b>, and the control terminal <b>1122</b><i>b </i>is also coupled to the inductor Lg<b>2</b> <b>1112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0162" num="0161">The transistor MP<b>1</b> <b>1124</b><i>a </i>includes a first controlled terminal (e.g. source terminal) <b>1126</b><i>a</i>, a second controlled terminal (e.g. drain terminal) <b>1128</b><i>a </i>and a control terminal (e.g. gate terminal) <b>1130</b><i>a</i>, and the transistor MP<b>2</b> <b>1124</b><i>b </i>includes a first controlled terminal (e.g. source terminal) <b>1126</b><i>b</i>, a second controlled terminal (e.g. drain terminal) <b>1128</b><i>b </i>and a control terminal (e.g. gate terminal) <b>1130</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0163" num="0162">The first controlled terminals <b>1126</b><i>a</i>, <b>1126</b><i>b </i>are coupled to each other. The second controlled terminals <b>1128</b><i>a</i>, <b>1128</b><i>b </i>are coupled to each other. The control terminal <b>1130</b><i>a </i>is coupled to the input terminal <b>1106</b> and the control terminal <b>1130</b><i>b </i>is coupled to the input terminal <b>1108</b>. The control terminal <b>1130</b><i>a </i>is also coupled to the inductor Lg<b>1</b> <b>1110</b>, and the control terminal <b>1130</b><i>b </i>is also coupled to the inductor Lg<b>2</b> <b>1112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0164" num="0163">The inductor Lg<b>1</b> <b>1110</b> includes a first terminal coupled to the input terminal <b>1106</b>, and a second terminal coupled to the control terminal <b>1122</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>1102</b><i>a </i>and the control terminal <b>1130</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MP<b>1</b> <b>1124</b><i>a</i>. The inductor Ls <b>1111</b> includes a first terminal coupled to the first controlled terminal <b>1118</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>1102</b><i>a</i>, the first controlled terminal <b>1118</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MN<b>2</b> <b>1102</b><i>b</i>, the first controlled terminal <b>1126</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MP<b>1</b> <b>1124</b><i>a </i>and the first controlled terminal <b>1126</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MP<b>2</b> <b>1124</b><i>b</i>. The inductor Lg<b>2</b> <b>1112</b> includes a first terminal coupled to the control terminal <b>1122</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MN<b>2</b> <b>1102</b><i>b </i>and the control terminal <b>1130</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MP<b>2</b> <b>1124</b><i>b</i>, and a second terminal coupled to the input terminal <b>1108</b>. The capacitor Cex<b>1</b> <b>1113</b> is coupled between the control terminal <b>1122</b><i>a </i>and the first controlled terminal <b>1118</b><i>a</i>, the capacitor Cex<b>2</b> <b>1114</b> is coupled between the control terminal <b>1122</b><i>b </i>and the first controlled terminal <b>1118</b><i>b</i>, the capacitor Cex<b>3</b> <b>1115</b> is coupled between the control terminal <b>1130</b><i>a </i>and the first controlled terminal <b>1126</b><i>a</i>, and the capacitor Cex<b>4</b> <b>1116</b> is coupled between the control terminal <b>1130</b><i>b </i>and the first controlled terminal <b>1126</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0165" num="0164">The input matching circuit may further include a capacitor Cs <b>1117</b>, wherein a first terminal of the capacitor Cs <b>1117</b> is coupled to the second terminal of the inductor Ls <b>1111</b>, and a second terminal of the capacitor Cs <b>1117</b> is coupled to a voltage reference point V<sub>1</sub>, which may be a ground terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0166" num="0165">The circuit arrangement <b>1100</b> further includes a resistive element Rf<b>1</b> <b>1132</b> coupled between the control terminal <b>1122</b><i>a </i>and the second controlled terminal <b>1120</b><i>a</i>, a resistive element Rf<b>2</b> <b>1134</b> coupled between the control terminal <b>1122</b><i>b </i>and the second controlled terminal <b>1120</b><i>b</i>, a resistive element Rf<b>3</b> <b>1136</b> coupled between the control terminal <b>1130</b><i>a </i>and the second controlled terminal <b>1128</b><i>a</i>, and a resistive element Rf<b>4</b> <b>1138</b> coupled between the control terminal <b>1130</b><i>b </i>and the second controlled terminal <b>1128</b><i>b</i>. The resistive element Rf<b>1</b> <b>1132</b>, the resistive element Rf<b>2</b> <b>1134</b>, the resistive element Rf<b>3</b> <b>1136</b> and the resistive element Rf<b>4</b> <b>1138</b> may be at least substantially same.</p>
<p id="p-0167" num="0166">The resistive element Rf<b>1</b> <b>1132</b> includes transistors (e.g. PMOS transistors) MPR<b>1</b> <b>1140</b><i>a </i>and MPR<b>2</b> <b>1140</b><i>b</i>. The transistor MPR<b>1</b> <b>1140</b><i>a </i>includes a first controlled terminal (e.g. source terminal) <b>1142</b><i>a</i>, a second controlled terminal (e.g. drain terminal) <b>1144</b><i>a</i>, a control terminal (e.g. gate terminal) <b>1146</b><i>a</i>, and a bulk terminal <b>1147</b><i>a</i>, and the transistor MPR<b>2</b> <b>1140</b><i>b </i>includes a first controlled terminal (e.g. source terminal) <b>1142</b><i>b</i>, a second controlled terminal (e.g. drain terminal) <b>1144</b><i>b</i>, a control terminal (e.g. gate terminal) <b>1146</b><i>b</i>, and a bulk terminal <b>1147</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0168" num="0167">The first controlled terminals <b>1142</b><i>a</i>, <b>1142</b><i>b </i>are coupled to each other. The second controlled terminal <b>1144</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MPR<b>1</b> <b>1140</b><i>a </i>is coupled to the control terminal <b>1122</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>1102</b><i>a</i>. The second controlled terminal <b>1144</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MPR<b>2</b> <b>1140</b><i>b </i>is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>1120</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>1102</b><i>a</i>. The control terminal <b>1146</b><i>a </i>is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>1144</b><i>a</i>. The control terminal <b>1146</b><i>b </i>is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>1144</b><i>b</i>. The bulk terminals <b>1147</b><i>a</i>, <b>1147</b><i>b </i>are coupled to each other and also coupled to the first controlled terminals <b>1142</b><i>a</i>, <b>1142</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0169" num="0168">The resistive element Rf<b>2</b> <b>1134</b> includes transistors (e.g. PMOS transistors) MPR<b>3</b> <b>1148</b><i>a </i>and MPR<b>4</b> <b>1148</b><i>b</i>. The transistor MPR<b>3</b> <b>1148</b><i>a </i>includes a first controlled terminal (e.g. source terminal) <b>1150</b><i>a</i>, a second controlled terminal (e.g. drain terminal) <b>1152</b><i>a</i>, a control terminal (e.g. gate terminal) <b>1154</b><i>a</i>, and a bulk terminal <b>1156</b><i>a</i>, and the transistor MPR<b>4</b> <b>1148</b><i>b </i>includes a first controlled terminal (e.g. source terminal) <b>1150</b><i>b</i>, a second controlled terminal (e.g. drain terminal) <b>1152</b><i>b</i>, a control terminal (e.g. gate terminal) <b>1154</b><i>b</i>, and a bulk terminal <b>1156</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0170" num="0169">The first controlled terminals <b>1150</b><i>a</i>, <b>1150</b><i>b </i>are coupled to each other. The second controlled terminal <b>1152</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MPR<b>3</b> <b>1148</b><i>a </i>is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>1120</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MN<b>2</b> <b>1102</b><i>b</i>. The second controlled terminal <b>1152</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MPR<b>4</b> <b>1148</b><i>b </i>is coupled to the control terminal <b>1122</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MN<b>2</b> <b>1102</b><i>b</i>. The control terminal <b>1154</b><i>a </i>is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>1152</b><i>a</i>. The control terminal <b>1154</b><i>b </i>is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>1152</b><i>b</i>. The bulk terminals <b>1156</b><i>a</i>, <b>1156</b><i>b </i>are coupled to each other and also coupled to the first controlled terminals <b>1150</b><i>a</i>, <b>1150</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0171" num="0170">The resistive element Rf<b>3</b> <b>1136</b> includes transistors (e.g. PMOS transistors) MPR<b>5</b> <b>1158</b><i>a </i>and MPR<b>6</b> <b>1158</b><i>b</i>. The transistor MPR<b>5</b> <b>1158</b><i>a </i>includes a first controlled terminal (e.g. source terminal) <b>1160</b><i>a</i>, a second controlled terminal (e.g. drain terminal) <b>1162</b><i>a</i>, a control terminal (e.g. gate terminal) <b>1164</b><i>a</i>, and a bulk terminal <b>1166</b><i>a</i>, and the transistor MPR<b>6</b> <b>1158</b><i>b </i>includes a first controlled terminal (e.g. source terminal) <b>1160</b><i>b</i>, a second controlled terminal (e.g. drain terminal) <b>1162</b><i>b</i>, a control terminal (e.g. gate terminal) <b>1164</b><i>b</i>, and a bulk terminal <b>1166</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0172" num="0171">The first controlled terminals <b>1160</b><i>a</i>, <b>1160</b><i>b </i>are coupled to each other. The second controlled terminal <b>1162</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MPR<b>5</b> <b>1158</b><i>a </i>is coupled to the control terminal <b>1130</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MP<b>1</b> <b>1124</b><i>a</i>. The second controlled terminal <b>1162</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MPR<b>6</b> <b>1158</b><i>b </i>is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>1128</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MP<b>1</b> <b>1124</b><i>a</i>. The control terminal <b>1164</b><i>a </i>is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>1162</b><i>a</i>. The control terminal <b>1164</b><i>b </i>is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>1162</b><i>b</i>. The bulk terminals <b>1166</b><i>a</i>, <b>1166</b><i>b </i>are coupled to each other and also coupled to the first controlled terminals <b>1160</b><i>a</i>, <b>1160</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0173" num="0172">The resistive element Rf<b>4</b> <b>1138</b> includes transistors (e.g. PMOS transistors) MPR<b>7</b> <b>1168</b><i>a </i>and MPR<b>8</b> <b>1168</b><i>b</i>. The transistor MPR<b>7</b> <b>1168</b><i>a </i>includes a first controlled terminal (e.g. source terminal) <b>1170</b><i>a</i>, a second controlled terminal (e.g. drain terminal) <b>1172</b><i>a</i>, a control terminal (e.g. gate terminal) <b>1174</b><i>a</i>, and a bulk terminal <b>1176</b><i>a</i>, and the transistor MPR<b>8</b> <b>1168</b><i>b </i>includes a first controlled terminal (e.g. source terminal) <b>1170</b><i>b</i>, a second controlled terminal (e.g. drain terminal) <b>1172</b><i>b</i>, a control terminal (e.g. gate terminal) <b>1174</b><i>b</i>, and a bulk terminal <b>1176</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0174" num="0173">The first controlled terminals <b>1170</b><i>a</i>, <b>1170</b><i>b </i>are coupled to each other. The second controlled terminal <b>1172</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MPR<b>7</b> <b>1168</b><i>a </i>is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>1128</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MP<b>2</b> <b>1124</b><i>b</i>. The second controlled terminal <b>1172</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MPR<b>8</b> <b>1168</b><i>b </i>is coupled to the control terminal <b>1130</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MP<b>2</b> <b>1124</b><i>b</i>. The control terminal <b>1174</b><i>a </i>is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>1172</b><i>a</i>. The control terminal <b>1174</b><i>b </i>is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>1172</b><i>b</i>. The bulk terminals <b>1176</b><i>a</i>, <b>1176</b><i>b </i>are coupled to each other and also coupled to the first controlled terminals <b>1170</b><i>a</i>, <b>1170</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0175" num="0174">It should be appreciated that any one or each of the resistive element Rf<b>1</b> <b>1132</b>, the resistive element Rf<b>2</b> <b>1134</b>, the resistive element Rf<b>3</b> <b>1136</b> and the resistive element Rf<b>4</b> <b>1138</b> may also be at least substantially same, for example in terms of the arrangements of the PMOS transistors, as any one of the resistive element Rf<b>1</b> <b>430</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) or the resistive element Rf<b>2</b> <b>432</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0176" num="0175">The circuit arrangement <b>1100</b> may further include a capacitor C<b>1</b> <b>1178</b> coupled in series with the inductor Lg<b>1</b> <b>1110</b> and the control terminal <b>1122</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>1102</b><i>a </i>(e.g. coupled between the second terminal of the inductor Lg<b>1</b> <b>1110</b> and the control terminal <b>1122</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>1102</b><i>a</i>), a capacitor C<b>2</b> <b>1179</b> coupled in series with the inductor Lg<b>2</b> <b>1112</b> and the control terminal <b>1122</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MN<b>2</b> <b>1102</b><i>b </i>(e.g. coupled between the first terminal of the inductor Lg<b>2</b> <b>1112</b> and the control terminal <b>1122</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MN<b>2</b> <b>1102</b><i>b</i>), a capacitor C<b>3</b> <b>1180</b> coupled in series with the inductor Lg<b>1</b> <b>1110</b> and the control terminal <b>1130</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MP<b>1</b> <b>1124</b><i>a </i>(e.g. coupled between the second terminal of the inductor Lg<b>1</b> <b>1110</b> and the control terminal <b>1130</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MP<b>1</b> <b>1124</b><i>a</i>), and a capacitor C<b>4</b> <b>1181</b> coupled in series with the inductor Lg<b>2</b> <b>1112</b> and the control terminal <b>1130</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MP<b>2</b> <b>1124</b><i>b </i>(e.g. coupled between the first terminal of the inductor Lg<b>2</b> <b>1112</b> and the control terminal <b>1130</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MP<b>2</b> <b>1124</b><i>b</i>).</p>
<p id="p-0177" num="0176">The circuit arrangement <b>400</b> further includes an output terminal <b>1182</b>, from which an output signal (e.g. a baseband signal) V<sub>on </sub><b>1183</b> may be extracted, coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>1120</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>1102</b><i>a </i>and the second controlled terminal <b>1120</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MN<b>2</b> <b>1102</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0178" num="0177">The circuit arrangement <b>400</b> further includes an output terminal <b>1184</b>, from which an output signal (e.g. a baseband signal) V<sub>op </sub><b>1185</b> may be extracted, coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>1128</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MP<b>1</b> <b>1124</b><i>a </i>and the second controlled terminal <b>1128</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MP<b>2</b> <b>1124</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0179" num="0178">The circuit arrangement <b>1100</b> may further include a current source <b>1186</b> providing a current I<sub>REF</sub>, wherein a first terminal of the current source <b>1186</b> is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>1120</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MN<b>1</b> <b>1102</b><i>a</i>, the second controlled terminal <b>1120</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MN<b>2</b> <b>1102</b><i>b </i>and the output terminal <b>1182</b>, and a second terminal of the current source <b>1186</b> is coupled to a voltage reference point V<sub>2</sub>, which may be a power supply line.</p>
<p id="p-0180" num="0179">In various embodiments, the circuit arrangement <b>1100</b> may further include a capacitor Con <b>1188</b>, wherein a first terminal of the capacitor Con <b>1188</b> is coupled to the first terminal of the current source <b>1186</b> and the output terminal <b>1182</b>, and a second terminal of the capacitor Con <b>1188</b> is coupled to a voltage reference point V<sub>1</sub>, which may be a ground terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0181" num="0180">The circuit arrangement <b>1100</b> may further include a resistor R<sub>REF </sub><b>1190</b>, wherein a first terminal of the resistor R<sub>REF </sub><b>1190</b> is coupled to the second controlled terminal <b>1128</b><i>a </i>of the transistor MP<b>1</b> <b>1124</b><i>a</i>, the second controlled terminal <b>1128</b><i>b </i>of the transistor MP<b>2</b> <b>1124</b><i>b </i>and the output terminal <b>1184</b>, and a second terminal of the resistor R<sub>REF </sub><b>1190</b> is coupled to a voltage reference point V<sub>1</sub>, which may be a ground terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0182" num="0181">In various embodiments, the circuit arrangement <b>1100</b> may further include a capacitor Cop <b>1192</b>, wherein a first terminal of the capacitor Cop <b>1192</b> is coupled to the first terminal of the R<sub>REF </sub><b>1190</b> and the output terminal <b>1184</b>, and a second terminal of the capacitor Cop <b>1192</b> is coupled to a voltage reference point V<sub>1</sub>, which may be a ground terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0183" num="0182">The gates or control terminals <b>1122</b><i>a</i>, <b>1122</b><i>b</i>, <b>1130</b><i>a</i>, <b>1130</b><i>b </i>of the transistors MN<b>1</b> <b>1102</b><i>a</i>, MN<b>2</b> <b>1102</b><i>b</i>, MP<b>1</b> <b>1124</b><i>a</i>, MP<b>2</b> <b>1124</b><i>b </i>are biased via the pseudo-resistors or resistive elements Rf<b>1</b> <b>1132</b>, Rf<b>2</b> <b>1134</b>, Rf<b>3</b> <b>1136</b>, Rf<b>4</b> <b>1138</b> respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0184" num="0183">The capacitors C<b>1</b> <b>1178</b> and C<b>3</b> <b>1180</b> provide direct current (DC) blocking from the input terminal <b>1106</b>, and the capacitors C<b>2</b> <b>1179</b> and C<b>4</b> <b>1181</b> provide direct current (DC) blocking from the input terminal <b>1108</b>, and therefore their capacitance should be large compared to the gate capacitance of the respective transistors MN<b>1</b> <b>1102</b><i>a</i>, MN<b>2</b> <b>1102</b><i>b</i>, MP<b>1</b> <b>1124</b><i>a</i>, MP<b>2</b> <b>1124</b><i>b </i>in order to obtain maximum voltage swing at the respective control terminals <b>1122</b><i>a</i>, <b>1122</b><i>b</i>, <b>1130</b><i>a</i>, <b>1130</b><i>b</i>. The capacitors Con <b>1188</b> and Cop <b>1192</b> act to sustain the output voltages and may work as part of the low pass filter (e.g. <b>306</b>) with an output resistance.</p>
<p id="p-0185" num="0184">It should be appreciated that the descriptions of features in the context of the circuit arrangement <b>400</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> that are similarly present in the circuit arrangement <b>1100</b>, and also the associated results of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 to 10</figref>, may be applicable to the circuit arrangement <b>1100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0186" num="0185">The circuit arrangement <b>1100</b> illustrates a fully differential implementation of the active RF detector of various embodiments, which may be robust or provide at least some immunity against common mode noise.</p>
<p id="p-0187" num="0186">The circuit arrangement <b>400</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) illustrates an implementation of the active RF detector of various embodiments, including an amplitude detector having a pair of transistors MN<b>1</b> <b>402</b><i>a</i>, MN<b>2</b> <b>402</b><i>b</i>, and an LC matching circuit, with differential inputs V<sub>RF+</sub> <b>404</b>, V<sub>RF&#x2212;</sub> <b>405</b>, received through a &#x201c;positive&#x201d; input terminal <b>406</b> and a &#x201c;negative&#x201d; input terminal <b>408</b>, and a single-ended output V<sub>out </sub><b>453</b> provided from the output terminal <b>452</b>. The circuit arrangement <b>1100</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) illustrates an implementation of the active RF detector of various embodiments, including an amplitude detector having two pairs of transistors MN<b>1</b> <b>1102</b><i>a</i>, MN<b>2</b> <b>1102</b><i>b</i>, and MP<b>1</b> <b>1124</b><i>a</i>, MP<b>2</b> <b>1124</b><i>b</i>, and an LC matching circuit, with differential inputs V<sub>RF+</sub> <b>1104</b>, V<sub>RF&#x2212;</sub> <b>1105</b>, received through a &#x201c;positive&#x201d; input terminal <b>1106</b> and a &#x201c;negative&#x201d; input terminal <b>1108</b>, and differential outputs V<sub>on </sub><b>1183</b>, V<sub>op </sub><b>1185</b> provided from the output terminals <b>1182</b>, <b>1184</b>. Therefore, the circuit arrangement <b>1100</b> is a fully differential implementation or version of the circuit arrangement <b>400</b>, and may provide improved robustness or immunity against common mode noise.</p>
<p id="p-0188" num="0187">Various embodiments may provide an ultra-low power wake-up receiver (RF receiver) based on the high sensitivity RF detector of various embodiments. The active RF detector of various embodiments, co-designed or embedded with an inductive source degeneration LC network or input matching network/circuit, provides high sensitivity and selectivity for the RF receiver. The input matching network or LC network provides selectivity and impedance matching to the antenna and also offers voltage gain via its quality factor.</p>
<p id="p-0189" num="0188">As shown by the fully integrated schematic and system analysis, the sensitivity of the RF detector may achieve approximately &#x2212;70 dBm, without power burden compared to conventional approaches, so as to achieve ultra-low power consumptions of about 10 &#x3bc;W. The receiver or detector of various embodiments may also be designed to be powered by ambient energy harvesting, without battery, and/or having an average current of about 10 nA and/or having an operating current of about 200 &#x3bc;A.</p>
<p id="p-0190" num="0189">Various embodiments of the ultra-low power wake-up receiver includes a continuous-time sigma-delta analogue-to-digital converter (CT &#x3a3;&#x394; ADC) to provide oversampling to improve the signal to noise ratio (SNR) of the receiver.</p>
<p id="p-0191" num="0190">Various embodiments of the receiver or detector offer low power and high carrier frequency operation with high sensitivity. Various embodiments of the receiver or detector may be employed in on-off keyed (OOK) and amplitude modulated (AM) applications.</p>
<p id="p-0192" num="0191">Various embodiments may not require RF gain amplifiers in order to reduce power consumption. Therefore, a wake-up receiver with a high sensitivity detector, without RF amplification, may be power efficient. Various embodiments may also not require oscillators or additional external components.</p>
<p id="p-0193" num="0192">While the invention has been particularly shown and described with reference to specific embodiments, it should be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes in form and detail may be made therein without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention as defined by the appended claims. The elements of the various embodiments may be incorporated into each of the other species to obtain the benefits of those elements in combination with such other species, and the various beneficial features may be employed in embodiments alone or in combination with each other. The scope of the invention is thus indicated by the appended claims and all changes which come within the meaning and range of equivalency of the claims are therefore intended to be embraced.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00001" nb-file="US08626110-20140107-M00001.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00001" he="8.47mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08626110-20140107-M00001.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00002" nb-file="US08626110-20140107-M00002.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00002" he="7.03mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08626110-20140107-M00002.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00003" nb-file="US08626110-20140107-M00003.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00003" he="17.27mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08626110-20140107-M00003.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00004" nb-file="US08626110-20140107-M00004.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00004" he="6.35mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08626110-20140107-M00004.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00005" nb-file="US08626110-20140107-M00005.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00005" he="6.69mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08626110-20140107-M00005.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00006" nb-file="US08626110-20140107-M00006.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00006" he="6.01mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08626110-20140107-M00006.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00007" nb-file="US08626110-20140107-M00007.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00007" he="7.79mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08626110-20140107-M00007.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00008" nb-file="US08626110-20140107-M00008.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00008" he="8.47mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08626110-20140107-M00008.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00009" nb-file="US08626110-20140107-M00009.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00009" he="12.70mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08626110-20140107-M00009.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00010" nb-file="US08626110-20140107-M00010.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00010" he="7.03mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08626110-20140107-M00010.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00011" nb-file="US08626110-20140107-M00011.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00011" he="7.45mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08626110-20140107-M00011.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A circuit arrangement, comprising:
<claim-text>a first input terminal and a second input terminal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first transistor and a second transistor, each of the first transistor and the second transistor having a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal and a control terminal, the first controlled terminal of the first transistor being coupled to the first controlled terminal of the second transistor, the control terminal of the first transistor being coupled to the first input terminal, the control terminal of the second transistor being coupled to the second input terminal, and the second controlled terminal of the first transistor being coupled to the second controlled terminal of the second transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an input matching circuit coupled to the first input terminal, the second input terminal, the first transistor and the second transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first resistive element coupled between the control terminal of the first transistor and the second controlled terminal of the first transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second resistive element coupled between the control terminal of the second transistor and the second controlled terminal of the second transistor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an output terminal coupled to the second controlled terminal of the first transistor and the second controlled terminal of the second transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the input matching circuit comprises a first inductor, a second inductor, a third inductor, a first capacitor and a second capacitor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first inductor is coupled between the first input terminal and the control terminal of the first transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second inductor is coupled between the first controlled terminal of the first transistor and the first controlled terminal of the second transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the third inductor is coupled between the second input terminal and the control terminal of the second transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first capacitor is coupled between the control terminal of the first transistor and the first controlled terminal of the first transistor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second capacitor is coupled between the control terminal of the second transistor and the first controlled terminal of the second transistor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The circuit arrangement of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a third capacitor coupled in series with the first input terminal and the first inductor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth capacitor coupled in series with the second input terminal and the third inductor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The circuit arrangement of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the first resistive element comprises:
<claim-text>a third transistor and a fourth transistor, each of the third transistor and the fourth transistor having a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal, a control terminal and a bulk terminal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first controlled terminal of the third transistor is coupled to the first controlled terminal of the fourth transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second controlled terminal of the third transistor is coupled to the control terminal of the first transistor, and the second controlled terminal of the fourth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the first transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the bulk terminal of the third transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the third transistor, and the bulk terminal of the fourth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the fourth transistor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the control terminal of the third transistor is coupled to the control terminal of the fourth transistor, the first controlled terminal of the third transistor and the first controlled terminal of the fourth transistor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The circuit arrangement of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the second resistive element comprises:
<claim-text>a fifth transistor and a sixth transistor, each of the fifth transistor and the sixth transistor having a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal, a control terminal and a bulk terminal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first controlled terminal of the fifth transistor is coupled to the first controlled terminal of the sixth transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second controlled terminal of the fifth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the second transistor, and the second controlled terminal of the sixth transistor is coupled to the control terminal of the second transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the bulk terminal of the fifth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the fifth transistor, and the bulk terminal of the sixth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the sixth transistor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the control terminal of the fifth transistor is coupled to the control terminal of the sixth transistor, the first controlled terminal of the fifth transistor and the first controlled terminal of the sixth transistor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The circuit arrangement of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a current mirror circuit coupled to the second controlled terminal of the first transistor, the second controlled terminal of the second transistor, and the output terminal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The circuit arrangement of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the current mirror circuit comprises:
<claim-text>a seventh transistor and an eighth transistor, each of the seventh transistor and the eighth transistor having a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal and a control terminal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first controlled terminal of the seventh transistor and the first controlled terminal of the eighth transistor are coupled to a first voltage reference point;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the control terminal of the seventh transistor is coupled to the control terminal of the eighth transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second controlled terminal of the seventh transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the first transistor, the second controlled terminal of the second transistor and the output terminal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second controlled terminal of the eighth transistor is coupled to the control terminal of the seventh transistor and the control terminal of the eighth transistor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The circuit arrangement of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, further comprising a current source having a first terminal and a second terminal, wherein the first terminal of the current source is coupled to the control terminal of the seventh transistor, the control terminal of the eighth transistor and the second controlled terminal of the eighth transistor, and the second terminal of the current source is coupled to a second voltage reference point.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A receiver comprising a circuit arrangement of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A circuit arrangement, comprising:
<claim-text>a first input terminal and a second input terminal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first transistor and a second transistor, each of the first transistor and the second transistor having a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal and a control terminal, the first controlled terminal of the first transistor being coupled to the first controlled terminal of the second transistor, the control terminal of the first transistor being coupled to the first input terminal, the control terminal of the second transistor being coupled to the second input terminal, and the second controlled terminal of the first transistor being coupled to the second controlled terminal of the second transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third transistor and a fourth transistor, each of the third transistor and the fourth transistor having a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal and a control terminal, the first controlled terminal of the third transistor being coupled to the first controlled terminal of the fourth transistor, the control terminal of the third transistor being coupled to the first input terminal, the control terminal of the fourth transistor being coupled to the second input terminal, and the second controlled terminal of the third transistor being coupled to the second controlled terminal of the fourth transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an input matching circuit coupled to the first input terminal, the second input terminal, the first transistor, the second transistor, the third transistor and the fourth transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first resistive element coupled between the control terminal of the first transistor and the second controlled terminal of the first transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second resistive element coupled between the control terminal of the second transistor and the second controlled terminal of the second transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third resistive element coupled between the control terminal of the third transistor and the second controlled terminal of the third transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth resistive element coupled between the control terminal of the fourth transistor and the second controlled terminal of the fourth transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first output terminal coupled to the second controlled terminal of the first transistor and the second controlled terminal of the second transistor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second output terminal coupled to the second controlled terminal of the third transistor and the second controlled terminal of the fourth transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the input matching circuit comprises a first inductor, a second inductor, a third inductor, a first capacitor, a second capacitor, a third capacitor and a fourth capacitor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first inductor comprises a first terminal coupled to the first input terminal, and a second terminal coupled to the control terminal of the first transistor and the control terminal of the third transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second inductor comprises a first terminal coupled to the first controlled terminal of the first transistor, the first controlled terminal of the second transistor, the first controlled terminal of the third transistor and the first controlled terminal of the fourth transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the third inductor comprises a first terminal coupled to the control terminal of the second transistor and the control terminal of the fourth transistor, and a second terminal coupled to the second input terminal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first capacitor is coupled between the control terminal of the first transistor and the first controlled terminal of the first transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second capacitor is coupled between the control terminal of the second transistor and the first controlled terminal of the second transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the third capacitor is coupled between the control terminal of the third transistor and the first controlled terminal of the third transistor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the fourth capacitor is coupled between the control terminal of the fourth transistor and the first controlled terminal of the fourth transistor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The circuit arrangement of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the input matching circuit further comprises a fifth capacitor having a first terminal and a second terminal, wherein the first terminal of the fifth capacitor is coupled to a second terminal of the second inductor of the input matching circuit, and the second terminal of the fifth capacitor is coupled to a first voltage reference point.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The circuit arrangement of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a sixth capacitor coupled in series with the first inductor and the control terminal of the first transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a seventh capacitor coupled in series with the third inductor and the control terminal of the second transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an eighth capacitor coupled in series with the first inductor and the control terminal of the third transistor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a ninth capacitor coupled in series with the third inductor and the control terminal of the fourth transistor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The circuit arrangement of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the first resistive element comprises:
<claim-text>a fifth transistor and a sixth transistor, each of the fifth transistor and the sixth transistor having a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal, a control terminal and a bulk terminal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first controlled terminal of the fifth transistor is coupled to the first controlled terminal of the sixth transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second controlled terminal of the fifth transistor is coupled to the control terminal of the first transistor, and the second controlled terminal of the sixth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the first transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the control terminal of the fifth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the fifth transistor, and the control terminal of the sixth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the sixth transistor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the bulk terminal of the fifth transistor is coupled to the bulk terminal of the sixth transistor, the first controlled terminal of the fifth transistor and the first controlled terminal of the sixth transistor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The circuit arrangement of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the second resistive element comprises:
<claim-text>a seventh transistor and an eighth transistor, each of the seventh transistor and the eighth transistor having a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal, a control terminal and a bulk terminal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first controlled terminal of the seventh transistor is coupled to the first controlled terminal of the eighth transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second controlled terminal of the seventh transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the second transistor, and the second controlled terminal of the eighth transistor is coupled to the control terminal of the second transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the control terminal of the seventh transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the seventh transistor, and the control terminal of the eighth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the eighth transistor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the bulk terminal of the seventh transistor is coupled to the bulk terminal of the eighth transistor, the first controlled terminal of the seventh transistor and the first controlled terminal of the eighth transistor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The circuit arrangement of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the third resistive element comprises:
<claim-text>a ninth transistor and a tenth transistor, each of the ninth transistor and the tenth transistor having a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal, a control terminal and a bulk terminal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first controlled terminal of the ninth transistor is coupled to the first controlled terminal of the tenth transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second controlled terminal of the ninth transistor is coupled to the control terminal of the third transistor, and the second controlled terminal of the tenth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the third transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the control terminal of the ninth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the ninth transistor, and the control terminal of the tenth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the tenth transistor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the bulk terminal of the ninth transistor is coupled to the bulk terminal of the tenth transistor, the first controlled terminal of the ninth transistor and the first controlled terminal of the tenth transistor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The circuit arrangement of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the fourth resistive element comprises:
<claim-text>an eleventh transistor and a twelfth transistor, each of the eleventh transistor and the twelfth transistor having a first controlled terminal, a second controlled terminal, a control terminal and a bulk terminal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first controlled terminal of the eleventh transistor is coupled to the first controlled terminal of the twelfth transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second controlled terminal of the eleventh transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the fourth transistor, and the second controlled terminal of the twelfth transistor is coupled to the control terminal of the fourth transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the control terminal of the eleventh transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the eleventh transistor, and the control terminal of the twelfth transistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the twelfth transistor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the bulk terminal of the eleventh transistor is coupled to the bulk terminal of the twelfth transistor, the first controlled terminal of the eleventh transistor and the first controlled terminal of the twelfth transistor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The circuit arrangement of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further comprising a current source having a first terminal and a second terminal, wherein the first terminal of the current source is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the first transistor, the second controlled terminal of the second transistor and the first output terminal, and the second terminal of the current source is coupled to a second voltage reference point.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The circuit arrangement of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, further comprising a tenth capacitor having a first terminal and a second terminal, wherein the first terminal of the tenth capacitor is coupled to the first terminal of the current source and the first output terminal, and the second terminal of the tenth capacitor is coupled to the first voltage reference point.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The circuit arrangement of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further comprising a resistor having a first terminal and a second terminal, wherein the first terminal of the resistor is coupled to the second controlled terminal of the third transistor, the second controlled terminal of the fourth transistor and the second output terminal, and the second terminal of the resistor is coupled to a first voltage reference point.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The circuit arrangement of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, further comprising an eleventh capacitor having a first terminal and a second terminal, wherein the first terminal of the eleventh capacitor is coupled to the first terminal of the resistor and the second output terminal, and the second terminal of the eleventh capacitor is coupled to the first voltage reference point.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. A receiver comprising a circuit arrangement of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
