<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624128-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624128</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13235110</doc-number>
<date>20110916</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2010-0093756</doc-number>
<date>20100928</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>83</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>174259</main-classification>
<further-classification>174255</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Printed circuit board and manufacturing method thereof</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6787923</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Tan et al.</name>
<date>20040900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257779</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7271347</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Ohwaki</name>
<date>20070900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>174252</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7321099</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Mishiro</name>
<date>20080100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>174260</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>8</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>12</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120073861</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120329</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hong</last-name>
<first-name>Ju-Pyo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kweon</last-name>
<first-name>Young-Do</first-name>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Jin-Gu</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="004" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Moon</last-name>
<first-name>Seon-Hee</first-name>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="005" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lee</last-name>
<first-name>Dong-Jin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="006" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Park</last-name>
<first-name>Seung-Wook</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hong</last-name>
<first-name>Ju-Pyo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kweon</last-name>
<first-name>Young-Do</first-name>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Jin-Gu</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="004" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Moon</last-name>
<first-name>Seon-Hee</first-name>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="005" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lee</last-name>
<first-name>Dong-Jin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="006" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Park</last-name>
<first-name>Seung-Wook</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>McDermott Will &#x26; Emery LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Samsung Electro-Mechanics Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Suwon</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Patel</last-name>
<first-name>Ishwarbhai</first-name>
<department>2835</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A printed circuit board and a manufacturing method of the printed circuit board are disclosed. The printed circuit board includes: a first insulation layer having a first pattern formed thereon; a first trench caved in one surface of the first insulation layer along at least a portion of the first pattern; and a second insulation layer stacked on one surface of the first insulation layer so as to cover the first pattern. The first trench is filled by the second insulation layer.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="54.86mm" wi="150.71mm" file="US08624128-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="124.54mm" wi="153.84mm" file="US08624128-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="204.30mm" wi="127.51mm" file="US08624128-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="112.78mm" wi="123.61mm" file="US08624128-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="196.17mm" wi="156.04mm" file="US08624128-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="187.20mm" wi="158.24mm" file="US08624128-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="127.85mm" wi="147.24mm" file="US08624128-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of Korean Patent Application No. 10-2010-0093756, filed with the Korean Intellectual Property Office on Sep. 28, 2010, the disclosure of which is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention is related to a printed circuit board and a manufacturing method of the printed circuit board.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Background Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Generally, a printed circuit board is manufactured by forming a circuit pattern on the surface of a core board, stacking an insulation layer over the circuit pattern, and then forming a circuit pattern again on the surface of the insulation layer. By repeating this process, a printed circuit board having the desired number of layers can be manufactured.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In order for this printed circuit board to have sufficient product reliability during its use, the problem of the circuit pattern being peeled off from the core board and the insulation layer or being cracked needs to be resolved.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">However, in the conventional printed circuit board, the core board is relatively wider and more continuous than the circuit pattern, and thus the overall rigidity and expansion of the core board has caused thermal stress in the wired circuit. In effect, this thermal stress has caused the circuit pattern to be peeled off and cracked.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The present invention provides a printed circuit board and a manufacturing method of the printed circuit board that can reduce the stress occurred in the circuit pattern by reducing the thermal stress at a portion where the circuit pattern is formed.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">An aspect of the preset invention features a printed circuit board that includes: a first insulation layer having a first pattern formed thereon; a first trench caved in one surface of the first insulation layer along at least a portion of the first pattern; and a second insulation layer stacked on one surface of the first insulation layer so as to cover the first pattern. The first trench can be filled by the second insulation layer.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Here, materials for the first insulation layer and the second insulation layer can be different from each other.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The printed circuit board can also include: a second pattern formed on one surface of the second insulation layer; a second trench caved in one surface of the second insulation layer along at least a portion of the second pattern; and a third insulation layer stacked on one surface of the second insulation layer so as to cover the second pattern. The second trench can be filled by the third insulation layer.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The first insulation layer can be a core board.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The first pattern can include a plurality of wired lines that are separated from one another, and the first trench can be formed between the plurality of wired lines. Moreover, distances between the plurality of wired lines may not be constant, and the width of the first trench can vary according to the distance between the plurality of wired lines.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The first pattern can include a plurality of parts that are functionally distinguishable, and the first trench can be formed along a border of adjacent parts. Also, the first trench can be formed to surround at least one of the plurality of parts.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The first insulation layer can include: a base layer; and</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">a medium layer formed on the base layer. The first pattern and the first trench can be formed on the medium layer.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Another aspect of the present invention features a method of manufacturing a printed circuit board. The method of manufacturing a printed circuit board in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention can include: forming a first pattern on one surface of a first insulation layer; caving a first trench in one surface of the first insulation layer along at least a portion of the first pattern; and stacking a second insulation layer on one surface of the first insulation layer so as to cover the first pattern. The first trench can be filled by the second insulation layer.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The caving of the first trench can be performed by a laser processing, and materials for the first insulation layer and the second insulation layer can be different from each other.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The method can also include: forming a second pattern on one surface of the second insulation layer; caving a second trench in one surface of the second insulation layer along at least a portion of the second pattern; and stacking a third insulation layer on one surface of the second insulation layer so as to cover the second pattern. The second trench can be filled by the third insulation layer.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The first pattern can include a plurality of wired lines that are separated from one another, and the first trench can be formed between the plurality of wired lines. Moreover, distances between the plurality of wired lines may not be constant, and the width of the first trench can vary according to the distance between the plurality of wired lines.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The first pattern can include a plurality of parts that are functionally distinguishable, and the first trench can be formed along a border of adjacent parts. Also, the first trench can be formed to surround at least one of the plurality of parts.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The first insulation layer can include: a base layer; and a medium layer formed on the base layer. The first pattern and the first trench can be formed on the medium layer.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a sectional view illustrating an embodiment of a printed circuit board in accordance with an aspect of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a sectional view illustrating another embodiment of a printed circuit board in accordance with an aspect of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a top view illustrating an embodiment of a printed circuit board in accordance with an aspect of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref> are top views illustrating another embodiment of a printed circuit board in accordance with an aspect of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flow diagram illustrating an embodiment of a manufacturing method of the printed circuit board in accordance with another aspect of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 to 12</figref> are process diagrams illustrating an embodiment of a manufacturing method of the printed circuit board in accordance with another aspect of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Since there can be a variety of permutations and embodiments of the present invention, certain embodiments will be illustrated and described with reference to the accompanying drawings. This, however, is by no means to restrict the present invention to certain embodiments, and shall be construed as including all permutations, equivalents and substitutes covered by the ideas and scope of the present invention. Throughout the description of the present invention, when describing a certain technology is determined to evade the point of the present invention, the pertinent detailed description will be omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Terms such as &#x201c;first&#x201d; and &#x201c;second&#x201d; can be used in describing various elements, but the above elements shall not be restricted to the above terms. The above terms are used only to distinguish one element from the other.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The terms used in the description are intended to describe certain embodiments only, and shall by no means restrict the present invention. Unless clearly used otherwise, expressions in a singular form include a meaning of a plural form. In the present description, an expression such as &#x201c;comprising&#x201d; or &#x201c;including&#x201d; is intended to designate a characteristic, a number, a step, an operation, an element, a part or combinations thereof, and shall not be construed to preclude any presence or possibility of one or more other characteristics, numbers, steps, operations, elements, parts or combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Hereinafter, some embodiments of a printed circuit board and a manufacturing method of the printed circuit board in accordance with the present invention will be described with reference to the accompanying drawings. In describing with reference to the accompanying drawings, any identical or corresponding elements will be given same reference numerals, and description of the identical or corresponding elements will not be repeated.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a sectional view of an embodiment of a printed circuit board in accordance with an aspect of the present invention. Illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> are a first insulation layer <b>100</b>, a first pattern <b>110</b>, a first trench <b>120</b>, a second insulation layer <b>200</b>, a second pattern <b>210</b>, a second trench <b>220</b> and a third insulation layer <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the printed circuit board in accordance with the present embodiment includes: the first insulation layer <b>100</b>, which has the first pattern <b>110</b> formed on one surface of thereof; the first trench <b>120</b>, which is caved in one surface of the first insulation layer <b>100</b> along at least a portion of the first pattern <b>110</b>; and the second insulation layer <b>200</b>, which is stacked on one surface of the first insulation layer <b>100</b> so as to cover the first pattern <b>110</b>. The first trench <b>120</b> is filled by the second insulation layer <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">With this embodiment, by forming the first trench <b>120</b>, which is formed along the first pattern <b>110</b>, on the first insulation layer <b>100</b> having the first pattern <b>110</b> formed on the surface thereof, the continuity of expansion can be locally blocked by the first trench <b>120</b> and the second insulation layer that fills up the first trench <b>120</b> in case the first insulation layer <b>100</b> is expanded by heat. As a result, the rigidity of the first insulation layer <b>100</b> can be reduced, and the stress exerted to the first pattern <b>110</b> by the expansion can be reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Here, the first insulation layer <b>100</b> in which the first pattern <b>110</b> and the first trench <b>120</b> are formed can be a core board in which a reinforcing material, such as glass fiber and carbon fiber, is impregnated in an epoxy resin, and can be an individual insulation layer that carries out an inter-layer insulating function in a multi-layer printed circuit board. Moreover, the first insulation layer <b>100</b> can be a substrate or an interposer that uses ceramic or silicon.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the first insulation layer <b>100</b> can include a base layer <b>100</b>A and a medium layer <b>100</b>B, which is formed above the base layer <b>100</b>A. In some cases, it may be difficult to form roughness on a surface of a board material that is used for the first insulation layer <b>100</b>, and it may be difficult to form the first pattern <b>110</b> on the first insulation layer <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In such cases, by using a material having the structure in which the medium layer <b>100</b>B is formed above the base layer <b>100</b>A, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, roughness can be readily formed on the medium layer <b>100</b>B, making it possible to solve the above-described problem. Here, the first pattern <b>110</b> and the first trench <b>120</b> can be formed on the medium layer <b>100</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Used for the base layer <b>100</b>A can be a copper-clad laminate (CCL), a silicon substrate, an LCP substrate and the like, and used for the medium layer <b>100</b>B can be polyimide, photo-resistor, benzocyclobutene (BCB).</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In case the materials for the first insulation layer <b>100</b> and the second insulation layer <b>200</b> are different from each other, the first trench <b>120</b> formed in the first insulation layer <b>100</b> can function as a stress buffer between the materials.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the printed circuit board in accordance with the present embodiment can also include: the second pattern <b>210</b>, which is caved in one surface of the second insulation layer <b>200</b>; the second trench, which is formed on one surface of the second insulation layer <b>200</b> along at least a portion of the second pattern <b>210</b>; and the third insulation layer <b>300</b>, which is stacked on one surface of the second insulation layer <b>200</b> so as to cover the second pattern <b>210</b>. The second trench <b>220</b> is filled by the third insulation layer <b>300</b>. In other words, the structure in which the trench is formed along the pattern can be repeated in each layer of a multi-layered printed circuit board.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the first pattern <b>110</b> can include a plurality of wired lines <b>110</b>A, <b>110</b>B that are separated from one another, and the first trench <b>120</b> can be formed between the plurality of wired lines <b>110</b>A, <b>110</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Here, in case the distances between the plurality of wired lines <b>110</b>A, <b>110</b>B are not constant, the width of the first trench <b>120</b> can vary according to the distance between the plurality of wired lines <b>110</b>A, <b>110</b>B. That is, if the adjacent wired lines <b>110</b>A, <b>110</b>B are arranged with a uniform distance and are bent to diverge from each other at one end, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the space becomes larger where the wired lines <b>110</b>A, <b>110</b>B are bent. Here, in order to better function as the stress buffer, the width of the first trench <b>120</b>B where the space between the wired lines <b>110</b>A, <b>110</b>B becomes larger can be greater than that of the first trench <b>120</b>A that is formed elsewhere.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, in case the first pattern <b>110</b> includes a plurality of parts <b>110</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>110</b>-<b>2</b> that are functionally distinguishable, the first trench <b>120</b> can be formed along a border between the adjacent parts <b>110</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>110</b>-<b>2</b>. For example, if a digital part <b>110</b>-<b>1</b>, which transceives digital signals, and an RF part <b>110</b>-<b>2</b>, which transceives analog signals, are arranged together on the first insulation layer <b>100</b>, the first trench <b>120</b> can be formed between the two parts to mitigate the stress exerted on the two parts.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Moreover, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the first trench <b>120</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>120</b>-<b>2</b>, <b>120</b>-<b>3</b>, <b>120</b>-<b>4</b>, <b>120</b>-<b>5</b> can be formed to surround at least one of a plurality of parts <b>110</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>110</b>-<b>2</b>, <b>110</b>-<b>3</b>, <b>110</b>-<b>4</b>, <b>110</b>-<b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Hitherto, the structure of a printed circuit board in accordance with an aspect of the present invention has been described, and hereinafter a manufacturing method of the printed circuit board will be described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 to 12</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flow diagram illustrating an embodiment of a manufacturing method of the printed circuit board in accordance with another aspect of the present invention, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 to 12</figref> are process diagrams illustrating an embodiment of a manufacturing method of the printed circuit board in accordance with another aspect of the present invention. Illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 to 12</figref> are the first insulation layer <b>100</b>, the base layer <b>100</b>A, the medium layer <b>100</b>B, the first pattern <b>110</b>, the first trench <b>120</b>, the second insulation layer <b>200</b>, the second pattern <b>210</b>, the second trench <b>220</b> and the third insulation layer <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">First, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the first pattern <b>110</b> is formed on one surface of the first insulation layer <b>100</b> (S<b>10</b>). Used for the first insulation layer <b>100</b> in the present embodiment is a material having the structure in which the base layer <b>100</b>A and the medium layer <b>100</b>B are stacked. However, the present invention is not restricted to this embodiment, and it is possible that a core board in which a reinforcing material, such as glass fiber or carbon fiber, is impregnated in an epoxy resin, or an individual insulation layer carrying out an inter-layer insulation function in a multi-layer printed circuit board, is used for the first insulation layer <b>100</b>. Moreover, the first insulation layer <b>100</b> can be a substrate or an interposer that uses ceramic or silicon.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In order to form the first pattern <b>110</b> on the first insulation layer <b>100</b>, it is possible to proceed with a plating process or stack a metal thin film before selectively etching the metal thin film. Moreover, it is possible that printing is made directly on the first insulation layer <b>100</b> using an inkjet head and conductive ink.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Then, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the first trench <b>120</b> is caved in one surface of the first insulation layer <b>100</b> along at least a portion of the first pattern <b>110</b> (S<b>20</b>). Although <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> shows that the first trench <b>120</b> is formed in the medium layer <b>100</b>B only, it shall be possible that the first trench <b>120</b> is formed in the base layer <b>100</b>A as well if necessary. A laser processing method using an excimer laser can be used in order to form the first trench <b>120</b> on the first insulation layer <b>100</b>. In addition, various dry etching methods or wet etching methods can be used.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Here, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, and as described earlier, the first pattern <b>110</b> can include a plurality of wired lines <b>110</b>A, <b>110</b>B that are separated from one another, and the first trench <b>120</b>A, <b>120</b>B can be formed between the plurality of wired lines <b>110</b>A, <b>110</b>B. Moreover, as described earlier, in case the distances between the plurality of wired lines <b>110</b>A, <b>110</b>B are not constant, the width of the first trench <b>120</b>A, <b>120</b>B can vary according to the distance between the plurality of wired lines <b>110</b>A, <b>110</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, in case the first pattern <b>110</b> includes a plurality of parts <b>110</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>110</b>-<b>2</b> that are functionally distinguishable, the first trench <b>120</b> can be formed along a border between the adjacent parts <b>110</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>110</b>-<b>2</b>. Moreover, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, and as described earlier, the first trench <b>120</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>120</b>-<b>2</b>, <b>120</b>-<b>3</b>, <b>120</b>-<b>4</b>, <b>120</b>-<b>5</b> can be formed to surround at least one of a plurality of parts <b>110</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>110</b>-<b>2</b>, <b>110</b>-<b>3</b>, <b>110</b>-<b>4</b>, <b>110</b>-<b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Then, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the second insulation layer <b>200</b> is stacked on one surface of the first insulation layer <b>100</b> so as to cover the first pattern <b>110</b> (S<b>30</b>). Here, the first trench <b>120</b> is filled by the second insulation layer <b>200</b>. In case the materials for the first insulation layer <b>100</b> and the second insulation layer <b>200</b>, more specifically, the materials for the medium layer <b>100</b>B and the second insulation layer <b>200</b>, are different from each other, the first trench <b>120</b> formed in the first insulation layer <b>100</b> can function as a stress buffer between the materials.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Afterwards, the second pattern <b>210</b> is formed on one surface of the second insulation layer <b>200</b> (S<b>40</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>), and the second trench <b>220</b> is caved in one surface of the second insulation layer <b>200</b> along at least a portion of the second pattern <b>210</b> (S<b>50</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>). Then, the third insulation layer <b>300</b> can be stacked on one surface of the second insulation layer <b>200</b> so as to cover the second pattern <b>210</b> (S<b>60</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>). Here, the second trench <b>220</b> is filled by the third insulation layer <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Through the above processes, the structure with circuit patterns and trenches can be repeatedly formed in a multi-layer printed circuit board.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Although certain embodiments of the present invention have been described, it shall be appreciated by anyone ordinarily skilled in the art to which the present invention pertains that there can be a variety of permutations and modifications of the present invention without departing from the technical ideas and scopes of the present invention that are disclosed in the claims appended below.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">A large number of embodiments in addition to the above-described embodiments are present within the claims of the present invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A printed circuit board comprising:
<claim-text>a first insulation layer having a first pattern formed thereon;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first trench caved in one surface of the first insulation layer along at least a portion of the first pattern; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second insulation layer stacked on one surface of the first insulation layer so as to cover the first pattern,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first trench is filled by the second insulation layer,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second insulation layer is integrally formed on the first insulation layer and the first pattern such that a portion of the second insulation layer fills the first trench,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first insulation layer comprises:
<claim-text>a base layer made of an insulation material; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a medium layer formed on the base layer and made of an insulation material,</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first pattern and the first trench are formed on the medium layer,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first trench is formed by penetrating the medium layer such that a portion of the base layer is exposed by the first trench, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the medium layer is made of a different insulation material from the base layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The printed circuit board of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein materials for the first insulation layer and the second insulation layer are different from each other.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The printed circuit board of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a second pattern formed on one surface of the second insulation layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second trench caved in one surface of the second insulation layer along at least a portion of the second pattern; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third insulation layer stacked on one surface of the second insulation layer so as to cover the second pattern,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second trench is filled by the third insulation layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The printed circuit board of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first insulation layer is a core board.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The printed circuit board of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the first pattern comprises a plurality of wired lines that are separated from one another; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first trench is formed between the plurality of wired lines.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The printed circuit board of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>distances between the plurality of wired lines are not constant; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the width of the first trench varies according to the distance between the plurality of wired lines.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The printed circuit board of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the first pattern comprises a plurality of parts that are functionally distinguishable; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first trench is formed along a border of adjacent parts.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The printed circuit board of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the first pattern comprises a plurality of parts that are functionally distinguishable; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first trench is formed to surround at least one of the plurality of parts. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
