<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624628-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624628</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13568227</doc-number>
<date>20120807</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>19</main-group>
<subgroup>0175</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>326 80</main-classification>
<further-classification>326 82</further-classification>
<further-classification>326 83</further-classification>
<further-classification>327333</further-classification>
<further-classification>327562</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Adjustable level shifter</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4150308</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Adlhoch</name>
<date>19790400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5532619</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Bonaccio</name>
<date>19960700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5623230</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Goldthorp</name>
<date>19970400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5825229</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Manaresi et al.</name>
<date>19981000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6005439</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Fong</name>
<date>19991200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>330253</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6222385</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Kang</name>
<date>20010400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6259299</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Ryu</name>
<date>20010700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6696869</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Tan</name>
<date>20040200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>327108</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7551017</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Felder</name>
<date>20090600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>327333</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0104767</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Prexl et al.</name>
<date>20040600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>329347</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0046495</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Li</name>
<date>20050300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>331 57</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0002483</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kim</name>
<date>20060100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0008001</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Sanchez et al.</name>
<date>20070100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>19</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>16</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>326 60- 81</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>327333</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>327592</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chen</last-name>
<first-name>Ming</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shanghai</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cheng</last-name>
<first-name>Shu Dong</first-name>
<address>
<city>Nanjing</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chen</last-name>
<first-name>Ming</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shanghai</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cheng</last-name>
<first-name>Shu Dong</first-name>
<address>
<city>Nanjing</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Agere Systems LLC</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Allentown</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Ismail</last-name>
<first-name>Shawki</first-name>
<department>2819</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>White</last-name>
<first-name>Dylan</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Described embodiments include a level shifter that provides a voltage level shift to applied signals, the amount of voltage shift being accurately controlled and independent of PVT. The level shifter has first transistor configured as a voltage follower with the gate coupled to an input terminal of the shifter and the source coupled to a node, a diode-connected transistor coupled between the node and an output terminal of the circuit, a first controlled current source coupled to the node, and a second controlled current source coupled to the output terminal. A controller receives a bandgap-stabilized voltage, squares the stabilized voltage to produce a control signal that controls the first and second controlled current sources. The voltage shift is proportional to a digitally-controlled scale factor (K) times the stabilized voltage. The ratio of the current from the first current source to the second current source is (K+1)/K.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="103.89mm" wi="113.37mm" file="US08624628-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="114.89mm" wi="112.27mm" file="US08624628-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="208.11mm" wi="154.01mm" file="US08624628-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="187.62mm" wi="125.22mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624628-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="194.90mm" wi="152.82mm" file="US08624628-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">Many integrated circuit designs use multiple power supplies to reduce power consumption while still providing high performance. But the voltage levels of logic signals processed by logic circuitry powered by one power supply domain might be different, and possibly incompatible, with the voltage levels of logic signals processed by logic powered by different power supply domain. For example, a field-programmable gate array (FPGA) typically has core signal processing logic and input-output buffers interfacing the core logic with off-chip logic circuitry. Generally, the input-output buffers are powered from one or more power supplies having voltages higher than the power supplies powering the core logic. Because the voltage levels of logic signals for the input-output buffers are usually greater than the voltage levels of logic signals utilized by the core logic, level shifters are used to &#x201c;translate&#x201d; the logic signals passing between the core logic and the input-output buffers.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">A similar use for level shifters exists in analog circuitry where it is desirable to shift the level of analog signals originating from one analog function for use by another analog function. For example, a phase-locked-loop (PLL) might require the use of a level shifter to have an error signal from a phase detector shifted to a voltage range that is suitable for use by a voltage-controlled oscillator (VCO).</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Two similar examples of a level shifter used to change the voltage levels of logic or analog signals are source or emitter followers where the output voltage levels are reduced by an amount approximately equal to the gate-to-source voltage or base-to-emitter voltage of a single MOSFET or bipolar transistor, respectively. Because the amount of voltage reduction is dependent on the electrical characteristics of the transistor, the amount of voltage reduction is relatively large (e.g., 0.5-0.7 volts), is not controllable, and varies with process, temperature, and operating voltage.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">This Summary is provided to introduce a selection of concepts in a simplified form that are further described below in the Detailed Description. This Summary is not intended to identify key features or essential features of the claimed subject matter, nor is it intended to be used to limit the scope of the claimed subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Described embodiments provide a level shifting circuit comprising first and second transistors and first and second controlled current sources. The first transistor has a control terminal coupled to an input terminal of the level shifting circuit, a first controlled terminal, and a second controlled terminal coupled to a first node. The second transistor has a first controlled terminal coupled to an output terminal of the level shifting circuit, a second controlled terminal coupled to the first node, and a control terminal coupled to the first controlled terminal of the second transistor. The first controlled current source is coupled to the node and the second controlled current source is coupled to the first controlled terminal of the second transistor. The current from the first controlled current source and current from the second current source are substantially independent of signals applied to the input terminal.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Other embodiments of the present invention will become more fully apparent from the following detailed description, the appended claims, and the accompanying drawings in which like reference numerals identify similar or identical elements.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a simplified schematic diagram illustrating an exemplary level translator according to an embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a simplified schematic diagram illustrating exemplary level translator according to another embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a simplified schematic diagram illustrating an exemplary control circuit for the level translators of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref> according to an embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a block diagram of a logic device incorporating the level translator of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows a simplified block diagram of an analog function (a phase-locked-loop) incorporating the level translator of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Reference herein to &#x201c;one embodiment&#x201d; or &#x201c;an embodiment&#x201d; means that a particular feature, structure, or characteristic described in connection with the embodiment can be included in at least one embodiment of the invention. The appearances of the phrase &#x201c;in one embodiment&#x201d; in various places in the specification are not necessarily all referring to the same embodiment, nor are separate or alternative embodiments necessarily mutually exclusive of other embodiments. The same applies to the term &#x201c;implementation&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">It should be understood that the steps of the exemplary methods set forth herein are not necessarily required to be performed in the order described, and the order of the steps of such methods should be understood to be merely exemplary. Likewise, additional steps might be included in such methods, and certain steps might be omitted or combined, in methods consistent with various embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Also for purposes of this description, the terms &#x201c;couple&#x201d;, &#x201c;coupling&#x201d;, &#x201c;coupled&#x201d;, &#x201c;connect&#x201d;, &#x201c;connecting&#x201d;, or &#x201c;connected&#x201d; refer to any manner known in the art or later developed in which energy is allowed to be transferred between two or more elements, and the interposition of one or more additional elements is contemplated, although not required. Conversely, the terms &#x201c;directly coupled&#x201d;, &#x201c;directly connected&#x201d;, etc., imply the absence of such additional elements. Signals and corresponding nodes or ports might be referred to by the same name and are interchangeable for purposes here. The term &#x201c;or&#x201d; should be interpreted as inclusive unless stated otherwise.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The present invention will be described herein in the context of illustrative embodiments of a level shifter adapted to be for use in an integrated circuit or the like. It is to be appreciated, however, that the invention is not limited to the specific apparatus and methods illustratively shown and described herein. Rather, aspects of the invention are directed broadly to techniques for beneficially providing a level shifter with a controllable voltage drop compatible with complementary metal-oxide-semiconductor technology (CMOS) or bipolar technology.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a block diagram of an exemplary level shifter <b>100</b> implemented using CMOS, although the level shifter <b>100</b> may be implemented using bipolar technology or using a combination of bipolar technology and CMOS technology known as bi-CMOS technology. A first transistor <b>102</b>, operating as a voltage follower, has a gate terminal coupled to an input V<sub>in </sub>of the level shifter and a source terminal coupled to a common node <b>104</b>. A second transistor <b>106</b> has a source terminal coupled to the node <b>104</b> and a drain terminal coupled to an output V<sub>out </sub>of the level shifter. The gate terminal of the second transistor <b>106</b> also couples to the drain terminal of the transistor <b>106</b>, to form a diode-connected transistor <b>106</b>. A first current source <b>108</b> couples to node <b>104</b> and a second current source <b>110</b> couples to the drain and gate of the transistor <b>106</b>. As will be explained in more detail below, the current sources <b>108</b> and <b>110</b> are controlled by a common control signal V<sub>ICONT </sub>that serves to control the currents passed by the current sources. In one embodiment, the current passed by current source <b>108</b> to that passed by current source <b>110</b> is approximately equal to (K+1)/K, where K is a scalar value greater than zero. For example, the current passed by source <b>110</b> is proportional to K times a function of V<sub>ICONT </sub>and the current passed by current source <b>108</b> is proportional to (K+1) times a function of V<sub>ICONT</sub>, the function of V<sub>ICONT </sub>being that of the gate-to-source voltage to drain current transfer characteristic of a MOSFET as explained below. In an alternative embodiment, the two current sources are controlled independently. In either embodiment, neither current source provides a current that follows the input signal applied to input V<sub>in</sub>, except for variations resulting from imperfections in the current source itself. It is also understood that the currents from the sources might be adjusted to suit the input voltage range of signals being applied to input V<sub>in</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The transistors <b>102</b>, <b>106</b> serve to first reduce then increase a voltage applied to the input V<sub>in </sub>such that a voltage on the output Vout is offset or shifted by a voltage &#x394;V from the voltage on the input Vin. The amount of shift is related to the currents passed by the current sources <b>108</b> and <b>110</b>. This is understood by recognizing that the current passed (drain current) by a MOSFET is approximately</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">
<maths id="MATH-US-00001" num="00001">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <msub>
          <mi>C</mi>
          <mi>ox</mi>
        </msub>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <mfrac>
          <mi>&#x3bc;</mi>
          <mn>2</mn>
        </mfrac>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <mfrac>
          <mi>W</mi>
          <mi>L</mi>
        </mfrac>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <msup>
          <mrow>
            <mo>(</mo>
            <mrow>
              <msub>
                <mi>V</mi>
                <mi>gs</mi>
              </msub>
              <mo>-</mo>
              <msub>
                <mi>V</mi>
                <mi>t</mi>
              </msub>
            </mrow>
            <mo>)</mo>
          </mrow>
          <mn>2</mn>
        </msup>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Eq</mi>
          <mo>.</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>1</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">where is C<sub>ox </sub>being the gate oxide capacitance, &#x3bc; the channel mobility, and</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">
<maths id="MATH-US-00002" num="00002">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mfrac>
  <mi>W</mi>
  <mi>L</mi>
</mfrac>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
the channel width-to-length ratio, V<sub>gs </sub>the gate-to-source voltage, and V<sub>t </sub>the threshold voltage. Assuming current I<sub>1 </sub>is passed by transistor <b>102</b>, I<sub>2 </sub>(the current supplied by current source <b>110</b>) is passed by transistor <b>106</b>, and I<sub>3 </sub>is the current through current source <b>108</b>, then
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>I</i><sub>3</sub><i>=I</i><sub>1</sub><i>+I</i><sub>2</sub>.&#x2003;&#x2003;(Eq. 2)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The voltage shift &#x394;V by the level shifter is determined by the difference between the gate-to-source voltages of transistors <b>102</b> (here V<sub>gs1</sub>) and transistor <b>106</b> (here V<sub>gs2</sub>):
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>&#x394;<i>V=V</i><sub>out</sub><i>&#x2212;V</i><sub>in</sub><i>=V</i><sub>gs2</sub><i>&#x2212;V</i><sub>gs1</sub>&#x2003;&#x2003;(Eq. 3)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Rewriting Eq. 1 to solve for gate-to-source voltages and substituting it into Eq. 3 and assuming that transistors <b>102</b> and <b>106</b> are substantially matched results in:</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">
<maths id="MATH-US-00003" num="00003">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mrow>
            <mi>&#x394;</mi>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mi>V</mi>
          </mrow>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mrow>
            <msqrt>
              <mfrac>
                <msub>
                  <mi>I</mi>
                  <mn>2</mn>
                </msub>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>C</mi>
                    <mi>ox</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mfrac>
                    <mi>&#x3bc;</mi>
                    <mn>2</mn>
                  </mfrac>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mfrac>
                    <mi>W</mi>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                  </mfrac>
                </mrow>
              </mfrac>
            </msqrt>
            <mo>-</mo>
            <msqrt>
              <mfrac>
                <msub>
                  <mi>I</mi>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                </msub>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>C</mi>
                    <mi>ox</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mfrac>
                    <mi>&#x3bc;</mi>
                    <mn>2</mn>
                  </mfrac>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mfrac>
                    <mi>W</mi>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                  </mfrac>
                </mrow>
              </mfrac>
            </msqrt>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <mstyle>
          <mtext>
</mtext>
        </mstyle>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <mi>or</mi>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Eq</mi>
          <mo>.</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>4</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mi>&#x394;</mi>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mi>V</mi>
        </mrow>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <msqrt>
            <mfrac>
              <mn>1</mn>
              <mrow>
                <msub>
                  <mi>C</mi>
                  <mi>ox</mi>
                </msub>
                <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                <mfrac>
                  <mi>&#x3bc;</mi>
                  <mn>2</mn>
                </mfrac>
                <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                <mfrac>
                  <mi>W</mi>
                  <mi>L</mi>
                </mfrac>
              </mrow>
            </mfrac>
          </msqrt>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>
              <mrow>
                <msqrt>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>I</mi>
                    <mn>2</mn>
                  </msub>
                </msqrt>
                <mo>-</mo>
                <msqrt>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>I</mi>
                    <mn>1</mn>
                  </msub>
                </msqrt>
              </mrow>
              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>
            <mo>.</mo>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Eq</mi>
          <mo>.</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>5</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Assuming here that I<sub>3</sub>=(K+1)I<sub>1</sub>, then from Eq. 2,
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>I</i><sub>2</sub><i>=KI</i><sub>1</sub>&#x2003;&#x2003;(Eq. 6)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>and thus the ratio of <i>I</i><sub>3 </sub>to <i>I</i><sub>2</sub>(<i>I</i><sub>3</sub><i>/I</i><sub>2</sub>) is (<i>K+</i>1)/<i>K.</i>&#x2003;&#x2003;(Eq. 7)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Substituting Eq. 6 into Eq. 5 results in:</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">
<maths id="MATH-US-00004" num="00004">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mrow>
            <mi>&#x394;</mi>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mi>V</mi>
          </mrow>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mrow>
            <msqrt>
              <mfrac>
                <msub>
                  <mi>I</mi>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                </msub>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>C</mi>
                    <mi>ox</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mfrac>
                    <mi>&#x3bc;</mi>
                    <mn>2</mn>
                  </mfrac>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mfrac>
                    <mi>W</mi>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                  </mfrac>
                </mrow>
              </mfrac>
            </msqrt>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>
              <mrow>
                <msqrt>
                  <mi>K</mi>
                </msqrt>
                <mo>-</mo>
                <mn>1</mn>
              </mrow>
              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mi>&#x2026;</mi>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <mstyle>
          <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
        </mstyle>
        <mo>,</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Eq</mi>
          <mo>.</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>8</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">As stated above, the currents I<sub>3 </sub>and I<sub>2 </sub>are a function of (K+1) and V<sub>ICONT</sub>, and K and V<sub>ICONT</sub>, respectively. Because I<sub>1 </sub>is the difference between currents I<sub>3 </sub>and I<sub>2 </sub>(Eq. 2), it follows that I<sub>1 </sub>in this embodiment is approximately proportional to the square of the control signal V<sub>ICONT</sub>. Thus, from Eq. 8:</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">
<maths id="MATH-US-00005" num="00005">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mi>&#x394;</mi>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mi>V</mi>
        </mrow>
        <mo>&#x221d;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <msub>
            <mi>V</mi>
            <mi>ICONT</mi>
          </msub>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <msqrt>
            <mrow>
              <msub>
                <mi>C</mi>
                <mi>ox</mi>
              </msub>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mfrac>
                <mi>&#x3bc;</mi>
                <mn>2</mn>
              </mfrac>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mfrac>
                <mi>W</mi>
                <mi>L</mi>
              </mfrac>
            </mrow>
          </msqrt>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mo>(</mo>
            <mrow>
              <msqrt>
                <mi>K</mi>
              </msqrt>
              <mo>-</mo>
              <mn>1</mn>
            </mrow>
            <mo>)</mo>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Eq</mi>
          <mo>.</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>9</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Therefore, the voltage shift is a function of V<sub>ICONT </sub>and K. In this embodiment, &#x394;V is positive when the level shifter <b>100</b> reduces (more negative in this embodiment) the input signal's voltage, and &#x394;V is negative when the input signal's voltage is increased (more positive).</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Optional voltage dropping resistor <b>112</b> may be used to improve the accuracy of the voltage shift by reducing the voltage from power supply node <b>114</b> so that the drain-to-source voltage of transistor <b>102</b> is similar to the drain-to-source voltage of transistor <b>106</b>. As illustrated here, the power supply voltage on node <b>114</b> can be different from the power supply voltage on node <b>116</b> so that transistor <b>102</b> might be subject to less overvoltage stress when signals applied to input V<sub>in </sub>come from circuitry operating at a higher voltage than circuitry responsive to signals on output V<sub>out</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a simplified schematic diagram of another embodiment of a level shifter <b>200</b> illustrating a combined analog and digital control for the current sources <b>108</b> and <b>110</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. Identically numbered features in both figures are the same for both figures. In this embodiment, the scalar value K discussed above is specified by a digital control word on lines <b>212</b> and the currents generated by the sources in response to the common control signal V<sub>ICONT </sub>are scaled by K. Digitally-scaled current source <b>214</b> in controlled current source <b>108</b> receives the one or more bit control word K to selectively close switches <b>216</b> that couples the transistors <b>218</b> to node <b>104</b>. The gates of transistors <b>218</b> are coupled to receive the common control signal V<sub>ICONT</sub>. A transistor <b>220</b> also coupled to the node <b>104</b> and receives the common control signal V<sub>ICONT</sub>. In this embodiment and for purposes of this description, the width-to-length ratio of transistor <b>220</b> is X and the width-to-length ratios of the transistors <b>218</b> are binary-weighted sequentially: X, 2X, 4X, etc., to implement the K+1 weighting for the current source <b>108</b> as discussed above. Other integer (e.g., X, 4X, 8X, etc.) and non-integer sequences might also be used. Further, the width-to-length ratios of transistors <b>102</b> and <b>106</b> might be designed to have different ratios, providing additional technique to determine &#x394;V.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Generally, the digitally scaled current source <b>214</b> passes a current that is a function of K and V<sub>ICONT </sub>as described above. In addition, the transistor <b>220</b> also passes a current that is a function of V<sub>ICONT</sub>, such that the total current conducted by conductor <b>222</b>, and hence by current source <b>108</b>, is a function of (K+1) and V<sub>ICONT</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Transistors <b>230</b> generate a control voltage on node <b>232</b> corresponding to the common control signal V<sub>ICONT</sub>. That signal is coupled to the gates of transistors <b>234</b> of a digitally-scaled current source <b>236</b>. As with digitally-scaled current source <b>214</b>, the current source <b>236</b> receives the control word K to selectively close switches <b>238</b> that couples the transistors <b>234</b> to the drain and gate terminals of transistor <b>106</b>. Thus, the digitally-scaled current source <b>236</b> produces a current to the transistor <b>106</b> that is a function of K and V<sub>ICONT</sub>. By appropriately scaling the transistors <b>230</b> and <b>234</b> to the transistors <b>218</b> as is well known in the art, the currents passed by the current sources <b>214</b> and <b>236</b> will be substantially equal.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">It is understood that the digitally-scaled current sources <b>214</b> and <b>236</b> may be implemented in a variety of ways, such as selectively coupling, in response to the control word K, the gates of the transistors <b>218</b> and <b>234</b> to their respective control signal instead of using the switches <b>216</b> and <b>238</b> as shown. Alternatively, the switches may be placed in series with the source terminals instead of the drain terminals of their respective transistors.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates an exemplary controller <b>300</b> for generating the common control signal V<sub>ICONT </sub>that is used to establish currents flowing in the current sources <b>108</b> and <b>110</b> (FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b>). As will be explained below, those currents are proportional to the square of a reference voltage that is substantially independent of process, temperature, and power supply voltage. The controller <b>300</b> may be used in common with multiple level shifters <b>100</b>, <b>200</b> as required.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">A stabilized voltage reference <b>302</b>, such as a conventional bandgap reference, provides a substantially constant voltage V<sub>BG </sub>that differential amplifier <b>304</b>, transistor <b>306</b>, and resistor <b>308</b> utilize in combination to establish a current passing through the resistor <b>308</b> of approximately V<sub>BG</sub>/R<sub>308</sub>, where R<sub>308 </sub>is the resistance of resistor <b>308</b> which is located on the same semiconductor substrate as the rest of the circuitry shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref>. While the voltage V<sub>BG </sub>is stabilized over process, temperature, and power supply variations, R<sub>308 </sub>is not. Transistor <b>310</b> mirrors the current flowing in transistor <b>306</b> and resistor <b>308</b> to produce a reference current I<sub>ref</sub>. The current I<sub>ref </sub>passes through resistor <b>312</b> to produce a stabilized reference voltage V<sub>C</sub>, diode-connected transistor <b>314</b>, and resistor <b>316</b>. Assuming that substantially equal currents flow in both transistors <b>306</b> and <b>310</b>, then V<sub>C</sub>=V<sub>P</sub>&#x2212;V<sub>N</sub>=V<sub>BG</sub>(R<sub>312</sub>/R<sub>308</sub>), where R<sub>312 </sub>is the resistance of resistor <b>312</b>. For purposes here, the transistor <b>314</b> and resistor <b>316</b> are used to provide adequate voltages to properly bias circuitry in a squaring circuit <b>320</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The voltage V<sub>C </sub>is stabilized over process and temperature because the ratio of the resistances of resistors <b>308</b> and <b>312</b> is substantially constant over process and temperature, so that the voltage V<sub>C </sub>is, for purposes here, invariant with changes in the resistors <b>308</b> and <b>312</b> but is proportional to V<sub>BG </sub>which is designed to be insensitive to process, temperature, and power supply voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Circuitry <b>320</b>, in response to the reference voltage V<sub>C</sub>, generates the common control signal V<sub>ICONT </sub>so that the currents generated by the current sources <b>108</b> and <b>110</b> are proportional to the square of the stabilized reference voltage V<sub>C</sub>. In this embodiment, differentially-connected transistors <b>322</b> and <b>324</b> receive V<sub>C </sub>and produce an output current I<sub>out </sub>on line <b>326</b>. Transistors <b>328</b> and <b>330</b> form a current mirror coupling to the drain terminals of transistors <b>322</b> and <b>324</b>, respectively, while transistor <b>332</b> couple to the source terminals of the transistors <b>322</b> and <b>324</b>. Transistors <b>332</b>, <b>334</b>, and <b>336</b> form a folded cascade current mirror to generate V<sub>ICONT </sub>in response to the output current I<sub>out</sub>. In this embodiment, transistor <b>332</b> decouples the voltage of the control signal V<sub>ICONT </sub>from the drain voltages of transistors <b>324</b> and <b>330</b> so that the transistor <b>330</b> has sufficient drain voltage for saturated operation. By having transistor <b>334</b> approximately the same size as transistor <b>324</b> so that the V<sub>gs </sub>and V<sub>ds </sub>(drain-to-source voltage) of transistor <b>324</b> is approximately the same as the V<sub>gs </sub>and V<sub>ds </sub>of transistor <b>334</b>, transistor <b>334</b> improves the performance of the current mirror of transistors <b>332</b> and <b>336</b> so that current passed by transistor <b>332</b> tracks the current I<sub>out </sub>more closely than without transistor <b>334</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">A bias circuit comprising transistors <b>338</b> and current source <b>340</b> provides the appropriate bias voltage to the gate of transistor <b>332</b> so that the transistor <b>330</b> has sufficient drain voltage for saturated operation.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">As will be explained in more detail below, by making the size of transistor <b>328</b> twice the size of transistor <b>330</b>, and the width-to-length of transistor <b>332</b> five times that of each of the substantially identical transistors <b>322</b>, <b>324</b>, <b>334</b>, and <b>336</b>, approximately twice the output current I<sub>out </sub>will flow through transistor <b>330</b>, four times the output current I<sub>out </sub>will flow through transistor <b>328</b>, and five time the output current I<sub>out </sub>will flow through transistor <b>332</b>. In this way, the output current I<sub>out </sub>will be approximately equal to</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">
<maths id="MATH-US-00006" num="00006">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <mrow>
    <msqrt>
      <mrow>
        <msub>
          <mi>C</mi>
          <mi>ox</mi>
        </msub>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <mfrac>
          <mi>&#x3bc;</mi>
          <mn>2</mn>
        </mfrac>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <mfrac>
          <mi>W</mi>
          <mi>L</mi>
        </mfrac>
      </mrow>
    </msqrt>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <msup>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <msub>
          <mi>V</mi>
          <mi>C</mi>
        </msub>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
      <mn>2</mn>
    </msup>
  </mrow>
  <mo>,</mo>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
where the values of C<sub>ox</sub>, &#x3bc;, and
</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">
<maths id="MATH-US-00007" num="00007">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <mfrac>
    <mi>W</mi>
    <mi>L</mi>
  </mfrac>
  <mo>,</mo>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
as defined above, are those for each of the substantially identical transistors <b>322</b>, <b>324</b>, <b>334</b>, and <b>336</b>. Because I<sub>out </sub>will have this characteristic, then currents in the current sources <b>108</b> and <b>110</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>) will be proportional to the square of V<sub>C</sub>. The result, per Eq. 8, is that the voltage offset or shift &#x394;V by the level shifter <b>100</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) or <b>200</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) is proportional to the reference voltage V<sub>C </sub>and can be accurately controlled thereby.
</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">As mentioned above, transistor <b>314</b> and resistor <b>316</b> are used to set an appropriate gate voltage for transistor <b>324</b> so that both transistors <b>324</b> and <b>332</b> are saturated. In this example, resistor <b>316</b> has about 200 mV across it and transistor <b>314</b> is sized to have a similar width-to-length ratio as transistor <b>324</b> so that the Vgs of transistor <b>314</b> is approximately the same as the V<sub>gs </sub>of transistor <b>324</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The operation of the circuit <b>320</b> is as follows. As stated above, in one embodiment, the width-to-length ratio of transistor <b>332</b> five times that of transistor <b>336</b>, the width-to-length ratio of transistor <b>328</b> is approximately twice that of transistor <b>330</b>, and the width-to-length ratio of transistor <b>322</b> is approximately the same as that of transistors <b>324</b> and <b>334</b>. Because of the sizing of the transistors, the current passed by or flowing in transistor <b>332</b> (I<sub>332</sub>) is approximately five time the output current I<sub>out </sub>(which is equal to the current passed by transistors <b>332</b>-<b>336</b>) and the current flowing in transistor <b>328</b> (I<sub>328</sub>) is twice that passed by current mirror transistor <b>330</b> (I<sub>330</sub>). It then follows that:
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>I</i><sub>328</sub><i>+I</i><sub>330</sub><i>=I</i><sub>out</sub><i>+I</i><sub>332</sub>&#x2003;&#x2003;(Eq. 10)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Because transistor <b>328</b> carries twice the current of transistor <b>330</b>, and transistor <b>332</b> carries five times the current passed by transistor <b>336</b> (I<sub>out</sub>), then:
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>2<i>I</i><sub>330</sub><i>+I</i><sub>330</sub><i>=I</i><sub>out</sub>+5<i>I</i><sub>out</sub>=6<i>I</i><sub>out</sub>, and&#x2003;&#x2003;(Eq. 11)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>I</i><sub>330</sub>=2<i>I</i><sub>out </sub>and,&#x2003;&#x2003;(Eq. 12)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>I</i><sub>328</sub><i>=I</i><sub>322</sub>=4<i>I</i><sub>out</sub>.&#x2003;&#x2003;(Eq. 13)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The current flowing in transistor <b>324</b> (I<sub>324</sub>) is then calculated to be:
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>I</i><sub>324</sub><i>=I</i><sub>320</sub><i>&#x2212;I</i><sub>336</sub>=2<i>I</i><sub>out</sub><i>&#x2212;I</i><sub>out</sub><i>=I</i><sub>out</sub>.&#x2003;&#x2003;(Eq. 14)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Expressing Eq. 1 for the current passed by transistor <b>322</b> according to Eq. 13 yields:</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">
<maths id="MATH-US-00008" num="00008">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mn>4</mn>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <msub>
            <mi>I</mi>
            <mi>out</mi>
          </msub>
        </mrow>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <msub>
            <mi>C</mi>
            <mi>ox</mi>
          </msub>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mfrac>
            <mi>&#x3bc;</mi>
            <mn>2</mn>
          </mfrac>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mfrac>
            <mi>W</mi>
            <mi>L</mi>
          </mfrac>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <msup>
            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>
              <mrow>
                <msub>
                  <mi>V</mi>
                  <mi>P</mi>
                </msub>
                <mo>-</mo>
                <msub>
                  <mi>V</mi>
                  <mi>S</mi>
                </msub>
                <mo>-</mo>
                <msub>
                  <mi>V</mi>
                  <mi>th</mi>
                </msub>
              </mrow>
              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>
            <mn>2</mn>
          </msup>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Eq</mi>
          <mo>.</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>15</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
and expressing Eq. 1 for the current passed by transistor <b>324</b> according to Eq. 14 yields:
</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">
<maths id="MATH-US-00009" num="00009">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <msub>
          <mi>I</mi>
          <mi>out</mi>
        </msub>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <msub>
            <mi>C</mi>
            <mi>ox</mi>
          </msub>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mfrac>
            <mi>&#x3bc;</mi>
            <mn>2</mn>
          </mfrac>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mfrac>
            <mi>W</mi>
            <mi>L</mi>
          </mfrac>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <msup>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>V</mi>
                    <mi>N</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>V</mi>
                    <mi>S</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>V</mi>
                    <mi>th</mi>
                  </msub>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
              <mn>2</mn>
            </msup>
            <mo>.</mo>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Eq</mi>
          <mo>.</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>16</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Solving Eq. 15 for gate-to-source voltage of transistor <b>322</b> yields:</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">
<maths id="MATH-US-00010" num="00010">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <msqrt>
          <mfrac>
            <mrow>
              <mn>4</mn>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mstyle>
                <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
              </mstyle>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <msub>
                <mi>I</mi>
                <mi>out</mi>
              </msub>
            </mrow>
            <mrow>
              <msub>
                <mi>C</mi>
                <mi>ox</mi>
              </msub>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mfrac>
                <mi>&#x3bc;</mi>
                <mn>2</mn>
              </mfrac>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mfrac>
                <mi>W</mi>
                <mi>L</mi>
              </mfrac>
            </mrow>
          </mfrac>
        </msqrt>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <msub>
            <mi>V</mi>
            <mi>P</mi>
          </msub>
          <mo>-</mo>
          <msub>
            <mi>V</mi>
            <mi>S</mi>
          </msub>
          <mo>-</mo>
          <msub>
            <mi>V</mi>
            <mi>th</mi>
          </msub>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Eq</mi>
          <mo>.</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>17</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">and solving Eq. 16 for the gate-to-source voltage of transistor <b>324</b> yields:</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">
<maths id="MATH-US-00011" num="00011">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <msqrt>
          <mfrac>
            <msub>
              <mi>I</mi>
              <mi>out</mi>
            </msub>
            <mrow>
              <msub>
                <mi>C</mi>
                <mi>ox</mi>
              </msub>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mfrac>
                <mi>&#x3bc;</mi>
                <mn>2</mn>
              </mfrac>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mfrac>
                <mi>W</mi>
                <mi>L</mi>
              </mfrac>
            </mrow>
          </mfrac>
        </msqrt>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <msub>
            <mi>V</mi>
            <mi>N</mi>
          </msub>
          <mo>-</mo>
          <msub>
            <mi>V</mi>
            <mi>S</mi>
          </msub>
          <mo>-</mo>
          <mrow>
            <msub>
              <mi>V</mi>
              <mi>th</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>.</mo>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Eq</mi>
          <mo>.</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>18</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Subtracting Eq. 18 from Eq. 17 yields:</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">
<maths id="MATH-US-00012" num="00012">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <msqrt>
          <mfrac>
            <msub>
              <mi>I</mi>
              <mi>out</mi>
            </msub>
            <mrow>
              <msub>
                <mi>C</mi>
                <mi>ox</mi>
              </msub>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mfrac>
                <mi>&#x3bc;</mi>
                <mn>2</mn>
              </mfrac>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mfrac>
                <mi>W</mi>
                <mi>L</mi>
              </mfrac>
            </mrow>
          </mfrac>
        </msqrt>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mrow>
            <msub>
              <mi>V</mi>
              <mi>P</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>-</mo>
            <msub>
              <mi>V</mi>
              <mi>N</mi>
            </msub>
          </mrow>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <msub>
            <mi>V</mi>
            <mi>C</mi>
          </msub>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Eq</mi>
          <mo>.</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>19</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">and solving Eq. 19 for I<sub>out </sub>yields:</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">
<maths id="MATH-US-00013" num="00013">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <msub>
          <mi>I</mi>
          <mi>out</mi>
        </msub>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mrow>
            <msub>
              <mi>C</mi>
              <mi>ox</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mfrac>
              <mi>&#x3bc;</mi>
              <mn>2</mn>
            </mfrac>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mfrac>
              <mi>W</mi>
              <mi>L</mi>
            </mfrac>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <msup>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>V</mi>
                    <mi>P</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>V</mi>
                    <mi>N</mi>
                  </msub>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
              <mn>2</mn>
            </msup>
          </mrow>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mrow>
            <msub>
              <mi>C</mi>
              <mi>ox</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mfrac>
              <mi>&#x3bc;</mi>
              <mn>2</mn>
            </mfrac>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mfrac>
              <mi>W</mi>
              <mi>L</mi>
            </mfrac>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <msubsup>
                <mi>V</mi>
                <mi>C</mi>
                <mn>2</mn>
              </msubsup>
              <mo>.</mo>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Eq</mi>
          <mo>.</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>20</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Because V<sub>ICONT </sub>controls both I<sub>out </sub>and the currents passed current sources <b>108</b> and <b>110</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>) and that I<sub>out </sub>is approximately equal to</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">
<maths id="MATH-US-00014" num="00014">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <mrow>
    <msqrt>
      <mrow>
        <msub>
          <mi>C</mi>
          <mi>ox</mi>
        </msub>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <mfrac>
          <mi>&#x3bc;</mi>
          <mn>2</mn>
        </mfrac>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <mfrac>
          <mi>W</mi>
          <mi>L</mi>
        </mfrac>
      </mrow>
    </msqrt>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <msup>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <msub>
          <mi>V</mi>
          <mi>C</mi>
        </msub>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
      <mn>2</mn>
    </msup>
  </mrow>
  <mo>,</mo>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
then currents passed by the current sources <b>108</b> and <b>110</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>) will be proportional to the square of V<sub>C</sub>. As a result and per Eq. 8, the voltage offset or shift &#x394;V by the level shifter <b>100</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) or <b>200</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) is proportional to the reference voltage V<sub>C</sub>:
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>&#x394;<i>V&#x221d;V</i><sub>C</sub>(<i>&#x221a;{square root over (K)}&#x2212;</i>1).&#x2003;&#x2003;(Eq. 21)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Thus &#x394;V can be be scaled to V<sub>C </sub>by correspondingly scaling the width-to-length ratios of the transistors in the current sources <b>108</b>, <b>110</b> to that of transistor <b>336</b>. However, for the case where I<sub>out</sub>=I<sub>1 </sub>(<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>),
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>&#x394;<i>V=V</i><sub>C</sub>(<i>&#x221a;{square root over (K)}&#x2212;</i>1).&#x2003;&#x2003;(Eq. 22)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Because V<sub>C </sub>is set by V<sub>BG</sub>, then &#x394;V is accurately controlled.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">As is well known in the art, a conventional start-up circuit (not shown) is added to the circuit <b>320</b> to insure that the circuit <b>320</b> operates upon applying power thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a simplified block diagram of an exemplary logic device <b>400</b>, such as a field-programmable gate array (FPGA), integrated into a common substrate or chip and having at least two logic circuit blocks. Each of the logic blocks being powered by it own power supply or power domain and using one or more of the above-described level shifters to translate or shift the voltage levels of logic signals from the first logic block to the second logic block. In this exemplary embodiment, a first logic circuit block <b>402</b> produces one or more logic signals on leads <b>404</b> and a second logic block <b>406</b> receives logic signals over leads <b>408</b>. In this example, the logic circuit <b>402</b> is powered from a power supply <b>410</b> and logic circuit <b>406</b> is powered from a power supply <b>412</b>, the voltage of power supply <b>410</b> being greater than that of power supply <b>412</b>. Because logic signal voltage levels are generally proportional to the power supply voltage of the logic circuitry generating the logic signals, in this example the logic signals on leads <b>404</b> have a voltage greater than the logic circuitry <b>406</b> can reliably or safely handle. To provide the desired logic levels to logic circuitry <b>406</b>, one or more level shifters <b>100</b>, such as that shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> or <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, shift the logic level voltages of logic signals on leads <b>404</b> to acceptable logic level voltages on leads <b>408</b> for logic circuitry <b>406</b> to process. Here, the level shifters <b>100</b> couple to both power supplies <b>410</b> and <b>412</b>. Referring temporarily to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the power supply node <b>114</b> couples to power supply <b>410</b> and the power supply node <b>116</b> couples to power supply <b>412</b>. This allows transistor <b>102</b> to sustain the higher voltage logic signals on leads <b>404</b> without undue stress compared to having power supply nodes <b>114</b> and <b>116</b> coupled to the same, lower voltage power supply <b>412</b>. In this case, the resistor <b>112</b> might not be needed. However, it is understood that both power supply nodes <b>114</b> and <b>116</b> may be connected to either power supply as appropriate and that the voltage on node <b>116</b> can be greater than that on node <b>114</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">While the controller <b>300</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is not shown, one or more of the controllers might be provided on the same chip as the FPGA circuitry <b>400</b>. The digital control word K might be supplied by logic circuit block <b>402</b>, <b>404</b>, or other logic (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a simplified block diagram of an analog function <b>500</b>, here a phase-locked-loop (PLL), using the above-described level shifter to translate or shift the voltage levels of signals from one sub-block of the PLL to another sub-block of the PLL. In this exemplary embodiment of an analog function, a phase comparator <b>502</b> compares an input signal to the output signal of a voltage-controlled oscillator <b>504</b>. An error signal representing the phase difference between the input signal and the VCO output signal is filtered by low-pass filter <b>506</b>. Because the voltage level of signals from the filter <b>506</b> might be out of the range of the control signal to the VCO <b>504</b>, the level shifter <b>100</b>, such as that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> or <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, translates the signal to a range usable by the VCO <b>504</b>. Moreover, by precisely controlling the amount of voltage shift, the level shifter <b>100</b> may be used to precisely shift the phase of the VCO output signal while the PLL is locked.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In this example, the level shifter <b>100</b> is powered by one power supply (not shown). However, as is common in many modern analog designs, the VCO <b>504</b> is powered from a different power supply as the rest of the circuitry to reduce jitter and other noise from appearing in the output signal from the VCO. In this case, the level shifter <b>100</b> may be powered from two different power sources, one for the phase detector <b>502</b> and the filter <b>506</b>, and one for the VCO <b>504</b>, similar to how the level shifter <b>100</b> is powered in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">While the controller <b>300</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is not shown, one or more of the controllers might be provided on the same chip as the analog function <b>500</b>. The digital control word K might be supplied by logic circuitry either on the same chip as the function <b>500</b> or external to the chip.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">It is understood that various changes in the details, materials, and arrangements of the parts which have been described and illustrated in order to explain the nature of this invention might be made by those skilled in the art without departing from the scope of the invention as expressed in the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00001" nb-file="US08624628-20140107-M00001.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00001" he="6.35mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624628-20140107-M00001.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00002" nb-file="US08624628-20140107-M00002.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00002" he="6.01mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624628-20140107-M00002.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00003" nb-file="US08624628-20140107-M00003.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00003" he="27.86mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624628-20140107-M00003.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00004" nb-file="US08624628-20140107-M00004.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00004" he="10.92mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624628-20140107-M00004.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00005" nb-file="US08624628-20140107-M00005.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00005" he="8.47mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624628-20140107-M00005.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00006" nb-file="US08624628-20140107-M00006.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00006" he="8.13mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624628-20140107-M00006.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00007" nb-file="US08624628-20140107-M00007.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00007" he="6.01mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624628-20140107-M00007.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00008" nb-file="US08624628-20140107-M00008.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00008" he="6.35mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624628-20140107-M00008.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00009" nb-file="US08624628-20140107-M00009.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00009" he="6.35mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624628-20140107-M00009.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00010" nb-file="US08624628-20140107-M00010.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00010" he="10.92mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624628-20140107-M00010.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00011" nb-file="US08624628-20140107-M00011.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00011" he="10.92mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624628-20140107-M00011.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00012" nb-file="US08624628-20140107-M00012.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00012" he="10.92mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624628-20140107-M00012.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00013" nb-file="US08624628-20140107-M00013.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00013" he="6.35mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624628-20140107-M00013.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00014" nb-file="US08624628-20140107-M00014.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00014" he="8.13mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624628-20140107-M00014.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-claim-statement>We claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A level shifting circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a first transistor having a control terminal coupled to an input terminal of the level shifting circuit, a first controlled terminal, and a second controlled terminal coupled to a first node;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second transistor having a first controlled terminal coupled to an output terminal of the level shifting circuit, a second controlled terminal coupled to the first node, and a control terminal coupled to the first controlled terminal of the second transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first controlled current source coupled to the first node; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second controlled current source coupled to the first controlled terminal of the second transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein current from the first controlled current source and current from the second controlled current source are substantially independent of signals applied to the input terminal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The level shifter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the first and second transistors have substantially equal width-to-length ratios and signals on the output terminal are shifted in voltage from signals applied to the input terminal the amount of voltage shift being controlled by the amount of current from the first and second current sources.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The level shifter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> wherein a ratio of the currents from the first and second controlled current sources is substantially equal to (K+1)/K, where K is greater than zero.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The level shifter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref> wherein the first and second controlled current sources each comprise a plurality of switchable current mirror transistors, each of the switchable current mirror transistors being coupled to a common control signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The level shifter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the first and second transistors have different width-to-length ratios and signals on the output terminal are shifted in voltage from signals applied to the input terminal and the amount of voltage shift being controlled by a ratio of the currents from the first and second controlled current sources scaled a ratio of the width-to-length ratios of the first transistor to the second transistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The level shifter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>a controller, including a bandgap reference and a reference resistor, for adjusting the currents passed by the first and second current sources.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The level shifter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> wherein the controller comprises:
<claim-text>a voltage-to-current generating circuit coupling to the bandgap reference and the reference resistor and adapted to generate a reference current;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first resistor receiving the reference current and adapted to generate a first voltage signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a squaring circuit, having an input coupled to the first resistor, adapted to generate a control signal proportional to the first voltage signal squared;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first and second current sources are responsive to the control signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The level shifter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> wherein the level shifter, the reference resistor, and the first resister are fabricated in a common integrated circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The level shifter of claim wherein the second transistor is a diode-connected MOSFET.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The level shifter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising a dropping resistor coupled between a power supply node and the first controlled terminal of the first transistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. An integrated circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a first logic circuit coupled between ground and a first power supply domain;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second logic block coupled between ground and a second power supply domain; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one level shifter according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, for at least one of the level shifters, the input terminal is coupled to the first logic circuit, the output terminal is coupled to the second logic circuit, and the first controlled terminal of the first transistor is coupled to the first power supply domain.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The integrated circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> wherein for the at least one level shifter, the first current source is coupled between ground and the first node, and the second current source is coupled between the second power supply domain and the first controlled node of the second transistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. An integrated circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a first analog function circuit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second analog function circuit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one level shifter according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, for at least one of the level shifters, the input terminal is coupled to the first analog function circuit, and the output terminal is coupled to the second analog function circuit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A level shifting circuit comprising: a first transistor, configured as a voltage follower, having a control terminal coupled to an input terminal of the circuit and to a node; a diode connected transistor coupled between the node and an output terminal of the circuit; a first controlled current source coupled to the node; a second controlled current source coupled to the output terminal; wherein current from the first controlled current source and current from the second controlled current source are substantially independent of signals applied to the input terminal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The level shifting circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref> wherein the first and second controlled current sources each comprise a plurality of switchable current mirror transistors, each of the switchable current mirror transistors being coupled to a common control signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A level shifting circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a first transistor having a control terminal coupled to an input terminal of the level shifting circuit, a first controlled terminal, and a second controlled terminal coupled to a first node;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second transistor having a first controlled terminal coupled to an output terminal of the level shifting circuit, a second controlled terminal coupled to the first node, and a control terminal coupled to the first controlled terminal of the second transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first controlled current source coupled to the first node; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second controlled current source coupled to the first controlled terminal of the second transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first and second transistors have substantially equal width-to-length ratios and signals on the output terminal are shifted in voltage from signals applied to the input terminal the amount of voltage shift being controlled by the amount of current from the first and second controlled current sources.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The level shifting circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref> wherein a ratio of the currents from the first and second controlled current sources is substantially equal to (K+1)/K, where K is greater than zero.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The level shifting circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>a controller, including a bandgap reference and a reference resistor, for adjusting the currents passed by the first and second current sources.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The level shifting circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the level shifting circuit is fabricated as part of an integrated circuit. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
