<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624242-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624242</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13711169</doc-number>
<date>20121211</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2011-271806</doc-number>
<date>20111213</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>23</main-group>
<subgroup>52</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257 48</main-classification>
<further-classification>257690</further-classification>
<further-classification>257691</further-classification>
<further-classification>257E23141</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e61">Semiconductor integrated circuit</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6097622</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Shimizu et al.</name>
<date>20000800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>365145</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6287885</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Muto et al.</name>
<date>20010900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438 48</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2012/0079882</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Chiba et al.</name>
<date>20120400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 7351429</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2013/0062605</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Takahashi</name>
<date>20130300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257 48</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2000-188305</doc-number>
<date>20000700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2005-72554</doc-number>
<date>20050300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>9</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257690-697</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257 48</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E23141</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>10</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130146874</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130613</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kojima</last-name>
<first-name>Hiroshi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ora-gun</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Marutani</last-name>
<first-name>Fumio</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ora-gun</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kojima</last-name>
<first-name>Hiroshi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ora-gun</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Marutani</last-name>
<first-name>Fumio</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ora-gun</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Morrison &#x26; Foerster LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Semiconductor Components Industries, LLC</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Phoenix</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Nguyen</last-name>
<first-name>Thanh</first-name>
<department>2893</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">There is offered a semiconductor integrated circuit provided with a function to electrically identify a location where a defect such as chipping of an LSI die or separation of resin is caused. Corresponding to each of the four corners of a semiconductor substrate, each of L-shaped first through fourth peripheral wirings having a first end and a second end is disposed on a periphery of the semiconductor substrate. The first end of each of the first through fourth peripheral wirings is connected with a power supply wiring. Each of first through fourth detection circuits detects breaking of corresponding each of the first through fourth peripheral wirings in response to a voltage at the second end of corresponding each of the first through fourth peripheral wirings, and outputs corresponding each of first through fourth detection signals to corresponding each of output pads.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="164.17mm" wi="164.34mm" file="US08624242-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="168.32mm" wi="165.02mm" file="US08624242-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="216.83mm" wi="161.80mm" file="US08624242-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="218.95mm" wi="154.77mm" file="US08624242-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="87.88mm" wi="153.16mm" file="US08624242-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="218.95mm" wi="144.02mm" file="US08624242-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="180.17mm" wi="149.44mm" file="US08624242-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority from Japanese Patent Application No. 2011-271806, the content of which is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">This invention relates to a semiconductor integrated circuit, specifically to a semiconductor integrated circuit using a WLP (Wafer Level Package) or a CSP (Chip Size Package).</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In recent years, the wafer level package (hereafter referred to as WLP) and the chip size package (hereafter referred to as CSP) have come into widespread use. The WLP and the CSP are packages intended for high density mounting, and have a size comparable to an LSI die packaged in it.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The WLP and the CSP are manufactured at a semiconductor fab, and is shipped to a customer after a pre-shipment test. The customer manufactures his products by mounting various kinds of electronic parts including the WLP or the CSP onto a circuit board using electronic parts mounting apparatus such as a chipmounter at his production plant. Related technologies are disclosed in Japanese Patent Application Publication Nos. 2000-188305 and 2005-72554, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The WLP and the CSP are more susceptible to mechanical damage in handling or in mounting onto the circuit board compared with a resin mold package. Potential defects resulting from the damage are chipping or cracking of the LSI die, separation of a resin layer covering a surface of the LSI die and the like, which are prone to be caused in a periphery of the die.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In the production process at the customer, it is required for the purpose of helping failure analysis and improvement of the process that a location of the semiconductor die in which the defect is caused due to the stress applied to the WLP or the CSP when the WLP of the CSP is mounted onto the circuit board is electrically identified.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">This invention is directed to offering a semiconductor integrated circuit provided with a function to detect the defect such as the chipping of the LSI die or the separation of the resin layer, specifically a function to electrically identify the location of the defect.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">A semiconductor integrated circuit includes a semiconductor substrate having four edges and four corners. Each of the four corners corresponds to an intersection of a neighboring pair of the edges. The circuit also includes four L-shaped peripheral wirings. Each of the four L-shaped peripheral wirings has a first end and a second end and disposed on a periphery of the semiconductor substrate around a corresponding one of the four corners. The circuit also includes a power supply wiring that is of a closed-loop shape and disposed on a periphery of the semiconductor substrate. The power supply wiring is connected with the first end of each of the four peripheral wirings and is provided with a power supply voltage. The circuit also includes four detection circuits disposed on the semiconductor substrate so as to be surrounded by the power supply wiring. Each of the four detection circuits detects breaking of a corresponding one of the four peripheral wirings in response to a voltage at the second end of the corresponding one of the four peripheral wirings and outputting a detection signal, and four output pads disposed on the semiconductor substrate or adjacent the semiconductor substrate. The detection signal of each of the four detection circuits is outputted through a corresponding one of the four output pads.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a plan view showing a semiconductor integrated circuit according to a first embodiment of this invention.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross-sectional view showing a section X-X in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a first circuit of each of first through fourth detection circuits in a laser beam detection state.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows the first circuit of each of the first through fourth detection circuits in a normal state.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows the first circuit of each of the first through fourth detection circuits in an abnormal state.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows a second circuit of each of the first through fourth detection circuits.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a plan view showing a semiconductor integrated circuit according to a second embodiment of this invention.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a cross-sectional view showing a section Y-Y in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> shows a third circuit of each of the first through fourth detection circuits.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> shows a fourth circuit of each of the first through fourth detection circuits.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">First Embodiment</heading>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">Overall Structure of a Semiconductor Integrated Circuit <b>100</b></heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a plan view of a semiconductor integrated circuit <b>100</b> according to a first embodiment of this invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross-sectional view of a section X-X shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The semiconductor integrated circuit <b>100</b> is provided with a function to detect electrically a laser beam from a semiconductor laser in an optical disk unit, and is packaged using the CSP technology, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">A semiconductor substrate <b>1</b> has four edges L<b>1</b>-L<b>4</b> and four corners K<b>1</b>-K<b>4</b> each corresponding to an intersection of a neighboring pair of the edges, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The four edges L<b>1</b>-L<b>4</b> are depicted with broken lines in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The edges L<b>1</b>-L<b>4</b> have convex portions and concave portions in which pads P<b>1</b>-P<b>18</b> of the semiconductor integrated circuit <b>100</b> are disposed. A ring-shaped power supply wiring <b>3</b> is disposed along an entire periphery of a top surface of the semiconductor substrate <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The power supply wiring <b>3</b> is provided with a power supply voltage Vcc from a power supply pad P<b>1</b> through a wiring (not shown). A region of the semiconductor substrate <b>1</b> surrounded by the power supply wiring <b>3</b> makes a circuit forming region. The power supply wiring <b>3</b> serves to block infiltration of moisture and contaminating material from outside as well as supplying the power supply voltage Vcc to the circuit. For that purpose, it is preferable that the power supply wiring <b>3</b> is made of a multilayer wiring having a width of 20 &#x3bc;m, for example, that is larger than widths of other wirings in the circuit forming region.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Each of L-shaped first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>4</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>4</b>-<b>4</b> having a first end and a second end is disposed correspondingly to each of the four corners K<b>1</b>-K<b>4</b> on the periphery of the semiconductor substrate <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">That is, each of the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>4</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>4</b>-<b>4</b> extends from each of locations C<b>1</b>-C<b>4</b> in the circuit forming region corresponding to each of the four corners K<b>1</b>-K<b>4</b> halfway along a neighboring pair of the edges. The first end of each of the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>4</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>4</b>-<b>4</b> is connected with the power supply wiring <b>3</b>. The second ends of the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>4</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>4</b>-<b>4</b> are separated from each other so as not to make a short-circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>4</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>4</b>-<b>4</b> are disposed on the periphery of the semiconductor substrate <b>1</b> because defects such as chipping of the semiconductor substrate <b>1</b> (LSI die) and separation of a resin layer for protection are prone to be caused in the periphery. The reason why the four peripheral wirings that are the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>4</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>4</b>-<b>4</b> are provided instead of a single peripheral wiring is to identify a location where the defect is caused.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">It is preferable that a width of each of the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>4</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>4</b>-<b>4</b> is determined in accordance with a minimum design rule of the semiconductor integrated circuit <b>100</b>, which is 0.6 &#x3bc;m, for example, that is substantially smaller than the width of the power supply wiring <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The width of each of the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>4</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>4</b>-<b>4</b> is formed relatively small so that the defects such as the chipping of the semiconductor substrate <b>1</b> (LSI die) and the separation of the resin layer for protection are detected by its breaking. That is, when this kind of defect is caused, the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>4</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>4</b>-<b>4</b> are more prone to be broken because of their smaller width by a mechanical damage or a stress which caused the defect.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">It is noted that the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>4</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>4</b>-<b>4</b> may be formed on the semiconductor substrate <b>1</b> outside the power supply wiring <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Each of first through fourth detection circuits <b>10</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>10</b>-<b>4</b> is disposed in the circuit forming region surrounded by the power supply wiring <b>3</b>, detects the breaking of corresponding each of the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>4</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>4</b>-<b>4</b> in response to a voltage at the second end of corresponding each of the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>4</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>4</b>-<b>4</b>, and outputs corresponding each of first through fourth detection signals Amp_out<b>1</b>-Amp_out<b>4</b> to corresponding each of output pads P<b>1</b>-P<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">As a result, whether each of the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>4</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>4</b>-<b>4</b> is broken or not can be detected based on corresponding each of the first through fourth detection signals Amp_out<b>1</b>-Amp_out<b>4</b>. Examples of concrete structures of the first through fourth detection circuits <b>10</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>10</b>-<b>4</b> are to be described.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross-sectional view of a region around the output pad P<b>2</b>. The output pad P<b>2</b>, the power supply wiring <b>3</b> and the third peripheral wiring <b>4</b>-<b>3</b> are disposed on the top surface of the semiconductor substrate <b>1</b> through a first insulation film <b>2</b>. According to the CSP technology, the output pad P<b>2</b> is disposed in the concave portion of the semiconductor substrate <b>1</b> (an opening formed by partially cutting the semiconductor substrate <b>1</b>), and a part of or whole of its back surface is exposed out of the semiconductor substrate <b>1</b>. That is, the output pad P<b>2</b> is disposed on the semiconductor substrate <b>1</b> or adjacent the semiconductor substrate <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">A supporting material <b>6</b> made of a transparent substrate such as a glass substrate is attached to the top surface of the semiconductor substrate <b>1</b> through an adhesion layer <b>5</b> made of resin. A second insulation film <b>7</b> is formed on a back surface and a side surface of the semiconductor substrate <b>1</b>. A wiring layer <b>8</b> that extends over the back surface and the side surface to reach the top surface of the semiconductor substrate <b>1</b> is formed on the second insulation film <b>7</b>. An end of the wiring layer <b>8</b> is electrically connected to the back surface of the output pad P<b>2</b>. The back surface and the side surface of the semiconductor substrate <b>1</b>, on which the wiring layer <b>8</b> is formed, are covered with a resin layer <b>9</b> for protection.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">An opening is formed in a portion of the resin layer <b>9</b> on the back surface of the semiconductor substrate <b>1</b>, and there is formed a bump electrode <b>11</b> (protruding electrode) that is electrically connected with the wiring layer <b>8</b> through the opening. Regions around the other pads such as the power supply pad P<b>1</b> and the output pads P<b>3</b>-P<b>5</b> are formed similarly.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The semiconductor integrated circuit <b>100</b> formed by the CSP technology as described above is shipped to the customer. The customer manufactures various kinds of products by mounting various kinds of electronic parts including the semiconductor integrated circuit <b>100</b> onto a circuit board using electronic parts mounting apparatus such as a chipmounter.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">At that time, the semiconductor integrated circuit <b>100</b> is aligned to the circuit board so that the bump electrode <b>11</b> on the back surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit <b>100</b> is electrically connected to a printed wiring or the like on the circuit board. In some cases, the defect such as chipping of the semiconductor substrate <b>1</b> of the semiconductor integrated circuit <b>100</b> is caused by the mechanical damage or the stress on that occasion. With the semiconductor integrated circuit <b>100</b> according to the embodiment, it is made possible to electrically identify which of the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>4</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>4</b>-<b>4</b> corresponds to the location where the damage is caused.</p>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">Examples of the First Through Fourth Detection Circuits <b>10</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>10</b>-<b>4</b></heading>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Each of the first through fourth detection circuits <b>10</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>10</b>-<b>4</b> that are identical to each other has a structure as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3-5</figref>. While <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3-5</figref> show the same circuit diagram, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is to explain operation in a laser beam detection state, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is to explain operation in a normal state (without breaking of the peripheral wiring) and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is to explain operation in an abnormal state (with breaking of the peripheral wiring).</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In the following explanation, one of the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>4</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>4</b>-<b>4</b> is represented as a peripheral wiring <b>4</b>-X, and a corresponding one of the first through fourth detection circuits <b>10</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>10</b>-<b>4</b> is represented as a detection circuit <b>10</b>-X. The detection circuit <b>10</b>-X includes a first resistor R<b>1</b>, a second resistor R<b>2</b>, a third resistor R<b>3</b>, an amplifier circuit Amp<b>1</b>, a reference voltage source VS and a P-channel type MOS transistor M<b>1</b> (switching device).</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The first resistor R<b>1</b> and the second resistor R<b>2</b> are connected in series between the power supply wiring <b>3</b> and a ground. A first end of the peripheral wiring <b>4</b>-X is electrically connected with the power supply wiring <b>3</b>, while a second end of the peripheral wiring <b>4</b>-X is electrically connected with a connecting node N<b>1</b> between the first resistor R<b>1</b> and the second resistor R<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In this case, the second end of the peripheral wiring <b>4</b>-X is connected with the connecting node N<b>1</b> through an internal wiring <b>12</b> in the circuit forming region, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The peripheral wiring <b>4</b>-X and the internal wiring <b>12</b> are formed as a contiguous metal wiring by a semiconductor manufacturing process. The peripheral wiring <b>4</b>-X shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3-5</figref> includes the internal wiring <b>12</b>. A resistance of the peripheral wiring <b>4</b>-X including the internal wiring <b>12</b> is set to be small enough to be neglected compared with a resistance R<b>1</b> of the first resistor R<b>1</b> and a resistance R<b>2</b> of the second resistor R<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">A reference voltage Vref is outputted from an output terminal of the reference voltage source VS. One end of the third resistor R<b>3</b> (detection resistor) is connected with the output terminal of the reference voltage source VS. A source of the P-channel type MOS transistor M<b>1</b> is connected with the power supply wiring <b>3</b> while its drain is connected with the other end of the third resistor R<b>3</b>. A voltage at the second end of the peripheral wiring <b>4</b>-X, that is, the connecting node N<b>1</b> between the first resistor R<b>1</b> and the second resistor R<b>2</b> is applied to a gate of the P-channel type MOS transistor M<b>1</b>. A resistor R<b>4</b> for current limiting may be connected between the drain of the P-channel type MOS transistor M<b>1</b> and the third resistor R<b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">While whether the peripheral wiring <b>4</b>-X is broken or not can be detected based on a voltage at a connecting node N<b>2</b> between the drain of the P-channel type MOS transistor M<b>1</b> and the resistor R<b>3</b>, the amplifier circuit Amp<b>1</b> is used to output the voltage with a low impedance.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The amplifier circuit Amp<b>1</b> includes an operational amplifier OP, a fifth resistor R<b>5</b> (feedback resistor) and a photo diode PDx. The voltage at the connecting node N<b>2</b> between the drain of the P-channel type MOS transistor M<b>1</b> and the third resistor R<b>3</b> is applied to a non-inverting input terminal (+) of the operational amplifier OP. A cathode of the photo diode PDx is connected with an inverting input terminal (&#x2212;) of the operational amplifier OP while its anode is grounded.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">As a result, the photo diode PDx is reverse-biased. The fifth resistor R<b>5</b> is connected between an output terminal and the inverting input terminal (&#x2212;) of the operational amplifier OP. There are disposed four photo diodes PDx (x=1, 2, 3 or 4) in a matrix form, each of which is rectangle-shaped as shown in the plan view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and corresponds to each of the first through fourth detection circuits <b>10</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>10</b>-<b>4</b>. The photo diode PDx is formed by stacking a P-type layer and an N-type layer in the top surface of the semiconductor substrate <b>1</b> in the circuit forming region.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The semiconductor integrated circuit <b>100</b> has the function to detect electrically the laser beam from the semiconductor laser in the optical disk unit, as described above. The reference voltage source VS and the amplifier circuit Amp<b>1</b> form a laser beam detection circuit that is intrinsically provided to the semiconductor integrated circuit <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">First, the operation of the detection circuit <b>10</b>-X in the laser beam detection state is explained referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. It is assumed that the peripheral wiring <b>4</b>-X is not broken in this case. The resistance of the peripheral wiring <b>4</b>-X including the internal wiring <b>12</b> is small enough to be neglected compared with the resistance R<b>1</b> of the first resistor R<b>1</b> and the resistance R<b>2</b> of the second resistor R<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Therefore, the voltage at the second end of the peripheral wiring <b>4</b>-X, that is, the connecting node N<b>1</b> between the first resistor R<b>1</b> and the second resistor R<b>2</b> is approximately equal to the power supply voltage Vcc, and the voltage applied to the gate of the P-channel type MOS transistor M<b>1</b> is also approximately equal to the power supply voltage Vcc. Since a voltage between the gate and the source of the P-channel type MOS transistor M<b>1</b> is approximately 0 V because a voltage at the source is equal to the power supply voltage Vcc, the P-channel type MOS transistor M<b>1</b> is turned off. As a result, the voltage at the connecting node N<b>2</b> becomes Vref, and the reference voltage Vref is applied to the non-inverting input terminal (+) of the operational amplifier OP.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">When the reverse-biased photo diode PDx is irradiated with the laser beam in this state, a reverse diode current Ipx corresponding to strength of the laser beam and an area irradiated with the laser beam flows through the photo diode PDx. The diode current Ipx flows from the output terminal of the operational amplifier OP to the photo diode PDx through the fifth resistor R<b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">An output voltage Amp_outx from the operational amplifier OP when irradiated with the laser beam is represented by following Equation (1).
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>Amp_out<i>x=Vref+Ipx&#xd7;R</i>5&#x2003;&#x2003;(1)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
here, R<b>5</b> denotes a resistance of the fifth resistor R<b>5</b>.
</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">When not irradiated with the laser beam, Amp_outx=Vref, because Ipx=0.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Thus, a spot location and the strength of the laser beam can be detected based on the output voltages Amp_out<b>1</b>-Amp_out<b>4</b> of the first through fourth detection circuits <b>10</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>10</b>-<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">For example, when a center of the laser beam spot (a circle depicted by a dashed line) coincides with a center O of the four photo diodes PD<b>1</b>-PD<b>4</b> arrayed in the matrix form as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the four output signals Amp_out<b>1</b>-Amp_out <b>4</b> are equal to each other.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">When the laser beam spot is displaced from the center O of the four photo diodes PD<b>1</b>-PD<b>4</b> arrayed in the matrix form, there are caused differences among the four output signals Amp_out<b>1</b>-Amp_out<b>4</b>, and the displacement of the laser beam spot can be detected in accordance with the differences.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Next, the operation of the detection circuit <b>10</b>-X in the normal state (without breaking of the peripheral wiring <b>4</b>-X) is explained referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. In this case also as in the laser beam detection state shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the P-channel type MOS transistor M<b>1</b> is turned off because the voltage applied to the gate of the P-channel type MOS transistor M<b>1</b> is approximately equal to the power supply voltage Vcc. The photo diode PDx is not irradiated with the laser beam. As a result, the voltage at the connecting node N<b>2</b> becomes Vref, and the output voltage Amp_outx from the detection circuit <b>10</b>-X after going through the operational amplifier OP becomes Vref.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Next, the operation of the detection circuit <b>10</b>-X in the abnormal state (with breaking of the peripheral wiring <b>4</b>-X) is explained referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. Since the peripheral wiring <b>4</b>-X is broken in this case, the voltage at the connecting node N<b>1</b> between the first resistor R<b>1</b> and the second resistor R<b>2</b> is determined as a divided voltage by the first resistor R<b>1</b> and the second resistor R<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">That is, the voltage V(N<b>1</b>) at the connecting node N<b>1</b> is represented by Equation (2).
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>V</i>(<i>N</i>1)=<i>Vcc&#xb7;R</i>2/(<i>R</i>1+<i>R</i>2)&#x2003;&#x2003;(2)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
here, R<b>1</b> denotes the resistance of the first resistor R<b>1</b> and R<b>2</b> denotes the resistance of the second resistor R<b>2</b>.
</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Denoting a threshold voltage of the P-channel type MOS transistor M<b>1</b> as Vtp, R<b>1</b>, R<b>2</b> and Vtp are set to satisfy following Inequality (3).
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>Vcc&#x2212;V</i>(<i>N</i>1)&#x3e;<i>Vtp</i>&#x2003;&#x2003;(3)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">When Inequality (3) is satisfied, the P-channel type MOS transistor M<b>1</b> is turned on. Then, a current Id flows from the P-channel type MOS transistor M<b>1</b> to the reference voltage source VS through the fourth resistor R<b>4</b> and the third resistor R<b>3</b>. Above explanation assumes that Vcc&#x3e;Vref. In the case where Vcc&#x3c;Vref on the other hand, the current Id flows in the opposite direction.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The voltage V(N<b>2</b>) at the connecting node N<b>2</b> is represented by following Equation (4).
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>V</i>(<i>N</i>2)=<i>Vref+Id&#xd7;R</i>3&#x2003;&#x2003;(4)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">It is assumed that the photo diode PDx is not irradiated with the laser beam. Therefore, the output voltage Amp_outx after going through the operational amplifier OP becomes the same as V(N<b>2</b>), and is represented by Equation (5).
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>Amp_out<i>x=Vref+Id&#xd7;R</i>3&#x2003;&#x2003;(5)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">As described above, the output voltage Amp_outx becomes Vref in the case where the peripheral wiring <b>4</b>-X is not broken, while the output voltage Amp_outx becomes Vref+Id&#xd7;R<b>3</b> in the case where the peripheral wiring <b>4</b>-X is broken. Although in reality there appears an error of several tens of millivolts when the output voltage Amp_outx becomes Vref, the two cases can be distinguished from each other by setting Id&#xd7;R<b>3</b> larger enough than the error from Vref. For example, Id&#xd7;R<b>3</b> is set to 1 V when Vref is 2.2 V. As a result, whether the peripheral wiring <b>4</b>-X is broken can be detected based on the output voltage Amp_outx from the detection circuit <b>10</b>-X.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">When the semiconductor integrated circuit <b>100</b> is not provided with the function to detect the laser beam, the operational amplifier circuit Amp<b>1</b> described above may be replaced with an amplifier circuit Amp<b>2</b> that is composed of the operational amplifier OP only, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. That is, the voltage at the connecting node N<b>2</b> is applied to the non-inverting input terminal (+) of the operational amplifier OP and the output voltage from the operational amplifier OP is fed back to the inverting input terminal (&#x2212;) of the operational amplifier OP. In this case, the operational amplifier OP works as an output buffer.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Each of the first through fourth detection circuits <b>10</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>10</b>-<b>4</b> may be formed of a circuit shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> or <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> that is to be described.</p>
<heading id="h-0009" level="1">Second Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a plan view of a semiconductor integrated circuit <b>200</b> according to a second embodiment of this invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a cross-sectional view of a section Y-Y shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>. The semiconductor integrated circuit <b>200</b> is packaged using the WLP technology.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">A semiconductor substrate <b>21</b> is rectangle-shaped as shown in the plan view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, and has four edges L<b>1</b>-L<b>4</b> and four corners K<b>1</b>-K<b>4</b> each corresponding to an intersection of a neighboring pair of the edges. A ring-shaped power supply wiring <b>22</b> is disposed along an entire periphery of a top surface of the semiconductor substrate <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">A region of the semiconductor substrate <b>21</b> surrounded by the power supply wiring <b>22</b> makes a circuit forming region. Pads P<b>1</b>-P<b>8</b> are disposed on a periphery of the circuit forming region. Bump electrodes (protruding electrodes) B<b>1</b>-B<b>8</b> each connected with corresponding each of the pads P<b>1</b>-P<b>8</b> through a wiring layer <b>25</b> are disposed. The power supply wiring <b>22</b> is provided with the power supply voltage Vcc from a power supply pad P<b>6</b> through a wiring (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">As in the first embodiment, each of L-shaped first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>23</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>23</b>-<b>4</b> having a first end and a second end is disposed correspondingly to each of the four corners K<b>1</b>-K<b>4</b> on the periphery of the semiconductor substrate <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">That is, each of the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>23</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>23</b>-<b>4</b> extends from each of locations C<b>1</b>-C<b>4</b> in the circuit forming region corresponding to each of the four corners K<b>1</b>-K<b>4</b> halfway along a neighboring pair of the edges. The first end of each of the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>23</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>23</b>-<b>4</b> is connected with the power supply wiring <b>22</b>. The second ends of the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>23</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>23</b>-<b>4</b> are separated from each other so as not to make a short-circuit. The first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>23</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>23</b>-<b>4</b> may be formed on the semiconductor substrate <b>21</b> outside the power supply wiring <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">It is preferable that a width of the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>23</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>23</b>-<b>4</b> is determined in accordance with a minimum design rule of the semiconductor integrated circuit <b>200</b>, which is 0.6 &#x3bc;m, for example, that is substantially smaller than the width of the power supply wiring <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">Each of first through fourth detection circuits <b>24</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>24</b>-<b>4</b> is disposed in the circuit forming region surrounded by the power supply wiring <b>22</b>, detects the breaking of corresponding each of the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>23</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>23</b>-<b>4</b> in response to a voltage at the second end of corresponding each of the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>23</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>23</b>-<b>4</b>, and outputs corresponding each of first through fourth detection signals Amp_out<b>1</b>-Amp_out<b>4</b> to corresponding each of output pads P<b>1</b>, P<b>4</b>, P<b>5</b> and P<b>8</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">As a result, whether each of the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>23</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>23</b>-<b>4</b> is broken or not can be detected based on corresponding each of the first through fourth detection signals Amp_out<b>1</b>-Amp_out<b>4</b>. The first through fourth detection circuits <b>24</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>24</b>-<b>4</b> have structures identical to the first through fourth detection circuits <b>10</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>10</b>-<b>4</b> in the first embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a cross-sectional view of a region around the output pad P<b>1</b>. The top surface of the semiconductor substrate <b>21</b> on which the power supply wiring <b>22</b>, the output pad P<b>1</b> and the wiring layer <b>25</b> are formed is covered by a resin layer <b>26</b>. The resin layer <b>26</b> on the wiring layer <b>25</b> has a circle-shaped opening through which a bump electrode B<b>1</b> is formed on the wiring layer <b>25</b>. Regions around the other pads P<b>2</b>-P<b>8</b> are formed similarly.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The semiconductor integrated circuit <b>200</b> formed by the WLP technology as described above is shipped to the customer. The customer manufactures various kinds of products by mounting various kinds of electronic parts including the semiconductor integrated circuit <b>200</b> onto a circuit board using electronic parts mounting apparatus such as a chipmounter.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">At that time, the semiconductor integrated circuit <b>200</b> is aligned to the circuit board so that the bump electrodes B<b>1</b>-B<b>8</b> on the back surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit <b>200</b> are electrically connected to printed wirings or the like on the circuit board. In some cases, the defect such as chipping of the semiconductor substrate <b>21</b> of the semiconductor integrated circuit <b>200</b> is caused by the mechanical damage or the stress on that occasion. With the semiconductor integrated circuit <b>200</b> according to the embodiment, it is made possible to electrically identify which of the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>23</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>23</b>-<b>4</b> corresponds to the location where the damage is caused.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">Each of the first through fourth detection circuits <b>24</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>24</b>-<b>4</b> may be formed of a circuit shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> or <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>. Explanation is given assuming that the detection circuit <b>24</b>-X shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> or <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> makes one of the first through fourth detection circuits <b>24</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>24</b>-<b>4</b> and the peripheral wiring <b>23</b>-X shown in the same figure makes corresponding one of the first through fourth peripheral wirings <b>23</b>-<b>1</b>-<b>23</b>-<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The detection circuit <b>24</b>-X shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> includes a sixth resistor R<b>6</b> (detection resistor) and an inverter <b>27</b>. A first end of the peripheral wiring <b>23</b>-X is connected with the power supply wiring <b>22</b>. A second end of the peripheral wiring <b>23</b>-X is connected with one end of the sixth resistor R<b>6</b>. A connecting node between the peripheral wiring <b>23</b>-X and the resistor R<b>6</b> is denoted as N<b>3</b>. Another end of the sixth resistor R<b>6</b> is grounded. A voltage at the connecting node N<b>3</b> is applied to an input terminal of the inverter <b>27</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">In this case, the second end of the peripheral wiring <b>23</b>-X is connected with the connecting node N<b>3</b> through an internal wiring in the circuit forming region, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>. The peripheral wiring <b>23</b>-X and the internal wiring are formed as a contiguous metal wiring by the semiconductor manufacturing process. The peripheral wiring <b>23</b>-X shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> includes the internal wiring. A resistance of the peripheral wiring <b>23</b>-X including the internal wiring is set to be small enough to be neglected compared with a resistance of the sixth resistor R<b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">When the peripheral wiring <b>23</b>-X is not broken, the voltage at the connecting node N<b>3</b> is approximately equal to the power supply voltage Vcc. When the peripheral wiring <b>23</b>-X is broken, the voltage at the connecting node N<b>3</b> is equal to the ground voltage (0 V). When a threshold voltage of the inverter <b>27</b> is set to a voltage between the power supply voltage Vcc and the ground voltage (0 V), preferably to &#xbd;Vcc, an output voltage ERRFLG from the inverter <b>27</b> becomes an L level in the case where the peripheral wiring <b>23</b>-X is not broken, and the output voltage ERRFLG from the inverter <b>27</b> becomes an H level when the peripheral wiring <b>23</b>-X is broken. Thus, whether the peripheral wiring <b>23</b>-X is broken or not can be detected.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">The detection circuit <b>24</b>-X shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> includes a sixth resistor R<b>6</b>, a comparator <b>28</b>, a reference voltage source <b>29</b> and an inverter <b>30</b>. A voltage at a connecting node N<b>3</b> between the peripheral wiring <b>23</b>-X and the sixth resistor R<b>6</b> is applied to a first input terminal (+) of the comparator <b>28</b>. A reference voltage Vref from the reference voltage source <b>29</b> is applied to a second input terminal (&#x2212;) of the comparator <b>28</b>. An output from the comparator <b>28</b> is applied to an input terminal of the inverter <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">When the reference voltage Vref is set to a voltage between the power supply voltage Vcc and the ground voltage (0 V), preferably to &#xbd;Vcc, the output from the comparator <b>28</b> becomes the H level and an output signals ERRFLG from the inverter <b>30</b> becomes the L level because the voltage at the connecting node N<b>3</b> is approximately equal to the power supply voltage Vcc in the case where the peripheral wiring <b>23</b>-X is not broken. On the other hand, the output from the comparator <b>28</b> becomes the L level and the output signal ERRFLG from the inverter <b>30</b> becomes the H level because the voltage at the connecting node N<b>3</b> is at the ground voltage (0 V) when the peripheral wiring <b>23</b>-X is broken. Thus, whether the peripheral wiring <b>23</b>-X is broken or not can be detected.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">Since the defect such as the chipping is prone to be caused in the periphery of the LSI die in the package using the CSP or WLP technology, this invention is particularly effective for detecting the defects in these packages as described above. However, this invention may be also applied to a semiconductor die in general because a similar defect is caused in the general semiconductor die before resin molding in some cases.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">With the semiconductor integrated circuit according to the embodiment of this invention, it is made possible to electrically detect whether there is the defect such as chipping of the LSI die or separation of the resin layer for protection and in which location corresponding to each of the first through fourth peripheral wirings the defect is caused. As a result, controlling so that the LSI die with the defect is not shipped is made possible as well as contributing to analyzing the failure in the LSI die and improving the manufacturing process.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A semiconductor integrated circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a semiconductor substrate comprising four edges and four corners, each of the four corners corresponding to an intersection of a neighboring pair of the edges;</claim-text>
<claim-text>four L-shaped peripheral wirings, each of the four L-shaped peripheral wirings having a first end and a second end and disposed on a periphery of the semiconductor substrate around a corresponding one of the four corners;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a power supply wiring that is of a closed-loop shape and disposed on a periphery of the semiconductor substrate, the power supply wiring being connected with the first end of each of the four peripheral wirings and being provided with a power supply voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>four detection circuits disposed on the semiconductor substrate so as to be surrounded by the power supply wiring, each of the four detection circuits detecting breaking of a corresponding one of the four peripheral wirings in response to a voltage at the second end of the corresponding one of the four peripheral wirings and outputting a detection signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>four output pads disposed on the semiconductor substrate or adjacent the semiconductor substrate, the detection signal of each of the four detection circuits being outputted through a corresponding one of the four output pads.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The semiconductor integrated circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of the four detection circuits comprises a reference voltage source outputting a reference voltage from its output terminal, a detection resistor comprising one end connected with the output terminal of the reference voltage source, and a switching device connected between the power supply wiring and another end of the detection resistor and turning on and off in response to a voltage at the second end of corresponding each of the first through fourth peripheral wirings, so that the breaking of a corresponding one of the four peripheral wirings is detected in accordance with a voltage at a connecting node between the switching device and the detection resistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The semiconductor integrated circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the switching device comprises an MOS transistor, each of the four detection circuits comprises first and second resistors connected in series between the power supply wiring and a ground, the second end of a corresponding one of the four peripheral wirings is connected with a connecting node between the first and second resistors, and the voltage at the second end of each of the four peripheral wirings is applied to a gate of the MOS transistor in a corresponding one of the four detection circuits.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The semiconductor integrated circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein each of the four detection circuits comprises an operational amplifier comprising a first input terminal and a second input terminal, the voltage at the connecting node between the switching device and the detection resistor being applied to the first input terminal of the operational amplifier.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The semiconductor integrated circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein each of the four detection circuits comprises a feedback resistor and a photo diode receiving a laser beam and converting the laser beam into a current, the feedback resistor being connected between an output terminal of the operational amplifier and the photo diode, the second input terminal of the operational amplifier being connected with a cathode of the photo diode.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The semiconductor integrated circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of the four detection circuits comprises a detection resistor and an inverter, the detection resistor being connected between the second end of a corresponding one of the four peripheral wirings and a ground, a voltage at a connecting node between a corresponding one of the four peripheral wirings and the detection resistor being applied to the inverter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The semiconductor integrated circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of the four detection circuits comprises detection resistor, a comparator having a first and second input terminals and a reference voltage source outputting a reference voltage, the detection resistor being connected between the second end of a corresponding one of the four peripheral wirings and a ground, a voltage at a connecting node between a corresponding one of the four peripheral wirings and the detection resistor being applied to the first input terminal of the comparator, the reference voltage being applied to the second input terminal of the comparator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The semiconductor integrated circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the four detection circuits are disposed on a front surface of the semiconductor substrate, and the semiconductor circuit further comprises four protruding electrodes disposed on a back surface of the semiconductor substrate and four wiring layers formed over the back surface and a side surface of the semiconductor substrate, each of the four wiring layers being connected between a corresponding one of the four protruding electrodes and a corresponding one of the four output pads.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The semiconductor integrated circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the four detection circuits are disposed on a front surface of the semiconductor substrate, and the semiconductor circuit further comprises four protruding electrodes disposed on the front surface of the semiconductor substrate and four wiring layers formed over the front surface of the semiconductor substrate and connected between a corresponding one of the four protruding electrodes and a corresponding one of the four output pads. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
