<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08621944-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08621944</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12596213</doc-number>
<date>20080414</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>515</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>10</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7386385</main-classification>
<further-classification> 7386414</further-classification>
<further-classification>422570</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Actuated septa and systems and methods using the same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5637099</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Durdin et al.</name>
<date>19970600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>604192</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6146362</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Turnbull et al.</name>
<date>20001100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>604256</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6361744</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Levy</name>
<date>20020300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7163525</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Franer</name>
<date>20070100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7309469</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Anderson et al.</name>
<date>20071200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>422550</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8034272</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Pavlovic et al.</name>
<date>20111000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>264153</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0036735</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Jepson et al.</name>
<date>20030200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>604247</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0245260</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Rohr et al.</name>
<date>20041200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>220785</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0132877</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>McKinnon et al.</name>
<date>20080600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>604500</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00010">
<othercit>International Search Report from PCT Application No. PCT/US08/60180.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>7</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7386401</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7386414</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7386385</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>422570</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>60912338</doc-number>
<date>20070417</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20100107784</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20100506</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Stein</last-name>
<first-name>David</first-name>
<address>
<city>Succasunna</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Stein</last-name>
<first-name>David</first-name>
<address>
<city>Succasunna</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Siemens Healthcare Diagnostics Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Tarry Town</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Williams</last-name>
<first-name>Hezron E</first-name>
<department>2856</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Fayyaz</last-name>
<first-name>Nashmiya</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/US2008/060180</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20080414</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20091016</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2008/130880</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20081030</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A device, system, and method for passively sealing a vessel containing a fluid and for sampling the fluid without carry-over or cross-contamination between the fluid sampling device, the sealing septum, and the vessel contents. The device includes an actuated septum having a plurality of septum fingers, to passively seal the vessel, and an actuation device, to open the passive seal without carry-over or cross-contamination. Each of the plurality of septum fingers includes a corresponding rib portion. The actuation device can be an actuation ring having an annulus. The plurality of septum fingers and corresponding rib portions are disposed internal or substantially internal to the vessel, while the actuation device is disposed external to the vessel.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="72.81mm" wi="101.35mm" file="US08621944-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="252.73mm" wi="125.14mm" file="US08621944-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="257.73mm" wi="170.35mm" file="US08621944-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="248.67mm" wi="154.60mm" file="US08621944-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The right to priority to U.S. Provisional Patent Application No. 60/912,338 filed on Apr. 17, 2007 and entitled &#x201c;Actuated Septum&#x201d; is hereby asserted.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">STATEMENT REGARDING FEDERALLY SPONSORED RESEARCH OR DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Not Applicable</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates generally to septa that are adapted to seal vessels containing fluids and, more particularly, to actuated septa that reduce cross-contamination between fluid transfer devices, the septa, and the vessel contents and to systems using the same.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Septa are elastomeric, plastic, and/or metallic barriers positioned at the opening of a vessel, e.g., a fluid-containing vessel, that provide a seal between the vessel contents and the ambient environment. Septa serve a myriad of purposes, chief of which are: preventing contamination of the vessel contents and mitigating evaporation of the vessel contents.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">To access vessel contents using a conventional septum-sealed container, a fluid transfer device, such as a sampling probe or hollow cannulus, pierces the seal and/or pushes open septum &#x201c;fingers&#x201d; that passively seal the opening of the vessel. U.S. Pat. No. 5,209,737 to Ritchart, et al. discloses septa having actuation mechanisms that include a plurality of levers radially disposed about a frame. The levers include a pair of wings. The wings are structured and arranged so that as a sampling probe is inserted into the septum, the probe forces open the levers and wings, allowing the probe access to the inner end of a surgical trocar.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">However, when the sampling probe or hollow cannulus is used to push open septum fingers, the potential for carry-over and cross-contamination between the probe or cannulus, the septum, and the vessel contents increases. Therefore, it would be desirable to provide septa having a passive, &#x201c;self-healing&#x201d; closure, and to eliminate such carry-over or cross-contamination. More particularly, it would be desirable to provide actuated septa that include an actuator that precludes the fluid transfer device from having to pierce the septum.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">A device, system, and method for passively sealing a vessel containing a fluid and for sampling the fluid without carry-over or cross-contamination between the fluid sampling device, the sealing septum, and the vessel contents is disclosed. The device includes an actuatable septum having a plurality of septum fingers, to passively seal the vessel, and an actuation device, to open the passive seal without carry-over or cross-contamination of the fluid sampling device. Each of the plurality of septum fingers includes a corresponding rib portion. The actuation device can be an actuation ring having an annulus. The plurality of septum fingers and corresponding rib portions are disposed internal or substantially internal to the vessel, while the actuation device is disposed external to the vessel.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The system includes a fluid transfer device, e.g., a hollow cannulus, a sampling probe, and the like, for adding fluid to or removing fluid from the vessel, the actuatable septum, means for depressing the actuation device against the ribs of the plurality of septum fingers, to break the passive seal and provide an opening into the vessel through the septum, and control means for controlling the means for depressing the actuation device and for introducing into, positioning within, and withdrawing the fluid sampling device from the vessel.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The method includes sealing the vessel with the actuatable septum; depressing the actuation device against the ribs of the plurality of septum fingers, causing the septum fingers to move downward, out and away from the passive seal, to provide an opening; introducing a fluid sampling device through an annulus in the actuation device and the opening; sampling the fluid through the fluid sampling device; removing the fluid sampling device from the opening; and removing the actuation device from against the ribs, allowing the plurality of septum fingers to close and passively re-seal the vessel.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWING</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The invention will be more fully understood with reference to the following Detailed Description of the Invention in conjunction with the Drawings of which:</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a cross-sectional view showing an actuated septum in a passive seal state in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross-sectional view showing an actuated septum in an unsealed state in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a block diagram of an illustrative sampling system in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref> is a cross-sectional view showing a sampling system having an actuated septum in a passive seal state, an actuation ring, and a sampling device in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</figref> is a cross-sectional view showing the sampling system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref> in an unsealed state in accordance with the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an isometric view of the sampling system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">U.S. Provisional Patent Application No. 60/912,338 filed on Apr. 17, 2007 and entitled &#x201c;Actuated Septum&#x201d; from which priority is claimed is incorporated in its entirety herein. An illustrative actuatable septum <b>10</b> for use in sealing a cylindrical vessel is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The septum <b>10</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows the septum <b>10</b> in a passive seal state. The septum <b>10</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows the septum <b>10</b> in an unsealed state.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The septum <b>10</b> is an elastomeric or plastic device that includes an outer ring portion <b>11</b>, a flexible neck portion <b>13</b>, a plurality of septum fingers <b>15</b>, and an actuation ring <b>14</b>. Although the term &#x201c;ring&#x201d; connotes a circle structure, the actuation ring <b>14</b> can be any circular or polygonal shape that includes a central annulus <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The outer ring portion <b>11</b> is structured and arranged to fit snugly in the neck portion of a sample-containing vessel (not shown), to provide a tight, interference fit between the sample-containing vessel and the ambient atmosphere. The flexible neck portion <b>13</b> is connected to the actuation ring <b>14</b> at an upper end <b>16</b> and to the outer ring portion <b>11</b> at a lower end <b>17</b>. Although <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> show a septum <b>10</b> having the actuation ring <b>14</b> connected to the outer ring portion <b>11</b> by the flexible neck portion <b>13</b> in a unitary construction, those of ordinary skill in the art can appreciate that the actuation ring <b>14</b> and septum <b>10</b> can be separate structures (as will be described in greater detail below).</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The septum fingers <b>15</b> are elongate, elastomeric or plastic portions that are structured and arranged to provide a passive seal when in a passive seal state (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) and, moreover, to provide an opening <b>18</b> for accessing the contents of the sampling-containing vessel when in an unsealed state (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). The septum fingers <b>15</b> can be cantilevered from the outer ring portion <b>11</b> into a natural, at-rest position. Although <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> show the septum fingers <b>15</b> joined at the top of the outer ring portion <b>11</b>, the point of juncture can be anywhere along the length of the outer ring portion <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In the natural, at-rest position (&#x201c;passive seal state&#x201d;), each septum finger <b>15</b> is capable of supporting its own weight with a negligible deflection at the center of the passive seal <b>19</b> and along the finger <b>15</b> edges. More specifically, in the passive seal state, each septum finger <b>15</b> is biased so that, absent any applied forces to the actuation ring <b>14</b> or to the septum finger <b>15</b> itself, each septum finger <b>15</b> is in contact with adjacent septum fingers <b>15</b> to provide a passive seal.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, an embodiment having four septum fingers <b>15</b> is shown. Those skilled in the art can appreciate that the septa <b>10</b> can include more or fewer fingers <b>15</b> than those shown. Slits <b>25</b> (whose widths are over-exaggerated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> for illustrative purposes) are provided between adjacent fingers <b>15</b>. Theses slits <b>25</b> can be razor thin discontinuities between adjacent fingers <b>15</b> whereby the adjacent fingers <b>15</b> abut along the respective slit <b>25</b>, thereby forming a tight seal along the length of the slit <b>25</b>. Alternatively, the slits <b>25</b> can have a wider dimension, in which case, each finger <b>15</b> can include a flexible flap <b>26</b> that will provide a tight seal when in the passive seal state. In the passive seal state, the flap <b>26</b> of one of the adjacent fingers <b>15</b> can be above, below or partially above and partially below the flap <b>26</b> of the other adjacent finger <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Each septum finger <b>15</b> is also connected to or includes an organic or integrated rib <b>12</b>. Although <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows the flexible neck portion <b>13</b> connected to the outer ring portion <b>11</b> at a lower end <b>17</b>, alternatively, the flexible neck portion <b>13</b> can be connected to the upper ridge portion <b>21</b> of the ribs <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In a passive seal state, the septum fingers <b>15</b> and corresponding ribs <b>12</b> are disposed internal or substantially internal to the cylindrical vessel, while the actuation ring <b>14</b> is disposed external or substantially external to the cylindrical vessel. In an unsealed state, the actuation ring <b>14</b> is pushed into the ribs <b>12</b>, forcing the septum fingers <b>15</b> to rotate downward, out and away from the center of the passive seal <b>19</b>, to create an opening <b>18</b>. The opening <b>18</b> and the annulus <b>22</b> of the actuation ring <b>14</b> provide a sampling path into which a fluid sampling device <b>34</b> can be inserted and retracted freely without carry-over or cross-contamination between the vessel contents, the septum <b>10</b>, and/or the fluid sampling device <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">After a desired volume of fluid has been sampled from the cylindrical vessel and the fluid sampling device <b>34</b> withdrawn from the opening <b>18</b> and the annulus <b>22</b>, force on the actuation ring <b>14</b> can be removed. With the force removed, the passive nature of the septum fingers <b>15</b> causes the fingers <b>15</b> to return to their natural, passive seal state, producing a passive seal again.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Having described an actuated septum <b>10</b>, a method of accessing the contents of a passively-sealed cylindrical vessel using the same will be described. In a first step, an external actuation ring is depressed against a surface, e.g., the corresponding ribs, of the septum fingers (STEP <b>1</b>) that produce the passive seal. The actuation ring can be depressed mechanically, e.g., using a stepper motor that is capable of moving the actuation ring up and down, and/or magnetically or electromagnetically, e.g., using a permanent magnet or electromagnet.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The applied force of the actuation ring is sufficient to cause the septum fingers to move downward, out and away from the center of the passive seal. Once the septum fingers have moved sufficiently downward, out and away from the center of the passive seal, a fluid sampling device can be inserted into the vessel (STEP <b>2</b>). More specifically, the fluid sampling device can be inserted into the vessel, through the annulus of the actuation ring and through the opening created by the rotational displacement of the septum fingers (STEP <b>2</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The fluid sampling device can then be positioned for sampling the vessel contents. Once a desired volume of the contents of the vessel has been taken by the fluid sampling device (STEP <b>3</b>), the fluid sampling device can be withdrawn from the vessel (STEP <b>4</b>). Finally, the force applied to the actuation ring is removed (STEP <b>5</b>), causing the septum fingers and corresponding ribs to return to their natural, passive seal state.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Having described a method of accessing the contents of a septum-sealed cylindrical vessel, a fluid sampling system for accessing the contents of a septum-sealed cylindrical vessel will now be described. A block diagram of the system <b>30</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</figref>, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> provide cross-sectional and isometric views of the illustrative system <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The system <b>30</b> includes at least one septum-sealed cylindrical vessel <b>32</b>, an actuated septum <b>10</b>, an actuation ring <b>14</b>, means <b>35</b> for depressing the actuation ring, and a fluid sampling device <b>34</b>. The actuated septum <b>10</b> can be of a type described above, i.e., of unitary construction including the actuation ring <b>14</b>. Alternatively, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</figref>, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the septum <b>10</b> and actuation ring <b>14</b> can be separate structures. The fluid sampling device <b>34</b> can be, for example, a sampling probe, a hollow cannulus, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The means <b>35</b> for depressing the actuator ring <b>14</b> of the actuated septum <b>10</b>, can be any mechanical, magnetic, and/or electro-mechanical device that is adapted to depress or otherwise force the actuator ring <b>14</b> against the corresponding ribs <b>12</b> of the septum fingers <b>15</b>, causing the septum fingers <b>15</b> to move downward into the cylindrical vessel <b>32</b>, out and away from the center of the passive seal provided by the septum <b>10</b> in its natural, passive seal state. The means <b>35</b> can include a reciprocating arm(s) (not shown) that can move the actuation ring <b>14</b> up or down in the central axis of the septum <b>10</b> and the vessel <b>32</b>, to engage or disengage from the ribs <b>12</b> of the septum fingers <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Alternatively, the means <b>35</b> can include a projection or protrusions (not shown) that are disposed on the circumferential surface <b>31</b> of the fluid sampling device <b>34</b>. The projection or protrusion is structured and arranged to engage the actuation ring <b>14</b> and to depress or force the actuation ring <b>14</b> into the septum fingers <b>15</b> before the tip <b>39</b> of the fluid sampling device <b>34</b>, as it is being lowered towards the vessel, would otherwise make contact with any portion of the ribs <b>12</b> or fingers <b>15</b>. For example, the projection or protrusion could be cone-shaped with the larger opening of the cone disposed near the tip <b>29</b> at the distal end of the fluid sampling device <b>34</b>. The means <b>35</b> can also include magnetic or electromagnetic means for moving the actuation ring <b>14</b> into or away from the ribs <b>12</b> of the septum fingers <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The system <b>30</b> further includes control means <b>38</b> for controlling the means <b>35</b> for depressing the actuation ring <b>14</b>; for controlling the introduction, advancement, and withdrawal of the fluid sampling device <b>34</b> after an opening <b>18</b> in the actuated septum <b>10</b> has been created; and for controlling sampling of the contents by the fluid sampling device <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">For example, when a protrusion or projection from the circumferential surface of the fluid sampling device is used, the control means <b>38</b> can include a sensor (not shown) and/or an arresting means (not shown). The arresting means is adapted to arrest further advancement of the protrusion or projection into the vessel <b>32</b> only after sensing or otherwise determining that a sufficient sized opening <b>18</b> was created (or should have been created based on the altitude of the protrusion or projection with respect to the altitude of the septum <b>10</b>), while simultaneously allowing the fluid sampling device <b>34</b> to advance to any desired position within the vessel <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The control means <b>38</b> can include a processor or microprocessor that includes software- or hardware-based applications or driver programs to control various stepper motors, vacuum pumps, and the like (not shown), to control the timing of the breaking of the passive seal, the insertion of the fluid sampling device, the sampling of the vessel contents, the withdrawal of the fluid sampling device, and the re-sealing of the septum. Optionally, the control means <b>38</b> can also include software- or hardware-based applications or driver programs for cleaning the tip of the fluid sampling device; for removing and installing disposable tips on the tip of the fluid sampling device; and/or for placing the fluid sample into another vessel.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Although the invention has been described in connection with a cylindrical vessel, the invention is not to be construed as being limited thereto. For example, the vessels could be other than cylindrical. Those of ordinary skill in the art will appreciate that variations to and modification of the above-described device, system, and method. Accordingly, the invention should not be viewed as limited except as by the scope and spirit of the appended Claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A system for sealing a vessel containing a fluid and for providing contamination-free sampling of the fluid from the vessel, the vessel having an opening into the vessel interior, the system comprising:
<claim-text>a fluid transfer device for adding to or removing the fluid from the vessel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an actuatable septum for sealing the vessel, the septum comprising:
<claim-text>an outer ring portion to provide a tight, interference seal between the actuatable septum and an outer surface of the opening of the vessel, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least three septum fingers that are cantilevered from the outer ring portion, the septum fingers in a natural state producing a passive seal, each of the septum fingers having a corresponding upwardly projecting rib portion, the septum fingers and corresponding upwardly projecting rib portions being disposed internal or substantially internal to the vessel;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a substantially ring-shaped actuation device disposed external to the vessel and adapted for selective engagement with the upwardly projecting rib portions of the septum fingers, wherein engagement between the actuation device and the upwardly projecting rib portions of the septum fingers results in a deflection of the septum fingers; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a flexible, skirt-like neck portion encircling and connecting the actuation device with the outer ring portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The system as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the fluid transfer device is selected from the group consisting of a hollow annulus or a sampling probe.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The system as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the fluid transfer device and actuation device are structured and arranged coaxially with the fluid transfer device disposed inside of an annulus of the actuation device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The system as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>means for depressing the actuation device against the upwardly projecting ribs of the septum fingers, to break the passive seal and to provide an opening into the vessel through the actuatable septum.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The system as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>control means for controlling the means for depressing the actuation device and for introducing, advancing, and withdrawing the fluid transfer device into or from the vessel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A method of sampling a fluid from a passively sealed vessel with reduced carry-over or cross contamination, the vessel having an opening into the vessel interior, the method comprising:
<claim-text>sealing the vessel with an actuatable septum having a central axis, the actuatable septum comprising:
<claim-text>an outer ring portion to provide a tight, interference seal between the actuatable septum and an outer surface of the opening of the vessel, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least three septum fingers that are cantilevered from the outer ring portion, the septum fingers in a natural state producing a passive seal, each of the septum fingers having a corresponding upwardly projecting rib portion, the septum fingers and corresponding upwardly projecting rib portions being disposed internal or substantially internal to the vessel;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>depressing a substantially ring-shaped actuation device connected to the outer ring portion by a flexible, skirt-like neck portion, the actuation device being disposed external to the vessel and adapted for selective engagement with the upwardly projecting rib portions of the septum fingers, against said upwardly projecting rib portions of the septum fingers, causing said septum fingers to deflect, to provide an opening in the actuatable septum;</claim-text>
<claim-text>introducing a fluid sampling device through an annulus in the actuation device and the opening in the actuatable septum;</claim-text>
<claim-text>sampling the fluid through the fluid sampling device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>removing the fluid sampling device from the opening in the actuatable septum; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>removing the actuation device from against the upwardly projecting rib portions, allowing the septum fingers to close and passively re-seal the vessel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein depressing the actuation device includes translating the actuation device in the central axis of the actuatable septum mechanically, magnetically or electromechanically.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
