<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622567-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622567</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13764214</doc-number>
<date>20130211</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>21</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>21</main-group>
<subgroup>084</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362105</main-classification>
<further-classification>362103</further-classification>
<further-classification>362106</further-classification>
<further-classification>362107</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Portable light source</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4521831</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Thayer</name>
<date>19850600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362106</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6616294</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Henry</name>
<date>20030900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362106</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7549763</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kim et al.</name>
<date>20090600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362106</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0237422</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Dalton</name>
<date>20081000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2482291</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>13</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362103-108</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation-in-part>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12477614</doc-number>
<date>20090603</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8371707</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13764214</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation-in-part>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130155656</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130620</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Uzar</last-name>
<first-name>Robert Timothy</first-name>
<address>
<city>Newnan</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Uzar</last-name>
<first-name>Robert Timothy</first-name>
<address>
<city>Newnan</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Colton</last-name>
<first-name>Laurence P.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Smith Risley Tempel Santos LLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Carter</last-name>
<first-name>William</first-name>
<department>2875</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A portable light source for connection to a hardhat. The portable light source has a battery housing with an LED light mounted in a lamp holder that is connected either directly to or via a boom or wires to the battery housing. The housing or the lamp holder also has a mounting post that engages an aperture on the side of the hardhat for holding the portable light source in place. The lamp housing may be rotatably connected to the battery housing.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="102.62mm" wi="117.43mm" file="US08622567-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="183.05mm" wi="118.87mm" file="US08622567-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="184.66mm" wi="133.86mm" file="US08622567-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="168.23mm" wi="108.03mm" file="US08622567-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="154.52mm" wi="134.11mm" file="US08622567-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">STATEMENT OF RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 12/477,614 filed on 3 Jun. 2009.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This invention relates to a portable light source that can be mounted on a hardhat.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In an environment in which a worker is required to wear a hardhat, there may also exist a need for supplemental lighting to assist the worker in completing a task or inspecting work product. A conventional handheld flashlight commonly used in such situations occupies the use of one hand of the worker, leaving only one hand free to perform the required tasks. Alternatively, a second helper may be required simply to hold the flashlight while work is being accomplished. In order to free up both hands, a headlamp attached to a headband may be used to provide supplemental lighting to assist the worker in the task at hand. Such a headlamp with a headband may preclude the wearing of a hardhat. Also, a headlamp with a set of straps specifically designed for a hardhat may be strapped to the worker's hardhat in order to free up both of the workers hands. Such a headlamp with a set of straps may be cumbersome, expensive, and difficult to use.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The present invention addresses the difficulties encountered when a worker, required to wear a hardhat, must have supplemental light in order to perform an assigned task that requires both hands. Particularly, the present invention is a compact, lightweight, portable light source that clips into one or both side apertures on a conventional hardhat. A first embodiment of the portable light source includes a housing for containing a battery, a lamp holder rotatably connected to the housing and containing a lamp, preferably a light emitting diode (LED), and a mounting post attached to the housing for engaging a side aperture of the hardhat. A second embodiment of the portable light source includes a housing for containing a battery, a lamp holder fixedly connected to the housing and containing a lamp, preferably a light emitting diode (LED), and a mounting post attached to the housing for engaging a side aperture of the hardhat. A third embodiment of the portable light source includes a housing for containing a battery, a lamp holder containing a lamp, preferably a light emitting diode (LED), a mounting post attached to the lamp holder for engaging a side aperture of the hardhat, and a connector for connecting the housing and the lamp holder together. The portable light source further includes necessary wiring between the battery and the LED, as well as an interconnected switch to connect and disconnect the battery to and from the LED.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The side aperture on both sides of the conventional hardhat typically serves as a mounting mechanism for a facemask or for ear protection. The mounting post of the portable light source is configured and dimensioned to fit into the side aperture on either side of the hardhat. In addition, the mounting post includes a resilient clip that flexes as the mounting post is inserted into the side aperture and engages the side aperture once the mounting post has been completely inserted into the side aperture to hold the portable light source firmly in place within the side aperture.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In the first embodiment, the lamp holder of the portable light source can rotate approximately 360&#xb0; with respect to the housing, the portable light source can be fitted to either side of the hardhat with the LED facing forward or two portable light sources can be fitted to both sides of the hardhat with both LEDs facing forward. In the second embodiment, the lamp holder does not rotate and lamp holders having mirror structures relative to each other can be used on either side of the helmet. In the third embodiment, the portable light source can either rotate or not rotate. With two portable light sources mounted on each side of the hardhat, the hardhat is balanced, and the light from the two portable light sources is spread over a broader field of vision. Further, with rotatable lamp holders, rotating the lamp holder with respect to the housing, allows the LED to be aimed to provide optimum lighting.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Further objects, features and advantages will become apparent upon consideration of the following detailed description of the invention when taken in conjunction with the drawings and the appended claims.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a front perspective view of the portable light source attached to a conventional hardhat in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a front perspective view of the portable light source in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a side elevation view of the portable light source in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a side elevation view of the portable light source attached to a conventional hardhat in accordance with the present invention embodiment of a rotatable lamp holder.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a top plan detailed view of the side aperture of the hardhat shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a side elevation view of a second embodiment of the portable light source in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a side cross sectional view of the portable light source as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> generally along a vertical plane extending into the page in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a side view of a third embodiment of the portable light source in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a rear view of the third embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 3</figref> show a portable light source <b>14</b> constructed in accordance with the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 4</figref> show the portable light source <b>14</b>, in accordance with the present invention, attached to a conventional hardhat <b>10</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows a second embodiment of the portable light source <b>14</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows a cross-section of the invention generally representative of the first and second embodiments. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</figref> show a third embodiment of the portable light source <b>14</b> with the housing <b>16</b> containing the battery <b>70</b> separate from the lamp holder <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Turning to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>3</b> and <b>7</b>, the portable light source <b>14</b> comprises a housing <b>16</b>, a lamp holder <b>22</b>, and a mounting post <b>34</b>. The housing <b>16</b> is generally round or oval in shape and is generally hollow to accommodate a battery compartment covered by an access panel <b>18</b> and a battery <b>70</b> within the battery compartment. An electric switch <b>44</b> is mounted on the housing <b>16</b>. The mounting post <b>34</b> is fixed to the bottom of the housing <b>16</b> and extends from the housing <b>16</b>. The lamp holder <b>22</b> can be rotatably connected to the housing <b>16</b> by means of a pivot joint <b>30</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, or can be non-rotatably connected to the housing <b>16</b>, which also is represented in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref> and <b>6</b>-<b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The lamp holder <b>22</b> comprises a generally hollow body <b>24</b> and generally hollow extension <b>26</b>. A light emitting diode (LED) <b>28</b> is mounted within the extension <b>26</b>. If the pivot joint is present, the pivot joint <b>30</b>, which rotatably connects the body <b>24</b> of the lamp holder <b>22</b> to the housing <b>16</b>, includes an opening <b>74</b> between the hollow housing <b>16</b> and the hollow lamp holder <b>22</b> to accommodate wires <b>72</b> from the battery <b>70</b> in the hollow housing <b>16</b> to the LED in the lamp holder <b>22</b>. Alternatively, the battery <b>70</b> could be mounted within hollow body <b>24</b> of the lamp holder <b>22</b> thereby eliminating the need for an opening <b>74</b> between the housing <b>16</b> and the lamp holder <b>22</b>. The pivot joint <b>30</b> is configured so that sufficient friction exists between the body <b>24</b> of the lamp holder <b>22</b> and the housing <b>16</b> so that the lamp holder <b>22</b> can be rotated to any particular position within a 360&#xb0; arc, and the friction in the pivot joint <b>30</b> will retain the lamp holder <b>22</b> in that relative orientation to the housing <b>16</b>. If the pivot joint is not present, the connection between the body <b>24</b> of the lamp holder <b>22</b> and the housing <b>16</b> also includes an opening <b>74</b> between the hollow housing <b>16</b> and the hollow lamp holder <b>22</b> to accommodate wires <b>72</b> from the battery <b>70</b> in the hollow housing <b>16</b> to the LED in the lamp holder <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">As will be appreciated by those of ordinary skill in the art, wires <b>72</b> connect the LED <b>28</b> to the battery <b>70</b> in the compartment covered by access panel <b>18</b> through the switch <b>44</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The mounting post <b>34</b> is configured and dimensioned to fit into a side aperture <b>12</b> of the hardhat <b>10</b>. The side aperture <b>12</b>, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, is created by loop member <b>20</b>, with a top and bottom opening, molded into the side of the hardhat <b>10</b>. The side aperture <b>12</b> is located on each side of the hardhat <b>10</b> just above the ear of the wearer. The mounting post <b>34</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref> comprises a stop <b>38</b> at the proximal end of the mounting post <b>34</b> and a clip fastener <b>32</b>. The clip fastener <b>32</b> comprises a resilient leg <b>36</b> extending from the stop <b>38</b>, and keepers/cams <b>40</b> located at the distal end of the mounting post <b>34</b>. In the first and second embodiments, the mounting post preferably extends from the housing <b>16</b>, and in the third embodiment, the mounting post <b>34</b> preferably extends from the lamp holder holder <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In use, the mounting post <b>34</b> is inserted into the side aperture <b>12</b> of the hardhat <b>10</b>. The keepers/cams <b>40</b> engage the inside of the side aperture <b>12</b>, and the resilient leg <b>36</b> is forced inwardly toward the hardhat <b>10</b> by the camming action of the keepers/cams <b>40</b> so that the mounting post <b>34</b> can slide into the side aperture <b>12</b>. Once the mounting post <b>34</b> is fully inserted into the side aperture <b>12</b> and the stop <b>38</b> has engaged the top <b>13</b> of the loop member <b>20</b> of the side aperture <b>12</b>, the keepers/cams <b>40</b> clear the bottom <b>15</b> of the loop member <b>20</b> of the side aperture <b>12</b>. Once the keepers/cams <b>40</b> clear the bottom <b>15</b> of the loop member <b>20</b> of the side aperture <b>12</b>, the keepers/cams <b>40</b> engage the bottom <b>15</b> of the loop member <b>20</b> of the side aperture <b>12</b> and hold the mounting post <b>34</b> within the side aperture <b>12</b>. In that manner, the portable light source <b>14</b>, secured within the side aperture <b>12</b>, is securely mounted to the hardhat <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In an alternative embodiment, a mounting post <b>48</b> has a stop <b>60</b> at its proximal end a clip fastener <b>62</b>. The clip fastener <b>62</b> comprises two downwardly extending resilient legs <b>50</b> and <b>54</b> separated by a split <b>58</b>. Each leg has a keeper/cam <b>52</b> and a keeper/cam <b>56</b> respectively at its distal end. The resilient legs <b>50</b> and <b>54</b> are compressed together by the camming action of the keepers/cams <b>52</b> and <b>56</b> when the mounting post <b>48</b> is inserted into the loop member <b>20</b> of the side aperture <b>12</b>. Once the mounting post <b>48</b> has been fully inserted into the side aperture <b>12</b> and the stop <b>60</b> engages the top <b>13</b> of the loop member <b>20</b> of the side aperture <b>12</b>, the keepers/cams <b>52</b> and <b>56</b> are forced outwardly by the resiliency of the legs <b>50</b> and <b>54</b> and engage the bottom <b>15</b> of the loop member <b>20</b> of the side aperture <b>12</b> of the hardhat <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In the first embodiment, in which the lamp holder <b>22</b> is shown in a first position (solid lines) and a second position (dashed lines) in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the lamp holder <b>22</b> can be rotated to various positions relative to the housing <b>12</b>, such as pointing generally forward, as shown in the first position, or pointing generally upwards, as shown in the second position. The pivot joint <b>30</b> can be structured so that the lamp holder <b>22</b> can be rotated to any particular position within a 360&#xb0; arc, and the friction in the pivot joint <b>30</b> will retain the lamp holder <b>22</b> in that relative orientation to the housing <b>16</b>. Alternatively, the pivot joint <b>30</b> can be structured to allow the lamp holder to rotate to set positions or to positions within an arc smaller than 360&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In the second embodiment, in which the lamp holder <b>22</b> is shown in only one position (solid lines) such as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the lamp holder <b>22</b> is not rotatable and will remain in the set position relative to the housing <b>12</b>, such as pointing generally forward, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. In this second embodiment, the lamp holder <b>22</b> can be rigidly attached to the housing <b>16</b>, such as for example by adhesives, heat or sonic welding, or non-rotatable clips or snaps.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In the third embodiments, in which the lamp holder <b>22</b> and the housing <b>16</b> are separate from each other as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</figref>, the lamp holder <b>22</b> comprises the mounting post <b>34</b> and the lamp holder <b>22</b> is mounted into the loop member <b>20</b> of the side aperture <b>12</b>. In a preferred embodiment, two lamp holders <b>22</b> are used, one on each side of the hardhat <b>10</b>, and an elastic strap <b>80</b> extends from the rear side of each of the lamp holders <b>22</b> to the housing <b>16</b>, with a first end of each respective elastic strap <b>80</b> attached to the lamp holder <b>22</b> and a second opposite end of each elastic strap <b>80</b> attached to the housing <b>16</b>. Thus, the housing <b>16</b> is held against the rear of the hardhat <b>10</b> by the action of the elastic straps. Wires <b>72</b> extend between the battery <b>70</b> in the housing to the LED in the lamp holder <b>22</b>. Alternatively, instead of an elastic strap <b>80</b>, a boom member <b>84</b> extends from the rear side of the lamp holder <b>22</b> to the housing <b>16</b>, with a first end of the boom member <b>80</b> attached to the lamp holder <b>22</b> and a second opposite end of the boom member <b>80</b> attached to the housing <b>16</b>. The wires can be located outside of the boom member <b>80</b> or within a cavity through the boom member <b>80</b>. An on-off switch <b>82</b> can be mounted on the housing <b>16</b> to activate the LED.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In the third embodiments, one, two, or more lamp housings <b>22</b> can be used, preferably one or two, and even more preferably two, all preferably attached electrically or physically and electrically to the same housing <b>16</b>. If two lamp housings <b>22</b> are used, each lamp housing <b>22</b> can have an elastic strap <b>80</b> or a boom member <b>84</b> connecting the respective lamp housing to the housing <b>16</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, one elastic strap <b>80</b> or boom member <b>84</b> can extend from each side of the housing <b>16</b> to the respective lamp holder <b>22</b> on either side of the hardhat <b>10</b>. Similarly, wires <b>72</b> can extend from a battery <b>70</b> to a respective LED in a respective lamp holder <b>22</b>. Housing <b>16</b> can be physically attached to the hardhat <b>10</b> via adhesives, clips, tapes, or the like, or can be supported against or proximal to the hardhat <b>10</b> via the elastic straps <b>80</b> or boom members <b>84</b>. Boom members <b>84</b> can be rigid or flexible members made of any suitable material, such as for example, metal or plastic. In the third embodiments, each lamp holder <b>22</b> can comprise a pivot joint <b>30</b> and be rotatable, or not comprise a pivot joint <b>30</b> and not be rotatable. In one embodiment, two pivotable lamp holders <b>22</b> can be used, in another embodiment, two non-pivotable lamp holders <b>22</b> can be used, and in yet another embodiment, one pivotable and one non-pivotable lamp holder <b>22</b> can be used.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">While this invention has been described with reference to preferred embodiments thereof, it is to be understood that variations and modifications can be affected within the spirit and scope of the invention as described herein and as described in the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A portable light source for mounting on a hardhat having a side aperture, the portable light source comprising:
<claim-text>a) a housing holding a battery;</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) a lamp holder, for supporting a lamp, mounted to the housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) an opening between the housing and the lamp holder; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) a mounting post fixed to the housing and having a resilient clip fastener,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein wires between the battery and the lamp pass through the opening between the housing and the lamp holder, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the mounting post is configured and dimensioned to fit into the side aperture of the hardhat, and the clip fastener engages the side aperture to secure the portable light source to the hardhat.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The portable light source of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the lamp holder includes a hollow body for holding a battery.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A portable light source for mounting on a hardhat having a side aperture, the portable light source comprising:
<claim-text>a) a housing holding a battery;</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) a lamp holder, for supporting a lamp;</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) a connecting member connecting the lamp holder to the housing, wherein the connecting member is a boom;</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) electrical wires for connecting the battery to the lamp; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>e) a mounting post fixed to the lamp holder and having a resilient clip fastener,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the mounting post is configured and dimensioned to fit into the side aperture of the hardhat, and the clip fastener engages the side aperture to secure the portable light source to the hardhat, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the housing is separately supported by the connecting member.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The portable light source of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, further comprising a pivot joint between the lamp housing and the mounting post, wherein the pivot joint is configured so that the lamp holder is rotatable relative to the mounting post.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The portable light source of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the pivot joint is configured so that the lamp holder is rotatable relative to the mounting post to any position within a 360&#xb0; arc.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The portable light source of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, comprising two lamp holders and only one housing, wherein the two lamp holders are connected to the one housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A combination hardhat and light source, comprising:
<claim-text>a) a hardhat having a side aperture; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) a portable light source for mounting on the hardhat, the portable light source comprising:
<claim-text>i) a housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>ii) a lamp holder, for supporting a lamp, mounted to the housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>iii) an opening between the housing and the lamp holder; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>iv) a mounting post fixed to the housing and having a resilient clip fastener,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the mounting post is configured and dimensioned to fit into the side aperture of the hardhat, and the clip fastener engages the side aperture to secure the portable light source to the hardhat, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the housing holds a battery, and wires between the battery and the lamp pass through the opening between the housing and the lamp holder.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The combination hardhat and light source of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the side aperture is a loop member having a top and bottom opening molded into a side of the hardhat.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The combination hardhat and light source of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the hardhat further comprises two side apertures, and wherein the mounting post is configured and dimensioned to fit into either of the two side apertures of the hardhat.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A combination hardhat and light source comprising:
<claim-text>a) a hardhat comprising a side aperture; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) a portable light source for mounting on the hardhat, the portable light source comprising:
<claim-text>i) a housing holding a battery;</claim-text>
<claim-text>ii) a lamp holder, for supporting a lamp;</claim-text>
<claim-text>iii) a connecting member connecting the lamp holder to the housing, wherein the connecting member is a boom;</claim-text>
<claim-text>iv) electrical wires for connecting the battery to the lamp; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>v) a mounting post fixed to the lamp holder and having a resilient clip fastener,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the mounting post is configured and dimensioned to fit into the side aperture of the hardhat, and the clip fastener engages the side aperture to secure the portable light source to the hardhat, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the housing is separately supported by the connecting member.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The portable light source of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising a pivot joint between the lamp housing and the mounting post, wherein the pivot joint is configured so that the lamp holder is rotatable relative to the mounting post.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The portable light source of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the pivot joint is configured so that the lamp holder is rotatable relative to the mounting post to any position within a 360&#xb0; arc.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The portable light source of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, comprising two lamp holders and only one housing, wherein the two lamp holders are connected to the one housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
