<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624789-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624789</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12743336</doc-number>
<date>20071218</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2007-0123291</doc-number>
<date>20071130</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>396</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>Q</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>08</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>343757</main-classification>
<further-classification>343763</further-classification>
<further-classification>343766</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Apparatus for adjusting an inclination angle in an antenna</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0155828</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Heinz et al.</name>
<date>20040800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>343757</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0209572</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Thomas</name>
<date>20041000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0066494</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Trejtnar et al.</name>
<date>20060300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>343757</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0198080</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Duan</name>
<date>20080800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>343758</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>1020070049459</doc-number>
<date>20070500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO 2006/128339</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20051200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-cpc-text>H01Q 3/32</classification-cpc-text>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>2006128339</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20061200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO 2006128339</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20061200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00009">
<othercit>International Search Report dated Aug. 25, 2008, based on PCT/KR2007/006627.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>11</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>343757</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>343763</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>343766</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110134005</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110609</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Oh</last-name>
<first-name>Gun-Seok</first-name>
<address>
<city>Incheon</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Oh</last-name>
<first-name>Byung-II</first-name>
<address>
<city>Gyeonggi-Do</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Byung-Hwan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Incheon</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Oh</last-name>
<first-name>Gun-Seok</first-name>
<address>
<city>Incheon</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Oh</last-name>
<first-name>Byung-II</first-name>
<address>
<city>Gyeonggi-Do</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Byung-Hwan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Incheon</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Edwards Wildman Palmer LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Ace Antenna Corp.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Incheon</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Owens</last-name>
<first-name>Douglas W</first-name>
<department>2821</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Dawkins</last-name>
<first-name>Collin</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/KR2007/006627</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20071218</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20100517</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2009/069842</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20090604</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An apparatus for adjusting an inclination angle of an antenna using a rotatory power is disclosed, wherein a remote control unit is easily combined with the apparatus. The apparatus in an antenna having a phase shifter includes a power delivering member connected to the phase shifter, and a driving member combined with the power delivering member, and for providing a power to the power delivering member. Here, an inserting section is formed at a part of outside surfaces of the driving member, a remote control unit is inserted into the inserting section and rotates the driving member, and the power delivering member rotates in response to the power provided from the driving member. Accordingly, any given member is not removed when the remote control unit is combined with the apparatus. As a result, the remote control unit may be easily combined with the apparatus, and any member is not lost.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="76.79mm" wi="171.96mm" file="US08624789-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="225.38mm" wi="192.79mm" file="US08624789-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="208.20mm" wi="189.48mm" file="US08624789-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="165.61mm" wi="164.59mm" file="US08624789-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="176.95mm" wi="175.60mm" file="US08624789-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="143.17mm" wi="122.94mm" file="US08624789-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCES TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a U.S. national phase application, pursuant to 35 U.S.C. &#xa7;371 of PCT/KR2007/006627, filed Dec. 18, 2007, designating the United States, which claims priority to Korean Application No. 10-2007-0123291, filed Nov. 30, 2007. The entire contents of the aforementioned patent applications are incorporated herein by this reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Example embodiment of the present invention relates to an inclination angle adjusting apparatus for adjusting an inclination angle of an antenna using a rotatory power, wherein a remote control unit is easily combined with the inclination angle apparatus.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND ART</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">An antenna transmits or receives an electromagnetic wave by outputting a certain beam, and thus the antenna must be able to adjust direction of the beam. An apparatus of adjusting the direction of the beam is an inclination angle adjusting apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a common first inclination angle adjusting apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the first inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>100</b> includes a power delivering member <b>102</b>, a body <b>104</b> and a driving member <b>106</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In case that a user rotates the driving member <b>106</b> using his hand, the power delivering member <b>102</b> moves linearly in response to the rotation of the driving member <b>106</b>. As a result, a phase shifter (not shown) connected to the power delivering member <b>102</b> controls phase of a RF signal inputted from an outside, thereby adjusting an inclination angle of the antenna. Here, a thread <b>108</b> is formed on the power delivering member <b>102</b>, and a structure (not shown) corresponding to the thread <b>108</b> is formed on an internal surface of the driving member <b>106</b> so that the power delivering member <b>102</b> moves in response to operation of the driving member <b>106</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In the above first inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>100</b>, the driving member <b>106</b> may be moved by an external force such as quake, impact, etc despite a user does not rotate the driving member <b>106</b>. Accordingly, to prevent this moving phenomenon, the first inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>100</b> fixes the driving member <b>106</b> using a cap <b>110</b> when the inclination angle is not adjusted.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In case that the user wants to rotate the driving member <b>106</b> using a remote control unit such as a motor, etc, the cap <b>110</b> is separated from the driving member <b>106</b>, and then the remote control unit is combined with the driving member <b>106</b>. As a result, it is inconvenient to separate the cap <b>110</b>, and the separated cap <b>110</b> may be lost.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a common second inclination angle adjusting apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the second inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>200</b> includes a power delivering member <b>202</b>, a body <b>204</b> and a driving member <b>206</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The driving member <b>206</b> is combined with a thread <b>216</b> formed on an end of the power delivering member <b>202</b> so that the driving member <b>206</b> is fixed to the power delivering member <b>202</b>. Here, the power delivering member <b>202</b> moves linearly according as a user pushes or pulls the driving member <b>206</b>, and a phase shifter connected to the power delivering member <b>202</b> adjusts an inclination angle of the antenna in response to the moving.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The body <b>204</b> houses the power delivering member <b>202</b>, thereby protecting the power delivering member <b>202</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Power delivering member fixing members, i.e. a nut <b>208</b>, a bush <b>210</b> and a fixing member <b>212</b> fix the power delivering member <b>202</b> so that the power delivering member <b>202</b> is not separated from the body <b>204</b> by an external force such as quake, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">However, in case of controlling the second inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>200</b> using a remote control unit, the power delivering member fixing members and the driving member <b>206</b> must be separated before the remote control unit is combined with the power delivering member <b>202</b>. As a result, inconvenient process of combining or separating the power delivering member fixing members and the driving member <b>206</b> should be performed. In addition, the separated members may be lost.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DISCLOSURE OF INVENTION</heading>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">Technical Problem</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Accordingly, the present invention is provided to substantially obviate one or more problems due to limitations and disadvantages of the related art.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Example embodiment of the present invention provides an inclination angle adjusting apparatus for combining easily with a remote control unit and preventing loss of a specific member.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Another example embodiment of the present invention provides an inclination angle adjusting apparatus for fixing easily a driving member to a body or separating easily the driving member from the body by using a simple method of combining a hook member with a cylindrical home or an imperfect cylindrical home.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">Technical Solution</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">An inclination angle adjusting apparatus in an antenna having a phase shifter according to one example embodiment of the present invention includes a power delivering member connected to the phase shifter; and a driving member combined with the power delivering member, and configured to provide a power to the power delivering member. Here, a first inserting section is formed on a part of outside surfaces of the driving member, a remote control unit is inserted into the first inserting section of the driving member and rotates the driving member, and the power delivering member rotates in response to the power provided from the driving member.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The inclination angle adjusting apparatus further includes a body configured to house the power delivering member, wherein the driving member is combined with the body.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">At least one hook member is formed on an end of the driving member, and a cylindrical home and imperfect cylindrical homes are formed on an outside surface of the body. Here, the driving member is rotated on the body when the hook member is combined with the cylindrical home, and the driving member is fixed to the body when the hook member is combined with the imperfect cylindrical home.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The inclination angle adjusting apparatus further includes a fixing member combined with an end of the body so that the hook member is not separated from the imperfect cylindrical home by an outside force when the hook member is combined with the imperfect cylindrical home.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The driving member has a projection member, and a second inserting section is formed on an end of the power delivering member, and wherein the projection member is inserted into the second inserting section when the driving member is combined with the power delivering member.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The driving member has cylindrical shape, and the projection member is projected from an internal surface of the driving member.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The projection member has polygon shape, and the second inserting section has shape corresponding to the projection member.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The first inserting section has polygon shape.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">At least one hook member is formed on an end of the driving member, and a cylindrical home and imperfect cylindrical homes are formed on an outside surface of the body. Here, the driving member is rotated on the body when the hook member is combined with the cylindrical home, the driving member is fixed to the body when the hook member is combined with the imperfect cylindrical home, and the hook member combined with the imperfect cylindrical home is automatically moved on the cylindrical home when the remote control unit is inserted into the first inserting section of the driving member.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">At least one sliding protection projection member is formed on the outside surface of the driving member.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">A thread is formed on a part of an outside surface of the power delivering member, and an indicating member for indicating change degree of an inclination angle is disposed on the thread.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The rotatory power delivered from the driving member is provided to a phase shifter through the power delivering member, and the phase shifter adjusts an inclination angle of the antenna using the provided rotatory power.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The phase shifter includes a gear worm combined with the power delivering member; and a gear wheel connected to the gear worm and configured to rotate in accordance with operation of the gear worm. Here, the inclination angle of the antenna is adjusted in accordance with rotation of the gear wheel.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">An inclination angle adjusting apparatus in an antenna according to another example embodiment of the present invention includes a body, wherein a cylindrical home and at least one imperfect cylindrical home are formed on the body; and a driving member configured to have one or more hook member. Here, the driving member is rotated on the body when the hook member is combined with the cylindrical home, and the driving member is fixed to the body when the hook member is combined with the imperfect cylindrical home.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The inclination angle adjusting apparatus of claim <b>14</b> further includes a power delivering member combined with a phase shifter, and configured to deliver a rotatory power in accordance with rotation of the driving member to the phase shifter; and a fixing member combined with an end of the body so that the hook member is not separated from the imperfect cylindrical home by an outside force when the hook member is combined with the imperfect cylindrical home, wherein the body houses the power delivering member.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The driving member has a projection member, and an inserting section is formed on an end of the power delivering member. Here, the projection member is inserted into the inserting section of the power delivering member when the driving member is combined with the power delivering member.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The projection member has polygon shape, and the inserting section has shape corresponding to the projection member.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">At least one sliding protection projection member is formed on the outside surface of the driving member.</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">Advantageous Effects</heading>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In an inclination angle adjusting apparatus of the present invention, an inserting section is formed on an outside surface of a driving member, wherein a remote control unit is inserted into the inserting section. Accordingly, certain members may not be removed when the remote control unit is combined with the inclination angle adjusting apparatus. As a result, the remote control unit may be easily combined with the inclination angle adjusting apparatus, and certain members may not be lost.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In an inclination angle adjusting apparatus according to another example embodiment of the present invention, a driving member is fixed to a body or separated from the body through a simple method of combining a hook member with a cylindrical home or an imperfect cylindrical home. That is, extra members for fixing the inclination angle adjusting apparatus are not needed, and the driving member may be easily fixed to the body through the above simple method.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Example embodiments of the present invention will become more apparent by describing in detail example embodiments of the present invention with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a common first inclination angle adjusting apparatus;</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a common second inclination angle adjusting apparatus;</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view illustrating an inclination angle adjusting apparatus in an antenna according to one example embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a top view illustrating a phase shifter according to one example embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a lower part of the phase shifter in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a sectional view illustrating schematically the phase shifter in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a perspective view illustrating the inclination angle adjusting apparatus in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a perspective view illustrating an inclination angle adjusting apparatus according to one example embodiment of the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a perspective view illustrating internal structure of an inclination angle adjusting apparatus according to one example embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0009" level="1">MODE FOR THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Example embodiments of the present invention are disclosed herein. However, specific structural and functional details disclosed herein are merely representative for purposes of describing example embodiments of the present invention, however, example embodiments of the present invention may be embodied in many alternate forms and should not be construed as limited to example embodiments of the present invention set forth herein.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Accordingly, while the invention is susceptible to various modifications and alternative forms, specific embodiments thereof are shown by way of example in the drawings and will herein be described in detail. It should be understood, however, that there is no intent to limit the invention to the particular forms disclosed, but on the contrary, the invention is to cover all modifications, equivalents, and alternatives falling within the spirit and scope of the invention. Like numbers refer to like elements throughout the description of the figures.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">It will be understood that, although the terms first, second, etc. may be used herein to describe various elements, these elements should not be limited by these terms. These terms are only used to distinguish one element from another. For example, a first element could be termed a second element, and, similarly, a second element could be termed a first element, without departing from the scope of the present invention. As used herein, the term &#x201c;and/or&#x201d; includes any and all combinations of one or more of the associated listed items.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">It will be understood that when an element is referred to as being &#x201c;connected&#x201d; or &#x201c;coupled&#x201d; to another element, it can be directly connected or coupled to the other element or intervening elements may be present. In contrast, when an element is referred to as being &#x201c;directly connected&#x201d; or &#x201c;directly coupled&#x201d; to another element, there are no intervening elements present. Other words used to describe the relationship between elements should be interpreted in a like fashion (i.e., &#x201c;between&#x201d; versus &#x201c;directly between&#x201d;, &#x201c;adjacent&#x201d; versus &#x201c;directly adjacent&#x201d;, etc.).</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The terminology used herein is for the purpose of describing particular embodiments only and is not intended to be limiting of the invention. As used herein, the singular forms &#x201c;a&#x201d;, &#x201c;an&#x201d; and &#x201c;the&#x201d; are intended to include the plural forms as well, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise. It will be further understood that the terms &#x201c;comprises&#x201d;, &#x201c;comprising,&#x201d;, &#x201c;includes&#x201d; and/or &#x201c;including&#x201d;, when used herein, specify the presence of stated features, integers, steps, operations, elements, and/or components, but do not preclude the presence or addition of one or more other features, integers, steps, operations, elements, components, and/or groups thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Unless otherwise defined, all terms (including technical and scientific terms) used herein have the same meaning as commonly understood by one of ordinary skill in the art to which this invention belongs. It will be further understood that terms, such as those defined in commonly used dictionaries, should be interpreted as having a meaning that is consistent with their meaning in the context of the relevant art and will not be interpreted in an idealized or overly formal sense unless expressly so defined herein.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view illustrating an inclination angle adjusting apparatus in an antenna according to one example embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b> of the present embodiment adjusts an inclination angle of the antenna, and is connected to a phase shifter <b>316</b> as described below. Particularly, the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b> delivers a rotatory power to the phase shifter. The phase shifter <b>316</b> changes phase of a RF signal inputted from an outside device (not shown) in accordance with the delivered rotatory power, thereby adjusting direction of a beam outputted from the antenna. This will be described in detail with reference to accompanying drawing.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b> includes a power delivering member <b>302</b>, a body <b>304</b>, a driving member <b>306</b> and an indicating member <b>312</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The power delivering member <b>302</b> is connected to the phase shifter <b>316</b>, and delivers the rotatory power generated by the driving member <b>306</b> to the phase shifter <b>316</b>. Here, connection of the power delivering member <b>302</b> and the phase shifter <b>316</b> is not shown, but may be variously modified as long as the power delivering member <b>302</b> delivers the rotatory power to the phase shifter.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The body <b>304</b> houses the power delivering member <b>302</b>, thereby protecting the power delivering member <b>302</b>. A scale for indicating change degree of the inclination angle may be indicated on a part of the body <b>304</b>, preferably a part corresponding to the indicating member <b>312</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The driving member <b>306</b> combines with the body <b>304</b> so that the driving member <b>306</b> is rotated on the body <b>304</b>. That is, the driving member <b>306</b> combines with the body <b>304</b> so that a user can rotate the driving member <b>306</b> using his hands. In addition, a projection member combined with the power delivering member <b>302</b> is formed on an internal surface of the driving member <b>306</b> as described below. Accordingly, in case that the user rotates the driving member <b>306</b>, the rotatory power is generated from the driving member <b>306</b>. The generated rotatory power is delivered to the power delivering member <b>302</b> through the projection member.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">An inserting section <b>310</b> is formed on an outside surface of the driving member <b>306</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">In the above description, the user rotates directly the driving member <b>306</b>, but the driving member <b>306</b> may be rotated by a remote control unit, e.g. a motor. In this case, the remote control unit <b>314</b> rotates the driving member <b>306</b> under the condition that the remote control unit is inserted into the inserting section <b>310</b> of the driving member <b>306</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In one example embodiment of the present invention, the inserting section <b>310</b> of the driving member <b>306</b> may have polygon shape so that the rotatory power of the remote control unit is more much delivered.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The driving member <b>306</b> has cylindrical shape as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. Here, a sliding protection projection member <b>308</b> may be formed on an outside surface of the driving member <b>306</b> so that the user's hand does not slide when the user rotates the driving member <b>306</b> using his hand.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The indicating member <b>312</b> indicates change degree of the inclination angle, and moves in response to the rotation of the driving member <b>306</b>. In this case, a user detects change degree of the inclination angle by verifying location of the indicating member <b>312</b> through scale indicated at the body <b>304</b>. In one example embodiment of the present invention, a first thread is formed on a part of the power delivering member <b>302</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, and a second thread corresponding to the first thread is formed on an internal surface of the indicating member <b>312</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">In brief, the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b> of the present embodiment generates the rotatory power by rotating the driving member <b>306</b>, and adjusts the inclination angle of the antenna using the generated rotatory power. Specially, the remote control unit is directly combined with the driving member <b>306</b> by inserted into the inserting section <b>310</b> without removing some of elements in the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b>. Hence, the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b> of the present invention may more easily combine the remote control unit with the driving member <b>306</b> or separate the remote control unit from the driving member <b>306</b> than the inclination angle adjusting apparatus in related art.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In addition, since no element is removed when the remote control unit is combined with the driving member <b>306</b>, the elements in the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b> of the present invention may be not lost unlike in the inclination angle adjusting apparatus in related art.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Hereinafter, the phase shifter combined with the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b> and for changing phase of corresponding signal will be described.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a top view illustrating a phase shifter according to one example embodiment of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a lower part of the phase shifter in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a sectional view illustrating schematically the phase shifter in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the phase shifter of the present embodiment includes a dielectric substrate <b>400</b>, a first line <b>402</b>, a second line <b>404</b>, an input line <b>406</b>, an output line <b>408</b>, a rotation axis member <b>410</b>, an arm member <b>412</b>, a guide member <b>414</b>, a first rotation member <b>500</b> and a second rotation member <b>502</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The rotation members <b>500</b> and <b>502</b> located in a lower part of the phase shifter are combined with the members <b>400</b>, <b>412</b> and <b>414</b> located in an upper part of the phase shifter as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">Hereinafter, operation of the elements in the phase shifter will be described in detail.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">The dielectric substrate <b>400</b> is made up of dielectric material having a certain dielectric constant. Here, a ground plate (not shown) is formed on a lower surface of the dielectric substrate <b>400</b> or in the dielectric substrate <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The first line <b>402</b> is a conductor, and is formed on the dielectric substrate <b>400</b> with for example curve shape. Here, ends of the first line <b>402</b> are electrically connected to some of radiation devices (not shown), e.g. a first radiation device and a second radiation device, which is not shown.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The second line <b>404</b> is a conductor, and is formed on the dielectric substrate <b>400</b> with for example curve shape. Here, ends of the first line <b>402</b> are electrically connected to some of the radiation devices, e.g. a third radiation device and a fourth radiation device, which is not shown.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">The input line <b>406</b> is a conductor. Here, a RF signal is inputted to the input line <b>406</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">Some of the inputted RF signal is outputted to a corresponding radiation device through a first dielectric substrate area located below the output line <b>408</b> without change of its phase. The other RF signal is coupled at the rotation axis member <b>410</b>, and then is outputted to corresponding radiation devices through a second dielectric substrate area located below the arm member <b>412</b>. As a result, an array antenna having the radiation devices radiates a given beam which is changed in response to phase change of the RF signal in accordance with transmission path of the RF signal.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">The second rotation member <b>502</b> combines with the power delivering member <b>302</b> of the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b>, and rotates in response to the rotatory power delivered from the power delivering member <b>302</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">The first rotation member <b>500</b> rotates in response to the rotation of the second rotation member <b>502</b>. In one example embodiment of the present invention, the second rotation member <b>502</b> is a gear worm, and the first rotation member <b>500</b> is a gear wheel.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">The rotation axis member <b>410</b> is connected to the first rotation member <b>500</b> located in the lower part of the phase shifter, and is connected to the arm member <b>412</b> and the guide member <b>414</b> located in the upper part of the phase shifter.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">The rotation axis member <b>410</b> rotates in accordance with the rotation of the rotation members <b>500</b> and <b>502</b>, and so the arm member <b>412</b> and the guide member <b>414</b> rotate in response to the rotation of the rotation axis member <b>410</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">The guide member <b>414</b> is connected to the rotation axis member <b>410</b> and the arm member <b>412</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, and delivers the rotatory power in accordance with the rotation of the rotation axis member <b>410</b> to the arm member <b>412</b>. As a result, the arm member <b>412</b> rotates with guide member <b>414</b> in accordance with the delivered rotatory power.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">In brief, the phase shifter is connected to the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b>, and controls the phase of the inputted RF signal in response to the rotatory power delivered from the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b>. As a result, direction of the beam outputted from the antenna is adjusted. That is, the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b> provides the rotatory power to the phase shifter, thereby adjusting the inclination angle of the antenna.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">The phase shifter of the present embodiment may be variously modified as long as the phase shifter uses the rotatory power delivered from the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b>, i.e. is not limited as structure in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">Hereinafter, structure of the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b> will be described in detail with reference to accompanying drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a perspective view illustrating the inclination angle adjusting apparatus in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, a cylindrical home <b>700</b> and at least one imperfect cylindrical home <b>702</b> are formed on the body <b>304</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">In case that the driving member <b>306</b> is combined with the cylindrical home <b>700</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the driving member <b>306</b> may rotate on the cylindrical home <b>700</b> due to characteristic of the cylindrical home <b>700</b>. However, in case that the driving member <b>306</b> is combined with the imperfect cylindrical home <b>702</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the driving member <b>306</b> is fixed to the imperfect cylindrical home <b>702</b> without rotated.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">In one example embodiment, at least one hook member is formed on the internal surface of the driving member <b>306</b>, which is not shown. In this case, the hook member is hung at the imperfect cylindrical home <b>702</b>, and so the driving member <b>306</b> is fixed to the body <b>304</b>. As a result, the driving member <b>306</b> may be stably fixed to the body <b>304</b> though an external force such as impact, etc is generated.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">In other words, a user combines the driving member <b>306</b> with the cylindrical home <b>700</b>, and then rotates the driving member <b>306</b>, thereby adjusting the inclination angle of the antenna. Subsequently, the user pulls the driving member <b>306</b> and combines the driving member <b>306</b> with the imperfect cylindrical home <b>702</b>, thereby fixing the driving member <b>306</b> to the imperfect cylindrical home <b>702</b> so that the driving member <b>306</b> is not rotated by the external force. In case that the user wants to adjust again the inclination angle of the antenna, the user pushes the driving member <b>306</b> so that the driving member <b>306</b> is located on the cylindrical home <b>700</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">In short, unlike the inclination angle adjusting apparatus in related art where the driving member is fixed by using extra members, the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b> of the present embodiment fixes the driving member <b>306</b> through a simple method of pulling or pushing the driving member <b>306</b>. Accordingly, extra member for fixing the driving member <b>306</b> is not needed in the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a perspective view illustrating an inclination angle adjusting apparatus according to one example embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b> of the present embodiment includes fixing members <b>802</b>, <b>804</b> and <b>806</b> as well as the power delivering member <b>302</b>, the body <b>304</b> and the driving member <b>306</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">A projection member <b>800</b> is formed on an internal surface of the driving member <b>306</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>. An inserting section <b>808</b> is formed on an end of the power delivering member <b>302</b>, wherein the projection member <b>800</b> is inserted into the inserting section <b>808</b>. That is, the driving member <b>306</b> is combined with the power delivering member <b>302</b> by inserting the projection member <b>800</b> into the inserting section <b>808</b> when the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b> is assembling.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">In one example embodiment of the present invention, the projection member <b>800</b> has polygon shape so that the rotatory power generated by the driving member <b>306</b> is more delivered to the power delivering member <b>302</b>. The inserting section <b>808</b> has also shape corresponding to the projection member <b>800</b>, i.e. polygon shape.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">The fixing member <b>802</b> combines with a thread <b>810</b> formed on an end of the body <b>304</b>. Accordingly, in case that the driving member <b>306</b> is combined with the imperfect cylindrical home <b>702</b>, the driving member <b>306</b> is not separated from the imperfect cylindrical home <b>702</b> by the fixing member <b>802</b> though the external force is generated. In other words, the fixing member <b>802</b> fixes the driving member <b>306</b>, and thus structure corresponding to the thread <b>810</b> is formed on an internal surface the fixing member <b>802</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">The fixing members <b>804</b> and <b>806</b> are combined with thread <b>812</b> formed on an outside surface of the power delivering member <b>302</b> so that the indicating member <b>312</b>, etc is not separated by the external force.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">As described above, the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b> of the present embodiment rotates the driving member <b>306</b>, thereby rotating the power delivering member <b>302</b>. In other words, unlike the inclination angle adjusting apparatus in related art which moves linearly in accordance with operation of the driving member, the power delivering member <b>302</b> rotates in accordance with operation of the driving member <b>306</b> in the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b> of the present invention. Here, the phase shifter operates in response to the rotation of the power delivering member <b>302</b> as mentioned above.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">Additionally, the inserting section <b>310</b> is formed on the outside surface of the driving member <b>306</b>, wherein the remote control unit is inserted into the inserting section <b>310</b>. Hence, the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b> of the present embodiment may combine the remote control unit with the driving member <b>306</b> without removal of certain members. Accordingly, the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b> of the present invention may combine (separate) more easily with (from) the remote control unit than the inclination angle adjusting apparatus in related art.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">In one example embodiment of the present invention, in case that the remote control unit is inserted into the inserting section <b>310</b> under the condition that the driving member <b>306</b> is fixed to the imperfect cylindrical home <b>702</b>, the driving member <b>306</b> may be automatically separated from the imperfect cylindrical home <b>702</b> and then be combined with the cylindrical home <b>700</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a perspective view illustrating internal structure of an inclination angle adjusting apparatus according to one example embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, at least one projecting member <b>308</b> is formed on the driving member <b>306</b> so that the user's hand does not slide. In addition, the projection member <b>800</b> for combining the driving member <b>306</b> with the power delivering member <b>302</b> is formed on an internal surface of the driving member <b>306</b>. Here, shape of the projection member <b>800</b> may be variously modified. It is desirable that the projection member <b>800</b> has polygon shape so as to more deliver the rotatory power generated by the driving member <b>306</b> to the power delivering member <b>302</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">At least one hook member <b>900</b> is formed on an end of the driving member <b>306</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>. The hook member <b>900</b> is combined with the cylindrical home <b>700</b> or the imperfect cylindrical home <b>702</b> of the body <b>304</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">In one example embodiment of the present invention, number of the imperfect cylindrical homes <b>702</b> is greater than that of the hook members <b>900</b>. For example, the imperfect cylindrical homes <b>702</b> has twice number than the hook members <b>900</b>. This is because the hook members <b>900</b> combine more rapidly and easily with the imperfect cylindrical homes <b>702</b> as the number of the imperfect cylindrical homes <b>702</b> is increased.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">In brief, the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b> of the present embodiment combines the driving member <b>306</b> with the power delivering member <b>302</b> using the projection member <b>800</b>, and fixes the driving member <b>306</b> to the body <b>304</b> using the hook member <b>900</b> and the homes <b>700</b> and <b>702</b>. As a result, the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b> may deliver more the rotatory power generated by the driving member <b>306</b> to the power delivering member <b>302</b>, and fix the driving member <b>306</b> to the body <b>304</b> through the above simple method. Accordingly, the user may control easily the inclination angle adjusting apparatus <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">Any reference in this specification to &#x201c;one embodiment,&#x201d; &#x201c;an embodiment,&#x201d; &#x201c;example embodiment,&#x201d; etc., means that a particular feature, structure, or characteristic described in connection with the embodiment is included in at least one embodiment of the invention. The appearances of such phrases in various places in the specification are not necessarily all referring to the same embodiment. Further, when a particular feature, structure, or characteristic is described in connection with any embodiment, it is submitted that it is within the purview of one skilled in the art to affect such feature, structure, or characteristic in connection with other ones of the embodiments. Although embodiments have been described with reference to a number of illustrative embodiments thereof, it should be understood that numerous other modifications and embodiments can be devised by those skilled in the art that will fall within the spirit and scope of the principles of this disclosure. More particularly, various variations and modifications are possible in the component parts and/or arrangements of the subject combination arrangement within the scope of the disclosure, the drawings and the appended claims. In addition to variations and modifications in the component parts and/or arrangements, alternative uses will also be apparent to those skilled in the art.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An inclination angle adjusting apparatus in an antenna having a phase shifter, the inclination angle adjusting apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a power delivering member connected to the phase shifter; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a driving member combined with the power delivering member, and configured to provide a power to the power delivering member; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a body configured to house the power delivering member,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the driving member is combined with the body, a first inserting section is formed on a part of outside surfaces of the driving member, a remote control unit is inserted into the first inserting section of the driving member and rotates the driving member, and the power delivering member rotates in response to the power provided from the driving member, at least one hook member is formed on an end of the driving member, and a cylindrical home and imperfect cylindrical homes are formed on an outside surface of the body, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the driving member is rotated on the body when the hook member is combined with the cylindrical home, and the driving member is fixed to the body when the hook member is combined with the imperfect cylindrical home.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The inclination angle adjusting apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a fixing member combined with an end of the body so that the hook member is not separated from the imperfect cylindrical home by an outside force when the hook member is combined with the imperfect cylindrical home.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The inclination angle adjusting apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the driving member has a projection member, and a second inserting section is formed on an end of the power delivering member, and wherein the projection member is inserted into the second inserting section when the driving member is combined with the power delivering member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The inclination angle adjusting apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first inserting section has polygon shape.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The inclination angle adjusting apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the hook member combined with the imperfect cylindrical home is automatically moved on the cylindrical home when the remote control unit is inserted into the first inserting section of the driving member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The inclination angle adjusting apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein at least one sliding protection projection member is formed on the outside surface of the driving member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The inclination angle adjusting apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a thread is formed on a part of an outside surface of the power delivering member, and an indicating member for indicating change degree of an inclination angle is disposed on the thread.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The inclination angle adjusting apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the rotatory power delivered from the driving member is provided to a phase shifter through the power delivering member, and the phase shifter adjusts an inclination angle of the antenna using the provided rotatory power.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The inclination angle adjusting member of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the driving member has cylindrical shape, and the projection member is projected from an internal surface of the driving member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The inclination angle adjusting apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the projection member has polygon shape, and the second inserting section has shape corresponding to the projection member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The inclination angle adjusting apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the phase shifter includes:
<claim-text>a gear worm combined with the power delivering member; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a gear wheel connected to the gear worm and configured to rotate in accordance with operation of the gear worm, and wherein the inclination angle of the antenna is adjusted in accordance with rotation of the gear wheel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
