<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625382-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625382</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13168699</doc-number>
<date>20110624</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>255</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>11</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>8</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36523006</main-classification>
<further-classification>365226</further-classification>
<further-classification>36523003</further-classification>
<further-classification>36523001</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Block-row decoders, memory block-row decoders, memories, methods for deselecting a decoder of a memory and methods of selecting a block of memory</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7023750</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Aakjer</name>
<date>20060400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7177201</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Takayanagi</name>
<date>20070200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7675317</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Perisetty</name>
<date>20100300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0159053</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yan et al.</name>
<date>20080700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36523006</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0080256</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lee et al.</name>
<date>20090300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36518511</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0273984</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Tanzawa</name>
<date>20091100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0090739</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Goda et al.</name>
<date>20110400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2012/0195142</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lee et al.</name>
<date>20120800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>365194</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>19</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36523006</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>365226</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36523003</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36523001</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120327735</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121227</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hendrickson</last-name>
<first-name>Nicholas</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ranch Cordova</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hendrickson</last-name>
<first-name>Nicholas</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ranch Cordova</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Dorsey &#x26; Whitney LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Micron Technology, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Boise</city>
<state>ID</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Le</last-name>
<first-name>Vu</first-name>
<department>2824</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Yang</last-name>
<first-name>Han</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Block-row decoders, memory block-row decoders, memories, methods for deselecting a decoder of a memory and methods of selecting a block of memory are disclosed. An example memory block-row decoder includes a plurality of block-row decoders, each of the block-row decoders having a decoder switch tree. Each block-row decoder is configured to bias a block select switch of the decoder switch tree with a first voltage while the block-row decoder is deselected and further configured to bias decoders switches of the decoder switch tree that are coupled to the block select switch with a second voltage while the block-row decoder is deselected, the second voltage less than the first voltage. An example method of deselecting a decoder of a memory includes providing decoder signals having different voltages to decoder switches from at least two different levels of a decoder switch tree while the decoder is deselected.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="215.82mm" wi="155.11mm" file="US08625382-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="212.43mm" wi="160.87mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625382-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="166.29mm" wi="170.10mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625382-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="234.27mm" wi="174.67mm" file="US08625382-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="143.51mm" wi="166.79mm" file="US08625382-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">Embodiments of the present invention relate generally to semiconductor memories, and more specifically in one or more of the illustrated embodiments, to biasing block-row decoders for deselected memory blocks of a memory.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Data in electronic circuits may be stored in memory, for example, semiconductor memory. Examples of semiconductor memory include volatile memory, which is limited to storing data while power is provided to the memory, and non-volatile memory, which can store data even when power is no longer provided to the memory. Non-volatile memories have become more popular as mobile and compact electronic devices, for example, mobile phones, digital cameras, portable computers, and other such devices, require storage of information even after the electronic device is switched off.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Memory typically includes an array of memory cells which are used to store data. The memory cells are arranged in the array in a manner which can be addressed using memory addresses. The memory addresses are provided to the memory and decoded by address decoders to select a memory location or locations corresponding to a memory address. In operating the address decoders, the memory locations corresponding to the memory address are selected while the remaining memory locations remain deselected in order to preserve the data stored by the deselected memory locations.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In decoding memory addresses, circuitry included in the address decoders are operated by biasing the various circuitry, for example, decoders switches, to different voltages. For example, voltages are provided to close decoder switches coupled to memory locations to be accessed while decoder switches coupled to deselected memory locations are biased to remain open. The voltages applied to the decoder circuitry over time may degrade their performance, and in extreme cases, cause the circuitry to fail such as due to voltage induced stresses. In these cases where the decoder circuitry fails, the memory may become non-functional.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Therefore, it is desirable to have alternative designs for decoder circuitry and alternative methods for operating decoder circuitry.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a simplified block drawing of a memory including a block-row decoder according to an embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a simplified block drawing of a memory block-row decoder including block-row decoders according to an embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic drawing of portions of a block-row decoder according to an embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic drawing of portions of a block-row decoder during operation according to an embodiment of the invention for a deselected block-row decoder.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Certain details are set forth below to provide a sufficient understanding of embodiments of the invention. However, it will be clear to one skilled in the art that embodiments of the invention may be practiced without these particular details. Moreover, the particular embodiments of the present invention described herein are provided by way of example and should not be used to limit the scope of the invention to these particular embodiments. In other instances, well-known circuits, control signals, timing protocols, and software operations have not been shown in detail in order to avoid unnecessarily obscuring the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a memory <b>100</b> including a block-row decoder according to an embodiment of the invention. The memory <b>100</b> includes an array <b>130</b> of memory cells which may be arranged in blocks of memory <b>120</b>(<b>0</b>)-<b>120</b>(S). Command signals, address signals and write data signals may be provided to the memory <b>100</b> as sets of sequential input/output (&#x201c;I/O&#x201d;) signals transmitted through an I/O bus <b>134</b>. Similarly, read data signals may be provided from the memory <b>100</b> through the I/O bus <b>134</b>. The I/O bus is connected to an I/O control unit <b>140</b> that routes the signals between the I/O bus <b>134</b> and an internal data bus <b>142</b>, an internal address bus <b>144</b>, and an internal command bus <b>146</b>. The memory <b>100</b> also includes a control logic unit <b>150</b> that receives a number of control signals either externally or through the command bus <b>146</b> to control the operation of the memory <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The address bus <b>144</b> provides block-row address signals to a memory block-row decoder <b>160</b> and column address signals to a column decoder <b>164</b>. The memory block-row decoder <b>160</b> and column decoder <b>164</b> may be used to select memory cells for memory operations. The memory block-row decoder <b>160</b> includes block-row decoders <b>135</b> according to embodiments of the invention. Each of the block-row decoders <b>135</b> is associated with a respective one of the blocks of memory <b>120</b> and is configured to decode memory addresses for selecting a row of memory cells on which memory operations are performed, for example, erase, program, and read operations. The column decoder <b>164</b> enables write data signals to be applied to columns of memory corresponding to the column address signals and allow read data signals to be coupled from columns corresponding to the column address signals.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In response to the memory commands decoded by the control logic unit <b>150</b>, the memory cells in the array <b>130</b> are erased, programmed, or read. After the block-row address signals have been provided on the address bus <b>144</b>, the I/O control unit <b>140</b> routes write data signals to a cache register <b>170</b>. The write data signals are stored in the cache register <b>170</b> in successive sets each having a size corresponding to the width of the I/O bus <b>134</b>. The cache register <b>170</b> sequentially stores the sets of write data signals for an entire page (e.g. a row or part of a row of memory cells) of memory cells in the array <b>130</b>. All of the stored write data signals are then used to program a of memory cells in the array <b>130</b> selected, at least in part, by the block-row address coupled through the address bus <b>144</b>. In a similar manner, during a read operation, data signals from a row or block of memory cells selected, at least in part, by the block-row address provided on the address bus <b>144</b> are stored in a data register <b>180</b>. Sets of data signals corresponding in size to the width of the I/O bus <b>134</b> are then sequentially transferred through the I/O control unit <b>140</b> from the data register <b>180</b> to the I/O bus <b>134</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates a portion of a memory block row-decoder <b>200</b> according to an embodiment of the invention. The portion of the memory block-row decoder <b>200</b> may be included in the memory block-row decoder <b>160</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. Memory block select logic <b>210</b> included in the memory block-row decoder <b>200</b> is configured to receive block and row addresses BLKROW and select a block-row decoder <b>220</b>(<b>0</b>)-<b>220</b>(N) based on the BLKROW addresses. The block select logic <b>210</b> provides an active block selection signal BLKSEL to select a block-row decoder <b>220</b> and provides inactive BLKSEL signals to maintain deselection of the other block-row decoders <b>220</b>. The block-row decoders <b>220</b> are coupled to respective blocks of memory, for example, to memory cells of a respective block of memory through word lines WLs. The block-row decoders <b>220</b> are configured to provide signals to a respective block of memory to perform a requested memory operation for the memory corresponding to row memory addresses ROWADD when selected. In operation, the block select logic <b>210</b> decodes the BLKROW addresses to provide an active BLKSEL signal to select a memory block-row decoder <b>220</b> for a memory operation, for example, read, program, or erase operations. Other memory block-row decoders <b>220</b> remain deselected by an inactive BLKSEL signal provided by the block select logic <b>210</b>. As will be described in more detail below, the deselected memory block-row decoders <b>220</b> are biased to prevent inadvertent memory access to the respective blocks of memory to which they are coupled.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a portion of a block-row decoder <b>300</b> according to an embodiment of the invention. The portions of the block-row decoder <b>300</b> may be included in the block-row decoders <b>220</b> of the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The block-row decoder <b>300</b> includes a first decoder switch <b>310</b> and further includes a voltage translator <b>306</b> configured to receive the BLKSEL signal and provide a first decoder select signal <b>1</b>DSEL signal to the first decoder switch <b>310</b>. As previously described, the BLKSEL signal may be provided by block select logic (e.g., block select logic <b>210</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). The voltage translator <b>306</b> is configured to provide a <b>1</b>DSEL signal having a voltage of VMAX responsive to an inactive BLKSEL signal. The first decoder switch <b>310</b> is configured to selectively provide a voltage provided to its input based on the <b>1</b>DSEL signal. The first decoder switch <b>310</b> may represent a block select switch which when closed (i.e., conductive) provides the voltage at its input to the rest of a tree of decoder switches of the block-row decoder. When the first decoder switch <b>310</b> is open (i.e., non-conductive) the rest of the tree of decoder switches is decoupled from receiving the input voltage. An active <b>1</b>DSEL signal closes the first decoder switch <b>310</b> while an inactive <b>1</b>DSEL signal opens the first decoder switch <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The first decoder switch <b>310</b> is coupled to second decoder switches <b>320</b>, which are in turn coupled to a respective group of third decoder switches <b>330</b>. The third decoder switches <b>330</b> may be included in word line drivers <b>340</b>. The first, second, and third decoder switches may be p-channel field-effect transistors (pFETs) as illustrated for the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. Other circuits known to those ordinarily skilled in the art may be used for the first, second, and third decoders switches <b>310</b>, <b>320</b>, <b>330</b> as well. The word line drivers <b>340</b> are configured to drive respective word lines WLs to which they are coupled. As illustrated by <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the second and third decoder switches <b>220</b> and <b>230</b> fanout from the first decoder switch <b>210</b> to provide a tree of decoder switches. The embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is illustrated as having an example fanout configuration, however, other fanout configurations may be used as well without departing from the scope of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Row decode logic <b>350</b> is configured to provide word line driver select signals WLDSEL to a respective group of word line drivers <b>340</b>, and is further configured to provide second decoder switch select signals <b>2</b>DSEL to respective second decoder switches <b>220</b>. The WLDSEL and <b>2</b>DSEL signals may be used to select WLs for memory operations based at least in part on ROWADD addresses provided to the row decode logic <b>350</b>. For example, in a selected block-row decoder, the first, second and third decoder switches <b>310</b>, <b>320</b>, and <b>330</b> may be closed to couple a WL to the voltage provided to an input of the first decoder switch <b>310</b> (e.g., VMAX) to drive the WL. WLs not selected remain coupled to a reference voltage through respective word line drivers <b>340</b> as controlled by respective WLDSEL signals. In the event the block-row decoder <b>300</b> is deselected, the first, second, and third decoder switches <b>310</b>, <b>320</b>, <b>330</b> are controlled by the <b>1</b>DSEL, <b>2</b>DSEL and WLDSEL signals to remain open to prevent the voltage provided to the input of the first decoder switch <b>310</b> from being provided to the decoder switches.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The block-row decoder <b>300</b> further includes a voltage multiplexer <b>360</b> configured to provide one of a plurality of voltages as a select voltage VSEL to row decode logic <b>350</b>. Which one of the plurality of voltages is based at least in part on a state of the BLKSEL signal. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> voltages VSAFE and VMAX may be provided as the VSEL voltage. The VSAFE voltage is less than the VMAX voltage. For example, in some embodiments the VSAFE voltage may be approximately 1-2 volts less than the VMAX voltage. In some embodiments, the VSAFE voltage may be even less than this range.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Operation of the block-row decoder <b>300</b> for a deselected condition will be described, that is, operation responsive to an inactive BLKSEL signal. The voltage translator <b>306</b> provides a <b>1</b>DSEL signal having a voltage of VMAX to control the first decoder switch <b>310</b> to be open (e.g., non-conductive) responsive to the inactive BLKSEL signal. As a result, the second decoder switches <b>320</b> remain decoupled from the voltage provided to the input of the first decoder switch <b>310</b>. Additionally, the voltage multiplexer <b>360</b> is controlled by the inactive BLKSEL signal to provide a VSEL voltage to the row decode logic <b>350</b> having the VSAFE voltage. As a result, the row decode logic <b>360</b> provides <b>2</b>DSEL signals having a voltage of VSAFE to control the second decoder switches <b>320</b> to remain open (i.e., non-conductive). The row decode logic <b>360</b> further provides WLDSEL signals having the VSAFE voltage to control the word line drivers <b>340</b> to couple the respective WLs to the reference voltage. Coupling the WLs to the reference voltage causes the WLs to remain deselected.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">By providing the second decoder switches <b>320</b> and the word line drivers <b>340</b> the <b>2</b>DSEL and WLDSEL having the VSAFE voltage, the second decoder switches <b>320</b> and the third decoder switches <b>330</b> of the word line drivers <b>340</b> are not subjected to the higher voltage of VMAX while the block-row decoder is in a deselected state. As a result, voltage induced stress on the second and third decoder switches may be reduced in comparison to providing <b>2</b>DSEL and WLDSEL signals having a higher voltage of VMAX. Reducing the stress on the second and third decoder switches <b>320</b>, <b>330</b> for the deselected blocks of memory may improve failure rate, for example, for those memory failures related to transistor breakdown which may be promoted by voltage induced stress.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates in simplified form portions of the block-row decoder <b>300</b> during operation for a deselected block of memory. An example decoder switch fanout of decoder switches <b>310</b>, <b>320</b>, and <b>330</b> is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> by the designation of &#x201c;x1&#x201d; for the first decoder switch <b>310</b>, &#x201c;x8&#x201d; for the second decoder switch <b>320</b>, and &#x201c;x256&#x201d; for the third decoder switch <b>330</b>. That is, in the example fanout of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, each block-row decoder includes one first decoder switch <b>310</b>, which is coupled to eight second decoder switches <b>320</b>, and each of the second decoder switches is coupled to 256 third decoder switches <b>330</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">As illustrated in the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a voltage of VMAX is provided to the first decoder switch <b>310</b>, and while the block-row decoder <b>300</b> is deselected a <b>1</b>DSEL signal having a voltage of VMAX is provided to control the decoder switch <b>310</b> to remain open and thereby cut-off the VMAX voltage from being provided to inputs of any of the second decoder switches <b>320</b>. Additionally, while the block-row decoder <b>300</b> is deselected the voltage multiplexer <b>360</b> is controlled to provide a VSEL voltage to the row decode logic <b>350</b> having the VSAFE voltage. As previously discussed, the VSAFE voltage is a voltage less than the VMAX voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The VSEL (i.e., VSAFE) voltage is provided to voltage translators <b>380</b>. The voltage translators <b>380</b> may be included in the row decode logic <b>350</b>. The voltage translators <b>380</b> provide <b>2</b>DSEL and WDSEL signals having the VSAFE voltage responsive to decode signals <b>2</b>DDEC and WDDEC provided by row decoder <b>370</b>, which may also be induced in the row decode logic <b>350</b>. The <b>2</b>DDEC and WDDEC signals have voltage levels that are relatively low in comparison to the VMAX and VSAFE voltages. The relatively low voltage decode signals are translated into the higher VSAFE voltage <b>2</b>DSEL and WDSEL signals through the voltage translators <b>380</b>. The <b>2</b>DSEL and WDSEL signals control the respective decoder switches to remain open (i.e., non-conductive) to thereby cut-off the VMAX voltage from being provided through the second and third decoder switches <b>320</b>, <b>330</b> to the WLs.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In the previous example a voltage of VSAFE was provided to the second decoder switches <b>320</b> and to the third decoder switches <b>330</b> while the block-row decoder <b>300</b> is deselected. In some embodiments, the voltage provided to the second and third decoder switches <b>320</b>, <b>330</b> are different. For example, a voltage of VSAFE may be provided to only the second decoder switches <b>320</b> or to only the third decoder switches <b>330</b>. In the latter example, the <b>2</b>DSEL signals provided to the second decoder switches <b>320</b> may have the VMAX voltage and the WDSEL signals provided to the third decoder switches <b>330</b> may have the VSAFE voltage. In some embodiments, the different voltages that are applied to the second and third decoder switches <b>320</b>, <b>330</b> while the block-row decoder <b>300</b> is deselected are both lower than the VMAX voltage. For example, the <b>2</b>DSEL signals provided to the second decoder switches <b>320</b> may have a VSAFE voltage and the WDSEL signals provided to the third decoder switches <b>330</b> may have a different voltage. The different voltage provided to the third decoder switches <b>330</b> may be less than both the VMAX and VSAFE voltages.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">As illustrated in the previous example, embodiments of the invention include applying decoder switch select signals (e.g., <b>2</b>DSEL and WDSEL) while the block-row decoder is deselected that have voltages which are less than the voltage of the decoder switch select signal (e.g., <b>1</b>DSEL) that controls whether a voltage provided to the block-row decoder is also provided to switches further down in the decoder switch tree, such as the second and third decoder switches <b>320</b>, <b>330</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">From the foregoing it will be appreciated that, although specific embodiments of the invention have been described herein for purposes of illustration, various modifications may be made without deviating from the spirit and scope of the invention. Accordingly, the invention is not limited except as by the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A block-row decoder, comprising:
<claim-text>a first decoder switch configured to receive a first decoder switch signal having a first voltage responsive to the block-row decoder being deselected to control the first decoder switch to be open;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of second decoder switches coupled to the first decoder switch, the second decoder switches configured to be open and closed responsive to second decoder switch signals; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>row decode logic coupled to the second decoder switches and configured to decode memory addresses and provide the second decoder switch signals to the plurality of second decoder switches, the row decode logic further configured to provide the second decoder switch signals having a second voltage responsive to the block-row decoder being deselected, the second voltage less than the first voltage.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The block-row decoder of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of third decoders switches coupled to one of the second decoder switches, the third decoders switches configured to be opened and closed responsive to third decoder switch signals, the row decode logic coupled to the third decoder switches and configured to decode memory addresses and provide the third decoder switch signals to the plurality of third decoder switches, the row decode logic further configured to provide the third decoder switch signals having a third voltage responsive to the block-row decoder being deselected, the third voltage less than the first voltage.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The block-row decoder of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> wherein the second and third voltages are substantially equal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The block-row decoder of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the row decode logic comprises:
<claim-text>a voltage translator configured to provide the second decoder switch signal having the second voltage responsive to a decode signal, the decode signal having a logic level based at least in part on a received memory addresses.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The block-row decoder of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref> wherein the decode signal has a voltage less than the second voltage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The block-row decoder of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a voltage multiplexer configured to receive the first and second voltage and further configured to selectively provide the first and second voltage to the row decode logic responsive to a block selection signal, the block selection signal indicative of the block-row decoder being deselected or selected.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The block-row decoder of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the first decoder switch is configured to receive an input voltage substantially equal to the first voltage while the block-row decoder is deselected.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A memory block-row decoder, comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of block-row decoders, each of the block-row decoders having a decoder switch tree and each block-row decoder configured to bias a block select switch of the decoder switch tree with a first voltage while the block-row decoder is deselected and further configured to bias decoders switches of the decoder switch tree that are coupled to the block select switch with a second voltage while the block-row decoder is deselected, wherein the second voltage less than the first voltage and the second voltage is within a range of 1 to 2 volts less than the first voltage.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The memory block-row decoder of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> wherein each of the decoder switches of the decoder switch tree comprise pFETs.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The memory block-row decoder of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> wherein the block select switch of each of the block-row decoders comprises a pFET.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The memory block-row decoder of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> wherein each of the block-row decoders further include a plurality of word line drivers coupled to the decoder switches.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The memory block-row decoder of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> wherein a word line driver comprises a pFET coupled to a respective decoder switch and an nFET coupled to the pFET, the pFET and nFET of the word line driver coupled to be provided the second voltage while the block-row decoder is deselected.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A memory, comprising:
<claim-text>an array of memory arranged in blocks of memory; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a memory block-row decoder coupled to the blocks of memory, the memory block-row decoder comprising:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of block-row decoders, each block-row decoder coupled to word lines of a respective one of the blocks of memory, each block-row decoder having a decoder switch tree and configured to bias a block select switch of the decoder switch tree with a first voltage while the block-row decoder is deselected and further configured to bias decoders switches of the decoder switch tree that are coupled to the block select switch with a second voltage while the block-row decoder is deselected, wherein the second voltage less than the first voltage and the second voltage is within a range of 1 to 2 volts less than the first voltage.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A method of deselecting a decoder of a memory, the method comprising:
<claim-text>providing a first voltage while the decoder is deselected to a first decoder switch, the first decoder switch configured to be a first level of a decoder switch tree and further configured to provide an input voltage to all other levels of the decoder switch tree;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a second voltage while the decoder is deselected to a plurality of second decoder switches coupled to the first decoder switch, the second decoder switches configured to be a second level of the decoder switch tree, the second voltage less than the first voltage; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a third voltage while the decoder is deselected to a plurality third decoder switches coupled to one of the second decoder switches, the third decoder switches configured to be a third level of the decoder switch tree and each of the third decoder switches coupled to a respective word line.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref> wherein the third voltage is substantially equal to the second voltage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, further comprising providing the third voltage while the decoder is deselected to a plurality of transistors coupled to a reference voltage, each of the plurality of transistors coupled to a respective word line.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. A method of selecting a block of memory from a plurality of blocks of memory, the method comprising:
<claim-text>providing a first voltage to the plurality of block-row decoders, each block-row decoder coupled to a respective one of the plurality of blocks of memory;</claim-text>
<claim-text>controlling a block select switch of a block-row decoder coupled to a selected one of the plurality of blocks of memory to be conductive;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing the first voltage to block select switches of the block-row decoders coupled to deselected ones of the plurality of blocks of memory to control the block select switches to be non-conductive; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a second voltage to decoder switches of the block-row decoders coupled to the deselected ones of the plurality of blocks of memory including translating a third voltage to the second voltage responsive to an inactive decode signal, the decoder switches coupled to the block select switch of a respective block-row decoder, wherein the second voltage is less than the first voltage and the third voltage less than the second voltage.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref> wherein the second voltage is substantially in a range of 1 to 2 volts less than the first voltage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, further comprising driving word lines of the selected block of memory with the first voltage. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
