<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624161-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624161</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12640449</doc-number>
<date>20091217</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>559</us-term-extension>
<disclaimer>
<text>This patent is subject to a terminal disclaimer.</text>
</disclaimer>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>23</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>9</main-group>
<subgroup>10</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>21913021</main-classification>
<further-classification>21913033</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e55">Welding process employing variable minimum current</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5149940</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Davis et al.</name>
<date>19920900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>21913021</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5866873</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Wang et al.</name>
<date>19990200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>21913051</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6015964</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Baker</name>
<date>20000100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>21913033</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6023046</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Holverson et al.</name>
<date>20000200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6617549</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Ihde</name>
<date>20030900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0078812</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Peters et al.</name>
<date>20080400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0126976</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kawamoto et al.</name>
<date>20100500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1992440</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20081100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>2008036433</doc-number>
<kind>A2</kind>
<date>20080300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00010">
<othercit>PCT/US10/22336 Search Report and Written Opinion Jul. 12, 2010.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>18</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>21913021</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>21913033</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>61157007</doc-number>
<date>20090303</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20100224607</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20100909</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hutchison</last-name>
<first-name>Richard Martin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Iola</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Uecker</last-name>
<first-name>James Lee</first-name>
<address>
<city>Appleton</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hutchison</last-name>
<first-name>Richard Martin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Iola</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Uecker</last-name>
<first-name>James Lee</first-name>
<address>
<city>Appleton</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Fletcher Yoder P.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Illinois Tool Works Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Glenview</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Hoang</last-name>
<first-name>Huan</first-name>
<department>2827</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A constant voltage (CV) welding process power supply including a controller that implements a variable minimum current is provided. The controller is configured to periodically compute a running current value during a welding operation. The controller is also configured to periodically compute a minimum current value based on a difference between the running current value and a preset offset value, wherein the preset offset value remains constant throughout the welding operation.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="85.77mm" wi="175.60mm" file="US08624161-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="171.37mm" wi="172.13mm" file="US08624161-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="104.31mm" wi="174.84mm" file="US08624161-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="224.71mm" wi="180.26mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624161-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="242.82mm" wi="176.95mm" file="US08624161-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="228.01mm" wi="185.50mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624161-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="229.28mm" wi="154.18mm" file="US08624161-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a Non-Provisional patent application of U.S. Provisional Patent Application No. 61/157,007, entitled &#x201c;Method and Apparatus for MIG Welding&#x201d;, filed Mar. 3, 2009, which is herein incorporated by reference.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The invention relates generally to welding power supplies, and, more particularly, to constant voltage welding process power supplies.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Welding is a process that has become increasingly ubiquitous in various industries and applications. While such processes may be automated in certain contexts, a large number of applications continue to exist for manual welding operations, which often rely on the use of control loops to regulate the welding process. For instance, many constant voltage (CV) welding processes rely on standard CV control loops to regulate processes that use self shielded flux cored wires. A typical CV controller modifies the current output of the power supply to generate a relatively constant voltage output. Accordingly, in high voltage instances (e.g., high voltage when coming out of a short circuit), traditional CV controllers ramp down the current to accommodate the high voltage. However, in high voltage instances, such controllers may decrease the current to current levels that disadvantageously have the effect of extinguishing the welding arc. Accordingly, there exists a need for improved CV control loops that maintain a constant voltage level without extinguishing the welding arc.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In one exemplary embodiment, a constant voltage (CV) welding process power supply includes a controller. The controller is configured to compute a varying minimum current level during a welding process, decrease a welding current based upon a computed voltage error, and generate a current command signal to minimize the computed voltage error. The controller is further configured to compare the current command signal to the computed varying minimum current level and apply either the current command signal or the computed varying minimum current level for control of welding output based upon the comparison.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In a second embodiment, a CV welding process power supply includes a current sensor configured to sense current of welding power supplied by the power supply to a welding process and a voltage sensor configured to sense voltage of the welding power. The power supply also includes a control circuit that receives signals indicative of the sensed current and voltage, and is configured to periodically compute a voltage error and a current command signal based on the voltage error, and if the current command signal is not less than a periodically computed minimum current level, then apply a current level indicated by the current command signal for control of welding output, and if the current command signal is less than the periodically computed minimum current level, then apply the periodically computed minimum current level for control of welding output.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In a third embodiment, a CV welding process power supply includes a controller configured to periodically compute a running current value during a welding process. The controller is also configured to periodically compute a minimum current value based on the running current value and an offset value.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">These and other features, aspects, and advantages of the present invention will become better understood when the following detailed description is read with reference to the accompanying drawings in which like characters represent like parts throughout the drawings, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of an exemplary welding power supply including a controller in accordance with aspects of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram illustrating exemplary circuitry associated with the power supply of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in accordance with aspects of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram of exemplary current and voltage waveforms over time, illustrating an embodiment of a method that may be employed by a controller to clear a short circuit in the welding power;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is an exemplary short circuit clearing flow chart including steps that a controller may implement to clear a short circuit in the welding power in accordance with aspects of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a diagram of exemplary current and voltage waveforms over time, illustrating an embodiment of a method that may be employed by a controller to regulate the minimum allowable current value; and</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flow chart including steps that a controller may implement to set a minimum current value in accordance with embodiments of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">As described in detail below, various embodiments of a constant voltage (CV) welding process power supply configured to detect and clear short circuit events are provided. The CV welding power supply is capable of automatically adjusting the CV current waveform in sub-millisecond time frames based on received feedback, efficiently detecting short circuit events, responding to short circuit events in a stepped manner, and adjusting the weld voltage setpoint. The CV power supply is also capable of responding to a detected short circuit event by increasing the welding current based upon a periodically computed voltage error and a gain. The power supply may be further configured to increase the welding current based upon increasingly more aggressive gains if the short circuit event does not clear. Additionally, the power supply may allow a predetermined time delay to elapse during which voltage feedback is ignored. The foregoing features may have the effect of avoiding excessive splatter levels, preventing arc outages and wire stubbing, and improving the ability of the system to respond to short circuit events, among other benefits.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Turning now to the drawings, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of an exemplary welding system <b>10</b>, which functions to power, control and provide consumables to a welding operation and auxiliary equipment. The welding system <b>10</b> includes a power supply <b>12</b> and a wire feeder <b>13</b> based in a cabinet or enclosure <b>14</b>. In some embodiments, the welding system may be configured to permit the power supply to be moved from place to place relatively easily, or may be designed as a generally stationary system. Moreover, the system may be designed for field operation, in which case it may include an engine and generator within the enclosure <b>14</b> that provide the necessary power, conditioned appropriately for the given welding operation. In some embodiments, the power supply unit <b>12</b> may be communicatively coupled to additional system components, such as a wall power outlet, a battery, engine-driven power sources, and so forth.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The power supply <b>12</b> includes a control panel <b>16</b>, through which a user may control the supply of materials, such as power, gas flow, and so forth, to a welding operation, via dials <b>18</b>, switches <b>20</b>, and so forth. As the user adjusts welding parameters via the control panel <b>16</b>, signals are generated and received by a controller within the welding power supply <b>12</b>. The power supply <b>12</b> controller implements the desired welding operation in accordance with its inputs. For instance, in one embodiment, the controller may implement a constant voltage regime and a wire feed suitable for use with a MIG welding operation.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">An electrode assembly <b>22</b> extends from the power supply <b>12</b> to the location of the weld. A first cable <b>24</b> and a welding electrode <b>26</b> couple to the power supply unit <b>12</b> as components of the electrode assembly <b>22</b>. The electrode <b>26</b> may be any electrode suitable for a variety of welding processes. For instance, the electrode <b>26</b> may be a torch suitable for metal inert gas (MIG) operations, a stinger suitable for stick welding operations, and so forth. A work assembly <b>28</b> extending from the power supply <b>12</b> to the weld includes a second cable <b>30</b> terminating in a work lead clamp <b>32</b>. During operation, the work lead clamp <b>32</b> typically connects to a workpiece <b>34</b> to close the circuit between the electrode <b>26</b>, the workpiece <b>34</b>, and the power supply <b>12</b>, thus ensuring proper current flow. That is, as the welding operator contacts or closely approaches the tip of the electrode <b>26</b> to the workpiece <b>34</b>, an electrical circuit is completed through the cables <b>24</b> and <b>30</b>, the electrode <b>26</b>, the workpiece <b>34</b>, and the clamp <b>32</b> to generate an arc between the electrode tip and the workpiece <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram illustrating circuitry associated with the power supply of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The power supply includes power supply circuitry <b>36</b>, control circuitry <b>38</b>, an operator interface <b>40</b>, a short circuit detection circuit <b>42</b>, and interface circuitry <b>44</b>. A voltage sensor <b>46</b> and a current sensor <b>48</b> are coupled to the power supply cable <b>24</b> that extends to the weld location. The voltage sensor <b>46</b> is coupled to the power output via cables <b>24</b> and <b>30</b> and is configured to sense the voltage level of the welding power. Likewise, the current sensor <b>48</b> also interfaces with cable <b>24</b> to sense the current level of the welding power. The voltage sensor <b>46</b> and the current sensor <b>48</b> are communicatively coupled to the short circuit detection circuit <b>42</b> via the interface circuit <b>44</b>. The interface circuit <b>44</b> is coupled to the short circuit detection circuit <b>42</b> and the control circuitry <b>38</b>. The control circuitry <b>38</b>, the short circuit detection circuit <b>42</b>, and the interface circuitry <b>44</b> are components of the system controller <b>49</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">During operation, the power supply circuitry <b>36</b> conditions incoming primary power to generate a power output suitable for the welding operation. The voltage sensor <b>46</b> and the current sensor <b>48</b> detect the voltage and current levels, respectively, of the power output. The sensors <b>46</b> and <b>48</b> communicate the sensed information to the short circuit detection circuit <b>42</b> via the interface circuitry <b>44</b>. The interface circuitry <b>44</b> receives and processes the sensed data and transmits such information to the short circuit detection circuit <b>42</b>. The short circuit detection circuit <b>42</b> is configured to detect a short circuit in the welding power. For example, in one embodiment, the short circuit detection circuit <b>42</b> may detect a short circuit by comparing the voltage feedback to a preset voltage level. If the voltage feedback drops below the preset level, the detection circuitry <b>42</b> may determine that a short circuit in the welding power has occurred. That is, the short circuit detection circuit <b>42</b> is communicatively coupled to the voltage sensor <b>46</b> and is configured to receive and process voltage feedback to determine a short circuit in the welding power. Other techniques could be used to detect short circuits as well, such as by reference to current, power, or resistance, or by detecting rates of change of voltage, current, power, or current with respect to voltage and vice versa.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The control circuitry <b>38</b> is configured to receive a signal from the detection circuitry <b>42</b> indicating a short circuit and output a control signal based on this input. For example, the control circuit <b>38</b> may be configured to direct the power supply circuitry <b>36</b> to increase the current of the welding power in two or more progressively aggressive short circuit clearing stages. That is, based on a voltage error (e.g., a difference between a detected voltage and a preset voltage) and a gain, the control circuit <b>38</b> may direct an increase in the current of the welding power to attempt to clear the short circuit. If the short does not clear after a first clearing stage, the control circuit <b>38</b> may again direct an increase in the current of the welding power in one or more additional progressively aggressive short circuit clearing stages. Such functionalities of the control circuit <b>38</b> are described in more detail below with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The control circuitry <b>38</b> may also be configured to receive and process signals from the operator interface <b>40</b>. For instance, the operator interface may receive inputs from the user regarding desired weld operating parameters (e.g., desired current level or welding process). The control circuitry <b>38</b> is configured to process such inputs concurrently with the inputs received from the detection circuitry <b>42</b> and the interface circuitry <b>44</b>. That is, the control circuitry <b>38</b> may receive feedback regarding the voltage and current levels of the power output from the interface circuitry <b>44</b>. To this end, the control circuitry <b>38</b> functions as an intermediate between various input and feedback sources (e.g., sensors and manual input) and the power supply circuitry <b>36</b>. The control circuitry <b>38</b> then continuously outputs one or more control signals to the power supply circuitry <b>36</b>, thus guiding the proper operation of the welding process.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram of exemplary current and voltage waveforms over time, illustrating a method that may be employed by the control circuitry of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> to clear a short circuit in the welding power during a welding operation. The diagram includes a current waveform <b>50</b> and a voltage waveform <b>52</b>. The current waveform <b>50</b> is a plot of current versus time. The current waveform <b>50</b> includes a minimum current level <b>54</b>, which represents the minimum amount of current that the CV portion of the control system can regulate. This minimum current level <b>54</b> is constantly being adjusted during the weld and is derived from the average current that is being run as described in more detail below. The current waveform <b>50</b> also includes a first current level <b>56</b> and a second current level <b>58</b> that represent the maximum current available at the first setting and the second setting, respectively. A maximum current level <b>60</b> represents the maximum current available from the power source. The voltage waveform <b>52</b> is a plot of voltage versus time. The voltage waveform <b>52</b> includes a short circuit voltage level <b>62</b> and a clear voltage level <b>64</b>. The initiation of a short circuit in the welding power occurs when the voltage drops below the short circuit voltage level <b>62</b>. The clearing of a short circuit occurs when the voltage exceeds the clear voltage level <b>64</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In the illustrated <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a welding operation begins at a first time <b>66</b>. A welding voltage <b>68</b> and a welding current <b>70</b> are established during the welding process. During operation, at point <b>72</b> on the voltage waveform <b>52</b>, the welding voltage begins to drop off from the welding voltage level <b>68</b>. At a second time <b>74</b>, the voltage level crosses the short circuit voltage level <b>62</b>, and, thus, a short circuit event occurs at point <b>76</b>. A time period <b>78</b> labeled T<sub>wet </sub>then elapses from time <b>74</b> to a time <b>80</b>. During time period <b>78</b>, the controller maintains the welding current at the welding level as in the portion of the waveform <b>50</b> indicated by arrow <b>82</b> to allow the short circuit event time to naturally clear. That is, since many short circuit events, such as those associated with self shielded electrode wires, naturally clear in a short period of time, the controller initially remains inactive for the duration of time period <b>78</b>. Curve <b>84</b> represents the voltage waveform path that may occur if the short circuit event clears during time period <b>78</b>. If curve <b>84</b> is followed, the voltage level exceeds the voltage clear level <b>64</b>, and the controller reverts to a normal operating mode; the short circuit event is over.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">If the short circuit does not naturally clear during time period <b>78</b>, at time point <b>80</b>, the controller increases the welding current (curve <b>86</b>) based on a periodically computed voltage error and a first gain in an attempt to clear the short circuit. That is, based on the first gain and the difference between the actual voltage level at point <b>88</b> and the preset voltage level <b>64</b>, the controller determines an appropriate increase in welding current. After initiating the increase in voltage at time point <b>80</b>, the controller operates without regard to voltage feedback during a delay time period <b>90</b> from time point <b>80</b> to a time point <b>92</b>. The foregoing feature may be advantageous because the change in current with respect to time during time period <b>90</b> induces a voltage across the output of the power source that is proportional to the magnitude of the inductance of the work and electrode assemblies. This induced voltage may create a transient voltage spike above the clear voltage level <b>64</b>, thereby rendering voltage feedback during the delay time period <b>90</b> unreliable as an indicator of a short circuit clearing. Accordingly, the controller operates without regard for voltage feedback during time period <b>90</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">At time point <b>92</b>, the controller begins to monitor voltage feedback as the current is further increased (curve <b>94</b>). During a first time period <b>96</b> from time point <b>92</b> to time point <b>98</b>, the voltage level may exceed the voltage clear level <b>64</b>, thus clearing the short circuit event. If such a clearing occurs, the voltage waveform <b>52</b> follows curve <b>100</b>, and the controller reverts to a normal operating mode. If the time period <b>96</b> elapses and the voltage feedback remains below the clear voltage level <b>64</b>, at time point <b>98</b>, the controller initiates a second increase in welding current based upon the periodically computed voltage error and a second gain higher than the first gain (curve <b>102</b>). That is, at time point <b>98</b>, the controller initiates a second short circuit clearing stage that is more aggressive than the first clearing stage. A second delay period <b>104</b> elapses from time point <b>98</b> to time point <b>106</b>, during which the controller again operates without regard to voltage feedback. That is, although curve <b>108</b> exceeds the clear voltage threshold <b>64</b>, the controller does not impede the current increase. After time point <b>106</b>, the controller again monitors voltage feedback during a second time period <b>110</b> that lasts until time point <b>112</b>. During the second period <b>110</b>, the voltage may exceed the clear voltage level <b>64</b>, as indicated by curve <b>114</b>. If the waveform follows curve <b>114</b>, the short circuit event is cleared, and the controller returns to normal operation. In the illustrated voltage and current waveforms <b>50</b> and <b>52</b>, two periods <b>96</b> and <b>110</b> are shown. However, in alternate embodiments, more than two progressively aggressive periods may be initiated by the controller to clear the short circuit event.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In the illustrated embodiment, after the welding current is increased based on the second gain, at time point <b>112</b>, the controller increases the welding current to the maximum current level <b>60</b> to attempt to clear the short circuit (curve <b>116</b>). A third delay period <b>118</b> elapses from time point <b>112</b> to time point <b>120</b>, during which the controller operates with a disregard for voltage feedback. Again, when curve <b>122</b> exceeds the clear voltage level <b>64</b>, this is ignored by the controller until time point <b>120</b>. At time point <b>120</b>, the controller receives voltage feedback indicating that the voltage level has exceeded the clear threshold <b>64</b> at point <b>124</b>. The controller then decreases the welding current, as indicated by curve <b>126</b>. At time point <b>128</b>, the controller returns to a normal CV control loop, and the current level stabilizes (curve <b>130</b>), the voltage level stabilizes (curve <b>132</b>), and normal welding operation resumes. That is, the short circuit event has been cleared, so the controller returns to normal operation.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a short circuit clearing flow chart <b>134</b> including steps that the controller may implement to clear a short circuit in the welding power. First, the controller detects a short circuit event (block <b>136</b>). For example, the controller may receive feedback from a voltage sensor indicating that the sensed voltage has dropped below a voltage threshold. Next, the controller allows a preset delay time to elapse, during which the short circuit may naturally clear (block <b>138</b>). The controller then checks to see if the short circuit event has cleared (block <b>140</b>). If the short circuit has cleared, the controller directs the power supply circuitry to return the voltage and current levels to normal welding levels (block <b>142</b>). If the short circuit has not cleared, the controller increases the current based on the first gain and the voltage error (block <b>144</b>) and allows a delay time to elapse (block <b>146</b>). That is, the controller operates without regard to voltage feedback during the delay time. Such an action is necessary since the current increase may lead to a temporarily elevated induced voltage, which is not indicative of a short circuit clearing.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">After the delay time, the controller again checks if the short circuit event has cleared (block <b>140</b>), and if the short circuit has cleared, the controller regulates the return of the voltage and current to welding levels (block <b>142</b>). If the short circuit event has not cleared, the controller increases the current based on the second gain, which is higher than the first gain, and the computed voltage error (block <b>148</b>). The controller again allows a delay time to elapse (block <b>150</b>) during which the controller operates without regard for the voltage feedback. The controller again checks if the short circuit event has cleared (block <b>140</b>), and if the short circuit has cleared, the controller regulates the return of the voltage and current to welding levels (block <b>142</b>). The controller may repeat such current increases, time delays, and clearing check steps any number of times as suitable for the given welding operation.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Once the controller has exhausted a series of progressively aggressive current increases in an attempt to clear the short circuit, the current is increased to the maximum current the power supply is capable of realizing (block <b>152</b>). After such an increase and a preset delay time, the controller again checks if the short circuit has cleared (<b>140</b>) and returns the current and voltage to welding levels if the short circuit event has cleared. If the short circuit event still has not cleared, the controller maintains the current at the maximum until clearing (block <b>154</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">It should be noted that the particular algorithm noted above, in which the progressively increasing current for short clearing is based upon voltage errors (i.e., comparison) and gains may be supplemented or complemented in various ways. For example, although a simple error-proportional control may be implemented, more complex current control schemes may be envisioned that may take into account rates of change of voltage, change in error, and so forth. Moreover, the gains may be fixed or changing, and may be set by default, or may be subject to some degree of modification, such as by operator adjustment of a parameter that offers a difference in the feel or responsiveness of the system to short circuit events.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates a plot <b>156</b> of voltage vs. time and a plot <b>158</b> of current vs. time during an exemplary weld event controlled by the disclosed system controller. A typical constant voltage (CV) controller modifies the current output of the power supply to generate a relatively constant voltage output. Accordingly, in high voltage instances (e.g., high voltage when coming out of a short circuit), traditional CV controllers ramp down the current to accommodate the high voltage. However, in high voltage instances, such controllers may decrease the current to current levels that disadvantageously have the effect of extinguishing the welding arc. The control method implemented by the system controller disclosed herein may offer distinct benefits over such CV controllers. Specifically, the system controller described below utilizes a running average of the current to continuously set and reset a minimum current value, thereby ensuring that the welding arc does not extinguish during high voltage instances.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The voltage vs. time plot <b>156</b> and the current vs. time plot <b>158</b> illustrate such a feature of the system controller. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, a running average current level is indicated by dashed line <b>160</b>, and a continuously adjusted current minimum is indicated by dashed line <b>162</b>. A distance <b>164</b> between the running average current level <b>160</b> and the continuously adjusted minimum level <b>162</b> remains constant during the weld event, as indicated by arrows <b>166</b>. That is, the minimum current level <b>162</b> is continuously reset a preset amount (e.g., 70 Amps) below the running average current level <b>160</b> throughout the weld event. Accordingly, during operation, the instantaneous current is sampled throughout the weld at predetermined time intervals (e.g., sample once every 100 &#x3bc;s). At each time interval, the acquired measurement is averaged with the previous measurements to generate the instantaneous running average current level at that point. The instantaneous minimum current level at that time point is then set at the preset distance <b>164</b> below the instantaneous running average level. In such a way, in the illustrated embodiment, the minimum current level <b>162</b> is continuously adjusted throughout the weld event, but the minimum current level <b>162</b> always remains at a constant offset <b>164</b> from the running average level <b>160</b>. However, it should be noted that in other embodiments the offset <b>164</b> may not remain constant. For instance, in one embodiment, the minimum current level <b>162</b> may be further constrained by a current minimum limit. That is, in some embodiments, the continuously updated minimum current <b>162</b> may be prohibited from dropping below a preset current limit (e.g., 50 Amps) even if the offset value <b>164</b> must change. In operation, as can be seen from the plots, as the voltage changes due to changing welding conditions, a difference between the actual (sensed) voltage and a desired voltage output is considered a voltage error, and the current will be controlled to reduce this voltage error. Conversely, when the voltage rises substantially, however, and the current command would otherwise drop the current level below the minimum allowable current, the command is set to the minimum level. The minimum level continues to change based upon the offset from the running average and any preset current limit.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In practice, various techniques may be used to generate the baseline current that is used to compute the following minimum current level. The presently contemplated approach uses a running average of the actual current. Any suitable technique may be used, however, including weighted averages, values based upon more or fewer samples of actual current, values based on commanded current, and so forth. Moreover, while the presently contemplated technique uses a fixed offset from this reference value of current, other approaches may use an offset that is computed and that may vary over time, or as a function of a welding parameter.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Referring more particular to the plots of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the foregoing features may have distinct advantages over traditional CV control loop systems. For example, during high voltage instances, a traditional CV controller would dictate a large current drop. However, in presently contemplated embodiments, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, current drops in response to high voltage instances are capped by the continuously adjusted minimum current level <b>162</b>. For example, consider a portion <b>168</b> of the voltage curve <b>156</b>, which represents an increase in the voltage level. A proportional current response needed to return the voltage to the preset level would require a substantial drop in current below the minimum current level <b>162</b>. However, the controller prevents the current from dropping below the minimum current level, as indicated by portion <b>170</b> of the current plot <b>158</b>. Likewise, consider the high voltage event indicated by portion <b>172</b> of the voltage curve <b>156</b>. A substantial current drop would be dictated by a traditional CV controller in response to portion <b>172</b> of the voltage curve <b>156</b>. However, the presently contemplated controller caps the current response at the continuously adjusted minimum current level <b>162</b>, as indicated by portion <b>174</b> of the current waveform <b>158</b>. In this way, the present controller may prevent current drops to levels below the continuously adjusted minimum, thus ensuring that the welding arc is not extinguished due to current level adjustments.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flow chart <b>176</b> illustrating a method that may be employed by the system controller to regulate the current level in accordance with embodiments of the present invention. The controller first samples the current (i) (block <b>178</b>). The running value (I) is then computed by the controller (block <b>180</b>). For example, I may be the running average of the current, as indicated by curve <b>160</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. The minimum current level (I<sub>min</sub>) is then computed by the controller (block <b>182</b>). In one embodiment, an instantaneous I<sub>min </sub>may be determined by subtracting a preset offset distance (e.g., 70 Amps) from 1 (i.e., I<sub>min</sub>=I&#x2212;offset). That is, the minimum current level at a given time point may be determined by subtracting the offset distance from the running current value at that time point.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The controller then inquires as to whether I<sub>min </sub>is less than a preset current minimum limit (I<sub>min lim</sub>) (block <b>184</b>). That is, in some embodiments, I<sub>min lim </sub>may limit how low I<sub>min </sub>may drop (e.g., lower limit of 50 Amps). If I<sub>min </sub>is not less than I<sub>min lim</sub>, the controller may then sample the voltage (V) (block <b>186</b>). If I<sub>min </sub>is less than I<sub>min lim</sub>, the controller sets I<sub>min</sub>=I<sub>min lim</sub>, (block <b>188</b>), thus limiting the minimum current level to the preset limit before sampling V (block <b>186</b>). The controller then computes a voltage error (V<sub>error</sub>), which indicates the difference between the actual voltage and the preset voltage (block <b>190</b>). That is, V<sub>error </sub>may equal the sampled voltage (V<sub>sample</sub>) minus the target voltage (V<sub>target</sub>), thus indicating the degree to which the voltage is not remaining at the constant preset value. The controller may then output a current control command (i<sub>command</sub>) that indicates the current level necessary to minimize V<sub>error </sub>and return the operating voltage to the preset voltage level (block <b>192</b>). The controller then inquires as to whether i<sub>command </sub>less than I<sub>min </sub>(block <b>194</b>). If i<sub>command </sub>is not less than I<sub>min</sub>, the controller applies i<sub>command </sub>(block <b>196</b>), the current level is dropped to the commanded current level, and the controller again samples the current (block <b>178</b>). If i<sub>command </sub>is less than I<sub>min</sub>, then i<sub>command </sub>is reset to I<sub>min </sub>(block <b>198</b>). That is, the controller prohibits the current level from dropping below I<sub>min </sub>even in instances where such a current level is computationally determined to be necessary to minimize the voltage error. Again, such a feature may have the effect of preventing welding arc outages resulting from high voltage levels driving down the commanded current levels.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">While only certain features of the invention have been illustrated and described herein, many modifications and changes will occur to those skilled in the art. It is, therefore, to be understood that the appended claims are intended to cover all such modifications and changes as fall within the true spirit of the invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A constant voltage (CV) welding process power supply comprising:
<claim-text>a control circuit that, in operation:
<claim-text>computes a varying minimum current level during a welding process;</claim-text>
<claim-text>computes, during the welding process, a voltage error between an instantaneous welding voltage level of the welding process and a desired voltage level;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generates a current command signal to minimize the computed voltage error;</claim-text>
<claim-text>compares the current command signal to the computed varying minimum current level; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>applies either the current command signal or the computed varying minimum current level for control of welding output based upon the comparison.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The CV welding process power supply of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the desired voltage level comprises a short circuit clearance voltage level.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The CV welding process power supply of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the computed varying minimum current level is approximately equal to a computed running current value minus an offset value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The CV welding process power supply of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the computed running current value is approximately equal to an instantaneous current value averaged with one or more previous current values.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The CV welding process power supply of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the offset value remains constant throughout a welding process.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The CV welding process power supply of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the offset value is equal to approximately 70 Amps.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The CV welding process power supply of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the control circuit, in operation, samples an instantaneous current one or more times and resets the computed varying minimum current level based on the sampled current.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A CV welding process power supply comprising:
<claim-text>a current sensor configured to sense current of welding power supplied by the power supply to a welding process;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a voltage sensor configured to sense voltage of the welding power; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control circuit that receives signals indicative of the sensed current and voltage, and is configured to periodically compute a voltage error between the sensed voltage of the welding power and a desired voltage level, and to periodically compute a current command signal based on the voltage error, and if the current command signal is not less than a periodically computed minimum current level, then apply a current level indicated by the current command signal for control of welding output, and if the current command signal is less than the periodically computed minimum current level, then apply the periodically computed minimum current level for control of welding output.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The CV welding process power supply of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the desired voltage level comprises a short circuit clearance voltage level.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The CV welding process power supply of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the periodically computed minimum current level is approximately equal to a periodically computed running current value minus an offset value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The CV welding process power supply of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the periodically computed running current value is approximately equal to an instantaneous current value averaged with one or more previous current values.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The CV welding process power supply of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the offset value remains constant throughout a welding process.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The CV welding process power supply of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the control circuit is further configured to sample an instantaneous current one or more times with the current sensor and reset the periodically computed minimum current level based on the sampled current.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The CV welding process power supply of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the instantaneous current is sampled approximately every 100&#x3bc;s.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A constant voltage (CV) welding process power supply comprising:
<claim-text>a control circuit that, in operation:
<claim-text>periodically computes a running current value during a welding process;</claim-text>
<claim-text>periodically computes a minimum current value based on the running current value and an offset value; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>generates a current command signal to minimize a periodically computed voltage error, wherein if the current command signal is not less than the periodically computed minimum current value, then the power supply applies a current level indicated by the current command signal for control of welding output, and if the current command signal is less than the periodically computed minimum current value, then the power supply applies the periodically computed minimum current level for control of welding output.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The CV welding process power supply of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the periodically computed voltage error is based upon a difference between a desired welding voltage and a sensed voltage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The CV welding process power supply of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the running current value is a running average of welding output current.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The CV welding process power supply of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the offset value is a fixed value.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
