<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624691-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624691</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13110926</doc-number>
<date>20110519</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2011 2 0070118 U</doc-number>
<date>20110317</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>318</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>P</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>205</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>P</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>333203</main-classification>
<further-classification>333223</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Cavity filter</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6466110</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Wulff et al.</name>
<date>20021000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>333222</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>10</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>333202</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>333203</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>333222</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>333223</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>333227</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>333206</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>333207</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120235771</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120920</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wong</last-name>
<first-name>Kwo-Jyr</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tu-Cheng</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wong</last-name>
<first-name>Kwo-Jyr</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tu-Cheng</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Lee</last-name>
<first-name>Benny</first-name>
<department>2843</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Patel</last-name>
<first-name>Rakesh</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A cavity filter includes a unitarily formed piece, a cap, a cover, and a tuning adjustment screw. The unitarily formed piece includes a bottom plate portion, a resonator tube body portion formed on a center of the bottom plate portion, and a sidewall portion extending from the bottom plate portion surrounding the resonator tube body portion. The resonator tube body portion defines a resonating cavity therein. The cap is attached onto a distal end of the resonator tube body portion. The cap and the resonator tube body portion cooperatively forms a resonator tube. The cover is attached to the sidewall portion, and the cover includes a screw hole. The cover, the sidewall portion, and the bottom plate portion cooperatively forms a chamber. The tuning adjustment screw is extending through the cover, threadedly engaged in the screw hole and aligned with the resonator tube.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="137.41mm" wi="153.75mm" file="US08624691-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="211.07mm" wi="158.24mm" file="US08624691-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="194.65mm" wi="156.46mm" file="US08624691-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="186.10mm" wi="133.52mm" file="US08624691-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="171.11mm" wi="160.10mm" file="US08624691-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="194.31mm" wi="136.91mm" file="US08624691-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="190.33mm" wi="160.70mm" file="US08624691-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to cavity filters including resonator tubes.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Cavity filters are the basic circuitry behind a duplexer and are in a sharply tuned resonant circuit that allows only certain frequencies to pass. A typical cavity filter has one or more resonator tubes each in corporation with one tuning adjustment screw. Traditionally, the resonator tubes are fixed in the cavity filter by fixing members, such that the more resonator tubes and tuning adjustment screws, the longer it takes to assemble the cavity filter.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">What is needed, therefore, is a cavity filter capable of being assembled quickly.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Many aspects of the present cavity filter can be better understood with reference to the following drawings. The components in the drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the present resonator tube and cavity filter including the resonator tube. Moreover, in the drawings, like reference numerals designate corresponding parts throughout the views.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a sectional view of a cavity filter in accordance with a first embodiment, the cavity filter including a resonator tube.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows the resonator tube of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a support and a resonator tube body portion of the cavity filter of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a cap of the cavity filter of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a bottom plan view of the cap of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows an alternative configuration of the resonator tube.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, a cavity filter <b>100</b> provided by a first exemplary embodiment includes a unitarily formed piece <b>10</b>, a cover <b>12</b>, a cap <b>22</b>, and a tuning adjustment screw <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The unitarily formed piece <b>10</b> is made by casting or molding operation. The unitarily formed piece <b>10</b> includes a bottom plate portion <b>141</b>, a resonator tube body portion <b>20</b> formed on a center of the bottom plate portion <b>141</b>, and a sidewall portion <b>14</b> extending from the bottom plate portion <b>141</b> surrounding the resonator tube body portion <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The resonator tube body portion <b>20</b> defines a resonating cavity <b>200</b> therein. The cap <b>22</b> is attached onto a distal end, that is, the top end of the resonator tube body portion <b>20</b>. The cap <b>22</b> and the resonator tube body portion <b>20</b> cooperatively form a resonator tube <b>16</b>. The size and shape of the cap <b>22</b> can be varied to effect the frequency of the cavity filter <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The sidewall portion <b>14</b> is substantially cylindrical in shape. The sidewall portion <b>14</b> has a top opening <b>140</b>. The cover <b>12</b> is attached onto the sidewall portion <b>14</b> and shade the top opening <b>140</b>. The cover <b>12</b>, the sidewall portion <b>14</b>, and the bottom plate portion <b>141</b> cooperatively form a chamber <b>300</b>. The chamber <b>300</b> communicates with the resonating cavity <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The tuning adjustment screw <b>122</b> extends through the cover <b>12</b> by a screw hole <b>120</b> formed in a central area of the cover <b>12</b>. The tuning adjustment screw <b>122</b> is threadedly engaged in the screw hole <b>120</b> and aligned with the resonator tube <b>16</b>. The tuning adjustment screw <b>122</b> is formed from a conductive material, such as brass, for example. There may be a number of resonator tubes <b>16</b> and a number of corresponding tuning adjustment screws in one cavity filter.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 3</figref>, the resonator tube body portion <b>20</b> includes a top end surface <b>202</b> at the distal end, an inner annular step surface <b>206</b> located in the resonating cavity <b>200</b>, and an annular beveled surface <b>204</b> connecting the top end surface <b>202</b> and the inner annular step surface <b>206</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The top end surface <b>202</b> is a flat surface parallel to the bottom plate portion <b>141</b>. The beveled surface <b>204</b> inclines to the interior of the resonating cavity <b>200</b> about &#x3b8; degrees. &#x3b8; is an acute angle. One step part <b>2061</b> of the step surface <b>206</b> is parallel to the bottom plate portion <b>141</b> and configured to support an inner tube <b>222</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the cap <b>22</b>. The length of the step part <b>2061</b> is equal to that of the inner tube <b>222</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">There is a bottom surface <b>201</b> located on the center of the resonator tube body portion <b>20</b>. The resonator tube body portion <b>20</b> also includes a support <b>26</b> below the bottom surface <b>201</b> and over the bottom plate portion <b>141</b>. The support <b>26</b> is solid and free of apertures, thus the probability of a third-order harmonic distortion is lowered.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The detail structure of the cap <b>22</b> is mainly shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>. The cap <b>22</b> is hollow in its central part. The cap <b>22</b> includes an inner tube <b>222</b>, an outer tube <b>224</b> surrounding the inner tube <b>222</b>, and a ring-shaped flange <b>220</b> extending outwardly from the inner tube <b>222</b> to the outer tube <b>224</b>. The inner tube <b>222</b> is inserted in the resonator tube body portion <b>20</b> and abutting the step surface <b>206</b> (as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the ring-shaped flange <b>220</b> is attached on the distal end of the resonator tube body portion <b>20</b>. Because the cap <b>22</b> is manufactured by a method of continuous stamping, there may be some protrusions (now shown) at the corner of the inner tube <b>222</b> and the ring-shaped flange <b>220</b>. A gap <b>221</b> between the ring-shaped flange <b>220</b> and the beveled surface <b>204</b> will be helpful to these protrusions when the cap <b>22</b> is located on the resonator tube body portion <b>20</b>. Thus, the cap <b>22</b> is capable of abutting the resonator tube body portion <b>20</b> firmly, and a third-order harmonic distortion is lowered</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, an alternative resonator tube <b>36</b> includes an annual outer step surface <b>304</b> located outside the resonating cavity <b>400</b>. The cap <b>32</b> includes a tube <b>322</b> and a ring-shaped flange <b>320</b> extending outwardly from the tube <b>322</b>. The tube <b>322</b> is surrounding the resonator tube body portion <b>360</b> and abutting the outer step surface <b>304</b>. The ring-shaped flange <b>320</b> is not lower than the resonator tube body portion <b>360</b>. The length of the tube <b>322</b> is equal to that of the step part <b>3041</b> of the outer step surface <b>304</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The resonator tube (except the cap), the bottom plate portion, and the sidewall portion are formed unitarily, therefore, the location of the resonator tube is accurate according to the predetermined design, and does not need to be moved or adjusted. The cap also does not need fixing members to be matched with the resonator tube body portion. In all, the time for producing or assembling the cavity filter is minimized.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">It is understood that the above-described embodiments are intended to illustrate rather than limit the disclosure. Variations may be made to the embodiments without departing from the spirit of the disclosure. Accordingly, it is appropriate that the appended claims be construed broadly and in a manner consistent with the scope of the disclosure.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A cavity filter, comprising:
<claim-text>a unitarily formed piece comprising a bottom plate portion, a resonator tube body portion formed on a center of the bottom plate portion, and a sidewall portion extending from the bottom plate portion surrounding the resonator tube body portion, the resonator tube body portion defining a resonating cavity therein;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cap attached onto a distal end of the resonator tube body portion, the cap and the resonator tube body portion cooperatively forming a resonator tube;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cover attached to the sidewall portion, and the cover comprising a screw hole; the cover, the sidewall portion, and the bottom plate portion cooperatively forming a chamber; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a tuning adjustment screw extending through the cover, threadedly engaged in the screw hole and aligned with the resonator tube, wherein the resonator tube body portion comprises an inner annular step surface located in the resonating cavity, the cap comprises an inner tube, an outer tube surrounding the inner tube, and a ring-shaped flange extending outwardly from the inner tube to the outer tube, the inner tube is inserted in the resonator tube body portion and abuts the inner annular step surface, the ring-shaped flange is attached on the distal end of the resonator tube body portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The cavity filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the sidewall portion is substantially cylindrical.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The cavity filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the distal end of the resonator tube body portion comprises an annular beveled surface, a gap being formed between the ring-shaped flange and the annular beveled surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The cavity filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the inner annular step surface comprises a step part substantially parallel to the bottom plate portion to support the cap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The cavity filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the resonating cavity communicates with the chamber.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The cavity filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the unitarily formed piece comprises a support connected between the bottom plate portion and the resonator tube body portion, the support is solid and free of apertures.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A cavity filter, comprising:
<claim-text>a unitarily formed piece comprising a bottom plate portion, a resonator tube body portion formed on a center of the bottom plate portion, and a sidewall portion extending from the bottom plate portion surrounding the resonator tube body portion, the resonator tube body portion defining a resonating cavity therein;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cap attached onto a distal end of the resonator tube body portion, the cap and the resonator tube body portion cooperatively forming a resonator tube;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cover attached to the sidewall portion, and the cover comprising a screw hole; the cover, the sidewall portion, and the bottom plate portion cooperatively forming a chamber; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a tuning adjustment screw extending through the cover, threadedly engaged in the screw hole and aligned with the resonator tube, wherein the resonator tube body portion comprises an outer step surface located outside the resonating cavity, the cap comprises a tube and a ring-shaped flange extending outwardly from the tube, the tube surrounds the resonator tube body portion and abuts the outer step surface.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The cavity filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the unitarily formed piece comprises a support connected between the bottom plate portion and the resonator tube body portion, the support is solid and free of apertures.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The cavity filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the resonating cavity communicates with the chamber.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The cavity filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the sidewall portion is substantially cylindrical. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
