<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623188-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623188</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13281314</doc-number>
<date>20111025</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-239634</doc-number>
<date>20101026</date>
</priority-claim>
<priority-claim sequence="02" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2011-204266</doc-number>
<date>20110920</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>90</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>27</main-group>
<subgroup>419</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>204424</main-classification>
<further-classification>204425</further-classification>
<further-classification>204426</further-classification>
<further-classification>204427</further-classification>
<further-classification>204428</further-classification>
<further-classification>204429</further-classification>
<further-classification> 73 2331</further-classification>
<further-classification> 73 2332</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e90">Gas sensor</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4902400</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Usami et al.</name>
<date>19900200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>204426</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2001/0050229</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Schnaibel et al.</name>
<date>20011200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>204421</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0094416</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Chen et al.</name>
<date>20040500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>204426</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0084724</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Mori et al.</name>
<date>20070400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>204424</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2003294687</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20031000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2009180634</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20090800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>5</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>204424-429</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 73 2331- 2332</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>2</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120103808</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120503</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Igarashi</last-name>
<first-name>Ai</first-name>
<address>
<city>Konan</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Furuta</last-name>
<first-name>Noboru</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kasugai</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Igarashi</last-name>
<first-name>Ai</first-name>
<address>
<city>Konan</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Furuta</last-name>
<first-name>Noboru</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kasugai</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Sughrue Mion, PLLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>NGK Spark Plug Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Aichi</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Dinh</last-name>
<first-name>Bach</first-name>
<department>1756</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A gas sensor including a plate-shaped laminate disposed in a housing and fixed thereto via an element passage member and formed by laminating a gas sensor element and a heating element. The gas sensor element includes a plate-shaped solid electrolyte member, and a pair of detection electrodes formed on front and back surfaces thereof and constituting, in cooperation with the solid electrolyte member, a detection section for detecting the concentration of a specific gas. Insulating substrates mainly composed of alumina are provided on opposite sides of the laminate in the laminating direction. Coating layers mainly composed of a first material higher in toughness than alumina are formed on at least portions of outer surfaces of the insulating substrates in the laminating direction, the portions facing the element passage member. The coating layers are not formed on surfaces of the laminate parallel to the laminating direction.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="252.39mm" wi="175.01mm" file="US08623188-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="255.27mm" wi="177.88mm" file="US08623188-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="258.06mm" wi="148.08mm" file="US08623188-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to a gas sensor for detecting the concentration of a specific gas component of a gas to be measured (hereinafter referred to as an &#x201c;object gas&#x201d;).</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND ART</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Conventionally, there has been known a gas sensor which detects the concentration of a specific gas component of an object gas, such as exhaust gas discharged from, for example, an automobile. Such a gas sensor uses a gas sensor element whose electrical characteristic changes in accordance with the concentration of the specific gas component of the object gas. A known gas sensor element is configured such that a pair of electrodes are formed on a solid electrolyte member mainly formed of zirconia, and an insulating layer, a heater, etc. are laminated thereon, whereby the gas sensor element assumes a plate-like outer shape as a whole.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In the above-described gas sensor element, the insulating layer is formed of ceramic whose predominant component is alumina, which is excellent in insulating property and heat resistance. The heater has a structure in which a heating resistor or the like is buried in a heater insulating layer formed of a ceramic material whose predominant component is alumina (for example, see Patent Document 1).</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">PRIOR ART DOCUMENT</heading>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">Patent Document</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">[Patent Document 1] Japanese Patent Application Laid-Open (kokai) No. 2003-294687</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DISCLOSURE OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">Problems to be Solved by the Invention</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In the above-described gas sensor element has the following problem. In a process of manufacturing the gas sensor element, particles of alumina, mullite, or the like may drop from a firing setter which is used during firing (such particles will be referred to debris of dropped particle). In this case, the debris of dropped particles may adhere to the surfaces of an unfired insulating layer and an unfired heater insulating layer provided on opposite sides of the gas sensor element with respect to the lamination direction (hereinafter, each of the unfired insulating layer and unfired heater insulating layer will be referred to as an unfired insulating substrate, and each of the insulating layer and the heater insulating layer will be referred to as an insulating substrate). The debris of dropped particles adhering to the surface of an unfired insulating substrate reacts with alumina, which is the predominant component of the insulating substrate during a firing stage, whereby particles of alumina grow anomalously, which causes a problem of lowering the breakage strength of the insulating substrate. Also, such a drop in the breakage strength of the insulating substrate raises the following problem. When the gas sensor element is assembled into a metallic shell and fixed thereto, the gas sensor element comes into contact with an element passage member such as a holder, a ceramic member (e.g., a sleeve), or a talc layer, which are disposed between the element and the metallic shell (housing) and into which the element is inserted. Thus, the pressure applied to the gas sensor element during the assembly may affect a contact portion of the gas sensor element, whereby the gas sensor element may be broken. Also, when measurement is performed by use of the gas sensor, due to vibration from an internal combustion engine or the like, the gas sensor element may come into contact with the element passage member, which may result in breakage of the gas sensor element.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The present invention has been accomplished in view of the foregoing, and an object of the present invention is to provide a gas sensor which can secure a required breakage strength even in the case where debris of particles dropped from a setter for firing in a manufacturing process adheres to the surface of an unfired gas sensor element, to thereby restrain occurrence of breakage of the gas sensor element.</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">Means for Solving the Problems</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">A gas sensor of the present invention includes a plate-shaped laminate which is disposed in a housing and fixed thereto via an element passage member and which is formed by laminating a gas sensor element and a heater having a heating element. The gas sensor element includes a plate-shaped solid electrolyte member, and a pair of detection electrodes formed on front and back surfaces of the solid electrolyte member and constituting, in cooperation with the solid electrolyte member, a detection section for detecting the concentration of a specific gas contained in an object gas. Insulating substrates containing alumina as a predominant component are provided on opposite sides of the laminate with respect to the lamination direction thereof. Coating layers containing, as a predominant component, a first material which is higher in toughness than alumina are formed on at least portions of outer surfaces of the insulating substrates with respect to the lamination direction, the portions facing the element passage member. The coating layers are not formed on surfaces of the laminate parallel to the lamination direction.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In the gas sensor element of the present invention having the above-described structure, coating layers containing, as a predominant component, a first material which is higher in toughness than alumina are formed on at least portions of the outer surfaces of the insulating substrates, which are provided on opposite sides of the laminate with respect to the lamination direction and which contain alumina as a predominant component, the portions facing the element passage member. By virtue of this configuration, the breakage strength of the portion on which the coating layers are provided can be increased. Therefore, even in the case where debris of particles dropped from a setter for firing in a manufacturing process adheres to the surface of the gas sensor element in an unfired state, a required breakage strength can be secured, whereby breakage of the gas sensor element during assembly to a housing can be restrained. Also, when measurement is performed by use of the gas sensor, due to vibration from an internal combustion engine or the like, the gas sensor element may come into contact with the element passage member. However, since a required breakage strength can be secured through provision of the coating layers, breakage of the gas sensor element can be restrained. Notably, the above-mentioned coating layers are not provided on the side surfaces (surfaces parallel to the lamination direction) of the laminate. Since the width of the gas sensor element is greater than the thickness thereof, a require breakage strength can be secured without provision of the coating layers on the surfaces parallel to the lamination direction. Therefore, even in the case where dropped particles or like debris is adhered to the surface of the gas sensor element in an unfired state, breakage of the gas sensor element can be retrained. Therefore, through omission of such coating layers, productivity is increased, and cost is lowered.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Notably, the phrase &#x201c;insulating substrates containing alumina as a predominant component&#x201d; means that the alumina content of the insulating substrates is 50% by mass or greater. Also, the phrase &#x201c;coating layers containing, as a predominant component, a first material&#x201d; means that the content of the first material of the coating layers is 50% by mass or greater.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Moreover, the phrase &#x201c;a first material which is higher in toughness than alumina&#x201d; means that the first material may be those which are higher in toughness than alumina defined by JIS R 1607 (1990). Examples of the first material include zirconia, silicon nitride, and silicon carbide.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Preferably, the thickness of the coating layers is set to fall within a range of 10 &#x3bc;m to 50 &#x3bc;m. When the thickness of the coating layers is equal to or greater than 10 &#x3bc;m, the effect of increasing breakage strength by the coating layers can be attained. Even when the thickness of the coating layers is increased to 20 &#x3bc;m, the breakage strength increasing effect hardly changes as compared with the case where the thickness is 10 &#x3bc;m. Also, in consideration of the fact that the gas sensor element is inserted into the element passage member, the upper limit of the thickness of the coating layers must be set to about 50 &#x3bc;m.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Preferably, the coating layers are formed of a material which is lower in thermal conductivity than the insulating substrates. By virtue of this, it become possible to reduce conduction of heat of the gas sensor element, which is heated by the heater, to the element passage member via the coating layers. Thus, the amount of electric power supplied to the heater can be reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Preferably, the coating layers are formed of a material selected such that the difference in coefficient of thermal expansion between the material and the insulating substrates becomes 0.7&#xd7;10<sup>&#x2212;6 </sup>or less. By virtue of this, separation of the coating layers from the insulating substrates can be prevented. Notably, when the difference in coefficient of thermal expansion between the coating layers and the insulating substrates exceeds 0.7&#xd7;10<sup>&#x2212;6</sup>, this effect cannot be obtained in some cases.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Preferably, the coating layers contain zirconia as a predominant component. By virtue of this, the breakage strength of the portion on which the coating layers are provided can be increased. In addition, since zirconia is lower in volume resistivity than alumina. Therefore, generation of electrical leakage can be suppressed by not providing the above-mentioned coating layers on the side surfaces (surfaces parallel to the lamination direction) of the laminate.</p>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">Effect of the Invention</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">According to the present invention, there can be provided a gas sensor which can secure a required breakage strength even in the case where debris of particles dropped from a setter for firing in a manufacturing process adheres to the surface of an unfired gas sensor element, to thereby restrain occurrence of breakage of the gas sensor element when it is assembled into a housing.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0009" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">[<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>] Exploded perspective view schematically showing the structure of a gas sensor element according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">[<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>] Cross-sectional view showing the structure of a gas sensor according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0010" level="1">MODE FOR CARRYING OUT THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">A laminate-type gas sensor element <b>100</b> according to an embodiment of the present invention will now be described with reference to the drawings. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an exploded perspective view showing the structure of the gas sensor <b>100</b>, which assumes a platelike shape as a whole. The gas sensor element <b>100</b> is configured by stacking a gas sensor element main body <b>3</b> and a heater <b>2</b> in layers.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The gas sensor element main body <b>3</b> includes an oxygen concentration detection cell <b>130</b> and an oxygen pump cell <b>140</b>. A gas detection chamber forming layer <b>160</b> is provided between the oxygen concentration detection cell <b>130</b> and the oxygen pump cell <b>140</b>, and a protection layer <b>12</b> is provided on the outer side (the upper side in the drawing) of the oxygen pump cell <b>140</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The oxygen concentration detection cell <b>130</b> includes a solid electrolyte member <b>11</b>, and a reference electrode <b>13</b> and a detection electrode <b>14</b> formed on the opposite surfaces, respectively, of the solid electrolyte member <b>11</b>. The solid electrolyte member <b>11</b> has oxygen ion conductivity and is formed of a zirconia (ZrO<sub>2</sub>) sintered body or an LaGaO<sub>3 </sub>sintered body containing yttria (Y<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>) or calcia (CaO) added thereto as a stabilizer. The solid electrolyte member <b>11</b> is used for an oxygen concentration cell. In the present embodiment, the solid electrolyte member <b>11</b> is formed of a zirconia sintered body containing yttria added thereto as a stabilizer, and also containing alumina (10 to 80% by mass).</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The reference electrode <b>13</b>, which is formed of a porous material, is formed on the surface of the solid electrolyte member <b>11</b> facing the heater <b>2</b>. The detection electrode <b>14</b>, which is also formed of a porous material, is formed on the surface of the solid electrolyte member <b>11</b> opposite the reference electrode <b>13</b>. The reference electrode <b>13</b> and the detection electrode <b>14</b> respectively have a reference electrode portion <b>132</b> and a detection electrode portion <b>142</b>, which face each other and which constitute a detection section in cooperation with the solid electrolyte member <b>11</b>. A reference electrode lead portion <b>131</b> and a detection electrode lead portion <b>141</b> extend along the longitudinal direction of the solid electrolyte member <b>11</b> from the reference electrode portion <b>132</b> and the detection electrode portion <b>142</b>, respectively. The reference electrode portion <b>132</b>, the detection electrode portion <b>142</b>, the reference electrode lead portion <b>131</b>, the detection electrode lead portion <b>141</b> are formed of, for example, Pt or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The oxygen pump cell <b>140</b> includes a second solid electrolyte member <b>181</b>, and a third electrode <b>170</b> and a fourth electrode <b>190</b> formed on the opposite sides, respectively, of the second solid electrolyte member <b>181</b>. The third electrode <b>170</b> and the fourth electrode <b>190</b> respectively have a third electrode portion <b>172</b> and a fourth electrode portion <b>192</b>, which face each other and which constitute a detection section in cooperation with the second solid electrolyte member <b>181</b>. A third lead portion <b>171</b> extends from the third electrode portion <b>172</b> in the longitudinal direction of the second electrolyte member <b>181</b>, and a fourth lead portion <b>191</b> extends from the fourth electrode portion <b>192</b> in the longitudinal direction of the second electrolyte member <b>181</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The gas detection chamber forming layer <b>160</b> provided between the oxygen pump cell <b>140</b> and the oxygen concentration detection cell <b>130</b> is composed of an insulating portion <b>161</b> and diffusion rate limiting portions <b>163</b>. A gas detection chamber <b>162</b> is formed in the insulating portion <b>161</b> of the gas detection chamber forming layer <b>160</b> at a position corresponding to the detection electrode portion <b>142</b> and the third electrode portion <b>172</b>. This gas detection chamber <b>162</b> communicates with the atmosphere outside the sensor element via communication portions of the gas detection chamber forming layer <b>160</b> located on opposite sides of the gas detection chamber <b>162</b> with respect to the width direction thereof. The diffusion rate limiting portions <b>163</b> are disposed in the communication portions so as to enables the object gas from the outside atmosphere to diffuse into the gas detection chamber <b>162</b> at a predetermined limited speed.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">No limitation is imposed on the material of the insulating portion <b>161</b> so long as it is formed of a ceramic sintered body having insulating properties. Examples of the material of the insulating portion <b>161</b> include oxide ceramics such as alumina or mullite. The diffusion rate limiting portions <b>163</b> are formed of porous alumina. The diffusion rate limiting portions <b>163</b> limit the speed at which the object gas flows into the gas detection chamber <b>162</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Notably, the end of the reference electrode lead portion <b>131</b> is electrically connected to one of three signal takeout terminals <b>126</b> via a through hole <b>110</b> provided in the solid electrolyte member <b>11</b>, a through hole <b>164</b> provided in the insulating layer <b>160</b>, a through hole <b>182</b> provided in the second solid electrolyte member <b>181</b>, and a through hole <b>123</b> provided in the protection layer <b>12</b>. The end of the detection electrode lead portion <b>141</b> is electrically connected to another of the signal takeout terminals <b>126</b> via a through hole <b>165</b> provided in the insulating layer <b>160</b>, a through hole <b>183</b> provided in the second solid electrolyte member <b>181</b>, and a through hole <b>124</b> provided in the protection layer <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Also, the end of the third lead portion <b>171</b> is connected to one signal takeout terminal <b>126</b> via the through hole <b>183</b> provided in the second solid electrolyte member <b>181</b> and the through hole <b>124</b> provided in the protection layer <b>12</b>. The end of the fourth lead portion <b>191</b> is connected to another signal takeout terminal <b>126</b> via a through hole <b>125</b> provided in the protection layer <b>12</b>. Notably, the detection electrode lead portion <b>141</b> and the third lead portion <b>171</b> are connected together via the through hole <b>165</b> so that they have the same potential.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The heater <b>2</b> includes a heating resistor <b>21</b>, which is sandwiched between a first insulating substrate <b>22</b> and a second insulating substrate <b>23</b> (corresponding to the &#x201c;insulating substrate&#x201d; of the claims), which are formed of a ceramic sintered body of alumina, which is excellent in insulation properties. The heating resistor <b>21</b> has a heat generation portion <b>212</b> formed into a meandering shape, and a pair of heater lead portions <b>213</b> connected to opposite ends of the heat generation portion <b>212</b> and extending along the longitudinal direction. End portions of the heater lead portions <b>213</b> opposite the side where they are connected to the heat generation portion <b>212</b> are electrically connected to a pair of heater electricity supply terminals <b>232</b> via two through holes <b>231</b>, which penetrate the second insulating substrate <b>23</b>. The heater electricity supply terminals <b>232</b> are connected to external terminals for connection of an external circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The heating resistor <b>21</b> may be formed of noble metal, tungsten, molybdenum, or the like. Examples of noble metal include Pt, Au, Ag, Pd, Ir, Ru, and Rh. Only one of these noble metals may be used, or two or more of these noble metals may be used in combination. Notably, preferably, the heating resistor <b>21</b> is mainly formed of a noble metal from the viewpoint of heat resistance, oxidation resistance, etc. More preferably, the heating resistor <b>21</b> is mainly formed of Pt. Also, desirably, the heating resistor <b>21</b> contains a ceramic component, in addition to the noble metal which mainly constitutes the heating resistor <b>21</b>. From the viewpoint of bonding strength, preferably, the heating resistor <b>21</b> contains, as a ceramic component, the same component as the predominant component (alumina in the present embodiment) of the first and second ceramic insulating substrates <b>22</b> and <b>23</b> in which-the heating resistor <b>21</b> is buried.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In the heating resistor <b>21</b>, the heat generation portion <b>212</b> is a portion which generates heat upon supply of electricity thereto, and the lead portions <b>213</b> are portions which convey an externally supplied DC voltage to the heat generation portion <b>212</b> and which hardly generate heat. No limitation is imposed on the shapes of the heat generation portion <b>212</b> and the lead portions <b>213</b>. For example, the heat generation portion <b>212</b> may have a width smaller than that of the lead portions <b>213</b>, and have a meandering shape so that the heat generation portion <b>212</b> has a denser pattern as compared with the lead portions <b>213</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The protection layer <b>12</b> includes a porous electrode protection layer <b>122</b> which is formed on the surface of the fourth electrode portion <b>192</b> and protects the fourth electrode portion <b>192</b> from poisoning, and a reinforcing protection layer (corresponding to the &#x201c;insulating substrate&#x201d; the claims <b>121</b> which is formed on the surface of the fourth lead portion <b>191</b> and protects the second solid electrolyte member <b>181</b>. This reinforcing protection layer <b>121</b> is formed of a ceramic sintered boy of alumina.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In the gas sensor element <b>100</b> constituted by laminating the gas sensor element main body <b>3</b> and the heater <b>2</b>, the reinforcing protection layer <b>121</b> formed of alumina and the second insulating substrate <b>23</b> formed of alumina are located on the opposite sides of the gas sensor element <b>100</b> with respect to the lamination direction thereof (the upper and lower sides in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). Coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> are formed on at least portions of the respective outer surfaces of the reinforcing protection layer <b>121</b> and the second insulating substrate <b>23</b> with respect to the lamination direction (in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the upper surface of the reinforcing protection layer <b>121</b> and the lower surface of the second insulating substrate <b>23</b>), the portions facing a member through which the gas sensor element <b>100</b> is passed (hereinafter referred to as the &#x201c;element passage member&#x201d;) (specifically, a metallic holder <b>34</b>, a ceramic holder <b>35</b>, a talc layer <b>36</b>, and a sleeve <b>39</b>). In the present embodiment, the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> are formed to extend from a point about <b>12</b> mm away from the front end of the gas sensor element <b>100</b>, to a point about <b>30</b> mm away from the front end of the gas sensor element <b>100</b>. Such a coating layer is not formed on the side surfaces <b>153</b> of the reinforcing protection layer <b>121</b> and the side surfaces <b>154</b> of the second insulating substrate <b>23</b>, which are parallel to the lamination direction of the laminate. Similarly, such a coating layer is not formed on the side surfaces of the second solid electrolyte member <b>181</b>, the side surfaces of the gas detection chamber forming layer <b>160</b>, the side surfaces of the solid electrolyte member <b>11</b>, and the side surfaces of the first insulating substrate <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> contain zirconia as a predominant component, and may be formed, for example, through a process of applying, through printing, paste containing zirconia (about 50%) to portions of an unfired laminate where the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> are to be formed, flowed by dewaxing and firing performed for the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> along with the laminate. Notably, in addition to zirconia, the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> may contain insulating ceramics such as alumina, mullite, or titania.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">A porous protection layer (not shown) is formed on a front end portion of the gas sensor element <b>100</b>, which is constituted by laminating the gas sensor element main body <b>3</b> and the heater <b>2</b>, the front end portion being exposed to the object gas, such that the porous protection layer covers the entire circumference of the front end portion.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In the gas sensor element <b>100</b>, which includes the oxygen pump cell <b>140</b> and the oxygen concentration detection cell <b>130</b> as described above, oxygen contained in the object gas within the gas detection chamber <b>162</b> can be pumped out and oxygen can be pumped thereinto by making use of the oxygen pumping action of the oxygen pump cell <b>140</b>; and oxygen concentration can be measured by making use of the concentration cell action of the oxygen concentration detection cell <b>130</b>. Therefore, the gas sensor element <b>100</b> can be used as an air-fuel-ratio sensor or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an overall cross-sectional view showing an example of a gas sensor into which the above-described gas sensor element <b>100</b> is incorporated; specifically, a gas sensor <b>200</b> which is attached to an exhaust pipe of an internal combustion engine and used for, for example, measurement of oxygen concentration of exhaust gas.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The metallic shell (housing) <b>30</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> has an external thread portion <b>31</b> for mounting the gas sensor onto the exhaust pipe, and a hexagonal portion <b>32</b>, with which a mounting tool is engaged when the gas sensor is to be mounted. The metallic shell <b>30</b> also has a shell side step portion <b>33</b> projecting radially inward. This shell side step portion <b>33</b> supports a metallic holder <b>34</b> for holding the gas sensor element <b>100</b>. The above-mentioned ceramic holder <b>35</b> and the talc layer <b>36</b>, which dispose the gas sensor element <b>100</b> at a predetermined position, are disposed inside the metallic holder <b>34</b> in this sequence from the front end side.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The talc layer <b>36</b> is composed of a first talc layer <b>37</b> disposed inside the metallic holder <b>34</b>, and a second talc layer <b>38</b> projects from the rear end of the metallic holder <b>34</b>. The above-mentioned sleeve <b>39</b>, which is formed of alumina, is disposed on the rear end side of the second talc layer <b>38</b>. This sleeve <b>39</b> is a cylindrical member having a plurality of cylindrical portions of different diameters. The sleeve <b>39</b> has an axial hole <b>391</b> extending along the axis thereof, and the gas sensor element <b>100</b> is passed through the axial hole <b>391</b>. A rear-end-side crimp portion <b>301</b> of the metallic shell <b>30</b> is bent inward, whereby the sleeve <b>39</b> is pressed toward the front end side of the metallic shell <b>30</b> via a ring member <b>40</b> formed of stainless steel.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The above-described coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> formed on the surface of the gas sensor element <b>100</b> are located in a region extending from the front end of the metallic holder <b>34</b> to the rear end of the sleeve <b>39</b>; i.e., they face the metallic holder <b>34</b>, the ceramic holder <b>35</b>, the talc layer <b>36</b>, and the sleeve <b>39</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Also, a protector <b>24</b> is attached, through welding, to the outer circumference of a front end portion of the metallic shell <b>30</b> so as to cove a front end portion <b>101</b> of the gas sensor element <b>100</b> projecting from the front end of the metallic shell <b>30</b>. The protector <b>24</b> is formed of metal, and has a plurality of gas introduction holes <b>241</b>. The protector <b>24</b> has a double structure; i.e., is composed of an outer protector <b>41</b> and an inner protector <b>42</b>. The outer protector <b>41</b> has a bottomed, cylindrical tubular shape and has a constant outer diameter. The inner protector <b>42</b> has a bottomed, cylindrical tubular shape, and its rear end portion <b>421</b> is greater in outer diameter than its front end portion <b>422</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Meanwhile, a front end portion of an outer cover <b>25</b> is fitted onto a rear end portion of the metallic shell <b>30</b>. A front end portion <b>251</b> of the outer cover <b>25</b>, whose diameter is increased on the front end side thereof, is fixed to the metallic shell <b>30</b> by means of laser welding or the like. A separator <b>50</b> is disposed inside a rear end portion of the outer cover <b>25</b>, and a holding member <b>51</b> is provided in the clearance between the separator <b>50</b> and the outer cover <b>25</b>. This holding member <b>51</b> is in engagement with a projecting portion <b>501</b> of the separator <b>50</b>, and is fixedly held between the outer cover <b>25</b> and the separator <b>50</b> when the outer cover <b>25</b> is crimped.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The separator <b>50</b> has through holes <b>502</b> extending from the front end to rear end thereof. Lead wires <b>111</b> to <b>115</b> of the gas sensor element <b>100</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows the lead wires <b>111</b> to <b>113</b> only) are inserted into the through holes <b>502</b>. Connection terminals <b>116</b> for connecting the lead wires <b>111</b> to <b>115</b> to the external terminals of the gas sensor element <b>100</b> are accommodated in the through holes <b>502</b>. The lead wires <b>111</b> to <b>115</b> are connected to an unillustrated outside connector. Electrical signals are transmitted between the lead wires <b>111</b> to <b>115</b> and external equipment such as an ECU via the connector. Although not illustrated in detail, each of the lead wires <b>111</b> to <b>115</b> has a structure in which a conductor is covered with an insulative coating formed of resin.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Furthermore, a rubber cap <b>52</b> having a generally circular columnar shape is disposed on the rear side of the separator <b>50</b> so as to close a rear end opening <b>252</b> of the outer cover <b>25</b>. This rubber cap <b>52</b> is fixed to the outer cover <b>25</b> through a process of crimping the outer cover <b>25</b> radially inward in a state in which the rubber cap <b>52</b> is placed inside the rear end of the outer cover <b>25</b>. The rubber cap <b>52</b> also has through holes <b>521</b> extending from the front end to rear end thereof. The lead wires <b>111</b> to <b>115</b> are passed through the through holes <b>521</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In the gas sensor <b>200</b> of the present embodiment having the above-described structure, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b>, whose predominant component is zirconia that is higher in toughness than alumina, are formed on at least portions of the respective outer surfaces of the reinforcing protection layer <b>121</b> and the second insulating substrate <b>23</b> (in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the upper surface of the reinforcing protection layer <b>121</b> and the lower surface of the second insulating substrate <b>23</b>), which are the outermost layers of the laminate that constitutes the gas sensor element <b>100</b>, the portions facing the element passage member such as the metallic holder <b>34</b>, the ceramic holder <b>35</b>, the talc layer <b>36</b>, and the sleeve <b>39</b>. By virtue of this configuration, even in the case where, during firing of the gas sensor element <b>100</b>, debris of particles dropped from a setter for firing adheres to the surface of the gas sensor element <b>100</b> in an unfired state, a required breakage strength can be secured, whereby breakage of the gas sensor element <b>100</b> during assembly to the metallic shell <b>30</b> can be restrained. Also, when measurement is performed by use of the gas sensor <b>200</b>, due to vibration from an internal combustion engine or the like, the gas sensor element <b>100</b> may come into contact with the element passage member. However, since a required breakage strength can be secured through provision of the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b>, breakage of the gas sensor element <b>100</b> can be restrained.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Actually, two lots of gas sensor elements (each lot includes <b>30</b> gas sensor elements) were manufactured as each of Examples 1 to 8 and Comparative Example 1 (in total, 540 gas sensor elements were manufactured), and the breakage strength of each gas sensor element was measured. As Examples 1 to 8, there were manufacture gas sensor elements in which the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> were formed by applying the material of the layers one time (Examples 1 to 4) and gas sensor elements in which the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> were formed by applying the layer material two times (Examples 5 to 8). For one lot of the gas sensor elements manufactured as each of Examples 1 to 8 and Comparative Example 1, breakage strength was measured for the case where a foreign object equivalent to debris of particles dropped from the setter for firing adhered to the gas sensor elements. For the other lot of the gas sensor elements manufactured as each of Examples 1 to 8 and Comparative Example 1, breakage strength was measured for the case where a foreign object equivalent to debris of particles dropped from the setter for firing did not adhere to the gas sensor elements. Notably, a three-point bending test was employed so as to measure breakage strength. The three-point bending test was performed as follows. A span of 20 mm was set on each gas sensor element, and a gauge was lowered at a speed of 10 mm/min toward the center of the span (a portion where the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> were provided). A load value at the time when the gas sensor element was broken was obtained. The average load value was obtained for each of Examples and Comparative Example.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In the case where a foreign object equivalent to debris of particles dropped from the setter for firing adhered to the gas sensor elements, when the average breakage strength of Comparative Example 1 was considered 1, the average breakage strength of Examples 1 to 8 was about 1.09, and was about 9% higher than that of Comparative Example 1. As to the average breakage strength, there was no significant difference between Examples 1 to 4 (in which the layer material was applied one time) and Examples 5 to 8 (in which the layer material was applied two times).</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In the case where a foreign object equivalent to debris of particles dropped from the setter for firing did not adhere to the gas sensor elements, when the average breakage strength of Comparative Example 1 was considered 1, the average breakage strength of Examples 1 to 8 was about 1.15, and was about 15% higher than that of Comparative Example 1. As to the average breakage strength, there was no significant difference between Examples 1 to 4 (in which the layer material was applied one time) and Examples 5 to 8 (in which the layer material was applied two times).</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">As shown in the above-described Examples, it was confirmed that the gas sensor elements of Examples 1 to 8 which have the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> containing zirconia as a predominant component exhibit higher breakage strength as compared with those of Comparative Example 1 which do not have the coating layers.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Notably, in the present embodiment, the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> are not provided on the side surfaces (surfaces parallel to the lamination direction) of the laminate that constitutes the gas sensor element <b>100</b>. Since the width of the gas sensor element <b>100</b> is greater than the thickness thereof, a require breakage strength can be secured without provision of the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> on the surfaces parallel to the lamination direction. Therefore, even in the case where dropped particles or like debris is adhered to the surface of the gas sensor element <b>100</b> in an unfired state, breakage of the gas sensor element <b>100</b> can be retrained. Therefore, through omission of such coating layers, productivity is increased, and cost is lowered.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Notably, in the case where the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> were formed by applying the layer material one time, the thickness of the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> became about 10 &#x3bc;m, and, in the case where the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> were formed by applying the layer material two times, the thickness of the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> became about 20 &#x3bc;m. However, as to breakage strength, no difference was observed between the two cases. In consideration of the fact that the gas sensor element is inserted into the element passage member, the upper limit of the thickness of the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> must be set to about 50 &#x3bc;m. Therefore, preferably, the thickness of the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> falls within a range of 10 &#x3bc;m to 50 &#x3bc;m, inclusive.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> are formed of a material which is lower in thermal conductivity than the reinforcing protection layer <b>121</b> and the second insulating substrate <b>23</b>. Therefore, it is possible to reduce conduction of heat of the gas sensor element <b>100</b>, which is heated by the heater <b>2</b>, to the element passage member via the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b>. Thus, the amount of electric power supplied to the heater <b>2</b> can be reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Preferably, the difference in coefficient of thermal expansion between the coating layer <b>151</b> (<b>152</b>) and the reinforcing protection layer <b>121</b> or the second insulating substrate <b>23</b> is 0.7&#xd7;10<sup>&#x2212;6 </sup>or less. Thus, it is possible to prevent separation of the coating layer <b>151</b> (<b>152</b>) from the reinforcing protection layer <b>121</b> or the second insulating substrate <b>23</b>. Notably, in the present embodiment, the coefficient of thermal expansion of the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> is 8.7&#xd7;10<sup>&#x2212;6</sup>, and the coefficient of thermal expansion of the reinforcing protection layer <b>121</b> and the second insulating substrate <b>23</b> is 8.6&#xd7;10<sup>&#x2212;6</sup>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Since the predominant component of the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> is zirconia, the breakage strength of a portion on which the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> are provided can be increased. In addition, since zirconia is lower in volume resistivity than alumina. Therefore, generation of electrical leakage can be suppressed by not providing the above-mentioned coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> on the side surfaces (surfaces parallel to the lamination direction) of the laminate.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Although the present invention has been described on the basis of the above-described embodiment, the present invention is not limited to the embodiment, and may be modified freely without departing from the scope of the invention. For example, in the embodiment, the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> are formed of a material containing zirconia as a predominant component. However, the material of the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> is not limited thereto, and the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> may be mainly formed of a first material which is higher in toughness than alumina. For example, the first material may be those which are higher in toughness than alumina defined by JIS R 1607 (1990). More specifically, the coating layers <b>151</b> and <b>152</b> may be formed of a material whose predominant component is silicon nitride or silicon carbide.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In the above-described embodiment, the reinforcing protection layer <b>121</b> and the second insulating substrate <b>23</b> are formed of alumina. However, their may be formed of another material so long as the material contains alumina as a predominant component. The material may also contain zirconia and/or mullite.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The present invention can be applied to a laminate-type gas sensor element used in gas sensors other than the air-fuel-ratio sensor, such as an HC sensor, a CO sensor, and an NOx sensor.</p>
<heading id="h-0011" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF REFERENCE NUMERALS</heading>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056"><b>2</b> . . . heater; <b>3</b> . . . gas sensor element main body; <b>11</b> . . . solid electrolyte member; <b>13</b> . . . reference electrode; <b>14</b> . . . detection electrode; <b>21</b> . . . heating resistor; <b>23</b> . . . second insulating substrate; <b>100</b> . . . gas sensor element; <b>121</b> . . . reinforcing protection layer; <b>151</b>, <b>152</b> . . . coating layer; <b>153</b>, <b>154</b> . . . side surface; <b>200</b> . . . gas sensor</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A gas sensor comprising a plate-shaped laminate which is disposed in a housing and fixed thereto via an element passage member and which is formed by laminating a gas sensor element having a major dimension extending in a longitudinal direction and a heater having a heating element, the gas sensor element comprising:
<claim-text>a plate-shaped solid electrolyte member; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of detection electrodes formed on front and back surfaces of the solid electrolyte member and constituting, in cooperation with the solid electrolyte member, a detection section for detecting the concentration of a specific gas contained in an object gas, wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second insulating substrates containing alumina as predominant component are provided on opposite sides of the laminate with respect to the lamination direction thereof;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first insulating substrate is a protection layer comprising a reinforcing protection layer and a porous electrode protection layer, the porous electrode protection layer protecting the detection electrode formed on the front surface of the solid electrolyte member,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said reinforcing protection layer having a width equal to that of the solid electrolyte member in a direction perpendicular to the longitudinal direction of the gas sensor element,</claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second coating layers containing, as a predominant component, a first material which is higher in toughness than alumina are formed on at least portions of outer surfaces of the first and second insulating substrates with respect to the lamination direction, respectively, the portions facing the element passage member;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the coating layer formed on the first insulating substrate is formed throughout the entire width of the reinforcing protection layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the coating layers are not formed on surfaces of the laminate parallel to the lamination direction; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first and second insulating substrates are outermost members of the laminate and the first and second coating layers are directly formed on at least portions of outer surfaces of the first and second insulating substrates, respectively.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A gas sensor according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the thickness of the coating layers falls within a range of 10 &#x3bc;m to 50 &#x3bc;m.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A gas sensor according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the coating layers are formed of a material which is lower in thermal conductivity than the insulating substrates.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A gas sensor according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the coating layers are formed of a material selected such that the difference in coefficient of thermal expansion between the material and the insulating substrates becomes 0.7&#xd7;10<sup>&#x2212;6 </sup>or less.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A gas sensor according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the coating layers contain zirconia as a predominant component.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
