<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622678-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622678</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13275456</doc-number>
<date>20111018</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2011 2 0152605 U</doc-number>
<date>20110513</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>122</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>37</main-group>
<subgroup>14</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>411429</main-classification>
<further-classification>4113726</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Nut assembly</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>1900098</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Cooper</name>
<date>19330300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2202571</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5017068</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Cooksey</name>
<date>19910500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>411373</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5350266</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Espey et al.</name>
<date>19940900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>411431</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5480273</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Jou</name>
<date>19960100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>411373</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5586790</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Bynum</name>
<date>19961200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>285 89</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5624218</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Dauwalter</name>
<date>19970400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>411 87</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7713012</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Coonjohn</name>
<date>20100500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4113726</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>8</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>411431</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>411429</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4113725-373</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>411377</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>411119-121</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120288346</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121115</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liu</last-name>
<first-name>Cong</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liu</last-name>
<first-name>Cong</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Shenzhen Futaihong Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>FIH (Hong Kong) Limited</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Kowloon</city>
<country>HK</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Saether</last-name>
<first-name>Flemming</first-name>
<department>3677</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A nut assembly includes a nut and an carrier. The nut defines a number of latching grooves. The carrier includes a planar board and a number of flexible holding elements protruding from the planar board. Each flexible holding element is releasably latched in one of the latching grooves to latch the carrier to the nut. The carrier is capable of moving relative to the nut from a first state to a second state, so the flexible holding elements slide out of the latching grooves to release the carrier from the nut.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="120.06mm" wi="118.19mm" file="US08622678-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="180.51mm" wi="117.86mm" file="US08622678-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="212.51mm" wi="125.31mm" file="US08622678-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="176.45mm" wi="134.87mm" file="US08622678-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="207.77mm" wi="156.72mm" file="US08622678-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This disclosure relates to nut assemblies, particularly to a nut assembly with a carrier.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A nut is a type of hardware fastener with a threaded hole. Nuts are almost always used opposite a mating bolt to fasten a stack of parts together. In manufacture, the nut is carried by a vacuum suction cup, and then assembled with a nut hole or a mating bolt. However, the shapes of different nuts may be different, so there is a requirement of designing different vacuum suction cups, each of which has a shape according to one of the different nuts. Additionally, the nut defines a threaded hole so it is difficult to attach the nut by the vacuum suction cup if the vacuum suction cup is not aligned with the nut precisely.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Therefore, there is a room for improved in the art.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Many aspects of the embodiments can be better understood with reference to the following drawings. The components in the drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the exemplary nut assembly. Moreover, in the drawings like reference numerals designate their respective parts throughout the several views. Wherever possible, the same reference numbers are used throughout the drawings to refer to the same or like elements of an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view of an exemplary embodiment of a nut assembly in a first state.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exploded view of the nut assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is another schematic view of the nut assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in a second state.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic view of the nut assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> assembled to a circuit board.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, an exemplary embodiment of a nut assembly <b>30</b> includes a nut <b>10</b> and an carrier <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the nut <b>10</b> includes a main body <b>11</b> and a threaded hole <b>13</b> defined through the main body <b>11</b>. In this exemplary embodiment, the main body <b>11</b> is stepped, includes a first cylindrical body <b>112</b> and a second cylindrical body <b>114</b> protruding from an end of the first cylindrical body <b>112</b>. The first cylindrical body <b>112</b> is larger than the second cylindrical body <b>114</b> so a shoulder <b>116</b> is formed between the first cylindrical body <b>112</b> and the second cylindrical body <b>114</b>. The nut <b>10</b> further defines a plurality of latching grooves <b>16</b> for latching with the carrier <b>20</b>. In this exemplary embodiment, the latching grooves <b>16</b> are defined in an outer surface of the first cylindrical body <b>112</b> and extend through the shoulder <b>116</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The carrier <b>20</b> includes a planar board <b>21</b> and a plurality of flexible holding elements <b>22</b> protruding from the planar board <b>21</b> corresponding to the latching grooves <b>16</b>. The planar board <b>21</b> provides an attaching surface facilitating sucking the nut <b>10</b> by a vacuum suction cup <b>50</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>). A distal end of each flexible holding element <b>22</b> forms a hook <b>23</b>, which is latched in one of the latching grooves <b>16</b> to latch the carrier <b>20</b> to the nut <b>10</b> so the nut assembly <b>30</b> is in a first state shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. For reasons discussed below, the flexible holding elements do not completely surround the nut <b>10</b> and typically, should surround no more than 180 degrees of circumference.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, when the nut assembly <b>30</b> is in the first state, the planar board <b>21</b> is spaced from the nut <b>10</b> so a gap <b>12</b> is defined between the planar board <b>21</b> and the nut <b>10</b>. Thus, when the carrier <b>20</b> is pressed, the carrier <b>20</b> can move toward the nut <b>10</b> to slide the hooks <b>23</b> out of the latching grooves <b>16</b> so the nut assembly <b>30</b> is in a second state shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. Once the hooks <b>23</b> slide out of the latching grooves <b>16</b>, the latching engagement of the carrier <b>20</b> and the nut <b>10</b> is released, so the carrier <b>20</b> can be transversely removed from the nut <b>10</b> in the direction of arrow A.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, during assembling the nut <b>10</b> to a circuit board <b>60</b>. The vacuum suction cup <b>50</b> is aligned with and sucks the planar board <b>21</b> so the nut assembly <b>30</b> is sucked by the vacuum suction cup <b>50</b>. The nut assembly <b>30</b> is then positioned on the circuit board <b>60</b>. The vacuum suction cup <b>50</b> moves toward and drives the planar board <b>21</b> to move toward the nut <b>10</b>, until the hooks <b>23</b> slide out of the latching grooves <b>16</b> like shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. The vacuum suction cup <b>50</b> moves transversely to drive the carrier <b>20</b> to remove from the nut <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">It is to be further understood that even though numerous characteristics and advantages of the exemplary embodiments have been set forth in the foregoing description, together with details of structures and functions of various embodiments, the disclosure is illustrative only, and changes may be made in detail, especially in matters of shape, size, and arrangement of parts within the principles of the exemplary invention to the full extent indicated by the broad general meaning of the terms in which the appended claims are expressed.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A nut assembly comprising:
<claim-text>a nut including a main body, the main body defining a plurality of latching grooves;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a carrier including a planar board and a plurality of flexible holding elements protruding from the planar board;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein in a first state, each flexible holding element is latched in one of the latching grooves to latch the carrier to the nut; in a second state, the flexible holding elements slide out of the latching grooves to release the carrier from the nut;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the main body is stepped, includes a first cylindrical body and a second cylindrical body protruding from an end of the first cylindrical body; the first cylindrical body is larger than the second cylindrical body so a shoulder is formed between the first cylindrical body and the second cylindrical body; the latching grooves are defined in an outer surface of the first cylindrical body and extend through the shoulder.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The nut assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a distal end of each flexible holding element is bent inwardly to form a hook, which is latched in one of the latching grooves to latch the carrier to the nut.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The nut assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein when the nut assembly is in the first state, the planar board is spaced from the nut so a gap is defined between the carrier and the nut.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The nut assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein when the carrier is pressed, the carrier can move toward the nut to make the hooks slide out of the latching grooves until the nut assembly is in the second state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A nut assembly comprising:
<claim-text>a nut including a shoulder and defining a plurality of latching grooves, the latching grooves extending through the shoulder;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a carrier including a planar board and a plurality of flexible holding elements protruding from the planar board, each flexible holding element including a hook releasably latched in one of the latching grooves to latch the carrier to the nut;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the carrier is capable of moving relative to the nut from a first state to a second state, so the hooks of the flexible holding elements slide out of the latching grooves to release the carrier from the nut;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the nut includes a main body, the main body is stepped, includes a first cylindrical body and a second cylindrical body protruding from an end of the first cylindrical body; the first cylindrical body is larger than the second cylindrical body so the shoulder is formed between the first cylindrical body and the second cylindrical body; the latching grooves are defined in an outer surface of the first cylindrical body and extend through the shoulder.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The nut assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein a distal end of each flexible holding element is bent inwardly to form the hook, which is latched in one of the latching grooves to latch the carrier to the nut.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The nut assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein when the nut assembly is in the first state, the planar board is spaced from the nut so a gap is defined between the carrier and the nut.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The nut assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein when the carrier is pressed, the carrier can move toward the nut to make the hooks slide out of the latching grooves until the nut assembly is in the second state.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
