<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623299-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623299</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13119949</doc-number>
<date>20090917</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2008-247422</doc-number>
<date>20080926</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>65</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>10</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>422536</main-classification>
<further-classification>422 63</further-classification>
<further-classification>422 64</further-classification>
<further-classification>422 65</further-classification>
<further-classification>422 66</further-classification>
<further-classification>422 67</further-classification>
<further-classification>436180</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Tissue treating apparatus</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3892197</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kinney et al.</name>
<date>19750700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>118667</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>5849245</doc-number>
<date>19830400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>05149846</doc-number>
<date>19930600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>11271194</doc-number>
<date>19991000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2001124679</doc-number>
<date>20010500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00006">
<othercit>Sakura Seiki Co., Ltd., et al., International Search Report mailed Dec. 15, 2009 for PCT/JP2009/066251.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>8</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>422 50</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>422501-503</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>422536</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>422 63- 67</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>436180</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>12</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110171088</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110714</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Takahashi</last-name>
<first-name>Kenji</first-name>
<address>
<city>Chikuma</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Takahashi</last-name>
<first-name>Kenji</first-name>
<address>
<city>Chikuma</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Blakely Sokoloff Taylor &#x26; Zafman LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Sakura Seiki Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Nagano</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Sakura Finetek Japan Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Nagpaul</last-name>
<first-name>Jyoti</first-name>
<department>1773</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/JP2009/066251</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20090917</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20110318</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2010/035685</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20100401</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present invention solves a problem of conventional tissue treating apparatuses: liquid chemicals which have been used given times and have become useless in a tissue specimen infiltration treatment and a cleaning liquid which has been used given times and has decreased in cleaning ability are required to be separately discarded/replaces. The tissue treating apparatus (<b>10</b>), which supplies given liquid chemicals to and discharges the same from a processing chamber (<b>12</b>) containing a tissue specimen so as to perform the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, comprises: liquid-chemical reservoirs (<b>14, 16</b>) for storing the liquid chemicals to be used in the infiltration treatment; cleaning-liquid reservoirs (<b>19, 21</b>) for storing the liquid chemicals which have become useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment and which are usable as cleaning liquids for removing a residual liquid chemical remaining in the processing chamber (<b>12</b>); and cleaning means for supplying the liquid chemicals in the cleaning-liquid reservoirs (<b>19, 21</b>) to and discharging the same from the processing chamber (<b>12</b>) so as to clean the inside of the processing chamber (<b>12</b>).</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="159.17mm" wi="287.61mm" file="US08623299-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="270.09mm" wi="166.20mm" file="US08623299-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="176.19mm" wi="151.89mm" file="US08623299-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="158.24mm" wi="180.09mm" file="US08623299-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="270.43mm" wi="117.26mm" file="US08623299-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="267.21mm" wi="132.67mm" file="US08623299-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="169.84mm" wi="153.84mm" file="US08623299-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="265.94mm" wi="139.70mm" file="US08623299-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="194.82mm" wi="192.87mm" file="US08623299-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This is a non-provisional application claiming the benefit of International Patent Application No. PCT/JP2009/066251, filed Sep. 17, 2009.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF TECHNOLOGY</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a tissue-treating apparatus, more precisely relates to a tissue-treating apparatus, in which a tissue specimen infiltration treatment is performed by supplying different kinds or different concentrations of liquid chemicals to and discharging the same from a processing chamber, in which a tissue specimen is contained, in a predetermined order.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF TECHNOLOGY</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In hospitals and laboratories, tissue treating apparatuses, in each of which tissue specimens are automatically fixed, dehydrated, degreased, replaced and embedded in paraffin, are used for producing microscopic specimens of tissue specimens taken from living bodies.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">For example, a conventional tissue treating apparatus is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>. In the tissue treating apparatus shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, a main body of the apparatus includes: a processing chamber <b>102</b> accommodating baskets <b>100</b>, in which tissue specimens are contained; a plurality of liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>104</b><i>a</i>-<b>104</b><i>e </i>being mounted on a rack <b>104</b> and storing liquid chemicals, with sequentially different concentrations, for performing an infiltration treatment of the tissue specimens in the baskets <b>100</b>; and paraffin reservoirs <b>106</b><i>a </i>and <b>106</b><i>b </i>accommodated in a heat-retaining chamber <b>106</b>. As to the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>104</b><i>a</i>-<b>104</b><i>b</i>, concentrations of the liquid chemicals in the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>104</b><i>a</i>-<b>104</b><i>e </i>are <b>104</b><i>a</i>&#x3c;<b>104</b><i>b</i>&#x3c;<b>104</b><i>c</i>&#x3c;<b>104</b><i>d</i>&#x3c;<b>104</b><i>e </i>(numbers of times of using the liquid chemicals are <b>104</b><i>a</i>&#x3e;<b>104</b><i>b</i>&#x3e;<b>104</b><i>c</i>&#x3e;<b>104</b><i>d</i>&#x3e;<b>104</b><i>e</i>).</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Each of the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>104</b><i>a</i>-<b>104</b><i>e </i>and the paraffin reservoirs <b>106</b><i>a </i>and <b>106</b><i>b </i>is connected to a rotary valve <b>108</b> provided to the main body as a selection valve, and the rotary valve <b>108</b> is connected to the processing chamber <b>102</b> via an open/close valve <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">With this structure, each of the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>104</b><i>a</i>-<b>104</b><i>e </i>and the paraffin reservoirs <b>106</b><i>a </i>and <b>106</b><i>b </i>is selectively connected to the processing chamber <b>102</b> by the rotary valve <b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Further, inner pressure of the processing chamber <b>102</b> is increased and reduced by a pump <b>112</b>, and the liquid chemical or paraffin can be supplied to the processing chamber <b>102</b> from one of the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>104</b><i>a</i>-<b>104</b><i>e </i>and the paraffin reservoirs <b>106</b><i>a </i>and <b>106</b><i>b</i>, which is selected by the rotary valve <b>108</b>, in a state where the inner pressure of the processing chamber <b>12</b> is reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The liquid chemical or paraffin, which has been supplied to the processing chamber <b>102</b> and brought into contact with the tissue specimens in the basket <b>100</b>, is returned to the original reservoir by increasing the inner pressure of the processing chamber <b>102</b> by the pump <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Since the rotary valve <b>108</b>, the open/close valve <b>110</b> and the pump <b>112</b> are controlled by a control unit <b>114</b>, the tissue specimens are infiltrated in the given liquid chemicals and the paraffin according to a predetermined treatment sequence, which has been previously set in the control unit <b>114</b>, and then the tissue specimens are infiltrated in the paraffin.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In the tissue treating apparatus shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the residual paraffin, which remains in the processing chamber <b>102</b> after completing the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, is cleaned by using a cleaning liquid stored in a cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>107</b> as described in Patent Document 1. Each of the liquid chemicals used for the infiltration treatment may be used as the cleaning liquid.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Patent Document 1: Japanese Laid-open Patent Publication No. 5-149846</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In the tissue treating apparatus shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the residual paraffin, which remains in the processing chamber <b>102</b> after completing the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, can be cleaned and removed, and the tissue specimen infiltration treatment can be newly started in the processing chamber <b>102</b> in which no paraffin remains.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">However, in the tissue treating apparatus shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the cleaning liquid is separately stored, from the liquid chemicals, in the dedicated cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>107</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">If the liquid chemicals used in the tissue treating apparatus shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> are used given times, the liquid chemicals will badly influence the completed tissue specimens. Thus, the liquid chemicals which have been used given times are discarded and replaced with new chemicals (new liquid chemicals) so as to secure qualities of the completed tissue specimens.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Cleaning ability of the cleaning liquid is drastically decreased after using the cleaning liquid given times, so the cleaning liquid too is discarded and replaced with a new cleaning liquid.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">As described above, an operator must separately discard and replace the liquid chemicals for performing the tissue specimen infiltration treatment and the cleaning liquid for cleaning the processing chamber <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">From the viewpoint of resource saving, it is wasteful to immediately discard the liquid chemicals which have been used given times and have become useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">An object of the present invention is to provide a tissue treating apparatus, which is capable of: solving the problem of the conventional apparatus, i.e., liquid chemicals, which have been used given times and have become useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, and the cleaning liquid, which has been used given times and has decreased in cleaning ability, being required to be separately discarded/replaces; reusing the liquid chemicals, which have been used given times and have become useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment; and highly saving the trouble of discarding/replacing the liquid chemicals, which have become useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, and the cleaning liquid, which has decreased in the cleaning ability.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The inventor of the present invention has studied to solve the above described problems, thus he performed the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, in the processing chamber <b>102</b> of the tissue treating apparatus shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, in ethanol, xylene and paraffin in that order, and then the processing chamber <b>102</b> was cleaned by using the xylene to be discarded, which had been used given times, so that he found that the processing chamber <b>102</b> could be fully cleaned and he reached the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Namely, the tissue treating apparatus of the present invention, which supplies different kinds or different concentrations of liquid chemicals to and discharges the same, in a predetermined order, from a processing chamber containing a tissue specimen so as to perform a tissue specimen infiltration treatment, comprises: liquid-chemical reservoirs for storing the liquid chemicals to be used in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment; and a cleaning-liquid reservoir for storing liquid chemical which has become useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment and which is usable as a cleaning liquid for removing a residual liquid chemical remaining in the processing chamber, and cleaning means supplies the liquid chemical in the cleaning-liquid reservoir to and discharges the same from the processing chamber so as to clean the inside of the processing chamber.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The tissue treating apparatus may further comprise means for transferring the liquid chemical which has been used given times and have become useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment from the liquid-chemical reservoir to the cleaning-liquid reservoir. With this structure, the liquid chemical which has become useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment can be easily transferred to the cleaning-liquid reservoir.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The tissue treating apparatus may further comprise means for supplying the liquid chemical of an amount corresponding to an insufficiency of an amount of the cleaning liquid supplied from the liquid-chemical reservoir, in which the liquid chemical for the tissue specimen infiltration treatment is stored, when the amount of the cleaning liquid supplied from the cleaning-liquid reservoir to the processing chamber is insufficient. With this structure, the processing chamber can be continuously cleaned without discontinuation.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The tissue treating apparatus may further comprise means for discarding the liquid chemical from the cleaning-liquid reservoir to an external drain reservoir. With this structure, the cleaning liquid can be easily discarded from the cleaning-liquid reservoir to the external drain reservoir.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The tissue treating apparatus may further comprise: means for reducing inner pressure of the processing chamber; and means for heating the processing chamber. With this structure, the residual liquid chemical remaining in the processing chamber can be effective cleaned, and cleaning ability of the cleaning liquid can be improved by evaporating and removing low-boiling components.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The tissue treating apparatus may further comprise means for warming the liquid chemicals stored in the cleaning-liquid reservoirs. With this structure, the cleaning liquid supplied to the processing chamber can be warmed until reaching a predetermined temperature, so that an amount of time for cleaning the processing chamber can be shortened.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Further, in the tissue treating apparatus, ethanol, xylene and paraffin may be used as the liquid chemicals for the tissue specimen infiltration treatment performed in the processing chamber, and the liquid chemicals may be stored in the liquid-chemical reservoirs respectively; an ethanol cleaning liquid, which is the ethanol useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, may be stored in a first cleaning-liquid reservoir, and a xylene cleaning liquid, which is the xylene useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, may be stored in a second cleaning-liquid reservoir; and the cleaning means may firstly clean the inside of the processing chamber with the xylene cleaning liquid stored in the second cleaning-liquid reservoir, and then the cleaning means may clean the inside of the processing chamber with the ethanol cleaning liquid stored in the first cleaning-liquid reservoir. With this structure, the tissue specimen can be infiltration-treated, with ethanol, in the processing chamber from which paraffin and xylene have been sufficiently removed.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">EFFECTS OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In the tissue treating apparatus of the present invention, the liquid chemical, which has become useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment but is capable of removing the residual chemical remaining in the processing chamber, can be stored in the cleaning-liquid reservoir as the cleaning liquid. The cleaning liquid in the cleaning-liquid reservoir can be used to remove the residual liquid chemical.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In the present invention, the liquid chemicals which have become useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment can be used to clean the processing chamber, so that effective use of the liquid chemicals can be realized.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The tissue treating apparatus of the present invention has the liquid-chemical reservoirs, which store the liquid chemicals being useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, and the cleaning-liquid reservoir, which stores the used liquid chemical as the cleaning liquid. Therefore, the liquid chemical, which has become useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, can be transferred to the empty cleaning-liquid reservoir, from which the cleaning liquid has been discarded, so that discarding/replacing the cleaning liquid can be performed.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Therefore, in comparison with the conventional tissue treating apparatus in which the liquid chemicals being useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment and the cleaning liquid having a poor cleaning ability are separately discarded/replaced, the liquid chemicals and cleaning liquid can be easily discarded/replaced in the tissue treating apparatus of the present invention.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> includes a front view and a plan view of an embodiment of the tissue treating apparatus relating to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an explanation view explaining reinforcement of new liquid reservoirs of the tissue treating apparatus shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a systematic chart of the tissue treating apparatus shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is an explanation view of an infiltration treatment performed in the tissue treating apparatus shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an explanation view of a cleaning operation for cleaning a processing chamber <b>12</b> of the tissue treating apparatus shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is an explanation view explaining a supplementary operation which is performed when an amount of a cleaning liquid for cleaning the processing chamber <b>12</b> is insufficient.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is an explanation view explaining a discarding operation of xylene stored in a second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is an explanation view explaining a transferring operation, in which liquid chemicals are sequentially transferred to the liquid-chemical reservoirs, from which the liquid chemical has been transferred to the second liquid-chemical reservoir <b>21</b>, from other liquid-chemical reservoirs.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a schematic view of the conventional tissue treating apparatus.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">EMBODIMENTS OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">An embodiment of the tissue treating apparatus relating to the present invention is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> is a front view of the tissue treating apparatus, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> is a plan view of the tissue treating apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In the tissue treating apparatus shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a processing chamber <b>12</b>, in which baskets storing tissue specimens are accommodated, is opened and closed by a lid <b>12</b><i>a</i>. In the processing chamber <b>12</b>, moisture in the tissue specimens is replaced by ethanol, and then xylene is supplied to replace ethanol in the tissue specimens by xylene, further molten paraffin is supplied to replace xylene in the tissue specimens by paraffin.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Thus, a plurality of liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>14</b>, <b>14</b> . . . , in which ethanol to be supplied to the processing chamber <b>12</b>, with different concentrations, are stored, are arranged in a lowermost part of a main body of the apparatus including the processing chamber <b>12</b>. The ethanol having different concentrations are respectively stored in the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>14</b>, <b>14</b> . . . . And, a plurality of liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>16</b>, <b>16</b> . . . , in which xylene to be supplied to the processing chamber <b>12</b>, with different concentrations, are stored, are arranged in a second part above the lowermost part, in which the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>14</b>, <b>14</b> . . . are arranged. The xylene having different concentrations are respectively stored in the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>16</b>, <b>16</b> . . . .</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Further, a plurality of liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>18</b>, <b>18</b> . . . , in which molten paraffin to be supplied to the processing chamber <b>12</b> are stored respectively, are arranged in a third part above the second part, in which the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>16</b>, <b>16</b> . . . are arranged. The part accommodating the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>18</b>, <b>18</b> . . . is a heat-retaining chamber capable of maintaining a molten state of paraffin. Capacity of the rightmost liquid-chemical reservoir <b>18</b> of the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>18</b>, <b>18</b> . . . is larger than that of other liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>18</b>, <b>18</b> . . . , and molten paraffin is stored therein.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">An ethanol cleaning liquid, which is ethanol being useless in a tissue specimen infiltration treatment, is stored in a first cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>19</b> and a xylene cleaning liquid, which is xylene being useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, is stored in a second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b> as cleaning liquids for cleaning the inside of the processing chamber <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">A new chemical reservoir <b>15</b>, whose capacity is larger than that of the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>14</b>, <b>14</b> . . . (e.g., twice or three times as large as the capacity of the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>14</b>, <b>14</b> . . . ) and in which unused new ethanol (new liquid chemical) is stored, is integrally attached to one of sidewall faces of the main body; a new chemical reservoir <b>17</b>, whose capacity is larger than that of the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>16</b>, <b>16</b> . . . (e.g., twice or three times as large as the capacity of the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>16</b>, <b>16</b> . . . ) and in which unused new xylene (new chemical) is stored, is integrally attached to the other sidewall face of the main body. By integrally attaching the new chemical reservoirs <b>15</b> and <b>17</b> to the both sidewall faces, structural strength of the apparatus can be improved.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The new chemical reservoirs <b>15</b> and <b>17</b> have capacities larger than those of the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>14</b>, <b>14</b> . . . and <b>16</b>, <b>16</b> . . . , and they are slimmer than the liquid-chemical reservoirs. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, an inner wall face of each of the new chemical reservoirs <b>15</b> and <b>17</b> is reinforced by reinforcing members <b>20</b>, <b>20</b> . . . , which are bonded crosswise. By reinforcing the inner wall face with the reinforcing members <b>20</b>, <b>20</b> . . . , even if inner pressure of the new chemical reservoirs <b>15</b> and <b>17</b> are reduced when the new liquid chemicals are supplied to the new chemical reservoirs or the inner pressure (hydraulic head pressure) of the new chemical reservoirs are increased when prescribed amounts of ethanol and xylene are supplied to the new chemical reservoirs, deformation of the new chemical reservoirs <b>15</b> and <b>17</b> can be highly restrained.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Supply ports <b>22</b> and <b>24</b> for supplying the new liquid chemicals to the new chemical reservoirs <b>15</b> and <b>17</b> and a supply/discharge port <b>26</b> for supplying the liquid chemical to and discharging the same from the processing chamber <b>12</b> are provided in the front face of the main body of the tissue treating apparatus <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">A display unit <b>28</b> is provided on the upper face of the main body of the apparatus <b>10</b> so as to show treating states of the tissue specimens in the processing chamber <b>12</b>, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">A schematic diagram of the tissue treating apparatus <b>10</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>14</b><i>a</i>-<b>14</b><i>d </i>for storing ethanol and the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>16</b><i>a</i>-<b>16</b><i>d </i>for storing xylene are accommodated in the main body of the apparatus <b>10</b>. Further, the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>18</b><i>a</i>-<b>18</b><i>d </i>for storing molten paraffin are accommodated therein, the capacity of the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>18</b><i>d </i>is larger than those of the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>18</b><i>a</i>-<b>18</b><i>c </i>so as to refill the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>18</b><i>a</i>-<b>18</b><i>c</i>, in which molten paraffin of insufficient amounts have been stored, with the molten paraffin of the amount corresponding to the insufficiencies. When paraffin is supplied to the tissue treating apparatus, new paraffin is supply to the chemical reservoir <b>18</b><i>d. </i></p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The xylene cleaning liquid, which is the xylene being useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, is stored in the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b>, and the ethanol cleaning liquid, which is the ethanol being useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, is stored in the first cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>19</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a rotary valve <b>30</b>, which acts as a selection valve, is provided to the main body of the apparatus <b>10</b> so as to selectively connect the liquid-chemical reservoir, which is one selected from the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>14</b><i>a</i>-<b>14</b><i>d</i>, <b>16</b><i>a</i>-<b>16</b><i>d </i>and <b>18</b><i>a</i>-<b>18</b><i>d </i>and which stores the liquid-chemical with a prescribed concentration, to the processing chamber <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The rotary valve <b>30</b> connects the processing chamber <b>12</b> to the first cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>19</b> or the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Note that, the molten paraffin stored in the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>18</b><i>a</i>-<b>18</b><i>d </i>is supplied to the processing chamber <b>12</b>, so a heater <b>11</b> is provided to a bottom part of the processing chamber <b>12</b> in order to heat the processing chamber <b>12</b> and maintain the molten state of the paraffin.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In the tissue treating apparatus shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, concentrations of ethanol stored in the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>14</b><i>a</i>-<b>14</b><i>d </i>are <b>14</b><i>a</i>&#x3c;<b>14</b><i>b</i>&#x3c;<b>14</b><i>c</i>&#x3c;<b>14</b><i>d</i>. Numbers of times of infiltrating tissue specimens in the ethanol stored in the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>14</b><i>a</i>-<b>14</b><i>d </i>and amounts of impurities, e.g., water, fat, remaining therein are <b>14</b><i>a</i>&#x3e;<b>14</b><i>b</i>&#x3e;<b>14</b><i>c</i>&#x3e;<b>14</b><i>d. </i></p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Concentrations of xylene stored in the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>16</b><i>a</i>-<b>16</b><i>d </i>are <b>16</b><i>a</i>&#x3c;<b>16</b><i>b</i>&#x3c;<b>16</b><i>c</i>&#x3c;<b>16</b><i>d </i>due to interfusion of ethanol.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>18</b><i>a</i>-<b>18</b><i>d </i>are arranged in the heat-retaining chamber, and concentrations of molten paraffin stored therein are <b>18</b><i>a</i>&#x3c;<b>18</b><i>b</i>&#x3c;<b>18</b><i>c</i>&#x3c;<b>18</b><i>d</i>. Numbers of times of infiltrating tissue specimens in the paraffin stored in the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>18</b><i>a</i>-<b>18</b><i>d </i>and amounts of xylene interfused therein are <b>18</b><i>a</i>&#x3e;<b>18</b><i>b</i>&#x3e;<b>18</b><i>c</i>&#x3e;<b>18</b><i>d. </i></p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">An open/close valve <b>32</b> is provided midway between a pipe <b>31</b>, which is connected to a bottom face of the processing chamber <b>12</b> and the rotary valve <b>30</b>, and a pipe <b>33</b> is connected to the open/close valve <b>32</b> and the upper part of the processing chamber <b>12</b>. The open/close valve <b>32</b> is a three-way valve capable of connecting the pipe <b>31</b> to the rotary valve <b>30</b> and connecting the pipe <b>33</b> to the rotary valve <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">A pump <b>34</b> is capable of increasing and reducing inner pressure of the processing chamber <b>12</b>, and the liquid chemical or the cleaning liquid can be supplied to the processing chamber <b>12</b> from the prescribed liquid-chemical reservoir or cleaning-liquid reservoir, which has been selected by the rotary valve <b>30</b>, by reducing the inner pressure of the processing chamber <b>12</b> by the pump <b>34</b> and connecting the prescribed liquid-chemical reservoir or cleaning-liquid reservoir to the pipe <b>33</b> by the open/close valve <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">On the other hand, the liquid chemical stored in the processing chamber <b>12</b> can be sent to the prescribed liquid-chemical reservoir, which has been selected by the rotary valve <b>30</b>, by increasing the inner pressure of the processing chamber <b>12</b> by the pump <b>34</b> and connecting the prescribed liquid-chemical reservoir to the pipe <b>31</b> by the open/close valve <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Therefore, the processing chamber <b>12</b>, the pump <b>34</b>, the rotary valve <b>30</b> and the open/close valve <b>32</b> can be used as means for transferring the liquid chemicals between the liquid-chemical reservoirs or between the liquid-chemical reservoirs and the cleaning-liquid reservoirs. Namely, after the liquid chemical stored in one of the liquid-chemical reservoirs is completely supplied to the processing chamber <b>12</b> via the rotary valve <b>30</b>, the liquid chemical stored in the processing chamber <b>12</b> can be transferred to another liquid-chemical reservoir or cleaning-liquid reservoir.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Note that, the pump <b>34</b> is capable of sucking air through a filter <b>37</b> and discharging a gas including liquid chemicals from the processing chamber <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The processing chamber <b>12</b> has a detection sensor <b>36</b> for detecting that a prescribed amount of liquid chemical is supplied thereto. The detection sensor <b>36</b> is constituted by a level-securing sensor <b>36</b><i>a </i>and an upper limit sensor <b>36</b><i>b</i>. The level-securing sensor <b>36</b><i>a </i>is used for securing the amount of the liquid chemical in the processing chamber <b>12</b> so as to fully infiltrate the tissue specimens in the liquid chemical; the upper limit sensor <b>36</b><i>b </i>is used for detecting upper limit of the amount of the liquid chemical stored in the processing chamber <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The new chemical reservoirs <b>15</b> and <b>17</b> are respectively integrally attached to the both sidewall faces of the main body including the liquid-chemical reservoirs, the cleaning-liquid reservoirs, the rotary valve <b>30</b>, the open/close valve <b>32</b>, etc. The capacity of the new chemical reservoir <b>15</b> is twice or three times as large as that of the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>14</b><i>a</i>-<b>14</b><i>d</i>, and unused new ethanol is stored therein. The unused new ethanol can be supplied to the new chemical reservoir <b>15</b> via the supply port <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The capacity of the new chemical reservoir <b>17</b> is twice or three times as large as that of the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>16</b><i>a</i>-<b>16</b><i>d</i>, and unused new xylene is stored therein. The unused new xylene can be supplied to the new chemical reservoir <b>17</b> via the supply port <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Pressure equalizing lines are provided between the processing chamber <b>12</b> and the new chemical reservoirs <b>15</b> and <b>17</b>, and open/close valves <b>54</b> and <b>56</b> are respectively provided to the pressure equalizing lines.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The chemicals in the new chemical reservoirs <b>15</b> and <b>17</b> are evaporated by outside air temperature, so inner pressures of the new chemical reservoirs <b>15</b> and <b>17</b> are increased. To keep the inner pressures, which are increased by the evaporating gas, below a prescribed pressure, safety valves <b>40</b> and <b>42</b> are provided and the evaporating gas is discharged through the filter <b>37</b> to get rid of foul odor.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the tissue treating apparatus <b>10</b> has a control unit <b>38</b> for controlling the rotary valve <b>30</b>, the open/close valve <b>32</b> and the pump <b>34</b>. The control unit <b>38</b> firstly infiltrates the tissue specimens, which have been contained in the processing chamber <b>12</b>, in ethanol so as to replace moisture and fat in the tissue specimens by ethanol. The tissue specimens are infiltrated in ethanol by the steps of: firstly supplying ethanol from the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>14</b><i>a </i>to the processing chamber <b>12</b>; and sequentially supplying ethanol from the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>14</b><i>b</i>, <b>14</b><i>c </i>and <b>14</b><i>d </i>to perform the tissue specimen infiltration treatment therein.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">Next, the tissue specimens, which have been infiltration-treated in ethanol, are infiltrated in xylene so as to replace ethanol in the tissue specimens by xylene. Firstly, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the control unit <b>38</b> supplies xylene from the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>16</b><i>a </i>to the processing chamber <b>12</b> containing baskets <b>50</b>, in which the tissue specimens have been contained, so as to infiltrate the tissue specimens in xylene. Then, xylene stored in the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>16</b><i>b</i>, <b>16</b><i>c </i>and <b>16</b><i>d </i>are sequentially supplied to the processing chamber <b>12</b> so as to perform the infiltration treatment.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">Next, the tissue specimens, which are stored in the processing chamber <b>12</b> and which have been infiltration-treated in xylene, are infiltrated in paraffin by sequentially supplying molten paraffin from the liquid-chemical reservoirs <b>18</b><i>a</i>-<b>18</b><i>d </i>to the processing chamber <b>12</b>. The xylene in the tissue specimens can be replaced by paraffin by the sequential infiltration in the molten paraffin.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">After completing the infiltration treatment of the tissue specimens performed in paraffin, residual solids of paraffin are left in the processing chamber <b>12</b>, so the inside of the processing chamber <b>12</b> is cleaned by using a xylene cleaning liquid stored in the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b>. The xylene, which has been used given times and has become useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, is used as the xylene cleaning liquid. The xylene cleaning liquid includes ethanol from the tissue specimens, moisture therefrom, fragments of the tissue specimens, etc., but it has a sufficient cleaning (dissolving) ability for cleaning (dissolving) residual paraffin in the processing chamber <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">When the inside of the processing chamber <b>12</b> is cleaned by the cleaning liquid stored in the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b>, the xylene cleaning liquid stored in the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b> is supplied to the processing chamber <b>12</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. Firstly, the control unit <b>38</b> actuates the pump <b>34</b> to reduce the inner pressure of the processing chamber <b>12</b>, and then the xylene cleaning liquid stored in the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b> is supplied to the processing chamber <b>12</b> via the rotary valve <b>30</b> and the open/close valve <b>32</b>. While cleaning the processing chamber, the processing chamber <b>12</b> is heated by the heater <b>11</b>, which is provided to an outer bottom face, so that the residual liquid chemical in the processing chamber <b>12</b> can be effectively removed and the cleaning ability of the xylene cleaning liquid can be improved by evaporating low-boiling components of ethanol, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">The xylene cleaning liquid, which has been used to clean the processing chamber <b>12</b> for a predetermined time, is returned to the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b>, via the open/close valve <b>32</b> and the rotary valve <b>30</b>, by actuating the pump <b>34</b> to increase the inner pressure of the processing chamber <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">Preferably, a heater is provided on an outer face of the second cleaning liquid reservoir <b>21</b> so as not to deposit paraffin in the second cleaning liquid reservoir <b>21</b>, because xylene including residual paraffin remained in the processing chamber <b>12</b> is stored in the second cleaning liquid reservoir <b>21</b>. By maintaining temperature of the xylene cleaning liquid, at given treatment temperature, in the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b>, a heating time of the heater <b>11</b>, which heats the processing chamber <b>12</b>, can be shortened.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">After cleaning the inside of the processing chamber <b>12</b> by the xylene cleaning liquid stored in the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b>, residual xylene in the processing chamber <b>12</b> is removed by an ethanol cleaning liquid stored in the first cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>19</b>. The ethanol cleaning liquid is constituted by ethanol which has been used given times and has become useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment. The ethanol cleaning liquid includes moisture from the tissue specimens, fragments of the tissue specimens, etc., but it has a sufficient cleaning (dissolving) ability for cleaning (dissolving) residual xylene in the processing chamber <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">When the inside of the processing chamber <b>12</b> is cleaned by the ethanol cleaning liquid stored in the first cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>19</b>, the control unit <b>38</b> of the cleaning means actuates the pump <b>34</b> to reduce the inner pressure of the processing chamber <b>12</b>, and then the ethanol cleaning liquid stored in the first cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>19</b> is supplied to the processing chamber <b>12</b> via the rotary valve <b>30</b> and the open/close valve <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The ethanol cleaning liquid, which has been used to clean the processing chamber <b>12</b> for a predetermined time, is returned to the first cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>19</b>, via the open/close valve <b>32</b> and the rotary valve <b>30</b>, by actuating the pump <b>34</b> to increase the inner pressure of the processing chamber <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">The processing chamber <b>12</b>, in which the tissue specimens have been infiltrated in molten paraffin, is cleaned by the xylene cleaning liquid stored in the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b>, and then the processing chamber is cleaned by the ethanol cleaning liquid stored in the first cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>19</b>, so new tissue specimens can be newly infiltration-treated, in the processing chamber <b>12</b>, by ethanol, xylene and molten paraffin sequentially.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">When the xylene cleaning liquid stored in the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b> is supplied to the processing chamber <b>12</b>, if the xylene cleaning liquid does not reach the level-securing sensor <b>36</b><i>a </i>as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref>, the control unit <b>38</b> actuates the rotary valve <b>30</b> and the pump <b>34</b> so as to supply xylene from the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>16</b><i>a</i>, in which the lowest-concentration xylene is stored, to the processing chamber <b>12</b>. With this operation, the processing chamber <b>12</b> can be continuously cleaned by xylene, and new tissue specimens can be infiltration-treated, after cleaning the processing chamber, by ethanol stored in the first cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>19</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">Note that, when the new tissue specimens are infiltration-treated, an amount of the liquid chemical supplied from the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>16</b><i>a </i>to the processing chamber <b>12</b> is insufficient as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref> because xylene stored in the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>16</b><i>a </i>has been used for cleaning. In this case, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref>, new xylene of an amount corresponding to the insufficiency is supplied to the processing chamber <b>12</b> from the new chemical reservoir <b>17</b>, so that the tissue specimen infiltration treatment can be continued.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6A</figref> and B show the infiltration treatment in xylene, control for performing the infiltration treatment in ethanol is similar to that in xylene, so detailed explanation will be omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">The xylene cleaning liquid stored in the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b> is discarded after it has been used given times to clean the processing chamber <b>12</b> or the liquid chemical (xylene) stored in the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>16</b><i>a </i>has been used given times to perform the tissue specimen infiltration treatment.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">Similarly, the ethanol cleaning liquid stored in the first cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>19</b> is discarded after it has been used given times to clean the processing chamber <b>12</b> or the liquid chemical (ethanol) stored in the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>14</b><i>a </i>has been used given times to perform the tissue specimen infiltration treatment.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">In the tissue treating apparatus <b>10</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref>, after the ethanol cleaning liquid stored in the first cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>19</b> or the xylene cleaning liquid stored in the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b> is discarded outside, xylene or ethanol which has been used given times and has become useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment is reused as the cleaning liquid. In comparison with the conventional tissue treating apparatus in which the cleaning liquid and the liquid chemicals being useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment are discarded, the tissue treating apparatus <b>10</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref> is capable of reducing amounts of the liquid chemicals discarded and discarding the liquid chemicals easily.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">Discarding the cleaning liquid from the cleaning-liquid reservoir will be explained with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is an explanation view showing a discarding operation of xylene stored in the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, an end of a tube extended from a drain reservoir <b>60</b> located outside of the tissue treating apparatus <b>10</b> is connected to a supply/discharge port <b>26</b>, which constitutes discarding means and which is provided to a front face of the tissue treating apparatus <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">Next, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the pump and the rotary valve <b>30</b>, which constitute the discarding means, are actuated so as to supply all of the xylene cleaning liquid from the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b> to the processing chamber <b>12</b> to clean the processing chamber <b>12</b>, and then all of the cleaning liquid in the processing chamber <b>12</b> is discharged to the drain reservoir <b>60</b> via the rotary valve <b>30</b>, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">By discharging all of the cleaning liquid from the processing chamber <b>12</b>, the processing chamber <b>12</b> gets empty. The-most used liquid chemical (xylene) is transferred from the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>16</b><i>a </i>to the empty second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b> as the cleaning liquid. The liquid chemical is transferred by the above described transferring means. Firstly, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</figref>, all of the liquid chemical (xylene) in the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>16</b><i>a </i>is supplied to the processing chamber <b>12</b> to perform the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, and then the liquid chemical in the processing chamber <b>12</b> is discharged to the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b>, so that the liquid chemical in the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>16</b><i>a </i>can be transferred to the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">By transferring the all of the liquid chemical in the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>16</b><i>a </i>to the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b>, the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>16</b><i>a </i>gets empty, but the tissue specimen infiltration treatment is performed, in the processing chamber <b>12</b>, by supplying the second-most-used liquid chemical from the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>16</b><i>b</i>, whose number of times being used is next to that of the liquid chemical stored in the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>16</b><i>a</i>, to the processing chamber <b>12</b> instead of the liquid chemical stored in the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>16</b><i>a</i>. Further, the tissue specimen infiltration treatment is performed by using the liquid chemical stored in the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>16</b><i>c </i>instead of the liquid chemical stored in the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>16</b><i>b</i>, and the tissue specimen infiltration treatment is performed by using the liquid chemical stored in the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>16</b><i>d </i>instead of the liquid chemical stored in the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>16</b><i>c</i>. Therefore, the tissue specimen infiltration treatment is performed by supplying the new liquid chemical (xylene) from the new chemical reservoir <b>17</b> to the processing chamber <b>12</b> instead of the liquid chemical stored in the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>16</b><i>d </i>as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8B</figref>. The liquid chemical used in the infiltration treatment is transferred to the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>16</b><i>d. </i></p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">Note that, the discarding operation of the first cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>19</b> and the transferring operation for transferring the liquid chemical from the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>14</b><i>a </i>to the first cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>19</b> are similar to the discarding operation of the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b> and the transferring operation for transferring the liquid chemical from the liquid-chemical reservoir <b>16</b><i>a </i>to the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b>, so explanation will be omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">In the above described tissue treating apparatus, when the liquid chemicals are transferred to the first cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>19</b> and the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b> from the liquid-chemical reservoirs or when the cleaning liquids stored in the first cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>19</b> and the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b> are discarded, the liquid chemicals and the cleaning liquids are transferred via the processing chamber <b>12</b>, but they may be transferred, without passing through the processing chamber <b>12</b>, via chemical transfer tubes or drain tubes.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">In the above described embodiment, the cleaning liquids stored in the first cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>19</b> and the second cleaning-liquid reservoir <b>21</b>, which are used for cleaning the processing chamber <b>12</b>, are the liquid chemicals which have been used given times in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment performed in the processing chamber <b>12</b>, further they may be used to clean the processing chamber <b>12</b> when the tissue treating apparatus which has been stopped is restarted.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A tissue treating apparatus, which supplies different kinds or different concentrations of liquid chemicals to and discharges the same, in a predetermined order, from a processing chamber containing a tissue specimen so as to perform a tissue specimen infiltration treatment, comprising:
<claim-text>a processing chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of liquid-chemical reservoirs operable to store liquid chemicals to be used in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cleaning-liquid reservoir operable to store a used liquid chemical which is a liquid chemical that has become useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment and which is usable as a cleaning liquid for removing a residual liquid chemical remaining in the processing chamber; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a valve operable to transfer (1) a liquid chemical from one of the plurality of liquid chemical reservoirs or a used liquid chemical from the cleaning-liquid reservoir to the processing chamber, and (2) a used liquid chemical from one of the plurality of liquid-chemical reservoirs to the cleaning-liquid reservoir.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The tissue treating apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising means for supplying a liquid chemical in an amount corresponding to an insufficiency of an amount of used liquid chemical supplied from the cleaning-liquid reservoir from one of the liquid chemical reservoirs in which the liquid chemical for the tissue specimen infiltration treatment is stored, when the amount of the used liquid chemical supplied from the cleaning-liquid reservoir to the processing chamber is insufficient.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The tissue treating apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, further comprising means for warming the liquid chemical stored in the cleaning-liquid reservoir.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The tissue treating apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein ethanol, xylene and paraffin are used as the liquid chemicals for the tissue specimen infiltration treatment performed in the processing chamber, and the liquid chemicals are stored in the liquid-chemical reservoirs respectively,
<claim-text>wherein an ethanol cleaning liquid, which is the ethanol useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, is stored in a first cleaning-liquid reservoir, and a xylene cleaning liquid, which is the xylene useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, is stored in a second cleaning-liquid reservoir, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the valve is firstly operable to the xylene cleaning liquid stored in the second cleaning-liquid reservoir, and then the ethanol cleaning liquid stored in the first cleaning-liquid reservoir.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The tissue treating apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein ethanol, xylene and paraffin are used as the liquid chemicals for the tissue specimen infiltration treatment performed in the processing chamber, and the liquid chemicals are stored in the liquid-chemical reservoirs respectively,
<claim-text>wherein an ethanol cleaning liquid, which is the ethanol useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, is stored in a first cleaning-liquid reservoir, and a xylene cleaning liquid, which is the xylene useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, is stored in a second cleaning-liquid reservoir, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the valve is firstly operable to transfer the xylene cleaning liquid stored in the second cleaning-liquid reservoir, and then the ethanol cleaning liquid stored in the first cleaning-liquid reservoir.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The tissue treating apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising means for warming the liquid chemical stored in the cleaning-liquid reservoir.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The tissue treating apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein ethanol, xylene and paraffin are used as the liquid chemicals for the tissue specimen infiltration treatment performed in the processing chamber, and the liquid chemicals are stored in the liquid-chemical reservoirs respectively,
<claim-text>wherein an ethanol cleaning liquid, which is the ethanol useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, is stored in a first cleaning-liquid reservoir, and a xylene cleaning liquid, which is the xylene useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, is stored in a second cleaning-liquid reservoir, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the valve is firstly operable to transfer the xylene cleaning liquid stored in the second cleaning-liquid reservoir, and then the ethanol cleaning liquid stored in the first cleaning-liquid reservoir.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The tissue treating apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein ethanol, xylene and paraffin are used as the liquid chemicals for the tissue specimen infiltration treatment performed in the processing chamber, and the liquid chemicals are stored in the liquid-chemical reservoirs respectively,
<claim-text>wherein an ethanol cleaning liquid, which is the ethanol useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, is stored in a first cleaning-liquid reservoir, and a xylene cleaning liquid, which is the xylene useless in the tissue specimen infiltration treatment, is stored in a second cleaning-liquid reservoir, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the valve is firstly operable to transfer the xylene cleaning liquid stored in the second cleaning-liquid reservoir, and then the ethanol cleaning liquid stored in the first cleaning-liquid reservoir. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
