<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626318-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626318</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13187662</doc-number>
<date>20110721</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2011 1 0041733</doc-number>
<date>20110218</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>255</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>01</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>700 11</main-classification>
<further-classification>315113</further-classification>
<further-classification>362 86</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Lamp device</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0179578</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Albert et al.</name>
<date>20030900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362276</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0116179</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Aguirre et al.</name>
<date>20050600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2504921</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0185398</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Scannell, Jr.</name>
<date>20050800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362227</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0228999</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kit</name>
<date>20071000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>315291</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0230197</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Scannell, Jr.</name>
<date>20071000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362418</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0268687</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Scannell, Jr.</name>
<date>20071100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362154</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0273290</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ashdown et al.</name>
<date>20071100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>315113</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0073694</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Scannell, Jr.</name>
<date>20090300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362253</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0196016</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Massara et al.</name>
<date>20090800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362 86</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0096993</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ashdown et al.</name>
<date>20100400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>315113</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>11</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>700 11</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>315113</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362 86</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120215325</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120823</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wu</last-name>
<first-name>Chih-Yen</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wu</last-name>
<first-name>Chih-Yen</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Rosenberg, Klein &#x26; Lee</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Lite-On Electronics (Guangzhou) Limited</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Guangzhou</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Lite-On Technology Corp.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Ali</last-name>
<first-name>Mohammad</first-name>
<department>2127</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Whittington</last-name>
<first-name>Anthony</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A lamp device is controllable by a control terminal, and includes a light-emitting module, a driving circuit for driving the light-emitting module, a control unit for controlling duty cycle of the driving circuit, a first connector electrically coupled to the control unit, and a communication module. The communication module includes a second connector pluggably coupled to the first connector. The communication module is adapted to receive a control command from the control terminal and transmits the control command to the control unit via the first and second connectors, such that the control unit controls the driving circuit in accordance with the control command.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="107.70mm" wi="157.56mm" file="US08626318-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="196.68mm" wi="161.46mm" file="US08626318-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="210.23mm" wi="154.86mm" file="US08626318-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="118.96mm" wi="119.63mm" file="US08626318-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority of Chinese Application No. 201110041733.6, filed on Feb. 18, 2011.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to a lamp device, more particularly to a lamp device with an interchangeable communication module.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Currently, light-emitting diode (LED) lamp devices have be come more popular owing to maturity of technology. Advantages of the LED lamp device, such as long service time and high controllability, encourages communication control technology for lamp devices, such as infrared, Zigbee, Digital Addressable Lighting Interface (DALI), or power line, to flourishingly develop. A controller of a conventional LED lamp device may wiredly or wirelessly communicate with a control terminal through a communication interface, so as to control luminance and color temperature of a LED lamp in the LED lamp device in accordance with a control command from the control terminal. However, the communication interface and the controller of the conventional LED lamp device are usually inseparably disposed (or disposed on the same circuit board). Therefore, when a user wants to adopt a new communication protocol for controlling the LED lamp device (i.e., to change a way for communication with the control terminal) the user has to replace the whole LED lamp device since the communication interface and the controller of the LED lamp device are inseparable and since firmware for configuring the controller is incompatible with the new communication protocol. It will cost the user a lot of money to replace the whole LED lamp device, and it is a waste of resources to replace the LED lamp device which is still usable especially in view of environmental protection awareness.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Therefore, an object of the present invention is to provide a lamp device that is compatible with different communication protocols by merely replacing communication interfaces thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Accordingly, a lamp device of the present invention is controllable by a control terminal. The lamp device includes a light-emitting module, a driving circuit, a control unit, a first connector and a communication module. The driving circuit is electrically coupled to the light-emitting module for driving the light-emitting module. The control unit is electrically coupled to the driving circuit for controlling duty cycle of the driving circuit. The first connector is electrically coupled to the control unit. The communication module includes a second connector pluggably coupled to the first connector. The communication module is adapted to receive a control command from the control terminal and transmits the control command to the control unit via the first and second connectors, such that the control unit controls the driving circuit in accordance with the control command. The communication module stores a communication module type to which the communication module belongs and a firmware corresponding to the communication module type stored in the communication module. The firmware includes instructions for executing the control command so as to generate a pulse-width modulation signal for controlling the driving circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The control unit is configured with a firmware set corresponding to different communication module types.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">When the second connector of the communication module is electrically coupled to the first connector, the communication module is configured to send a notification signal for notifying the control unit, and the control unit sends an identification command for requesting the communication module to respond with the communication module type stored in the communication module.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">When the control unit determines that the communication module type of the communication module is not supported by the firmware set of the control unit, the control unit is configured to download firmware corresponding to the communication module type from the communication module.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Preferably, the communication module further includes a micro controller coupled to the second connector, and a signal receiving unit coupled to the micro controller. The signal receiving unit is adapted to receive the control command from the control terminal. The micro controller transforms a format of the control command received from the signal receiving unit into a signal format conforming to the first connector and the second connector prior to transmitting the control command to the second connector.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Preferably, the signal format is an I<sup>2</sup>C signal format, and the first connector and the second connector are I<sup>2</sup>C interfaces.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Preferably, the communication module is selected from an infrared communication module, a Zigbee communication module, a Digital Addressable Lighting Interface (DALI) communication module, and a power line communication module.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Preferably, the light-emitting module is a light-emitting diode module including a plurality of light-emitting diodes.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Preferably, the lamp device further includes a housing that receives the driving circuit, the control unit and the first connector, and that has an opening aligned with the first connector. The communication module is disposed in the housing via the opening to couple electrically the first and second connectors. The housing further has a cover disposed at the opening for concealing the communication module in the housing.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Other features and advantages of the present invention will become apparent in the fol lowing detailed description of the preferred embodiment with reference to the accompanying drawings, of which:</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram illustrating a preferred embodiment of a lamp device of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram illustrating a communication module of the preferred embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a flow chart of the preferred embodiment illustrating an interactive process between the lamp device and the communication module when the communication module is pluggably coupled to the lamp device; and</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a perspective view of the lamp device of the preferred embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a block diagram of a preferred embodiment of a lamp device <b>1</b> of the present invention is illustrated. The lamp device <b>1</b> is for pluggable and electrical connection to a communication module <b>2</b> so as to receive a control command from a control terminal <b>3</b> through the communication module <b>2</b>. The lamp device <b>1</b> includes a light-emitting module <b>11</b>, a driving circuit <b>12</b> electrically coupled to the light-emitting module <b>11</b> for driving the light-emitting module <b>11</b>, a control unit <b>13</b> electrically coupled to the driving circuit <b>12</b> for controlling duty cycle of the driving circuit <b>12</b>, and a first connector <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In this embodiment, the light-emitting module <b>11</b> is a light-emitting diode module including a plurality of light-emitting diodes, but is not limited to the disclosure herein. The driving circuit <b>12</b> is a pulse-width modulation driving circuit and is electrically coupled to the light-emitting module <b>11</b>. The driving circuit <b>12</b> adjusts duty cycle thereof for driving the light-emitting module <b>11</b> in accordance with a pulse-width modulation signal, so as to control luminance or color temperature of the light-emitting module <b>11</b>. The control unit <b>13</b> is electrically coupled to the driving circuit <b>12</b>, and outputs the pulse-width modulation signal for controlling duty cycle of the driving circuit <b>12</b>. The first connector <b>14</b> is electrically coupled to the control unit <b>13</b> so as to transmit the control command from the control terminal <b>3</b> to the control unit <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The communication module <b>2</b> is pluggably and electrically coupled to the lamp device <b>1</b>. The communication module <b>2</b> includes a second connector <b>21</b> pluggably coupled to the first connector <b>14</b>, a micro controller <b>22</b> coupled to the second connector <b>21</b>, and a signal receiving unit <b>23</b> coupled to the micro controller <b>22</b>. The signal receiving unit <b>23</b> is adapted to receive the control command from the control terminal <b>3</b>. In this embodiment, the first connector <b>14</b> and the second connector <b>21</b> are I<sup>2</sup>C interfaces. Therefore, the micro controller <b>22</b> transforms a format of the control command received from the signal receiving unit <b>23</b> into a I<sup>2</sup>C signal format conforming to the first connector <b>14</b> and the second connector <b>21</b> prior to transmitting the control command to the second connector <b>21</b>. The micro controller <b>22</b> of the communication module <b>2</b> stores a communication module type to which the communication module <b>2</b> belongs and a firmware corresponding to the communication module type stored in the communication module <b>2</b>. The firmware includes instructions for executing the control command so as to generate the pulse-width modulation signal for controlling the driving circuit <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In this embodiment, the communication module <b>2</b> may belong to different communication module types (such as infrared, Zigbee, DALI, and power line) for matching different communication protocols used by the control terminal <b>3</b>. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, if a control terminal A transmits a control command through infrared, the communication module <b>2</b> matched with the control terminal A is an infrared communication module A&#x2032;. If a control terminal B transmits a control command through Zigbee technology, the communication module <b>2</b> matched with the control terminal B is a Zigbee communication module If a control terminal C transmits a control command through Digital Addressable Lighting Interface (DALI) technology, the communication module <b>2</b> matched with the control terminal C is a DALI communication module C&#x2032;. Further, the communication module <b>2</b> may be a power line communication module D&#x2032; which communicates with a control terminal D through a power line <b>20</b>. Specifically, the signal receiving unit <b>23</b> in each of the infrared communication module A&#x2032;, the Zigbee communication module B&#x2032; and the DALT communication module C&#x2032; includes an antenna and a demodulation circuit (not shown), and each of the control terminal A, the control terminal B and the control terminal C is a remote controller. The signal receiving unit <b>23</b> of the power line communication module D&#x2032; is a coupler coupled to the power line <b>20</b>, and the control terminal D controls the lamp device <b>1</b> through the power line <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In an aspect of the lamp device <b>1</b>, for compatibility with different communication modules <b>2</b>, the control unit <b>13</b> is configured with a firmware set corresponding to different communication module types (for example, the infrared communication module A&#x2032; and the Zigbee communication module B&#x2032;). A firmware in the firmware set corresponds to the communication module type to which the communication module <b>2</b> belongs and includes instructions for executing the control command so as to generate the pulse-width modulation signal for controlling the driving circuit <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a flow chart illustrates an interactive process between the lamp device <b>1</b> and the communication module <b>2</b> when the communication module <b>2</b> is pluggably coupled to the lamp device <b>1</b>. In step <b>31</b>, the first connector <b>14</b> of the lamp device <b>1</b> is electrically coupled to the second connector <b>21</b> of the communication module <b>2</b>. In step <b>32</b>, the micro controller <b>22</b> of the communication module <b>2</b> is configured to send a notification signal for notifying the control unit <b>13</b>. In step <b>33</b>, the control unit <b>13</b> sends an identification command for requesting the communication module <b>2</b> to respond with the communication module type to which the communication module <b>2</b> belongs. In step <b>34</b>, the control unit <b>13</b> determines whether the communication module type of the communication module <b>2</b> is supported by the control unit <b>13</b>. If result of the determination is affirmative (i.e., the communication module <b>2</b> is one of the infrared communication module A&#x2032; and the Zigbee communication module B&#x2032;), step <b>35</b> is performed. In step <b>35</b>, the control unit <b>13</b> is configured with the firmware corresponding to the communication module type to which the communication module <b>2</b> belongs so as to control the driving circuit <b>12</b>. If the result of the determination is negative (i.e., the communication module <b>2</b> is not one of the infrared communication module A&#x2032; and the Zigbee communication module <b>2</b>&#x2032;, such as the DALI communication module C&#x2032;), step <b>36</b> is performed. In step <b>36</b>, the control unit <b>13</b> is configured to download latest firmware corresponding to the communication module type from the micro controller <b>22</b> of the communication module <b>2</b> (i.e., the DALI communication module C&#x2032;), and is configured with the latest firmware which includes instructions for executing the control command so as to control the driving circuit <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Furthermore, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a perspective view of the lamp device <b>1</b> of the preferred embodiment is illustrated. The lamp device <b>1</b> further includes a housing <b>15</b> that receives the driving circuit <b>12</b>, the control unit <b>13</b> and the first connector <b>14</b>, and that has a surface with a recessed area <b>10</b> within which the light-emitting module <b>11</b> is mounted. In this embodiment, the light-emitting module is a pair of light-emitting diode modules as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, but is not limited to the disclosure herein. The light-emitting module <b>11</b> may be a single light-emitting diode module or more than two light-emitting diode modules, and disposition of the light-emitting diodes (LED) in each of the light-emitting diode modules is not limited to longitudinal formation and may be circular formation or any other formations. The housing <b>15</b> further has an opening <b>16</b> aligned with the first connector <b>14</b>, such that the first connector <b>14</b> received in the housing <b>15</b> may be accessible from an exterior of the housing <b>15</b>. The communication module <b>2</b> is disposed in the housing <b>15</b> via the opening <b>16</b> to couple electrically the second connector <b>21</b> with the first connector <b>14</b>. The housing <b>15</b> further has a cover <b>17</b> disposed at the opening <b>16</b> for concealing the communication module <b>2</b> in the housing <b>15</b>, such that the communication module <b>2</b> may be protected from moisture and dust. Moreover, an appearance of the housing <b>15</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is merely an illustrative example, and should not be limited to the disclosure herein. In practice, the lamp device <b>1</b> in this embodiment may not only be applied in interior illumination, but also be applied to traffic lights and outdoor warning lamps.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In summary, in the preferred embodiment, the lamp device <b>1</b> and the communication module <b>2</b> may be pluggably coupled to each other, such that when a user wants to replace communication protocol of the control terminal <b>3</b>, the user only needs to replace the communication module <b>2</b> individually without replacing the communication module <b>2</b> together with the lamp device <b>1</b>. In this way, expense may be saved, and an effect of environmental protection may be achieved. Furthermore, the lamp device <b>1</b> is capable of automatically identifying the communication module type of the communication module <b>2</b> coupled thereto, and updating firmware if the communication module <b>2</b> is not supported by the current firmware set of the lamp device <b>1</b>. In this way, the lamp device <b>1</b> may be compatible with different communication modules <b>2</b>, and the communication module <b>2</b> may be replaced with relative ease.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">While the present invention has been described in connection with what is considered the most practical and preferred embodiment, it is understood that this invention is not limited to the disclosed embodiment but is intended to cover various arrangements included within the spirit and scope of the broadest interpretation so as to encompass all such modifications and equivalent arrangements.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A lamp device controllable by a control terminal, said lamp device comprising:
<claim-text>a light-emitting module;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a driving circuit electrically coupled to said light-emitting module for driving said light-emitting module;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control unit electrically coupled to said driving circuit for controlling duty cycle of said driving circuit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first connector electrically coupled to said control unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a communication module including a second connector pluggably coupled to said first connector, said communication module being adapted to receive a control command from the control terminal and transmitting the control command to said control unit via said first and second connectors, such that said control unit controls said driving circuit in accordance with the control command, said communication module storing a communication module type to which said communication module belongs and a firmware corresponding to the communication module type stored in said communication module, said firmware including instructions for executing the control command so as to generate a pulse-width modulation signal for controlling said driving circuit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said control unit is configured with a firmware set corresponding to different communication module types;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein when said second connector of said communication module is electrically coupled to said first connector, said communication module is configured to send a notification signal for notifying said control unit, and said control unit sends an identification command for requesting said communication module to respond with the communication module type stored in said communication module; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein when said control unit determines that the communication module type of said communication module is not supported by said firmware set of said control unit, said control unit is configured to download firmware corresponding to the communication module type from said communication module.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The lamp device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said communication module further includes a micro controller coupled to said second connector, and a signal receiving unit coupled to said micro controller, said signal receiving unit being adapted to receive the control command from the control terminal, said micro controller transforming a format of the control command received from said signal receiving unit into a signal format conforming to said first connector and said second connector prior to transmitting the control command to said second connector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The lamp device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said light-emitting module is a light-emitting diode module including a plurality of light-emitting diodes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The lamp device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a housing that receives said driving circuit, said control unit and said first connector, and that has an opening aligned with said first connector,
<claim-text>said communication module being disposed in said housing via said opening to couple electrically said first and second connectors,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said housing further having a cover disposed at said opening for concealing said communication module in said housing.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A lamp device for pluggable and electrical connection to a communication module so as to receive a control command from a control terminal through the communication module, said lamp device comprising:
<claim-text>a light-emitting module;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a driving circuit electrically coupled to said light-emitting module for driving said light-emitting module;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control unit electrically coupled to said driving circuit for controlling duty cycle of said driving circuit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first connector electrically coupled to said control unit, and pluggably coupled to a second connector of the communication module so as to receive the control command from the control terminal through the communication module and to transmit the control command to said control unit, such that said control unit controls said driving circuit in accordance with the control command;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein when said first connector is electrically coupled to the second connector of the communication module, said control unit is configured to receive a notification signal from the communication module via said first connector, and to send an identification command for requesting the communication module to respond with a communication module type to which the communication module belongs, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein when said control unit determines that the communication module type of the communication module is not supported by said control unit, said control unit is configured to download firmware corresponding to the communication module type from the communication module.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The lamp device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein said control unit is configured with a firmware set corresponding to different communication module types, a firmware in said firmware set corresponding to the communication module type to which the communication module belongs and including instructions for executing the control command so as to generate a pulse-width modulation signal for controlling said driving circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The lamp device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein said light-emitting module is a light-emitting diode module including a plurality of light-emitting diodes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The lamp device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, further comprising a housing that receives said driving circuit, said control unit and said first connector, and that has a surface with a recessed area within which said light-emitting module is mounted,
<claim-text>said housing further having an opening aligned with said first connector, the communication module being disposed in said housing via said opening to couple electrically the second connector with said first connector,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said housing further having a cover disposed at said opening for concealing the communication module in said housing.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A lamp device for pluggable and electrical connection to a communication module so as to receive a control command from a control terminal through the communication module, said lamp device comprising:
<claim-text>a light-emitting module;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a driving circuit electrically coupled to said light-emitting module for driving said light-emitting module;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control unit electrically coupled to said driving circuit for controlling duty cycle of said driving circuit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first connector electrically coupled to said control unit, and pluggably coupled to a second connector of the communication module so as to receive the control command from the control terminal through the communication module and to transmit the control command to said control unit, such that said control unit controls said driving circuit in accordance with the control command; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a housing that receives said driving circuit, said control unit and said first connector, and that has a surface with a recessed area within which said light-emitting module is mounted,
<claim-text>said housing further having an opening aligned with said first connector, the communication module being disposed in said housing via said opening to couple electrically the second connector with said first connector,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said housing further having a cover disposed at said opening for concealing the communication module in said housing.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The lamp device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein said control unit is configured with a firmware set corresponding to different communication module types, a firmware in said firmware set corresponding to the communication module type to which the communication module belongs and including instructions for executing the control command so as to generate a pulse-width modulation signal for controlling said driving circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The lamp device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein said light-emitting module is a light-emitting diode module including a plurality of light-emitting diodes. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
