<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623561-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623561</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13143568</doc-number>
<date>20090629</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="international">
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/US2009/003147</doc-number>
<date>20090121</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>60</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>M</subclass>
<main-group>8</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>M</subclass>
<main-group>8</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>N</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>429410</main-classification>
<further-classification>429413</further-classification>
<further-classification>429414</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Acid dilution device in condenser of phosphoric acid fuel cell</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4372759</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Sederquist et al.</name>
<date>19830200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 95228</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6376114</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Bonville et al.</name>
<date>20020400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>429425</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>6052879</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19940200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>6168732</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19940600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>8007909</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19960100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>8017454</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19960100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2766434</doc-number>
<date>19980600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00008">
<othercit>International Preliminary Report on Patentability for International application No. PCT/US2009/049045 dated Aug. 4, 2011.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00009">
<othercit>International Preliminary Report on Patentability for International application No. PCT/US2009/031476 dated Aug. 4, 2011.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00010">
<othercit>International Search Report and Written Opinion of the International Searching Authority for International Application No. PCT/US2009/049045 mailed Feb. 24, 2010.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>17</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110269036</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20111103</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Avis</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas Bruce</first-name>
<address>
<city>Manchester</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Saito</last-name>
<first-name>Kazuo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Glastonbury</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lines</last-name>
<first-name>Michael T.</first-name>
<address>
<city>South Windsor</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="004" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Brown</last-name>
<first-name>Ricardo O.</first-name>
<address>
<city>West Hartford</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Avis</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas Bruce</first-name>
<address>
<city>Manchester</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Saito</last-name>
<first-name>Kazuo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Glastonbury</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lines</last-name>
<first-name>Michael T.</first-name>
<address>
<city>South Windsor</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="004" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Brown</last-name>
<first-name>Ricardo O.</first-name>
<address>
<city>West Hartford</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Carlson, Gaskey &#x26; Olds, P.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Clearedge Power Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>South Windsor</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Ryan</last-name>
<first-name>Patrick</first-name>
<department>1726</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>McConnell</last-name>
<first-name>Wyatt</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/US2009/049045</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20090629</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20110707</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2010/085273</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20100729</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The condenser heat exchanger includes a housing that provides a gaseous stream flowpath and a bottom wall. A gaseous stream contains acid. The housing has a fluid inlet configured to introduce a liquid, such as water. A coolant tube is disposed within the housing in the gaseous stream flowpath and provides a coolant path. Acid condenses on and falls from the coolant tube into a collection area that is provided at the bottom wall near the coolant tube. The collection area is configured to maintain storage of a predetermined amount of fluid that includes the liquid, which dilutes the condensed acid.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="132.33mm" wi="173.74mm" file="US08623561-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="255.27mm" wi="179.75mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623561-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="257.22mm" wi="178.99mm" file="US08623561-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority to PCT Application No. PCT/US2009/031476, which was filed on Jan. 21, 2009.</p>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This disclosure relates to an acid fuel cell, such as a phosphoric acid electrolyte fuel cell. More particularly, the disclosure relates to a condenser heat exchanger for use in an acid fuel cell.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">One type of acid fuel cell uses a phosphoric acid electrolyte. Typically, a condenser is used in conjunction with the phosphoric acid fuel cell to condense and remove water from a gas stream, such as anode or cathode exhaust. One type of condenser heat exchanger uses multiple tubes supported in multiple fins. A coolant flows through the tubes to condense water from the gas stream flowing between the fins. The water vapor in the gas stream includes a small amount of phosphoric acid. The heat transfer fins at an upstream portion of the condenser heat exchanger have exhibited corrosion due to acid condensation on the fins. The fin edge temperature is much higher than the coolant temperature due to the heat resistance through the fin. As a result, the fin edge temperature is typically higher than the water dew point but lower than the acid dew point, which causes strong acid condensation on the fin leading to corrosion build-up.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Corrosion products must be removed during a maintenance procedure to prevent condenser corrosion and the fins from becoming blocked, which could inhibit the gas stream flow through the condenser heat exchanger. Corrosion-resistant metals, such as stainless steel and HASTELLOY, have been used for the fins and tubes. Use of corrosion-resistant metals has not extended the maintenance interval for removing corrosion products from the condenser heat exchanger to a desired duration, which may be ten years or more.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">A fuel cell assembly is disclosed that includes a cell stack assembly having a flow field configured to provide a gaseous flow stream having an acid. A condenser heat exchanger is arranged downstream from and fluidly connected to the flow field by a fluid flow passage. The condenser heat exchanger includes a cooling tube that is exposed to the gaseous flow stream from the flow field through the fluid flow passage. The cooling tube cools the gaseous flow stream and creates a condensed acid on the cooling tube. A water supply system includes a water source and is in fluid communication with the condenser heat exchanger at a water inlet. The condenser heat exchanger includes a collection area near the cooling tube that is configured to receive the condensed acid. The collection area maintains storage of a predetermined amount of fluid, which includes the water.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The condenser heat exchanger includes a housing that provides a gaseous stream flowpath and a bottom wall. The housing has a water or fluid inlet configured to introduce a liquid, such as water. The coolant tube is disposed within the housing in the gaseous stream flowpath and provides a coolant flowpath. The collection area is provided the bottom wall near the coolant tube.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">A method of diluting an acid within a fuel cell condenser heat exchanger includes cooling a gaseous stream with a coolant flow. A first liquid from the gaseous stream is condensed on a cooling loop. A second liquid is introduced to a collection area beneath the first liquid. A predetermined amount of fluid is maintained in the collection area. The predetermined amount of fluid includes the second liquid.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">These and other features of the disclosure can be best understood from the following specification and drawings, the following of which is a brief description.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view of a portion of an acid fuel cell having a condenser heat exchanger, in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic view of a water supply system including a condenser heat exchanger and an ammonia scrubber.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a cross-sectional elevational view of an example condenser heat exchanger.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the condenser heat exchanger shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, taken along line <b>4</b>-<b>4</b>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">A fuel cell <b>10</b> is depicted in a highly schematic fashion in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The fuel cell <b>10</b> includes a cell stack assembly <b>12</b> having an anode <b>14</b> and a cathode <b>16</b>. In one example, a phosphoric acid electrolyte <b>18</b> is arranged between the anode <b>14</b> and the cathode <b>16</b>. The cell stack assembly <b>12</b> produces electricity to power a load <b>20</b> in response to a chemical reaction. A fuel source <b>22</b> supplies hydrogen to a fuel flow field provided by the anode <b>14</b>. In one example, the fuel source is a natural gas. Components, such as a desulfurizer, a reformer, and a saturator, may be arranged between the fuel source <b>22</b> and the anode <b>14</b> to provide a clean source of hydrogen. A wet ammonia scrubber <b>84</b> is arranged between the fuel source <b>22</b> and anode <b>14</b> to remove ammonia from the hydrogen supply. Ammonia can contaminate anode <b>14</b>, reducing the efficiency of the fuel cell <b>10</b>. An oxidant source <b>24</b>, such as air, is supplied to an oxidant flow field provided by the cathode <b>16</b> using a blower <b>26</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The cell stack assembly <b>12</b> includes a coolant plate <b>28</b>, in one example, to cool the cell stack assembly <b>12</b> to desired temperature. A coolant loop <b>30</b> is in fluid communication with the coolant plate <b>28</b> and a condenser heat exchanger <b>32</b>. A heat exchanger <b>31</b> including coolant tubes is arranged in the coolant loop <b>30</b> to reject heat from the fuel cell <b>10</b> to ambient <b>65</b>. A fluid flow or gaseous stream (G in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</figref> and <b>4</b>) containing water vapor flows through the condenser heat exchanger <b>32</b>. In one example, the gaseous stream is provided by anode exhaust from the anode <b>14</b>. However, it should be understood that a condenser heat exchanger can also be used in connection with the cathode <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The condenser heat exchanger <b>32</b> includes an inlet manifold <b>34</b> providing a fluid inlet receiving the gaseous stream. The gaseous stream flows through a common housing <b>36</b> to a fluid outlet <b>64</b> in an outlet manifold <b>38</b>. In one example, the housing <b>36</b> is constructed from stainless steel. A fluid flow passage <b>33</b> within the housing <b>36</b> receives the gaseous stream. In one example, the condenser heat exchanger <b>32</b> is provided by a bare tube section <b>41</b><i>a </i>and a tube-in-fin section <b>41</b><i>b</i>. The heat exchanger is constructed from 316L stainless steel that is brazed together with nickel, in one example.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In one example, the tubes <b>42</b> are illustrated in a horizontal orientation. The fins <b>40</b> in the tube-in-fin section <b>41</b><i>b </i>of the condenser heat exchanger <b>32</b> are illustrated in a vertical orientation such that the tubes <b>42</b> are perpendicular to the fins <b>40</b>. The fins <b>40</b> are arranged parallel to one another and include holes to accommodate the passage of and provide support to the tubes <b>42</b> through the fins <b>40</b>. The coolant tube sections <b>41</b><i>a</i>, <b>41</b><i>b </i>illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref> can be oriented and/or configured differently than shown and still fall within the scope of the claims. The tubes <b>42</b> provide a coolant flow passage <b>43</b> that extends between a coolant inlet <b>52</b> and coolant outlet <b>54</b>, which are arranged within the coolant loop <b>30</b>. The coolant inlet and outlet manifolds are not shown for clarity. Alternatively, manifolds may not be used. The fins <b>40</b> are spaced apart from and parallel with one another to provide the fluid flow passage <b>33</b>, which extends between the inlet manifold <b>34</b> and the outlet manifold <b>38</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In addition to containing water vapor, the gas stream entering the fluid flow passage <b>33</b> also contains a small amount of phosphoric acid. Phosphoric acid has a dew point of approximately 160&#xb0; C., and water vapor has a dew point of approximately 65&#xb0; C. within the condenser heat exchanger <b>32</b>. The coolant within the coolant flow passage <b>43</b> includes a first temperature, and the fluid, which may be anode exhaust, within the fluid flow passage <b>33</b> includes a second temperature that is greater than the first temperature. Coolant flow through the coolant flow passage <b>43</b> condenses the phosphoric acid and water vapor within the fluid flow passage <b>33</b> onto the exterior of the tubes <b>42</b>. The configuration illustrated should provide a tendency for the acid to condense in the bare tube section <b>41</b><i>a </i>of the condenser heat exchanger <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The outlet manifold <b>38</b> includes a fluid line <b>60</b>, for example that is fluidly connected to a first water storage tank <b>56</b>. In one example, water from the condenser heat exchanger <b>32</b> can be supplied to the first water storage tank <b>56</b> that supplies the recovered water to a reformer <b>63</b> through fluid line <b>60</b>. The exhaust gas from the outlet manifold <b>38</b> is exhausted to ambient <b>65</b> through fluid outlet <b>64</b>. A fluid line <b>61</b> may provide a degas column that carries CO<sub>2</sub>, C, back to the outlet manifold from which it is expelled from the fuel cell <b>10</b>. The phosphoric acid tends to condense upstream from where the water vapor condenses due to the difference in dew points between phosphoric acid and water. Some water vapor may condense with the acid producing a diluted phosphoric acid.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Water supply system <b>248</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The wet ammonia scrubber <b>84</b> receives fuel from the fuel source <b>22</b> before providing the fuel to the anode <b>14</b> of the cell stack assembly <b>12</b>. In one example, the water source <b>244</b> is provided by a second water storage tank <b>86</b> that receives excess water from the wet ammonia scrubber <b>84</b>. Water from the water storage tank <b>86</b> is supplied to the condenser heat exchanger <b>32</b> through the water inlet <b>46</b> by a sprayer <b>92</b> in one example. A pump <b>88</b> pumps and pressurizes the water to the sprayer <b>92</b>. A controller <b>90</b> communicates with the pump <b>88</b> to supply the water to the water inlet <b>46</b> in response to a predetermined condition, for example, at a desired interval. By using a periodic injection of water sprayed to the water inlet <b>46</b>, the water dew point of the inlet gas can be lowered. As a result, excess acid forms on the heat exchanger and falls off. In one example, the wet ammonia scrubber <b>84</b> supplies water to the water storage tank <b>86</b> at 2 g/s. In the example, the water quantity desired to desuperheat the condenser heat exchanger <b>32</b> at the water inlet <b>46</b> is approximately 33.3 g/s. As a result, water will be sprayed by the sprayer 6% of the time, or approximately 5 minutes every 90 minutes of operation. An example, water storage volume for the wet ammonia scrubber <b>84</b> is 2.8 gallons, which can be reasonably accommodated in most fuel cell designs.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref>, a condenser heat exchanger <b>132</b> is shown. The housing <b>36</b> includes a bottom wall <b>100</b> to which a fluid or water inlet <b>192</b> is fluidly connected. In one example, water is supplied to the water inlet <b>192</b> by the water scrubber <b>84</b>, for example, in a similar manner to that described relative to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. A collection area <b>96</b> is provided in the bottom wall <b>100</b> near the bare tube section <b>41</b><i>a</i>. The water inlet <b>192</b> fills the collection area <b>96</b> with water. In one example, the collection area <b>96</b> is arranged immediately beneath the cooling tubes in the bare tube section <b>41</b><i>a </i>to collect condensed acid F<b>1</b> falling from the coolant tubes, which is then diluted by the water in the collection are <b>96</b> preventing the acid from solidifying.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In one example, the bottom wall <b>100</b> is sloped downward from the inlet manifold <b>34</b> to the outlet manifold <b>38</b>. A baffle <b>102</b>, which acts as a dam, is provided on the bottom wall <b>100</b> slightly downstream from the inlet manifold <b>34</b> to provide the collection area <b>96</b>, which sets the predetermined amount of fluid held in the collection area <b>96</b>. In one example, the collection area <b>96</b> extends the full width beneath the bare-tube section <b>41</b><i>a</i>. The water inlet <b>192</b> provides water to the collection area at a desired interval, similar to the sprayer <b>92</b>, for example, to ensure that the collection area maintains storage of a predetermined amount of water sufficient to dilute the condensed acid F<b>1</b> to a dilute acid F<b>2</b> having a relatively low acid concentration. Overflow from the collection area <b>96</b> flows downward along the bottom wall <b>100</b> beneath the tube-in-fin section <b>41</b><i>b </i>toward the fluid line <b>60</b>. The dilute acid F<b>2</b> is further diluted by condensed water falling from the tube-in-fin section <b>41</b><i>b </i>to another area beneath the tube-in-fin section <b>41</b><i>b</i>, providing a further dilute acid F<b>3</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Although example embodiments have been disclosed, a worker of ordinary skill in this art would recognize that certain modifications would come within the scope of the claims. For that reason, the following claims should be studied to determine their true scope and content.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A fuel cell assembly comprising:
<claim-text>a cell stack assembly including a flow field configured to provide a gaseous flow stream having an acid;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a condenser heat exchanger arranged downstream from and fluidly connected to the flow field by a fluid flow passage, the condenser heat exchanger including a cooling tube exposed to the gaseous flow stream from the flow field through the fluid flow passage and configured to cool the gaseous flow stream and create a condensed acid on the cooling tube;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a water supply system including a water source and in fluid communication with the condenser heat exchanger at a water inlet, the condenser heat exchanger including a collection area near the cooling tube configured to receive the condensed acid and maintain storage of a predetermined amount of fluid, which includes water;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the condenser heat exchanger includes a first tube section and a second tube section, the collection area arranged beneath the first tube section, and another area arranged beneath the second tube section downstream from the collection area, the other area receiving an overflow of the fluid from the collection area; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the water supply system is configured to provide water to a first tube section, the fluid, including the condensed acid and water, overflowing the collection area to a region beneath the second tube section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the water source includes an ammonia scrubber configured to provide the water.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, comprising a fuel source in fluid communication with the ammonia scrubber, and the cell stack assembly includes an anode downstream from and in fluid communication with the ammonia scrubber.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the water supply system includes a controller and a water storage tank configured to receive the water from the ammonia scrubber, the controller configured to selectively provide the water to the water inlet in response to a predetermined condition.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the water supply system includes a pump, the controller in communication with the pump and configured to selectively command the pump to provide the additional water to the water inlet the predetermined condition including an interval.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the condenser heat exchanger includes an inlet manifold and an outlet manifold respectively providing a fluid flow inlet and a fluid flow outlet, and multiple cooling tubes providing a coolant flow passage, the coolant flow passage arranged between the inlet and the outlet manifolds, the fluid flow passage extending between the inlet and the outlet manifolds, and the inlet manifold configured to receive the water.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first tube section corresponds to a bare tube section, and the second tube section corresponds to a tube-in-fin section, the second tube section is arranged downstream from the first tube section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the condenser heat exchanger includes a housing having a bottom wall providing the collection area, the bottom wall sloped downward from the bare tube section to the tube-in-fin section, and a baffle provided on the bottom wall to set the predetermined amount of fluid in the collection area and inhibit downward fluid flow from the collection area to the other area.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the collection area is arranged immediately beneath the bare tube section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A condenser heat exchanger for a fuel cell assembly comprising:
<claim-text>a housing providing a gaseous stream flow path and including a bottom wall, the housing having a fluid inlet configured to introduce a liquid;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a coolant tube disposed within the housing in the gaseous stream flow path and providing a coolant flow path; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a collection area provided at the bottom wall near the coolant tube, the collection area configured to maintain storage of a predetermined amount of fluid that includes the liquid; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the bottom wall is sloped downward from the fluid inlet, and the fluid inlet is provided on the bottom wall.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The condenser heat exchanger according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein another area is arranged downstream from the collection area and configured to receive overflow fluid from the collection area.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The condenser heat exchanger according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the coolant tubes including a bare tube section and a tube-in-fin section, the collection area receiving condensed fluid from the bare tube section and the other area receiving condensed fluid from the tube-in-fin section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The condenser heat exchanger according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the bottom wall includes a baffle downstream from the fluid inlet and that sets the predetermined amount of fluid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The condenser heat exchanger according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the collection area is arranged immediately beneath the coolant tube, and another area is arranged downstream from the collection area and is configured to receive overflow of the fluid from the collection area.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A method of diluting an acid within a fuel cell condenser heat exchanger comprising:
<claim-text>cooling a gaseous stream with a coolant flow;</claim-text>
<claim-text>condensing a first liquid from the gaseous stream on a coolant loop;</claim-text>
<claim-text>introducing a second liquid to a collection area beneath the first liquid, the introducing step includes intermittently supplying the second liquid, which includes water, at a desired interval; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>maintaining a predetermined amount of fluid in the collection area that includes the second liquid.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the first liquid includes a condensed acid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, comprising overflowing the second liquid into another area downstream from the collection area. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
