<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623568-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623568</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13259245</doc-number>
<date>20090403</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>M</subclass>
<main-group>8</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>429444</main-classification>
<further-classification>429443</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Fuel cell and flow field plate with flow guides</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0063919</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yang et al.</name>
<date>20080300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006278247</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20061000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>102008002812</doc-number>
<date>20080300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00004">
<othercit>International Preliminary Report on Patentability mailed on Oct. 13, 2011 for PCT/US2009/039411.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00005">
<othercit>Search Report and Written Opinion mailed on Nov. 26, 2009 for PCT/US2009/039411.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>19</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>429444</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120015274</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120119</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Darling</last-name>
<first-name>Robert Mason</first-name>
<address>
<city>South Windsor</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Darling</last-name>
<first-name>Robert Mason</first-name>
<address>
<city>South Windsor</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Carlson, Gaskey &#x26; Olds, P.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>United Technologies Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Hartford</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Gilliam</last-name>
<first-name>Barbara</first-name>
<department>1727</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Harris</last-name>
<first-name>Gary</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/US2009/039411</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20090403</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20110923</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2010/114556</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20101007</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A flow field plate for use in a fuel cell includes a non-porous plate body having a flow field with a plurality of channels extending between a channel inlet end and a channel outlet end, a first flow distribution portion adjacent the channel inlet end for distributing a fluid to the plurality of channels, and a second flow distribution portion adjacent the channel outlet end for collecting the fluid from the plurality of channels. A first flow guide within the first flow distribution portion establishes a desired flow distribution to the plurality of channels, and a second flow guide within the second flow distribution portion establishes a desired flow distribution from the plurality of channels.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="62.91mm" wi="140.72mm" file="US08623568-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="213.44mm" wi="139.70mm" file="US08623568-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="232.58mm" wi="146.73mm" file="US08623568-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This disclosure relates to flow field plates in a fuel cell. Fuel cells typically include an anode catalyst, a cathode catalyst, and an electrolyte between the anode and cathode catalysts for generating an electric current in a known electrochemical reaction between reactants, such as fuel and oxidant. The fuel cell may include flow field plates with channels for directing the reactants to the respective catalyst. Conventional fuel cells utilize inlet and exit manifolds that extend through the flow field plates to deliver the reactant gases and coolant to the channels and receive exhaust gas and coolant from the channels. The flow field plates are typically rectangular.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The locations of the manifolds often necessitate a multi-pass flow field design in which a reactant flows from one side of the flow field to the other through a first set of channels and turns to flow back across the flow field in another set of channels to make at least several passes over the flow field. One challenge associated with a multi-pass design is achieving high fuel cell performance. For instance, the concentration, temperature, and other properties of the reactant gases change significantly through the channels and can diminish the performance of the fuel cell. Single pass designs with specific arrangements among the fuel, air, and coolant streams have been proposed as a solution to reduce changes in the concentration and temperature of the gases, for example. However, single pass designs do not provide adequate distribution of the reactant gases to the catalyst to achieve the desired performance with the given packaging and manifold location constraints.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">An exemplary flow field plate for use in a fuel cell includes a non-porous plate body having a flow field with a plurality of channels extending between a channel inlet end and a channel outlet end, a first flow distribution portion adjacent the channel inlet end for distributing a fluid to the plurality of channels, and a second flow distribution portion adjacent the channel outlet end for collecting the fluid from the plurality of channels. A first flow guide within the first flow distribution portion establishes a first mass transport rate of the reactant gas to an adjacent catalyst, and a second flow guide within the second flow distribution portion establishes a second, different mass transport rate of the reactant gas to the catalyst.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">An exemplary fuel cell may include the flow field plate, an electrode assembly including an electrolyte between an anode catalyst and a cathode catalyst, and a plurality of manifolds for transporting fluids in the fuel cell.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">An exemplary method of managing delivery of the reactant gas in the fuel cell includes establishing a first mass transport rate of the reactant gas from the first flow distribution portion to the electrode assembly, and establishing a second, different mass transport rate of the reactant gas from the second flow distribution portion to the electrode assembly.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The various features and advantages of the disclosed examples will become apparent to those skilled in the art from the following detailed description. The drawings that accompany the detailed description can be briefly described as follows.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates an example fuel cell.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates an example flow field plate having first and second flow distribution portions with respective first and second flow guides having different population densities of protrusions.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates another example flow field plate having first and second flow distribution portions with respective first and second flow guides having different sizes.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates another example flow field plate having first and second flow distribution portions with respective first and second flow guides having different shapes.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates an example protrusion of a flow guide in a flow distribution portion of a flow field plate.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a partially exploded view of selected portions of an example fuel cell <b>10</b> for generating an electric current in a known electrochemical reaction between reactant gases, for example. It is to be understood that the disclosed arrangement of the fuel cell <b>10</b> is only an example and that the concepts disclosed herein may be applied to other fuel cell arrangements.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The example fuel cell <b>10</b> includes one or more fuel cell units <b>12</b> that may be stacked in a known manner to provide the assembly of the fuel cell <b>10</b>. Each of the fuel cell units <b>12</b> includes an electrode assembly <b>14</b> and flow field plates <b>16</b><i>a </i>and <b>16</b><i>b </i>for delivering reactant gases (e.g., air and hydrogen) to the electrode assembly <b>14</b>. The flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a </i>may be regarded as an air plate for delivering air and the flow field plate <b>16</b><i>b </i>may be regarded as a fuel plate for delivering hydrogen. The flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a, </i>flow field plate <b>16</b><i>b, </i>or both may also circulate coolant (in coolant channels <b>34</b>) for maintaining a desired operating temperature of the fuel cell <b>10</b> and hydrating the reactant gases indirectly by maintaining the electrode assembly <b>14</b> in a desired temperature range.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The electrode assembly <b>14</b> includes an electrolyte <b>18</b> between a cathode catalyst <b>20</b><i>a </i>and an anode catalyst <b>20</b><i>b. </i>Gas diffusion layers <b>22</b> may be used between the respective flow field plates <b>16</b><i>a </i>and <b>16</b><i>b </i>and the electrode assembly <b>14</b> to facilitate distribution of the reactant gases.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The flow field plates <b>16</b><i>a </i>and <b>16</b><i>b </i>may be substantially similar. Thus, the disclosed examples made with reference to the flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a </i>may also apply to the flow field plate <b>16</b><i>b. </i>In other examples, the flow field plate <b>16</b><i>b </i>may be different or include some of the same features as the flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a </i>includes a non-porous plate body <b>30</b>. Non-porous refers to the body being solid and free of pores that are known in porous plates for holding or transporting liquid water or other fluids. Thus, the non-porous plate body <b>30</b> is a barrier to fluids.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The non-porous plate body <b>30</b> includes reactant gas channels <b>32</b> and coolant channels <b>34</b>. The reactant gas channels <b>32</b> are located on a side of the flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a </i>that faces in the direction of the electrode assembly <b>14</b> in the fuel cell unit <b>12</b> and the coolant channels <b>34</b> are located on the opposite side of the flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a </i>may be stamped or otherwise formed into the desired shape. In this regard, positive features on one side of the flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a </i>are negative features on the other side, and vice versa. Stamping allows the flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a </i>to be made at a relatively low cost with a reduced need for machining operations, for example. The flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a </i>may be formed from steel, such as stainless steel, or other suitable alloy or material.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates one side of the flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a. </i>It is to be understood that the other side is the negative of the visible side. The channels <b>32</b> and <b>34</b> include inlets <b>42</b> for receiving a fluid (reactant gas or coolant) and outlets <b>44</b> for discharging the fluid.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a </i>extends between a first terminal end <b>36</b> and a second terminal end <b>38</b> of the non-porous plate body <b>30</b> and includes flow fields <b>40</b> (one shown). The term &#x201c;flow field&#x201d; as used in this disclosure may refer to any or all of the channels <b>32</b> and <b>34</b> for delivering the air, fuel, and coolant and any other area between the channels <b>32</b> and <b>34</b> and manifolds for transporting the air, fuel, or coolant, such as the manifolds <b>62</b> and <b>68</b> in the case of air. The reactant gas channels <b>32</b> may be regarded as a flow field for the reactant gas (air in the case of flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a </i>and fuel in the case of flow field plate <b>16</b><i>b</i>) and the coolant channels <b>34</b> may be regarded as a flow field for coolant.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The flow fields <b>40</b> may each include a first flow distribution portion <b>50</b> and a second flow distribution portion <b>52</b>. The flow fields of the reactant gases are active areas that are side by side with the electrode assembly <b>14</b>, for delivering the reactant gases to the electrode assembly <b>14</b> for the electrochemical reaction. Thus, the first flow distribution portion <b>50</b> and the second flow distribution portion <b>52</b> are also side by side with a portion of the electrode assembly <b>14</b>. In the illustrated example, the first flow distribution portion <b>50</b> diverges from the first terminal end <b>36</b> to the channel inlets <b>42</b>, and the second first flow distribution portion <b>52</b> converges from the channel outlets <b>44</b> to the second terminal end <b>38</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a </i>includes another first flow distribution portion <b>50</b> and another second flow distribution portion <b>52</b> (as the negatives) on the back side of the flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a </i>for distributing the coolant to and from the coolant channels <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In the illustrated example, the flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a </i>has an irregular octagonal shape to achieve the divergent and convergent shape. However, the shape is not limited to octagonal, and in other examples the flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a </i>may have a different polygonal shape or a non-polygonal shape, such as elliptical, to achieve the divergent and convergent shape.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The first flow distribution portion <b>50</b> and the second flow distribution portion <b>52</b> may each include a straight end wall <b>54</b> and two straight side walls <b>56</b> that non-perpendicularly extend from the straight end wall <b>54</b>. The angle between the side walls <b>56</b> and the end wall <b>54</b> provides the respective diverging or converging shape. The angles shown may be varied, depending on a desired degree of divergence or convergence.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The diverging and converging shapes of the respective first flow distribution portion <b>50</b> and second flow distribution portion <b>52</b> facilitate distribution of a fluid to the given flow field <b>40</b>. For instance, the flow of a fluid delivered into the first flow distribution portion <b>50</b> follows along the side walls <b>56</b> to the outer channels near the edges of the flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a. </i>Likewise, the second flow distribution portion <b>52</b> converges and thereby funnels the fluid flowing from the channels to facilitate collection of the fluid.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The fuel cell <b>10</b> also includes manifolds <b>60</b>, <b>62</b>, <b>64</b>, <b>66</b>, <b>68</b>, and <b>70</b> to deliver and collect reactant gas and coolant to and from the flow fields <b>40</b>. The manifolds <b>60</b> and <b>64</b> are located near the side walls <b>56</b> of the first flow distribution portion <b>50</b>, and the manifold <b>62</b> is located near the end wall <b>54</b>. The manifolds <b>66</b> and <b>70</b> are located near the side walls <b>56</b> of the second flow distribution portion <b>52</b>, and the manifold <b>68</b> is located near the end wall <b>54</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The individual manifolds <b>60</b>, <b>62</b>, <b>64</b>, <b>66</b>, <b>68</b>, and <b>70</b> may be used as inlets for delivering the fuel, air, or coolant to a given flow field <b>40</b> or as outlets for collecting the fuel, air, or coolant from the given flow field <b>40</b> to facilitate fluid distribution or achieve other fuel cell objectives.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The first flow distribution portion <b>50</b> includes a first flow guide <b>78</b><i>a </i>for establishing a first mass transport rate of the reactant gas to the electrode assembly <b>14</b> (e.g., transport of air to the cathode catalyst <b>20</b><i>a </i>in the case of flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a</i>). The second flow distribution portion <b>52</b> includes a second flow guide <b>78</b><i>b </i>for establishing a second, different mass transport rate of the reactant gas to the electrode assembly <b>14</b> (also the cathode catalyst <b>20</b><i>a </i>in the case of flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a</i>). For example, the first flow guide <b>78</b><i>a </i>may include first protrusions <b>80</b><i>a </i>within the first flow distribution portion <b>50</b>, and the second flow guide <b>78</b><i>b </i>may include second protrusions <b>80</b><i>b </i>within the second flow distribution portion <b>52</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The first flow guide <b>78</b><i>a </i>also establishes a desired flow distribution between a given manifold <b>60</b>, <b>62</b>, <b>64</b> and the channels. The second flow guide <b>78</b><i>b </i>also establishes a desired flow distribution between a given manifold <b>66</b>, <b>68</b>, or <b>70</b> and the channels <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The manifold <b>62</b> may deliver a reactant gas into the first flow distribution portion <b>50</b>. Although this example is made with reference to manifold <b>62</b>, it is to be understood that the example may also apply to the other manifolds <b>64</b> and <b>66</b>. In this case, the manifold <b>62</b> is not equidistantly spaced from the inlets <b>42</b> of the reactant gas channels <b>32</b>. Therefore, the reactant gas channels <b>32</b>A located towards the outside of the flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a </i>are farther away from the manifold <b>62</b> than the reactant gas channels <b>32</b>B in the center. The distances from the manifold <b>62</b> to the reactant gas channels <b>32</b> causes a tendency for non-uniform flow of the reactant gas into the reactant gas channels <b>32</b>, which could diminish the performance of the fuel cell <b>10</b>. However, the first flow guide <b>78</b><i>a </i>counteracts the tendency by limiting flow to the closer channels <b>32</b>B and promoting flow to the farther channels <b>32</b>A to provide a more uniform flow into the reactant gas channels <b>32</b>. A uniform flow into the reactant gas channels <b>32</b> provides the benefit of increased performance of the fuel cell <b>10</b> in a single-pass design.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The manifold <b>68</b> may collect the reactant gas from the second flow distribution portion <b>52</b>. Although this example is made with reference to manifold <b>68</b>, it is to be understood that the example may also apply to the other manifolds <b>66</b> and <b>70</b>. The reactant gas channels <b>32</b>A located towards the outside of the flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a </i>are farther away from the manifold <b>68</b> than the reactant gas channels <b>32</b>B in the center. The distances from the manifold <b>62</b> to the reactant gas channels <b>32</b> causes a tendency for non-uniform flow of the reactant gas from the reactant gas channels <b>32</b> to the manifold <b>68</b>, which could diminish the performance of the fuel cell <b>10</b>. However, the second flow guide <b>78</b><i>b </i>counteracts the tendency by limiting flow from the closer channels <b>32</b>A and promoting flow from the farther channels <b>32</b>B to provide a more uniform flow into the manifold <b>68</b>. The shape of the first and second protrusions <b>80</b><i>a </i>and <b>80</b><i>b, </i>arrangement of the first and second protrusions <b>80</b><i>a </i>and <b>80</b><i>b, </i>or both may contribute to limiting flow to or from selected reactant gas channels <b>32</b>B and promoting flow to or from other of the reactant gas channels <b>32</b>A. Given this description, one of ordinary skill in the art will recognize particular shapes and arrangements to suit their particular needs.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In the illustrated example, the first flow guide <b>78</b><i>a </i>includes a first population density of the first protrusions <b>80</b><i>a </i>and the second flow guide <b>78</b><i>b </i>includes a second population density of the second protrusions <b>80</b><i>b </i>that is different than the first population density. The term &#x201c;population density&#x201d; refers to the number of first or second protrusions <b>80</b><i>a </i>or <b>80</b><i>b </i>per unit area of the respective first or second flow distribution portion <b>50</b> or <b>52</b>. In this case, the first population density is greater than the second population density.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Although the flow guides <b>78</b><i>a </i>and <b>78</b><i>b </i>facilitate uniform flow, the flow guides <b>78</b><i>a </i>and <b>78</b><i>b </i>limit the mass transport rate of the reactant gas to the electrode assembly <b>14</b> by occupying a portion of the open space of the respective first and second flow distribution portions <b>50</b> and <b>52</b>. That is, the protrusions <b>78</b><i>a </i>and <b>78</b><i>b </i>generally reduce the available surface area of the flow field <b>40</b> through which the reactant gas can diffuse to the electrode assembly <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In the first flow distribution portion <b>50</b> the concentration of the reactant gas (oxygen in the air in the case of flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a</i>) is relatively high. However, the concentration of the reactant gas in the second flow distribution portion <b>52</b> is relatively low because of oxygen consumption through the reactant gas channels <b>32</b>. Therefore, the electrode assembly <b>14</b> requires more air at the second flow distribution portion <b>52</b> to avoid limiting the electrochemical reaction because of the lower oxygen concentration.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In the illustrated example, the higher first population density in the first flow distribution portion <b>50</b> provides a first mass transport rate and the lower second population density in the second flow distribution portion <b>52</b> provides a second, higher mass transport rate to counteract the lower oxygen concentration. A low oxygen concentration in combination with a lower mass transport rate would limit the electrochemical reaction. Thus, the flow guides <b>78</b><i>a </i>and <b>78</b><i>b </i>facilitate flow to and from the channels and establish desirable mass transport rates for maintaining the electrochemical reaction given the different reactant gas concentrations in the first and second flow distribution portions <b>50</b> and <b>52</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Additionally, the electrode assembly <b>14</b> requires relatively high electron mobility given the higher oxygen concentration at the first flow distribution portion <b>50</b>. Conversely, the electrode assembly <b>14</b> requires relatively lower electron mobility given the lower oxygen concentration at the second flow distribution portion <b>52</b>. The higher population density in the first flow distribution portion <b>50</b> favors electrical conductivity and thereby facilitates electron mobility to avoid limiting the electrochemical reaction. The lower population density in the second flow distribution portion <b>52</b> favors mass transport over electron mobility to avoid limiting the electrochemical reaction.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates another example flow field plate <b>116</b><i>a </i>that may be used in the fuel cell <b>10</b> in place of the flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a. </i>In this disclosure, like reference numerals designate like elements where appropriate, and reference numerals with the addition of one-hundred or multiples thereof designate modified elements. The modified elements are understood to incorporate the same features and benefits of the corresponding original elements. In this example, the first flow distribution portion <b>50</b> includes a first flow guide <b>178</b><i>a </i>having first protrusions <b>180</b><i>a, </i>and the second flow distribution portion <b>52</b> includes a second flow guide <b>178</b><i>b </i>having second protrusions <b>180</b><i>b. </i>In this case, the population density of the first and second protrusions <b>180</b><i>a </i>and <b>180</b><i>b </i>are equal but the first protrusions <b>180</b><i>a </i>each have a first size and the second protrusions <b>180</b><i>b </i>each have a second size that is different than the first size. In the illustrated example, the first size is greater than the second size. The sizes of the first and second protrusions <b>180</b><i>a </i>and <b>180</b><i>b </i>may refer to the volume, surface area, or other size indicator.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Similar to the higher first population density, the larger size of the first protrusions <b>180</b><i>a </i>favors electrical conductivity over mass transport rate in the first flow distribution portion <b>50</b> and the smaller second size of the second protrusions <b>180</b><i>b </i>in the second flow distribution portion <b>52</b> favors mass transport over electron mobility. That is, the protrusions <b>178</b><i>a </i>generally provide less available surface area than the second protrusions <b>178</b><i>b </i>through which the reactant gas can diffuse to the electrode assembly <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates another example flow field plate <b>216</b><i>a </i>that may be used in the fuel cell <b>10</b> in place of the flow field plate <b>16</b><i>a. </i>In this example, the first flow distribution portion <b>50</b> includes a first flow guide <b>278</b><i>a </i>having first protrusions <b>280</b><i>a, </i>and the second flow distribution portion <b>52</b> includes a second flow guide <b>278</b><i>b </i>having second protrusions <b>280</b><i>b. </i>In this case, the population density of the first and second protrusions <b>180</b><i>a </i>and <b>180</b><i>b </i>are equal and the size may be approximately equal but the first protrusions <b>280</b><i>a </i>each have a first shape and the second protrusions <b>180</b><i>b </i>each have a second shape that is different than the first shape. Similar to the higher first population density, the shape of the first protrusions <b>280</b><i>a </i>favors electrical conductivity over mass transport and the shape of the second protrusions <b>280</b><i>b </i>favors mass transport over electron mobility. In this regard, the selected shape of the protrusions <b>278</b><i>a </i>provides less available surface area than the shape second protrusions <b>178</b><i>b </i>through which the reactant gas can diffuse to the electrode assembly <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates an example of one of the first protrusions <b>280</b><i>a. </i>It is to be understood that the protrusions <b>80</b><i>a, </i><b>180</b><i>a, </i><b>80</b><i>b, </i>and <b>180</b><i>b </i>may have a similar shape as the protrusion <b>280</b><i>a. </i>In this example, the protrusion <b>280</b><i>a </i>has a non-equiaxed cross-sectional shape, with a long axis L and short axis S. The long axes L of the protrusions <b>280</b><i>a </i>in the first flow distribution portion <b>50</b> may be parallel. In this example, the protrusions <b>280</b><i>a </i>have an oval cross-section, but in other examples the protrusions <b>280</b><i>a </i>may have other cross-sectional shapes.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The non-equiaxed cross-sectional shape of the protrusions <b>280</b><i>a </i>limits flow along the S-axis direction and promotes flow along the L-axis. For instance, the reactant gas flows around the protrusions <b>280</b><i>a. </i>The protrusion <b>280</b><i>a </i>provides less obstruction to flow along the direction of the long axis L than along the direction of the short axis S because the protrusions <b>280</b><i>a </i>are relatively narrow along the short axes S and relatively wide along the long axes L. In the case of the flow field plate <b>216</b><i>a, </i>the second protrusions <b>280</b><i>b </i>have a different shape than the first protrusions <b>280</b><i>a. </i>The protrusions <b>280</b><i>a </i>may be designed with an orientation that limits flow to or from closer channels <b>32</b>B and promotes flow to or from farther channels <b>32</b>A to provide a more uniform flow distribution.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Although a combination of features is shown in the illustrated examples, not all of them need to be combined to realize the benefits of various embodiments of this disclosure. In other words, a system designed according to an embodiment of this disclosure will not necessarily include all of the features shown in any one of the Figures or all of the portions schematically shown in the Figures. Moreover, selected features of one example embodiment may be combined with selected features of other example embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The preceding description is exemplary rather than limiting in nature. Variations and modifications to the disclosed examples may become apparent to those skilled in the art that do not necessarily depart from the essence of this disclosure. The scope of legal protection given to this disclosure can only be determined by studying the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A flow field plate for use in a fuel cell, comprising:
<claim-text>a non-porous plate body including a flow field having a plurality of channels extending between a channel inlet end and a channel outlet end, a first flow distribution portion adjacent the channel inlet end for distributing a reactant gas to the plurality of channels, and a second flow distribution portion adjacent the channel outlet end for collecting the reactant gas from the plurality of channels;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first flow guide within the first flow distribution portion for establishing a first mass transport rate of the reactant gas to an adjacent catalyst, the first flow guide including a plurality of first protrusions; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second flow guide within the second flow distribution portion for establishing a second, different mass transport rate of the reactant gas to the adjacent catalyst, the second flow guide including a plurality of second protrusions, the plurality of first protrusions collectively differing from the plurality of second protrusions in at least one of population density, surface area and volume.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The flow field plate as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of the plurality of first protrusions has a first geometric shape and each of the plurality of second protrusions has a second geometric shape that is different than the first geometric shape.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The flow field plate as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further including a first population density of the plurality of first protrusions represented as a number of the first protrusions per unit area and a second population density of the plurality of second protrusions represented as a number of the second protrusions per unit area, wherein the second population density is different than the first population density.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The flow field plate as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the first population density is greater than the second population density.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A fuel cell comprising:
<claim-text>an electrode assembly including an electrolyte between an anode catalyst and a cathode catalyst;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of manifolds for transporting fluids in the fuel cell;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a non-porous plate body including a flow field having a plurality of channels extending between a channel inlet end and a channel outlet end, a first flow distribution portion adjacent the channel inlet end for distributing a reactant gas to the plurality of channels, and a second flow distribution portion adjacent the channel outlet end for collecting the reactant gas from the plurality of channels;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first flow guide within the first flow distribution portion for establishing a first mass transport rate of the reactant gas to the electrode assembly, the first flow guide including a plurality of first protrusions; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second flow guide within the second flow distribution portion for establishing a second, different mass transport rate of the reactant gas to the electrode assembly, the second flow guide including a plurality of second protrusions, the plurality of first protrusions collectively differing from the plurality of second protrusions in at least one of population density, surface area and volume.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The fuel cell as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the first flow guide includes a plurality of first protrusions and the second flow guide includes a plurality of second protrusions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The fuel cell as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein each of the plurality of first protrusions has a first size and each of the plurality of second protrusions has a second size that is different than the first size.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The fuel cell as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the first size is larger than the second size.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The fuel cell as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein each of the plurality of first protrusions has a first shape and each of the plurality of second protrusions has a second shape that is different than the first shape.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The fuel cell as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, further including a first population density of the plurality of first protrusions and a second population density of the plurality of second protrusions that is different than the first population density.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The fuel cell as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the first population density is greater than the second population density.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The fuel cell as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, further comprising a gas diffusion layer between the non-porous plate body and the electrode assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A method of managing delivery of a reactant gas in a fuel cell comprising an electrode assembly having an electrolyte between an anode catalyst and a cathode catalyst, a plurality of manifolds for transporting fluids in the fuel cell, a non-porous plate body including a flow field having a plurality of channels extending between a channel inlet end and a channel outlet end, a first flow distribution portion adjacent the channel inlet end for distributing the reactant gas to the plurality of channels, and a second flow distribution portion adjacent the channel outlet end for collecting the reactant gas from the plurality of channels, a first flow guide within the first flow distribution portion, and a second flow guide within the second flow distribution portion, the method comprising:
<claim-text>establishing a first mass transport rate of the reactant gas from the first flow distribution portion to the electrode assembly using a plurality of first protrusions of the first flow guide; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>establishing a second, different mass transport rate of the reactant gas from the second flow distribution portion to the electrode assembly, using a plurality of second protrusions of the second flow guide, where the plurality of first protrusions collectively differ from the plurality of second protrusions in at least one of population density, surface area and volume.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the first mass transport rate is less than the second mass transport rate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The flow field plate as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of first protrusions collectively differ from the plurality of second protrusions in surface area.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The flow field plate as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of first protrusions collectively differ from the plurality of second protrusions in volume.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The flow field plate as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of first protrusions collectively differ from the plurality of second protrusions in population density.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The flow field plate as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first flow distribution portion converges to the channel inlet end of the flow field and the second flow distribution portion diverges from the channel outlet end of the flow field.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The flow field plate as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of first protrusions and the plurality of second protrusions include a protrusion having a non-equiaxed cross-sectional shape. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
