<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624326-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624326</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13277669</doc-number>
<date>20111020</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>218</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>21</main-group>
<subgroup>70</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257369</main-classification>
<further-classification>438216</further-classification>
<further-classification>257E29255</further-classification>
<further-classification>257E27062</further-classification>
<further-classification>257E21628</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">FinFET device and method of manufacturing same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0073667</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lochtefeld</name>
<date>20080300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257190</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0068407</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yeh et al.</name>
<date>20110300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00003">
<othercit>J.-S. Park, et al., &#x201c;Defect Reduction of Selective Ge Epitaxy in Trenches on Si(001) Substrates Using Aspect Ratio Trapping,&#x201d; Applied Physics Letters 90, 052113, 2007, 3 pages, American Institute of Physics.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257368-369</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E21409</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E29255</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E27062</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438269</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>12</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>12</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130099282</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130425</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chen</last-name>
<first-name>Chi-Ming</first-name>
<address>
<city>Zhubei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yu</last-name>
<first-name>Chung-Yi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsinchu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hwang</last-name>
<first-name>Ho-Yung David</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsinchu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chen</last-name>
<first-name>Chi-Ming</first-name>
<address>
<city>Zhubei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yu</last-name>
<first-name>Chung-Yi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsinchu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hwang</last-name>
<first-name>Ho-Yung David</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsinchu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Haynes and Boone, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company, Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Hsin-Chu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Maldonado</last-name>
<first-name>Julio J</first-name>
<department>2898</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>McCall Shepard</last-name>
<first-name>Sonya D</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A semiconductor device and method for fabricating a semiconductor device is disclosed. An exemplary semiconductor device includes a substrate including a first dielectric layer disposed over the substrate. The semiconductor device further includes a buffer layer disposed over the substrate and between first and second walls of a trench of the dielectric layer. The semiconductor device further includes an insulator layer disposed over the buffer layer and between the first and second wall of the trench of the dielectric layer. The semiconductor device also includes a second dielectric layer disposed over the first dielectric layer and the insulator layer. Further, the semiconductor device includes a fin structure disposed over the insulator layer and between first and second walls of a trench of the second dielectric layer.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="128.69mm" wi="187.03mm" file="US08624326-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="192.02mm" wi="164.76mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624326-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="161.29mm" wi="159.43mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624326-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="162.39mm" wi="159.43mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624326-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="163.24mm" wi="159.09mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624326-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="165.35mm" wi="158.16mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624326-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="162.39mm" wi="162.39mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624326-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="163.24mm" wi="160.36mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624326-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="163.75mm" wi="161.12mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624326-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="165.95mm" wi="158.92mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624326-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="162.98mm" wi="161.21mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624326-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="162.98mm" wi="159.60mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624326-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="186.86mm" wi="160.19mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624326-20140107-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The semiconductor integrated circuit (IC) industry has experienced rapid growth. In the course of the IC evolution, functional density (i.e., the number of interconnected devices per chip area) has generally increased while geometry size (i.e., the smallest component (or line) that can be created using a fabrication process) has decreased. This scaling down process generally provides benefits by increasing production efficiency and lowering associated costs. Such scaling down has also increased the complexity of processing and manufacturing ICs and, for these advances to be realized, similar developments in IC manufacturing are needed.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">For example, as the semiconductor industry has progressed into nanometer technology process nodes in pursuit of higher device density, higher performance, and lower costs, challenges from both fabrication and design have resulted in the development of fin-like field effect transistor (FinFET) devices. Although existing FinFET devices and methods of fabricating FinFET devices have been generally adequate for their intended purposes, they have not been entirely satisfactory in all respects.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present disclosure is best understood from the following detailed description when read with the accompanying figures. It is emphasized that, in accordance with the standard practice in the industry, various features are not drawn to scale and are used for illustration purposes only. In fact, the dimensions of the various features may be arbitrarily increased or reduced for clarity of discussion.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a flowchart illustrating a method of fabricating a semiconductor device according to various aspects of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-11</figref> illustrate diagrammatic cross-sectional side views of one embodiment of a semiconductor device at various stages of fabrication, according to the method of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> illustrates a perspective view of one embodiment of the semiconductor device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-11</figref>, at a later stage of fabrication, according to the method of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The following disclosure provides many different embodiments, or examples, for implementing different features of the invention. Specific examples of components and arrangements are described below to simplify the present disclosure. These are, of course, merely examples and are not intended to be limiting. For example, the formation of a first feature over or on a second feature in the description that follows may include embodiments in which the first and second features are formed in direct contact, and may also include embodiments in which additional features may be formed between the first and second features, such that the first and second features may not be in direct contact. In addition, the present disclosure may repeat reference numerals and/or letters in the various examples. This repetition is for the purpose of simplicity and clarity and does not in itself dictate a relationship between the various embodiments and/or configurations discussed. Also, the components disclosed herein may be arranged, combined, or configured in ways different from the exemplary embodiments shown herein without departing from the scope of the present disclosure. It is understood that those skilled in the art will be able to devise various equivalents that, although not explicitly described herein, embody the principles of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Examples of devices that can benefit from one or more embodiments of the present invention are semiconductor devices. Such a device, for example, is a fin-like field effect transistor (FinFET). The FinFET device, for example, may be a P-type metal-oxide-semiconductor (PMOS) FinFET device, a N-type metal-oxide-semiconductor (NMOS) FinFET device, or a complementary metal-oxide-semiconductor (CMOS) FinFET device including a PMOS FinFET device and a NMOS FinFET device. The following disclosure will continue with a FinFET example to illustrate various embodiments of the present invention. It is understood, however, that the invention should not be limited to a particular type of device, except as specifically claimed.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">With reference to FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b>-<b>12</b>, a method <b>100</b> and a semiconductor device <b>200</b> are collectively described below. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a flow chart of a method <b>100</b> for fabricating an integrated circuit device/semiconductor device according to various aspects of the present disclosure. In the present embodiment, the method <b>100</b> is for fabricating a semiconductor device that includes a fin-like field effect transistor (FinFET) device.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The method <b>100</b> begins at block <b>102</b> where a substrate is provided and a first dielectric layer is deposited on the substrate. At block <b>104</b>, a first trench is formed in the first dielectric layer. The formation of the first trench may include patterning a mask layer and etching the first dielectric layer using the mask layer such that a surface of the substrate is exposed. At block <b>106</b>, a buffer layer is deposited over the exposed surface of the substrate within the first trench and perform a planarizing process on the substrate including the buffer layer. The buffer layer may be deposited such that it substantially fills the first trench. The buffer layer may be deposited by epitaxially (epi) growing the buffer layer within the first trench. The planarizing process may be performed such that excess material of the buffer layer is removed. The method continues with block <b>108</b> where a portion of the buffer layer is removed within the first trench and an insulator layer is deposited over the buffer layer within the first trench. Removing the portion of the buffer layer may include recessing back the buffer layer by an etching process. Depositing the insulator layer may include epi growing the insulator layer over the buffer layer within the first trench. At block <b>110</b>, a second dielectric layer is deposited over the substrate including the insulator layer and a second trench is formed in the second dielectric layer. The formation of the second trench may include patterning a mask layer and etching the second dielectric layer using the mask layer such that a surface of the insulator layer is exposed. At block <b>112</b>, a fin structure is formed by depositing a semiconductor material over the insulator layer within the second trench and perform a planarizing process on the substrate including the fin structure. Forming the fin structure may include epi growing the semiconductor material over the insulator layer within the second trench such that the semiconductor material substantially fills the second trench. The planarizing process may be performed such that excess material of the semiconductor material of the fin structure is removed. The method continues with block <b>114</b> where a portion of the second dielectric layer is removed. Removing the second dielectric layer may include an etching process such that the sidewalls of the fin structure are exposed. The method <b>100</b> continues with block <b>116</b> where fabrication of the integrated circuit device is completed.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Completing the fabrication process may include, among other things, forming a gate stack over a channel region of the fin structure and forming source and drain (S/D) feature in a S/D region of the semiconductor device. Forming the gate stack may be a gate first or a gate last process. For example, in a gate first process, forming the gate stack may include depositing a dielectric layer over the fin structure in the central region, forming a gate structure (e.g., gate electrode) over the dielectric layer, and forming gate spacers on the walls of the gate structure and adjacent to the S/D region of the semiconductor device. Thereafter, a S/D feature may be formed in the S/D region by recessing the semiconductor material in the S/D region and depositing a doped semiconductor material in the S/D region. The deposition of the doped semiconductor material may include epi growing the semiconductor material. Additional steps can be provided before, during, and after the method <b>100</b>, and some of the steps described can be replaced or eliminated for other embodiments of the method. The discussion that follows illustrates various embodiments of a semiconductor device that can be fabricated according to the method <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-11</figref> illustrate diagrammatic cross-sectional side views of one embodiment of a semiconductor device at various stages of fabrication, according to the method of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. Additionally, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> illustrates a perspective view of one embodiment of the semiconductor device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-11</figref>, at a later stage of fabrication, according to the method of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. As noted above, in the present disclosure, the semiconductor device is a FinFET device. The FinFET device includes any fin-based, multi-gate transistor. The FinFET device <b>200</b> may be included in a microprocessor, memory cell, and/or other integrated circuit device. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-12</figref> have been simplified for the sake of clarity to better understand the inventive concepts of the present disclosure. Additional features can be added in the FinFET device <b>200</b>, and some of the features described below can be replaced or eliminated in other embodiments of the semiconductor device <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the FinFET device <b>200</b> includes a substrate (e.g., wafer) <b>210</b>. The substrate <b>210</b> is a bulk substrate that includes, for example, silicon, silicon germanium, and/or germanium, or any other suitable material. Alternatively, the substrate <b>210</b> comprises an elementary semiconductor; a compound semiconductor, such as silicon carbide, gallium arsenic, gallium phosphide, indium phosphide, indium arsenide, and/or indium antimonide; or combinations thereof. Alternatively, the substrate <b>210</b> includes a silicon-on-insulator (SOI) substrate. The SOI substrate can be fabricated using separation by implantation of oxygen (SIMOX), wafer bonding, and/or other suitable methods. The substrate <b>210</b> may include various doped regions and other suitable features. In the above alternative embodiments, the substrate <b>210</b> may further include epitaxial (epi) silicon, epitaxial (epi) germanium, and/or epitaxial (epi) silicon germanium.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">With further reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, deposited over the substrate <b>210</b> is a first dielectric layer <b>212</b>. The first dielectric layer <b>212</b> is formed by any suitable process to any suitable thickness. In the present embodiment, the first dielectric layer <b>212</b> includes silicon oxide and is formed by a CVD or a thermal oxidation process to a thickness from about 3,000 Angstroms to about 5,000 Angstroms. Alternatively, the first dielectric layer <b>212</b> includes a dielectric material such as high-k dielectric material, other suitable dielectric material, or combinations thereof. In certain embodiments, the first dielectric layer <b>212</b> is formed to a thickness from about 2,000 Angstroms to about 10,000 Angstroms. Examples of high-k dielectric material include HfO2, HfSiO, HfSiON, HfTaO, HfTiO, HfZrO, zirconium oxide, aluminum oxide, hafnium dioxide-alumina (HfO2-Al2O3) alloy, other suitable high-k dielectric materials, and/or combinations thereof. The thermal oxidation process may be a dry or a wet process. In various examples, the silicon oxide can be formed by physical vapor deposition (PVD), atomic layer deposition (ALD), high density plasma CVD (HDPCVD), other suitable methods, and/or combinations thereof. The CVD process, for example, may use chemicals including Hexachlorodisilane (HCD or Si2C16), Dichlorosilane (DCS or SiH2Cl2), Bis(TertiaryButylAmino)Silane (BTBAS or C8H22N2Si) and Disilane (DS or Si2H6).</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a first trench <b>214</b> is formed in the first dielectric layer <b>212</b>. In the present embodiment, the first trench <b>214</b> is formed by an etching process such that a surface of the substrate <b>210</b> is exposed. The etching process may include a wet etching, a dry etching process, or a combination thereof. In one example, a dry etching process may include forming a photoresist layer, patterning the photoresist layer, etching the first dielectric layer <b>212</b>, and removing the photoresist layer. In furtherance of the example, the dry etching process used to etch the first dielectric layer <b>212</b> may include a chemistry including fluorine-containing gas. In furtherance of the example, the chemistry of the dry etch includes CF4, SF6, or NF3.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a buffer layer <b>216</b> is deposited over the exposed surface of the substrate <b>210</b> within the first trench <b>214</b>. In the present embodiment, depositing the buffer layer <b>216</b> includes a aspect ratio trapping (ART) method. The ART method includes epitaxially (epi) growing a buffer layer <b>216</b> such that it substantially fills the first trench <b>214</b> (e.g., epi growing the buffer layer <b>216</b> to a thickness of at least 3,000 Angstroms). The ART method traps defects arising from lattice mismatch (e.g., mismatch between the lattice of the substrate <b>210</b> and the buffer layer <b>216</b>) by laterally confining sidewalls of the buffer layer <b>216</b> within the first trench <b>214</b>, during the growing process. In other words, defects (e.g., dislocations) originating at the interface of the substrate <b>210</b> and the buffer layer <b>216</b> are trapped. As such, defects (e.g., dislocations) in the upper portion of the buffer layer <b>216</b> are minimized or eliminated. Minimizing defects in the buffer layer <b>216</b> is desirable because as defects are minimized substrate loss is also minimized.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The buffer layer material is chosen such that defects arising from lattice mismatch are eliminated as the buffer layer <b>216</b> grows. The buffer layer <b>216</b> can be either a dielectric material, high/low band material, or a conductive material. In the present embodiment, the buffer layer <b>216</b> includes a type III/V material having a crystal structure, for example, the buffer layer <b>216</b> includes a material selected from the group consisting of AlAs, AlAs/Ge, InP, In(Ga)As, InAs, and InSb. Alternatively, the buffer layer <b>216</b> includes any suitable material that has a lattice constant that is close enough to the lattice constant of the substrate <b>210</b> such that as the buffer layer <b>216</b> epi grows, no defects (e.g., dislocations) are present toward the upper portion of the buffer layer <b>216</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, a planarizing process is performed on the substrate <b>210</b> including the buffer layer <b>216</b>. In the present embodiment, the planarizing process includes a chemical mechanical polishing (CMP) process applied to the FinFET device <b>200</b> to remove excessive portions of buffer layer <b>216</b>. The planarizing process may be performed such that a top surface of the buffer layer <b>216</b> is in a plane with a top surface of the first buffer layer <b>212</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the buffer layer <b>216</b> is recessed within the first trench <b>214</b>. In the present embodiment, recessing the buffer layer <b>216</b> includes removing a portion of the buffer layer <b>216</b> by a wet etching process that etches back excessive buffer layer <b>216</b> material in the first trench <b>214</b> of the FinFET device <b>200</b>, thus exposing a portion of the sidewalls of the trench <b>214</b>. The buffer layer <b>216</b>, for example, is etched back from about 500 Angstroms to about 2,000 Angstroms. The wet etching process may include a chemistry including HCl, Cl2, or any suitable chemistry appropriate for the buffer layer <b>216</b> material. Alternatively, the etching process may include a dry etching process, or a combination of wet and dry etching processes. In one example, a dry etching process may include forming a photoresist layer, patterning the photoresist layer, etching the buffer layer <b>216</b>, and removing the photoresist layer.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, an insulator layer <b>218</b> is deposited over the buffer layer <b>216</b> within the first trench <b>214</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. The insulator layer <b>218</b> may be deposited within the same chamber or by the same machine used to perform the processes of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> above. The insulator layer <b>218</b> may be deposited by any suitable process to any suitable thickness. For example, depositing the insulator layer <b>218</b> includes epitaxially (epi) growing the insulator layer <b>218</b> in the first trench <b>214</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. In the present embodiment, the insulator layer <b>218</b> is deposited to a thickness greater than about 500 Angstroms such the first trench <b>214</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is substantially filled. Alternatively, as long as the insulator layer <b>218</b> can function as an isolation structure, the insulator layer <b>218</b> is deposited such that the first trench <b>214</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is not substantially filled. In the present embodiment, the insulator layer <b>218</b> includes a high band gap III/V material having a crystal structure, for example, the insulator layer <b>218</b> includes a material selected from the group consisting of AlAsSb, GaAsSb, and InAlAs. Alternatively, the insulator layer <b>218</b> includes any suitable dielectric material that can function as an isolation material. The insulator layer <b>218</b> may be chosen such that the lattice constant of the buffer layer <b>216</b> is substantially similar to the lattice constant of the insulator layer <b>218</b>, thereby providing substantially dislocation free deposition of the insulator layer <b>218</b> on the buffer layer <b>216</b>. Also, because the top surface and/or interface of the buffer layer <b>216</b>, underlying the insulator layer <b>218</b>, is substantially defect free (e.g., few or no dislocations), the deposition process used to form the insulator layer <b>218</b> provides for an insulator layer <b>218</b> that includes few or no defects (e.g., dislocations). Because the insulator layer <b>218</b> includes few or no defects, the top surface and/or interface of the insulator layer <b>218</b> is substantially defect free, thereby reducing or even eliminating substrate losses through the insulator layer <b>218</b> and the buffer layer <b>216</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, a second dielectric layer <b>220</b> is deposited over the substrate <b>210</b> including the insulator layer <b>218</b>. The second dielectric layer <b>220</b> may be deposited by any suitable process to any suitable thickness. The thickness of the dielectric layer <b>220</b> defines the height of a fin structure that is subsequently formed. In the present embodiment, the second dielectric layer <b>220</b> includes silicon oxide and is formed by a CVD process to a thickness from about 1,000 Angstroms to about 3,000 Angstroms. Alternatively, the second dielectric layer <b>220</b> includes a dielectric material such as high-k dielectric material, other suitable dielectric material, or combinations thereof. Examples of high-k dielectric material include HfO2, HfSiO, HfSiON, HfTaO, HfTiO, HfZrO, zirconium oxide, aluminum oxide, hafnium dioxide-alumina (HfO2-Al2O3) alloy, other suitable high-k dielectric materials, and/or combinations thereof. In various examples, the silicon oxide can be formed by physical vapor deposition (PVD), atomic layer deposition (ALD), high density plasma CVD (HDPCVD), other suitable methods, and/or combinations thereof. The CVD process, for example, may use chemicals including Hexachlorodisilane (HCD or Si2C16), Dichlorosilane (DCS or SiH2Cl2), Bis(TertiaryButylAmino)Silane (BTBAS or C8H22N2Si) and Disilane (DS or Si2H6).</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, a second trench <b>222</b> is formed in the second dielectric layer <b>220</b>. In the present embodiment, the second trench <b>222</b> is formed by an etching process such that a surface of the insulator layer <b>218</b> is exposed (e.g., etching away a thickness of at least about 1,000 Angstroms of the second dielectric layer <b>220</b>). The etching process includes a multiple step etching combination process including a wet etching and a dry etching process. For example, the multiple step etching process includes first performing a dry etching process to substantially remove the second dielectric layer <b>220</b> material within the second trench <b>222</b>, and second performing a wet etching process to remove the remaining second dielectric layer <b>220</b> material within the trench and stopping on the insulator layer <b>218</b>, thereby exposing a surface of the insulator layer <b>218</b>. In further examples, the multiple step etching process includes performing additional sequences of dry and/or wet etching process. Alternatively the multiple step etching process includes first performing the wet etching process and second performing the dry etching process. The alternative embodiment further includes performing additional dry and/or wet etching processes. Alternatively, the etching process includes performing only a wet etching process or performing only a dry etching process. In one example, a wet etching process may include a chemistry including HCl, Cl2, or any suitable chemistry appropriate for the second dielectric layer <b>220</b> material. In one example, a dry etching process may include forming a photoresist layer, patterning the photoresist layer, etching the second dielectric layer <b>220</b>, and removing the photoresist layer. In furtherance of the example, the dry etching process used to etch the second dielectric layer <b>220</b> may include a chemistry including fluorine-containing gas. In furtherance of the example, the chemistry of the dry etch includes CF4, SF6, or NF3.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, a fin structure <b>224</b> of the FinFET device <b>200</b> is formed. Forming the fin structure <b>224</b> includes depositing a material, over the exposed surface of the insulator layer <b>218</b>, within the second trench <b>222</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>). In the present embodiment, depositing the buffer layer <b>216</b> includes epitaxially (epi) growing a semiconductor material such that it substantially fills the second trench <b>222</b> (e.g., epi growing the semiconductor material to a thickness of at least about 1,000 Angstroms). The epitaxy process may include CVD deposition techniques (e.g., vapor-phase epitaxy (VPE) and/or ultra-high vacuum CVD (UHV-CVD)), molecular beam epitaxy, and/or other suitable processes. In the present embodiment, the semiconductor material of the fin structure <b>224</b> includes a type III/V material such as InAs, InGaAs, InGaSb, InP, AlSb, and the like. Alternatively, the fin structure includes Ge or any other suitable semiconductor material.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, a planarizing process is performed on the FinFET device <b>200</b> including the fin structure <b>224</b>. In the present embodiment, the planarizing process includes a chemical mechanical polishing (CMP) process applied to the FinFET device <b>200</b> to remove excessive portions of the fin structure <b>224</b> material. The planarizing process may be performed such that a top surface of the fin structure <b>224</b> is in the same plane as a top surface of the second dielectric layer <b>220</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, the second dielectric layer <b>220</b> is recessed to expose sidewalls of the fin structure <b>224</b>. In the present embodiment, recessing the second dielectric layer <b>220</b> may include a photolithography and etching process that etches back excessive second dielectric layer <b>220</b> of the FinFET device <b>200</b>, thus exposing a portion of the sidewalls of the fin structure <b>224</b>. The second dielectric layer <b>220</b>, for example, is etched back at least about 100 Angstroms. Alternatively, the second dielectric layer <b>220</b> is etched back from about 100 Angstroms to about 2600 Angstroms. Alternatively, recessing the second dielectric layer <b>220</b> includes removing any suitable thickness of the second dielectric layer <b>220</b>, such that sidewalls of the fin structure <b>224</b> are exposed. The etching process may include a wet etching, a dry etching process, or a combination thereof. In one example, a wet etching process may include a chemistry including HCl, Cl2, or any suitable chemistry appropriate for the second dielectric layer <b>220</b> material. In one example, a dry etching process may include forming a photoresist layer, patterning the photoresist layer, etching the second dielectric layer <b>220</b>, and removing the photoresist layer. In furtherance of the example, the dry etching process used to etch the second dielectric layer <b>220</b> may include a chemistry including fluorine-containing gas. In furtherance of the example, the chemistry of the dry etch includes CF4, SF6, or NF3.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, the FinFET device <b>200</b> includes a gate structure <b>226</b>. The gate structure <b>226</b> traverses the fin structure <b>224</b>, separating a source and drain (S/D) feature <b>228</b> of the fin structure <b>224</b>. The S/D feature <b>228</b> defines a channel region therebetween and underlying the gate structure <b>226</b>. The gate structure <b>226</b> may include a gate dielectric layer <b>230</b>, a gate electrode <b>232</b>, and gate spacers. The gate dielectric layer <b>230</b> includes a dielectric material, such as silicon oxide, high-k dielectric material, other suitable dielectric material, or combinations thereof. Examples of high-k dielectric material include HfO2, HfSiO, HfSiON, HfTaO, HfTiO, HfZrO, zirconium oxide, aluminum oxide, hafnium dioxide-alumina (HfO2-Al2O3) alloy, other suitable high-k dielectric materials, and/or combinations thereof. The gate electrode <b>232</b> includes polysilicon and/or a metal including Al, Cu, Ti, Ta, W, Mo, TaN, NiSi, CoSi, TiN, WN, TiAl, TiAlN, TaCN, TaC, TaSiN, other conductive materials, or combinations thereof. The gate structure <b>226</b> may include numerous other layers, for example, capping layers, interface layers, diffusion layers, barrier layers, or combinations thereof. A hard mask layer may be formed over the gate structure <b>226</b>. The hard mask layer may include silicon oxide, silicon nitride, silicon oxynitride, silicon carbide, other suitable material, or combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The gate structure <b>226</b> is formed by a suitable process, including deposition, lithography patterning, and etching processes. The deposition processes include chemical vapor deposition (CVD), physical vapor deposition (PVD), atomic layer deposition (ALD), high density plasma CVD (HDPCVD), metal organic CVD (MOCVD), remote plasma CVD (RPCVD), plasma enhanced CVD (PECVD), low-pressure CVD (LPCVD), atomic layer CVD (ALCVD), atmospheric pressure CVD (APCVD), plating, other suitable methods, or combinations thereof. The lithography patterning processes include photoresist coating (e.g., spin-on coating), soft baking, mask aligning, exposure, post-exposure baking, developing the photoresist, rinsing, drying (e.g., hard baking), other suitable processes, or combinations thereof. Alternatively, the lithography exposing process is implemented or replaced by other methods, such as maskless photolithography, electron-beam writing, and ion-beam writing. In yet another alternative, the lithography patterning process could implement nanoimprint technology. The etching processes include dry etching, wet etching, and/or other etching methods.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The gate electrode <b>232</b> may be formed in a gate first or a gate last process. For example, in a gate first process, the gate structure <b>226</b> is formed and thereafter the S/D feature <b>228</b> is formed by any suitable process. For example, after forming the gate structure <b>226</b>, exposed portions of the fin structure <b>224</b> material (e.g., in the S/D region) are removed while the covered portions (e.g., in the channel region) of the fin structure <b>224</b> material are not removed. Removing the exposed portions of the fin structure <b>224</b> material may include removing the fin structure <b>224</b> material thereby forming recesses in the FinFET device <b>200</b> and exposing a surface of the insulator layer <b>218</b>. Alternatively, recesses are not formed and/or a surface of the insulator layer <b>218</b> is not exposed. Removing the exposed portions of the fin structure <b>224</b> may be performed by an etching process. The etching process may be a dry etching process, a wet etching process, or a combination thereof. Subsequent to the removal of the portions of the fin structure <b>224</b> material, S/D feature <b>228</b> of the fin structure <b>224</b> is epi grown in place of the removed fin structure <b>224</b> material.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">As noted above, the S/D feature <b>228</b> (which is stressed) may be formed using an epitaxy process. The epitaxy process may include CVD deposition techniques (e.g., vapor-phase epitaxy (VPE) and/or ultra-high vacuum CVD (UHV-CVD)), molecular beam epitaxy, and/or other suitable processes. The epitaxy process may use gaseous and/or liquid precursors, which interact with the composition (e.g., silicon) of the fin structure <b>224</b> and/or the exposed insulator layer <b>218</b>. In the present embodiment, S/D feature <b>228</b> includes type III/V semiconductor materials such as InGaAs, InP, GaSb, InAs, AlSb, InSb, and the like. Alternatively, S/D feature <b>228</b> includes Ge or any other suitable semiconductor material.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In a gate last process, similar processes/materials are used as respect to a gate first process; thus, these process/materials are not repeated herein. The difference being, however, between the gate first process and a gate last process, that a gate last process uses a dummy gate structure during the formation of the S/D feature. Thereafter, the dummy gate structure is removed and the gate final structure is formed.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In the depicted embodiment, the FinFET device <b>200</b> may be a PMOS device or an NMOS device. The S/D feature <b>228</b> may be doped during its deposition (growth) by adding n-type impurities (such as phosphorous) and p-type impurities (such as boron) to the source material of the epitaxy process or subsequent to its deposition growth process by an ion implantation process. The doped epitaxial layer may have a gradient doping profile. Subsequently, a CMP process may be performed to planarize the strained S/D feature <b>228</b>. Prior to or after forming the strained S/D feature <b>228</b>, implantation, diffusion, and/or annealing processes may be performed to form heavily doped S/D (HDD) features in the S/D feature <b>228</b> of the FinFET device <b>200</b>, of a p-type if the FinFET device <b>200</b> is a PMOS device, or of an n-type if the FinFET device <b>200</b> is an NMOS device.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">A benefit of the method <b>100</b> and FinFET device <b>200</b> is that the buffer layer <b>216</b> uses aspect ratio trapping (ART) method to trap defects (e.g., dislocations) and thereby minimize lattice mismatch and allow the insulator layer <b>218</b> to better isolate the S/D feature <b>228</b> of the fin structure <b>224</b>. As such, substrate leakage of the FinFET device is lowered or even eliminated, thereby improving efficiency and carrier mobility of the FinFET device <b>200</b>. Further, the method disclosed for achieving the FinFET device <b>200</b>, described herein, is easily implemented into current processing. Different embodiments may have different advantages, and no particular advantage is necessarily required of any embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The FinFET device <b>200</b> may include additional features, which may be formed by subsequent processing. For example, various contacts/vias/lines and multilayer interconnect features (e.g., metal layers and interlayer dielectrics) may be formed over the substrate <b>210</b>, configured to connect the various features or structures of the FinFET device <b>200</b>. The additional features may provide electrical interconnection to the FinFET device <b>200</b>. For example, a multilayer interconnection includes vertical interconnects, such as conventional vias or contacts, and horizontal interconnects, such as metal lines. The various interconnection features may implement various conductive materials including copper, tungsten, and/or silicide. In one example, a damascene and/or dual damascene process is used to form a copper related multilayer interconnection structure.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Thus, provided is a semiconductor device. An exemplary semiconductor device includes a substrate includes including a first dielectric layer disposed over the substrate. The semiconductor device further includes a buffer layer disposed over the substrate and between a first and second wall of a trench of the dielectric layer. The semiconductor device further includes an insulator layer disposed over the buffer layer and between the first and second wall of the trench of the dielectric layer. The semiconductor device also includes a second dielectric layer disposed over the first dielectric layer and the insulator layer. Further, the semiconductor device includes a fin structure disposed over the insulator layer and between a first and second wall of a trench of the second dielectric layer.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In some embodiments, the semiconductor device further includes a gate structure disposed over the fin structure. The gate structure separates a source and drain region of the semiconductor device. The source and drain region define a channel region therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In some embodiments, the buffer layer is a type III/V material having a crystal structure, and the insulator layer is a type III/V material having a crystal structure. In various embodiments, the buffer layer includes a material selected from the group consisting of InP, InGaAs, and InSb, and the insulator layer includes a material selected from the group consisting of AlAsSb and InAlAs. In certain embodiments, the buffer layer includes a thickness from about 3,000 Angstroms to about 10,000 Angstroms, and the insulator layer includes a thickness from about 500 Angstroms to about 2,000 Angstroms. In some embodiments, the buffer layer is an aspect ratio trapped (ART) layer, and the insulator layer is substantially dislocation free. In various embodiments, the semiconductor device is one of a P-type metal-oxide-semiconductor (PMOS) fin-like field effect transistor (FinFET) device or a N-type metal-oxide-semiconductor (NMOS) FinFET device, and the semiconductor device is included in an integrated circuit device.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Also provided is a alternative embodiment of a semiconductor device. The exemplary semiconductor device includes a substrate and a buffer layer formed over the substrate and interposed between a first dielectric layer. The semiconductor device further includes an insulator layer formed over the buffer layer and interposed between the first dielectric layer. Further, the semiconductor device includes a fin structure formed over the insulator layer and interposed between a second dielectric layer, the second dielectric layer being formed over the first dielectric layer and over the insulator layer.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In some embodiments, the semiconductor device further includes a gate dielectric layer disposed on a central portion of the fin structure and a gate electrode disposed on the dielectric layer. The gate electrode traverses the fin structure and separates a strained source and drain feature of the semiconductor device. The strained source and drain feature define a channel region of the fin structure therebetween. The strained source and drain feature include a type III/V material. The strained source and drain feature and the channel region of the fin structure have different lattice constants. In various embodiments, the semiconductor device further includes an interface between the buffer layer and the insulator layer that is substantially dislocation free, and an interface between the insulator layer and the fin structure that is substantially dislocation free.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In some embodiments, the buffer layer includes a material having a crystal structure, and the insulator layer includes a material having a crystal structure. In various embodiments, the buffer layer includes a dielectric material, and the insulator layer includes a high band gap dielectric material.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Also provided is a method. The method includes providing a substrate and depositing a first dielectric layer on the substrate. The method further includes, forming a first trench in the first dielectric layer exposing a surface of the substrate. The method further includes depositing a buffer layer over the exposed surface of the substrate within the first trench. The method also includes recessing the buffer layer within the first trench and depositing an insulator layer over the recessed buffer layer within the first trench. The method also includes depositing a second dielectric layer over the substrate including the insulator layer. Further, the method includes forming a second trench in the second dielectric layer exposing a surface of the insulator layer. Also, the method includes forming a fin structure over the exposed surface of the insulator layer within the second trench and removing a portion of the second dielectric layer exposing sidewalls of the fin structure.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In some embodiments, the method further includes after depositing the buffer layer and before recessing the buffer layer, performing a planarizing process on the substrate including the buffer layer. The method further includes after forming the fin structure and before removing the portion of the second dielectric layer, performing a planarizing process on the substrate including the fin structure. The method further includes forming a gate structure over the fin structure including the exposed sidewalls. The gate structure separates a source and drain region of the semiconductor device. The source and drain region define a channel region therebetween. The method further includes removing the fin structure in the source and drain region, and forming a stressed source and drain feature of the fin structure in the source and drain region.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In some embodiments, removing the fin structure in the source and drain region includes forming recesses in the semiconductor device and exposing a surface of the insulator layer, and forming the stressed source and drain feature includes epitaxially (epi) growing the source and drain feature on the exposed surface of the insulator layer within the recesses. In certain embodiments, forming the gate structure includes, in a central region of the fin structure, forming a gate dielectric layer and forming a gate electrode over the gate dielectric layer. In various embodiments, depositing the buffer layer includes epi growing a type III/V material, and depositing the insulator layer includes epi growing a type III/V material. In further embodiments, depositing the buffer layer includes utilizing an aspect ratio trapping (ART) method. The ART method includes epi growing the buffer layer such that the first trench is substantially filled, and trapping dislocations of the buffer layer by laterally confining sidewalls of the buffer layer within the first trench during the epi growing process such that a top surface of the buffer layer is substantially dislocation free. In certain embodiments, depositing the insulator layer includes epi growing a dielectric material that is substantially dislocation free. In various embodiments, recessing the buffer layer includes performing a wet etching process in an apparatus, depositing the insulator layer includes epi growing a high band III/V dielectric material in the apparatus, and forming the second trench includes a two step etching process comprising: a first step including a dry etching process; and a second step including a wet etching process, the wet etching process stopping on the insulator layer.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The foregoing outlines features of several embodiments so that those skilled in the art may better understand the aspects of the present disclosure. Those skilled in the art should appreciate that they may readily use the present disclosure as a basis for designing or modifying other processes and structures for carrying out the same purposes and/or achieving the same advantages of the embodiments introduced herein. Those skilled in the art should also realize that such equivalent constructions do not depart from the spirit and scope of the present disclosure, and that they may make various changes, substitutions, and alterations herein without departing from the spirit and scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A semiconductor device comprising:
<claim-text>a substrate</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first dielectric layer disposed over the substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a buffer layer disposed over the substrate and between first and second walls of a trench of the dielectric layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an insulator layer disposed over the buffer layer and between the first and second wall of the trench of the dielectric layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second dielectric layer disposed over the first dielectric layer and the insulator layer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fin structure disposed over the insulator layer and between first and second walls of a trench of the second dielectric layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The semiconductor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>a gate structure disposed over the fin structure, the gate structure separating source and drain regions of the semiconductor device, the source and drain regions defining a channel region therebetween.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The semiconductor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the buffer layer is a type III/V material having a crystal structure, and
<claim-text>wherein insulator layer is a type III/V material having a crystal structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The semiconductor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the buffer layer includes a material selected from the group consisting of AlAs, AlAs/Ge, InP, InGaAs, InAs, and InSb, and
<claim-text>wherein the insulator layer includes a material selected from the group consisting of A<b>1</b>AsSb, GaAsSb, and InAlAs.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The semiconductor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the buffer layer includes a thickness from about 3,000 Angstroms to about 10,000 Angstroms, and
<claim-text>wherein the insulator layer includes a thickness from about 500 Angstroms to about 2,000 Angstroms.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The semiconductor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein buffer layer is an aspect ratio trapped (ART) layer, and
<claim-text>wherein the insulator layer is substantially dislocation free.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The semiconductor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the semiconductor device is one of a P-type metal-oxide-semiconductor (PMOS) fin-like field effect transistor (FinFET) device or a N-type metal-oxide-semiconductor (NMOS) FinFET device, and
<claim-text>wherein the semiconductor device is included in an integrated circuit device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A semiconductor device comprising:
<claim-text>a substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a buffer layer formed over the substrate and interposed between a first dielectric layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an insulator layer formed over the buffer layer and interposed between the first dielectric layer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fin structure formed over the insulator layer and interposed between a second dielectric layer, the second dielectric layer being formed over the first dielectric layer and over the insulator layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The semiconductor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>a gate dielectric layer disposed on a central portion of the fin structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a gate electrode disposed on the dielectric layer, the gate electrode traversing the fin structure and separating a strained source and drain feature of the semiconductor device, the strained source and drain feature defining a channel region of the fin structure therebetween,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the strained source and drain feature includes a type III/V material, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the strained source and drain feature and the channel region of the fin structure have different lattice constants.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The semiconductor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> further comprising;
<claim-text>an interface between the buffer layer and the insulator layer that is substantially dislocation free; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an interface between the insulator layer and the fin structure that is substantially dislocation free.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The semiconductor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> wherein the buffer layer includes a material having a crystal structure, and
<claim-text>wherein the insulator layer includes a high band gap material having a crystal structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The semiconductor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> wherein the buffer layer includes a dielectric material, and
<claim-text>wherein the insulator layer includes a high band gap dielectric material.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A method of manufacturing a semiconductor device, comprising:
<claim-text>providing a substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a first dielectric layer on the substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first trench in the first dielectric layer exposing a surface of the substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a buffer layer over the exposed surface of the substrate within the first trench;</claim-text>
<claim-text>recessing the buffer layer within the first trench;</claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing an insulator layer over the recessed buffer layer within the first trench;</claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a second dielectric layer over the substrate including the insulator layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second trench in the second dielectric layer exposing a surface of the insulator layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a fin structure over the exposed surface of the insulator layer within the second trench; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>removing a portion of the second dielectric layer exposing sidewalls of the fin structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>after depositing the buffer layer and before recessing the buffer layer, performing a planarizing process on the substrate including the buffer layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>after forming the fin structure and before removing the portion of the second dielectric layer, performing a planarizing process on the substrate including the fin structure;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a gate structure over the fin structure including the exposed sidewalls, the gate structure separating a source and drain region of the semiconductor device, the source and drain region defining a channel region therebetween;</claim-text>
<claim-text>removing the fin structure in the source and drain region; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a stressed source and drain feature of the fin structure in the source and drain region.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref> wherein removing the fin structure in the source and drain region includes forming recesses in the semiconductor device and exposing a surface of the insulator layer, and
<claim-text>wherein forming the stressed source and drain feature includes epitaxially (epi) growing the source and drain feature on the exposed surface of the insulator layer within the recesses.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref> wherein forming the gate structure includes, in a central region of the fin structure, forming a gate dielectric layer and forming a gate electrode over the gate dielectric layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> wherein depositing the buffer layer includes epi growing a type III/V material, and
<claim-text>wherein depositing the insulator layer includes epi growing a type III/V material.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> wherein depositing the buffer layer includes utilizing an aspect ratio trapping (ART) method, the ART method including:
<claim-text>epi growing the buffer layer such that the first trench is substantially filled, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>trapping dislocations of the buffer layer by laterally confining sidewalls of the buffer layer within the first trench during the epi growing process such that a top surface of the buffer layer is substantially dislocation free.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> wherein depositing the insulator layer includes epi growing a dielectric material that is substantially dislocation free.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> wherein recessing the buffer layer includes performing a wet etching process in an apparatus,
<claim-text>wherein depositing the insulator layer includes epi growing a high band III/V dielectric material in the apparatus, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein forming the second trench includes a two step etching process comprising:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first step including a dry etching process; and
<claim-text>a second step including a wet etching process, the wet etching process stopping on the insulator layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
