<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622345-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622345</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13063054</doc-number>
<date>20090910</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>FR</country>
<doc-number>08 56085</doc-number>
<date>20080910</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>325</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>64</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2441186</main-classification>
<further-classification>297232</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Passenger seat system incorporating a multi-functional furniture unit, and an aircraft comprising such a system</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2947349</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kryter</name>
<date>19600800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5954401</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Koch et al.</name>
<date>19990900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6059364</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Dryburgh et al.</name>
<date>20000500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2001/0000639</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Park et al.</name>
<date>20010500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2001/0003962</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Park et al.</name>
<date>20010600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2001/0015566</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Park et al.</name>
<date>20010800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0218095</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Saint Jalmes</name>
<date>20031100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2441185</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0241232</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Thompson</name>
<date>20071000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2441186</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10 2006 007854</doc-number>
<date>20070800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>GB</country>
<doc-number>2 295 962</doc-number>
<date>19960600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00011">
<othercit>International Search Report issued Nov. 23, 2009 in PCT/FR09/001082 filed Sep. 10, 2009.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>10</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2441185</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2441186</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>297232</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>297248</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>105315</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>15</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110210204</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110901</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Collins</last-name>
<first-name>Alexandra</first-name>
<address>
<city>Geneva</city>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CH</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Collins</last-name>
<first-name>Mark</first-name>
<address>
<city>Geneva</city>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CH</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Collins</last-name>
<first-name>Alexandra</first-name>
<address>
<city>Geneva</city>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Collins</last-name>
<first-name>Mark</first-name>
<address>
<city>Geneva</city>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Oblon, Spivak, McClelland, Maier &#x26; Neustadt, L.L.P.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Airbus</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Blagnac</city>
<country>FR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Swiatek</last-name>
<first-name>Rob</first-name>
<department>3643</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/FR2009/001082</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20090910</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20110516</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2011/030006</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20110317</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A passenger seat system including a plurality of seat modules, in which each seat module may be configured to form a more or less flat bed. The seat modules are arranged side by side in longitudinally offset relative positions, and each seat module is configured to form a bed from a convertible seat and a fixed footrest. The footrest is integrated into a box structure, which includes an upper surface arranged as a fixed shelf for the passenger in the adjacent seat module.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="101.77mm" wi="154.94mm" file="US08622345-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="220.39mm" wi="179.83mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622345-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="229.02mm" wi="172.30mm" file="US08622345-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="188.38mm" wi="165.27mm" file="US08622345-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="210.48mm" wi="165.61mm" file="US08622345-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="232.83mm" wi="167.72mm" file="US08622345-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="217.42mm" wi="171.96mm" file="US08622345-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="234.95mm" wi="172.64mm" file="US08622345-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="213.95mm" wi="133.10mm" file="US08622345-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This invention relates to a passenger seat system, especially for an aircraft, and to an associated aircraft, and more particularly to such a system comprising a plurality of seat modules where each seat module may be configured to form a more or less flat bed.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">On commercial aircraft flights, particularly in the classes known as higher (first class, &#x201c;business&#x201d; class, . . . ), the passengers are the object of special attention on the part of the aircraft manufacturers.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In particular, the passengers in the higher classes often have the possibility of tilting their seat in a more or less horizontal position, in order to convert their armchair into a bed, as for example the convertible aircraft seat such as described in the patent application EP 1 207 074 or US 2001/000639.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In order to isolate the passengers from each other and to preserve a certain privacy among the passengers, it is known, in document FR 2 904 805, to propose a seat module integrating such convertible seats and a separation panel concealing the passenger occupying the seat from the eyes of the other passengers seated in the same aircraft cabin.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">To further enhance the comfort of the passengers, the bed formed in the module comprises an additional sitting surface or an ottoman, situated adjacent to the back of the module in front, which extends the armchair in a horizontal position to accommodate and support the passenger's feet. It will be easily understood that the upper surface of the additional sitting surface is more or less coplanar with the seat in bed position.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">These seat modules are installed parallel to the longitudinal axis of the aircraft, either by pair aligned in a double column in the middle of the cabin (central group), or individually in a column of a single module near the two fuselages (side groups). In this way, traffic aisles are formed between the side groups and the central group.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">It also is known, from document US 2007/080566, to dispose the seat modules nonparallel to the longitudinal axis of the aircraft, which has the effect of increasing the number of modules in the cabin. In the proposed cabin layout, the seat modules are arranged side by side in longitudinally offset relative position (that is to say offset along their own longitudinal axis), according to an acute angle in relation to the longitudinal axis of the aircraft. These modules also comprise an ottoman, serving as a fixed footrest which, combined with the armchair placed in more or less horizontal position, furnishes the passenger with a bed.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In document GB 2 295 692, a secondary seat is provided facing the passenger's seat so that when the latter is placed in horizontal position in order to create a bed, the secondary seat serves as an end of the bed.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In these different known configurations of seat modules, the passengers moving about in the aisles may be bothered by the direct view onto the feet of the recumbent passengers, the feet resting on the ottoman or on the secondary seat, and this despite the presence, at times, of isolation panels.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Moreover, the spaces for stowage or for setting down objects often are limited in number, the seat modules being unable to be enlarged for fear of causing the traffic aisles to be lost.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">There also is known from document U.S. Pat. No. 2,947,349 a layout of rows of seats in longitudinally offset relative positive position, the rows being staggered. In this configuration, the seat for a passenger extends, to serve as a bed, into a box structure for a passenger in the preceding row.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">This invention has as a purpose to resolve at least one of the aforementioned drawbacks and to propose a seat module that provides in particular an additional stowage shelf.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">To this end, this invention relates in particular to a passenger seat system comprising a plurality of seat modules arranged side by side in longitudinally offset relative position, each seat module being able to be configured to form a bed from a convertible seat and a footrest, the said footrest being integrated into the interior of a fixed box structure, which box structure comprises an upper surface arranged as a fixed shelf for the passenger in the adjacent seat module and comprises, underneath the footrest, a storage compartment for the passenger in the corresponding module.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">According to the invention, the box structure that accommodates the passenger's feet in its interior provides, in its upper part, a shelf for the neighboring passenger, and in its lower part, a stowage space.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In this way, the system according to the invention provides a passenger with an additional shelf surface taken from the space of the neighboring module, without changing the dimensions of the seat modules and therefore the cabin layout. The loss is minimal for the passenger deprived, since only the area at the feet, the one difficult to use, is affected.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Furthermore, the relative offset of two consecutive modules allows an ideal positioning of the additional shelf in lateral proximity to the sitting surface for the neighboring passenger, increasing the comfort of the latter.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Finally, in this way the total volume occupied by the box structure is optimized and the stowage spaces available for the passenger are enhanced, without increasing the dimensions of the seat module.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In one embodiment, the said upper surface is vertical, above the said footrest.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In this configuration, the space taken away on the neighboring module only in the volume above the footrest in bed position is optimized.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In particular, the said footrest is formed by a lower surface of an intermediate space inside the said box structure and the said fixed shelf is formed from a first portion of the top of the said box structure.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">By virtue of this configuration, the footrest is in a space inside the box structure, which reduces the view of the passengers moving about in the aisles at the feet of a recumbent passenger.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">It furthermore will be noted that this intermediate space may be used as stowage space when the module is in seat, and not bed, position.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In one embodiment, a second portion of the said top of the box structure of a module forms a fixed shelf for the passenger in the corresponding module.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In this configuration, the upper surface of the box structure is divided in order to provide a shelf for each of the two passengers at the same time, each passenger taking the part that is the most accessible to him.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In one embodiment, the said top of the box structure has horizontal dimensions smaller than those of the footrest. The horizontal dimensions define the horizontal surface of the upper surface of the box structure. In this configuration, the footrest surface protrudes from the box structure. This portion that protrudes thus easily may be used by a second passenger to sit down facing the passenger in the module, in seated position.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">As a variant, the horizontal dimensions are identical, making it possible to optimize the available surface on the box-structure top to form fixed shelves for the various passengers.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In one embodiment of the invention, each seat module comprises a removable shelf arranged to be stored, in stowed position, in the top of the said intermediate space, added to the said box-structure top. In particular, the said removable shelf is arranged to be extracted from its stowed position by translation toward the passenger seat. In these two configurations, the space in the box structure for the feet is maximized irrespective of the use of a removable shelf that is to be stored in this space.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In one embodiment, the said upper surface arranged as a fixed shelf for the adjacent passenger comprises a vertical rim extending at least along the periphery of the fixed shelf facing the passenger in the corresponding seat module. Such a vertical rim, more or less high, acts as a separation panel shielding a passenger's shelf from the eyes of the neighboring passenger.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">According to one characteristic of the invention, the said box structure forms part of a shell partially surrounding the said adjacent seat.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">According to a specific embodiment, the said seat system being integrated into a vehicle, a system in which the said seat modules are arranged according to an acute angle in relation to the longitudinal axis of the said vehicle, in particular when the vehicle is an aircraft. In this configuration, the seat modules of the same column along the longitudinal axis of the vehicle are adjacent, or adjoining, for implementation of the invention. In this way the invention may be applied to all the seat groups of a vehicle, the central groups as well as the side groups of an aircraft, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">As a variant, the seat modules are arranged parallel to the longitudinal axis of the vehicle. In this case, the invention applies to two adjoining seat columns offset from one another, longitudinally, by a module half-length, for example. In each column, the modules may be aligned longitudinally one behind the other.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The invention also applies to a seat module and an aircraft comprising a seat system such as set forth above.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The aircraft optionally may comprise means relating to the system characteristics set forth above.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Other features and advantages of the invention also will become apparent in the description below, illustrated by the attached drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view from above of a seat module assembly with which an aircraft is equipped;</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> illustrates a seat module in a view from above in accordance with an embodiment of the invention, the seat being in upright position;</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref> is a view similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, the seat being in extended position;</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A and 3B</figref> are elevation views of a column of seat modules in a layout similar to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</figref> respectively;</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows an assembly making up a seat module of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, integrating a removable shelf;</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a view from above of seat modules illustrating the shelf of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> in different positions;</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref> is a view from below of the shelf of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, partially showing the movement means for the shelf;</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref> illustrates the movement means for the shelf between different use positions;</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6C</figref> illustrates means for locking the shelf in position;</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows an exemplary general structure of the shelf according to the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</figref> illustrate an exemplary extension mechanism for the removable shelf, in retracted position and in extended position, respectively;</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is an exploded view of the extension mechanisms of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> shows another exemplary cabin configuration for implementation of the seat and shelf modules according to the invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">First, an aircraft cabin layout in accordance with an embodiment of the invention is going to be described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">As partially shown on <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, an aircraft cabin <b>1</b> comprises a floor <b>2</b>, side walls, of which only one <b>3</b> provided with windows <b>4</b> is shown, as well as a ceiling, not shown for reasons of clarity.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The cabin comprises several seat modules designated by the general reference <b>10</b> making it possible to create a place for each passenger of the aircraft.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Each module <b>10</b> comprises a seat <b>14</b> and a separation panel <b>16</b> defining a personal space <b>12</b> for the passenger.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">As clearly illustrated on <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, various seat modules for a passenger are installed, namely modules <b>10</b> disposed along wall <b>3</b> of the cabin and modules <b>10</b> disposed in the central part of the cabin.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In this central part, seat modules <b>10</b> are, for example, installed in pairs.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Between the central part of the cabin and wall <b>3</b> of the cabin, seat modules <b>10</b> are placed on both sides of an aisle <b>5</b>, provided in the cabin for the movement of passengers and flight crew.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Furthermore, as clearly illustrated on <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, seat modules <b>10</b> are arranged staggered, in relation to each other, on both sides of aisle <b>5</b>. This layout makes it possible to increase the concealing effect produced by separation panels <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">A seat column along longitudinal axis X of the aircraft is made up of seat modules <b>10</b> arranged side by side in longitudinally offset relative position (that is to say in relation to their own longitudinal axis S). Longitudinal axis S of seat modules <b>10</b> forms an acute angle with longitudinal axis X of the aircraft, preferably an angle ranging between 15&#xb0; and 45&#xb0;, for example 30&#xb0;, making it possible to increase the number of seat modules <b>10</b> integrated into the same aircraft length.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">For the remainder of the description, the terms &#x201c;front&#x201d; and &#x201c;rear&#x201d; will refer to longitudinal axis X to designate in particular a passenger or a seat module <b>10</b> in relation to a neighboring passenger or seat module <b>10</b> along this axis.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">In each seat module <b>10</b>, seat <b>14</b> itself comprises a sitting surface <b>13</b> and a back <b>15</b>, positioned along axis S, allowing the passenger to be seated in standard manner in seat <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">On <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, each seat is in an upright position, back <b>15</b> of seat <b>14</b> thus extending more or less vertically in relation in particular to floor <b>2</b> of the aircraft.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Of course, this upright position of seat <b>14</b> also includes the intermediate positions of the seat in which back <b>15</b> is slightly tilted in relation to sitting surface <b>13</b>, for example by an angle of 20 to 30&#xb0; in relation to the vertical.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</figref> illustrate a seat module <b>10</b> in greater detail, each seat <b>14</b> being movable between an upright position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>) and an extended position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The mechanism allowing seat <b>14</b> to change over from the upright position to the extended position, and vice versa, is not illustrated on the Figures. This mechanism may be any mechanism, well known to the individual skilled in the art, making it possible to change the position of the seat.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">In particular, in the extended position, back <b>15</b> of seat <b>14</b> extends in a more or less horizontal position, more or less in the same plane as sitting surface <b>13</b> of the seat.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">As clearly illustrated on <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</figref>, back <b>15</b> preferably comprises a headrest <b>15</b>&#x2032;, forming a pillow for the head of the passenger recumbent on seat <b>14</b>, when the seat is in extended position.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">In this way, seat <b>14</b> in extended position such as illustrated on <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>, forms a bed for the passenger.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In order to increase the length of this bed, seat <b>14</b> may further comprise a wing <b>13</b>&#x2032; in the continuation of sitting surface <b>13</b>, adapted for moving between a more or less vertically folded back position when seat <b>14</b> is in upright position, and an extended position, more or less in the same horizontal plane as sitting surface <b>13</b> and back <b>15</b> of seat <b>14</b> when the latter is in extended position.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">As illustrated on <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A and 3B</figref>, in each seat module <b>10</b>, separation panel or rigid shell <b>16</b> surrounds seat <b>14</b> at the sides and at the rear, and ends, on one of the sides, in the form of a box structure <b>18</b>, or vertical unit, topped by a fixed shelf <b>20</b> available for the passenger.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The front part of personal area <b>12</b> is defined, facing seat <b>14</b> along axis S, by the rear of box structure <b>18</b> of the front module and, on the side opposite rear box structure <b>18</b>, by shell <b>16</b> of module <b>10</b> in front. The other side of the front part is left free so as to provide an access to seat <b>14</b> and to personal space <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">It will be noted here that, as a result of the relative offset of seat modules <b>10</b> among themselves, fixed shelf <b>20</b> is easily accessible for the front passenger, at sitting surface <b>13</b> in particular, while for the rear passenger, the corresponding box structure is far away at the feet and therefore not very convenient.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">As illustrated on <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, box structure <b>18</b> defining the front part of area <b>12</b> comprises a bottom area <b>22</b>, an intermediate area <b>24</b> and a top area <b>25</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">Bottom area <b>22</b> is hollow, forming a stowage space for the rear passenger, closed off by a sliding door, possibly comprising a lock.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">Intermediate area <b>24</b>, hollow, also forms a stowage space for the rear passenger when seat <b>14</b> is in raised upright position or a space to accommodate the feet of the rear passenger when seat <b>14</b> is in extended position. Lower surface <b>23</b> in this compartment <b>24</b> then forms a footrest surface for the rear passenger.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">In extended position, seat <b>14</b> is more or less coplanar with surface <b>23</b>, the end of wing <b>13</b>&#x2032; coming to bear, for example, on the edge of surface <b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">Top <b>25</b> of box structure <b>18</b> defines, as explained above, a fixed shelf <b>20</b> used by the front passenger. A separation rim <b>27</b>, extending vertically over a few centimeters and along the periphery of shelf <b>20</b> facing the rear passenger, makes it possible to conceal the contents of this fixed shelf <b>20</b> from the eyes of the rear passenger.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">Top <b>25</b> of the box structure possibly comprises a fixed shelf portion <b>21</b> for the rear passenger, for example for setting down a cup or a bottle. In this case, the two fixed shelves <b>20</b> and <b>21</b> are separated by vertical separation rim <b>27</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">On the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, top <b>25</b> of box structure <b>18</b> has dimensions, in the horizontal plane, identical to those of footrest surface <b>23</b>. In this way the use of the front part of seat module <b>10</b> is optimized, providing the largest possible surface for fixed shelves <b>20</b> and <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">As a variant, such as illustrated on <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>2</b>A and <b>2</b>B, top <b>25</b> comprises only a fixed shelf <b>20</b> for the front passenger and has horizontal dimensions smaller than those of surface <b>23</b>. In particular, the depth of top <b>25</b> parallel to axis S is smaller in comparison with the corresponding depth of surface <b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">In this way, the latter <b>23</b> partially protrudes from box-structure unit <b>18</b>. This surface part <b>23</b> that protrudes may be used, when seat <b>14</b> is in upright position, as an additional sitting surface for another passenger facing seat <b>14</b> in module <b>10</b>; the rim of top <b>25</b> facing seat <b>14</b> then being able to serve as a backing for the other passenger sitting on additional seat <b>23</b> formed in this way.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">In bed configuration, this surface part <b>23</b> that protrudes supportively accommodates wing <b>13</b>&#x2032; to form a bed (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">For the sake of clarity of these Figures, the references are cited for only a limited number of modules (10) shown, even though all the modules in the cabin are equipped with the corresponding elements.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">The explanations that follow concerning the retractable shelf may be applied equally well to one or the other of these two variants.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">There has been shown on <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> a retractable shelf <b>26</b> (not shown on <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>2</b>A and <b>2</b>B, but provided in these configurations) in opened-out position, that is to say overhanging at least a part of sitting surface <b>13</b> of seat <b>14</b> for an optimum use by the corresponding passenger. On <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref> retractable shelf <b>26</b> is in its stowed position (not visible).</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">On <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, shelf <b>26</b> has been shown in its two extreme positions, namely the fully opened-out position P<b>1</b> for an optimal use by the seated passenger (idem <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>) and the fully stowed position P<b>2</b> where shelf <b>26</b> is accommodated in the top of compartment <b>24</b>, and added underneath fixed shelf <b>20</b> (and possibly fixed shelf <b>21</b> when it is provided).</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">Shelf <b>26</b> in position P<b>2</b> and fixed shelf <b>20</b> (or top <b>25</b>) have similar horizontal dimensions, so that removable shelf <b>26</b> disappears completely into box structure <b>18</b> in stowed position.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">In these two positions P<b>1</b> and P<b>2</b>, retractable shelf <b>26</b> has a horizontal upper surface <b>28</b>. In position P<b>1</b>, this upper surface <b>28</b> forms the table ordinarily used by a passenger.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">The movement mechanism for shelf <b>26</b>, here shown by a rail <b>30</b> borne by &#x201c;front&#x201d; shell <b>16</b> more or less in longitudinal direction S, makes it possible to change over from one to the other of the positions, or even to take on an intermediate position, through a translation of shelf <b>26</b> along the rail. Upper surface <b>28</b> then is kept horizontal throughout the movement. In this way, the passenger may get out of his seat by simply pushing retractable shelf <b>26</b> into an intermediate position toward box structure <b>18</b>, without having to remove his belongings from shelf <b>26</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">Retractable shelf <b>26</b> is exceptional in that it has, in position P<b>2</b>, an upper surface <b>28</b> with smaller dimensions in comparison with position P<b>1</b>. Shelf <b>26</b> thus occupies less space in stowage, and provides a larger &#x201c;useful&#x201d; use surface for the passenger.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">In this way, modules <b>10</b> are less wide in the direction perpendicular to X and aisles <b>5</b> of the aircraft therefore are more spacious. It is noted here that since box structure <b>18</b> thus is not as wide as sitting surface <b>13</b> of seat <b>14</b>, wing <b>13</b>&#x2032;, once opened out to form a bed, may protrude from the box structure as becomes apparent from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>, without its creating a nuisance in the aisles <b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, retractable shelf <b>26</b> has a width L in position P<b>1</b> (horizontal dimension perpendicular to direction S, that is to say the width seen by the passenger) more or less equal to that of seat <b>14</b> (and of sitting surface <b>13</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">Box structure <b>18</b> and retractable shelf <b>26</b> in position P<b>2</b> have a width L smaller than L, for example three to ten centimeters less, especially five.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">There also has been shown a retractable shelf <b>26</b> in intermediate position Pi, in which upper surface <b>28</b> is partially extracted from compartment <b>24</b> provided for storage thereof. Shelf <b>26</b> already may be used in this position Pi, for example as a cocktail shelf for storing glasses.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">Other intermediate positions Pi may be provided along the way between P<b>1</b> and P<b>2</b>, for example an intermediate position allowing the passenger to get out of his seat as indicated above and in which upper surface <b>28</b> is completely outside compartment <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">In position Pi shown, width L&#x2033; of retractable shelf <b>26</b> ranges between L&#x2032; and L. As will be seen subsequently, different contours governing the width of shelf <b>26</b> may be contemplated according to the degree of extraction of shelf <b>26</b> from its compartment <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">In order to optimize the usable surface of shelf <b>26</b>, there preferably is chosen a contour which ensures that the width of shelf <b>26</b> takes on maximal value L as soon as entire upper surface <b>28</b> is extracted from compartment <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">The movement of shelf <b>26</b> between positions P<b>2</b> and P<b>1</b> now is illustrated with the aid of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6A to 6C</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref>, retractable shelf <b>26</b> comprises a main tray <b>32</b> with small thickness, for example less than two centimeters, which has a straight edge <b>34</b> extending over a large portion of the width of the shelf on the passenger side. From the side of this straight edge <b>34</b>, the rear part of main tray <b>32</b> extends along a curve toward outer shell <b>16</b> which comes to support shelf <b>26</b> and its movement mechanism.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">Box structure <b>18</b> has a shape more or less similar to that of main tray <b>32</b>, so that in stowed position P<b>2</b>, shelf <b>26</b> follows the interior shape of box structure <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">Main tray <b>32</b> has, in its lower face, an oblong-shape blind hole <b>36</b> extending parallel to edge <b>34</b> and serving as a handle for the passenger wishing to pull or push shelf <b>26</b>. The positioning of shelf <b>26</b> stored in the upper part of compartment <b>24</b> ensures an easy access to handle <b>36</b> for the passenger.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">Any other grasping means allowing the passenger to move shelf <b>26</b> may be contemplated.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">Now with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref>, tray <b>32</b> is fastened to means for movement by translation along one or more rails <b>30</b>, here to a rigid cassette <b>38</b> parallel to the plane of tray <b>32</b>, itself laterally fastened to a movable element <b>40</b> on rail <b>30</b>, here a kind of slide, sliding or rolling on two rails. The movement travel of the shelf between P<b>1</b> and P<b>2</b> is a few tens of centimeters, generally between fifty centimeters and one meter, especially between 75 and 80 cm in order to provide the passenger with a comfortable personal space <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">The fastening of shelf <b>26</b> through cassette <b>38</b> makes it possible to minimize the space occupied underneath the shelf by the movement mechanisms, and thus to enhance the comfort of the passenger in space <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">Under the traction or pushing exerted by the passenger on handle <b>36</b> along axis S, movable element <b>40</b> slides on rails <b>30</b> making it possible to move shelf <b>26</b> which is integral therewith between the various positions P<b>1</b>, P<b>2</b> and Pi.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">Rails <b>30</b> and movable element <b>40</b> are accommodated in the thickness of shell <b>16</b>, here made up of a double wall for example. A straight slot <b>42</b> thus is provided for the passage of cassette <b>38</b> along the movement between P<b>1</b> and P<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">Any means for holding movable element <b>40</b> in one of positions Pi may be provided. For example, on <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6C</figref>, slight grooves <b>42</b> are made in rails <b>30</b> at appropriate places. Wheels provided on movable element <b>40</b> then come to engage into these grooves <b>42</b>, locking shelf <b>26</b> into said positions Pi.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">The force exerted by the passenger on handle <b>36</b> makes it possible, if need be, to disengage the movable element from these grooves in order to move shelf <b>26</b> to another position.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">Grooves thus are provided at positions P<b>1</b> and P<b>2</b>, as well as at a cocktail position P<b>3</b> in which shelf <b>26</b> is partially (about half) extracted from compartment <b>24</b> and at a position P<b>4</b> midway between P<b>1</b> and P<b>2</b> in which the passenger may easily get out of his seat.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">As a variant, the holding means may be of friction type provided on the bearings of movable element <b>40</b> so that shelf <b>26</b> may take on any position along rails <b>30</b>, and no longer only those created by grooves <b>42</b>. The friction means ensure the locking of shelf <b>26</b> in position until a force exceeding a resistance threshold is applied to the shelf.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">Appropriate means for locking shelf <b>26</b> in these various positions also may be provided, in particular a manual lock locking retractable shelf <b>26</b> in position P<b>2</b> (to prevent an untimely extraction during take-off of the aircraft, for example).</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">As illustrated on <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref>, rails <b>30</b> and slot <b>42</b> slope slightly downward from stowed position P<b>2</b> to optimal use position P<b>1</b>. The difference in height between P<b>2</b> and P<b>1</b> is a few centimeters, especially three or four centimeters.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">This difference in height makes it possible to combine both a low height P<b>1</b> optimal for a seated passenger and high height P<b>2</b> in which retractable shelf <b>26</b> &#x201c;presses&#x201d; as close as possible to fixed shelf <b>20</b> so as to maximize the space of volume <b>24</b> for accommodating the feet of the passenger in lying-down position or to have a larger storage space.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111">Cassette <b>38</b> thus is fastened to movable element <b>40</b> which supports it, with an angle similar to that of inclination of rails <b>30</b> in relation to the floor (defining the horizontal), so that shelf <b>26</b> remains horizontal in its entire movement. In this way, shelf <b>26</b> according to the invention may be used when it is hardly (partially) extracted from compartment <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 to 10</figref>, the extension mechanism for retractable shelf <b>26</b> when the latter is pulled out of compartment <b>24</b> now is described.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">Retractable shelf <b>26</b> consists of main tray <b>32</b> such as set forth above, and a cover <b>44</b> extending over the part of shelf <b>26</b> adjacent to shell <b>16</b> along which it moves.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">Cover <b>44</b> consists of a tape that is not very thick, made of rigid plastic surrounding the edge of main tray <b>32</b> and cassette <b>38</b> added and partially fastened (as will be seen subsequently) underneath main tray <b>32</b> (see also <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref>). Tape <b>44</b> is fastened, by riveting for example, to a lower casing of cassette <b>38</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">Cover <b>44</b> is not fastened to tray <b>32</b> so that the latter is free to slide inside, in particular between a retracted position (as illustrated on FIGS. <b>6</b>A and <b>8</b>&#x2014;edge of tray <b>32</b> in dotted lines) generally corresponding to position P<b>2</b>, and an extended position (illustrated on FIG. <b>9</b>&#x2014;edge of tray <b>32</b> in dotted lines) corresponding to the shelf in position P<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116">It is this translation of tray <b>32</b> by sliding in cover <b>44</b> that allows shelf <b>26</b> to have a useful upper surface <b>28</b> (comprising the upper surface of tape <b>44</b> and the upper surface of tray <b>32</b>) of variable size.</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0117">In order to ensure an unbroken upper surface <b>28</b> between tape <b>44</b> and tray <b>32</b>, a tape <b>44</b> with width at least equal to the contemplated lateral travel of tray <b>32</b> is chosen. This travel corresponds in particular to the difference L-L, that is for example five centimeters. In particular a tape width equal to this travel is chosen so that in extended position, the left side edge (on the Figure) of tray <b>32</b> is directly in line with the right edge of tape <b>44</b>. In this way the usable surface of tray <b>32</b> in fully opened-out position P<b>1</b> is maximized.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0118">In order to improve the flatness of upper surface <b>28</b>, elastic means then may be provided, for example springs provided between cassette <b>38</b> and tray <b>32</b> to raise the latter from the thickness of tape <b>44</b> when the shelf is extended. In this way the upper surfaces of tray <b>32</b> and of cover <b>44</b> are at the same level. It is noted here that the rounded side edges for tray <b>32</b> and cover <b>44</b> make it possible, under a return force exerted via the translation means such as set forth below, to bring tray <b>32</b> back down into cover <b>44</b> when shelf <b>26</b> is stowed and tray <b>32</b> is returned into the cover.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0119"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 to 10</figref> illustrate more precisely means <b>46</b> controlling the translation of tray <b>32</b> by sliding in cover <b>44</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0120">These means <b>46</b> here are incorporated into cassette <b>38</b>, of rigid PVC type.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0121">Cassette <b>38</b> comprises a lower half-casing <b>50</b> and an upper half-casing <b>60</b> as shown in an exploded view on <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0122">Lower half-casing <b>50</b> is fastened, by screwing at one end, to movable element <b>40</b> from which it extends perpendicular to axis S. It also is fastened to cover <b>44</b> by riveting so as to drive same during the movement of shelf <b>26</b> via movable element <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0123">Lower half-casing <b>50</b> further comprises a groove <b>52</b> extending from its end fastened to movable element <b>40</b> in the longitudinal axis of cassette <b>38</b> (horizontal axis perpendicular to S), and two guides <b>54</b> parallel to groove <b>52</b> over a considerable length of the cassette.</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0124">Groove <b>52</b> is provided for accommodating the rack mechanisms introduced below and for this purpose has a variable width: wide on the movable element <b>40</b> side to accommodate two racks and narrower toward the opposite end to accommodate a single rack.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0125">Upper half-casing <b>60</b> is fastened underneath main tray <b>32</b> of shelf <b>26</b>, for example by screwing (via a plate <b>61</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0126">As for upper half-casing <b>60</b>, it comprises two grooves <b>62</b> more or less facing the two guides <b>54</b>. On closing the two half-casings <b>50</b> and <b>60</b> on top of one another, guides <b>54</b> engage into corresponding grooves <b>62</b>. In this way, upper half-casing <b>60</b> and tray <b>32</b> which is integral therewith are able to slide laterally (perpendicular to axis S) in relation to lower half-casing <b>50</b> and movable element <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0127">A rack <b>56</b> is engaged into groove <b>52</b> of lower half-casing <b>50</b> and is able to slide in the longitudinal direction inside cassette <b>38</b> (perpendicular to S). A vertical finger <b>58</b> is fastened integrally to the end of rack <b>56</b> on the movable element <b>40</b> side.</p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0128">A corresponding rack <b>64</b> is fastened in upper half-casing <b>60</b> and comes into groove <b>52</b> when cassette <b>38</b> is closed.</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0129">The two racks are interfaced by rack wheel <b>66</b>. In this way, when rack <b>56</b> slides in corresponding groove <b>52</b>, it drives rack wheel <b>66</b> in rotation, which itself drives second rack <b>64</b> in translation in the opposite direction (with the entire upper half-casing <b>60</b> and main tray <b>32</b>). The arrows shown on <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> illustrate the movement of the various parts during extension of shelf <b>26</b> (changeover from P<b>2</b> to P<b>1</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0130">In particular, rack wheel <b>66</b> has two stages, one engaging into first rack <b>56</b> and the other into second rack <b>64</b> (groove <b>52</b> being sufficiently deep to accommodate two racks <b>56</b>, <b>64</b> each at the respective stage of rack wheel <b>66</b>). In this way, the travel of the second rack may be easily reduced or geared-down according to that of the first rack. In particular, a rack wheel providing a ratio equal to 2 is chosen: the travel of rack <b>56</b> brings about a dual travel of rack <b>64</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0132" num="0131">Returning to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, outer shell <b>16</b> comprises a vertical double wall defining an inner space where the movement mechanism made up of movable element <b>40</b> and rails <b>30</b> is accommodated. A perpendicular wall <b>70</b> comes to close off the double wall at the top. This wall <b>70</b> in particular is parallel to rails <b>30</b>, that is to say, slightly sloping downward in the direction of seat <b>14</b>. Slot <b>42</b> provided for the movement of cassette <b>38</b> is implemented in the outer wall of shell <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0133" num="0132">A non-traversing groove <b>72</b> is implemented in the lower surface of wall <b>70</b>, in which finger <b>58</b> of cassette <b>38</b> comes to engage when shelf <b>26</b> is installed on module <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0134" num="0133">Groove <b>72</b> extends more or less over the same length as movement groove <b>42</b>, and gradually moves away from the outer wall where groove <b>42</b> is implemented in the direction of seat <b>14</b>. In particular, a lateral offset of 25 mm is provided between the two extreme positions.</p>
<p id="p-0135" num="0134">Thus, on pulling shelf <b>26</b> toward seat <b>14</b>, the shelf and movable element <b>40</b> slide on rails <b>30</b> toward the seat. At the same time, finger <b>58</b> is gradually moved way, over 25 mm, from shelf <b>26</b> via groove <b>72</b>, which drives rack <b>56</b> in a similar translation in relation to lower half-casing <b>50</b> (and groove <b>52</b>)) and drives rack wheel <b>66</b> in rotation.</p>
<p id="p-0136" num="0135">With the ratio of 2 of wheel <b>66</b>, rack <b>64</b> then moves in translation over a double distance, or 50 mm, in the opposite direction, causing tray <b>32</b> to slide out of cover <b>44</b>, via the translation of upper half-casing <b>60</b> integral with tray <b>32</b> in relation to lower half-casing <b>50</b> integral with cover <b>44</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0137" num="0136">Correlatively, when shelf <b>26</b> is pushed toward stowage compartment <b>24</b>, finger <b>58</b> and rack <b>56</b> gradually move in translation toward shelf <b>26</b>. Rack <b>64</b> and tray <b>32</b> then move in translation in the other direction, ensuring the return of same inside cover <b>44</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0138" num="0137">As a variant of groove <b>72</b>, guide ramps provided on the lower face of wall <b>70</b> may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0139" num="0138">The contour of groove <b>72</b> is chosen in particular to achieve maximum lateral offset (25 mm in the above example), for a movement of shelf <b>26</b> over a distance equal to the depth of box structure <b>18</b> along axis S. In that way, shelf <b>26</b> has a maximum useful surface starting from its extraction from compartment <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0140" num="0139">The second part of the contour of groove <b>72</b> then is straight, parallel to the movement of shelf <b>26</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0141" num="0140">Seat modules <b>10</b> such as described above also may be integrated into a cabin configuration such as shown on <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, showing only a central group of modules <b>10</b> in the aircraft cabin.</p>
<p id="p-0142" num="0141">In this configuration, seat modules <b>10</b> are aligned one behind the other, along longitudinal axis X of the aircraft. The central group is made up of two columns of modules <b>10</b> offset longitudinally by a half-length of module <b>10</b>. In this way box structure <b>18</b> of a module <b>10</b> provides the neighboring passenger with a fixed shelf <b>20</b>, at the height of his sitting surface <b>13</b>. It is seen here that it is not the front passenger (in the column) who gains fixed shelf <b>20</b>, but the passenger directly in front in the neighboring column.</p>
<p id="p-0143" num="0142">The different types of box structure <b>18</b> indicated above (with or without fixed shelf <b>21</b>), with footrest part <b>23</b> protruding or otherwise from box structure <b>18</b>), may be provided in this configuration, as well as removable shelves <b>26</b> such as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0144" num="0143">In this cabin configuration, only modules <b>10</b> of the central cabin group thus gain an additional shelf <b>20</b> on the neighboring module. In fact, the side groups against the fuselage generally are made up of a single module in width, which does not make it possible to gain a shelf on a neighboring module.</p>
<p id="p-0145" num="0144">It thus is noted that the cabin configuration shown in particular in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, where the modules form an angle with longitudinal axis X of the aircraft, makes it possible to provide this additional shelf to all the seat modules, in the central groups as well as the side groups.</p>
<p id="p-0146" num="0145">The above examples are merely embodiments of the invention which is not limited thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0147" num="0146">In particular, the translation mechanism for tray <b>32</b> may be simplified by the use of a single rack integral with upper part <b>60</b> of cassette <b>38</b>. The contour of groove <b>72</b> then is reversed: it gradually approaches the outer wall during movement toward the seat. In this way, the finger on the sole rack, the rack and tray <b>32</b> are driven integrally to cause the latter to slide in cover <b>44</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0148" num="0147">Furthermore, the invention, although described above in an aeronautical application, may be applied to any type of vehicle equipped with a seat, for example a train, but also to seat modules disposed in buildings, for example in a waiting room or a lounge.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A passenger seat system, comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of seat modules arranged side by side in longitudinally offset relative positions, each seat module configured to form a bed from a convertible seat and a footrest,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the footrest of a considered seat module is integrated into an interior of a fixed box structure, which box structure comprises an upper surface arranged as a fixed shelf for a passenger in a seat module adjacent to the considered seat module and comprises, underneath the footrest, a stowage compartment for the passenger in the considered seat module.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A seat system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the upper surface is substantially horizontal and is positioned vertically, above the footrest.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A seat system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, in which the footrest includes a lower surface of an intermediate space inside the box structure and the fixed shelf includes a first portion of a top part of the box structure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A seat system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the upper surface arranged as the fixed shelf includes a second portion of the top of the box structure of a module for the passenger in the considered seat module.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A seat system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, in which the top of the box structure has horizontal dimensions smaller than those of the footrest.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A seat system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, in which each seat module comprises a removable shelf configured to be stored, in stowed position, in the top of the intermediate space, added to the box-structure top.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A seat system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the upper surface arranged as a fixed shelf for the adjacent passenger comprises a vertical rim extending at least along a periphery of the fixed shelf facing the passenger in the considered seat module.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A seat system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the box structure forms part of a shell partially surrounding the seat module adjacent to the considered seat module.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A seat system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, the seat system being integrated into a vehicle, in which system the seat modules are arranged along an acute angle in relation to the horizontal axis of the vehicle.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. An aircraft comprising a system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
