<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625063-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625063</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13408595</doc-number>
<date>20120229</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2011-072217</doc-number>
<date>20110329</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>130</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>1335</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>349117</main-classification>
<further-classification>349118</further-classification>
<further-classification>349 96</further-classification>
<further-classification>349112</further-classification>
<further-classification>349114</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Display and electronic unit having particular optical laminate</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6577364</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Tillin et al.</name>
<date>20030600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>349119</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0107807</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Saiki et al.</name>
<date>20030600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>359485</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0188686</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yano et al.</name>
<date>20070800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>349119</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2771392</doc-number>
<date>19980700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>11-237623</doc-number>
<date>19990800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>16</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>349117</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>349118</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>349 96</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>349112</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>349114</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>7</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120249931</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121004</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tamaki</last-name>
<first-name>Masaya</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kanagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Maeda</last-name>
<first-name>Kazuyuki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Aichi</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kabe</last-name>
<first-name>Masaaki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kanagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tamaki</last-name>
<first-name>Masaya</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kanagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Maeda</last-name>
<first-name>Kazuyuki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Aichi</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kabe</last-name>
<first-name>Masaaki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kanagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>K&#x26;L Gates LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Japan Display West Inc.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Chita-Gun, Aichi-Ken</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Qi</last-name>
<first-name>Mike</first-name>
<department>2871</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A display capable of obtaining high contrast and an electronic unit including the display are provided. The display includes: a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer and a light reflective layer; and an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel, in which the optical laminate includes a first retardation layer, a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel, the first retardation layer is a negative C-plate, and the second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/4 plate or a combination of a &#x3bb;/4 plate and a &#x3bb;/2 plate arranged in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="118.28mm" wi="131.83mm" file="US08625063-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="212.09mm" wi="136.23mm" file="US08625063-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="233.93mm" wi="149.94mm" file="US08625063-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="158.92mm" wi="133.52mm" file="US08625063-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCES TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present application claims priority to Japanese Priority Patent Application JP 2011-072217 filed in the Japan Patent Office on Mar. 29, 2011, the entire content of which is hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present application relates to a display including a reflective display panel or a semi-transmissive display panel having both a reflection section and a transmission section. Moreover, the present application relates to an electronic unit including the above-described display.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In recent years, displays for mobile units such as cellular phones and electronic papers have been in increasing demand, and attention has been given to reflective displays. The reflective displays perform display by reflecting externally incident light (ambient light) by a reflective plate, and do not need a backlight. Therefore, power consumption is reduced by power for the backlight; therefore, a mobile unit using the reflective display is allowed to be driven for a longer time than a mobile unit using a transmissive display. Moreover, as the backlight is not necessary, the weight and size of the display are allowed to be reduced accordingly.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In the reflective display, to perform display with use of external light, it is necessary to include a layer having a scattering function in the display. For example, in Japanese Patent No. 2771392, there is disclosed a method of providing a scattering function to a reflective electrode by forming projections and recessions on the reflective electrode. Moreover, in Japanese Unexamined Patent Application Publication No. H11-237623, there is disclosed a method of providing a front scattering film having more front scattering characteristics and less back scattering characteristics to a top surface of a glass substrate, instead of providing projections and recessions on the reflective electrode.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In the method described in Japanese Patent No. 2771392, a process of forming projections and recessions on the reflective electrode is added to cause an increase in cost. The method described in Japanese Unexamined Patent Application Publication No. H11-237623 has an advantage over the method described in Japanese Patent No. 2771392 in that the number of processes is allowed to be reduced, compared to the case where projections and recessions are formed on the reflective electrode. However, in the method described in Japanese Unexamined Patent Application Publication No. H11-237623, a scattering angle range includes all directions; therefore, sufficient brightness in white display is not obtained to cause a low contrast ratio.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">It is desirable to provide a display capable of obtaining high contrast, and an electronic unit including the display.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">According to an embodiment, there is provided a first display including: a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer and a light reflective layer; and an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel. The optical laminate includes a first retardation layer, a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel. The first retardation layer is a negative C-plate. The second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/4 plate or a combination of a &#x3bb;/4 plate and a &#x3bb;/2 plate arranged in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to an embodiment, there is provided a first electronic unit including a display, the display including: a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer and a light reflective layer; and an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel, in which the optical laminate includes a first retardation layer, a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel, the first retardation layer is a negative C-plate, and the second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/4 plate or a combination of a &#x3bb;/4 plate and a &#x3bb;/2 plate arranged in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In the first display and the first electronic unit according to an embodiment, the negative C-plate is disposed between the light diffuser layer and the liquid crystal display panel. Therefore, when the retardation of the liquid crystal layer is shifted according to inclination of light incident to the liquid crystal layer, a phase difference of the negative C-plate is shifted to a direction compensating for the retardation shift. As a result, light leakage in black display is reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to an embodiment, there is provided a second display including: a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer and a light reflective layer; and an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel. The optical laminate includes a first retardation layer, a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel. The first retardation layer is a biaxial &#x3bb;/4 plate having an Nz coefficient larger than 1. The second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/2 plate.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to an embodiment, there is provided a second electronic unit including a display, the display including: a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer and a light reflective layer; and an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel, in which the optical laminate includes a first retardation layer, a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel, the first retardation layer is a biaxial &#x3bb;/4 plate having an Nz coefficient larger than 1, and the second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/2 plate.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In the second display and the second electronic unit according to an embodiment, the biaxial &#x3bb;/4 plate is disposed between the light diffuser layer and the liquid crystal display panel. Therefore, when the retardation of the liquid crystal layer is shifted according to inclination of light incident to the liquid crystal layer, the phase difference of the biaxial &#x3bb;/4 plate is shifted to a direction compensating for the retardation shift. As a result, light leakage in black display is reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to an embodiment, there is provided a third display including: a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer, a light reflective layer, and a first retardation layer; and an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel. The optical laminate includes a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel. The first retardation layer is a negative C-layer. The second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/4 plate or a combination of a &#x3bb;/4 plate and a &#x3bb;/2 plate arranged in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">According to an embodiment, there is provided a third electronic unit including a display, the display including: a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer, a light reflective layer, and a first retardation layer; and an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel, in which the optical laminate includes a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel, the first retardation layer is a negative C-layer, and the second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/4 plate or a combination of a &#x3bb;/4 plate and a &#x3bb;/2 plate arranged in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In the third display and the third electronic unit according to an embodiment, the negative C-layer is disposed in the liquid crystal display panel. Therefore, when the retardation of the liquid crystal layer is shifted according to inclination of light incident to the liquid crystal layer, the phase difference of the negative C-layer is shifted to a direction compensating for the retardation shift. As a result, light leakage in black display is reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">According to an embodiment, there is provided a fourth display including: a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer, a light reflective layer, and a first retardation layer; and an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel. The optical laminate includes a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel. The first retardation layer is a biaxial &#x3bb;/4 layer having an Nz coefficient larger than 1. The second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/2 plate.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">According to an embodiment, there is provided a fourth electronic unit including a display, the display including: a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer, a light reflective layer, and a first retardation layer; and an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel, in which the optical laminate includes a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel, the first retardation layer is a biaxial &#x3bb;/4 layer having an Nz coefficient larger than 1, and the second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/2 plate.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In the fourth display and the fourth electronic unit according to an embodiment, the biaxial &#x3bb;/4 layer is disposed in the liquid crystal display panel. Therefore, when the retardation of the liquid crystal layer is shifted according to inclination of light incident to the liquid crystal layer, the phase difference of the biaxial &#x3bb;/4 layer is shifted to a direction compensating for the retardation shift. As a result, light leakage in black display is reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In the first to fourth displays and the first to fourth electronic units according to an embodiment, light leakage in black display is reduced by a phase compensation function by the negative C-plate, the biaxial &#x3bb;/4 plate, the negative C-layer, or the biaxial &#x3bb;/4 layer; therefore, high contrast is allowed to be obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">It is to be understood that both the foregoing general description and the following detailed description are exemplary, and are intended to provide further explanation of the technology as claimed.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Additional features and advantages are described herein, and will be apparent from the following Detailed Description and the figures.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE FIGURES</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The accompanying drawings are included to provide a further understanding of the disclosure, and are incorporated in and constitute a part of this specification. The drawings illustrate embodiments and, together with the specification, serve to explain the principles of the technology.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a sectional view illustrating an example of a configuration of a display according to an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</figref> are sectional views of an example of a configuration of a light diffuser plate in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a sectional view illustrating a first modification of the display in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a sectional view illustrating a second modification of the display in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a sectional view illustrating a third modification of the display in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a perspective view illustrating an example of a configuration of an electronic unit according to an application example.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The present application will be described in detail below referring to the accompanying drawings, according to an embodiment. It is to be noted that description will be given in the following order.</p>
<p id="h-0006" num="0000">1. Embodiment (display)</p>
<p id="h-0007" num="0000">An example in which a negative C-plate is disposed on a liquid crystal display panel</p>
<p id="h-0008" num="0000">2. Modifications (display)</p>
<p id="h-0009" num="0000">An example in which a biaxial &#x3bb;/4 plate is disposed on a liquid crystal display panel</p>
<p id="h-0010" num="0000">An example in which a negative C-layer is included in a liquid crystal display panel</p>
<p id="h-0011" num="0000">An example in which a biaxial &#x3bb;/4 layer is included in a liquid crystal display panel</p>
<p id="h-0012" num="0000">3. Application Example (electronic unit)</p>
<p id="h-0013" num="0000">An example in which the display according to any of the above-described embodiment and modifications thereof is used</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">1. Embodiment</p>
<heading id="h-0014" level="1">Configuration</heading>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates an example of a sectional configuration of a display <b>1</b> according to an embodiment of the technology. It is to be noted that <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic illustration, and dimensions and shapes in the illustration are not necessarily the same as actual dimensions and shapes. For example, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the display <b>1</b> includes a liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b>, an optical laminate <b>20</b> disposed on the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b>, and a drive circuit <b>30</b> driving the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b> in response to a picture signal.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In the display <b>1</b>, a surface on a side farther from the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b> of the optical laminate <b>20</b> is a picture display surface, and a light source such as a backlight is not disposed on a back side of the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b>. In other words, the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b> is a reflective display panel displaying a picture by reflecting light incident from the picture display surface.</p>
<p id="h-0015" num="0000">(Liquid Crystal Display Panel <b>10</b>)</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">For example, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b> includes a TFT (Thin Film Transistor) substrate <b>11</b> and an opposed substrate <b>12</b> which face each other with a predetermined gap in between, and a liquid crystal layer <b>13</b> disposed between the TFT substrate <b>11</b> and the opposed substrate <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The liquid crystal layer <b>13</b> is made of, for example, a nematic liquid crystal, and as will be described later, the liquid crystal layer <b>13</b> has a modulation function of allowing light incident to the liquid crystal layer <b>13</b> to pass therethrough or blocking the light from one pixel to another by a voltage applied from the drive circuit <b>30</b>. It is to be noted that gradation of each pixel is adjusted by changing the light transmission level of the liquid crystal.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The TFT substrate <b>11</b> includes, for example, a plurality of pixel electrodes and pixel circuits provided to the pixel electrodes, respectively, on a substrate such as a glass substrate. The pixel circuits each include, for example, a TFT, a capacitive element, and the like. The TFT substrate <b>11</b> includes, for example, an alignment film. For example, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the TFT substrate <b>11</b> further includes a reflective layer <b>14</b> reflecting light incident from the liquid crystal layer <b>13</b>. The opposed substrate <b>12</b> includes, for example, a common electrode on a surface on a side closer to the TFT substrate <b>11</b> of a substrate such as a glass substrate. The opposed substrate <b>12</b> includes, for example, an alignment film. The opposed substrate <b>12</b> further includes, for example, a color filter in a region facing the pixel electrode, and a light-shielding film in a region not facing the pixel electrode.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In this case, the substrate in the TFT substrate <b>11</b> may be made of a material other than the glass substrate, for example, a translucent resin substrate, quartz, or a silicon substrate. The substrate in the opposed substrate <b>12</b> may be made of a transparent material other than the glass substrate, for example, a translucent resin substrate, or quartz.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The plurality of pixel electrodes drive, together with the common electrode in the opposed substrate <b>12</b>, the liquid crystal layer <b>13</b>, and are two-dimensionally arranged in the TFT substrate <b>11</b>. The common electrode is disposed to face the respective pixel electrodes. When a voltage is applied to the pixel electrodes and the common electrode by the drive circuit <b>30</b>, an electrical field corresponding to a potential difference between the pixel electrodes and the common electrode is generated between the pixel electrodes and the common electrode, and the liquid crystal layer <b>13</b> is driven according to the magnitude of the electrical field. A portion corresponding to a portion where each pixel electrode and the common electrode face each other in the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b> is a minimum unit where the liquid crystal layer is allowed to be partially driven by a voltage applied between the pixel electrode and the common electrode. This minimum unit corresponds to a pixel.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The reflective layer <b>14</b> may be configured of the pixel electrodes in the TFT substrate <b>11</b>, or may be provided separately from the pixel electrodes. In the case where the reflective layer <b>14</b> is configured of the pixel electrodes, the pixel electrodes are made of a conductive material reflecting visible light, for example, a metal material such as Ag. In the case where the reflective layer <b>14</b> is provided separately from the pixel electrodes, the pixel electrodes may be made of a metal material as in the above-described case, or a conductive material transparent to visible light (for example, ITO (Indium Tin Oxide)). The common electrode is made of a conductive material transparent to visible light, for example, ITO.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The alignment films align liquid crystal molecules in the liquid crystal layer <b>13</b> in a predetermined direction, and are directly in contact with the liquid crystal layer <b>13</b>. The alignment films are made of a polymer material such as polyimide, and are formed by performing a rubbing process on coated polyimide or the like. In the color filter, color filters separating light having passed through the liquid crystal layer <b>13</b> into, for example, three primary colors of red, green, and blue, respectively, are arranged corresponding to pixels, respectively. The light-shielding film has, for example, a function of absorbing visible light. The light-shielding film is formed between the pixels.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b> is configured to allow long axes of liquid crystal molecules in the liquid crystal layer <b>13</b> to be aligned in a direction parallel or substantially parallel to a normal to the TFT substrate <b>11</b> in black display. The liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b> is configured of, for example, normally white ECB (electrical control birefringence) mode liquid crystal cells. It is to be noted that as long as liquid crystal molecules are aligned in the above-described manner in black display, the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b> may be configured of liquid crystal cells of any other mode, for example, normally black VA (Vertical Alignment) mode liquid crystal cells.</p>
<p id="h-0016" num="0000">(Optical Laminate <b>20</b>)</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">For example, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the optical laminate <b>20</b> includes a negative C-plate <b>21</b>, a light diffuser plate <b>22</b>, a &#x3bb;/4 plate <b>23</b>, a &#x3bb;/2 plate <b>24</b>, and a polarizing plate <b>25</b> in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b>. The optical laminate <b>20</b> and the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b> are bonded together with a sticking layer or an adhesive layer. Likewise, members adjacent to each other in the optical laminate <b>20</b> are bonded together with, for example, a sticking layer or an adhesive layer.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The negative C-plate <b>21</b> is an optical compensation film having a high birefringence developing property in a thickness direction, and an optical film exhibiting birefringence in the thickness direction but not exhibiting birefringence in an in-plane direction. This property is represented by the following expression.
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>nx=ny&#x3e;nz </i><?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Herein, nx is a refractive index in one direction (an x-axis direction) in a plane of the negative C-plate <b>21</b>. Moreover, ny is a refractive index in another direction (a y-axis direction orthogonal to an x axis) in the plane of the negative C-plate <b>21</b>. Further, nz is a refractive index in a direction normal to the negative C-plate <b>21</b> (a z-axis direction).</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">A birefringence (&#x394;n) in the thickness direction is represented by (nx+ny)/2&#x2212;nz. A retardation Rth of the negative C-plate <b>21</b> is represented by &#x394;n&#xd7;d, where d is the thickness of the negative C-plate <b>21</b>. The negative C-plate <b>21</b> optically compensates for retardation caused by the liquid crystal layer <b>13</b> with use of the retardation Rth thereof. For example, Rth preferably has a value around 100 nm at a wavelength of 550 nm and a wavelength close thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The negative C-plate <b>21</b> is allowed to be formed by, for example, a casting method, a die coating method, a spray coating method, a spin coating method, a roll coating method, or an air knife coating method.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The light diffuser plate <b>22</b> is a front scattering plate having more front scattering characteristics and less back scattering characteristics. The light diffuser plate <b>22</b> is configured of one or a plurality of front scattering plates. For example, the light diffuser plate <b>22</b> is an isotropic front scattering plate scattering incident light in substantially the same scattering angle range even if light L<b>1</b> enters the light diffuser plate <b>22</b> in any direction. For example, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, the light diffuser plate <b>22</b> is configured by adding, to a base <b>22</b>A, a filler <b>22</b>B with a different refractive index from the refractive index of the base <b>22</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">It is to be noted that, for example, the light diffuser plate <b>22</b> may be an anisotropic front scattering plate scattering only light L<b>2</b> incident from a specific direction and allowing light L<b>3</b> incident from a direction other than the specific direction to pass therethrough. In this case, for example, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>, the light diffuser plate <b>22</b> is configured of first regions <b>22</b>C and second regions <b>22</b>D having different refractive indices from each other. The first regions <b>22</b>C and the second regions <b>22</b>D are configured to extend in a thickness direction and be inclined in a predetermined direction.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The &#x3bb;/4 plate <b>23</b> is a uniaxially stretched film of a resin such as cycloolefin polymer or polycarbonate. The retardation of the &#x3bb;/4 plate <b>23</b> is, for example, 0.14 &#x3bc;m, and is equivalent to approximately &#xbc; of the wavelength of green light having highest luminous efficiency in visible light. Therefore, the &#x3bb;/4 plate <b>23</b> has a function of converting linearly polarized light incident from the polarizing plate <b>25</b> into circularly polarized light. The &#x3bb;/2 plate <b>24</b> is, for example, a uniaxially stretched film of a polycarbonate resin. The retardation of the &#x3bb;/2 plate <b>24</b> is, for example, 0.27 &#x3bc;m, and is equivalent to approximately &#xbd; of the wavelength of green light having highest luminous efficiency in visible light. Herein, a combination of the &#x3bb;/4 plate <b>23</b> and the &#x3bb;/2 plate <b>24</b> has a function of converting linearly polarized light incident from the polarizing plate <b>25</b> into circularly polarized light, and functions as a (broadband) circular polarization plate for a wide-ranging wavelength as a whole.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The polarizing plate <b>25</b> has a function of absorbing a predetermined linearly polarized component, and allowing the other polarized component to pass therethrough. In other words, the polarizing plate <b>25</b> has a function of converting externally incident light into linearly polarized light. The polarizing plate <b>25</b> is configured by sandwiching, in TAC (triacetyl cellulose), a stretched polymer film of PVA (polyvinyl alcohol) with doping with a halogen material such as iodine or a dichroic dye.</p>
<heading id="h-0017" level="1">Functions and Effects</heading>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Next, functions and effects of the display <b>1</b> according to the embodiment will be described below.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In the embodiment, for example, external light incident from a specific direction is converted into linearly polarized light by the polarizing plate <b>25</b>, and further into counterclockwise circularly polarized light by the &#x3bb;/2 plate <b>24</b> and the &#x3bb;/4 plate <b>23</b>, and then the counterclockwise circularly polarized light passes through the light diffuser plate <b>22</b> and the negative C-plate <b>21</b> to enter the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b>. The light incident to the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b> is modulated by the liquid crystal layer <b>13</b> in response to a picture signal, and is reflected by the reflective layer <b>14</b> to pass through the negative C-plate <b>21</b> again, and then enter the light diffuser plate <b>22</b>. The light incident to the light diffuser plate <b>22</b> is diffused by the light diffuser plate <b>22</b> in a predetermined angle range, and then the light is converted into linearly polarized light by the &#x3bb;/2 plate <b>24</b> and the &#x3bb;/4 plate <b>23</b> to exit through the polarizing plate <b>25</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In the embodiment, the negative C-plate <b>21</b> is disposed between the light diffuser plate <b>22</b> and the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b>. Therefore, light leakage in black display is reduced by a phase compensation function by the negative C-plate <b>21</b>. As a result, high contrast is allowed to be obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In the embodiment, to effectively implement phase compensation by the negative C-plate <b>21</b>, it is only necessary that the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b> is configured to allow the long axes of the liquid crystal molecules in the liquid crystal layer <b>13</b> to be aligned in the direction parallel or substantially parallel to the normal to the TFT substrate <b>11</b> in black display. In other words, phase compensation by the negative C-plate <b>21</b> is allowed to be effectively implemented in liquid crystal cells of various modes. Therefore, high contrast is allowed to be obtained in various modes.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">2. Modifications</p>
<heading id="h-0018" level="1">First Modification</heading>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">For example, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the &#x3bb;/4 plate <b>23</b> and the negative C-plate <b>21</b> in the above-described embodiment may not be included, and instead of them, a biaxial &#x3bb;/4 plate <b>26</b> may be disposed in the position of the negative C-plate <b>21</b>. The biaxial &#x3bb;/4 plate <b>26</b> is a &#x3bb;/4 plate having an Nz coefficient larger than 1, for example, a biaxially stretched &#x3bb;/4 plate. The biaxially stretched &#x3bb;/4 plate is allowed to be formed by stretching, in one axial direction, a resin film without a phase difference to form a &#x3bb;/4 plate, and then stretching the &#x3bb;/4 plate in a direction different from the one axial direction. The biaxial &#x3bb;/4 plate <b>26</b> has an optical compensation function similar to that of the negative C-plate <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In the modification, the biaxial &#x3bb;/4 plate <b>26</b> is disposed between the light diffuser plate <b>22</b> and the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b>. Therefore, light leakage in black display is reduced by a phase compensation function by the biaxial &#x3bb;/4 plate <b>26</b>. As a result, high contrast is allowed to be obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Moreover, in the modification, to effectively implement phase compensation by the biaxial &#x3bb;/4 plate <b>26</b>, it is only necessary that the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b> is configured to allow long axes of liquid crystal molecules in the liquid crystal layer <b>13</b> to be aligned in a direction parallel or substantially parallel to the normal to the TFT substrate <b>11</b>. In other words, phase compensation by the biaxial &#x3bb;/4 plate <b>26</b> is allowed to be effectively implemented in liquid crystal cells of various modes. Therefore, high contrast is allowed to be obtained in various modes.</p>
<heading id="h-0019" level="1">Second Modification</heading>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The negative C-plate <b>21</b> in the above-described embodiment may not be included, and instead of the negative C-plate <b>21</b>, a negative C-layer <b>15</b> may be included in the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b>. For example, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the negative C-layer <b>15</b> is formed below the opposed substrate <b>12</b>. The negative C-layer <b>15</b> is an optical compensation layer having a high birefringence developing property in a thickness direction, and is an optical functional layer exhibiting birefringence in the thickness direction but not exhibiting birefringence in an in-plane direction. This property is represented by the following expression.
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>nx=ny&#x3e;nz </i><?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Herein, nx is a refractive index in one direction (an x-axis direction) in a plane of the negative C-layer <b>15</b>. Moreover, ny is a refractive index in another direction (a y-axis direction orthogonal to an x axis) in the plane of the negative C-layer <b>15</b>. Further, nz is a refractive index in a direction normal to the negative C-layer <b>15</b> (a z-axis direction).</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The negative C-layer <b>15</b> optically compensates for retardation caused by the liquid crystal layer <b>13</b> with use of retardation Rth thereof. For example, the retardation Rth of the negative C-layer <b>15</b> preferably has a value around 100 nm at a wavelength of 550 nm and a wavelength close thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The negative C-layer <b>15</b> is allowed to be formed by, for example, a casting method, a die coating method, a spray coating method, a spin coating method, a roll coating method, or an air knife coating method.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In the modification, the negative C-layer <b>15</b> is disposed in the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b>. Therefore, irrespective of the mode of the liquid crystal layer <b>13</b>, light leakage in black display is reduced by a phase compensation function by the negative C-layer <b>15</b>. As a result, high contrast is allowed to be obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Moreover, in the modification, to effectively implement phase compensation by the negative C-layer <b>15</b>, it is only necessary that the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b> is configured to allow long axes of liquid crystal molecules in the liquid crystal layer <b>13</b> to be aligned in a direction parallel or substantially parallel to the normal to the TFT substrate <b>11</b> in black display. In other words, a phase compensation function by the negative C-layer <b>15</b> is allowed to be effectively implemented in liquid crystal cells of various modes. Therefore, high contrast is allowed to be obtained in various modes.</p>
<heading id="h-0020" level="1">Third Modification</heading>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The negative C-layer <b>15</b> in the second modification may not be included, and instead of the negative C-layer <b>15</b>, a biaxial &#x3bb;/4 layer <b>16</b> may be included in the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b>. The biaxial &#x3bb;/4 layer <b>16</b> is a &#x3bb;/4 layer having an Nz coefficient larger than 1, for example, a biaxially stretched &#x3bb;/4 layer. The biaxially stretched &#x3bb;/4 layer is allowed to be formed by stretching, in one axial direction, a resin film without a phase difference to form a &#x3bb;/4 plate, and then stretching the &#x3bb;/4 plate in a direction different from the one axial direction. The biaxial &#x3bb;/4 layer <b>16</b> has an optical compensation function similar to that of the negative C-layer <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">In the modification, the biaxial &#x3bb;/4 layer <b>16</b> is disposed in the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b>. Therefore, light leakage in black display is reduced by a phase compensation function by the biaxial &#x3bb;/4 layer <b>16</b>. As a result, high contrast is allowed to be obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">Moreover, in the modification, to effectively implement phase compensation by the biaxial &#x3bb;/4 layer <b>16</b>, it is only necessary that the liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b> is configured to allow long axes of liquid crystal molecules in the liquid crystal layer <b>13</b> to be aligned in a direction parallel or substantially parallel to the normal to the TFT substrate <b>11</b>. In other words, phase compensation by the biaxial &#x3bb;/4 layer <b>16</b> is allowed to be effectively implemented in liquid crystal cells of various modes. Therefore, high contrast is allowed to be obtained in various modes.</p>
<heading id="h-0021" level="1">Fourth Modification</heading>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">In the above-described embodiment and the modifications thereof, in the case where the light diffuser plate <b>22</b> is an isotropic front scattering plate, the light diffuser plate <b>22</b> may be removed. However, in this case, a sticking layer having an isotropic front scattering function is preferably included between the negative C-plate <b>21</b>, the biaxial &#x3bb;/4 plate <b>26</b>, the negative C-layer <b>15</b> or the biaxial &#x3bb;/4 layer <b>16</b>, and the polarizing plate <b>25</b>. The above-described sticking layer is used to bond optical members together, and is made of, for example, a haze adhesive. Therefore, in an example of the display <b>1</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, an sticking layer having an isotropic front scattering function is disposed between the negative C-plate <b>21</b> and the &#x3bb;/4 plate <b>23</b>, between the &#x3bb;/4 plate <b>23</b> and the &#x3bb;/2 plate <b>24</b>, or between the &#x3bb;/2 plate <b>24</b> and the polarizing plate <b>25</b>. Thus, in the case where the sticking layer is used instead of the light diffuser plate <b>22</b>, the thickness of the display <b>1</b> is allowed to be reduced by the thickness of the light diffuser plate <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">3. Application Example</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">Next, an application example of the display <b>1</b> according to any of the above-described embodiment and modifications thereof will be described below. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a schematic perspective view of an example of a configuration of an electronic unit <b>100</b> according to the application example. The electronic unit <b>100</b> is a cellular phone, and, for example, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the electronic unit <b>100</b> includes a main body <b>111</b>, and a display section <b>112</b> openable and closable with respect to the main body <b>111</b>. The main body <b>111</b> includes operation buttons <b>115</b> and a transmitter section <b>116</b>. The display section <b>112</b> includes a display <b>113</b> and a receiver section <b>117</b>. The display <b>113</b> displays various indications for telephone communication on a display screen <b>114</b> thereof. The electronic unit <b>100</b> includes a control section (not illustrated) to control the operation of the display <b>113</b>. The control section is disposed in the main body <b>111</b> or the display section <b>112</b> as a part of a control section controlling the whole electronic unit <b>100</b> or a control section different from the control section controlling the whole electronic unit <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The display <b>113</b> has the same configuration as that of the display <b>1</b> according to any of the above-described embodiment and modifications thereof. Therefore, in the display <b>113</b>, high contrast is allowed to be obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">It is to be noted that, in addition to the above-described cellular phone, electronic units to which the display <b>1</b> according to any of the above-described embodiment and modifications thereof is applicable include a personal computer, a liquid crystal television, a viewfinder type or monitor direct-view type videotape recorder, a car navigation system, a pager, an electronic organizer, an electronic calculator, a word processor, a work station, a videophone, a POS terminal, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">Although the present technology is described referring to the embodiment, the modifications thereof, and the application examples, the technology is not limited thereto, and may be variously modified. For example, in the above-described embodiment and the like, the case where the technology is applied to the reflective liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b> is described as an example; however, the technology is applicable to a semi-transparent liquid crystal display panel. For example, the technology is applicable to a semi-transparent liquid crystal display panel having a configuration similar to the reflective liquid crystal display panel <b>10</b> as a reflection section, and including a transmission section with the reflection section.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">It is to be noted that the technology is allowed to have the following configurations.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">(1) A display including:</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer and a light reflective layer; and</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel,</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">in which the optical laminate includes a first retardation layer, a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel,</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">the first retardation layer is a negative C-plate, and</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">the second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/4 plate or a combination of a &#x3bb;/4 plate and a &#x3bb;/2 plate arranged in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">(2) A display including:</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer and a light reflective layer; and</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel,</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">in which the optical laminate includes a first retardation layer, a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel,</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">the first retardation layer is a biaxial &#x3bb;/4 plate having an Nz coefficient larger than 1, and</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">the second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/2 plate.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">(3) A display including:</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer, a light reflective layer, and a first retardation layer; and</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel,</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">in which the optical laminate includes a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel,</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">the first retardation layer is a negative C-layer, and</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">the second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/4 plate or a combination of a &#x3bb;/4 plate and a &#x3bb;/2 plate arranged in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">(4) A display including:</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer, a light reflective layer, and a first retardation layer; and</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel,</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">in which the optical laminate includes a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel,</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">the first retardation layer is a biaxial &#x3bb;/4 layer having an Nz coefficient larger than 1, and</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">the second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/2 plate.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">(5) The display according to any one of (1) to (4), in which</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">the liquid crystal display panel is configured to allow long axes of liquid crystal molecules in the liquid crystal layer to be aligned in a direction parallel or substantially parallel to a normal to the liquid crystal display panel in black display.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">(6) An electronic unit including a display, the display including:</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer and a light reflective layer; and</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel,</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">in which the optical laminate includes a first retardation layer, a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel,</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">the first retardation layer is a negative C-plate, and</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">the second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/4 plate or a combination of a &#x3bb;/4 plate and a &#x3bb;/2 plate arranged in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">(7) An electronic unit including a display, the display including:</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer and a light reflective layer; and</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel,</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">in which the optical laminate includes a first retardation layer, a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel,</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">the first retardation layer is a biaxial &#x3bb;/4 plate having an Nz coefficient larger than 1, and</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111">the second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/2 plate.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">(8) An electronic unit including a display, the display including:</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer, a light reflective layer, and a first retardation layer; and</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel,</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">in which the optical laminate includes a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel,</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116">the first retardation layer is a negative C-layer, and</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0117">the second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/4 plate or a combination of a &#x3bb;/4 plate and a &#x3bb;/2 plate arranged in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0118">(9) An electronic unit including a display, the display including:</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0119">a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer, a light reflective layer, and a first retardation layer; and</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0120">an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel,</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0121">in which the optical laminate includes a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel,</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0122">the first retardation layer is a biaxial &#x3bb;/4 layer having an Nz coefficient larger than 1, and</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0123">the second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/2 plate.</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0124">(10) The electronic unit according to any one of (6) to (9), in which</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0125">the liquid crystal display panel is configured to allow long axes of liquid crystal molecules in the liquid crystal layer to be aligned in a direction parallel or substantially parallel to a normal to the liquid crystal display panel in black display.</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0126">It should be understood that various changes and modifications to the presently preferred embodiments described herein will be apparent to those skilled in the art. Such changes and modifications can be made without departing from the spirit and scope of the present subject matter and without diminishing its intended advantages. It is therefore intended that such changes and modifications be covered by the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A display comprising:
<claim-text>a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer and a light reflective layer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the optical laminate includes a first retardation layer, a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first retardation layer is a negative C-plate, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/4 plate or a combination of a &#x3bb;/4 plate and a &#x3bb;/2 plate arranged in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The display according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the liquid crystal display panel is configured to allow long axes of liquid crystal molecules in the liquid crystal layer to be aligned in a direction parallel or substantially parallel to a normal to the liquid crystal display panel in black display.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A display comprising:
<claim-text>a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer and a light reflective layer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the optical laminate includes a first retardation layer, a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first retardation layer is a biaxial &#x3bb;/4 plate having an Nz coefficient larger than 1, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/2 plate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The display according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the liquid crystal display panel is configured to allow long axes of liquid crystal molecules in the liquid crystal layer to be aligned in a direction parallel or substantially parallel to a normal to the liquid crystal display panel in black display.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A display comprising:
<claim-text>a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer, a light reflective layer, and a first retardation layer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the optical laminate includes a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first retardation layer is a negative C-layer, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/4 plate or a combination of a &#x3bb;/4 plate and a &#x3bb;/2 plate arranged in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The display according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the liquid crystal display panel is configured to allow long axes of liquid crystal molecules in the liquid crystal layer to be aligned in a direction parallel or substantially parallel to a normal to the liquid crystal display panel in black display.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A display comprising:
<claim-text>a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer, a light reflective layer, and a first retardation layer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the optical laminate includes a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first retardation layer is a biaxial &#x3bb;/4 layer having an Nz coefficient larger than 1, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/2 plate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The display according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the liquid crystal display panel is configured to allow long axes of liquid crystal molecules in the liquid crystal layer to be aligned in a direction parallel or substantially parallel to a normal to the liquid crystal display panel in black display.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. An electronic unit including a display, the display comprising:
<claim-text>a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer and a light reflective layer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the optical laminate includes a first retardation layer, a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first retardation layer is a negative C-plate, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/4 plate or a combination of a &#x3bb;/4 plate and a &#x3bb;/2 plate arranged in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The electronic unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the liquid crystal display panel is configured to allow long axes of liquid crystal molecules in the liquid crystal layer to be aligned in a direction parallel or substantially parallel to a normal to the liquid crystal display panel in black display.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. An electronic unit including a display, the display comprising:
<claim-text>a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer and a light reflective layer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the optical laminate includes a first retardation layer, a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first retardation layer is a biaxial &#x3bb;/4 plate having an Nz coefficient larger than 1, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/2 plate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The electronic unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the liquid crystal display panel is configured to allow long axes of liquid crystal molecules in the liquid crystal layer to be aligned in a direction parallel or substantially parallel to a normal to the liquid crystal display panel in black display.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. An electronic unit including a display, the display comprising:
<claim-text>a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer, a light reflective layer, and a first retardation layer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the optical laminate includes a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first retardation layer is a negative C-layer, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/4 plate or a combination of a &#x3bb;/4 plate and a &#x3bb;/2 plate arranged in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The electronic unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the liquid crystal display panel is configured to allow long axes of liquid crystal molecules in the liquid crystal layer to be aligned in a direction parallel or substantially parallel to a normal to the liquid crystal display panel in black display.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. An electronic unit including a display, the display comprising:
<claim-text>a liquid crystal display panel including a liquid crystal layer, a light reflective layer, and a first retardation layer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical laminate disposed on the liquid crystal display panel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the optical laminate includes a light diffuser layer, a second retardation layer, and a polarization layer in order from a side closer to the liquid crystal display panel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first retardation layer is a biaxial &#x3bb;/4 layer having an Nz coefficient larger than 1, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second retardation layer is a &#x3bb;/2 plate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The electronic unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the liquid crystal display panel is configured to allow long axes of liquid crystal molecules in the liquid crystal layer to be aligned in a direction parallel or substantially parallel to a normal to the liquid crystal display panel in black display.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
