<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623217-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623217</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13951822</doc-number>
<date>20130726</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>24</main-group>
<subgroup>46</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>210722</main-classification>
<further-classification>210758</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Method for water treatment regeneration stage</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5919373</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Naaktgeboren</name>
<date>19990700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>210750</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>6</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>210722</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>210758</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>10</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>10</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12697949</doc-number>
<date>20100201</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8500999</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13951822</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130306578</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20131121</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Pentair Residential Filtration, LLC</orgname>
<address>
<city>Minneapolis</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tischendorf</last-name>
<first-name>Andrew</first-name>
<address>
<city>Campbellsport</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lindfors</last-name>
<first-name>Michael M.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Whitefish Bay</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Paull</last-name>
<first-name>Kyle</first-name>
<address>
<city>Thiensville</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Greenberg Traurig LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Pentair Residential Filtration, LLC</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Minneapolis</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Barry</last-name>
<first-name>Chester</first-name>
<department>1779</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Embodiments of the invention provide a method and system for providing a regeneration stage in a water treatment system. The method can include entering a first air bleed state to allow pressurized, deoxygenated air to exit the water treatment system, entering a second air bleed state to equalize a first air pressure of remaining deoxygenated air inside the water treatment system with a second air pressure outside the water treatment system, entering a backwash state to expel remaining deoxygenated air and particulates from inside the water treatment system, and entering an air draw state to allow oxygenated air to enter the water treatment system.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="250.02mm" wi="152.91mm" file="US08623217-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="264.67mm" wi="183.81mm" file="US08623217-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="263.48mm" wi="189.15mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623217-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="255.69mm" wi="171.96mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623217-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="256.54mm" wi="166.62mm" file="US08623217-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="259.00mm" wi="176.02mm" file="US08623217-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="256.96mm" wi="193.21mm" file="US08623217-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="252.48mm" wi="181.36mm" file="US08623217-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="247.57mm" wi="192.79mm" file="US08623217-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="138.51mm" wi="106.17mm" file="US08623217-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="256.12mm" wi="178.14mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623217-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a divisional of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 12/697,949, entitled &#x201c;System and Method for Water Treatment Regeneration Stage&#x201d;, by Andrew Tischendorf et al. filed Feb. 1, 2010, now U.S. Pat. No. 8,500,999, which is hereby incorporated by reference herein in its entirety.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Water treatment systems, such as mineral removal systems (e.g., iron, sulfide, and manganese) and/or water softener systems, are used to treat water in businesses, industries, and homes. Conventional water treatment systems include tanks into which untreated water flows and is forced to mix with oxygenated air. Ions in the untreated water can become oxidized by the oxygenated air, resulting is solid particulates. The untreated water can then pass through a resin bed. The resin bed can allow treated water to pass, while trapping the solid particulates. This process creates a pressure buildup inside the tank. As a result, when the tank is opened to the atmosphere, deoxygenated air can rapidly evacuate the tank. This rapid evacuation of air can jar pipes and other components, resulting in noisy water treatment systems.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Some embodiments of the invention provide a method for a regeneration stage in a water treatment system. The method can include entering a first air bleed state for a first time period to allow pressurized, deoxygenated air to exit the water treatment system, and entering a second air bleed state for a second time period to equalize a first air pressure of remaining deoxygenated air inside the water treatment system with a second air pressure outside the water treatment system. The method can also include entering a backwash state for a third time period to expel remaining deoxygenated air and particulates from inside the water treatment system, and entering an air draw state for a fourth time period to allow oxygenated air to enter the water treatment system. In some embodiments, the method can be used in a water treatment system designed to remove iron, sulfide, and/or manganese from water.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a cross-sectional view of a water treatment system, according to one embodiment of the invention, in a service state.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exploded view of a valve assembly of the water treatment system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an exploded view of a piston assembly and a spacer assembly of the valve assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a flowchart illustrating operation of the water treatment system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> according to one embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the water treatment system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in an air bleed state.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the water treatment system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in a backwash state.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the water treatment system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in an air draw state.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is an exploded view of a powerhead of the water treatment system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a back perspective view of a circuit board of the powerhead of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a block diagram of a user control method for a water treatment system according to one embodiment of the invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Before any embodiments of the invention are explained in detail, it is to be understood that the invention is not limited in its application to the details of construction and the arrangement of components set forth in the following description or illustrated in the following drawings. The invention is capable of other embodiments and of being practiced or of being carried out in various ways. Also, it is to be understood that the phraseology and terminology used herein is for the purpose of description and should not be regarded as limiting. The use of &#x201c;including,&#x201d; &#x201c;comprising,&#x201d; or &#x201c;having&#x201d; and variations thereof herein is meant to encompass the items listed thereafter and equivalents thereof as well as additional items. Unless specified or limited otherwise, the terms &#x201c;mounted,&#x201d; &#x201c;connected,&#x201d; &#x201c;supported,&#x201d; and &#x201c;coupled&#x201d; and variations thereof are used broadly and encompass both direct and indirect mountings, connections, supports, and couplings. Further, &#x201c;connected&#x201d; and &#x201c;coupled&#x201d; are not restricted to physical or mechanical connections or couplings.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The following discussion is presented to enable a person skilled in the art to make and use embodiments of the invention. Various modifications to the illustrated embodiments will be readily apparent to those skilled in the art, and the generic principles herein can be applied to other embodiments and applications without departing from embodiments of the invention. Thus, embodiments of the invention are not intended to be limited to embodiments shown, but are to be accorded the widest scope consistent with the principles and features disclosed herein. The following detailed description is to be read with reference to the figures, in which like elements in different figures have like reference numerals. The figures, which are not necessarily to scale, depict selected embodiments and are not intended to limit the scope of embodiments of the invention. Skilled artisans will recognize the examples provided herein have many useful alternatives and fall within the scope of embodiments of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a water treatment system <b>10</b> according to one embodiment of the invention. The water treatment system <b>10</b> can be used commercially or residentially to remove iron, sulfide, and/or manganese, among other oxidizable minerals, in water. The water treatment system <b>10</b> can include a tank <b>12</b> and a head portion <b>14</b>. The head portion <b>14</b> can include a powerhead <b>16</b> (as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>), a valve assembly <b>18</b>, and fluid ports <b>20</b>-<b>28</b>. The fluid ports can include a drain <b>20</b>, a top portion <b>22</b> of the tank <b>12</b>, an inlet <b>24</b>, an outlet <b>26</b>, and a distributor <b>28</b>. The head portion <b>14</b> can also include a threaded portion <b>30</b> for coupling the head portion <b>14</b> to the tank <b>12</b>. In certain operational states, the tank <b>12</b> can include an air layer <b>32</b>, a media layer <b>34</b>, and a water layer <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates the valve assembly <b>18</b> according to one embodiment of the invention. The valve assembly <b>18</b> can include a valve body <b>38</b>, a piston assembly <b>40</b>, a spacer assembly <b>42</b>, a turbine meter assembly <b>44</b>, an injector assembly <b>46</b>, and a bypass assembly <b>48</b>. In some embodiments, the water treatment system <b>10</b> can be used for water softening and the valve assembly <b>18</b> can also include a brine valve assembly <b>50</b> and a brine line flow control (BLFC) assembly <b>52</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The valve assembly <b>18</b> can also include a drain channel <b>54</b>, an inlet channel <b>56</b>, an outlet channel <b>58</b>, and a distributor channel <b>60</b> in fluid communication with the drain <b>20</b>, the inlet <b>24</b>, the outlet <b>26</b>, and the distributor <b>28</b>, respectively. The drain channel <b>54</b> can be connected to piping (not shown) via a drain housing <b>62</b> or an alternate drain housing <b>64</b> with a drain retainer clip <b>66</b>. The inlet channel <b>56</b> and the outlet channel <b>58</b> can be coupled to the bypass assembly <b>48</b> via H-clips <b>68</b>. The bypass assembly <b>48</b> can further be coupled to connectors <b>70</b> via o-rings <b>72</b> and H-clips <b>68</b>. In some embodiments, alternate connectors <b>74</b> or an elbow connector <b>76</b> (via an o-ring <b>72</b> and an H-clip <b>68</b>) can be used in place of the connectors <b>70</b>. The distributor channel <b>60</b> can be coupled to a first collector <b>78</b> via an adaptor <b>80</b> and o-rings <b>72</b>. In addition, the injector assembly <b>46</b> can include an injector cap <b>82</b>, an injector nozzle <b>84</b>, an injector throat <b>86</b>, a ball <b>88</b>, a ball gage <b>90</b>, an injector screen <b>92</b>, and o-rings <b>72</b>. The injector assembly <b>46</b> can be used to allow air to enter the valve assembly <b>18</b> and can be coupled to the valve body via an H-clip <b>68</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates the piston assembly <b>40</b> and the spacer assembly <b>42</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the spacer assembly <b>42</b> can include piston seals <b>94</b> separated by spacers <b>96</b>. The piston seals <b>94</b> can be aligned between the fluid ports <b>18</b>-<b>26</b> in the valve body <b>38</b>. The piston assembly <b>40</b> can include a link <b>98</b>, a piston rod <b>100</b>, an end plug <b>102</b>, an o-ring <b>72</b>, a quad ring <b>104</b>, an end plug seal <b>106</b>, a piston rod retainer <b>108</b>, and a piston <b>110</b>. The piston <b>110</b> can include large diameter sections <b>112</b> and small diameter sections <b>114</b>. The large diameter sections <b>112</b> can engage the piston seals <b>94</b> to substantially seal fluid paths between one or more of the fluid ports <b>18</b>-<b>26</b>, depending on the position of the piston <b>110</b> in the spacer assembly <b>42</b>. In addition, the small diameter portions <b>114</b> can permit fluid paths between one or more of the fluid ports <b>18</b>-<b>26</b>. The position of the piston <b>110</b> can affect an operational state of the water treatment system <b>10</b>, as described below.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a flowchart outlining the operation of the water treatment system <b>10</b> according to one embodiment of the invention. The water treatment system <b>10</b> can start in a service state at step <b>116</b> where the piston <b>110</b> is in a first position. If a regeneration stage is triggered in step <b>118</b>, the piston <b>110</b> can be repositioned at step <b>120</b> so that the water treatment system <b>10</b> is in a first air bleed state at step <b>122</b>. The water treatment system <b>10</b> can be in the first air bleed state (at step <b>122</b>) until a time limit has been reached at step <b>124</b>. The piston <b>110</b> can then be repositioned at step <b>126</b> so that the water treatment system <b>10</b> is in a second air bleed state at step <b>128</b>. After another time limit at step <b>130</b>, the piston <b>110</b> can be repositioned at step <b>132</b> so that the water treatment system <b>10</b> is in a backwash state at step <b>134</b>. The water treatment system <b>10</b> can be in the backwash state (at step <b>134</b>) until another time limit has been reached at step <b>136</b>. Once the time limit has been reached at step <b>136</b>, the piston <b>110</b> can again be repositioned at step <b>138</b> so that the water treatment system <b>10</b> is in an air draw state at step <b>140</b> for another time limit (at step <b>142</b>). The piston <b>110</b> can then return to the first position at step <b>144</b> and the water treatment system <b>10</b> can again be in the service state at step <b>116</b>. The time limits can be predefined and can differ from one another (as described below).</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates the water treatment system <b>10</b> in the service state (i.e., at step <b>116</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>). In the service state, the piston <b>110</b> can be positioned to the far right within the spacer assembly <b>42</b> such that untreated water can enter through the inlet <b>24</b>, through the top portion <b>22</b>, past a baffle <b>146</b>, and enter the air layer <b>32</b> of the tank <b>12</b>. The baffle <b>146</b> can disperse the untreated water into the air layer <b>32</b> to allow sufficient mixing of oxygen molecules in the air layer <b>32</b> with minerals (e.g., iron, sulfide, manganese, etc., in ion form) in the untreated water. By mixing with the oxygen molecules, the minerals can become oxidized and, as a result, become solid molecules or particulates. After passing through the air layer <b>32</b>, the untreated water can reach the media layer <b>34</b>. The media layer <b>34</b> can include a filtration media or resin <b>148</b>, which can filter the solid particulates formed in the air layer <b>32</b> as well as any other particulates to allow treated water to pass to the water layer <b>36</b>. The treated water can then pass through a second collector <b>150</b>, up a distributor pipe <b>152</b>, through the distributor <b>28</b>, and out through the outlet <b>26</b>. The second collector <b>150</b> can act as a screen to prevent the filtration media <b>148</b> from leaving the tank <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">While in the service state, oxygen in the air layer <b>32</b> can become depleted due to the oxidation of the minerals. As a result, the water treatment system <b>10</b> can enter the regeneration stage to replenish the air layer <b>30</b>. The regeneration stage can include the first air bleed state (i.e., step <b>122</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), the second air bleed state (i.e., step <b>128</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), the backwash state (i.e., step <b>134</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), and the air draw state (i.e., step <b>140</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>). In the first air bleed state, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the piston <b>110</b> can be moved slightly to the left such that the top portion <b>22</b> is no longer in fluid communication with the inlet <b>24</b>. The piston <b>110</b> can be positioned slightly offset from one of the piston seals <b>94</b> so that there is a small vent channel <b>154</b> between the top portion <b>22</b> and the drain <b>20</b>, allowing air (i.e., pressurized air) to exit the tank <b>12</b> through the drain <b>20</b>. In the second air bleed state, the piston <b>110</b> can again be moved to the left to further open the vent channel <b>154</b> and allow more air to leave the tank <b>12</b>. Following the second air bleed state, any air still in the tank <b>12</b> can be at the same pressure as air outside the tank <b>12</b> (i.e., there is no longer a pressurized air head inside the tank <b>12</b>). In some embodiments, the distance between the piston seal <b>94</b> and the piston <b>110</b> during the first air bleed can be in the range of about 0.01 inches to about 0.02 inches, creating a vent channel <b>154</b> with an area of about 0.05 square inches. The distance between the piston seal <b>94</b> and the piston <b>110</b> during the second air bleed can be greater than or equal to about 0.05 inches, creating a vent channel <b>154</b> with an area of about 0.1 square inches. These distances and areas have been found to provide effective air bleeding without adverse effects, such as noise and vibration.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">While in the service state, the addition of untreated water can compress the air within the tank <b>12</b>, creating the pressurized air head. If the piston <b>110</b> were to completely open a fluid path between the top portion <b>22</b> and the drain <b>20</b> during the regeneration stage, the pressurized air would rapidly evacuate the tank <b>12</b>. This rapid evacuation of air can cause noise from the air flow itself and can also jar pipes and components, resulting in a noisy water treatment system. Using the smaller vent channel <b>154</b> for the first air bleed state for a predefined time period allows the pressurized air to slowly bleed out, thus reducing noise in the water treatment system <b>10</b>. The time periods for the first air bleed state and the second air bleed state can be defined so that the air bleed states are performed within a substantially minimum time frame that still allows optimum air bleeding without the adverse effects.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The backwash state, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, can follow the second air bleed state. In the backwash state, the piston <b>110</b> can be positioned further to the left such that the inlet <b>24</b> is in communication with the distributor <b>28</b> and the top portion <b>22</b> is in communication with the drain <b>20</b>. Water from the inlet <b>24</b> can flow through the distributor <b>28</b> back into the tank <b>12</b> via the distributor pipe <b>152</b> and the second collector <b>150</b>. The water layer <b>36</b> can then rise, thus lifting and agitating the filtration media <b>148</b> to carry particulates (i.e., the solid molecules) out of the tank <b>12</b> through the top portion <b>22</b> to the drain <b>20</b>. In addition, as the water layer <b>36</b> rises, any air left in the tank <b>12</b> can be pushed out through the drain as well.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates the water treatment system <b>10</b> in the air draw state. After the backwash state, air from the atmosphere (i.e., oxygenated air) can reenter the tank <b>12</b> to replenish the air layer <b>32</b> and to pack down the media layer <b>34</b>. The air can enter the valve assembly <b>18</b> via the injector assembly <b>46</b>. The air can then pass through a venturi assembly <b>156</b>. The venturi assembly <b>156</b> can create a vacuum to draw the air and untreated water from the inlet <b>24</b> into the top portion <b>22</b>. The air can mix with the untreated water traveling through top portion <b>22</b> and replenish the air layer <b>32</b> in tank <b>12</b>. Once the air draw has been completed (i.e., the air layer <b>32</b> has a new supply of oxygen), the piston <b>110</b> can be repositioned back to the far right and the water treatment system <b>10</b> can return to the service state.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the piston assembly <b>40</b> can be operated by an encoder <b>158</b>, such as an optical encoder, in the powerhead <b>16</b>. The encoder <b>158</b> can include an encoder shaft <b>160</b> coupled to, or integral with, an eccentric shaft <b>162</b>. The eccentric shaft <b>162</b> can be coupled to the piston <b>110</b> by engaging a hole <b>164</b> in the link <b>98</b> (i.e., the link <b>98</b> of the piston assembly <b>40</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>). In some embodiments, the encoder <b>158</b> can include about 85 positioning slot/rib pairs and one homing slot/rib pair. The arrangement of the positioning slots/ribs can allow rotational control of the encoder <b>158</b> within about two-degree increments. The homing slot/rib pair can be used to stop rotation of the encoder <b>158</b>. The full lateral movement of the piston <b>110</b> can be about 1.125 inches, with movement control in increments of about 0.013 inches, because motion translated from a rotational element (i.e., the encoder <b>158</b>) to a linear element (i.e., the piston <b>110</b>) creates a sinusoidal relationship between rotational control and linear control. The precise control by the encoder <b>158</b> can allow the piston <b>110</b> to create the small vent channels <b>154</b> with respect to the piston seals <b>94</b> during the first and the second air bleed states.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Positional control of the encoder <b>158</b> can be provided through the use of a motor <b>166</b>, an optical sensor <b>167</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>), and a controller <b>169</b> (such as a microcontroller, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>). A motor drive gear <b>168</b> can be rotated by the motor <b>166</b> and can engage an encoder drive gear <b>170</b> to rotate the encoder <b>158</b>. The motor <b>166</b> can be coupled to and supported by an upper support plate <b>172</b> with fasteners <b>174</b>. The motor <b>166</b> can also be electrically connected to a circuit board <b>176</b> by a wire harness <b>178</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The controller <b>169</b> can be coupled to a front side <b>195</b> of the circuit board <b>176</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>. The optical sensor <b>167</b> can be separate or integral with the encoder <b>158</b> and can provide control inputs to the controller <b>169</b> regarding the position of the encoder <b>158</b>. In one embodiment, the optical sensor <b>167</b> can be coupled to a back side <b>179</b> of the circuit board <b>176</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>. The motor <b>166</b> can receive control outputs from the controller <b>169</b> to adjust or maintain the position of the encoder <b>158</b>. The optical sensor <b>167</b> can be positioned relative to the encoder <b>158</b> so that rotation of the encoder <b>158</b> via the motor <b>166</b> can alternately enable and disable the optical sensor's optical path.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The powerhead <b>16</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, can also include a backplate <b>180</b>, a cover <b>182</b>, a display <b>184</b>, a lower support plate <b>186</b>, a switch <b>188</b>, a cam <b>190</b>, a transformer <b>192</b>, and a meter cable <b>194</b>. The backplate <b>180</b> and the cover <b>182</b> can enclose the components of the powerhead <b>16</b>, including the motor <b>166</b>, the circuit board <b>176</b>, the encoder <b>158</b>, etc. The display <b>184</b> can be coupled to the front side <b>195</b> of the circuit board <b>176</b> and controlled by the controller <b>169</b>. A hole <b>196</b> in the cover <b>182</b> can allow a user to view the display <b>184</b>. The lower support plate <b>186</b> can support the encoder <b>185</b> and the encoder drive gear <b>170</b>. The switch <b>188</b> and the cam <b>190</b> can be supported by the upper support plate <b>172</b>. The transformer <b>192</b> can be electrically connected to a conventional outlet to power the water treatment system <b>10</b> (e.g., through the controller <b>169</b>). The meter cable <b>194</b> can be used to detect water flow to the tank <b>12</b> and can be electrically connected to the controller <b>169</b>. In some embodiments, the controller <b>169</b> can trigger the regeneration stage after a predetermined amount of water flow to the tank <b>12</b>, as detected by the meter cable <b>194</b>. In other embodiments, the controller <b>169</b> can trigger the regeneration stage after a predetermined amount of time.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> illustrates a block diagram of a user control method for the water treatment system <b>10</b> according to one embodiment of the invention. The steps described below can be adjustable operational controls used by the controller <b>169</b> to operate the water treatment system <b>10</b>. These steps can be displayed by the display <b>184</b> and a user can make adjustments accordingly by pressing buttons <b>198</b> on the circuit board <b>176</b> through button covers <b>200</b> on the cover <b>184</b>. In one embodiment, these steps can be displayed during a &#x201c;system setup&#x201d; of the water treatment system <b>10</b>. At step <b>202</b>, the user can choose the system type, such as a timed system or a metered system. The timed system can trigger regeneration stages after predetermined lengths of time, while the metered system can trigger regeneration stages after predetermined amounts of water flow, as described above with reference to the meter cable <b>194</b>. At step <b>204</b>, the user can choose the valve type, for example by entering or choosing the type of valve assembly being used in the water treatment system <b>10</b>. At step <b>206</b>, the user can choose what type of regenerant flow is needed. For example, the user can choose a 5-cycle regeneration stage to be performed. At step <b>208</b>, the user can choose whether information is displayed in metric (SI) or US units. At step <b>210</b>, the user can choose a regeneration override time, for example, a number of days. A regeneration override can occur when the regeneration stage has not been triggered in a predetermined length of time (as designated by the user). At step <b>212</b>, the user can choose a time of day the regeneration stage should be triggered. At step <b>214</b>, the user can choose a time period, such as about 2 minutes, for the water treatment system <b>10</b> to operate at a first cycle (e.g., the first air bleed state). At step <b>216</b>, the user can choose a time period, such as about 1 minute, for the water treatment system <b>10</b> to operate at a second cycle (e.g., the second air bleed state). At step <b>218</b>, the user can choose a time period, such as about 10 minutes, for the water treatment system <b>10</b> to operate at a third cycle (e.g., the backwash state). At control step <b>220</b>, the user can choose a time period, such as about 40 minutes, for the water treatment system <b>10</b> to operate at a fourth cycle (e.g., the air draw state). At step <b>222</b>, the user can choose a time period, such as about 10 minutes, for the water treatment system <b>10</b> to operate at a fifth cycle (e.g., a rapid rinse state, often used for water softening). At step <b>224</b>, the user can choose to enable or disable an auxiliary relay, such as an alarm. At control step, the user can choose to allow the water treatment system <b>10</b> to enter the service state (e.g., for the first time after installation).</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">It will be appreciated by those skilled in the art that while the invention has been described above in connection with particular embodiments and examples, the invention is not necessarily so limited, and that numerous other embodiments, examples, uses, modifications and departures from the embodiments, examples and uses are intended to be encompassed by the claims attached hereto. The entire disclosure of each patent and publication cited herein is incorporated by reference, as if each such patent or publication were individually incorporated by reference herein. Various features and advantages of the invention are set forth in the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method of providing a regeneration stage in a water treatment system, the method comprising:
<claim-text>pressurizing a tank by the addition of untreated water;</claim-text>
<claim-text>entering a first air bleed state for a first time period to allow pressurized, deoxygenated air to exit the water treatment system;</claim-text>
<claim-text>entering a second air bleed state for a second time period to equalize a first air pressure of remaining deoxygenated air inside the water treatment system with a second atmospheric air pressure outside the water treatment system;</claim-text>
<claim-text>entering a backwash state for a third time period to expel the remaining deoxygenated air and particulates from inside the water treatment system; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>entering an air draw state for a fourth time period to allow oxygenated air to enter the water treatment system.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> and further comprising providing a valve assembly and a powerhead to operate the water treatment system in the first air bleed state, the second air bleed state, the backwash state, and the air draw state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the first time period is about 2 minutes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the second time period is about 1 minute.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein each one of the first time period, the second time period, the third time period, and the fourth time period is adjustable.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> and further comprising removing at least one of iron, sulfide, and manganese using the water treatment system. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
