<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626309-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626309</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13892192</doc-number>
<date>20130510</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>36</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>607 57</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Convex cup internal receiver unit for a cochlear implant</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4532930</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Crosby et al.</name>
<date>19850800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8244366</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Chang et al.</name>
<date>20120800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2002/0029074</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Treaba et al.</name>
<date>20020300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0260361</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Gibson</name>
<date>20041200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>607 57</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0312717</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Gantz</name>
<date>20081200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0160892</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Tice</name>
<date>20100600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>604500</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1951175</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20011100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>4</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>607136-137</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>607 55- 56</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Alshemari</last-name>
<first-name>Hasan M. Sh. Sh.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Saad Al-Abdulla</city>
<country>KW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Alshemari</last-name>
<first-name>Hasan M. Sh. Sh.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Saad Al-Abdulla</city>
<country>KW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Litman</last-name>
<first-name>Richard C.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Layno</last-name>
<first-name>Carl H</first-name>
<department>3766</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Stice</last-name>
<first-name>Paula J</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The implantable medical device is configured as a cochlear implant or the like. The implantable medical device includes a stimulator unit, an elongate electrode carrier in electrical communication with said stimulator unit, and an internal receiver unit. The internal receiver unit is configured as a suction cup having first and second convex cup portions. The first convex cup portion is adapted for mounting against a bone surface. Preferably, each of the first and second convex cup portions is formed from a resilient, flexible, biocompatible material. The second convex cup portion has a central bore formed therein. When the second convex cup portion is mated against the first convex cup portion, a threaded screw extends through the bore to contact the first convex cup portion and is tightened, thus compressing the first convex cup portion against the bone surface for suctional adhesion thereto.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="86.19mm" wi="164.17mm" file="US08626309-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="220.73mm" wi="178.56mm" file="US08626309-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="215.48mm" wi="168.06mm" file="US08626309-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="209.55mm" wi="183.81mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626309-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="233.68mm" wi="175.01mm" file="US08626309-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to implantable medical devices, and particularly to cochlear implants or the like utilizing a suction cup for securement against a bone surface.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A cochlear implant is a surgically implanted electronic device that provides a sense of sound to a person who is profoundly deaf or severely hard of hearing. Cochlear implants may help provide hearing in patients who are deaf due to damage to sensory hair cells in their cochleas. In these patients, the implants often can enable sufficient hearing for better understanding of speech. The quality of sound is different from natural hearing, with less sound information being received and processed by the brain. However, many patients are able to hear and understand speech and environmental sounds. Cochlear implants are well known in the field of implantable medical devices. One such implant is shown in U.S. Pat. No. 4,532,930, which is hereby incorporated by reference in its entirety.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Cochlear implant systems typically consist of two components, namely, an external component, commonly referred to as a processor unit, and an internal, implanted component, commonly referred to as a receiver/stimulator unit. The internal component is implanted in the patient's skull, under the skin. In order to fix the internal component to the patient's skull, typical conventional cochlear implantation utilizes drilling into the patient's cortical bone to form anchor holes, and the internal component unit is then secured to the skull using bone screws or the like. Given the high risks involved in invasive surgical procedures, particularly in drilling into a patient's skull, it would be highly desirable to provide a far less invasive method of securing a cochlear implant to a patient's cortical bone.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Thus, an implantable medical device solving the aforementioned problems is desired.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The implantable medical device is configured as a cochlear implant or the like. The implantable medical device includes a stimulator unit, an elongate electrode carrier in electrical communication with the stimulator unit, and an internal receiver unit. The internal receiver unit is configured as a suction cup having first and second convex cup portions. The first convex cup portion is adapted for mounting against a bone surface. Preferably, each of the first and second convex cup portions is formed from a resilient, flexible, biocompatible material.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Preferably, the second convex cup portion has a central aperture formed therethrough. When the second convex cup portion is mated against the first convex cup portion, a threaded screw, which passes through the aperture to contact the first convex cup portion, is tightened, thus compressing the first convex cup portion against the bone surface for suctional adhesion thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">These and other features of the present invention will become readily apparent upon further review of the following specification and drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> diagrammatically illustrates implantation of an implantable medical device according to the present invention against a patient's cortical bone.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a plan view of the implantable medical device according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an exploded, perspective view of a suction cup assembly of the implantable medical device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a side view in section of the suction cup assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, illustrated in a non-compressed state.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a side view in section of the suction cup assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, illustrated in a compressed state.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Similar reference characters denote corresponding features consistently throughout the attached drawings.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates the implantable medical device <b>10</b> implanted within the head of a patient, fixed adjacent the patient's cortical bone. As shown, the implantable medical device <b>10</b> may be configured as a cochlear implant, although it should be understood that the implantable medical device <b>10</b> may be configured as any suitable type of medical implant or the like. As shown, device <b>10</b> includes an internal receiver unit <b>1</b>, a stimulator unit <b>2</b>, and an elongate electrode carrier <b>3</b>, as are well known in the field of cochlear implants and the like. As is also well known in the field of implantable medical devices, the internal receiver unit <b>1</b>, stimulator unit <b>2</b> and elongate electrode carrier <b>3</b> are preferably hermetically sealed within a biocompatible housing formed from silicone or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">As best shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, the internal receiver unit <b>1</b> unit is configured as a suction cup for mounting on the patient's cortical bone. The overall suction cup assembly <b>110</b> includes a first convex cup portion or layer <b>200</b>, having a central convex suction pad <b>4</b>. The central convex suction pad <b>4</b> is defined by a substantially circular, peripheral edge <b>5</b>, from which extends a flat, annular flange <b>6</b>. The flat, annular flange <b>6</b> extends about the peripheral edge <b>5</b> and is preferably formed from a biocompatible, resilient material.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">A second convex cup portion or layer <b>300</b> mates with, and is mounted over, the convex face of the suction pad <b>4</b>. The second convex cup portion includes a convex frame <b>7</b> having an annular, outer pressing portion <b>8</b> peripherally extending therefrom. Pressing portion <b>8</b> is also preferably formed from a biocompatible, resilient material. The second convex cup portion <b>300</b> also includes a central, ring-shaped fastening portion <b>9</b> having a bore <b>12</b> formed centrally therethrough. The pressing portion <b>8</b> is mated against the flat flange <b>6</b> of suction pad <b>4</b>, as best seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. A central screw <b>11</b> is threaded into the bore <b>12</b> of the central, ring-shaped fastening portion <b>9</b>. Preferably, both the central screw <b>11</b> and the central, ring-shaped fastening portion <b>9</b> are formed from a biocompatible material, such as titanium. The central, ring-shaped fastening portion <b>9</b>, the central screw <b>11</b>, or both are magnetic, thus forming the magnet of the cochlear implant, as is well known in the field of cochlear implants. The antenna of the cochlear implant, as is well known in the field of cochlear implants and the like, is preferably mounted within the pressing portion <b>8</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, after placing the central screw <b>11</b> in the bore <b>12</b> of the central, ring-shaped fastening portion <b>9</b>, the center of the suction cup assembly <b>110</b>, including the suction pad <b>4</b>, is pressed against the outer surface <b>400</b> of a bone, such as the cortical bone. The open volume <b>500</b> defined by the concave, lower portion of the first cup portion <b>200</b> is reduced as the central screw <b>11</b> pushes the suction pad <b>4</b> against the bone surface <b>400</b>. This action causes any air or other fluid within volume <b>500</b>, between the suction pad <b>4</b> and the bone outer surface <b>400</b>, to be expelled past the rims <b>6</b> and <b>8</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Preferably, the suction cup assembly <b>110</b> is formed from a generally elastic and resilient material. Thus, when the user ceases to apply pressure to the center of the outside of the suction cup assembly <b>110</b> (via central screw <b>11</b>), the suction cup assembly <b>110</b> is generally restored to its original, curved shape. The decrease in volume of space <b>500</b> also results in a decrease in fluid pressure, creating a pressure differential, similar to a conventional suction cup, which fixes the internal components of cochlear implant <b>10</b> to the bone outer surface <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Although the implantable medical device <b>10</b> is shown as having only a single suction cup attachment, it should be understood that any desired number of suction cup attachments may be utilized. Further, although shown as having the internal receiver unit <b>1</b> configured as a suction cup, it should be understood that any suitable portion of the implant may be configured as a suction cup. Additionally, it should be further understood that the first convex cup portion <b>200</b> may be configured having additional features or layers that are common to suction cups, such as additional gel layers, semi-gel layers or the like. The first convex cup portion <b>200</b> is preferably formed from a silicone rubber or other elastomeric biocompatible material having a relatively high coefficient of friction with respect to the bone surface <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">It is to be understood that the present invention is not limited to the embodiments described above, but encompasses any and all embodiments within the scope of the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>I claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An implantable medical device, comprising:
<claim-text>a stimulator unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an elongate electrode carrier in electrical communication with the stimulator unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an internal receiver unit, the internal receiver unit having a substantially convex contour defining a suction cup for attachment to a bone surface, the internal receiver unit comprises first and second convex cup portions, the first convex cup portion being adapted for mounting against the bone surface and including:
<claim-text>i) a central convex suction pad having a substantially circular peripheral edge; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>ii) a flat, annular flange extending from the substantially circular peripheral edge of the central convex suction pad;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second convex cup portion comprises:
<claim-text>i) a convex frame portion having a substantially circular peripheral edge;</claim-text>
<claim-text>ii) an outer peripheral portion annularly formed on the substantially circular peripheral edge of the convex frame portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>iii) a central, ring-shaped fastening portion and a central bore extending through the central, ring-shaped fastening portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The implantable medical device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a threaded screw threadable into the bore, whereby when said first and second convex cup portions are mated together, axial movement of the threaded screw selectively presses a central portion of the first convex cup portion against the bone surface for suctional attachment thereto.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The implantable medical device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein said first and second convex cup portions are each formed from a resilient, flexible, biocompatible material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A method of securing an implantable medical device to a bone surface, comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>providing an implantable medical device having an internal receiver unit having a substantially convex body defining a suction cup, wherein the body of the internal receiver unit has first and second convex cup portions; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>securing the implantable medical device to a bone surface through suction between the suction cup and the bone surface, wherein the step of securing the implantable medical device to the bone surface comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>i) pressing against a central portion of the first convex cup portion to generate the suction against the bone surface; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>ii) tightening a threaded screw through a bore formed through the second convex cup portion and contacting the first convex cup portion. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
