<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625982-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625982</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13327501</doc-number>
<date>20111215</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2011 1 0229893</doc-number>
<date>20110811</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>163</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>17</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>225</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>M</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>396535</main-classification>
<further-classification>348373</further-classification>
<further-classification>4555751</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Housing assembly</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0223969</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Chou</name>
<date>20110900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4555561</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>18</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>396535</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>396429</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>396448</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>348373</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>348 1402</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>348552</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4555561</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4555751</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>359511</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130039642</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130214</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wang</last-name>
<first-name>Zhi-Yun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wang</last-name>
<first-name>Zhi-Yun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Shenzhen Futaihong Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>FIH (Hong Kong) Limited</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Kowloon</city>
<country>HK</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Blackman</last-name>
<first-name>Rochelle-Ann J</first-name>
<department>2852</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A housing assembly includes a housing, a camera bezel and a retaining structure. The housing includes a plurality of latching elements. The retaining structure is fixed to the camera bezel, the retaining structure including a plurality of retaining elements corresponding to the latching elements. Each retaining element is bent to latch with one of the latching elements so the camera bezel is fixed to the housing.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="128.02mm" wi="155.11mm" file="US08625982-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="209.13mm" wi="164.85mm" file="US08625982-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="237.74mm" wi="168.23mm" file="US08625982-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="240.45mm" wi="170.26mm" file="US08625982-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="198.88mm" wi="169.59mm" file="US08625982-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="204.39mm" wi="166.20mm" file="US08625982-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The disclosure generally relates to housing assemblies, and particularly relates to a housing with a camera bezel.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Many electronic devices, such as mobile phones, have any one of a variety of camera modules to enable the taking of pictures. A camera module used in an electronic device is received in a housing. The housing has a camera bezel, which functions as a decorative element for attracting consumers and which also functions as a protective member, preventing the camera module from being damaged or soiled. However, it is difficult to firmly fix the camera bezel to the housing with a low profile.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Therefore, there is room for improvement within the art.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Many aspects of the exemplary housing for portable electronic device can be better understood with reference to the following drawings. These drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the exemplary housing assembly. Moreover, in the drawings like reference numerals designate corresponding parts throughout the several views. Wherever possible, the same reference numbers are used throughout the drawings to refer to the same or like elements of an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view of a housing assembly according to an exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exploded view of the housing assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is another exploded view of the housing assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> viewed from another aspect.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is an enlarged view of a retaining structure of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an assembled view of the housing assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">For illustrative purposes, the device is an electronic device such as a radiotelephone. The radiotelephone described herein is a representation of the type of wireless communication device that may benefit from the present disclosure. However, it is to be understood that the present disclosure may be applied to any type of hand-held or portable device including, but not limited to, the following devices: cordless phones, paging devices, personal digital assistants, portable computers, pen-based or keyboard-based handheld devices, remote control units, portable media players that have wireless communication capability and the like. Accordingly, any reference herein to the radiotelephone should also be considered to apply equally to other portable wireless electronic devices.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">An exemplary embodiment of a housing assembly <b>100</b> of an electronic device is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>. The housing assembly <b>100</b> includes a housing <b>10</b>, a camera bezel <b>20</b> and a retaining structure <b>30</b> retaining the camera bezel <b>20</b> on the housing <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the housing <b>10</b> includes a main panel <b>11</b>, a peripheral panel <b>12</b>, a mounting groove <b>13</b>, a plurality of latching elements <b>15</b> and a securing groove <b>16</b>. The rectangular main panel <b>11</b> includes an outer surface <b>111</b> and an inner surface <b>112</b> opposite to the outer surface <b>111</b>. The peripheral panel <b>12</b> protrudes from the inner surface <b>112</b>. The mounting groove <b>13</b> includes a groove bottom wall <b>131</b> defining a light incident hole <b>14</b> allowing light to enter into the camera module (not shown). A mounting wall <b>113</b> protrudes from the inner surface <b>112</b> surrounding the light incident hole <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Each latching element <b>15</b> includes a receiving groove <b>151</b>, a latching block <b>152</b> located in the receiving groove <b>151</b> and defines a channel <b>153</b> through the main panel <b>11</b> adjacent to the latching block <b>152</b>. The latching blocks <b>152</b> are made of plastic. The channels <b>153</b> further communicate with the mounting groove <b>13</b>. In this exemplary embodiment, the number of the latching elements <b>15</b> is four, and each two latching elements <b>15</b> are located at one side of the mounting wall <b>113</b>. The channels <b>153</b> are located between the mounting wall <b>113</b> and the latching blocks <b>152</b>. The securing groove <b>16</b> is defined through the main panel <b>11</b> adjacent to one of the receiving grooves <b>151</b>, communicating with the mounting groove <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The camera bezel <b>20</b> is received in the mounting groove <b>13</b>. The camera bezel <b>20</b> includes a main body <b>21</b> and a lens <b>22</b> fixed to the main body <b>21</b> aligning with the light incident hole <b>14</b>. The camera bezel <b>20</b> further includes a reflective mirror <b>23</b> adjacent to the lens <b>22</b>. The main body <b>21</b> includes a back surface <b>212</b> for fixing the retaining structure <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The retaining structure <b>30</b> includes a first supporting sheet <b>32</b>, a second supporting sheet <b>33</b> parallel to the first supporting sheet <b>32</b>, a connecting sheet <b>31</b> connecting the center portions of the first supporting sheet <b>32</b> and the second supporting sheet <b>33</b>, and a plurality of retaining elements <b>34</b>. In this exemplary embodiment, the number of the retaining elements <b>34</b> is four, each retaining element <b>34</b> is a metal sheet protruding from one end of the first supporting sheet <b>32</b> and the second supporting sheet <b>33</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, each retaining element <b>34</b> is retained in one of the receiving grooves <b>151</b> and latched with one of the latching blocks <b>152</b> so the retaining structure <b>30</b> is fixed to the housing <b>10</b>. Each retaining element <b>34</b> includes a contacting surface <b>35</b>, a retaining hole <b>36</b> and two slots <b>37</b>. Each retaining hole <b>36</b> is defined in a center of corresponding contacting surface <b>35</b> and latched with one of the latching blocks <b>152</b> to fix the retaining structure <b>30</b> to the housing <b>10</b>. Each slot <b>37</b> is defined in the corresponding contacting surface <b>35</b> and located at two sides of the corresponding retaining hole <b>36</b>. The slots <b>37</b> facilitate the retaining elements <b>34</b> to be bent along the slots <b>37</b>. The retaining structure <b>30</b> further defines a positioning protrusion <b>38</b> protruding from one end of the second supporting sheet <b>33</b>, to position the retaining structure <b>30</b> to the housing <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, to fix the camera bezel <b>20</b> to the housing <b>10</b>, the retaining structure <b>30</b> is welded to the back surface <b>212</b> of the camera bezel <b>20</b>. The camera bezel <b>20</b> is received in the mounting groove <b>13</b> with the positioning protrusion <b>38</b> positioned in the securing groove <b>16</b>, and the retaining elements <b>34</b> pass through the channels <b>153</b>. The retaining elements <b>34</b> are bent toward the latching blocks <b>152</b> to make the latching blocks <b>152</b> latch in the retaining holes <b>36</b>, until the retaining elements <b>34</b> are received in the receiving groove <b>151</b>. At this time, the contacting surfaces <b>35</b> contact with the main panel <b>11</b>. The latching blocks <b>152</b> are hot-melted to firmly fix the retaining element in the receiving grooves <b>151</b> so the camera bezel <b>20</b> is assembled to the housing <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">It is to be understood, however, that even through numerous characteristics and advantages of the exemplary disclosure have been set forth in the foregoing description, together with details of the structure and function of the disclosure, the disclosure is illustrative only, and changes may be made in detail, especially in matters of shape, size, and arrangement of parts within the principles of the disclosure to the full extent indicated by the broad general meaning of the terms in which the appended claims are expressed.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A housing assembly, comprising:
<claim-text>a housing including a plurality of latching elements and a main panel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a camera bezel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a retaining structure fixed to the camera bezel, the retaining structure including four retaining elements corresponding to the latching elements, each retaining element being bent to latch with one of the latching elements so the camera bezel is fixed to the housing; each retaining element is a metal sheet defining a retaining hole; each latching element includes a latching block and a channel defining through the main panel adjacent to the latching block; each retaining element passes through one of the channels and is bent to be latched with one of the latching blocks.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The housing assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each retaining element further defines two slots respectively located two sides of corresponding retaining hole, each retaining element is bent along corresponding slots to be latched in corresponding latching block.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The housing assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the retaining structure includes a first supporting sheet, a second supporting sheet parallel to the first supporting sheet, and a connecting sheet connecting the first supporting sheet and the second supporting sheet.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The housing assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein each retaining element protrudes from one of ends of the first supporting sheet and the second supporting sheet.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The housing assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the second supporting sheet protrudes a positioning protrusion, the housing defines a securing groove, the positioning protrusion is secured in the securing groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The housing assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein each latching element further defines a receiving groove, corresponding latching block is located in receiving groove; each retaining element is received in the receiving groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The housing assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the main panel includes an outer surface, a mounting groove defined in the outer surface, and an inner surface; the latching element is located in the inner surface; the camera bezel is received in the mounting groove; the channel and the securing groove both communicate with the mounting groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The housing assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the camera bezel includes a lens, the main panel further defines a light incident hole, in which the lens is fixed.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A housing assembly, comprising:
<claim-text>a housing including an inner surface, an outer surface and a plurality of latching elements, each latching element including a latching block protruding from the inner surface and a channel defining through the inner surface and the second surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a camera bezel mounted on the outer surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a retaining structure fixed to the camera bezel, the retaining structure including four retaining elements corresponding to the latching elements, each retaining element passing through one of the channels and being latched with one of the latching elements; wherein each retaining element is a metal sheet defining a retaining hole; each retaining element is bent to be latched with one of the latching blocks.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The housing assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein each retaining element further defines two slots respectively located two sides of corresponding retaining hole, each retaining element is bent along corresponding slots to be latched in corresponding latching block.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The housing assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the retaining structure includes a first supporting sheet, a second supporting sheet parallel to the first supporting sheet, and a connecting sheet connecting the first supporting sheet and the second supporting sheet.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The housing assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein each retaining element is protruding from one of ends of the first supporting sheet and the second supporting sheet.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The housing assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the second supporting sheet protrudes a positioning protrusion, the housing defines a securing groove, in which the positioning protrusion is secured.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The housing assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein each latching element further defines a receiving groove, in which corresponding latching block is located; each retaining element is received in the receiving groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The housing assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the housing includes a mounting groove defined in the outer surface, the camera bezel is received in the mounting groove; the channel and the securing groove both communicate with the mounting groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The housing assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the camera bezel includes a lens, the main panel further defines a light incident hole, in which the lens is fixed.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. A housing assembly, comprising:
<claim-text>a housing including an inner surface, an outer surface and a plurality of latching elements, each latching element including a latching block protruding from the inner surface and a channel defining through the inner surface and the second surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a camera bezel mounted on the outer surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a retaining structure fixed to the camera bezel, the retaining structure including a plurality of retaining elements corresponding to the latching elements;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the latching block is made of plastic, the retaining elements are made of metal; each retaining element defines a retaining hole; each retaining element passing through one of the channels and then being bent toward one of the latching blocks until each latching block is located in one of the retaining holes; the latching blocks are hot-melted to fix the retaining elements on the latching elements.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The housing assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein each latching element further defines a receiving groove, in which corresponding latching block is located; each retaining element is received in the receiving groove. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
