<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625384-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625384</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13053357</doc-number>
<date>20110322</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-241254</doc-number>
<date>20101027</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>392</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>11</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>8</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>3652331</main-classification>
<further-classification>36518908</further-classification>
<further-classification>365189011</further-classification>
<further-classification>36518915</further-classification>
<further-classification>36518916</further-classification>
<further-classification>36523316</further-classification>
<further-classification>36523317</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Synchronous type semiconductor storage device and DRAM</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5341341</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Fukuzo</name>
<date>19940800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36523314</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5659515</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Matsuo et al.</name>
<date>19970800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>365222</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5682343</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Tomishima et al.</name>
<date>19971000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>365 63</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6108229</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Shau</name>
<date>20000800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>365 52</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6813696</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kanda et al.</name>
<date>20041100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>711167</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6909658</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Arimoto et al.</name>
<date>20050600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>365222</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2000-105995</doc-number>
<date>20001100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>365189011</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36518915</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36518916</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>3652331</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36523316</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36523317</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120106268</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120503</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Iizuka</last-name>
<first-name>Mariko</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yokohama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Iizuka</last-name>
<first-name>Mariko</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yokohama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>White &#x26; Case LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Kabushiki Kaisha Toshiba</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Bui</last-name>
<first-name>Thao</first-name>
<department>2824</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A synchronous type semiconductor storage device includes an array unit which includes a cell array and sense amplifiers. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device includes a read/write pulse generator which generates a read pulse signal and a write pulse signal according to a clock signal, the clock signal defining one cycle time of a read operation and a write operation with respect to the array unit as one cycle. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device includes a secondary amplifier which is activated according to the read pulse signal to read out data stored in the sense amplifiers through the read/write line. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device includes a write driver which is activated according to the write pulse signal to write data in the sense amplifiers through the read/write line.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="102.36mm" wi="215.90mm" file="US08625384-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="231.90mm" wi="164.08mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625384-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="207.01mm" wi="163.24mm" file="US08625384-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="239.44mm" wi="134.03mm" file="US08625384-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="218.52mm" wi="117.35mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625384-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="186.61mm" wi="142.66mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625384-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="220.98mm" wi="151.98mm" file="US08625384-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="228.77mm" wi="152.06mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625384-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="234.02mm" wi="116.42mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625384-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is based upon and claims the benefit of priority from the prior Japanese Patent Application No. 2010-241254, filed on Oct. 27, 2010, the entire contents of which are incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Embodiments described herein relate generally to a Synchronous type semiconductor storage device and a DRAM.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Background Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Recently, an increasing integration of a memory device tends to lead to an increase in the capacity of an array unit of, for example, a DRAM. Due to such tendency, the capacitance of wirings thereof also increases. Therefore, when a transistor is at the so-called slow corner of the PVT conditions (process parameters, voltage, and temperature), the read/write time of the array unit is deteriorated greatly. In addition, in a highly integrated memory device, a ratio of a read/write time to a cycle time tends to be larger.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">On the other hand, although the line and space patterns of the column selection lines and the data lines of the DRAM are scaled, the R/C value of the internal wiring of the array unit is rarely scaled. Therefore, the read/write time is not reduced due to the R/C value of the internal wiring even at the fast corner of the transistor. Accordingly, it is not preferable to decrease the pulse width of the read/write pulse signal of the array unit at the fast corner.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Therefore, the read/write pulse signal may have a large duty ratio with respect to the cycle time defined as one cycle of a clock signal, and it is necessary to suppress the decrease in the pulse width at the fast corner (in other words, it is necessary to suppress the PVT change in the pulse width).</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The clock signal as a trigger clock for the read/write pulse signal is input to various circuits. For this reason, it is preferable that the pulse width of the clock signal is controlled independently of the read/write pulse width.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Therefore, conventionally, an edge trigger type pulse generator has been used as a read/write pulse generation circuit. Accordingly, the pulse generator may be compatible with both of the cases: one case where the pulse width of the clock signal is smaller than the read/write pulse width and the other case where the pulse width of the clock signal is larger than the read/write pulse width.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The edge trigger type pulse generator performs a pulse reset operation by using the pulse output as a trigger. In the edge trigger type pulse generator, a reset path for resetting is longer than a path for generating a pulse, and the reset path is a rate-controlling factor at the time of generating the pulse comprising a large duty ratio with respect to the cycle time as described.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In addition, for the speedy reset operation, there is a trend that the size of the transistor used for the reset operation increases. As a result, the number of logic stages in the path for generating the pulse is also increased in order to make it possible for more driving capacity for the reset transistor to be obtained. However, the increase in the number of logic stages acts as a negative factor in suppressing the PVT change in the read/write pulse signal.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram showing an example of a configuration of a synchronous type semiconductor storage device <b>1000</b> according to an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a diagram schematically showing an example of a configuration including an array unit <b>101</b>, a row decoder RD, a column decoder CD, a secondary amplifier 2ndAmp, and a write driver Wdrv of the synchronous type semiconductor storage device <b>1000</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram showing an example of waveforms of signals at the time of the read operation and at the time of the write operation of the synchronous type semiconductor storage device <b>1000</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagram showing an example of a configuration of the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b> of the synchronous type semiconductor storage device <b>1000</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a diagram showing an example of the circuit configuration of the first and second pulse generation circuits <b>100</b><i>b </i>and <b>100</b><i>c </i>illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a diagram showing an example of waveforms of the operations of the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, and an example of waveforms of the operations of an edge trigger type read/write pulse generator as a comparative example;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a diagram showing another example of a configuration the synchronous type semiconductor storage device <b>1000</b> according to the embodiment; and</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a diagram showing another example of a configuration of the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b> of the synchronous type semiconductor storage device <b>1000</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">A synchronous type semiconductor storage device according to an embodiment, includes an array unit which includes a cell array and sense amplifiers, the cell array comprising a plurality of memory cells disposed in a lattice shape, and the sense amplifiers connected to the memory cells through bit lines. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device includes a read/write pulse generator which generates a read pulse signal and a write pulse signal according to a clock signal, the clock signal defining one cycle time of a read operation and a write operation with respect to the array unit as one cycle. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device includes a secondary amplifier which is connected to the sense amplifiers through a read/write line and which is activated according to the read pulse signal to read out data stored in the sense amplifiers through the read/write line. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device includes a write driver which is connected to the sense amplifiers through the read/write line and which is activated according to the write pulse signal to write data in the sense amplifiers through the read/write line.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The read/write pulse generator includes a &#xbd; frequency divider which is input with the clock signal and outputs a first frequency-divided signal formed by &#xbd;-dividing a frequency of the clock signal. The read/write pulse generator includes a first inverter which is input with the first frequency-divided signal and outputs a second frequency-divided signal formed by inverting the first frequency-divided signal. The read/write pulse generator includes a first pulse generation circuit which is input with the first frequency-divided signal, and which generates and outputs a first pulse signal based on the first frequency-divided signal. The read/write pulse generator includes a second pulse generation circuit which has the same configuration as that of the first pulse generation circuit, which is input with the second frequency-divided signal, and which generates and outputs a second pulse signal based on the second frequency-divided signal. The read/write pulse generator includes a first OR circuit which is input with the first pulse signal and the second pulse signal, and which outputs the read pulse signal and the write pulse signal.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Hereinafter, although the case where a synchronous type semiconductor storage device is a DRAM is described in the following embodiments, the same description applies in the case of other types of the synchronous type semiconductor storage devices such as SDRAMs. Hereinafter, the embodiments will be described with reference to the drawings.</p>
<p id="h-0005" num="0000">(First Embodiment)</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram showing an example of a configuration of a synchronous type semiconductor storage device <b>1000</b> according to an embodiment of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a diagram schematically showing an example of a configuration including an array unit <b>101</b>, a row decoder RD, a column decoder CD, a secondary amplifier 2ndAmp, and a write driver Wdrv of the synchronous type semiconductor storage device <b>1000</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, and <b>2</b>, the synchronous type semiconductor storage device <b>1000</b> includes a read/write pulse generator <b>100</b>, the array unit <b>101</b>, an input/output circuit <b>102</b>, a command receiver CMDR, an address receiver AR, a clock receiver CLKR, a row controller RC, a command controller CC, an address controller AC, the row decoder RD, the column decoder CD, the secondary amplifier 2ndAmp, and the write driver Wdrv.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The command receiver CMDR is configured to receive external input commands VCS, VRAS, VCAS, and VWE for controlling operations of the DRAM and to transmit the information (various commands) to the command controller CC.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The command controller CC is configured to decode the external input commands VCS, VRAS, VCAS, and VWE. In addition, the command controller CC is configured to output control signals (various commands) based on the decoded information and to control the address controller AC, the row controller RC, the input/output circuit <b>102</b>, and the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The clock receiver CLKR is configured to receive an external input clock signal VCLK and to output a clock signal CLKIN according to the external clock signal VCLK to the row controller RC, the command controller CC, the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b>, the address controller AC, and the input/output circuit <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The address receiver AR is configured to receive an external input address VADD and to transfer the address information to the address controller AC.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The address controller AC is configured to control the address information received from the address receiver AR and to transmit the address information Add to the row decoder RD and the column decoder CD.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The row controller RC is configured to activate or inactivate a word line WL corresponding to the input address information Add through the row decoder RD in the case where the control signal (command) output by the command controller CC indicates the activation operation for the word line WL and the precharge operation for the word line WL.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The read/write pulse generator <b>100</b> is configured to generate a read/write pulse signal R/WPulse (hereinafter, for convenience, this signal may be individually denoted by a read pulse signal RPulse and a write pulse signal WPulse) according to the clock signal CLKIN defining one cycle time of the read operation and the write operation for the array unit <b>101</b> as one cycle.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In other words, the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b> generates the read/write pulse signal R/WPulse defining a read operation time or a write operation time of the internal portion of the array unit <b>101</b> based on the clock signal CLKIN in the case where the control signal (command) output by the command controller CC indicates the read operation or the write operation. An activation time of the column decoder CD, the secondary amplifier 2ndAmp, and the write driver Wdrv is controlled based on the read/write pulse signal R/WPulse.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The input/output circuit <b>102</b> is configured to transfer written data input from an external input/output terminal VDQ to the input line DW and to output the read data transferred through an output line QR to the external input/output terminal VDQ according to the clock signal CLKIN and the control signal of the command controller CC.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The array unit <b>101</b> is configured to include a cell array where a plurality of memory cells MC are disposed in a lattice shape and a sense amplifier block SABlock which includes a plurality of sense amplifiers SA connected to the memory cells MC through the bit lines BL (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). Each of the memory cells MC is connected to the word line WL and the bit line BL. Each word line WL is connected to the row decoder RD, and each bit line BL is connected to the sense amplifier SA.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In addition, in the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, for simplifying the description, it is exemplified that the number of the sense amplifiers SA selected by one column selection line CSL is one, and the number of the sense amplifiers SA connected to one set of complementary read/write lines DQt and DQc is four. In general, the combination varies depending on the capacity of the memory, the bit width, and the band width.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The column decoder CD is configured to select the sense amplifier SA by the column selection line CSL activated according to the address information Add among the sense amplifier block SABlock corresponding to the word line WL selected by the row decoder RD.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The secondary amplifier 2ndAmp is connected to the sense amplifier SA through the complementary read/write lines DQt and DQc. The secondary amplifier 2ndAmp is configured to be activated according to the read pulse signal Rpulse and to read out the data stored in the sense amplifier SA through the complementary read/write lines DQt and DQc.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">For example, the data of the memory cell MC connected to the word line WL selected by the row decoder RD are read out by bit lines BLt and BLc, amplified by the sense amplifier SA, written back to the memory cell MC, and at the same time, stored in the sense amplifier SA.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In addition, at the time of the read operation, the column decoder CD activates the column selection line CSL selected according to the address information Add. The data are read out from the sense amplifier SA connected to a switch T, which is turned on through the activation of the column selection line CSL, to the complementary read/write lines DQt and DQc.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Then, at the time of the read operation, the secondary amplifier 2ndAmp reads out data from the sense amplifier SA selected by the column selection line CSL activated by the column decoder CD in the group of the sense amplifiers corresponding to the word line WL selected by the row decoder RD. Subsequently, the secondary amplifier 2ndAmp amplifies the data. The amplified data are transferred through the output line QR to the input/output circuit <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In addition, the write driver Wdrv is connected to the sense amplifier SA through the complementary read/write lines DQt and DQc to be activated according to the write pulse signal WPulse and to write data in the sense amplifier SA through the complementary read/write lines DQt and DQc.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In other words, at the time of the write operation, the write driver Wdrv is configured to latch written data input from the input line DW and to transfer the data to the selected sense amplifier SA through the complementary read/write lines DQt and DQc according to the write control signal WCTL.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In other words, at the time of the write operation, the write driver Wdrv transfers the written data input through the input line DW to the complementary read/write lines DQt and DQc by activating the complementary read/write lines DQt and DQc according to the write control signal WCTL. Next, the data on the complementary read/write lines DQt and DQc are temporarily written in the sense amplifier SA. In addition, the data are written in the memory cell MC through the bit lines BLt and BLc by the sense amplifier SA, so that the data are retained in the memory cell MC after the word line WL selected by the row decoder RD is inactivated.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Next, an example of the operations of the synchronous type semiconductor storage device <b>1000</b> comprising the aforementioned configuration will be described.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram showing an example of waveforms of signals at the time of the read operation and at the time of the write operation of the synchronous type semiconductor storage device <b>1000</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b> activates the write driver Wdrv by setting the write control signal WCTL to the &#x201c;High&#x201d; level (activation) according to the control signal (write command) from the command controller CC.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Next, since the input line DW is driven as level 1 (&#x201c;High&#x201d; level), the write driver Wdrv changes one of the complementary read/write lines DQt and DQc during the time period when the read/write pulse R/WPulse is activated (&#x201c;High&#x201d; level).</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In addition, according to the activation (&#x201c;High&#x201d; level) of the read/write pulse R/WPulse, the column selection line CSL corresponding to the address information Add is activated (&#x201c;High&#x201d; level) by the column decoder CD, and the switch T corresponding to the activated column selection line CSL is turned on.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Accordingly, the sense amplifier SA changes the potentials of the bit lines BLt and BLc according to the potentials of the complementary read/write lines DQt and DQc.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">If the read/write pulse R/WPulse is inactivated (&#x201c;Low&#x201d; level), the column selection line CSL selected by the column decoder C/D is inactivated, and the complementary read/write lines DQt and DQc are equalized to have the same potential by the write driver Wdrv.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">On the other hand, the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b> activates the secondary amplifier 2ndAmp by setting the read control signal RCTL to the &#x201c;High&#x201d; level (activation) according to the control signal (read command) from the command controller CC.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Then, according to the activation (&#x201c;High&#x201d; level) of the read/write pulse R/WPulse, the column selection line CSL corresponding to the address information Add is activated (&#x201c;High&#x201d; level) by the column decoder CD, and the switch T corresponding to the activated column selection line CSL is turned on.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In general, in this case, at the same time, the equalization of the complementary read/write lines DQt and DQc to the same potential is released by the write driver Wdrv. Therefore, the sense amplifier SA changes the potentials of the complementary read/write lines DQt and DQc according to the potentials stored in the bit lines BLt and BLc.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In addition, the secondary amplifier 2ndAmp changes the potential of the output line QR according to the potentials of the complementary read/write lines DQt and DQc during the time period when the read/write pulse R/WPulse is activated (&#x201c;High&#x201d; level).</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">If the read/write pulse R/WPulse is inactivated (&#x201c;Low&#x201d; level), the column selection line CSL selected by the column decoder C/D is inactivated, and the complementary read/write lines DQt and DQc are equalized to have the same potential by the write driver Wdrv.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In this manner, the time of reading out the data from the sense amplifier SA is directly defined by the time of activating the column selection line CSL, that is, the activation time of the read/write pulse signal R/WPulse.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In addition, the time of sensing the data read out to the complementary read/write lines DQt and DQc is controlled by the sensing time of the secondary amplifier 2ndAmp, that is, the read/write pulse signal R/WPulse.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">In this manner, in the first embodiment, the time of reading the data from the sense amplifier SA and the time of sensing the data read out to the complementary read/write lines DQt and DQc are controlled by the read/write pulse signal R/WPulse.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The activation operation method for the secondary amplifier 2ndAmp or the write driver Wdrv by the read/write pulse signal R/WPulse is controlled by the read control signal RCTL and the write control signal WCTL.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagram showing an example of a configuration of the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b> of the synchronous type semiconductor storage device <b>1000</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b> includes a &#xbd; frequency divider <b>100</b><i>a</i>, a first inverter IN<b>1</b>, an edge trigger type first pulse generation circuit <b>100</b><i>b</i>, an edge trigger type second pulse generation circuit <b>100</b><i>c</i>, and a first OR circuit OR<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The &#xbd; frequency divider <b>100</b><i>a </i>is configured to be input with the clock signal CLKIN and to output a first frequency-divided signal CPe formed by &#xbd;-dividing the frequency of the clock signal CLKIN.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The &#xbd; frequency divider <b>100</b><i>a </i>includes a flip-flop <b>100</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> and a frequency dividing inverter <b>100</b><i>a</i><b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The flip-flop <b>100</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> is configured so that the clock terminal thereof is input with the clock signal CLKIN and the first frequency-divided signal CPe is output from the output terminal thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The frequency dividing inverter <b>100</b><i>a</i><b>2</b> is configured so that the input thereof is connected to the output terminal of the flip-flop <b>100</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> and the output thereof is connected to the data terminal of the flip-flop <b>100</b><i>a</i><b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In addition, the first inverter IN<b>1</b> is configured to be input with the first frequency-divided signal CPe and to output a second frequency-divided signal CPo formed by inverting the first frequency-divided signal CPe.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The first pulse generation circuit <b>100</b><i>b </i>is configured to be input with the first frequency-divided signal CPe through an input portion x thereof and to generate a first pulse signal CPDe based on the first frequency-divided signal CPe and output the first pulse signal CPDe through an output portion y thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The second pulse generation circuit <b>100</b><i>c </i>is configured to be input with the second frequency-divided signal CPo through the input portion x thereof and to generate a second pulse signal CPDo based on the second frequency-divided signal CPo and output the second pulse signal CPDo through the output portion y thereof. The second pulse generation circuit <b>100</b><i>c </i>has the same configuration as that of the first pulse generation circuit <b>100</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">The first OR circuit OR<b>1</b> is configured to be input with the first pulse signal CPDe and the second pulse signal CPDo and to perform the OR operation on the input signals and output a signal obtained through the OR operation, that is, the read/write pulse signal R/WPulse.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">Herein, an example of a circuit configuration of the first and second pulse generation circuits <b>100</b><i>b </i>and <b>100</b><i>c </i>of the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b> comprising the aforementioned configuration will be described.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a diagram showing an example of the circuit configuration of the first and second pulse generation circuits <b>100</b><i>b </i>and <b>100</b><i>c </i>illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. In addition, as described above, the first and second pulse generation circuits <b>100</b><i>b </i>and <b>100</b><i>c </i>have different input and output signals but have the same configuration. Therefore, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the first and second pulse generation circuits <b>100</b><i>b </i>and <b>100</b><i>c </i>are illustrated such that input and output signals CPe/CPo and CPDe/CPDo are divided.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the first pulse generation circuit or the second pulse generation circuit <b>100</b><i>b</i>/<b>100</b><i>c </i>includes a second inverter IN<b>2</b>, a third inverter IN<b>3</b>, a fourth inverter IN<b>4</b>, a fifth inverter IN<b>5</b>, a sixth inverter IN<b>6</b>, a seventh inverter IN<b>7</b>, an eighth inverter IN<b>8</b>, a first NAND circuit N<b>1</b>, a second NAND circuit N<b>2</b>, a third NAND circuit N<b>3</b>, a fourth NAND circuit N<b>4</b>, a pMOS transistor M<b>1</b>, an nMOS transistor M<b>2</b>, a resistor element R<b>1</b>, and a capacitor C<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The second inverter IN<b>2</b> is input with the first frequency-divided signal CPe (in the case of the first pulse generation circuit <b>100</b><i>b</i>) or the second frequency-divided signal CPo (in the case of the second pulse generation circuit <b>100</b><i>c</i>) through the input portion x thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The input of the first NAND circuit N<b>1</b> is connected to the output of the second inverter IN<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">The input of the second NAND circuit N<b>2</b> is connected to the output of the second inverter IN<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The input of the third NAND circuit N<b>3</b> is connected to the output of the first NAND circuit N<b>1</b> and the output of the second NAND circuit N<b>2</b>, and the output of the third NAND circuit N<b>3</b> is connected to the input of the second NAND circuit N<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">The input of the third inverter IN<b>3</b> is connected to the output of the second NAND circuit N<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">The input of the fourth inverter IN<b>4</b> is connected to the output of the third inverter IN<b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">The source of the pMOS transistor M<b>1</b> is connected to a power supply, and the gate of the pMOS transistor M<b>1</b> is connected to the output of the fourth inverter IN<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">The one end of the resistor element R<b>1</b> is connected to a drain of the pMOS transistor M<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">The nMOS transistor M<b>2</b> is connected between the other end of the resistor element R<b>1</b> and a ground, and the gate of the nMOS transistor M<b>2</b> is connected to the output of the fourth inverter IN<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">The capacitor C<b>1</b> is connected between the drain of the pMOS transistor M<b>1</b> and the ground.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">The input of the fifth inverter IN<b>5</b> is connected to the drain of the pMOS transistor M<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">The input of the sixth inverter IN<b>6</b> is connected to the output of the fifth inverter IN<b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">The input of the seventh inverter IN<b>7</b> is connected to the output of the sixth inverter IN<b>6</b>, and the output of the seventh inverter IN<b>7</b> is connected to the input of the first NAND circuit N<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">The input of the fourth NAND circuit N<b>4</b> is connected to the output of the second NAND circuit N<b>2</b> and the output of the sixth inverter IN<b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">The input of the eighth inverter IN<b>8</b> is connected to the output of the fourth NAND circuit N<b>4</b> so as to output the first pulse signal CPDe or the second pulse signal CPDo through the output portion y thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">Herein, an example of the operations of the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b> comprising the aforementioned configuration will be described.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6A and 6B</figref> are diagrams showing an example of waveforms of the operations of the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, and an example of waveforms of the operations of an edge trigger type read/write pulse generator as a comparative example.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">In addition, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6A and 6B</figref>, with respect to the relationship among the cycle time, the read/write time, and the reset time of the read/write pulse generator defined by using one cycle of the clock signal CLKIN, the comparative example and the first embodiment are separately illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6A and 6B</figref>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref>, in the comparative example, since the read/write pulse generator is of the edge trigger type, the read/write pulse signal R/WPulse needs to be activated for every cycle.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">Therefore, the sum of the read/write time defined by the pulse width of the read/write pulse signal R/WPulse and the reset time needs to be equal to or smaller than the cycle time.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">In other words, the pulse width of the read/write pulse signal R/WPulse is limited by the reset time of the edge trigger type read/write pulse generator.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">On the other hand, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref>, in the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b> in the first embodiment, the read/write pulse signal R/WPulse is generated from the first and second frequency-divided signals CPe and CPo comprising opposite phases that are twice the frequency of the clock signal CLKIN.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">Therefore, the sum of the read/write time and the reset time is equal to or smaller than twice the cycle time.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">In other words, the read/write time can be determined without limitation by the reset time of the first and second pulse generation circuits <b>100</b><i>b </i>and <b>100</b><i>c </i>of the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">Therefore, it is possible to increase the read/write time with respect to the array unit within the cycle time defined by the clock signal.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">The case of using the synchronous type semiconductor storage device <b>1000</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> where the column selection control pulse signal CSLPulse, the read pulse signal RPulse, and the write pulse signal WPulse are commonly used has been described above.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a diagram showing another example of a configuration the synchronous type semiconductor storage device <b>1000</b> according to the embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b> separately generates and supplies the column selection line (CSL) control pulse CSLPulse, the read pulse RPulse, and the write pulse WPulse.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">Except for the signals output from the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b>, the synchronous type semiconductor storage device <b>1000</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> has the same configuration as that of the synchronous type semiconductor storage device <b>1000</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the column selection line control signal CSLPulse and the read pulse signal RPulse controlling the secondary amplifier 2ndAmp may be supplied through separate wirings.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">In addition, at the time of the write operation, the time of writing the data in the sense amplifier SA is defined by the activation time of the column selection line CSL (that is, the activation time of the read/write pulse signal R/WPulse) and the driving time of the complementary read/write lines DQt and DQc driven by the write driver Wdrv.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">The driving time of the complementary read/write lines DQt and DQc driven by the write driver Wdrv is also defined by the read/write pulse signal R/WPulse.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">At the time of the write operation, the column selection line control signal CSLPulse and the write control signal WPulse may be supplied through separate wirings. Therefore, the control methods thereof may be considered to be basically the same.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">In other words, the control methods in the synchronous type semiconductor storage devices <b>1000</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 7</figref> may be considered to be basically the same. Therefore, the case of the synchronous type semiconductor storage device <b>1000</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is described to be the same as the case illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">As described above, according to the synchronous type semiconductor storage device according to the first embodiment, it is possible to increase the read/write time within one cycle of the clock signal defining the read/write cycle time with respect to the array unit.</p>
<p id="h-0006" num="0000">(Second Embodiment)</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">In a second embodiment, a configuration where an edge trigger type pulse generation circuit (for example, refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) is not used in the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b> will be described. In addition, except for the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b>, other configurations are the same as those of the synchronous type semiconductor storage device <b>1000</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a diagram showing another example of a configuration of the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b> of the synchronous type semiconductor storage device <b>1000</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b> includes a &#xbd; frequency divider <b>100</b><i>a</i>, a first inverter IN<b>1</b>, a first pulse generation circuit <b>100</b><i>b</i>, a second pulse generation circuit <b>100</b><i>c</i>, and a first OR circuit OR<b>1</b>. In addition, as described above, the first pulse generation circuit <b>100</b><i>b </i>and the second pulse generation circuit <b>100</b><i>c </i>are not an edge trigger type. Other configurations of the first pulse generation circuit <b>100</b><i>b </i>and the second pulse generation circuit <b>100</b><i>c </i>in the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b> are the same as those of the first embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111">Herein, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the first pulse generation circuit <b>100</b><i>b </i>includes a first delay circuit <b>100</b><i>b</i><b>1</b>, a first pulse generating inverter <b>100</b><i>b</i><b>2</b>, and a first pulse generating NAND circuit <b>100</b><i>b</i><b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">The first delay circuit <b>100</b><i>b</i><b>1</b> is configured to be input with the first frequency-divided signal CPe through the input portion x thereof and to output a first delay signal formed by delaying the first frequency-divided signal CPe.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">The first pulse generating inverter <b>100</b><i>b</i><b>2</b> is configured to be input with the first delay signal and to output a signal formed by inverting the first delay signal.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">The first pulse generating NAND circuit <b>100</b><i>b</i><b>3</b> is configured to be input with the first frequency-divided signal and the output signal of the first pulse generating inverter <b>100</b><i>b</i><b>2</b> and to output the first pulse signal CPDe through the output portion y thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">In addition, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the second pulse generation circuit <b>100</b><i>c </i>includes a second delay circuit <b>100</b><i>c</i><b>1</b>, a second pulse generating inverter <b>100</b><i>c</i><b>2</b>, and a second pulse generating NAND circuit <b>100</b><i>c</i><b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116">The second delay circuit <b>100</b><i>c</i><b>1</b> is configured to be input with the second frequency-divided signal CPo through the input portion x thereof and to output a second delay signal formed by delaying the second frequency-divided signal CPo.</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0117">In addition, the delay time of the first delay circuit <b>100</b><i>b</i><b>1</b> is set so as to be the same as the delay time of the second delay circuit <b>100</b><i>c</i><b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0118">The second pulse generating inverter <b>100</b><i>c</i><b>2</b> is configured to be input with the second delay signal and to output a signal formed by inverting the second delay signal.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0119">The second pulse generating NAND circuit <b>100</b><i>c</i><b>3</b> is configured to be input with the second frequency-divided signal CPo and the output signal of the second pulse generating inverter <b>100</b><i>c</i><b>2</b> and to output the second pulse signal CPDo through the output portion y thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0120">According to this configuration, it is possible to reduce the number of logic stages included in the delay circuit which determines the pulse width, making it possible to easily suppress PVT dependency of the pulse width.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0121">In addition, the operations of the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b> comprising the aforementioned configuration are the same as, for instance, those in the example of the waveforms of the operations of the read/write pulse generator <b>100</b> according to the first embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0122">In other words, although the trigger type pulse generation circuit is not used, the activation time of the first and second frequency-divided signals CPe and CPo becomes one cycle time, and the pulse width of the read/write pulse signal R/WPulse generated in each cycle time can be necessarily increased.</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0123">Therefore, it is possible to increase the read/write time within one cycle of the clock signal defining the read/write cycle time with respect to the array unit.</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0124">As described above, according to the synchronous type semiconductor storage device according to the second embodiment of the present invention, as described in the first embodiment, it is possible to increase the read/write time within one cycle of the clock signal defining the read/write cycle time with respect to the array unit.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0125">While certain embodiments have been described, these embodiments have been presented by way of example only, and are not intended to limit the scope of the inventions. Indeed, the novel methods and systems described herein may be embodied in a variety of other forms; furthermore, various omissions, substitutions and changes in the form of the methods and systems described herein may be made without departing from the spirit of the inventions. The accompanying claims and their equivalents are intended to cover such forms or modifications as would fall within the scope and spirit of the inventions.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A synchronous type semiconductor storage device comprising:
<claim-text>an array unit which includes a cell array and sense amplifiers, the cell array comprising a plurality of memory cells disposed in a lattice shape, and the sense amplifiers connected to the memory cells through bit lines;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a read/write pulse generator which generates a read pulse signal and a write pulse signal according to a clock signal, the clock signal defining one cycle time of a read operation and a write operation with respect to the array unit as one cycle;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a secondary amplifier which is connected to the sense amplifiers through a read/write line and which is activated according to the read pulse signal to read out data stored in the sense amplifiers through the read/write line; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a write driver which is connected to the sense amplifiers through the read/write line and which is activated according to the write pulse signal to write data in the sense amplifiers through the read/write line,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the read/write pulse generator includes:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a &#xbd; frequency divider which is input with the clock signal and outputs a first frequency-divided signal formed by &#xbd;-dividing a frequency of the clock signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first inverter which is input with the first frequency-divided signal and outputs a second frequency-divided signal formed by inverting the first frequency-divided signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first pulse generation circuit which is input with the first frequency-divided signal, and which generates and outputs a first pulse signal based on the first frequency-divided signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pulse generation circuit which has the same configuration as that of the first pulse generation circuit, which is input with the second frequency-divided signal, and which generates and outputs a second pulse signal based on the second frequency-divided signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first OR circuit which is input with the first pulse signal and the second pulse signal, and which outputs the read pulse signal and the write pulse signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first pulse generation circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a second inverter which is input with the first frequency-divided signal or the second frequency-divided signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first NAND circuit comprising an input connected to the output of the second inverter;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second NAND circuit comprising an input connected to the output of the second inverter;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third NAND circuit comprising an input connected to the output of the first NAND circuit and the output of the second NAND circuit, and comprising an output connected to the input of the second NAND circuit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third inverter comprising an input connected to the output of the second NAND circuit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth inverter comprising an input connected to the output of the third inverter;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pMOS transistor comprising a source connected to a power supply, and comprising a gate connected to the output of the fourth inverter;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a resistor element comprising a first end connected to a drain of the pMOS transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an nMOS transistor connected between a second end of the resistor element and a ground, and comprising a gate connected to the output of the fourth inverter;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a capacitor connected between a drain of the pMOS transistor and the ground;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fifth inverter comprising an input connected to the drain of the pMOS transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sixth inverter comprising an input connected to an output of the fifth inverter;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a seventh inverter comprising an input connected to an output of the sixth inverter, and comprising an output connected to the input of the first NAND circuit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth NAND circuit comprising an input connected to the output of the second NAND circuit and the output of the sixth inverter; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an eighth inverter comprising an input connected to an output of the fourth NAND circuit, and outputting the first pulse signal or the second pulse signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second pulse generation circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a second inverter which is input with the first frequency-divided signal or the second frequency-divided signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first NAND circuit comprising an input connected to the output of the second inverter;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second NAND circuit comprising an input connected to the output of the second inverter;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third NAND circuit comprising an input connected to the output of the first NAND circuit and the output of the second NAND circuit, and comprising an output connected to the input of the second NAND circuit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third inverter comprising an input connected to the output of the second NAND circuit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth inverter comprising an input connected to the output of the third inverter;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pMOS transistor comprising a source connected to a power supply, and comprising a gate connected to the output of the fourth inverter;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a resistor element comprising a first end connected to a drain of the pMOS transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an nMOS transistor connected between a second end of the resistor element and a ground, and comprising a gate connected to the output of the fourth inverter;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a capacitor connected between a drain of the pMOS transistor and the ground;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fifth inverter comprising an input connected to the drain of the pMOS transistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sixth inverter comprising an input connected to an output of the fifth inverter;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a seventh inverter comprising an input connected to an output of the sixth inverter, and comprising an output connected to the input of the first NAND circuit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth NAND circuit comprising an input connected to the output of the second NAND circuit and the output of the sixth inverter; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an eighth inverter comprising an input connected to an output of the fourth NAND circuit, and outputting the first pulse signal or the second pulse signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first pulse generation circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a first delay circuit which is configured to be input with the first frequency-divided signal and to output a first delay signal formed by delaying the first frequency-divided signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first pulse generating inverter which is configured to be input with the first delay signal and to output a signal formed by inverting the first delay signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first pulse generating NAND circuit which is configured to be input with the first frequency-divided signal and an output signal of the first pulse generating inverter, and which is configured to output the first pulse signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second pulse generation circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a second delay circuit which is configured to be input with the second frequency-divided signal and to output a second delay signal formed by delaying the second frequency-divided signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pulse generating inverter which is configured to be input with the second delay signal and to output a signal formed by inverting the second delay signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pulse generating NAND circuit which is configured to be input with the second frequency-divided signal and an output signal of the second pulse generating inverter, and which is configured to output the second pulse signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the first pulse generation circuit comprising:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first delay circuit which is configured to be input with the first frequency-divided signal and to output a first delay signal formed by delaying the first frequency-divided signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first pulse generating inverter which is configured to be input with the first delay signal and to output a signal formed by inverting the first delay signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first pulse generating NAND circuit which is configured to be input with the first frequency-divided signal and an output signal of the first pulse generating inverter, and which is configured to output the first pulse signal, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second pulse generation circuit comprising:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second delay circuit which is configured to be input with the second frequency-divided signal and to output a second delay signal formed by delaying the second frequency-divided signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pulse generating inverter which is configured to be input with the second delay signal and to output a signal formed by inverting the second delay signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pulse generating NAND circuit which is configured to be input with the second frequency-divided signal and an output signal of the second pulse generating inverter, and which is configured to output the second pulse signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein a delay time of the first delay circuit is equal to a delay time of the second delay circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the &#xbd; frequency divider comprising:
<claim-text>a flip-flop comprising a clock terminal input with the clock signal, and outputting the first frequency-divided signal from an output terminal thereof; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a frequency dividing inverter comprising an input connected to the output terminal of the flip-flop, and comprising an output connected to an data terminal of the flip-flop.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the &#xbd; frequency divider comprising:
<claim-text>a flip-flop comprising a clock terminal input with the clock signal, and outputting the first frequency-divided signal from an output terminal thereof; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a frequency dividing inverter comprising an input connected to the output terminal of the flip-flop, and comprising an output connected to an data terminal of the flip-flop.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the &#xbd; frequency divider comprising:
<claim-text>a flip-flop comprising a clock terminal input with the clock signal, and outputting the first frequency-divided signal from an output terminal thereof; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a frequency dividing inverter comprising an input connected to the output terminal of the flip-flop, and comprising an output connected to an data terminal of the flip-flop.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the &#xbd; frequency divider comprising:
<claim-text>a flip-flop comprising a clock terminal input with the clock signal, and outputting the first frequency-divided signal from an output terminal thereof; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a frequency dividing inverter comprising an input connected to the output terminal of the flip-flop, and comprising an output connected to an data terminal of the flip-flop.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the &#xbd; frequency divider comprising:
<claim-text>a flip-flop comprising a clock terminal input with the clock signal, and outputting the first frequency-divided signal from an output terminal thereof; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a frequency dividing inverter comprising an input connected to the output terminal of the flip-flop, and comprising an output connected to an data terminal of the flip-flop.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the &#xbd; frequency divider comprising:
<claim-text>a flip-flop comprising a clock terminal input with the clock signal, and outputting the first frequency-divided signal from an output terminal thereof; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a frequency dividing inverter comprising an input connected to the output terminal of the flip-flop, and comprising an output connected to an data terminal of the flip-flop.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the &#xbd; frequency divider comprising:
<claim-text>a flip-flop comprising a clock terminal input with the clock signal, and outputting the first frequency-divided signal from an output terminal thereof; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a frequency dividing inverter comprising an input connected to the output terminal of the flip-flop, and comprising an output connected to an data terminal of the flip-flop.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the synchronous type semiconductor storage device is a DRAM.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the synchronous type semiconductor storage device is a DRAM.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the synchronous type semiconductor storage device is a SDRAM.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The synchronous type semiconductor storage device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the synchronous type semiconductor storage device is a SDRAM.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A synchronous type semiconductor storage device comprising:
<claim-text>an array unit which includes a cell array and sense amplifiers, the cell array comprising a plurality of memory cells disposed in a lattice shape, and the sense amplifiers connected to the memory cells through bit lines;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a read/write pulse generator which generates a read pulse signal and a write pulse signal according to a clock signal, the clock signal defining one cycle time of a read operation and a write operation with respect to the array unit as one cycle;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a secondary amplifier which is connected to the sense amplifiers through a read/write line and which is activated according to the read pulse signal to read out data stored in the sense amplifiers through the read/write line; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a write driver which is connected to the sense amplifiers through the read/write line and which is activated according to the write pulse signal to write data in the sense amplifiers through the read/write line.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. A DRAM comprising:
<claim-text>an array unit which includes a cell array and sense amplifiers, the cell array comprising a plurality of memory cells disposed in a lattice shape, and the sense amplifiers connected to the memory cells through bit lines;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a read/write pulse generator which generates a read pulse signal and a write pulse signal according to a clock signal, the clock signal defining one cycle time of a read operation and a write operation with respect to the array unit as one cycle;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a secondary amplifier which is connected to the sense amplifiers through a read/write line and which is activated according to the read pulse signal to read out data stored in the sense amplifiers through the read/write line; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a write driver which is connected to the sense amplifiers through the read/write line and which is activated according to the write pulse signal to write data in the sense amplifiers through the read/write line.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
