<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626424-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626424</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12536010</doc-number>
<date>20090805</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>917</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20110101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>19</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>60</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>701110</main-classification>
<further-classification>701 94</further-classification>
<further-classification>180170</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Active coast and cruise control system and methods</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4825368</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Itoh et al.</name>
<date>19890400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>701 69</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4961475</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kurihara et al.</name>
<date>19901000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>180179</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6078860</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kerns</name>
<date>20000600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>701 93</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7223204</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Steen et al.</name>
<date>20070500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>477 97</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8187149</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Koenig</name>
<date>20120500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>477 98</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0152990</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Bjernetun et al.</name>
<date>20100600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>701 93</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>1930412</doc-number>
<date>20070300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2008/130288</doc-number>
<date>20081000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>701110</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>701 93</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>701 94</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>180170</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>180179</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110035135</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110210</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Schwalm</last-name>
<first-name>Jayson S.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Farmington Hills</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ford</last-name>
<first-name>Steven Thomas</first-name>
<address>
<city>Brighton</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Koenig</last-name>
<first-name>John J.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Howell</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Schwalm</last-name>
<first-name>Jayson S.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Farmington Hills</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ford</last-name>
<first-name>Steven Thomas</first-name>
<address>
<city>Brighton</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Koenig</last-name>
<first-name>John J.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Howell</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<orgname>GM Global Technology Operations LLC</orgname>
<role>02</role>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Gimie</last-name>
<first-name>Mahmoud</first-name>
<department>3747</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Hamaoui</last-name>
<first-name>David</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An engine control system of the present disclosure comprises a target speed module and a coupling module. The target speed module determines a target speed of a vehicle based on a speed of the vehicle and at least one of an accelerator input and a speed control input. The coupling module controls coupling of an engine system and a drive system of the vehicle based on the speed and the target speed. The engine system transfers torque to the drive system when coupled and does not transfer torque to the drive system when decoupled. In other features, the engine control system further comprises a torque control module that controls torque output by the engine system based on the coupling of the engine system and the drive system, the speed, and the target speed.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="229.11mm" wi="177.55mm" file="US08626424-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="235.37mm" wi="170.69mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626424-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="194.31mm" wi="121.50mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626424-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="245.79mm" wi="177.21mm" file="US08626424-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present disclosure relates to engine control systems, and more particularly to an active coast and cruise control system and methods.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The background description provided herein is for the purpose of generally presenting the context of the disclosure. Work of the presently named inventors, to the extent it is described in this background section, as well as aspects of the description that may not otherwise qualify as prior art at the time of filing, are neither expressly nor impliedly admitted as prior art against the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Various engine systems may be used to accelerate a vehicle and maintain a vehicle speed. Each engine system may use energy to produce drive torque. Internal combustion engines may use chemical energy from fuels such as gasoline, diesel, or hydrogen. Electric motors may use electricity energy from a battery source or a power source that may include fuel cells. A hybrid system may use a combination of an internal combustion engine and an electric motor.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The engine system may transfer the drive torque to a drive system when the engine system couples with the drive system. The drive system may include a transmission and/or a drive wheel. With each engine system and drive system, vehicle energy may be lost through friction losses, varying driving conditions such as elevation changes, and driving behavior.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">An engine control system of the present disclosure comprises a target speed module and a coupling module. The target speed module determines a target speed of a vehicle based on a speed of the vehicle and at least one of an accelerator input and a speed control input. The coupling module controls coupling of an engine system and a drive system of the vehicle based on the speed and the target speed. The engine system transfers torque to the drive system when coupled and does not transfer torque to the drive system when decoupled. In other features, the engine control system further comprises a torque control module that controls torque output by the engine system based on the coupling of the engine system and the drive system, the speed, and the target speed.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In yet other features, the coupling module decouples the engine system from the drive system and the torque control module reduces the torque output by the engine system to a predetermined torque output when the speed differs by less than a predetermined speed from the target speed. In still other features, the coupling module couples the engine system with the drive system and the torque control module reduces the torque output by the engine system when the speed is greater than the target speed by a predetermined speed.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In yet other features, the coupling module couples the engine system with the drive system and the torque control module increases the torque output by the engine system when the speed is less than the target speed by a predetermined speed. In still other features, the coupling module decouples the engine system from the drive system and the torque control module reduces the torque output by the engine system to a predetermined torque output when the accelerator input is less than a predetermined threshold.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In yet other features, the torque control module controls the torque output of at least one of an internal combustion engine and an electric motor. In still other features, the coupling module controls coupling of the engine system and the drive system by controlling at least one of engagement of a clutch and selection of a neutral gear of an automatic transmission.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In yet other features, the target speed module determines the target speed when the accelerator input is greater than a predetermined threshold and varies by less than a predetermined amount during a predetermined period. In still other features, the target speed module determines the target speed when the speed control input is turned on.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">A method of the present disclosure comprises: determining a target speed of a vehicle based on a speed of the vehicle and at least one of an accelerator input and a speed control input; and controlling coupling of an engine system and a drive system of the vehicle based on the speed and the target speed, wherein the engine system transfers torque to the drive system when coupled and does not transfer torque to the drive system when decoupled. In other features, the method further comprises controlling torque output by the engine system based on the coupling of the engine system and the drive system, the speed, and the target speed.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In yet other features, the method further comprises: decoupling the engine system from the drive system when the speed differs by less than a predetermined speed from the target speed; and reducing the torque output by the engine system to a predetermined torque output. In still other features, the method further comprises: coupling the engine system with the drive system when the speed is greater than the target speed by a predetermined speed; and reducing the torque output by the engine system.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In yet other features, the method further comprises coupling the engine system with the drive system when the speed is less than the target speed by a predetermined speed; and increasing the torque output by the engine system. In still other features, the method further comprises decoupling the engine system from the drive system when the accelerator input is less than a predetermined threshold; and reducing the torque output by the engine system to a predetermined torque output.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In yet other features, the method further comprises controlling the torque output of at least one of an internal combustion engine and an electric motor. In still other features, the method further comprises controlling coupling of the engine system and the drive system by controlling at least one of engagement of a clutch and selection of a neutral gear of an automatic transmission.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In yet other features, the method further comprises determining the target speed when the accelerator input is greater than a predetermined threshold and varies by less than a predetermined amount during a predetermined period. In still other features, the method further comprises determining the target speed when the speed control input is turned on.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Further areas of applicability of the present disclosure will become apparent from the detailed description provided hereinafter. It should be understood that the detailed description and specific examples are intended for purposes of illustration only and are not intended to limit the scope of the disclosure.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The present disclosure will become more fully understood from the detailed description and the accompanying drawings, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a functional block diagram of an exemplary engine system and an exemplary drive system according to the principles of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a functional block diagram of an exemplary engine control module according to the principles of the present disclosure; and</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a flowchart depicting exemplary steps of a method performed by the engine control module according to the principles of the present disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The following description is merely exemplary in nature and is in no way intended to limit the disclosure, its application, or uses. For purposes of clarity, the same reference numbers will be used in the drawings to identify similar elements. As used herein, the phrase at least one of A, B, and C should be construed to mean a logical (A or B or C), using a non-exclusive logical or. It should be understood that steps within a method may be executed in different order without altering the principles of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">As used herein, the term module refers to an Application Specific Integrated Circuit (ASIC), an electronic circuit, a processor (shared, dedicated, or group) and memory that execute one or more software or firmware programs, a combinational logic circuit, and/or other suitable components that provide the described functionality.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Vehicle energy may be conserved by increasing the time spent at low engine speeds and low drive torque, increasing the time spent coasting at a vehicle speed, such as in a neutral gear or with a disengaged clutch, and/or maintaining vehicle speed within a vehicle speed range. Road conditions such as inclines and descents may assist in maintaining vehicle speed within the speed range.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">For example only, vehicle energy may be conserved by disengaging the drive system and allowing the vehicle to coast without drive torque from the engine system, reducing friction losses when the engine system is not producing drive torque, controlling vehicle speed to a target vehicle speed range and using road conditions to assist in maintaining the vehicle speed, and/or converting kinetic energy of the vehicle to electrical energy during vehicle braking.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The active coast and cruise control system and method of the present disclosure may selectively couple the engine system with the drive system of the vehicle and adjust drive torque of the engine system to conserve energy. The engine system may be selectively coupled with the drive system based on a driver input and a sensed vehicle speed. The driver input may include an accelerator input, a brake input, a gear selector input, and a cruise control input. Drive torque produced by the engine system may be adjusted based on the coupling of the engine system with the drive system and the vehicle speed.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, engine system <b>100</b> includes an engine <b>102</b> that combusts an air/fuel mixture to produce drive torque for a vehicle based on input from a driver input module <b>104</b>. A driver may position an accelerator input device <b>104</b>-<b>1</b> and/or a brake input device <b>104</b>-<b>2</b> to control vehicle speed. The driver may position a cruise control input device <b>104</b>-<b>3</b> to an on or off position to control vehicle speed. The driver may position a gear selector input device <b>104</b>-<b>4</b> to a gear position such as a drive gear. The driver may position a speed deviation input device <b>104</b>-<b>5</b> to a speed deviation level to control a vehicle speed range.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The driver input module <b>104</b> may generate a driver input signal based on signals from the input devices. For example only, an accelerator position signal may be based on the position of the accelerator input device <b>104</b>-<b>1</b>. A brake position signal may be based on the position of the brake input device <b>104</b>-<b>2</b>. A cruise control signal may be based on the position of the cruise control input device <b>104</b>-<b>3</b>. A gear signal may be based on the selected gear from the gear selector input device <b>104</b>-<b>4</b>. A speed deviation signal may be based on the speed deviation level from the speed deviation input device <b>104</b>-<b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Air is drawn into an intake manifold <b>110</b> through a throttle valve <b>112</b>. For example only, the throttle valve <b>112</b> may include a butterfly valve having a rotatable blade. An engine control module (ECM) <b>114</b> controls a throttle actuator module <b>116</b>, which regulates opening of the throttle valve <b>112</b> to control the amount of air drawn into the intake manifold <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Air from the intake manifold <b>110</b> is drawn into cylinders of the engine <b>102</b>. While the engine <b>102</b> may include multiple cylinders, for illustration purposes a single representative cylinder <b>118</b> is shown. For example only, the engine <b>102</b> may include 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 8, 10, and/or 12 cylinders.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Air from the intake manifold <b>110</b> is drawn into the cylinder <b>118</b> through an intake valve <b>122</b>. The ECM <b>114</b> controls a fuel actuator module <b>124</b>, which regulates fuel injection to achieve a desired air/fuel ratio. Fuel may be injected into the intake manifold <b>110</b> at a central location or at multiple locations, such as near the intake valve of each of the cylinders. In various implementations not depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, fuel may be injected directly into the cylinders or into mixing chambers associated with the cylinders.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The injected fuel mixes with air and creates an air/fuel mixture in the cylinder <b>118</b>. A piston (not shown) within the cylinder <b>118</b> compresses the air/fuel mixture. Based upon a signal from the ECM <b>114</b>, a spark actuator module <b>126</b> energizes a spark plug <b>128</b> in the cylinder <b>118</b>, which ignites the air/fuel mixture. The timing of the spark may be specified relative to the time when the piston is at its topmost position, referred to as top dead center (TDC).</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The combustion of the air/fuel mixture drives the piston down, thereby driving a rotating crankshaft (not shown). The piston then begins moving up again and expels the byproducts of combustion through an exhaust valve <b>130</b>. The byproducts of combustion are exhausted from the vehicle via an exhaust system <b>134</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The spark actuator module <b>126</b> may be controlled by a timing signal indicating how far before or after TDC the spark should be provided. Operation of the spark actuator module <b>126</b> may therefore be synchronized with crankshaft rotation.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The intake valve <b>122</b> may be controlled by an intake camshaft <b>140</b>, while the exhaust valve <b>130</b> may be controlled by an exhaust camshaft <b>142</b>. In various implementations, multiple intake camshafts may control multiple intake valves per cylinder and/or may control the intake valves of multiple banks of cylinders. Similarly, multiple exhaust camshafts may control multiple exhaust valves per cylinder and/or may control exhaust valves for multiple banks of cylinders.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The vehicle may further include a drive system <b>143</b>. The drive system <b>143</b> may include an automatic transmission <b>144</b>, a driveshaft <b>146</b>, a differential <b>148</b>, and/or a final drive <b>150</b>. When the drive system <b>143</b> is coupled with the engine system <b>100</b>, drive torque may be transferred to the final drive <b>150</b> to propel the vehicle. For example, the automatic transmission <b>144</b> may transfer drive torque from the engine system <b>100</b> to the final drive <b>150</b> through the driveshaft <b>146</b> and the differential <b>148</b>. The final drive <b>150</b> may include a drive wheel. The differential <b>148</b> may transfer the torque to multiple drive wheels through an axle <b>152</b>. A speed of the vehicle may be measured at the final drive <b>150</b> by a speed sensor <b>154</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The engine system <b>100</b> may measure the speed of the crankshaft in revolutions per minute (RPM) using an RPM sensor <b>180</b>. The temperature of the engine coolant may be measured using an engine coolant temperature (ECT) sensor <b>182</b>. The ECT sensor <b>182</b> may be located within the engine <b>102</b> or at other locations where the coolant is circulated, such as a radiator (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The pressure within the intake manifold <b>110</b> may be measured using a manifold absolute pressure (MAP) sensor <b>184</b>. In various implementations, engine vacuum, which is the difference between ambient air pressure and the pressure within the intake manifold <b>110</b>, may be measured. The mass flow rate of air flowing into the intake manifold <b>110</b> may be measured using a mass air flow (MAF) sensor <b>186</b>. In various implementations, the MAF sensor <b>186</b> may be located in a housing that also includes the throttle valve <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The throttle actuator module <b>116</b> may monitor the position of the throttle valve <b>112</b> using one or more throttle position sensors (TPS) <b>190</b>. The ambient temperature of air being drawn into the engine <b>102</b> may be measured using an intake air temperature (IAT) sensor <b>192</b>. The ECM <b>114</b> may use signals from the sensors to make control decisions for the engine system <b>100</b>. The ECM <b>114</b> may generate an engine load signal based on the MAF signal, the throttle position signal, the IAT signal, and/or the MAP signal.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The ECM <b>114</b> may communicate with a transmission control module <b>194</b> to coordinate shifting gears in the automatic transmission <b>144</b>. For example only, the ECM <b>114</b> may reduce engine torque during a gearshift. The ECM <b>114</b> may coordinate selection of gears in the automatic transmission <b>144</b> based on the gear selector input device <b>104</b>-<b>4</b>. The ECM <b>114</b> may coordinate coupling of the automatic transmission <b>144</b> with the engine <b>102</b> such as through a clutch (not shown). The ECM <b>114</b> may coordinate coupling of the automatic transmission <b>144</b> with the engine <b>102</b> such as through a torque converter (not shown). When the engine <b>102</b> couples with the automatic transmission <b>144</b>, drive torque may be transferred to the final drive <b>150</b>. The ECM <b>114</b> may communicate with a hybrid control module <b>196</b> to coordinate operation of the engine <b>102</b>, the drive system <b>143</b>, and an electric motor <b>198</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The electric motor <b>198</b> may also produce drive torque for the vehicle. The electric motor <b>198</b> may couple with the drive system <b>143</b> to transfer drive torque to the final drive <b>150</b>. For example only, the electric motor <b>198</b> may couple with the automatic transmission <b>144</b> to transfer drive torque to the final drive <b>150</b>. The electric motor <b>198</b> may couple directly with the final drive <b>150</b> to transfer drive torque to the final drive <b>150</b>. The electric motor <b>198</b> may couple with the engine <b>102</b> through a belt and pulley system (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The electric motor <b>198</b> may also function as a generator to produce electrical energy for use by vehicle electrical systems and/or for storage in an electrical storage device <b>200</b>, such as a battery. For example only, the electric motor <b>198</b> may generate electrical energy when coupled with the drive system <b>143</b>. As the vehicle moves, the drive system <b>143</b> may rotate the electric motor <b>198</b>. The electric motor <b>198</b> may provide braking forces to the drive system <b>143</b> while generating electrical energy. In various implementations, various functions of the ECM <b>114</b>, the transmission control module <b>194</b>, and the hybrid control module <b>196</b> may be integrated into one or more modules.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Each system that varies an engine parameter may be referred to as an actuator that receives an actuator value. For example only, the throttle actuator module <b>116</b> may be referred to as an actuator and the throttle opening area may be referred to as the actuator value. In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the throttle actuator module <b>116</b> achieves the throttle opening area by adjusting the angle of the blade of the throttle valve <b>112</b>. Similarly, the spark actuator module <b>126</b> may be referred to as an actuator, while the corresponding actuator value may be the amount of spark advance relative to cylinder TDC. The ECM <b>114</b> may control actuator values in order to generate a desired torque from the engine <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The ECM <b>114</b> may selectively couple and decouple the engine system <b>100</b> with the drive system <b>143</b> when the gear selector input device <b>104</b>-<b>4</b> is in a drive gear of the drive system <b>143</b>. The ECM <b>114</b> may selectively couple and decouple the engine system <b>100</b> from the drive system <b>143</b> based on input from the accelerator input <b>104</b>-<b>1</b> and the vehicle speed. For example only, when a driver releases the accelerator input <b>104</b>-<b>1</b> and the vehicle speed is greater than a speed threshold, the ECM <b>114</b> may decouple the engine system <b>100</b> from the drive system <b>143</b>. When the driver controls the accelerator input <b>104</b>-<b>1</b> to achieve a target vehicle speed or the cruise control input <b>104</b>-<b>3</b> is set to the target vehicle speed, the ECM <b>114</b> may selectively couple and decouple the engine system <b>100</b> with the drive system <b>143</b> based on the vehicle speed and the target vehicle speed. The ECM <b>114</b> may selectively adjust torque produced by the engine system <b>100</b> based on the coupling of the drive system <b>143</b> with the engine system <b>100</b> and the vehicle speed.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a functional block diagram of an exemplary implementation of the ECM <b>114</b> is presented. The ECM <b>114</b> may include a target speed module <b>202</b>, a coupling module <b>204</b>, and a torque adjustment module <b>206</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The target speed module <b>202</b> may receive the driver input and the vehicle speed. The target speed module <b>202</b> may generate a target vehicle speed based on the driver input and/or the vehicle speed. For example only, the target vehicle speed may be set to the vehicle speed when the accelerator input is steady. The accelerator input may be steady when the accelerator position varies less than a predetermined amount over a predetermined time. The target vehicle speed may be set to the vehicle speed when the cruise control input device is turned on. The target speed module <b>202</b> may generate a first target speed and a second target speed based on the target vehicle speed. The first target speed may be less than the second target speed. The second target speed may be greater than or equal to the target vehicle speed.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">For example only, the first target speed and the second target speed may be based on a speed deviation from the target vehicle speed. The speed deviation may be a calibrateable, predetermined deviation, such as a percentage above or a percentage below the target vehicle speed. The speed deviation may be adjustable based on a driver input signal. For example, the driver may set the speed deviation by adjusting the speed deviation input device <b>104</b>-<b>5</b>. A target vehicle speed range may be defined as a range of speed greater than or equal to the first target speed and less than or equal to the second target speed.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The coupling module <b>204</b> may generate a coupling signal based on the driver input, the target vehicle speed range, and the vehicle speed. The coupling signal may cause the engine system <b>100</b> to couple and decouple the drive system <b>143</b> based on a state of the driver input and the vehicle speed.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">For example only, the driver input may be in a first state when the accelerator position is less than or equal to an accelerator off threshold and the cruise control input device is turned off. The driver input may be in a second state when the accelerator position is greater than the accelerator off position and varies by less than a predetermined amount over a predetermined time. The driver input may be in the second state when the cruise control input device is turned on. The driver input may be in a third state when the brake position is greater than a brake off threshold during a braking period. For each of the states, the gear selector input device <b>104</b>-<b>4</b> may be positioned to select a drive gear of the vehicle.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">When the driver input is in the first state, the coupling module <b>204</b> may decouple the drive system <b>143</b> from the engine system <b>100</b>. The vehicle may coast without drive torque from the engine <b>102</b> and/or the electric motor <b>198</b>. Vehicle speed may decrease at a lower rate than when the engine system <b>100</b> is coupled with the drive system <b>143</b>. Therefore, vehicle energy, in the form of kinetic energy, may be conserved.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">For example only, when the engine system <b>100</b> is coupled and the driver input is in the first state, engine friction due to engine pumping losses may decrease vehicle speed. The drive system <b>143</b> may rotate the electric motor <b>198</b> resulting in decreased vehicle speed. Decoupling the engine system <b>100</b> reduces vehicle energy losses associated with the engine friction and/or the electric motor <b>198</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The torque adjustment module <b>206</b> may adjust the drive torque of the engine system <b>100</b> based on the coupling signal. For example only, when the coupling module <b>204</b> decouples the drive system <b>143</b> from the engine system <b>100</b>, the torque adjustment module <b>206</b> may decrease the drive torque. Drive torque may be decreased by reducing the throttle value to decrease the drive torque of the engine <b>102</b>. Drive torque may be decreased by reducing the power to the electric motor <b>198</b>. Drive torque may be decreased by turning off the electric motor <b>198</b>. Drive torque may be decreased by reducing engine speed to an idle engine speed that is less than an engine speed corresponding to the vehicle speed.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">When the driver input is in the second state, the coupling module <b>204</b> may selectively couple the drive system <b>143</b> with the engine system <b>100</b> based on the vehicle speed. Selectively engaging the drive system <b>143</b> may include engaging and disengaging the drive system <b>143</b> with the engine system <b>100</b>. The torque adjustment module <b>206</b> may adjust the drive torque of the engine system <b>100</b> based on the coupling signal, the vehicle speed, and the target vehicle speed range. The torque adjustment module <b>206</b> may adjust the drive torque to maintain the vehicle speed within the target vehicle speed range.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">When the vehicle speed is greater than or equal to the first speed threshold and less than or equal to the second speed threshold, the coupling module <b>204</b> may decouple the drive system <b>143</b> from the engine system <b>100</b>. The torque adjustment module <b>206</b> may decrease drive torque when the coupling module <b>204</b> decouples the drive system <b>143</b>, similar to when the driver input is in the first state. The vehicle may coast without drive torque from the engine <b>102</b> and/or the electric motor <b>198</b> as discussed above.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">When the vehicle speed is less than the first speed threshold, the coupling module <b>204</b> may couple the drive system <b>143</b> with the engine system <b>100</b>. The torque adjustment module <b>206</b> may increase drive torque by a predetermined amount until the vehicle speed reaches the second speed threshold. Drive torque of the engine <b>102</b> may be increased by adjusting the throttle value to increase airflow into the engine <b>102</b>. The drive torque of the engine <b>102</b> may be increased based on an efficiency of the engine <b>102</b>. For example only, the predetermined amount may be based on a brake specific fuel consumption of the engine <b>102</b>. Drive torque of the electric motor <b>198</b> may be increased by adjusting power to the electric motor <b>198</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">When the vehicle speed is greater than the second speed threshold, the coupling module <b>204</b> may couple the drive system <b>143</b> with the engine system <b>100</b>. The torque adjustment module <b>206</b> may decrease drive torque until the vehicle speed is less than or equal to the second speed threshold. Drive torque of the engine <b>102</b> may be decreased by adjusting the throttle value to decrease airflow into the engine <b>102</b>. Fueling may be cut and engine friction and pumping losses may produce negative drive torque to decrease the vehicle speed. Drive torque of the electric motor <b>198</b> may be decreased by adjusting power to the electric motor <b>198</b>. The electric motor <b>198</b> may be used as a generator to generate electrical energy that decreases vehicle speed.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">When the driver input is in the third state, the coupling module <b>204</b> may couple the drive system <b>143</b> with the engine system <b>100</b>. The torque adjustment module <b>206</b> may adjust the drive torque of the engine system <b>100</b> based on the coupling signal. The torque adjustment module <b>206</b> may adjust the drive torque to decrease the vehicle speed. For example only, the torque adjustment module <b>206</b> may use the engine <b>102</b> for braking to decrease the vehicle speed. Engine braking may include cutting fuel to the engine <b>102</b> to increase engine friction and pumping losses. The electric motor <b>198</b> may be used as a generator to charge the electrical storage device.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a method <b>300</b> is shown. Control begins in step <b>302</b> when control determines the driver input and vehicle speed. In step <b>304</b>, control may determine whether a drive gear is selected based on the gear selector input. When the drive gear is not selected, control returns to step <b>302</b>, otherwise control continues to step <b>306</b>. In step <b>306</b>, control determines whether the brake input is greater than a brake off threshold for a predetermined time (t). When the brake is not applied for time (t), control proceeds to step <b>308</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In step <b>308</b>, control determines whether the cruise control input device <b>104</b>-<b>3</b> is turned on. When cruise control is turned on, control may determine the target vehicle speed based on a cruise control set speed in step <b>310</b>. Otherwise, control proceeds to step <b>312</b>. In step <b>312</b>, control determines whether the position of the accelerator input device <b>104</b>-<b>1</b> is greater than the accelerator off threshold. When the accelerator input is greater than the accelerator off threshold, control determines whether the accelerator input is steady in step <b>314</b>. For example only, control may determine the accelerator input is steady when the accelerator input varies by less than a predetermined amount over a predetermined time. When the accelerator input is steady, control may determine the target vehicle speed based on the accelerator input in step <b>316</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">When the accelerator input is less than or equal to the accelerator off threshold in step <b>312</b>, control may proceed to step <b>318</b>. In step <b>318</b>, control decouples the drive system <b>143</b> from the engine system <b>100</b>. In step <b>320</b>, control decreases drive torque to a predetermined drive torque. For example only, control may reduce the drive torque of the engine <b>102</b> by closing the throttle <b>112</b> and decreasing engine speed to an idle engine speed. Control may reduce the drive torque of the electric motor <b>198</b> by turning the electric motor <b>198</b> off. Control returns to step <b>302</b>. When the accelerator input is greater than the accelerator off threshold in step <b>312</b> and the accelerator input is not steady in step <b>314</b>, control returns to step <b>302</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Returning to steps <b>310</b> and <b>316</b>, control proceeds to step <b>322</b> after determining the target vehicle speed. In step <b>322</b>, control determines the first and second vehicle speed thresholds based on the target vehicle speed and proceeds to step <b>324</b>. When the vehicle speed is less than or equal to the second vehicle speed threshold in step <b>324</b>, control proceeds to step <b>326</b>. When the vehicle speed is greater than or equal to the first vehicle speed threshold in step <b>326</b>, control proceeds to step <b>318</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">When the vehicle speed is greater than the second vehicle speed threshold in step <b>324</b>, control proceeds to step <b>328</b>. In step <b>328</b>, control couples the drive system <b>143</b> with the engine system <b>100</b>. Control decreases the drive torque to a predetermined torque, such as a minimum drive torque of the engine system <b>100</b> in step <b>330</b>. In step <b>332</b>, control may use engine braking to assist in decreasing the vehicle speed. For example, control may use deceleration fuel cut off (DFCO) or other engine braking techniques to produce negative drive torque. The minimum drive torque may include negative drive torque. In step <b>334</b>, control may use the electric motor <b>198</b> as a generator to charge the electrical storage device <b>200</b> and assist in decreasing the vehicle speed.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Returning to step <b>326</b>, when the vehicle speed is less than the first vehicle speed threshold, control continues to step <b>336</b>. In step <b>336</b>, control couples the drive system <b>143</b> with the engine system <b>100</b>. In step <b>338</b>, control increases the drive torque by a predetermined amount. For example only, control may increase the drive torque until the vehicle speed reaches the second vehicle speed threshold.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The broad teachings of the disclosure can be implemented in a variety of forms. Therefore, while this disclosure includes particular examples, the true scope of the disclosure should not be so limited since other modifications will become apparent to the skilled practitioner upon a study of the drawings, the specification, and the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An engine control system, comprising:
<claim-text>a target speed module that determines a target speed of a vehicle based on a speed of the vehicle and at least one of an accelerator input and a speed control input; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a coupling module that:
<claim-text>controls coupling of an engine system and a transmission system of the vehicle based on the speed and the target speed when a speed control input device is on;</claim-text>
<claim-text>when a first position of an accelerator input device is less than a first predetermined value indicative of no driver requested torque and the speed control input device is off, selectively couples and de-couples the engine system and the transmission system based on the vehicle speed;</claim-text>
<claim-text>couples the engine system with the transmission system when the speed control input device is on, the first position is greater than the first predetermined value, and the first position varies by less than a predetermined amount over a predetermined period; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>couples the engine system with the transmission system when a second position of a brake input device is greater than a second predetermined value,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the engine system transfers torque to the transmission system when coupled and does not transfer torque to the transmission system when decoupled.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The engine control system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a torque control module that controls torque output by the engine system based on the coupling of the engine system and the drive system, the speed, and the target speed.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The engine control system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the coupling module decouples the engine system from the drive system and the torque control module reduces the torque output by the engine system to a predetermined torque output when the speed differs by less than a predetermined speed from the target speed.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The engine control system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the coupling module couples the engine system with the drive system and the torque control module reduces the torque output by the engine system when the speed is greater than the target speed by a predetermined speed.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The engine control system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the coupling module couples the engine system with the drive system and the torque control module increases the torque output by the engine system when the speed is less than the target speed by a predetermined speed.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The engine control system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the coupling module decouples the engine system from the drive system and the torque control module reduces the torque output by the engine system to a predetermined torque output when the first position of the accelerator input device is less than the first predetermined value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The engine control system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the torque control module controls the torque output of at least one of an internal combustion engine and an electric motor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The engine control system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the coupling module controls coupling of the engine system and the drive system by controlling at least one of engagement of a clutch and selection of a neutral gear of an automatic transmission.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The engine control system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the target speed module determines the target speed when the first position of the accelerator input device is greater than the first predetermined value and varies by less than the predetermined amount during the predetermined period.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The engine control system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the target speed module determines the target speed when the speed control input device is on.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A method, comprising:
<claim-text>determining a target speed of a vehicle based on a speed of the vehicle and at least one of an accelerator input and a speed control input;</claim-text>
<claim-text>controlling coupling of an engine system and a transmission system of the vehicle based on the speed and the target speed when a speed control input device is on;</claim-text>
<claim-text>when a first position of an accelerator input device is less than a first predetermined value indicative of no driver requested torque and the speed control input device is off, selectively coupling and de-coupling the engine system and the transmission system based on the vehicle speed;</claim-text>
<claim-text>coupling the engine system with the transmission system when the speed control input device is on, the first position is greater than the first predetermined value, and the first position varies by less than a predetermined amount over a predetermined period,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the engine system transfers torque to the transmission system when coupled and does not transfer torque to the transmission system when decoupled; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>coupling the engine system with the transmission system when a position of a brake input device is greater than a predetermined value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further comprising controlling torque output by the engine system based on the coupling of the engine system and the drive system, the speed, and the target speed.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>decoupling the engine system from the drive system when the speed differs by less than a predetermined speed from the target speed; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>reducing the torque output by the engine system to a predetermined torque output.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>coupling the engine system with the drive system when the speed is greater than the target speed by a predetermined speed; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>reducing the torque output by the engine system.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>coupling the engine system with the drive system when the speed is less than the target speed by a predetermined speed; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>increasing the torque output by the engine system.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>decoupling the engine system from the drive system when the first position of the accelerator input is less than the first predetermined value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>reducing the torque output by the engine system to a predetermined torque output.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, further comprising controlling the torque output of at least one of an internal combustion engine and an electric motor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further comprising controlling coupling of the engine system and the drive system by controlling at least one of engagement of a clutch and selection of a neutral gear of an automatic transmission.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further comprising determining the target speed when the first position of the accelerator input is greater than the first predetermined value and varies by less than the predetermined amount during the predetermined period.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further comprising determining the target speed when the speed control input device is on. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
