<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624981-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624981</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13585853</doc-number>
<date>20120815</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>100145936 A</doc-number>
<date>20111213</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>9</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>17</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>17</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>348187</main-classification>
<further-classification>348184</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Testing method for camera</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7629998</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Elberbaum</name>
<date>20091200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>348187</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7693411</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kwon et al.</name>
<date>20100400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>396127</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8023815</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Yu et al.</name>
<date>20110900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>396 90</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8073317</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kitano</name>
<date>20111200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>396 55</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8260130</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Wang</name>
<date>20120900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>396133</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8478119</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Heo</name>
<date>20130700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>396129</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>11</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>348184</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>348180</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>348187</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>348188</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>348340</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>348357</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>34820811</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>3482082</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>3482085</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>348174-175</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<us-classifications-ipcr>H01N 17/00</us-classifications-ipcr>
<us-classifications-ipcr>H01N 17/02</us-classifications-ipcr>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130147968</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130613</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lin</last-name>
<first-name>Yung-Feng</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lin</last-name>
<first-name>Yung-Feng</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Tran</last-name>
<first-name>Trang U</first-name>
<department>2422</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A testing method includes: providing a camera under test and a planar light source having a first mark, wherein the camera includes a voice coil motor (VCM) and a lens module is fixed on the VCM by glue, the VCM moves the lens module, the VCM includes an elastic tab for limiting and restoring the movement of the lens module; taking an image of a light source using the camera during the movement of the VCM; displaying the image having the first mark; determining if the first mark tilts using a detector; displaying a first message indicating that the tab is not stuck by glue when the detector determines the first mark does not tilt; and displaying a second message indicating that the tab is stuck by glue when the detector determines the first mark tilts.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="102.95mm" wi="140.55mm" file="US08624981-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="218.02mm" wi="172.38mm" file="US08624981-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="150.54mm" wi="146.47mm" file="US08624981-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="185.25mm" wi="181.19mm" file="US08624981-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="194.14mm" wi="180.51mm" file="US08624981-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to cameras and, more particularly, to a testing method for testing whether an elastic tab of a voice coil motor (VCM) of a camera is stuck by glue in a gluing process for fixing a lens module of the camera to the VCM.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">VCMs are used to adjust a focus state of a camera. The VCM defines a through hole for receiving a lens module and includes elastic tabs at ends of the through holes for limiting and restoring movement of the lens module. The lens module is fixed to the VCM by gluing. However, during gluing, excess glue may flow out of the through hole which in turn may stick the tabs. As such, the tabs may not be able to deform and restore freely and accordingly the lens module may tilt as the tabs can not deform and restore freely, which in turn degrades quality of the camera.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Therefore, it is desirable to provide a testing method for testing whether or not an elastic tab of a VCM of a camera is stuck by glue.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Many aspects of the present embodiments can be better understood with reference to the following drawings. The components in the drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the present embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a flowchart of a testing method in accordance with the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic diagram showing how the testing method in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is implemented.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic view of an image taken by a camera under test when an elastic tab in a VCM of the camera is not stuck by glue.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic view of an image taken by the camera when the elastic tab in the VCM of the camera is stuck by glue.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Embodiments of the present disclosure will be described below, with reference to the accompanying drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, a testing method is provided.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In step S<b>101</b>, a camera <b>1</b> and a power source <b>2</b> are provided, wherein the camera <b>1</b> includes a VCM <b>10</b> and a lens module <b>11</b> is fixed on the VCM <b>10</b> by glue. The power source <b>2</b> powers the VCM <b>10</b>, thereby driving the VCM <b>10</b> to move. The VCM <b>10</b> includes an elastic tab <b>12</b> for limiting and restoring the movement of the lens module <b>11</b>. A planar light source <b>4</b> having a first mark <b>41</b> with a first color is also provided.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In step S<b>102</b>, the camera <b>1</b> takes an image of a light source <b>4</b> during the movement of the VCM <b>10</b>. In this embodiment, the first mark <b>41</b> is positioned at an upper portion of the light source <b>4</b> and corresponds to an upper portion the tab <b>12</b>. Alternatively, the first mark <b>41</b> can be positioned at other suitable positions of the light source <b>4</b>, e.g., a lower, left, or right portion, and corresponds to other portion, e.g., a lower, left, or right portion, of the tab <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In step S<b>103</b>, a display <b>3</b> is provided and displays the image having the first mark <b>41</b> with the first color, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In step S<b>104</b>, a detector <b>5</b> is provided and determines if the first mark <b>41</b> tilts. In this embodiment, the first mark <b>41</b> is a straight line and, accordingly, if the first mark <b>41</b> tilts can be determined by the following sub-steps: obtaining an included angle between the first mark <b>41</b> and the horizontal direction; acquiring a pixel of the first mark <b>41</b>; taking the pixel as an origin and drawing a straight line extending from the origin at the obtained included angle in relative to the horizontal direction; detecting whether other pixels of the first mark <b>41</b> are on the straight line; and determining that the first mark <b>41</b> tilts if the other pixels of the first mark <b>41</b> are not all on the straight line or the first mark <b>41</b> does not tilt if the other pixels of the first mark <b>41</b> are all on the straight light.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In step S<b>105</b>, the display <b>3</b> displays a first message indicating that the tab <b>12</b> is not stuck by glue when the detector <b>5</b> determines the first mark <b>41</b> does not tilt as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. In principle, being stuck, the tab <b>12</b> is not able to deform and restore freely and accordingly the lens module <b>11</b> may tilt as the tab <b>12</b> can not deform and restore freely. In turn, the first mark <b>41</b> in the image of the light source <b>4</b> which is taken by the lens module <b>11</b> will tilt.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In step S<b>106</b>, the display <b>3</b> displays a second message indicating that the tab <b>12</b> is stuck by glue when the detector <b>5</b> determines the first mark <b>41</b> tilts.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In other embodiments, the light source <b>4</b> may include more than one marks positioned on both the upper, lower, left, and right portions of the light source <b>4</b> and correspond to the upper, lower, left, and right portions of the tab <b>12</b>, respectively, to increase accuracy of the testing. Specifically, in addition to the first mark <b>41</b> with the first color, the light source <b>4</b> further includes a second mark <b>42</b> with a second color positioned at a lower portion of the light source <b>4</b> and corresponding to the lower portion of the tab <b>12</b>, a third mark <b>43</b> with a third color positioned at a left portion of the light source <b>4</b> and corresponding to the left portion of the tab <b>12</b>, and a fourth mark <b>44</b> with a fourth color positioned at a right portion of the light source <b>4</b> and corresponding to the right portion of the tab <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">If the light source <b>4</b> further includes the second mark <b>42</b> with the second color, the testing method further includes following steps, after the detector <b>5</b> determines the first mark <b>41</b> does not tilt: the display <b>3</b> displays the second mark <b>42</b> with the second color; the detector <b>5</b> determines if the second mark <b>42</b> tilts; the display <b>3</b> displays the second message indicating that the tab <b>12</b> is stuck by glue when the detector <b>5</b> determines the second mark <b>42</b> tilts, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, and the display <b>3</b> displays the first message indicating that the tab <b>12</b> is not stuck by glue when the detector <b>5</b> determines the second mark <b>42</b> does not tilt, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">If the light source <b>4</b> includes the third mark <b>43</b> with the third color as well, the testing method further includes following steps after the detector <b>5</b> determines the second mark <b>42</b> does not tilt, the display <b>3</b> displays the third mark <b>43</b> with the third color; the detector <b>5</b> determines if the third mark <b>43</b> tilts; the display <b>3</b> displays the second message indicating that the tab <b>12</b> is stuck by glue <b>3</b> when the detector <b>5</b> determines the third mark <b>43</b> tilts, and the display <b>3</b> displays the first message indicating that the tab <b>12</b> is not stuck by glue when the detector <b>5</b> determines the third mark <b>43</b> does not tilt.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">If the light source <b>4</b> further includes the fourth mark <b>44</b> with the fourth color, the testing method further includes following steps after the detector <b>5</b> determines the third mark <b>43</b> is not tilted: the display <b>3</b> displays the fourth mark <b>44</b> with the fourth color; the detector <b>5</b> determines if the fourth mark <b>44</b> tilts; the display <b>3</b> displays the first message indicating that the tab <b>12</b> is not stuck by glue when the detector <b>5</b> determines the fourth mark <b>44</b> is not tilted, and the display <b>3</b> displays the second message that the tab <b>12</b> is stuck by glue when the detector <b>5</b> determines the fourth mark <b>44</b> is tilted.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">If the second mark <b>42</b>, the third mark <b>43</b>, or the fourth mark <b>44</b> is tilted can be determined by the same steps for determining if the first mark <b>41</b> tilt. The first, second, third, and fourth color can be the same or different.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Although the features and elements of the present disclosure are described as embodiments in particular combinations, each feature or element can be used alone or in other various combinations within the principles of the present disclosure to the full extent indicated by the broad general meaning of the terms in which the appended claims are expressed.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A testing method comprising:
<claim-text>providing a camera under test, a power source, and a planar light source having a first mark with a first color, wherein the camera includes a voice coil motor (VCM) and a lens module is fixed on the VCM by glue, the power source is configured to power the VCM to drive the VCM moving the lens module, the VCM comprises an elastic tab for limiting and restoring the movement of the lens module;</claim-text>
<claim-text>taking an image of the light source using the camera during the movement of the VCM;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a display and displaying the image having the first mark with the first color using the display;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a detector and determining if the first mark tilts using the detector;</claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying a first message indicating that the tab is not stuck by glue when the detector determines the first mark does not tilt using the display; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying a second message indicating that the tab is stuck by glue when the detector determines the first mark tilts using the display.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The testing method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first mark is positioned at an upper, lower, left, or right portion of the light source and corresponds to an upper, lower, left, or right portion the tab.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The testing method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first mark is a straight line and if the first mark tilts can be determined by the following sub-steps:
<claim-text>obtaining an included angle between the first mark and the horizontal direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>acquiring a pixel of the first mark;</claim-text>
<claim-text>taking the pixel as an origin and drawing a straight line extending from the origin at the obtained included angle in relative to the horizontal direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting whether other pixels of the first mark are on the straight line; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining that the first mark tilts if the other pixels of the first mark are not all on the straight line or the first mark does not tilt if the other pixels of the first mark are all on the straight light.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The testing method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the light source comprises another three marks positioned on the lower, left, and right portion of the light source and correspond to the lower, left, and right portions of the tab, respectively.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The testing method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the light source further comprises a second mark with a second color positioned at a lower portion of the light source and corresponding to the lower portion of the tab.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The testing method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, further comprising, after the detector determines the first mark does not tilt:
<claim-text>displaying the second mark with the second color using the display;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining if the second mark tilts using the detector;</claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying the second message indicating that the tab is stuck by glue when the detector determines the second mark tilts using the display; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying the first message indicating that the tab is not stuck by glue when the detector determines the second mark does not tilt using the display.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The testing method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the light source further comprises a third mark with a third color positioned at a left portion of the light source and corresponding to the left portion of the tab.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The testing method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, further comprising, after the detector determines the second mark does not tilt:
<claim-text>displaying the third mark with the third color using the display;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining if the third mark tilts using the detector;</claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying the third message indicating that the tab is stuck by glue when the detector determines the third mark tilts using the display; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying the first message indicating that the tab is not stuck by glue when the detector determines the third mark does not tilt using the display.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The testing method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the light source further comprises a fourth mark with a fourth color positioned at a right portion of the light source and corresponding to the right portion of the tab.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The testing method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further comprising, after the detector determines the third mark does not tilt:
<claim-text>displaying the fourth mark with the fourth color using the display;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining if the fourth mark tilts using the detector;</claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying the fourth message indicating that the tab is stuck by glue when the detector determines the fourth mark tilts using the display; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying the first message indicating that the tab is not stuck by glue when the detector determines the fourth mark does not tilt using the display.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The testing method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the first, second, third, and fourth colors are the same or different. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
