<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625269-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625269</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13172603</doc-number>
<date>20110629</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>100120781</doc-number>
<date>20110614</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>53</us-term-extension>
<disclaimer>
<text>This patent is subject to a terminal disclaimer.</text>
</disclaimer>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>16</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36167931</main-classification>
<further-classification>36167932</further-classification>
<further-classification>361737</further-classification>
<further-classification>361785</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e73">Serial advanced technology attachment DIMM</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0257184</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lee et al.</name>
<date>20091000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36167932</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0087094</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Chen et al.</name>
<date>20100400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>43960701</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2012/0212988</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Sugita et al.</name>
<date>20120800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>365 51</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2013/0003285</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Liang et al.</name>
<date>20130100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36167931</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>4</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36167931</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>361728</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36167901</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36167902</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36167932</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>3616794</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36167941</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>361737</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>361748</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>361784-789</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>361792</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>361803</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439 43</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439 45</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>2</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120320518</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121220</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chen</last-name>
<first-name>Yung-Chieh</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hsu</last-name>
<first-name>Shou-Kuo</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chen</last-name>
<first-name>Yung-Chieh</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hsu</last-name>
<first-name>Shou-Kuo</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Thompson</last-name>
<first-name>Timothy</first-name>
<department>2835</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Patel</last-name>
<first-name>Amol</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A serial advanced technology attachment (SATA) DIMM includes a board body. A control chip is arranged on the board body. An extending board extends from an end of the board body. A first edge connector is set on the extending board. A second edge connector is set on a bottom side of the board body. The first edge connector includes a number of signal pins connected to the control chip, and a number of ground pins.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="134.62mm" wi="168.57mm" file="US08625269-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="191.26mm" wi="170.01mm" file="US08625269-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="210.40mm" wi="175.51mm" file="US08625269-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to a serial advanced technology attachment (SATA) DIMM.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Solid state drives (SSD) store data on chips instead of magnetic or optical discs as traditional drives. One type of SSD has the form factor of a dual-in-line memory module (DIMM) module and is called a serial advanced technology attachment (SATA) DIMM. As such, the SATADIMM can be inserted into a memory slot of a motherboard, to receive a voltage from the motherboard through the memory slot. However, hard disk drive (HDD) signals need to be transmitted between the SATADIMM and the motherboard through a SATA connector set on the SATADIMM connected to a SATA connector of the motherboard. Moreover, the SATA connector set on the SATADIMM may occupy a lot of space. Therefore, there is room for improvement in the art.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Many aspects of the embodiments can be better understood with reference to the following drawings. The components in the drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the present embodiments. Moreover, in the drawings, like reference numerals designate corresponding parts throughout the several views.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic diagram of a serial advanced technology attachment (SATA) DIMM in accordance with an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic diagram of the SATADIMM of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> connected to a motherboard.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The disclosure, including the drawings, is illustrated by way of example and not by limitation. References to &#x201c;an&#x201d; or &#x201c;one&#x201d; embodiment in this disclosure are not necessarily to the same embodiment, and such references mean at least one.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, a serial advanced technology attachment (SATA) DIMM <b>100</b> in accordance with an exemplary embodiment includes a board body <b>10</b>. The board body <b>10</b> is substantially rectangle-shaped. A control chip <b>40</b> is arranged on the board body <b>10</b>. An edge connector <b>18</b> is set on a bottom side <b>16</b> of the board body <b>10</b>. An extending board <b>12</b> is extended from a first end <b>11</b> of the board body <b>10</b>. An edge connector <b>13</b> is set on the extending board <b>12</b>. Two grooves <b>14</b>, one defined in the first end <b>11</b> of the board body <b>10</b> and located under the extending board <b>12</b>, and other defined in a second end <b>15</b> of the board body <b>10</b>, corresponding to the groove <b>14</b>. The edge connector <b>13</b> and the extending board <b>12</b> compose a storage device connector <b>111</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">A top surface <b>121</b> of the extending board <b>12</b> is lower than a top side <b>19</b> of the board body <b>10</b> opposite to the bottom side <b>16</b>. When the storage device connector <b>111</b> is connected to a storage device interface <b>3</b>, a top surface <b>31</b> of the storage device interface <b>3</b> is lower than or coplanar with the top side <b>19</b> of the board body <b>10</b>. Thus, reducing the interference between the SATADIMM <b>100</b> and a chassis (not shown) when the SATADIMM <b>100</b> is mounted on a motherboard <b>1</b> accommodated in the chassis. The edge connector <b>18</b> is inserted into a memory slot <b>2</b> of the motherboard <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The edge connector <b>13</b> includes a plurality of signal pins (not labeled) and a plurality of ground pins (not labeled). The signal pins includes a pair of signal input pins and a pair of signal output pins. The ground pins includes three ground pins. The signal input pins and the signal output pins are connected to the control chip <b>40</b> through conductive lines of the board body <b>10</b>. The ground pins are connected to a ground layer (not shown) of the board body <b>10</b>, to be grounded.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In one embodiment, the storage device connector <b>111</b> is in accordance with a serial advanced technology attachment (SATA) standard. The storage device interface <b>3</b> is an SATA connector. In other embodiments, the storage device connector <b>111</b> can be set on another side or end of the board body <b>10</b>, such as the top side <b>19</b> or the second end <b>15</b>, according to need.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In use, the edge connector <b>18</b> of the SATADIMM <b>100</b> is inserted into the memory slot <b>2</b> of the motherboard <b>1</b>. The grooves <b>14</b> engage with fixing elements <b>7</b> of the memory slot <b>2</b>, to fix the SATADIMM <b>100</b> to the memory slot <b>2</b>. The storage device connector <b>111</b> is connected to the storage device interface <b>3</b>, to electrically connect the edge connector <b>13</b> to the storage device interface <b>3</b>. The top surface <b>31</b> of the storage device interface <b>3</b> is lower than or coplanar with the top side <b>19</b> of the board body <b>10</b>, to avoid interference. A storage device interface <b>5</b> is connected to the storage device interface <b>3</b> through a cable <b>4</b> and also connected to a storage device interface <b>6</b> of the motherboard <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">When the motherboard <b>1</b> is powered on, the motherboard <b>1</b> outputs a voltage to the DATADIMM <b>100</b> through the memory slot <b>2</b> and the edge connector <b>18</b> of the board body <b>10</b>. At the same time, the motherboard <b>1</b> outputs a hard disk drive (HDD) signal to the control chip <b>40</b> of the SATADIMM <b>100</b> through the storage device interfaces <b>6</b> and <b>5</b>, the cable <b>4</b>, the storage device interface <b>3</b>, and the edge connector <b>13</b> of the storage device connector <b>111</b>, to communicate with the SATADIMM <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The SATADIMM <b>100</b> can communicate with the motherboard <b>1</b> through the storage device connector <b>111</b>, which set on an end of the board body <b>10</b> of the SATADIMM <b>100</b> for replacing a general SATA connector set on the SATADIMM <b>100</b>, to save more space of the SATADIMM <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">It is to be understood, however, that even though numerous characteristics and advantages of the disclosure have been set forth in the foregoing description, together with details of the structure and function of the disclosure, the disclosure is illustrative only, and changes may be made in detail, especially in matters of shape, size, and the arrangement of parts within the principles of the disclosure to the full extent indicated by the broad general meaning of the terms in which the appended claims are expressed.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A serial advanced technology attachment (SATA) dual-in-line memory module (DIMM) comprising:
<claim-text>a board body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control chip arranged on the board body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an extending board extending from an end of the board body, a first edge connector set on the extending board, to be connected to a motherboard; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second edge connector set on a bottom side of the board body, to be inserted into a memory slot of the motherboard, the first edge connector comprising a plurality of signal pins connected to the control chip, and a plurality of ground pins;</claim-text>
<claim-text>when the motherboard is powered on, the motherboard outputs a voltage to the SATADIMM through the memory slot of the motherboard and the second edge connector, and the motherboard also outputs a hard disk drive signal to the control chip of the SATADIMM through the first edge connector, to communicate with the SATADIMM.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The SATADIMM of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the extending board and the first edge connector compose a storage device connector, the storage device connector conforms with a serial advanced technology attachment (SATA) standard.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The SATADIMM of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of signal pins comprises a pair of signal input pins and a pair of signal output pins.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The SATADIMM of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a top surface of the extending board is lower than a top side of the board body opposite to the bottom side, when a storage device interface is connected to the first edge connector, a top surface of the storage device interface is lower than or coplanar with the top side of the board body. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
