<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622482-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622482</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12870289</doc-number>
<date>20100827</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>381</us-term-extension>
<disclaimer>
<text>This patent is subject to a terminal disclaimer.</text>
</disclaimer>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>E</section>
<class>21</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>35</main-group>
<subgroup>18</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>299102</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e55">Bit holder usable in bit blocks having either of a cylindrical or non-locking taper bore</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7789468</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Sollami</name>
<date>20100900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>299107</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>264015</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19880400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>2</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>299100-113</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>14</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation-in-part>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12194195</doc-number>
<date>20080819</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7789468</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12870289</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation-in-part>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20100320829</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20101223</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sollami</last-name>
<first-name>Phillip</first-name>
<address>
<city>Herrin</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sollami</last-name>
<first-name>Phillip</first-name>
<address>
<city>Herrin</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Patnaude &#x26; Videbeck</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Singh</last-name>
<first-name>Sunil</first-name>
<department>3672</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A bit holder for use in a bit assembly in road milling, mining and trenching equipment has a hollow generally cylindrical shank and first and second elongate slots positioned in spaced axial relation through the shank. The first slot extends along the shank to the distal end thereof. The second slot may be altered in length and/or shaped to fine tune the outward radial force the shank exerts against the bore of a bit holder block into which it is inserted.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="104.31mm" wi="161.29mm" file="US08622482-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="251.88mm" wi="195.41mm" file="US08622482-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="260.18mm" wi="184.57mm" file="US08622482-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="265.26mm" wi="197.36mm" file="US08622482-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="259.00mm" wi="173.31mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622482-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="237.74mm" wi="189.65mm" file="US08622482-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This is a continuation-in-part of U.S. Ser. No. 12/194,195 filed Aug. 19, 2008, now U.S. Pat. No. 7,789,468, the contents of which are incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This invention relates generally to road surface removal equipment, reclaimer-stabilizer equipment and mining equipment, and more particularly, to bit assemblies including bits, bit holders, and bit blocks that last longer than heretofore known. Such assemblies provide for greater ease of replaceability.</p>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Bit assemblies have long been utilized in road and highway milling machinery, as well as in off-road trenching equipment and in mining machinery. On such machinery, a plurality of bit assemblies are mounted both across the width and around the perimeter, sometimes in spiral or herringbone orientation, on the outside of a hollow rotary drum. Such bit assemblies are also utilized on the outside of a continuous chain, or similar endless looping machinery where the bits are moved through an orbit that is intercepted by the face of the road material being milled, the earth material from which a trench is being dug, and the material being mined.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The bit assemblies include a bit that has a working end and a shank. The shank is received in and may also be rotatably mounted in a bit holder that is secured, in turn, onto a bit block mounted (usually welded) on the outside of the drum or welded on a stand which is welded to a drum. Bits typically have a hardened working end, preferably made of tungsten carbide or other hardened material, which impinges and digs into the surface it contacts to remove a portion of same. By utilizing a plurality of the bit assemblies around the outer surface of such a rotating drum or continuous chain, the amount of material removal in a given period of time may be substantial.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">While bit assemblies include a bit and a bit block, they may include an intermediate member, depending on the intended application and the severity of work to be expended. For light duty applications and especially for down drilling applications such as foundation work where the forces on the bit are mostly axial, sheet metal fashioned retainers may be utilized. For heavy duty applications such as road milling and mining operations where the bit receives forces from multiple angles during operation, a forged annular bit holder is used.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">A retainer is usually made of sheet spring steel having at least 0.5% carbon content (a differing material than the bit and bit block), a maximum thickness of about 0.050 inch, and is rolled in a circular discontinuous shape to elastically fit around the shank of the bit and within the bore of a bit block. The engineering concepts used to create retainers and bit holders are quite different. The retainer, and the bit, can rotate in the bit block. Usually, the bit shank is received in the bit block to allow space for the retainer to be mounted therearound. Retainer applications are limited to lighter duty applications or high axial loading applications. A force of about 70 pounds can remove a retainer and bit assembly from around a bit block. Thin walled retainers are not as long-lived as bit holders because lime and caustic action in the concrete or asphalt aggregate eats away the steel.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">A bit holder is typically made of forged steel, although it could be machined from bar stock or formed of powdered metal at more expense. The holder can be made of the same material as the bit block, typically 4140, 8640, 4340 or similar steels having less than 0.5% carbon content. A bit holder has an enlarged forward end that extends beyond the top of a bit block, positioning a bit substantially more forward than a retainer and adding bulk material for a stronger single member part capable of absorbing substantial forces from many angles. A bit holder does not rotate in the bit holder block.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Since such road milling, trenching and mining machinery is considered heavy duty earth, coal, mineral or macadam removal machinery, substantial forces will operate on the bit assemblies in question. Engineers and operators of such equipment have long sought to extend the working life of these components and decrease the down time of such equipment. A major breakthrough in the longevity of use of such equipment and in decreasing the time necessary to replace worn or broken bit assemblies used on such equipment was made by utilizing the bit assemblies shown and disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 6,585,326 issued Jul. 1, 2003. That patent disclosed a bit assembly utilizing a bit holder that was held in place in its bit block without the necessity of utilizing a nut, retaining clip, bolt, or the like to maintain the bit holder in operative position in its bit block.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">By providing a bit holder with a generally cylindrical hollow shank having an elongate slot axially positioned through one side of the shank from the distal end thereof and extending toward the forward body portion of the shank, the bit holder was able to be pressed or driven into a bore of the bit holder block such that the outer, generally cylindrical, radius of the thick walled shank was elastically collapsed an amount that was greater than the interference dimensions of a similarly sized solid shaft. It was found that the bit holder could be maintained in the bit holder block during operation, and be removed and replaced quickly by being driven in or out of its associated bit holder block with a force between 3,000 and 10,000 pounds, without the need of removing retaining clips, threaded nuts or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">A standard interference fit as used herein is a heavy duty fit sometimes referred to as force fits or class FN5 force fits. The limits for FN5 force fits are found in numerous engineering handbooks. The quick change bit holder invented by me has utilized a press or force fit greater than a standard interference fit or FN5 force fit, as note in my previous patents.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Additionally, the inventions disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 7,097,258 issued Aug. 29, 2006 disclose a quick-change bit holder preferably having a slightly tapered shank with a pair of raised outer surfaces on a mediate portion along the length of the shank. The shank also includes a pair of diametrically opposed axially oriented slots extending along the shank through the mediate portion and immediately adjacent the raised outer portions of the shank on either side thereof. In this embodiment, unlike the embodiment first disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 6,585,326, the dual opposed slots were totally internal in the shank and did not extend to the distal end of the shank.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">As such, the distal end of the shank provided more rigidity than the distal end of the shank disclosed in the '326 patent, but allowed enough deformation in the enlarged mediate portion of the shank, when pressed into a bit holder block to maintain the bit holder in a tapered bit holder block bore.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">While the preferred embodiments shown in U.S. Pat. Nos. 6,585,326 and 7,097,258, were slightly tapered to the order of 1 degree or less per side, additional disclosures were made not only of tapered shanks, but shanks going from such a taper through and including a concave shape. Such shanks on either side of a strictly cylindrical shank, would be more efficient than a cylindrical shank in a cylindrical bore because the amount of surface contact, i.e., the driving interference distance, of such shanks would be less than the driving interference distance necessary for a completely cylindrical shank. However, such a cylindrical shape shank could work, although less efficiently and with more effort to insert or remove than the other preferred mentioned shanks.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The preferred bit holder blocks shown and utilized in the '326 patent include bores therethrough that are generally cylindrical with preferably a slight taper of 1 degree per side or less (preferably the same taper as the bit holder shank). Bit block bores that are completely cylindrical and also with 3&#xbd; degree per side taper have been utilized in bit assemblies. There are solid bit holder shanks and bit holder block assemblies that are press fit assemblies.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">A bit holder utilizing a substantial distal shank portion having a straight cylindrical outline and fitting into a bit holder block bore having a straight cylindrical bottom end with a slightly widened top end thereof is shown at U.S. Pat. No. 6,854,810.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Since the bases of all of the known such bit block assemblies are welded to either the outside of a generally cylindrical drum or welded to the outside of links of a chain or similar continuous looping mechanism, and since such bit blocks have substantially more metal material to withstand shock, wear and the like, and since base blocks are shielded by the frontal portion of the holder, bit blocks tend to have a much longer service life than bit holders or bits. As such, the bit holders and bits are made to be replaceable, and the more easily replaceable the better.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">As mentioned previously, the use of a quick change type bit holder as disclosed in the '326 patent both lessens down time of its associated machinery, and the additional upper body material of such preferred bit holders lengthens the in-service life thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The use of bit holders with differing bit holder blocks having both slightly tapered bit holder block bores and partially cylindrical bit holder block bores has heretofore meant that when one picked a drum, chain, or the like of one manufacturer, one was limited to that manufacturer's bit holders. Therefore, a need has developed for the construction of a bit holder that may be utilized in either existing type quick change style bit holder blocks.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">It is therefore an object of the invention, generally stated, to provide a new and improved bit holder which may be utilized in bit blocks having bit holder block bores that are cylindrical along its entire length, or that are slightly constantly tapered along their length, and also bit holder block bores that are tapered along an upper portion thereof and cylindrical along a lower portion thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Another object of the present invention is the provision of a bit holder shank that deflects sufficiently to allow the bit holder to be inserted and retained in a bit block bore that has a bottom portion thereof that is either a cylindrical or a non-locking taper in shape.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The invention resides in a bit holder for use in road milling, trenching and mining equipment as part of an assembly including a bit, bit holder and bit holder block. The bit holder comprises a front body portion and a generally cylindrical hollow shank portion extending from a rear of the front body portion. A generally cylindrical hollow shank portion defines an annular side wall and includes a first elongate slot radially through the side wall extending generally axially along the side wall from a distal end thereof and has a termination on the side wall between the distal end of the shank and the rear of the front body portion.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">A second internal elongate slot is positioned substantially spatially opposite the shank from the first elongate slot and extends generally axially along the side wall with an upper termination spatially related to the rear of the front body portion, and a lower termination spatially related to the distal end of the shank. At least portions of the shank has a free standing diametrical dimension that is larger than a corresponding diametrical dimensions of one of a cylindrical bit holder block bore, and a non-locking tapered bit holder block bore. The insertion of the bit holder shank in the bit holder block bore provides sufficient outward radial force by radial deflection of the portions of the shank adjacent said slots to retain the shank in the bit holder block bore during use. A non-locking taper is defined as achieving continuous axial movement when the same force is applied to initially insert the shank of the holder into the bit holder block bore.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The features of the present invention which are believed to be novel are set forth with particularity in the appended claims. The invention may best be understood from the following detailed description of a currently preferred embodiment and modifications thereof taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings wherein like numerals refer to like parts, and in which:</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a &#xbe; front perspective view of a the bit holder, constructed in accordance with the present invention, that may be utilized in both constantly tapered and partially cylindrical bit block bores;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a top plan view of the body of the bit holder shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a bottom &#xbe; perspective view of the bit holder shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> emphasizing the construction of the shank thereof;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a top plan view of a first modification of a bit holder constructed in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a side elevational view of a back side of the bit holder shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a front side elevational view of the bit holder modification shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a top plan view of the body portion of a second modification of the bit holder constructed in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a front elevational view of the bit holder shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a back elevational view of the bit holder shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a front side elevational view of the bit holder of the first embodiment showing its outside shank dimensions prior to being inserted in a bit block;</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a front elevational view of the bit holder of the first embodiment showing the shank outside dimensions as they are after insertion into a partly tapered and partly cylindrical bit block;</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a cross-sectional diagrammatic view of the bit holder of the first embodiment shown as it appears after insertion in the bit block bore of a bit block including both an upper tapered section and a lowered cylindrical section thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a cross-sectional diagrammatic view of the bit holder of the first embodiment as it appears at the start of its insertion into a bit block having a slight (1 degree per side) constant taper; and</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is a cross-sectional diagrammatic view of the bit holder of the first embodiment fully inserted into the bit block shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>2</b> and <b>3</b>, a bit holder, generally indicated at <b>20</b>, and preferably made of a 4100, 4300 or 8600 series steel with about 0.40% carbon content, or one that produces similar compression and tensile strength, includes a front body portion <b>21</b> and a generally cylindrical shank <b>22</b> extending from the rear of the front body portion. As with previous bit holders made by the assignee of the applicant, the front body portion <b>21</b> includes a leading annular ring <b>23</b> or shoulder having a generally flat front annular surface <b>24</b> and a central bore <b>25</b> extending from that front surface through the body portion <b>21</b> and axially through the length of the shank <b>22</b> to the distal end <b>26</b> of the shank <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The diameter of bore <b>25</b>, in this preferred embodiment, which is meant for use in road milling equipment, approximates 0.782 inch. The expanded outer diameter of a retainer on a bit shank (not shown) is about 0.050 inch larger than the bit holder bore. A much greater diameter squeeze is required when using thin wall retention sleeves. The shank of the bit that fits in this holder central bore <b>25</b> when used on road milling equipment is about 0.665 inch in diameter. The retainer attaches around the shank of the bit and has a wall thickness of generally 0.045 inch. Mining bit shanks approximate 1 inch, 1 3/16 inch, 1&#x215c; inch and 1&#xbe; inch in diameter. Trenching bit shanks approximate 1 3/16 and 1&#xbd; inch in diameter. Other sizes may also be utilized.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">One of the features of the bit holder front body portion <b>21</b> is to provide substantial bulk along with a fairly streamlined outer surface, both to allow removed product to slide or slip by the sides of the bit, bit holder, and block, as well as to provide shoulder bulk to resist wear and extend the working life of this heavy duty equipment. As such, in the preferred embodiment, axially rearwardly of the front leading ring <b>23</b>, is a generally frustoconical portion <b>27</b> that widens as one proceeds axially along the length of the front body portion toward the shank <b>22</b> thereof until one comes to an outer rear portion of the body that is annular or cylindrical in shape, and is denoted in the industry as the &#x201c;tire&#x201d; portion <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In this embodiment the forward body portion is about 2.00 inches long and the shank is about 2.58 inches long, although other uses, such as mining and trenching utilize differing size equipment. As shown most clearly in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the rear of the outer tire portion <b>28</b> includes a generally rearwardly facing flat annular flange <b>29</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In this preferred embodiment <b>20</b>, a side hole generally indicated at <b>30</b>, which is the subject of co-pending application Ser. No. 11/998,676, filed Nov. 30, 2007, extends inwardly from the outside of frustoconical portion <b>27</b> and a part of the tire portion <b>28</b> of the bit holder body <b>21</b> at an acute angle toward the axis of the bit holder bore <b>25</b>. The side hole <b>30</b> is about the same diameter as the bit holder bore <b>25</b> and is used in connection with a slide hammer removal tool assembly that is the subject matter of co-pending application Ser. No. 12/193,866 filed Aug. 19, 2008.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">A cylindrical plug, such as shown at <b>147</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> fits in the side hole, although it may be left open in operation, further, if desired, a 0.750 inch nominal cylindrical plug may be utilized, as may a bit (not shown), since they are approximately the same diameter. The slide hammer (not shown) utilizes a central threaded shaft and a hook threaded thereon that includes a 0.750 inch cylindrical pin or plug at its distal end that is canted to fit in the side hole <b>30</b>. The central shaft is inserted in the bit holder bore until it impinges on the pin. The slide hammer then acts on a stop member on the opposite end of the shaft to provide sufficient axial impact force, 3,000 to 10,000 pounds, to manually remove the bit holder from the bit block. Pneumatic pressure is not required, making field changes and repairs quicker and easier than heretofore known.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">While the shank <b>22</b> extends axially rearwardly from the rear face <b>29</b> of the front body portion, the preferred embodiment <b>20</b> includes a recess <b>32</b> partially formed in the annular rear face <b>29</b> and <b>33</b> partially formed in the outer surface of the shank <b>22</b> adjacent and in continuation of recess <b>32</b>, provides a round, less stress, joinder between the shank <b>22</b> and front body portion <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Shank <b>22</b> extends in the preferred embodiment from the back annular face recess <b>32</b> to the distal end <b>26</b> of the shank. Shank <b>22</b> is generally cylindrical in shape a nominal diameter of 1.545 inch, a length of 2.577 inches and a wall thickness of about 0.35 inch. This is quite a thick wall in comparison with any retainer. For structural integrity, the wall thickness of the hollow shank of a bit holder of the present invention is at least about 1/7 of the length of the bit holder shank. The most heavy duty sleeve used on a bit shank related to the present invention is at least about 1/28 of the sleeve length divided by its thickness. A cylindrical shank is an example of a non-locking design feature. Up to about 2&#xbd; degrees per side taper is considered non-locking. This preferred embodiment includes two slightly tapered surfaces, the first generally annular surface extends from recess <b>32</b> and tapers slightly at <b>34</b> axially along the shank until it reaches a raised generally annular shoulder <b>35</b> which raises the outer diameter of the shank approximately 0.015 inch on the diameter and begins a second taper portion <b>36</b> that extends from the shoulder <b>35</b> to a chamfer <b>37</b> that extends to a slightly reduced diameter distal end portion <b>38</b> which extends to another chamfer <b>40</b> that meets distal end flat surface <b>26</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In one important aspect of the present invention, the hollow generally cylindrical shank that not only includes an elongate slot <b>41</b> that extends from the distal end <b>26</b> of the shank axially through the thick outer wall of the shank to a position at <b>42</b> which is close to but spatially adjacent from recess <b>32</b>. In the preferred embodiment, the distance is about &#x215c; inch. Along with the elongate first slot is, in this preferred embodiment, an elongate second totally internal slot <b>43</b> that extends completely through the side wall of the shank in a diametrically opposed position from elongate slot <b>41</b>. Slot <b>43</b>, while elongate, is completely enclosed within the shank in that it has opposed upper end portion <b>44</b> which is positioned axially along the shank a like distance from recess <b>32</b> to that of the inner end portion <b>42</b> of slot <b>41</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">It should be noted that the distal end of a bit shank (not shown) does not extend into the slotted portion of the bit holder shank bore, but ceases about the slots.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">It has been found that narrowing or slightly widening the 9/16 inch wide first slot <b>41</b> does not significantly change the radial force exerted by the shank on the bit block bore when the outer diameter <b>22</b> and inner diameter <b>25</b> remain mostly constant, as much as the addition of the second slot <b>43</b>. Varying the length of the second slot allows one to fine tune the radial force. For example, a larger trenching machine bit holder will have a shorter second slot to increase the radial force of the bit holder shank on the bit holder block.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">A second or opposing enclosed end portion <b>45</b> is positioned axially adjacent, but spatially related to the chamfer <b>37</b> such that slot <b>43</b> is completely surrounded by the shank, unlike slot <b>41</b>. Slot <b>43</b> also extends across the shoulder <b>35</b> and in this embodiment is approximately <b>120</b> percent the length in the first tapered portion <b>34</b> and approximately <b>140</b> percent the length in the second tapered portion <b>36</b>. The combination of the first and second elongate slots provides for more elastic deformation in the shank than in the embodiment shown in the '326 patent, while allowing for deformation at the distal end of the shank that is not contemplated in the dual slotted embodiment of the '258 patent.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The slightly additional elastic deformation capability of the shank <b>22</b> of the current embodiment is more symmetrical in its deformation because of the dual opposing slots <b>41</b> and <b>43</b> than the radial deformation in the single slot shown in the '326 patent when it is inserted into a bit holder block bore. These concepts will be discussed in more detail below. The provision of the second slot means the beam strength, radial force and frictional force between the bit holder shank and bit holder block bore may all be adjusted as necessary to maximize the fit between the two members.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Additionally, a locator pin hole <b>97</b> extends through the side wall of shank <b>22</b> to complete the disclosure of the physical structure of the first embodiment <b>20</b> of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">On mining equipment and trenching equipment, the shank of a bit holder will be larger than that for road milling equipment and will approximate a range of 1&#xbd; to 3&#xbd; inches in nominal cylindrical diameter. These are sizes presently in use and it will be appreciated that other sizes may also be utilized within the present invention, especially as equipment having greater processing capacity is desired by end users.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref>, <b>5</b> and <b>6</b>, a first modification of the present invention, generally indicated at <b>120</b>, is constructed identically with that of the first embodiment <b>20</b> with a few exceptions. Therefore, the numbers used to indicate the various structural portions of the first embodiment are used, with the addition of the numeral 1 in front thereof (the hundreds position), to identify the identical portions of the first modification.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows a plug <b>147</b> (shown in outline) that fits in the side hole <b>30</b>, <b>130</b>, etc. of all the embodiments shown in this application. The main difference between the first embodiment <b>20</b> and the first modification <b>120</b> of the present invention is the provision of a narrow slot <b>151</b>-<b>151</b><i>a </i>(not shown) that extends from the lower terminus <b>145</b> of the internal slot <b>143</b> of the second embodiment to the distal end <b>126</b> of the shank portion <b>122</b>. In the preferred embodiment, this slot is approximately 0.035 inch wide and may be formed by a band saw or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">In operation, when a shank of a bit holder <b>120</b> is pressed into a bit block bore, both the elongate slot <b>141</b> and the slot <b>151</b>-<b>151</b><i>a </i>of the second embodiment tend to close up or become smaller. While slot <b>141</b> is sufficiently large that it will not totally close, slot <b>151</b>-<b>151</b><i>a </i>is specifically formed with sides that are closer together so that at some point during the insertion, the sides of slot <b>151</b> may become contiguous, or meet, and that side of the distal end <b>126</b> of the shank <b>122</b> will thereafter act as a solid joined member.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The preferred use for bit holders of the first modification <b>120</b> is in lower horse-power machines where the radial force necessary to retain the bit holder in the bit block is less than in the first embodiment <b>20</b>. The construction allows the insertion and removal to be accomplished with less force than the first embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">A second difference between the first embodiment <b>20</b> and the first modification <b>120</b> resides in a generally cylindrical plug <b>154</b> that is press fittable within the internal slot <b>143</b> ( 9/16 inch in this embodiment), and the elongate slot <b>141</b> if desired, and is capable of acting on the side walls of the slot to inhibit further collapsing of the diameter of the side wall of the shank at a location anywhere along the length of the slot where the plug is press fit therein. The material and hardness of the cylindrical plug <b>154</b> may be varied to achieve desired results in limiting the collapsibility of the slot <b>143</b> and therefore, the collapsibility of the bit holder shank diameter. The position of the plug <b>154</b> along the internal slot <b>141</b> may also be varied to achieve desired results.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7</figref>, <b>8</b> and <b>9</b>, a second modification of the bit holder of the present invention is shown generally at <b>220</b>. As with the first modification, the second modification is identical to that of the first embodiment <b>20</b> bit holder with a single exception being the shape and length of the second elongate internal slot <b>243</b> that is positioned diametrically opposite the elongate slot <b>241</b> in shank <b>222</b>. As with the first modification, the second modification includes the same singles and tens numerals used in the first embodiment with the addition of a numeral 2 in front of that number (the hundreds position).</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">As with the first embodiment, the internal elongate slot <b>243</b> is found completely within the bounds of generally cylindrical shank <b>222</b>. It is also preferably diametrically opposite first elongate slot <b>241</b> and in the second modification, slot <b>243</b> has generally converging elongate sides <b>243</b><i>a </i>and <b>243</b><i>b</i>. The top terminus of slot <b>244</b> is, in this preferred embodiment, the same width and shape as the top terminus <b>44</b> of the first embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The bottom internal terminus <b>245</b> of the second modification has a smaller radius than that of top terminus <b>244</b> where it meets the converging sides <b>243</b><i>a</i>, <b>243</b><i>b</i>. The use of a slot shaped as slot <b>243</b> in the second modification <b>220</b> of the bit holder provides for a stiffer second tapered portion of the bit holder shank <b>236</b> than found in the second tapered portion <b>36</b> of the first embodiment of the bit holder. In other words, by varying the width of the internal slot <b>243</b> along its length, the stiffness of the side wall of the shank may be varied in accordance with desired characteristics.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Changing the width of the internal slot as shown in the second modification may have similar effects in the second modification as putting the cylindrical press fit plug <b>154</b> in the slot <b>143</b> of the first embodiment in a position lower, more toward the distal end, of the shank.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10</figref>, <b>11</b> and <b>12</b>, and specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, a bit holder of the first embodiment <b>20</b> is shown as it appears when inserted in a bit holder block bore <b>57</b> of bit block <b>56</b> that is completely cylindrical at <b>57</b><i>a </i>with a preferred diameter of 1.509 inches, the same as the holder shank diameter after insertion, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>. Toward the bottom end of the bore and tapered outwardly at <b>57</b><i>b </i>at about a 5&#xbd; degree angle per side toward the top of the bit holder block bore <b>57</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13 and 14</figref>, the use of a slight taper in both the bit block bore <b>66</b> of bit block <b>65</b> and the outer surface of the bit holder shank <b>22</b> allows the bit holder shank to be inserted within the bit holder block bore <b>66</b> for a greater distance before contacting with mating surfaces. The tapered surface of the bit holder shank <b>22</b> contacts the bit block bore <b>66</b> in the last approximately &#x215d; inch of travel when using current dimensions for bit holder shank and bit block bore, and is fully radially collapsed the amount of designed interference therein over that short distance, rather than being pressed for the entire length of the lower cylindrical portion up to 2 inches of the bit holder block bore shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Heretofore, bit holders having a completely cylindrical lower distal end portion of its shank have not been able to be inserted in a bit holder block bore having a constant tapered bore such as at <b>66</b>, and conversely, a generally cylindrical but slightly tapered bit holder shank has not been insertable in the bit holder block bore of a bit holder block having a completely cylindrical lower portion together with a widening tapered top portion.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> shows the outer shank dimensions of the shank <b>22</b> of the first embodiment <b>20</b> at three portions along its length, measured with the bit holder in its uninserted relaxed position.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> shows those dimensions at the same shank positions as they exist when the bit holder of the first embodiment <b>20</b> is completely inserted in the bit block <b>56</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>. The use of the second internal slot <b>43</b> together with the elongate first slot <b>41</b> in preferred diametrically opposed position on the bit shank <b>22</b> enables the bit holders <b>20</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>220</b> of the present invention to be utilized in all presently similar configurations of quick change type bit holder blocks found in the industry.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">As such, purchasers and users of mining, road milling and trenching equipment utilizing such bit assemblies are not limited to the maker of the individual assemblies that were purchased with the mining, milling or trenching equipment. Replacement bit holders may be purchased by others than those who made the original equipment and may be utilized to provide, in some cases, even easier insertion and removability of the bit holders and bits in connection with using the equipment, together with longer wear life.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10</figref>, <b>11</b> and <b>12</b>, the insertion of a bit holder, such as that shown at <b>20</b>, into a bit block <b>56</b> that has both tapered <b>57</b><i>b </i>and cylindrical <b>57</b><i>a </i>portions is actually inserted and removed with less force than that used with a bit holder having a cylindrical distal end portion, as presently known. This is because the contact distance and radial exerted forces of interference are less. In the bit block <b>56</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, the cylindrical contact zone of the inserted shank <b>22</b> approximates &#xbd; inch below the step up portion <b>35</b> of shank <b>22</b>, with a &#x215b; inch space of no contact above the step up portion, and a second cylindrical zone of contact &#xbc; inch above that space. While the entire shank contact zones are not perfectly consummated, they provide sufficient radial force between the bit holder shank and bit block bore to maintain the bit holder in the bit holder block during use.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">In considering how applicant's invention works, explanation has been made referring to interference fits or press fits, which relate to fitting a solid cylinder member into a cylindrical bit holder block bore that is somewhat smaller than the outside of the solid cylinder member. However, the present invention utilizes a hollow generally cylindrical shank that has not one, but two differing slots in the side of the shank. Standards for interference fits are found in engineering handbooks, so the terms and dimensions of those standards are used as references. But no such standards exist in the engineering world for what is accomplished by the present invention, or applicant's prior inventions on this subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">In a standard press fit, or force fit class 5 in this heavy duty application, the dimensional difference of the solid cylindrical shaft and of the cylindrical bore each slightly change by thousandths of an inch to allow for the standard press fit. In applicant's invention, utilizing a hollow cylinder that is slotted, the majority of the radial deflection occurs in the weakened slotted region. As shown by experimentation, the deflection of the hollow slotted cylinder is much greater than the deflection of a solid cylinder in a standard press fit by at least 4 times as much for the same size parts to achieve the same interference holding fit. However, the goal of the present invention is similar to the goal achieved by a cylindrical standard press fit, i.e., to provide sufficient radial force between the cylinder and the bore to maintain the cylinder mounted in the bore. By utilizing dimensional differences in the slotted shank design that are much greater than that of standard cylindrical interference press fits, dimensional tolerances are increased and parts become less expensive to make. The shank of the holder or the bore of the bit holder block are not machined after hardening of these parts. Cylindrical press fit members have heretofore always been machined after hardening. Therefore, the advantages of applicant's invention are multiple-fold over prior technology involving this subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">These larger (and less expensive to produce) dimensional differences mean that changes in the above noted bit holder dimensions can be readily accomplished to provide quick change type bit holders usable in completely cylindrical bit holder block bores, and also in bit holder block bores that have other tapers, such as 3&#xbd; degrees per side. The contacting of the back face of the bit holder body to seat on the bit holder block top surface means that fully engaged seating need not take place between the holder shank and the bit holder block bore.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">A full length axial matching fit between the shank and bore is not necessary, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>. The flexible center portion of the shank side wall, as a result of the two slots, may be manipulated from an engineering standpoint to provide for retention of the bit holder in the bit holder block for numerous configurations. Additionally, the wall thickness of the central portion of the bit holder shank may be manipulated to provide differing radial force parameters in the quick change unit. For example, at least a portion of the bit holder bore adjacent the slots may be diametrically increased to increase the radial deflection and reduce the beam strength of the shank during the insertion of the bit holder shank in the bit block bore.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">As a result of the above, a forged bit holder constructed in accordance with the principles herein and in patents by the instant inventor cited herein, forged bit holders and bit holder blocks may be made without resorting to finish machining after hardening of these components. The elasticity of the shank provides a fit sufficient to maintain the bit holder in the bit holder block in heavy duty applications.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">While one embodiment, and two modifications of the present invention have been shown and described, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art that many changes and modifications may be made without departing from the true spirit and scope of the present invention. It is the intent of the appended claims to cover all such changes and modifications which fall within the true spirit and scope of the invention</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A bit holder for use in road milling, trenching and mining equipment as part of an assembly including a bit, bit holder and bit holder block, with said bit holder block having a bit holder block bore that is one of: a) cylindrical, b) non-locking tapered and c) a combination of a non-locking tapered bore on a top portion of said bit block bore and a cylindrical bore on a bottom portion of said bit holder block bore,
<claim-text>said bit holder comprising,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a front body portion and a generally cylindrical hollow shank portion extending from a rear of said front body portion,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said generally cylindrical hollow shank portion defining a thick walled annular side wall and including a first elongate slot radially through said side wall extending generally axially along said side wall from a distal end thereof and having a termination on said thick annular side wall between said distal end of said shank to a forward end of said shank,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second internal elongate slot substantially diametrically opposite said shank from said first elongate slot, said second slot extending generally axially along said thick annular side wall and varying in width along its length, with an upper termination spatially related to said rear of said front body portion, and a lower termination spatially related to said distal end of said shank,</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least portions of said shank having a free standing diametrical dimension, larger than a corresponding diametrical dimension of said bit holder block bore, and the insertion of said bit holder shank in said bit holder block bore providing sufficient outward radial force by radial deflection of said portions of said shank to retain said shank in both said bit holder block cylindrical and non-locking tapered bores during use.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A bit holder for use in road milling, trenching and mining equipment as part of an assembly including a bit, bit holder and bit holder block, said bit holder block having a bit holder block bore,
<claim-text>said bit holder comprising,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a front body portion and a generally cylindrical hollow shank portion extending from a rear of said front body portion,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said generally cylindrical hollow shank portion defining a thick walled annular side wall and including a first elongate slot through said thick side wall extending generally axially along said side wall from a distal end thereof and having a termination on said thick side wall between said distal end of said shank and said forward end of said shank,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second internal elongate slot substantially diametrically opposite said shank from said first elongate slot, said second slot extending generally axially along said thick side wall and varying in width along its length, with an upper termination spatially related to said rear of said front body portion, and a lower termination spatially related to said distal end of said shank,</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least portions of said shank having a free standing diametrical dimension that is larger than a corresponding diametrical dimension of one of a cylindrical bit holder block bore and a non-locking tapered bit holder block bore, and the insertion of said bit holder shank in said bit holder block bore providing sufficient outward radial force by radial deflection of said portions of said shank adjacent said slots to retain said shank in either of said cylindrical and non-locking tapered bit holder block bores.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
