<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626899-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626899</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12682393</doc-number>
<date>20071023</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>341</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>173</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>709224</main-classification>
<further-classification>709223</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Method and system for multicast statistic collection</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0218980</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Fukushima et al.</name>
<date>20031100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>370230</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0231629</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Banerjee et al.</name>
<date>20031200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>370390</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0090970</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Sanchez et al.</name>
<date>20040500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0129017</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Guingo et al.</name>
<date>20050600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>370390</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0007930</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Dorenbosch</name>
<date>20060100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0098668</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Dona</name>
<date>20060500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>370401</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0294259</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Matefi et al.</name>
<date>20061200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>709248</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0086570</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Dey et al.</name>
<date>20080400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>709231</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>1972223</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20070500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1542394</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20050600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>2005041456</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20050500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>2007012767</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20070200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00013">
<othercit>International Search Report for PCT/US2007/022494 dated Jul. 14, 2008 (Forms PCT/ISA/220 &#x26; PCT/ISA/210).</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00014">
<othercit>Written Opinion of the International Searching Authority for PCT/US2007/022494 (Form PCT/ISA/237).</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>709224</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>2</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20100217861</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20100826</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wu</last-name>
<first-name>Solomon</first-name>
<address>
<city>Milpitas</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wu</last-name>
<first-name>Solomon</first-name>
<address>
<city>Milpitas</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Buchanan Ingersoll &#x26; Rooney PC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Siemens Enterprise Communications, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Boca Raton</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Hee Soo</first-name>
<department>2457</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/US2007/022494</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20071023</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20100512</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2009/054824</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20090430</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A system (<b>100</b>) and method (<b>200</b>) related to gathering statistical information regarding a data stream. The method (<b>200</b>) may include sending (<b>205</b>), by a data forwarding device (<b>110</b>), an internet protocol (IP) multicast data stream to a multicast group using an internet protocol (IP); and collecting (<b>210</b>) statistical data from a router (<b>120</b><i>a</i>-<i>g</i>) down stream of the forwarding device (<b>110</b>) to determine a number of end point recipients (<b>125, 130, 135</b>) associated with the multicast group and receiving the multicast data stream.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="176.70mm" wi="131.49mm" file="US08626899-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="238.76mm" wi="147.91mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626899-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="194.48mm" wi="134.45mm" file="US08626899-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is the United States national phase under 35 U.S.C. &#xa7;371 of PCT International Application No. PCT/US2007/022494, filed on Oct. 23, 2007. That application is incorporated by reference herein.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Embodiments may generally relate to methods and systems of multicasting. More particularly, some embodiments are concerned with collecting statistical data regarding recipients of multicast data streams.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Multicasting of video may provide a mechanism to deliver video to a number of recipients simultaneously, creating copies of the data stream only where necessary. Multicasting may be used to broadcast media presentations in commercial, entertainment, and educational contexts. In some environments, a broadcast may be supported by or based on the number of recipients that receive the broadcast. These environments may include advertisement support commercial broadcasts, as well as educational and enterprise training scenarios where the institution or service organization rendering training services may need an accurate accounting of the entities receiving the video training</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">As such, there exist a need for a system, method, and computer executable program for collecting statistical data regarding recipients of multicast data streams.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Some embodiments provide a system, method, device, program code and/or means to gather statistical information regarding a multicast data stream. The method may include sending, by a data forwarding device, an internet protocol (IP) multicast data stream to a multicast group using an internet protocol (IP); and collecting statistical data from a router down stream of the forwarding device to determine a number of end point recipients associated with the multicast group and receiving the multicast data stream.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">A system according to embodiments herein may include a data forwarding device to send an IP multicast data stream to a multicast group using an internet protocol (IP); a router down stream of the forwarding device to route the multicast data stream the multicast group; and a collection device to collect statistical data from the down stream router to determine a number of end point recipients associated with the multicast group and receiving the multicast data stream.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In some embodiments, a medium having machine executable program instructions stored thereon includes instructions to send, by a data forwarding device, an internet protocol (IP) multicast data stream to a multicast group using an internet protocol (IP); and instructions to collect statistical data from a router down stream of the forwarding device to determine a number of end point recipients associated with the multicast group and receiving the multicast data stream.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">With these and other advantages and features that will become hereinafter apparent, further information may be obtained by reference to the following detailed description and appended claims, and to the figures attached hereto.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Some embodiments are illustrated in the accompanying figures, in which like reference numerals designate like parts, and wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a representative block diagram of a system, according to some embodiments herein; and</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a flow diagram of a process, according to some embodiments.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an illustrative block diagram of system <b>100</b> according to some embodiments herein. System <b>100</b> may be provided to deliver, facilitate, improve, or enhance a multicast broadcast according to some embodiments. In some other embodiments, system <b>100</b> may include or be interfaced with a media source <b>105</b>, an encoder <b>110</b>, a data collection device <b>112</b>, a transport network <b>115</b>, and recipients <b>125</b><i>a</i>-<b>125</b><i>n</i>, <b>130</b>, <b>135</b>. Media source <b>105</b> may include live broadcasts, recorded presentations, store and forward broadcast, and other techniques and methods applicable for providing various forms of multimedia data. The multimedia data may be captured, obtained, or otherwise acquired for multicast broadcast in accordance with other aspects herein using a number of different techniques. For example, media source <b>105</b> may be video obtained using analog and video capture equipment, including standard definition and high definition processes, television broadcasts, and satellite communications.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The multimedia data obtained from video source <b>105</b> may be encoded to distribute video to end recipients <b>125</b><i>a</i>-<i>n</i>, <b>130</b>, <b>135</b>. Encoder <b>110</b> may be capable of processing and encoding various types and protocols of video signals, including but not limited to MPEG-4 data, a video coding standard by the ISO/IEC Moving Picture Experts Group (MPEG) under the formal standard ISO/IEC 14496.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In some embodiments herein, internet protocol (IP) data packets are multicast to multiple recipient destinations by encoder <b>110</b>. A single copy of the data stream from media source <b>105</b> is forwarded to a group of recipients using a single IP address for the group, in accordance with multicast protocols and techniques. Data addressed to the single multicast group IP address is forwarded to each of a group interested recipients. Routers (e.g. <b>120</b><i>a</i>-<b>120</b><i>g</i>) may be used to route the data the recipients <b>125</b><i>a</i>-<i>n</i>, <b>130</b>, <b>135</b>. Using standardized multicast IP addressing protocols, a multicast group identifying the set of recipients interested in receiving a particular data stream may be represented by a single address according to a defined standard. Recipients interested in receiving the multicast data stream may join a multicast group using standard IP protocols that manage membership of the multicast group(s). Multicast group membership discovery protocols herein may include, for example, Internet Group Management Protocol (IGMP), Multicast Listener Discovery (MLD), multicast of ATM (Asynchronous Transfer Mode), and others.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In accordance with embodiments herein, a multicast broadcast may use multicast addressing protocols that are now known and those that become known, multicast group membership discovery protocols that are now known and those that become known, and multicast routing protocols that are now known and those that become known. In some embodiments, the multicast routing protocols may include protocol independent Multicast Sparse Mode (PIM-SM), Protocol Independent Multicast Dense Mode (PIM-DM), and Distance Vector Multicast Routing Protocol (DVMRP). In some embodiments, a multicast routing protocol may generate a tree of recipients to indicate the recipients belonging to the multicast group(s).</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">It should be appreciated that a multicast group herein may include one, more, or none of the recipients <b>125</b><i>a</i>-<i>n</i>, <b>130</b>, <b>135</b>. It is also noted that more than one recipient may be connected to any one of routers <b>120</b><i>a</i>-<i>g</i>. That is, a plurality of recipients may be interfaced with any one of routers <b>120</b>. For example, televisions <b>125</b><i>a</i>-<b>125</b><i>n </i>may form a multicast group and are connected to router <b>120</b><i>e</i>. A single multicast data stream (e.g., a movie broadcast) may be forwarded from encoder <b>110</b> via routers <b>120</b><i>a </i>and <b>120</b><i>b </i>to router <b>120</b><i>e</i>. At router <b>120</b><i>e</i>, the multicast data stream may be duplicated (as needed) and sent to each of the recipient televisions <b>125</b><i>a</i>-<i>n </i>belonging to the multicast group.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">It is noted that recipient televisions <b>125</b><i>a</i>-<b>125</b><i>n </i>may include one or more recipient devices. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> depicts only two such recipient devices, as a matter of clarity and not as a limitation. Similarly, additional recipient devices <b>130</b> may be connected to, for example, router <b>120</b><i>g </i>and additional recipient devices <b>135</b> may be connected to, for example, router <b>120</b><i>c. </i></p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">It should also be understood that while routers <b>120</b><i>a</i>-<i>g </i>are shown as a network of routers, other network and interconnection topographies and arrangements may be provided. For example, the routers <b>120</b><i>a</i>-<i>g </i>may include more or fewer routing devices, be arranged in different configurations, and the connections between them (if any) may be provided on an ad hoc, selective, predetermined, variable, or reconfigurable basis. Thus, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an example of a system embodiment provided to clearly illustrate various aspects of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In some embodiments, encoder <b>110</b>, though effective in encoding the multicast data stream, does not provide an efficient manner for accounting for or determining the specific recipients of the multicast broadcast. In some embodiments the IP protocols used, including the use and delivery of the multicast data stream to a single multicast group address precludes determining the number of eventual recipients of the multicast data stream at encoder <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In some embodiments herein, data is collected from routers (e.g., <b>120</b><i>a</i>-<i>g</i>) downstream of encoder <b>110</b> that forwards the data stream to a designated multicast group address over network <b>115</b> for delivery to the multicast group(s) recipients by data collection device <b>112</b>. In accord with embodiments herein, routers located downstream of encoder <b>110</b> and prior to recipients <b>125</b><i>a</i>-<i>n</i>, <b>130</b>, <b>135</b> may be polled, queried, monitored, or otherwise viewed for the collection of data processed or available at the specific router to determine, for example, the number of recipients receiving a multicast broadcast. Aspects of the multicast addressing, multicast group membership discovery protocols, and multicast routing protocols may be leveraged to determine the number of recipients receiving the multicast data stream packets.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In some embodiments, information regarding a network address receiving the multicast data stream packets may be collected by data collection device <b>112</b> and used in the determinations herein. In some embodiments, information regarding a subnet address receiving the multicast data stream packets may be collected and used in the determinations herein.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In some embodiments, a router closest to the recipients of the multicast data stream may provide the data collected in the data collections herein. For example, router <b>120</b><i>c </i>may provide data relating to a recipient connected thereto (e.g., host <b>135</b>), router <b>120</b><i>e </i>may provide data relating to recipient <b>125</b><i>a</i>-<i>n </i>(e.g., televisions throughout an office park), and router <b>120</b><i>g </i>may provide data relating to a smartphone <b>135</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a flow diagram of process <b>200</b> according to some embodiments. Process <b>200</b> may be executed by system <b>100</b> using any suitable hardware and/or software arrangement, and may be executed by any suitable device or devices that are now known or become known.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">At operation <b>205</b>, a method for gathering statistical information regarding a data stream is facilitated by sending an IP multicast data stream to a multicast group using an Internet protocol (IP) by a data forwarding device. As discussed above, this aspect of the method may be accomplished by encoder <b>110</b>. In other embodiments, a device separate and distinct from encoder <b>110</b> may be used to provided the requisite functionality in connection with process <b>200</b>. That is, the forwarding device may be part of or separate from encoder <b>110</b>. It is also noted that the forwarding device may be implemented in hardware, software, and combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">At operation <b>210</b>, a process of collecting statistical data from a router down stream of the forwarding device to determine a number of end point recipients associated with the multicast group and receiving the multicast data stream is accomplished. This aspect of the method may be accomplished by data collection device <b>112</b>. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, routers <b>120</b><i>a</i>-<i>g </i>actively involved in the delivery of the multicast data stream to the particular recipients (e.g., <b>125</b><i>a</i>-<i>n</i>, <b>130</b>, <b>135</b>) may have data collected therefrom.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The collected data may be further processed and analyzed to ascertain statistical data regarding the recipients of the multicast data stream. The forwarding device (e.g., encoder <b>110</b>) may, in cooperation with data collection device <b>112</b>, be involved with some, none, or all of the collected data analysis and processing. In some embodiments, the data collection device <b>112</b> is separate and distinct, functionally and physically, from the forwarding device.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In some embodiments, the methods and systems disclosed herein may be implemented by a combination of hardware and software components. In some aspects, the methods and systems may be accomplished, at least in part, using computing processors to execute computer code and program instructions stored on a memory (e.g., flash memory, RAM, ROM, disk drive, and other media) or otherwise accessible by the processor.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Embodiments described above are not intended to be limited to the specific form set forth herein, but are intended to cover such alternatives, modifications and equivalents as can reasonably be included within the spirit and scope of the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method for gathering statistical information regarding a data stream, the method comprising:
<claim-text>sending by an encoder device the data stream received from a media source such that the sent data stream is forwarded over a network of routers for delivery to multicast group recipients, the data stream being an internet protocol multicast data stream sent via an internet protocol by the encoder device to a multicast group comprising the multicast group recipients, the multicast group recipients being end point devices, the encoder device not being one of the routers and not being a router;</claim-text>
<claim-text>collecting statistical data by a data collection device from routers of the network downstream of the encoder device that are actively involved in delivery of the data stream to the multicast group recipients to determine a number of recipients of the multicast group that received the multicast data stream wherein each of the routers are polled, queried, monitored, or otherwise viewed for the collection of data processed or available at that router, the data collection device not being one of the routers; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>processing and analyzing the collected data to ascertain statistical data regarding the recipients of the multicast data stream to determine a number of end point recipients associated with the multicast group recipients that received the data stream, wherein the encoder device in cooperation with the data collection device are involved with some or all of the collected data analysis and processing and wherein the data forwarding device and the data collection device are arranged outside of the network of routers.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein an end point device recipient joining the multicast group sends a message to the downstream routers using a multicast group membership discovery protocol.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the data collection device is a component of the encoder device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the collecting of statistical data from the routers is based, at least in part, on a multicast distribution tree of recipients.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the collected statistical data is comprised of at least one of subnet addresses and network addresses of end point devices that received the data stream.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the encoder device in cooperation with the data collection device are involved with all of the collected data analysis and processing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the encoder device in cooperation with the data collection device are involved with only some of the collected data analysis and processing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A system for gathering statistical information regarding a data stream, the system comprising:
<claim-text>a data forwarding device for forwarding the data stream from a media source over a network of routers for delivery to multicast group recipients, the data stream being sent as an internet protocol multicast data stream to a multicast group using an internet protocol, the multicast group comprising the multicast group recipients, the multicast group recipients comprising end point devices, the data forwarding device not being a router;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of routers of the network downstream of the forwarding device to route the multicast data stream to the multicast group; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a collection device to collect statistical data from the routers actively involved in delivery of the data stream to the multicast group recipients to determine a number of recipients that received the multicast data stream, each of the routers being polled, queried, monitored, or otherwise viewed for the collection of data processed or available at the router, the collection device not being one of the routers; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the forwarding device in cooperation with the collection device being involved with some or all of the collected data analysis and processing of that collected data to ascertain statistical data regarding recipients of the multicast data stream to determine a number of end point recipients associated with the multicast group recipients that received the data stream and wherein the data forwarding device and data collection device are arranged outside of the network of routers.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the forwarding device is an encoder device and the collection device is a component of the encoder device and wherein the encoder device in cooperation with the collection device being involved with all of the collected data analysis and processing of that collected data to ascertain statistical data regarding recipients of the multicast data stream.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the forwarding device is an encoder device and the collection device is a component of the encoder device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the collecting of statistical data from the first router downstream is based, at least in part, on a multicast distribution tree of recipients.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the collected statistical data is comprised of at least one of subnet addresses and network addresses of end point devices that received the data stream.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the collection device is a component of the forwarding device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the forwarding device in cooperation with the collection device are involved with all of the collected data analysis and processing of that collected data to ascertain statistical data regarding recipients of the multicast data stream.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the multicast data stream is one of: (a) video obtained using analog or video capture equipment, (b) satellite communications, and (c) television broadcasts.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the multicast data stream is one of: (a) video obtained using analog or video capture equipment, (b) satellite communications, and (c) at least one television broadcast.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the data collection device is upstream of the at least one router of the network from which the data collection device collects statistical data.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> wherein the collection device is upstream of the first router of the network.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A method for gathering statistical information regarding a data stream, the method comprising:
<claim-text>sending by an encoder device the data stream received from a media source such that the sent data stream is forwarded over a network of routers for delivery to multicast group recipients, the data stream being an internet protocol multicast data stream sent via an internet protocol by the encoder device to a multicast group comprising the multicast group recipients, the multicast group recipients being end point devices;</claim-text>
<claim-text>collecting statistical data by a data collection device from the routers of the network downstream of the encoder device that are actively involved in delivery of the data stream to the multicast group recipients to determine a number of recipients of the multicast group that received the multicast data stream, wherein each of the routers is polled, queried, monitored, or otherwise viewed for the collection of data processed or available at the router and wherein the data collection device and the encoder are outside of the network of routers; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>processing and analyzing the collected data to ascertain statistical data regarding the recipients of the multicast data stream to determine a number of end point recipients associated with the multicast group recipients that receive the data stream, wherein the encoder device in cooperation with the data collection device are involved with all of the collected data analysis and processing.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref> wherein the data collection device is a component of the encoder device.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
