<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623756-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623756</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13167257</doc-number>
<date>20110623</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>288</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>21</main-group>
<subgroup>283</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438614</main-classification>
<further-classification>438613</further-classification>
<further-classification>257E21159</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Reflow system and method for conductive connections</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0089983</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>MacKay et al.</name>
<date>20100400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>228256</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0285015</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Song et al.</name>
<date>20111100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257737</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>16</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438613</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438614</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E21159</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>7</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120329264</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121227</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chuang</last-name>
<first-name>Chita</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wu</last-name>
<first-name>Sheng-Yu</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsin-Chu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kuo</last-name>
<first-name>Tin-Hao</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsin-Chu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="004" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tsai</last-name>
<first-name>Pei-Chun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Zhongli</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="005" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cheng</last-name>
<first-name>Ming-Da</first-name>
<address>
<city>Jhubei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="006" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chen</last-name>
<first-name>Chen-Shien</first-name>
<address>
<city>Zhubei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chuang</last-name>
<first-name>Chita</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wu</last-name>
<first-name>Sheng-Yu</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsin-Chu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kuo</last-name>
<first-name>Tin-Hao</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsin-Chu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="004" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tsai</last-name>
<first-name>Pei-Chun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Zhongli</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="005" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cheng</last-name>
<first-name>Ming-Da</first-name>
<address>
<city>Jhubei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="006" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chen</last-name>
<first-name>Chen-Shien</first-name>
<address>
<city>Zhubei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Slater &#x26; Matsil, L.L.P.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company, Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Hsin-Chu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Ghyka</last-name>
<first-name>Alexander</first-name>
<department>2812</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Isaac</last-name>
<first-name>Stanetta</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A system and method for forming conductive connections is disclosed. An embodiment comprises forming conductive material on to contacts of a semiconductor substrate. The semiconductor substrate is then inverter such that the conductive material is beneath the semiconductor substrate, and the conductive material is reflowed to form a conductive bump. The reflow is performed using gravity in order to form a more uniform shape for the conductive bump.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="107.95mm" wi="216.07mm" file="US08623756-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="210.48mm" wi="181.19mm" file="US08623756-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="235.03mm" wi="200.24mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623756-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="229.53mm" wi="181.19mm" file="US08623756-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="218.02mm" wi="124.63mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623756-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">Conductive pillars may be formed on a semiconductor substrate in order to provide a physical and electrical connection for external connectors. These conductive pillars are generally formed through a top passivation layer of the semiconductor substrate, thereby providing an external connection to the active devices formed on the semiconductor substrate. The conductive pillars are formed through typical photolithographic and masking processes, and provide a surface for a conductive bump to be connected.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The conductive bump may be formed on the conductive pillars from a connecting material such as solder. Typically, the connective material may be placed onto the conductive pillars and then heated such that the connective material may partially liquefy and reflow into a bump shape due to the surface tension of the liquefied connective material. Once formed, the conductive bump may then be placed into contact with a separate substrate such as, for example, a printed circuit board or else another semiconductor substrate. After the conductive bump has been placed in contact, the conductive bump may again be reflowed in order to bond the conductive bump to the separate substrate, thereby providing not only an electrical connection between the semiconductor substrate and the separate substrate, but also providing a bonding mechanism between the semiconductor substrate and the separate substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">However, the reflow process generally proceeds with the conductive material being on top of the conductive pillar. As such, once the conductive material begins to liquefy, the force of gravity can interfere with the surface tension. This interference can result in a distortion of the bump as the force of gravity pulls the conductive material downwards against the conductive pillar, thereby distorting the overall bump shape.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">For a more complete understanding of embodiments, and the advantages thereof, reference is now made to the following descriptions taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a semiconductor wafer with active devices, a passivation layer, and conductive pillars in accordance with an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates the formation of conductive caps onto the conductive pillars in accordance with an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates the placement of the semiconductor wafer into a physical chuck in accordance with an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates the inversion of the chuck and the semiconductor wafer in accordance with an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates a reflow process to form conductive bumps in accordance with an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates an embodiment in which a vacuum chuck is utilized to maneuver the semiconductor wafer in accordance with an embodiment; and</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates the bonding of the semiconductor wafer with an external device in accordance with an embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Corresponding numerals and symbols in the different figures generally refer to corresponding parts unless otherwise indicated. The figures are drawn to clearly illustrate the relevant aspects of the embodiments and are not necessarily drawn to scale.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF ILLUSTRATIVE EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The making and using of embodiments are discussed in detail below. It should be appreciated, however, that the embodiments provides many applicable inventive concepts that can be embodied in a wide variety of specific contexts. The specific embodiments discussed are merely illustrative, and do not limit the scope of the embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The embodiments will be described with respect to embodiments in a specific context, namely a conductive bump connector for a semiconductor die. The embodiments may also be applied, however, to other conductive connections.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, there is shown a semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> onto which conductive bumps <b>501</b> (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> but illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> below) are desired to be formed. The semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> has a substrate <b>101</b>, active devices <b>103</b>, metallization layers <b>105</b>, a passivation layer <b>107</b> and a series of conductive pillars <b>109</b>. The substrate <b>101</b> may comprise bulk silicon, doped or undoped, or an active layer of a silicon-on-insulator (SOI) substrate. Generally, an SOI substrate comprises a layer of a semiconductor material such as silicon, germanium, silicon germanium, SOI, silicon germanium on insulator (SGOI), or combinations thereof. Other substrates that may be used include multi-layered substrates, gradient substrates, or hybrid orientation substrates.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The active devices <b>103</b> are represented in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> as a single transistor. However, as one of skill in the art will recognize, a wide variety of active devices such as capacitors, resistors, inductors and the like may be used to generate the desired structural and functional requirements of the design for the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b>. The active devices <b>103</b> may be formed using any suitable methods either within or else on the surface of the substrate <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The metallization layers <b>105</b> are formed over the substrate <b>101</b> and the active devices <b>103</b> and are designed to connect the various active devices <b>103</b> to form functional circuitry. While illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> as a single layer, the metallization layers <b>105</b> are formed of alternating layers of dielectric and conductive material and may be formed through any suitable process (such as deposition, damascene, dual damascene, etc.). In an embodiment there may be four layers of metallization separated from the substrate <b>101</b> by at least one interlayer dielectric layer (ILD), but the precise number of metallization layers <b>105</b> is dependent upon the design of the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The passivation layer <b>107</b> may be formed on the metallization layers <b>105</b> over the active devices <b>103</b> in order to provide protection from physical and environmental harm that exposure may cause. The passivation layer <b>107</b> may be made of one or more suitable dielectric materials such as a polymer, silicon oxide, silicon nitride, low-k dielectrics such as carbon doped oxides, extremely low-k dielectrics such as porous carbon doped silicon dioxide, combinations of these, or the like. The passivation layer <b>107</b> may be formed through a process such as chemical vapor deposition (CVD), although any suitable process may be utilized, and may have a thickness between about 0.5 &#x3bc;m and about 5 &#x3bc;m, such as about 9.25 K&#x212b;.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The conductive pillars <b>109</b> may be formed to provide conductive regions for contact between the metallization layers <b>105</b> and an external device <b>701</b> (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> but illustrated and discussed below with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>) such as printed circuit boards or other semiconductor dies in, e.g., a flip-chip arrangement. The pillar process may be formed by initially forming a first photoresist (not shown) over the passivation layer <b>107</b>, and then patterning the first photoresist to expose portions of the passivation layer <b>107</b>. Once patterned, the first photoresist may then be used as a mask to remove the desired portions of the passivation layer <b>107</b>, thereby exposing those portions of the underlying metallization layers <b>105</b> to which the conductive pillars <b>109</b> will make contact.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">After the passivation layer <b>107</b> has been patterned, the first photoresist may be removed and a second photoresist may be formed and patterned in the desired shape of the conductive pillars <b>109</b>. Conductive materials may be deposited to form the conductive pillars <b>109</b> within the openings of both the passivation layer <b>107</b> as well as the second photoresist. The conductive pillars <b>109</b> may be formed from a conductive material such as copper, although other conductive materials such as nickel, titanium (Ti), vanadium (V), or aluminum (Al), combinations of these, and the like may also be used. Additionally, the conductive pillars <b>109</b> may be formed using a process such as electroplating, by a combination of current and immersion within a solution deposit, e.g., copper within the openings in order to fill and/or overfill the openings of the conductive pillar photoresist and the passivation layer <b>107</b>, thereby forming the conductive pillars <b>109</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">After the conductive pillars <b>109</b> have been formed, the photoresist may be removed through a process such as ashing, whereby the temperature of the photoresist is increased until the photoresist decomposes and may be removed. After the removal of the photoresist, the conductive pillars <b>109</b> extend away from the passivation layer <b>107</b> a distance D<sub>1 </sub>of between about 5 &#x3bc;m to about 70 &#x3bc;m, such as about 40 &#x3bc;m. Optionally, a barrier layer (not shown) may be formed over the conductive pillars <b>109</b>, for example, by electroless plating, wherein the barrier layer may be formed of nickel, vanadium (V), chromium (Cr), and combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">However, as one of ordinary skill in the art will recognize, the above described process to form the conductive pillars <b>109</b> is merely one such description, and is not meant to limit the embodiments to this exact process. Rather, the described process is intended to be merely illustrative, and any other suitable process for forming the conductive pillars <b>109</b> may alternatively be utilized. All suitable processes are fully intended to be included within the scope of the present embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates a cross-sectional view of the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> after a conductive material <b>201</b> has been formed onto the conductive pillars <b>109</b>. The conductive material <b>201</b> may comprise a material such as tin, or other suitable materials, such as silver, lead-free tin, or copper. In an embodiment in which the conductive material <b>201</b> is tin, the conductive material <b>201</b> may be formed by initially forming a layer of tin through such commonly used methods such as evaporation, electroplating, printing, etc., to a thickness of between about 10 &#x3bc;m and about 30 &#x3bc;m, such as about 20 &#x3bc;m.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates the placement of the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> into a physical chuck <b>301</b> for further processing. In an embodiment the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> may be placed onto a bottom portion <b>303</b> of a physical chuck <b>301</b> with the conductive pillars <b>109</b> facing away from the bottom portion <b>303</b>. A top portion <b>305</b> of the physical chuck <b>301</b> may then be connected to the bottom portion <b>303</b> of the physical chuck <b>301</b>, with the top portion <b>305</b> of the physical chuck <b>301</b> overlying and protecting edges of the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> while also providing a sufficient grip to hold the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b>. A series of one or more seals (not shown) may be used to ensure an adequate seal between the physical chuck <b>301</b> and the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates that, once the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> has been placed into and secured by the physical chuck <b>301</b>, the physical chuck <b>301</b> and the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> may be inverted such that the conductive material <b>201</b> hangs from the conductive pillars <b>109</b>. The inversion may be achieved by simply applying a rotational force to the physical chuck <b>301</b>, which thereby also rotates the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b>. In an embodiment, the physical chuck <b>301</b> and the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> are inverted into a position such that the top surface of the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> is parallel with the ground (represented in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> by the dashed box <b>401</b>) and perpendicular to the pull of gravity (represented in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> by the arrow <b>403</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates that once the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> and physical chuck <b>301</b> have been inverted, a reflow process may be performed to transform the conductive material <b>201</b> into conductive bumps <b>501</b>. In the reflow process the temperature of the conductive material <b>201</b> is raised to a temperature of between about 200&#xb0; C. and about 270&#xb0; C., such as about 240&#xb0; C. for a time of between about 30 seconds and about 150 seconds, such as 90 seconds, in order to at least partially liquefy the conductive material <b>201</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Once liquefied, the surface tension of the conductive material <b>201</b> will pull the conductive material <b>201</b> into a bump shape. Additionally, in an embodiment the force of gravity <b>403</b>, instead of distorting the conductive material <b>201</b> onto the surface of the conductive pillars <b>109</b> and flattening the conductive bumps <b>501</b> as they form, actually applies a force and pulls the conductive material <b>201</b> away from the surface of the conductive pillars <b>109</b>. By reversing this applied force from the force of gravity, the shape of the conductive bumps <b>501</b> forms a more uniform shape.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates another embodiment in which the physical chuck <b>301</b> is replaced with a vacuum chuck <b>601</b>. The vacuum chuck <b>601</b>, instead of relying upon the top portion <b>305</b> of the physical chuck <b>301</b> to apply pressure to hold the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> to the physical chuck <b>301</b>, instead utilizes a difference in pressure to hold the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> to the vacuum chuck <b>601</b>. As an example, the vacuum chuck <b>601</b> may be applied to the back side of the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b>. The vacuum chuck <b>601</b> may then reduce the air pressure against the back side of the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> using a vacuum pump <b>603</b> to pull a vacuum.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The reduced air pressure on the back side of the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> generates an imbalance of pressures between the back side of the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> and the front side of the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b>. This imbalance of pressures generates a net force on the front side of the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> which will hold the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> against the vacuum chuck <b>601</b>. This force then allows the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> to be moved and manipulated by moving and manipulating the vacuum chuck <b>601</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Once the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> has been placed against the vacuum chuck <b>601</b>, the vacuum chuck <b>601</b> and semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> may be inverted and the conductive material <b>201</b> reflowed as described above with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. As an example, the vacuum chuck <b>601</b> and the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> may be inverted such that the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> is perpendicular with the pull of gravity, the conductive material <b>201</b> may be reflowed, and the pull of gravity helps the conductive material <b>201</b> to form the desired bump shape instead of being pulled down onto the conductive pillars <b>109</b>. As such, a more uniform bump shape is formed by using the pull of gravity instead of fighting the pull of gravity.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates a bonding of the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> to an external device <b>701</b>. The external device <b>701</b> may be a semiconductor die connected to the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> in a die-to-wafer bonding configuration, and the external device <b>701</b> may have external substrate <b>703</b>, external active devices <b>705</b>, external metallization layers <b>707</b>, an external passivation layer <b>709</b>, and external conductive pillars <b>711</b>. However, the external device <b>701</b> is not limited to another semiconductor die, and may include other devices, such as a printed circuit board, a packaging substrate, or any other suitable device that provides a desired connection to the conductive pillars <b>109</b> through the conductive bumps <b>501</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In an embodiment in which the external device <b>701</b> is similar to the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b>, the conductive bumps <b>501</b> (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> but illustrated and described above with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) are aligned and placed in physical and electrical contact to the external conductive pillars <b>711</b> on the external substrate <b>703</b>. Once the conductive bumps <b>501</b> are in physical contact with the external conductive pillars <b>711</b>, a bonding process may be performed. The bonding process may include raising the temperature of the conductive bumps <b>501</b> so as to again reflow the conductive bumps <b>501</b> while simultaneously applying a pressure. The reflow allows the conductive bumps <b>501</b> to bond to the external conductive pillars <b>711</b>, thereby bonding the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> to the external device <b>701</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Alternatively, the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> may be singulated prior to bonding with the external device <b>701</b>. For example, the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> may be sawed into a plurality of individual semiconductor dies (not explicitly shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>) that each have one or more of the conductive bumps <b>501</b>. After the semiconductor wafer <b>100</b> has been singulated into one or more semiconductor dies, the semiconductor dies may be bonded to other external devices <b>701</b>, such as another semiconductor die. The bonding process may be performed similar to the process described above with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, with the conductive bumps <b>501</b> being aligned with the external conductive pillars <b>711</b> and a reflow process being performed. This bonding process and any other suitable bonding process may alternatively be utilized, and all such bonding processes are fully intended to be included within the scope of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">By forming the conductive bumps <b>501</b> in conjunction with the force of gravity instead of forming the conductive bumps <b>501</b> against gravity, the conductive bumps <b>501</b> are formed in a more uniform shape. This more uniform shape helps during the bonding process to avoid bridges and gaps that might otherwise occur. As such, a higher yield of bonded products may be attained.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In accordance with an embodiment, a method comprising providing a conductive material attached to a first surface of a semiconductor substrate, the semiconductor substrate overlying the conductive material, is provided. The conductive material is reflowed such that the conductive material is pulled in a first direction that is away from the semiconductor substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In accordance with another embodiment, a method comprising forming a conductive material on a contact of a semiconductor substrate is provided. The semiconductor substrate is positioned such that the conductive material hangs from the contact, and the conductive material is reflowed to form conductive bumps while the conductive material hangs from the contact.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In accordance with yet another embodiment, a method comprising forming a conductive material on a contact of a semiconductor substrate is provided. The semiconductor substrate is placed on a chuck and the chuck is used to position the semiconductor substrate such that gravity is pulling the conductive material in a direction away from the contact. The conductive material is reflowed while gravity is pulling the conductive material in a direction away from the contact, the reflowing the conductive material forming a conductive bump.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Although the embodiments and their advantages have been described in detail, it should be understood that various changes, substitutions and alterations can be made herein without departing from the spirit and scope of the embodiments as defined by the appended claims. For example, the precise type of equipment to be utilized in the handling of the semiconductor wafer may be varied. Additionally, different materials for the conductive pillars and the conductive material may alternatively be utilized in the formation of the conductive bumps.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Moreover, the scope of the present application is not intended to be limited to the particular embodiments of the process, machine, manufacture, composition of matter, means, methods and steps described in the specification. As one of ordinary skill in the art will readily appreciate from the disclosure of the present embodiments, processes, machines, manufacture, compositions of matter, means, methods, or steps, presently existing or later to be developed, that perform substantially the same function or achieve substantially the same result as the corresponding embodiments described herein may be utilized according to the present embodiments. Accordingly, the appended claims are intended to include within their scope such processes, machines, manufacture, compositions of matter, means, methods, or steps.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method comprising:
<claim-text>providing a conductive material attached to a first surface of a semiconductor substrate, the semiconductor substrate overlying the conductive material; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>placing the semiconductor substrate into a chuck, wherein the chuck comprises a bottom portion adjacent a second surface of the semiconductor substrate and a top portion adjacent to the first surface of the semiconductor substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>reflowing the conductive material such that the conductive material is pulled in a first direction that is away from the semiconductor substrate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the conductive material is solder.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising inverting the chuck such that the semiconductor substrate is between the chuck and a ground.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the chuck is a vacuum chuck.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first direction is perpendicular to the first surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the providing the conductive material further comprises:
<claim-text>forming a conductive pillar on the semiconductor substrate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming the conductive material onto the conductive pillar.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A method comprising:
<claim-text>forming a conductive material on a contact of a semiconductor substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>placing the semiconductor substrate into a chuck, wherein the chuck comprises a first portion adjacent to a first surface of the semiconductor substrate and a second portion adjacent to a second surface of the semiconductor substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning the semiconductor substrate such that the conductive material hangs from the contact; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>reflowing the conductive material to form conductive bumps while the conductive material hangs from the contact.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the positioning the semiconductor substrate further comprises positioning the conductive material such that gravity applies a force to the conductive material, the force being directed away from the contact.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>contacting the conductive bumps to an external substrate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>reflowing the conductive bumps to bond the contact to the external substrate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the conductive material is solder.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the contact is located on a first surface of the semiconductor substrate, and wherein the chuck comprises a portion that overlies the first surface of the semiconductor substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the chuck is a vacuum chuck.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A method comprising:
<claim-text>forming a conductive material on a contact of a semiconductor substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>placing the semiconductor substrate onto a first portion of the chuck;</claim-text>
<claim-text>attaching a second portion of the chuck to the first portion of the chuck, wherein the second portion of the chuck is adjacent to the semiconductor substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>using the chuck to position the semiconductor substrate such that gravity is pulling the conductive material in a direction away from the contact; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>reflowing the conductive material while gravity is pulling the conductive material in a direction away from the contact, the reflowing the conductive material forming a conductive bump.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the chuck is a vacuum chuck.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the conductive material is solder.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>contacting a second substrate to the conductive bump; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>reflowing the conductive bump to bond the contact to the second substrate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
