<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624410-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624410</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13141057</doc-number>
<date>20091218</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>FR</country>
<doc-number>08 58836</doc-number>
<date>20081219</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>84</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>17</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>290  1A</main-classification>
<further-classification> 60651</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Electricity generation device with several heat pumps in series</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4724679</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Radermacher</name>
<date>19880200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 62101</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5042259</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Jones</name>
<date>19910800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 62 462</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0076639</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Shirk</name>
<date>20050400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0127657</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Fang et al.</name>
<date>20080600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 62 79</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>3433366</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19860300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>19925257</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20010200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>102004006837</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20050800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>GB</country>
<doc-number>2016668</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19790900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00009">
<othercit>International Search Report and Written Opinion, International Application No. PCT/FR2009/052615 dated Mar. 21, 2011.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>12</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-exemplary-claim>12</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>290  1 A</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>415916</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 62476</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 62499</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>16510412</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>165112</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>165480</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>1</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>1</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110309635</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20111222</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sardo</last-name>
<first-name>Alberto</first-name>
<address>
<city>Chateaurenard</city>
<country>FR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>FR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sardo</last-name>
<first-name>Alberto</first-name>
<address>
<city>Chateaurenard</city>
<country>FR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Knobbe Martens Olson &#x26; Bear, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Xeda International</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Saint Andiol</city>
<country>FR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Denion</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas</first-name>
<department>3748</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Mian</last-name>
<first-name>Shafiq</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/FR2009/052615</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20091218</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20110908</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2010/070242</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20100624</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The device for generating electricity (<b>1</b>) comprises:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0002-0001" num="0000">a first heat pump (<b>3</b>) provided with a first closed circuit (<b>15</b>) in which a first heat-transfer fluid circulates, and with a first heat exchanger (<b>17</b>) between the first heat-transfer fluid and a flow of atmospheric air in which the flow of atmospheric air transfers a quantity of heat to the first heat-transfer fluid,</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0002" num="0000">at least a second heat pump (<b>5</b>), provided with a second closed circuit (<b>23</b>) in which a second heat-transfer fluid circulates, and with a second heat exchanger (<b>25</b>) between the second heat-transfer fluid and a third heat-transfer fluid in which the second heat-transfer fluid transfers a quantity of heat to the third heat-transfer fluid;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0003" num="0000">means for transferring a quantity of heat from the first heat-transfer fluid to the second heat-transfer fluid;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0004" num="0000">a third closed circuit (<b>9</b>), in which the third heat-transfer fluid circulates;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0005" num="0000">a turbine (<b>11</b>) inserted on the third closed circuit (<b>9</b>) and driven by the third heat-transfer fluid;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0006" num="0000">an electric generator (<b>13</b>), mechanically driven by the turbine (<b>11</b>).</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="168.32mm" wi="233.85mm" file="US08624410-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="233.34mm" wi="169.50mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624410-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The invention generally concerns devices for generating electricity.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The devices known to date for generating electricity contribute towards global warming (fossil or biomass fuel production) or they are neutral with respect to global warming (hydraulic plants, wind farms, nuclear plants). Electricity generating devices operating with solar energy contribute towards reducing global warming by converting solar energy to electric energy. However, said solar energy installations are generally not very powerful, since the heat of the sun is only available at low temperature. For a rise in temperature, it is necessary to concentrate the sun's rays which is technically complex.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Solar energy is therefore useful for heating water or air, but it is ill-adapted for the mass production of electric energy. Photovoltaic cells at the present time are only able to provide small quantities of electric energy.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Also, it is known that heat pumps allow the production of heat at a higher temperature than ambient air. Heat pumps absorb energy from ambient air and output heat with a temperature difference generally of the order of 30 to 40&#xb0; C. relative to ambient air. Said machines are not adapted for the production of electric energy owing to the low difference in temperature between the hot and cold points of heat pumps.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Within this context, the invention sets out to propose a device for generating electricity which contributes towards limiting global warming and allows the production of large quantities of electricity with acceptable efficiency.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">For this purpose, the invention relates to a device for generating electricity of the type comprising:
<ul id="ul0003" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0003-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0004" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0004-0001" num="0007">a first heat pump, provided with a first closed circuit in which a first heat-transfer fluid circulates, and a first heat exchanger between the first heat-transfer fluid and a flow of atmospheric air, in which the flow of atmospheric air transfers a quantity of heat to the first heat-transfer fluid;</li>
        <li id="ul0004-0002" num="0008">at least one second heat pump provided with a second closed circuit in which a second heat-transfer fluid circulates, and with a second heat exchanger between the second heat-transfer fluid and a third heat-transfer fluid, in which the second heat-transfer fluid transfer a quantity of heat to the third heat-transfer fluid;</li>
        <li id="ul0004-0003" num="0009">means for transferring a quantity of heat from the first heat-transfer fluid to the second heat-transfer fluid;</li>
        <li id="ul0004-0004" num="0010">a third closed circuit in which the third heat-transfer fluid circulates;</li>
        <li id="ul0004-0005" num="0011">a turbine inserted in the third closed circuit and driven by the third heat-transfer fluid;</li>
        <li id="ul0004-0006" num="0012">an electric generator mechanically driven by the turbine.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0013">The generation device may also have one or more of the characteristics below, taken alone or in any technically possible combination:
<ul id="ul0005" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0005-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0006" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0006-0001" num="0014">the means for transferring a quantity of heat from the first heat-transfer fluid to the second heat-transfer fluid comprise a third heat pump provided with a fourth closed circuit in which a fourth heat-transfer fluid circulates, with a third heat exchanger between the first heat-transfer fluid and the fourth heat-transfer fluid in which the first heat-transfer fluid yields a quantity of heat to the fourth heat-transfer fluid, and with a fourth heat exchanger between the fourth heat-transfer fluid and the second heat-transfer fluid in which the fourth heat-transfer fluid yields a quantity of heat to the second heat-transfer fluid;</li>
        <li id="ul0006-0002" num="0015">the first heat-transfer fluid, at an inlet of the third heat exchanger, has a pressure of between 18 and 22 bars and a temperature of between 220 and 270&#xb0; C., the first heat-transfer fluid having at an inlet of the first heat exchanger a pressure of between 2 and 6 bars and a temperature of between 0 and 20&#xb0; C.;</li>
        <li id="ul0006-0003" num="0016">the fourth heat-transfer fluid, at an inlet of the fourth heat exchanger, has a pressure of between 17 and 22 bars and a temperature of between 290 and 330&#xb0; C., the fourth heat-transfer fluid having at an inlet of the third heat exchanger a pressure of between 2 and 6 bars and a temperature of between 30 and 70&#xb0; C.;</li>
        <li id="ul0006-0004" num="0017">the second heat-transfer fluid, at an inlet of the second heat exchanger, has a pressure of between 13 and 17 bars and a temperature of between 340 and 390&#xb0; C., the second heat-transfer fluid having at an inlet of the fourth heat exchanger a pressure of between 1 and 5 bars and a temperature of between 90 and 130&#xb0; C.;</li>
        <li id="ul0006-0005" num="0018">the third closed circuit comprises first and second loops in which the third heat-transfer fluid circulates, each of the first and second loops having a hot line connecting an outlet of the second heat exchanger with a high pressure inlet of the turbine, the first loop having a first feedback line connecting a low pressure outlet of the turbine to an inlet of the second heat exchanger, the second loop having an intermediate heat exchanger between the first heat-transfer fluid and the third transfer-fluid in which the third heat-transfer fluid yields a quantity of heat to the first heat-transfer fluid, an intermediate line connecting a low pressure outlet of the turbine to an inlet of the intermediate heat exchanger, and a second feedback line connecting an outlet of the intermediate exchanger with an inlet of the second heat exchanger;</li>
        <li id="ul0006-0006" num="0019">the first heat-transfer fluid essentially comprises propane;</li>
        <li id="ul0006-0007" num="0020">the second heat-transfer fluid essentially comprises hexane;</li>
        <li id="ul0006-0008" num="0021">the fourth heat-transfer fluid essentially comprises butane;</li>
        <li id="ul0006-0009" num="0022">the third heat-transfer fluid essentially comprises water.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0009" num="0023">Other characteristics and advantages of the invention will become apparent from the detailed description given below as an illustration which is in no way limiting, with reference to the appended single figure schematically illustrating a device for generating electricity conforming to the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0024">The device shown in the appended figure is intended for the generation of electricity. It comprises a steam turbine, inserted in a water/steam circuit, the heat required to supply water steam at high pressure to the turbine being obtained via several heat pumps placed in series. Therefore, the heat needed for the production of high pressure steam is essentially taken from the atmosphere.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0025">More precisely, the device for generating electricity comprises:
<ul id="ul0007" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0007-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0008" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0008-0001" num="0026">first, second and third heat pumps <b>3</b>, <b>5</b> and <b>7</b>;</li>
        <li id="ul0008-0002" num="0027">a water/steam circuit <b>9</b>;</li>
        <li id="ul0008-0003" num="0028">a steam turbine <b>11</b> inserted in the water/steam circuit <b>9</b>;</li>
        <li id="ul0008-0004" num="0029">an electric generator <b>13</b>, mechanically driven by the turbine <b>11</b>.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0030">The first heat pump <b>3</b> comprises a first closed circuit <b>15</b> in which a first heat-transfer circulates, a first heat exchanger <b>17</b> between the first heat-transfer fluid and atmospheric air, a compressor <b>19</b> and an expansion valve <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0031">The first heat-transfer fluid essentially comprises propane. Advantageously, the first heat-transfer fluid is technically pure propane.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0032">The first heat exchanger <b>17</b> comprises a first side in which atmospheric air circulates, and a second side in which propane circulates. Preferably, the device comprises means for forcing the circulation of air on the first side of the heat exchanger <b>17</b>. These means may comprise fans for example or any type of similar equipment.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0033">The second heat pump <b>5</b> comprises a second closed circuit <b>23</b> in which a second heat-transfer fluid circulates, a second heat exchanger <b>25</b> between the second heat-transfer fluid and the fluid circulating in the water/steam circuit <b>9</b>, a compressor <b>27</b> and an expansion valve <b>29</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0034">The second heat-transfer fluid essentially comprises hexane. For example, the second heat-transfer fluid is technically pure hexane.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0035">The second heat exchanger <b>25</b> comprises a first side in which the second heat-transfer fluid circulates, and a second side in which water circulates in liquid or steam form. The water forms a third heat-transfer fluid.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0036">The water circulating in the water/steam circuit <b>9</b> enters the heat exchanger <b>25</b> in steam form via inlet <b>31</b> and in liquid form via inlet <b>33</b>, receives the heat yielded by the second heat-transfer fluid, and leaves the heat exchanger <b>25</b> in the form of steam via outlets <b>35</b> and <b>37</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0037">The third heat pump <b>7</b> comprises a third closed circuit <b>39</b> in which a fourth heat-transfer circulates, a third heat exchanger <b>41</b> between said fourth heat-transfer fluid and the first heat-transfer fluid of the first heat pump <b>3</b>, a fourth heat exchanger <b>43</b> between said fourth heat-transfer fluid and the second heat-transfer fluid of the second heat pump <b>5</b>, a compressor <b>45</b> and an expansion valve <b>47</b>. The heat exchanger <b>41</b> has a first side in which the first heat-transfer fluid circulates, and a second side in which the fourth heat-transfer fluid circulates.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0038">The fourth heat exchanger <b>43</b> has a first side in which the fourth heat-transfer fluid circulates, and a second side in which the second heat-transfer fluid circulates.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0039">The fourth heat-transfer fluid preferably essentially comprises butane. For example, the fourth heat-transfer fluid is technically pure butane.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0040">The water/steam circuit <b>9</b> comprises first and second loops <b>49</b> and <b>51</b>. The same heat-transfer fluid circulates in both loops.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0041">The first loop <b>49</b> comprises a first hot line <b>53</b> connecting the steam outlet <b>35</b> of the second heat exchanger with a high pressure inlet <b>55</b> of the turbine <b>11</b>. The first loop also comprises a feedback line <b>57</b> connecting a low pressure outlet <b>59</b> of the turbine with the steam inlet <b>31</b> of the second heat exchanger. The first loop <b>49</b> also comprises a compressor <b>61</b> inserted on the first hot line <b>53</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0042">The second loop <b>51</b> of the water/steam circuit comprises a second hot line connecting the second steam outlet <b>37</b> of the heat exchanger <b>25</b> with the high pressure inlet <b>55</b> of the steam turbine.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0043">The second loop further comprises an intermediate heat exchanger <b>65</b> between the first heat-transfer fluid and the third heat-transfer fluid, an intermediate line <b>67</b> connecting the low pressure outlet <b>59</b> of the steam turbine with an inlet <b>69</b> of the intermediate exchanger, and a second feedback line connecting an outlet <b>73</b> of the intermediate exchanger with the liquid inlet <b>33</b> of the second heat exchanger <b>25</b>. The second loop also comprises a compressor <b>75</b> inserted on the feedback line <b>71</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0044">The intermediate exchanger <b>65</b> comprises a first side in which the first heat-transfer fluid circulates, and a second side in which the third heat-transfer fluid circulates, from inlet <b>69</b> as far as outlet <b>73</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0045">The closed circuit <b>15</b> connects a discharge outlet of the compressor <b>19</b> with an inlet of the first side of the heat exchanger <b>41</b>. The circuit <b>15</b> also connects the outlet of said first side with the inlet of the expansion valve <b>21</b>. The outlet of the expansion valve <b>21</b> is connected by the circuit <b>15</b> with an inlet of the second side of the heat exchanger <b>17</b>. The circuit also connects the outlet of the second side of exchanger <b>17</b> with the inlet of the first side of exchanger <b>65</b> and the outlet of the first side of exchanger <b>65</b> with the suction of the compressor <b>19</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0046">The first heat-transfer fluid is gaseous between the outlet of exchanger <b>17</b> and the inlet of exchanger <b>41</b>. It is liquid between the outlet of exchanger <b>41</b> and the inlet of exchanger <b>17</b>. In exchanger <b>17</b>, the first heat-transfer fluid is in thermal contact with the air circulating on the first side of this exchanger. The air imparts heat to the first heat-transfer fluid. The first heat-transfer fluid is vaporised when passing through the first heat exchanger <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0047">In the intermediate exchanger <b>65</b>, the first heat-transfer fluid circulating on the first side of the exchanger is in thermal contact with the steam circulating on the second side of the exchanger. The steam is at least partly condensed when passing through the intermediate exchanger and transfers heat to the first heat-transfer fluid.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0048">The first heat-transfer fluid circulating on the first side of heat exchanger <b>41</b> is in thermal contact with the fourth heat-transfer fluid circulating on the second side of exchanger <b>41</b>. The first heat-transfer fluid is condensed when passing through the exchanger <b>41</b> and transfers heat to the third heat-transfer fluid.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0049">The third closed circuit <b>39</b> connects the discharge of the compressor <b>45</b> with an inlet on the first side of heat exchanger <b>43</b>. It also connects the outlet of said first side of heat exchanger <b>43</b> with an inlet of the expansion valve <b>47</b>. The closed circuit <b>39</b> also connects the outlet of the expansion valve <b>47</b> with an inlet of the second side of heat exchanger <b>41</b>. Finally, the circuit <b>39</b> connects an outlet of said second side of exchanger <b>41</b> with the suction of the compressor <b>45</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0050">As indicated above, the fourth heat-transfer fluid is in thermal contact with the first heat-transfer fluid when passing through heat exchanger <b>41</b> from which it receives heat. The fourth heat-transfer fluid is vaporised in heat exchanger <b>41</b>. The fourth heat-transfer fluid when passing through the first side of heat exchanger <b>43</b> is in thermal contact with the second heat-transfer fluid circulating on the second side of exchanger <b>43</b>. The fourth heat-transfer fluid is condensed when passing through heat exchanger <b>43</b> and transfers heat to the second heat-transfer fluid.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0051">The fourth heat-transfer fluid is in the gaseous state between the outlet of the second side of heat exchanger <b>41</b> and the inlet of the first side of heat exchanger <b>43</b>. It is in the liquid state between the outlet of the first side of exchanger <b>43</b> and the inlet of the second side of exchanger <b>41</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0052">The second closed circuit <b>23</b> connects the discharge of the compressor <b>27</b> with an inlet of the first side of heat exchanger <b>25</b>. It also connects an outlet of the first side of heat exchanger <b>25</b> with an inlet of the expansion valve <b>29</b>. The circuit <b>23</b> also connects the outlet of the expansion valve <b>29</b> with the inlet of the second side of exchanger <b>43</b>, and the outlet of said second side with the suction of the compressor <b>27</b>. The second heat-transfer fluid, when passing through the second side of heat exchanger <b>43</b> is in thermal contact with the fourth heat-transfer fluid. It receives heat from the fourth heat-transfer fluid when passing through exchanger <b>43</b> and is vaporised.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0053">The second heat-transfer fluid is in thermal contact with the third heat-transfer fluid in heat exchanger <b>25</b>. When passing through the first side of heat exchanger <b>25</b> it is condensed and transfers heat to the third heat-transfer fluid.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0054">The second heat-transfer fluid is in the gaseous state between the outlet of the second side of exchanger <b>43</b> and the inlet of the first side of heat exchanger <b>25</b>. It is in the liquid state between the outlet of the first side of heat exchanger <b>25</b> and the inlet of the second side of heat exchanger <b>43</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0055">The heat exchanger <b>25</b> for example is a dual-zone exchanger, a first zone allowing heating of the steam circulating in the first loop and a second zone allowing vaporisation of the water circulating in the second loop. The second heat-transfer fluid circulating on the first side of heat exchanger <b>25</b> is first placed in thermal contact with the fluid circulating in the second loop, then placed in thermal contact with the fluid circulating in the first loop. The second side of heat exchanger <b>25</b> comprises two separate circuits, one between inlet <b>33</b> and outlet <b>37</b>, and the other between inlet <b>31</b> and outlet <b>35</b>. The fluid in these two circuits is separated.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0056">The water is in steam state in the first loop between the outlet <b>35</b> and the high pressure inlet <b>55</b> of the turbine. It is in steam state, close to saturation temperature, between the low pressure outlet <b>59</b> of the turbine and the inlet <b>31</b> of the second heat exchanger. In the second loop, the water is in steam state between the outlet <b>37</b> of the second heat exchanger and the high pressure inlet <b>55</b> of the turbine. It is in the steam state close to saturation temperature between the low pressure outlet <b>59</b> of the turbine and the inlet <b>69</b> of the intermediate exchanger <b>65</b>. The steam is at least partly condensed in the exchanger <b>65</b>. The water is in liquid form between the discharge of the compressor <b>75</b> and the inlet <b>33</b> of the second heat exchanger.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0057">The functioning of the above-described device described will now be detailed.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0058">The atmospheric air circulating on the second side of heat exchanger <b>17</b> transfers its heat to the first heat-transfer fluid. For example, the atmospheric air has a temperature difference of 12&#xb0; C. between the inlet and outlet of the exchanger <b>17</b>. The flow-rate of atmospheric air is approximately 1 million m<sup>3</sup>/h. For example, the air at the inlet of exchanger <b>17</b> has a temperature of 12&#xb0; C. and a temperature of 0&#xb0; C. at the outlet of exchanger <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0059">The flow-rate of propane in the first closed circuit <b>15</b> is about 40 t/h. The propane is vaporised in exchanger <b>17</b>. It has a pressure of 4 bars and a temperature or about 0&#xb0; C. at the inlet to exchanger <b>17</b> and a temperature of 10&#xb0; C. at the outlet of exchanger <b>17</b>. The propane is heated in the intermediate exchanger <b>65</b>. It has a pressure of <b>4</b> bars and a temperature of about 179&#xb0; C. at the outlet of the intermediate exchanger <b>65</b>. The propane is compressed by the compressor <b>19</b> and has a pressure of 20 bars and a temperature of about 245&#xb0; C. at the discharge of the compressor <b>19</b>. When passing through heat exchanger <b>41</b> the propane is condensed. At the outlet of heat exchanger <b>41</b> it has a pressure of about 20 bars and a temperature of about 60&#xb0; C. The propane finally undergoes expansion when passing through the expansion valve <b>21</b> and at the outlet of this valve has a pressure of 4 bars and a temperature of about 0&#xb0; C.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0060">The butane circulating in the fourth closed circuit <b>39</b> has a pressure of 4 bars and a temperature of about 50&#xb0; C. at the inlet to heat exchanger <b>41</b>. It is vaporised when passing through this exchanger and at the outlet has a pressure of 4 bars and a temperature or about 240&#xb0; C. The butane is then compressed by the compressor <b>45</b> to a pressure of 19 bars and a temperature of about 310&#xb0; C. It is condensed when passing through heat exchanger <b>43</b> and has a pressure of about 19 bars and a temperature of about 116&#xb0; C. at the outlet of heat exchanger <b>43</b>. The butane then undergoes expansion when passing through the expansion valve <b>47</b> to a pressure of 4 bars and a temperature of about 50&#xb0; C. The butane flow-rate in the fourth closed circuit is about 52 t/h.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0061">The flow-rate of hexane in the second closed circuit <b>23</b> is about 50 t/h. It has a pressure of 2.5 bars and a temperature of 110&#xb0; C. at the inlet to heat exchanger <b>43</b>. The hexane is vaporised in heat exchanger <b>43</b> and has a pressure of 2.5 bars and a temperature of 305&#xb0; C. at the outlet of exchanger <b>43</b>. The hexane is then compressed by the compressor <b>27</b> to a pressure of 15 bars and a temperature of 365&#xb0; C. The hexane is condensed on passing through heat exchanger <b>25</b> and undergoes expansion when passing through the expansion valve <b>29</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0062">The water flow-rate in the third closed circuit <b>9</b> totals about 65.2 t/h. The water flow-rate in the first loop is about 62 t/h and the water flow-rate in the second loop is about 3.2 t/h. At the inlet <b>31</b> to the second heat exchanger, the steam circulating in the first loop has a pressure of 9 bars and a temperature of about 180&#xb0; C. It is superheated when passing through heat exchanger <b>25</b>, the steam at the outlet <b>35</b> having a pressure of 9 bars and a temperature of about 360&#xb0; C. The steam is compressed by the compressor <b>61</b> to a pressure of 30 bars and temperature of 405&#xb0; C. The water circulating in the second loop, at the inlet <b>33</b> of the second heat exchanger, has a pressure of 30 bars and a temperature of about 180&#xb0; C. This water is vaporised in heat exchanger <b>25</b> to a temperature of about 370&#xb0; C. and a pressure of about 30 bars. The first and second loops are connected to the same inlet <b>55</b> of the turbine. As a variant, they can be connected to different inlets.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0063">The steam drives the turbine and at the same time undergoes expansion. It has a pressure of 9 bars and a temperature of about 180&#xb0; C. at the low pressure outlet of the turbine.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0064">The steam is subdivided into two flows and is partly directed towards the feedback line <b>57</b> of the first loop and partly towards the intermediate line <b>67</b> of the second loop.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0065">The steam is at least partly condensed in the intermediate exchanger <b>65</b>, the pressure and temperature remaining substantially constant. The water at the inlet of the compressor <b>75</b> has a pressure of 9 bars and a temperature of 180&#xb0; C., and at the discharge of said compressor it has a pressure of 30 bars and a temperature of 180&#xb0; C.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0066">The energy balance of the device is the following: the atmospheric air transfers about 3 700 000 kcal/hour to the propane. The propane receives about 1 660 000 kcal/hour in the intermediate exchanger. At the time of compression by the compressor <b>19</b> it also receives about 550 000 kcal/hour. The propane transfers about 5 900 000 kcal/hour to the butane in heat exchanger <b>41</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0067">The butane then receives about 600 000 kcal/hour at the time of compression by the compressor <b>45</b>. It transfers about 6 500 000 kcal/hour in exchanger <b>43</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0068">The hexane receives about 600 000 kcal/hour at the time of compression by the compressor <b>27</b>. It transfers about 7 000 100 kcal/hour to the water in heat exchanger <b>25</b>. Also, the water circulating in the first loop receives about 550 000 kcal/hour at the time of compression by the compressor <b>61</b>. No consideration is given to the energy received by the water circulating in the second loop at the time of compression by compressor <b>75</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0069">Therefore, the energy provided to the turbine is about 6 000 000 kcal/hour taking into account the heat transferred by the steam of the second loop in the intermediate exchanger <b>65</b>. The electric yield of the turbo-alternator assembly <b>11</b> and <b>13</b> is about 70%. The alternator <b>13</b> therefore produces about 4 000 200 kcal/hour of electricity i.e. an electric power of 4,900 kW.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0070">The electric consumption of the different compressors <b>19</b>, <b>27</b>, <b>45</b>, <b>61</b> and <b>75</b> is respectively 750 kW, 900 kW, 900 kW, 800 kW, 20 kW. The consumption of the fans intended to force the circulation of atmospheric air through exchanger <b>17</b> is estimated at about 100 kW.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0071">The electricity generating device therefore has a positive energy balance of about 1400 kW.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0072">The electricity generating device described in the foregoing has multiple advantages.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0073">Since this device comprises:
<ul id="ul0009" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0009-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0010" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0010-0001" num="0074">a first heat pump, provided with a first closed circuit in which a first heat-transfer fluid circulates, and with a first heat exchanger between the first heat-transfer fluid and an atmospheric air fluid in which the atmospheric air flow transfers a quantity of heat to the first heat-transfer fluid,</li>
        <li id="ul0010-0002" num="0075">at least one second heat pump, provided with a second closed circuit in which a second heat-transfer fluid circulates, and with a second heat exchanger between the second heat-transfer fluid and a third heat-transfer fluid in which the second heat-transfer fluid transfers a quantity of heat to the third heat-transfer fluid;</li>
        <li id="ul0010-0003" num="0076">means for transferring a quantity of heat from the first heat-transfer fluid to the second heat-transfer fluid;</li>
        <li id="ul0010-0004" num="0077">a third closed circuit in which the third heat-transfer fluid circulates;</li>
        <li id="ul0010-0005" num="0078">a turbine inserted in the third closed circuit and driven by the third heat-transfer fluid; and</li>
        <li id="ul0010-0006" num="0079">an electric generator mechanically driven by the turbine, the electricity generating device takes heat from the environment, whilst producing electricity. The devices draws advantage from the fact that in heat pumps for every 1 kW of energy applied, in particular for compression of the heat-transfer gas, it is possible to obtain 5 kW of thermal energy. By placing several heat pumps in series, one behind the other, it is possible to raise the temperature of the heat-transfer fluid at each step up to a temperature allowing the production of steam in sufficient quantity to drive the steam turbine coupled with an electric generator. Therefore the fact that several heat pumps in series are used, means that it is possible to overcome the shortcoming of heat pumps i.e. they only allow a small difference in temperature between the flow of absorbed heat and the flow of heat output by the heat pump.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0080">The heat-transfer fluids are chosen so that the condensation temperature of the fluid in a given heat pump substantially corresponds to the boiling temperature of the heat-transfer fluid in the following heat pump of the series.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0081">Therefore, by compressing each heat-transfer fluid with a compressor, then condensing each one by heat exchange with a more volatile fluid, this step being followed by expansion, it is possible to cause the heat of each heat-transfer fluid to be absorbed by the lesser volatile fluid used in the following heat pump of the series. In this way, a progressive increase in the temperature of the heat-transfer fluid is obtained in stages until a temperature of about 400&#xb0; C. is reached.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0082">Two heat pumps in series may be sufficient to produce electricity, but it is advantageous to use at least three to obtain sufficient energy yield.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0083">The use of propane, butane and hexane as heat-transfer fluids in the three heat pumps placed in series is particularly advantageous since these fluids have characteristics that are well adapted for the targeted objective.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0084">Similarly, the pressure and temperature profiles described above for the heat-transfer fluids of the three heat pumps are particularly well adapted.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0085">By sub-dividing the steam circuit into two loops, with one loop used to superheat the heat-transfer fluid of the first heat pump before compression, it is possible to optimise the total energy yield of the device. The electric yield of the turbine/alternator assembly is therefore higher than 60%, for example of the order of 70%.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0086">The above-described electricity generating device may entail multiple variants.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0087">It may only comprise two heat pumps or three heat pumps, or more than three heat pumps in series one after the other, in relation to the power that is to be obtained and the heat-transfer fluids used.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0088">The heat-transfer fluids used in the different heat pumps may be of any type, provided that the condensation temperature of one heat-transfer fluid used in a given heat pump substantially corresponds to the boiling temperature of the heat-transfer fluid used in the following heat pump of the series.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0089">Also, the pressure and temperature profiles may vary for each of the heat pumps in relation to the thermal power to be transferred and the heat-transfer fluids used.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0090">The water/steam circuit could only comprise a single loop.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0091">The heat exchanger <b>25</b> between the second heat-transfer fluid and the water may consist of one exchanger with several zones or may consist of several heat exchangers physically independent of each other.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A device for generating electricity, comprising:
<claim-text>a first heat pump comprising a first closed circuit in which a first heat-transfer fluid circulates, and with a first heat exchanger between the first heat-transfer fluid and a flow of atmospheric air in which the flow of atmospheric air transfers a quantity of heat to the first heat-transfer fluid,</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one second heat pump comprising a second closed circuit in which a second heat-transfer fluid circulates, and with a second heat exchanger between the second heat-transfer fluid and a third heat-transfer fluid in which the second heat-transfer fluid transfers a quantity of heat to the third heat-transfer fluid;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third heat pump configured to transfer a quantity of heat from the first heat-transfer fluid to the second heat-transfer fluid;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third closed circuit, in which the third heat-transfer fluid circulates;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a turbine inserted in the third closed circuit and driven by the third heat-transfer fluid; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an electric generator, mechanically driven by the turbine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the third closed circuit comprising first and second loops in which the third heat-transfer fluid circulates, each of the first and second loops having a hot line connecting an outlet of the second heat exchanger with a high pressure inlet of the turbine, the first loop having a first feedback line connecting a low pressure outlet of the turbine with an inlet of the second heat exchanger, the second loop having an intermediate heat exchanger between the first heat-transfer fluid and the third heat-transfer fluid in which the third heat-transfer fluid transfers a quantity of heat to the first heat-transfer fluid, an intermediate line connecting a low pressure outlet of the turbine with an inlet of the intermediate heat exchanger, and a second feedback line connecting an outlet of the intermediate exchanger with an inlet of the second heat exchanger.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the third heat pump comprises a fourth closed circuit in which a fourth heat-transfer fluid circulates, a third heat exchanger between the first heat-transfer fluid and the fourth heat-transfer fluid in which the first heat-transfer fluid transfers a quantity of heat to the fourth heat-transfer fluid, and a fourth heat exchanger between the fourth heat-transfer fluid and the second heat-transfer fluid in which the fourth heat-transfer fluid transfers a quantity of heat to the second heat-transfer fluid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>circulating a fourth heat-transfer fluid through a fourth closed circuit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>transferring a quantity of heat from the first heat-transfer fluid to the fourth heat-transfer fluid; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>transferring a quantity of heat from the from the fourth heat-transfer fluid to the second heat-transfer fluid.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the first heat-transfer fluid, at an inlet to the third heat exchanger, has a pressure of between 18 and 22 bars and a temperature of between 220 and 270&#xb0; C., the first heat-transfer fluid having at an inlet to the first heat exchanger a pressure of between 2 and 6 bars and a temperature of between 0 and 20&#xb0; C.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the fourth heat-transfer fluid, at an inlet to the fourth heat exchanger, has a pressure of between 17 and 22 bars and a temperature of between 290 and 330&#xb0; C., the fourth heat-transfer fluid having at an inlet to the third heat exchanger a pressure of between 2 and 6 bars and a temperature of between 30 and 70&#xb0; C.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the second heat-transfer fluid, at an inlet to the second heat exchanger, has a pressure of between 13 and 17 bars and a temperature of between 340 and 390&#xb0; C., the second heat-transfer fluid having at an inlet to the fourth heat exchanger a pressure of between 1 and 5 bars and a temperature of between 90 and 130&#xb0; C.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first heat-transfer fluid comprises propane.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second heat-transfer fluid comprises hexane.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the fourth heat-transfer fluid comprises butane.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the third heat-transfer fluid comprises water.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the turbine and the electric generator together have an electric yield of more than 60%.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. A method for generating electricity, comprising:
<claim-text>circulating a first heat-transfer fluid through a first closed circuit so as to exchange heat between the first heat-transfer fluid and a flow of atmospheric air in which the flow of atmospheric air transfers a quantity of heat to the first heat-transfer fluid,</claim-text>
<claim-text>circulating a second heat-transfer fluid through a second closed circuit so as to exchange heat between the second heat-transfer fluid and a third heat-transfer fluid in which the second heat-transfer fluid transfers a quantity of heat to the third heat-transfer fluid;</claim-text>
<claim-text>transferring a quantity of heat from the first heat-transfer fluid to the second heat-transfer fluid;</claim-text>
<claim-text>circulating the third heat-transfer fluid through a third closed circuit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>driving a turbine inserted in the third closed circuit by the third heat-transfer fluid; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>mechanically driving an electric generator by the turbine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the third closed circuit comprises first and second loops in which the third heat-transfer fluid circulates, each of the first and second loops having a hot line connecting an outlet of the second heat exchanger with a high pressure inlet of the turbine, the first loop having a first feedback line connecting a low pressure outlet of the turbine with an inlet of the second heat exchanger, the second loop having an intermediate heat exchanger between the first heat-transfer fluid and the third heat-transfer fluid in which the third heat-transfer fluid transfers a quantity of heat to the first heat-transfer fluid, an intermediate line connecting a low pressure outlet of the turbine with an inlet of the intermediate heat exchanger, and a second feedback line connecting an outlet of the intermediate exchanger with an inlet of the second heat exchanger.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
