<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622327-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622327</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12727846</doc-number>
<date>20100319</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>554</us-term-extension>
<disclaimer>
<text>This patent is subject to a terminal disclaimer.</text>
</disclaimer>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>23</main-group>
<subgroup>20</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>241 60</main-classification>
<further-classification>241605</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e55">Loosefill blowing machine having offset guide shells and vertical feed</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4111493</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Sperber</name>
<date>19780900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4465239</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Woten</name>
<date>19840800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5462238</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Smith et al.</name>
<date>19951000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6109488</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Horton</name>
<date>20000800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>222636</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0257833</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Johnson et al.</name>
<date>20091000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>CA</country>
<doc-number>2571819</doc-number>
<date>20070600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>2009005452</doc-number>
<date>20090900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>GB</country>
<doc-number>2099776</doc-number>
<date>19821200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>GB</country>
<doc-number>2124194</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19840200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>241 60</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2411655</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>241605</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110226814</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110922</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Evans</last-name>
<first-name>Michael E.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Granville</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Evans</last-name>
<first-name>Michael E.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Granville</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Fraser Clemens Martin &#x26; Miller LLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Charpie</last-name>
<first-name>Charles F.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Owens Corning Intellectual Capital, LLC</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Toledo</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Francis</last-name>
<first-name>Faye</first-name>
<department>3725</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A machine for distributing loosefill insulation is provided. The machine includes a chute having an inlet end configured to receive the loosefill insulation. A lower unit is associated with the chute and includes a shredder configured to shred the loosefill insulation and an agitator configured to finely condition the loosefill insulation. The lower unit includes a shredder guide shell positioned partially around the shredder and an agitator guide shell positioned partially around the agitator. A discharge mechanism is positioned in the lower unit. The discharge mechanism has a top inlet positioned below the agitator such that loosefill insulation exiting the agitator is allowed to fall in a substantially vertical direction from the agitator into the top inlet of the discharge mechanism. The position of the shredder guide shell at a passageway is offset in a vertical direction from the position of the agitator guide shell at the passageway.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="200.07mm" wi="160.19mm" file="US08622327-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="215.31mm" wi="160.87mm" file="US08622327-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="223.01mm" wi="171.11mm" file="US08622327-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="239.01mm" wi="180.09mm" file="US08622327-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="158.24mm" wi="154.43mm" file="US08622327-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="158.92mm" wi="179.41mm" file="US08622327-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="165.35mm" wi="173.65mm" file="US08622327-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">In the insulation of buildings, a frequently used insulation product is loosefill insulation. In contrast to the unitary or monolithic structure of insulation batts or blankets, loosefill insulation is a multiplicity of discrete, individual tufts, cubes, flakes or nodules. Loosefill insulation is usually applied to buildings by blowing the loosefill insulation into an insulation cavity, such as a wall cavity or an attic of a building. Typically, loosefill insulation is made of glass fibers although other mineral fibers, organic fibers, and cellulose fibers can be used.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Loosefill insulation, also referred to as blowing wool, is typically compressed and encapsulated in a bag. The compressed loosefill insulation and the bag form a package. Packages of compressed loosefill insulation are used for transport from an insulation manufacturing site to a building that is to be insulated. The bags can be made of polypropylene or other suitable materials. During the packaging of the loosefill insulation, it is placed under compression for storage and transportation efficiencies. The compressed loosefill insulation can be packaged with a compression ratio of at least about 10:1. The distribution of loosefill insulation into an insulation cavity typically uses a loosefill blowing machine that feeds the loosefill insulation pneumatically through a distribution hose. Loosefill blowing machines can have a chute or hopper for containing and feeding the compressed loosefill insulation after the package is opened and the compressed loosefill insulation is allowed to expand.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">It would be advantageous if the loosefill blowing machines could operate more efficiently.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The above objects as well as other objects not specifically enumerated are achieved by a machine for distributing loosefill insulation. The machine includes a chute having an inlet end. The inlet end is configured to receive the loosefill insulation. A lower unit is associated with the chute. The lower unit includes a shredder configured to shred and pick apart the loosefill insulation and an agitator configured to finely condition the loosefill insulation. The lower unit further includes a shredder guide shell positioned partially around the shredder and an agitator guide shell positioned partially around the agitator. A discharge mechanism is positioned in the lower unit. The discharge mechanism is configured to discharge loosefill insulation from an outlet of the lower unit. The discharge mechanism has a top inlet. The top inlet is positioned below the agitator such that loosefill insulation exiting the agitator is allowed to fall in a substantially vertical direction from the agitator into the top inlet of the discharge mechanism. The position of the shredder guide shell at a passageway is offset in a vertical direction from the position of the agitator guide shell at the passageway.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">According to this invention there are also provided a machine for distributing loosefill insulation. The machine includes a chute having an inlet end. The inlet end is configured to receive the loosefill insulation. A lower unit is associated with the chute. The lower unit includes a shredder configured to shred and pick apart the loosefill insulation and an agitator configured to finely condition the loosefill insulation. The lower unit further includes a shredder guide shell positioned partially around the shredder and an agitator guide shell positioned partially around the agitator. A discharge mechanism is positioned in the lower unit. The discharge mechanism is configured to discharge loosefill insulation from an outlet of the lower unit. The discharge mechanism has a top inlet. The top inlet is positioned below the agitator such that loosefill insulation exiting the agitator is directed by the agitator against a segment of a passageway positioned in the lower unit. The segment is configured to stop movement of the loosefill insulation such that the loosefill insulation falls in a substantially vertical direction into the top inlet of the discharge mechanism. The position of the shredder guide shell at the passageway is offset in a vertical direction from the position of the agitator guide shell at the passageway.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">According to this invention there are also provided a machine for distributing loosefill insulation. The machine includes a chute having an inlet end configured to receive the loosefill insulation. A lower unit is associated with the chute. The lower unit includes a first shredder, a second shredder and an agitator. The first and second shredders are configured to shred and pick apart the loosefill insulation. The agitator is configured to finely condition the loosefill insulation. The lower unit further includes a first shredder guide shell positioned partially around the first shredder, a second shredder guide shell positioned around the second shredder and an agitator guide shell positioned partially around the agitator. A discharge mechanism is positioned in the lower unit and is configured to discharge loosefill insulation from an outlet of the lower unit. The discharge mechanism has a top inlet positioned adjacent the agitator such that loosefill insulation exiting the agitator is allowed to fall in a substantially vertical direction into the top inlet of the discharge mechanism. A second end of the first shredder guide shell is offset in a vertical direction from the second end of the second shredder guide shell. The second end of the second shredder guide shell is offset in a vertical direction from a second end of the agitator guide shell.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Various objects and advantages of this invention will become apparent to those skilled in the art from the following detailed description of the preferred embodiment, when read in light of the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a front view in elevation of a blowing insulation machine.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a front view, partially in cross-section, of the blowing insulation machine of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a side view in elevation of the blowing insulation machine of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a front view, partially in cross-section, of a first embodiment of a lower unit of the blowing insulation machine of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a front view, partially in cross-section, of a second embodiment of a lower unit of the blowing insulation machine of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a front view, partially in cross-section, of a third embodiment of a lower unit of the blowing insulation machine of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The present invention will now be described with occasional reference to the specific embodiments of the invention. This invention may, however, be embodied in different forms and should not be construed as limited to the embodiments set forth herein. Rather, these embodiments are provided so that this disclosure will be thorough and complete, and will fully convey the scope of the invention to those skilled in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Unless otherwise defined, all technical and scientific terms used herein have the same meaning as commonly understood by one of ordinary skill in the art to which this invention belongs. The terminology used in the description of the invention herein is for describing particular embodiments only and is not intended to be limiting of the invention. As used in the description of the invention and the appended claims, the singular forms &#x201c;a,&#x201d; &#x201c;an,&#x201d; and &#x201c;the&#x201d; are intended to include the plural forms as well, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Unless otherwise indicated, all numbers expressing quantities of dimensions such as length, width, height, and so forth as used in the specification and claims are to be understood as being modified in all instances by the term &#x201c;about.&#x201d; Accordingly, unless otherwise indicated, the numerical properties set forth in the specification and claims are approximations that may vary depending on the desired properties sought to be obtained in embodiments of the present invention. Notwithstanding that the numerical ranges and parameters setting forth the broad scope of the invention are approximations, the numerical values set forth in the specific examples are reported as precisely as possible. Any numerical values, however, inherently contain certain errors necessarily resulting from error found in their respective measurements.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In accordance with embodiments of the present invention, the description and figures disclose loosefill blowing machines having offset guide shells and a vertical feed. The term &#x201c;loosefill insulation&#x201d;, as used herein, is defined to include any insulation materials configured for distribution in an airstream. The term &#x201c;finely condition&#x201d;, as used herein, is defined to mean the shredding of loosefill insulation to a desired density prior to distribution in an airstream.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">A loosefill blowing machine <b>10</b> configured for distributing compressed loosefill insulation is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref>. The loosefill blowing machine <b>10</b> includes a lower unit <b>12</b> and a chute <b>14</b>. The lower unit <b>12</b> can be connected to the chute <b>14</b> by a plurality of fastening mechanisms <b>15</b> configured to readily assemble and disassemble the chute <b>14</b> to the lower unit <b>12</b>. As further shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref>, the chute <b>14</b> has an inlet end <b>16</b> and an outlet end <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The chute <b>14</b> is configured to receive compressed loosefill insulation and introduce the loosefill insulation to a shredding chamber <b>23</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. Optionally, the chute <b>14</b> can include a handle segment <b>21</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, to facilitate easy movement of the loosefill blowing machine <b>10</b> from one location to another. However, the handle segment <b>21</b> is not necessary to the operation of the loosefill blowing machine <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">As further shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref>, the chute <b>14</b> can include an optional guide assembly <b>19</b> mounted at the inlet end <b>16</b> of the chute <b>14</b>. The guide assembly <b>19</b> is configured to urge a package of compressed loosefill insulation against an optional cutting mechanism <b>20</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 3</figref>, as the package of compressed loosefill insulation moves into the chute <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the shredding chamber <b>23</b> is mounted at the outlet end <b>18</b> of the chute <b>14</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the shredding chamber <b>23</b> includes a low speed shredder <b>24</b> and an agitator <b>26</b>. The low speed shredder <b>24</b> is configured to shred and pick apart the loosefill insulation as the loosefill insulation is discharged from the outlet end <b>18</b> of the chute <b>14</b> into the lower unit <b>12</b>. Although the loosefill blowing machine <b>10</b> is shown with a single low speed shredder <b>24</b>, any quantity of low speed shredder or any type of separator, such as a clump breaker, beater bar or any other mechanism that shreds and picks apart the loosefill insulation can be used.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">As further shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the shredding chamber <b>23</b> includes an agitator <b>26</b> configured to finely condition the loosefill insulation. In the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the agitator <b>26</b> is positioned substantially horizontally adjacent the low speed shredder <b>24</b>. The term &#x201c;substantially horizontally adjacent&#x201d;, as used herein, is defined to mean that the low speed shredder <b>24</b> and the agitator <b>26</b> as substantially in a same horizontal plane. Alternatively, the agitator <b>26</b> can be positioned in any desired location relative to the low speed shredder <b>24</b>, such as the non-limiting example of vertically adjacent to the low speed shredder <b>24</b>, sufficient to receive the loosefill insulation from the low speed shredder <b>24</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the agitator <b>26</b> is a high speed shredder. Alternatively, any type of agitator or shredder can be used, such as a clump breaker, beater bar or any other mechanism configured to finely condition the loosefill insulation and prepare the loosefill insulation for distribution in an airstream.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the low speed shredder <b>24</b> rotates at a lower speed than the agitator <b>26</b>. The low speed shredder <b>24</b> rotates at a speed of about 40-80 rpm and the agitator <b>26</b> rotates at a speed of about 300-500 rpm. In other embodiments, the low speed shredder <b>24</b> can rotate at a speed less than or more than 40-80 rpm, provided the speed is sufficient to shred and pick apart the loosefill insulation. The agitator <b>26</b> can rotate at a speed less than or more than 300-500 rpm provided the speed is sufficient to finely condition the loosefill insulation and prepare the loosefill insulation for distribution in an airstream.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a discharge mechanism <b>28</b> is positioned in a direction vertically below the low speed shredder <b>24</b> and the agitator <b>26</b>. The discharge mechanism <b>28</b> is configured to distribute the finely conditioned loosefill insulation into an airstream. In the illustrated embodiment, the discharge mechanism <b>28</b> is a rotary valve. Alternatively, the discharge mechanism <b>28</b> can be any mechanism including staging hoppers, metering devices, or rotary feeders, sufficient to distribute the finely conditioned loosefill insulation into an airstream.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In the illustrated embodiment as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the finely conditioned loosefill insulation is driven through the discharge mechanism <b>28</b> and through a machine outlet <b>32</b> by an airstream provided by a blower <b>36</b> mounted in the lower unit <b>12</b>. The airstream is indicated by an arrow <b>33</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. In other embodiments, the airstream <b>33</b> can be provided by other methods, such as by a vacuum, sufficient to provide an airstream <b>33</b> driven through the discharge mechanism <b>28</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the blower <b>36</b> provides the airstream <b>33</b> to the discharge mechanism <b>28</b> through a duct <b>38</b>, shown in phantom in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, extending from the blower <b>36</b> to the rotary valve <b>28</b>. Alternatively, the airstream <b>33</b> can be provided to the discharge mechanism <b>28</b> by other structures, such as a hose or pipe, sufficient to provide the discharge mechanism <b>28</b> with the airstream <b>33</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The low speed shredder <b>24</b>, agitator <b>26</b>, discharge mechanism <b>28</b> and the blower <b>36</b> are mounted for rotation. They can be driven by any suitable means, such as by a motor <b>34</b>, or any other means sufficient to drive rotary equipment. Alternatively, the shredder <b>24</b>, agitator <b>26</b>, discharge mechanism <b>28</b> and blower <b>36</b> can be provided with its own motor.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Generally, in operation, the chute <b>14</b> guides the loosefill insulation to the shredding chamber <b>23</b>. The shredding chamber <b>23</b> includes the low speed shredder <b>24</b> and the agitator <b>26</b>. The low speed shredder <b>24</b> is configured to shred and pick apart the loosefill insulation. The shredded loosefill insulation exits the low speed shredder <b>24</b> in the direction D<b>1</b> and enters the agitator <b>26</b>. The agitator <b>26</b> is configured to finely condition the loosefill insulation for distribution into the airstream <b>33</b> by further shredding the loosefill insulation. The finely conditioned loosefill insulation exits the agitator <b>26</b> and falls in direction D<b>2</b> into the discharge mechanism <b>28</b> for distribution into the airstream <b>33</b> caused by the blower <b>36</b>. The airstream <b>33</b>, with the finely conditioned loosefill insulation, exits the machine <b>10</b> at the machine outlet <b>32</b> and flows through a distribution hose <b>46</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, toward the insulation cavity, not shown.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the low speed shredder <b>24</b> rotates in a counter-clockwise direction R<b>1</b> and the agitator <b>26</b> rotates in a counter-clockwise direction R<b>2</b>. Rotating the low speed shredder <b>24</b> and the agitator <b>26</b> in the same counter-clockwise directions, R<b>1</b> and R<b>2</b>, allows the low speed shredder <b>24</b> and the agitator <b>26</b> to shred and pick apart the loosefill insulation while substantially preventing an accumulation of unshredded or partially shredded loosefill insulation in the shredding chamber <b>23</b>. In other embodiments, the low speed shredder <b>24</b> and the agitator <b>26</b> could rotate in a clock-wise direction or the low speed shredder <b>24</b> and the agitator <b>26</b> could rotate in different directions provided the relative rotational directions allow finely conditioned loosefill insulation to be fed into the discharge mechanism <b>28</b> while preventing a substantial accumulation of unshredded or partially shredded loosefill insulation in the shredding chamber <b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">As further shown <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the shredding chamber <b>23</b> includes a shredder guide shell <b>70</b> and an agitator guide shell <b>72</b>. Shredder guide shell <b>70</b> is positioned partially around the low speed shredder <b>24</b> and extends to form an arc of approximately 90&#xb0;. Shredder guide shell <b>70</b> has an inner surface <b>71</b>. Shredder guide shell <b>70</b> is configured to allow the low speed shredder <b>24</b> to seal against the inner surface <b>71</b> of the shredder guide shell <b>70</b> and thereby direct the loosefill insulation in a direction toward the agitator <b>26</b> as the low speed shredder <b>24</b> rotates in direction R<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In a manner similar to the shredder guide shell <b>70</b>, the agitator guide shell <b>72</b> is positioned partially around the agitator <b>26</b> and extends to form an arc of approximate 90&#xb0;. Agitator guide shell <b>72</b> has an inner surface <b>73</b>. Agitator guide shell <b>72</b> is configured to allow the agitator <b>26</b> to seal against the inner surface <b>73</b> and thereby direct the loosefill insulation in a downstream direction as the agitator <b>26</b> rotates in direction R<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the shredder inner surface <b>71</b> and the agitator inner surface <b>73</b> are made of high density polyethylene (hdpe) configured to provide a lightweight, low friction guide for the loosefill insulation. Alternatively, the inner surfaces, <b>71</b> and <b>73</b>, can be made of other materials, such as aluminum, sufficient to provide a sealing surface that allows the low speed shredder <b>24</b> and the agitator <b>26</b> to direct the loosefill insulation in a downstream direction.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the shredder guide shell <b>70</b> has a first end <b>80</b> and a second end <b>82</b>. Similarly, the agitator guide shell <b>72</b> has a first end <b>84</b> and a second end <b>86</b>. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the second end <b>82</b> of the shredder guide shell <b>70</b> is offset in a vertical direction from the second end <b>86</b> of the agitator guide shell <b>72</b> by an offset distance OD. The term &#x201c;offset&#x201d;, as used herein, is defined to mean vertical displacement. In the illustrated embodiment, the offset distance OD is in a range of from about 1.0 inch to about 8.0 inches. In other embodiments, the offset distance OD can be less than about 1.0 inch or more than about 8.0 inches.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The arrangement of the shredder guide shell <b>70</b> and the agitator guide shell <b>72</b> in an offset manner can provide significant benefits over arrangements of shredder guide shells and agitator guide shells that may be on a substantially similar horizontal plane. However, not all of the benefits may be realized in all situations and in all embodiments. First, the offset between the shredder guide shell <b>70</b> and the agitator guide shell <b>72</b> provides that the loosefill insulation is conditioned to a desired level at the shredder <b>24</b> prior to the loosefill insulation exiting the shredder <b>24</b> and entering the agitator <b>26</b>. While the loosefill insulation is at the low speed shredder <b>24</b>, the shredder guide shell <b>70</b> is configured to retain the loosefill insulation until the desired shredding is achieved prior to pushing the shredded loosefill insulation to the agitator <b>26</b>. This results in loosefill insulation having a desired level of shredding prior to entering the agitator <b>26</b>. Second, the offset between the shredder guide shell <b>70</b> and the agitator guide shell <b>72</b> provides for increased protection against jamming by large tufts of unshredded or improperly shredded loosefill insulation. Lastly, the offset between the shredder guide shell <b>70</b> and the agitator guide shell <b>72</b> provides for increased protection against an over-amperage surge to the motor <b>34</b> as a result of clogging or jamming of large tufts of unshredded or improperly shredded loosefill insulation.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the discharge mechanism <b>28</b> includes a valve shaft <b>50</b> mounted for rotation within the discharge mechanism <b>28</b>, a plurality of seal assemblies <b>52</b> mounted to and supported by the valve shaft <b>50</b>, and a valve housing <b>54</b>. Generally, the seal assemblies <b>52</b> are configured to seal against the valve housing <b>54</b> as the valve shaft <b>50</b> rotates within the valve housing <b>54</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the valve shaft <b>50</b> is made of steel, although the valve shaft <b>50</b> can be made of other desired materials, such as aluminum or plastic. In the illustrated embodiment, the seal assemblies <b>52</b> include a plurality of vanes extending radially from the valve shaft <b>50</b>, each of the vanes having a seal tip <b>56</b> configured to seal against the valve housing <b>54</b> as the valve shaft <b>50</b> rotates within the valve housing <b>54</b>. In other embodiments, the seal assemblies <b>52</b> can have any desired structure sufficient to seal against the valve housing <b>54</b> as the valve shaft <b>50</b> rotates within the valve housing <b>54</b>. While the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a quantity of six seal assemblies <b>52</b>, it should be appreciated that in other embodiments any desired quantity of seal assemblies <b>52</b> can be used.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the valve shaft <b>50</b>, having the seal assemblies <b>52</b> assembled on the valve shaft <b>50</b>, rotates within the valve housing <b>54</b> in a counter-clock wise direction as indicated by the arrow D<b>3</b>. Alternatively, the valve shaft <b>50</b> can be configured to rotate in a clockwise direction.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the valve housing <b>54</b> is made from an aluminum extrusion, although in other embodiments the valve housing <b>54</b> can be made from other desired materials, including brass or plastic, sufficient to form a housing within which the valve shaft <b>50</b> rotates. In the illustrated embodiment as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the valve housing <b>54</b> is made of a single segment. Alternatively, the valve housing <b>54</b> can be made of two or more associated segments.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the valve housing <b>54</b> includes an inner housing wall <b>58</b>. The inner housing wall <b>58</b> has an inner housing surface <b>60</b>. Optionally, the inner housing surface <b>60</b> can have a coating to provide a low friction and extended wear surface. One example of a low friction coating is a chromium alloy although other materials may be used. Alternatively, the inner housing surface <b>60</b> may not be coated with a low friction and extended wear surface.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the valve housing <b>54</b> is curved and extends to form a segment having a generally circular shape. The valve housing <b>54</b> has a first end <b>62</b> and a second end <b>64</b>. A valve housing wrap angle &#x3b1;-<b>1</b> extends from the first end <b>62</b> of the valve housing <b>54</b> to the second end <b>64</b> of the valve housing <b>54</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the valve housing wrap angle &#x3b1;-<b>1</b> is in a range of from about 265&#xb0; to about 300&#xb0;. Alternatively, the valve housing <b>54</b> can form other circular segments having other desired valve housing wrap angles &#x3b1;-<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the valve housing <b>54</b> includes an eccentric region <b>66</b>. The eccentric region <b>66</b> extends from or bulges out from a portion of the valve housing <b>54</b>. The eccentric region <b>66</b> can have any desired cross-sectional shape. The eccentric region <b>66</b> is within the airstream <b>33</b> flowing through the discharge mechanism <b>28</b>. In operation, as the seal assemblies <b>52</b> rotate into the airstream <b>33</b>, the airstream <b>33</b> flows along the seal tip <b>56</b>, thereby forcing any particles of loosefill insulation caught on the seal tip <b>56</b> to be blown off and assisting in preventing a buildup of finely conditioned loosefill insulation from forming within the discharge mechanisms <b>28</b>. While the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates the eccentric region <b>66</b> as being positioned in a right quadrant of the discharge mechanism <b>28</b>, it should be appreciated that the eccentric region <b>66</b> can be positioned in any suitable location within the discharge mechanism <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the valve housing <b>54</b> forms a top inlet <b>90</b>. The top inlet <b>90</b> is configured to receive the finely conditioned loosefill insulation as it is falls from the agitator <b>26</b>. The term &#x201c;top inlet&#x201d;, as used herein, is defined to mean an inlet that is positioned above a horizontal axis extending through the center of the valve shaft <b>50</b>. Positioning the top inlet <b>90</b> of the discharge mechanism <b>28</b> at the top of the discharge mechanism <b>28</b> allows finely conditioned loosefill insulation to fall in a substantially vertical direction D<b>2</b>, from the agitator <b>26</b> into the discharge mechanism <b>28</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the finely conditioned loosefill insulation falls in the substantially vertical direction D<b>2</b> as a result of the force of gravity. In other embodiments, the finely conditioned loosefill insulation falls in the substantially vertical direction D<b>2</b> as a result an urging from the agitator <b>26</b>. The term &#x201c;substantially vertical direction&#x201d;, as used herein, is defined to mean feeding of the finely conditioned loosefill insulation from the agitator <b>26</b> to the discharge mechanism <b>28</b> in a direction that is +/&#x2212;30&#xb0; to a vertical axis extending through the valve shaft <b>50</b>. Feeding finely conditioned loosefill insulation in a substantially vertical direction D<b>2</b> into the discharge mechanism <b>28</b> advantageously provides for a smooth flow of the finely conditioned loosefill insulation through the shredding chamber <b>23</b> and into the discharge mechanism <b>28</b> and substantially prevents the undesired build-up of accumulated loosefill insulation.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">As further shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a passageway <b>92</b> is formed between the shredder <b>24</b> and the agitator <b>26</b> and the discharge mechanism <b>28</b>. The passageway <b>92</b> is configured to channel the finely conditioned loosefill insulation exiting the agitator <b>26</b> and flowing into the discharge mechanism <b>28</b>. The passageway <b>92</b> includes a first segment <b>94</b> extending from the second end <b>82</b> of the shredder guide shell <b>70</b> to the first end <b>62</b> of the valve housing <b>54</b> and a second segment <b>96</b> extending from the second end <b>86</b> of the agitator guide shell <b>72</b> to the second end <b>64</b> of the valve housing <b>54</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the first and second segments, <b>94</b> and <b>96</b>, of the passageway <b>92</b> are made of high density polyethylene (hdpe) configured to provide a lightweight, low friction guide for the finely conditioned loosefill insulation. Alternatively, the first and second segments, <b>94</b> and <b>96</b>, can be made of other desired materials.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, another embodiment of a lower unit <b>112</b> of a loosefill blowing machine is illustrated. The lower unit <b>112</b> includes a low speed shredder <b>124</b>, an agitator <b>126</b> and a discharge mechanism <b>128</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the low speed shredder <b>124</b>, agitator <b>126</b> and discharge mechanism <b>128</b> are the same as, or similar to, the low speed shredder <b>24</b>, agitator <b>26</b> and discharge mechanism <b>28</b> described above and illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. Alternatively, the low speed shredder <b>124</b>, agitator <b>126</b> and discharge mechanism <b>128</b> can be different from the low speed shredder <b>24</b>, agitator <b>26</b> and discharge mechanism <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the lower unit <b>112</b> also includes a shredder guide shell <b>170</b> positioned partially around the low speed shredder <b>124</b> and an agitator guide shell <b>172</b> positioned partially around the agitator <b>126</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the shredder guide shell <b>170</b> and the agitator guide shell <b>172</b> are the same as, or similar to, the shredder guide shell <b>70</b> and the agitator guide shell <b>72</b> discussed above and illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. In other embodiments, the shredder guide shell <b>170</b> and the agitator guide shell <b>172</b> can be different from the shredder guide shell <b>70</b> and the agitator guide shell <b>72</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the shredder guide shell <b>170</b> has a first end <b>180</b> and a second end <b>182</b>. Similarly, the agitator guide shell <b>172</b> has a first end <b>184</b> and a second end <b>186</b>. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the second end <b>182</b> of the shredder guide shell <b>170</b> is offset in a vertical direction from the second end <b>186</b> of the agitator guide shell <b>172</b> by an offset distance OD<b>100</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the offset distance OD<b>100</b> is in a range of from about 1.0 inch to about 8.0 inches. In other embodiments, the offset distance OD<b>100</b> can be less than about 1.0 inch or more than about 8.0 inches.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">While the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, shows the second end <b>182</b> of the shredder guide shell <b>170</b> substantially coinciding with the first end <b>184</b> of the agitator guide shell <b>172</b>, it should be appreciated that in other embodiments the second end <b>182</b> of the shredder guide shell <b>170</b> may not substantially coincide with the first end <b>184</b> of the agitator guide shell <b>172</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the discharge mechanism <b>128</b> includes a valve housing <b>154</b>. The valve housing <b>154</b> extends to form a top inlet <b>190</b>. The top inlet <b>190</b> is configured to receive finely conditioned loosefill insulation as it is falls from the agitator <b>126</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">As further shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, a passageway <b>192</b> is formed between the agitator <b>126</b> and the discharge mechanism <b>128</b>. The passageway <b>192</b> is configured to channel the finely conditioned loosefill insulation exiting the agitator <b>126</b> and flowing into the discharge mechanism <b>128</b>. The passageway <b>192</b> includes a first segment <b>194</b> extending from the second end <b>186</b> of the agitator guide shell <b>172</b> to a first end <b>162</b> of the valve housing <b>154</b> and a second segment <b>196</b> extending vertically upward from the second end <b>164</b> of the valve housing <b>154</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the first and second segments, <b>194</b> and <b>196</b>, of the passageway <b>192</b> are made of high density polyethylene (hdpe) configured to provide a lightweight, low friction guide for the finely conditioned loosefill insulation. Alternatively, the first and second segments, <b>194</b> and <b>196</b>, can be made of other desired materials.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In operation, the low speed shredder <b>124</b> shreds and picks apart the loosefill insulation. The shredded loosefill insulation exits the low speed shredder <b>124</b> in the direction D<b>100</b> and enters the agitator <b>126</b>. The agitator <b>26</b> is configured to finely condition the loosefill insulation for distribution into an airstream (not shown) by further shredding the loosefill insulation. The finely conditioned loosefill insulation exits the agitator <b>126</b> in direction D<b>110</b> and contacts the second segment <b>196</b> of the passageway <b>192</b>. Contacting the second segment <b>196</b> causes the movement of the finely conditioned loosefill insulation to stop, wherein the finely conditioned loosefill insulation falls, by the force of gravity in direction D<b>120</b>, into the top inlet <b>190</b> of the discharge mechanism <b>28</b> for distribution into the airstream.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">While the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows the finely conditioned loosefill insulation contacting the second segment <b>196</b> of the passageway <b>192</b>, it should be appreciated that in other embodiments, the finely conditioned loosefill insulation can be directed to contact other structures, including the non-limiting example of a wall <b>140</b> of the lower unit <b>112</b> for the purpose of stopping the movement of the finely conditioned loosefill insulation. In a similar manner to the structure illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the combination of the offset guide shells and the vertical feed of the finely conditioned loosefill insulation advantageously provides for a smooth flow of the finely conditioned loosefill insulation through the shredding chamber <b>123</b> and into the discharge mechanism <b>128</b> and substantially prevents the undesired build-up of accumulated loosefill insulation.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, another embodiment of a lower unit <b>212</b> of a loosefill blowing machine is illustrated. The lower unit <b>212</b> includes a first low speed shredder <b>224</b><i>a</i>, a second low speed shredder <b>224</b><i>b</i>, an agitator <b>226</b> and a discharge mechanism <b>228</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the first low speed shredder <b>224</b><i>a </i>and the second low speed shredder <b>224</b><i>b </i>are the same as, or similar to, the low speed shredder <b>24</b> discussed above and shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. However, in some embodiments the first low speed shredder <b>224</b><i>a </i>and the second low speed shredder <b>224</b><i>b </i>can be different from the low speed shredder <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the agitator <b>226</b> and the discharge mechanism <b>228</b> are the same as, or similar to, the agitator <b>26</b> and the discharge mechanism <b>28</b> described above and illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. Alternatively, the agitator <b>226</b> and the discharge mechanism <b>228</b> can be different from the agitator <b>26</b> and discharge mechanism <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the lower unit <b>212</b> also includes a first shredder guide shell <b>270</b><i>a </i>positioned partially around the first low speed shredder <b>224</b><i>a</i>, a second shredder guide shell <b>270</b><i>b </i>positioned partially around the second low speed shredder <b>224</b><i>b</i>, and an agitator guide shell <b>272</b> positioned partially around the agitator <b>226</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the shredder guide shells, <b>270</b><i>a </i>and <b>270</b><i>b</i>, and the agitator guide shell <b>272</b> are the same as, or similar to, the shredder guide shell <b>70</b> and the agitator guide shell <b>72</b> discussed above and illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. In other embodiments, the shredder guide shells, <b>270</b><i>a </i>and <b>270</b><i>b</i>, and the agitator guide shell <b>272</b> can be different from the shredder guide shell <b>70</b> and the agitator guide shell <b>72</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">As further shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the first shredder guide shell <b>270</b><i>a </i>has a first end <b>280</b><i>a </i>and a second end <b>280</b><i>b</i>. Similarly, the second shredder guide shell <b>270</b><i>b </i>has a first end <b>282</b><i>a </i>and a second end <b>282</b><i>b</i>. The agitator guide shell <b>272</b> has a first end <b>284</b><i>a </i>and a second end <b>284</b><i>b</i>. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the second end <b>280</b><i>b </i>of the first shredder guide shell <b>270</b><i>a </i>is offset in a vertical direction from the second end <b>282</b><i>b </i>of the second shredder guide shell <b>282</b><i>b </i>by an offset distance OD<b>200</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the offset distance OD<b>200</b> is in a range of from about 1.0 inch to about 8.0 inches. In other embodiments, the offset distance OD<b>200</b> can be less than about 1.0 inch or more than about 8.0 inches. Similarly, the second end <b>282</b><i>b </i>of the second shredder guide shell <b>270</b><i>b </i>is offset in a vertical direction from the second end <b>284</b><i>b </i>of the agitator guide shell <b>272</b> by an offset distance OD<b>210</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the offset distance OD<b>210</b> is in a range of from about 1.0 inch to about 8.0 inches. In other embodiments, the offset distance OD<b>210</b> can be less than about 1.0 inch or more than about 8.0 inches.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">While the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, shows the second end <b>280</b><i>b </i>of the first shredder guide shell <b>270</b><i>a </i>substantially coinciding with the first end <b>284</b><i>a </i>of the agitator guide shell <b>272</b>, it should be appreciated that in other embodiments the second end <b>280</b><i>b </i>of the shredder guide shell <b>270</b><i>a </i>may not substantially coincide with the first end <b>284</b><i>a </i>of the agitator guide shell <b>272</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the discharge mechanism <b>228</b> includes a valve housing <b>254</b>. The valve housing <b>254</b> extends to form a top inlet <b>290</b>. The top inlet <b>290</b> is configured to receive the finely conditioned loosefill insulation as it is falls from the agitator <b>226</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">As further shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, a passageway <b>292</b> is formed between the agitator <b>226</b> and the discharge mechanism <b>228</b>. The passageway <b>292</b> is configured to channel the finely conditioned loosefill insulation exiting the agitator <b>226</b> and falling into the discharge mechanism <b>228</b>. The passageway <b>292</b> includes a first segment <b>294</b> extending from the second end <b>284</b><i>b </i>of the agitator guide shell <b>272</b> to a first end <b>262</b> of the valve housing <b>254</b> and a second segment <b>296</b> extending in a downward from the second end <b>282</b><i>b </i>of the second shredder guide shell <b>270</b><i>b</i>. In the illustrated embodiment, the first and second segments, <b>294</b> and <b>296</b>, of the passageway <b>292</b> are made of high density polyethylene (hdpe) configured to provide a lightweight, low friction guide for the finely conditioned loosefill insulation. Alternatively, the first and second segments, <b>294</b> and <b>296</b>, can be made of other desired materials.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In operation, the first low speed shredder <b>224</b><i>a </i>rotates in the counter-clockwise direction indicated by the arrow R<b>200</b>. Similarly, the second low speed shredder <b>224</b><i>b </i>rotates in the counter-clockwise direction indicated by the arrow R<b>210</b>. The first low speed shredder <b>224</b><i>a </i>is configured to shred and pick apart the loosefill insulation. The shredded loosefill insulation exits the first low speed shredder <b>224</b><i>a </i>in the direction D<b>300</b> and enters the second low speed shredder <b>224</b><i>b</i>. The second low speed shredder <b>224</b><i>b </i>is configured to shred and pick apart the loosefill insulation. The shredded loosefill insulation exits the second low speed shredder <b>224</b><i>b </i>in the direction D<b>310</b> and enters the agitator <b>226</b>. The agitator <b>226</b> rotates in the counter-clockwise direction indicated by the arrow R<b>220</b>. The agitator <b>226</b> is configured to finely condition the loosefill insulation for distribution into an airstream (not shown) by further shredding the loosefill insulation. The finely conditioned loosefill insulation exits the agitator <b>226</b> in direction D<b>320</b> and contacts the second segment <b>296</b> of the passageway <b>292</b>. Contacting the second segment <b>296</b> causes the movement of the finely conditioned loosefill insulation to be deflected such that the finely conditioned loosefill insulation falls, by the force of gravity in direction D<b>330</b>, into the top inlet <b>290</b> of the discharge mechanism <b>228</b> for distribution into the airstream.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">While the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows the finely conditioned loosefill insulation contacting the second segment <b>296</b> of the passageway <b>292</b>, it should be appreciated that in other embodiments, the finely conditioned loosefill insulation can be directed to contact other structures, including the non-limiting example of a wall <b>240</b> of the lower unit <b>212</b> for the purpose of stopping the movement of the finely conditioned loosefill insulation. In a similar manner to the structure illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the combination of the offset guide shells and the vertical feed of the finely conditioned loosefill insulation advantageously provides for a smooth flow of the finely conditioned loosefill insulation through the shredding chamber and into the discharge mechanism <b>228</b> and substantially prevents the undesired build-up of accumulated loosefill insulation.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The principle and mode of operation of this loosefill blowing machine have been described in its preferred embodiments. However, it should be noted that the loosefill blowing machine may be practiced otherwise than as specifically illustrated and described without departing from its scope.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A machine for distributing loosefill insulation, the machine comprising:
<claim-text>a chute having an inlet end, the inlet end configured to receive the loosefill insulation;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lower unit associated with the chute, the lower unit including a shredder configured to shred and pick apart the loosefill insulation, the shredder further configured to guide the shredded insulation into an agitator, the shredder and the agitator positioned in substantially the same horizontal plane, the agitator configured to finely condition the loosefill insulation, the lower unit further including a shredder guide shell positioned partially around the shredder and configured to allow the shredder to seal against an inner surface of the shredder guide shell, and an agitator guide shell positioned partially around the agitator and configured to allow the agitator to seal against an inner surface of the agitator guide shell; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a discharge mechanism positioned in the lower unit, the discharge mechanism being configured to discharge loosefill insulation from an outlet of the lower unit, the discharge mechanism having a top inlet, the top inlet positioned below the agitator such that loosefill insulation exiting the agitator is allowed to fall in a substantially vertical direction from the agitator into the top inlet of the discharge mechanism;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a lower end of the shredder guide shell is offset in a vertical direction from a lower end of the agitator guide shell.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the loosefill insulation exiting the agitator is allowed to fall by the force of gravity from the agitator into the top inlet of the discharge mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a second end of the shredder guide shell positioned at the passageway is positioned vertically above a second end of the agitator guide shell positioned at the passageway.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the offset of the second end of the shredder guide shell from the second end of the agitator is in a range of from about 1.0 inch to about 8.0 inches.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein a first segment of the passageway extends from second end of the shredder guide shell to the discharge mechanism and a second segment of the passageway extends from the second end of the agitator guide shell to the discharge mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the discharge mechanism includes a valve housing, wherein the valve housing extends in a range of from about 260&#xb0; to about 300&#xb0;.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the top inlet has an opening in a range of from about 60&#xb0; to about 100&#xb0;.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the agitator is positioned substantially horizontally adjacent the low speed shredder.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A machine for distributing loosefill insulation, the machine comprising:
<claim-text>a chute having an inlet end, the inlet end configured to receive the loosefill insulation;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lower unit associated with the chute, the lower unit including a shredder configured to shred and pick apart the loosefill insulation, the shredder further configured to guide the shredded insulation into an agitator, the shredder and the agitator positioned in substantially the same horizontal plane, the agitator configured to finely condition the loosefill insulation, the lower unit further including a shredder guide shell positioned partially around the shredder and configured to allow the shredder to seal against an inner surface of the shredder guide shell, and an agitator guide shell positioned partially around the agitator, and configured to allow the agitator to seal against an inner surface of the agitator guide shell; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a discharge mechanism positioned in the lower unit, the discharge mechanism being configured to discharge loosefill insulation from an outlet of the lower unit, the discharge mechanism having a top inlet, the top inlet positioned below the agitator such that loosefill insulation exiting the agitator is directed by the agitator against a segment of a passageway positioned in the lower unit, the segment configured to stop movement of the loosefill insulation such that the loosefill insulation falls in a substantially vertical direction into the top inlet of the discharge mechanism;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a lower end of the shredder guide shell is offset in a vertical direction from a lower end of the agitator guide shell.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the segment extends upward from the top inlet of the discharge mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the segment is a wall of the lower unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the loosefill insulation exiting the agitator is allowed to fall by the force of gravity from the segment into the top inlet of the discharge mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein a second end of the shredder guide shell positioned at the passageway is positioned vertically above a second end of the agitator guide shell positioned at the passageway.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the offset of the second end of the shredder guide shell from the second end of the agitator is in a range of from about 1.0 inch to about 8.0 inches.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the agitator is positioned substantially horizontally adjacent the shredder.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the second end of the shredder guide shell and the first end of the agitator guide shell substantially coincide.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the shredder and the agitator rotate in the same direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. A machine for distributing loosefill insulation, the machine comprising:
<claim-text>a chute having an inlet end, the inlet end configured to receive the loosefill insulation;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lower unit associated with the chute, the lower unit including a first shredder, a second shredder and an agitator, the first and second shredders configured to shred and pick apart the loosefill insulation, the first shredder configured to guide the shredded insulation into the second shredder, the first and second shredders positioned in substantially the same horizontal plane, the agitator configured to finely condition the loosefill insulation, the lower unit further including a first shredder guide shell positioned partially around the first shredder and configured to allow the first shredder to seal against an inner surface of the first shredder guide shell, a second shredder guide shell positioned around the second shredder and configured to allow the second shredder to seal against an inner surface of the second shredder guide shell, and an agitator guide shell positioned partially around the agitator and configured to allow the agitator to seal against an inner surface of the agitator guide shell; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a discharge mechanism positioned in the lower unit, the discharge mechanism being configured to discharge loosefill insulation from an outlet of the lower unit, the discharge mechanism having a top inlet, the top inlet positioned adjacent the agitator such that loosefill insulation exiting the agitator is allowed to fall in a substantially vertical direction into the top inlet of the discharge mechanism;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a second end of the first shredder guide shell is offset in a vertical direction from a second end of the second shredder guide shell;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second end of the second shredder guide shell is offset in a vertical direction from a second end of the agitator guide shell.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the second end of the first shredder guide shell is positioned vertically above the second end of the shredder guide shell and the second end of the second shredder guide shell is positioned vertically above the second end of the agitator guide shell.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the offset between the second end of the first shredder guide shell and the second end of the second shredder guide shell is in a range of from about 1.0 inch to about 8.0 inches, and the offset between the second end of the second shredder guide shell and the second end of the agitator guide shell is in a range of from about 1.0 inch to about 8.0 inches. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
