<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623144-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623144</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13304333</doc-number>
<date>20111124</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>95121708 A</doc-number>
<date>20060616</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>256</us-term-extension>
<disclaimer>
<text>This patent is subject to a terminal disclaimer.</text>
</disclaimer>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>C</section>
<class>23</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>16</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>118729</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e73">Apparatus for manufacturing large-area carbon nanotube films</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0151835</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Croci et al.</name>
<date>20040800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4272491</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>16</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>118728</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>118729</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11608612</doc-number>
<date>20061208</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13304333</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120063968</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120315</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liu</last-name>
<first-name>Chang-Hong</first-name>
<address>
<city>Beijing</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Fan</last-name>
<first-name>Shou-Shan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Beijing</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liu</last-name>
<first-name>Chang-Hong</first-name>
<address>
<city>Beijing</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Fan</last-name>
<first-name>Shou-Shan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Beijing</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Tsinghua University</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Beijing</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Gramaglia</last-name>
<first-name>Maureen</first-name>
<department>1716</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An apparatus for manufacturing a large-area carbon nanotube film includes a reactor chamber, a helical-shaped substrate, and a supporter. The reactor chamber includes an inlet and an outlet. The inlet and the outlet are aligned on an axis of the reactor chamber. The helical-shaped substrate and the supporter are located wholly inside the reactor chamber. The supporter is moveable along the axis of the reactor chamber, and the helical-shaped substrate is supported by the supporter.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="107.95mm" wi="168.06mm" file="US08623144-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="208.03mm" wi="177.63mm" file="US08623144-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="176.45mm" wi="110.32mm" file="US08623144-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="164.17mm" wi="104.22mm" file="US08623144-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 11/608,612, filed on Dec. 8, 2006 entitled, &#x201c;APPARATUS AND METHOD FOR MANUFACTURING LARGE-AREA CARBON NANOTUBE FILMS&#x201d;. The disclosures of the above-identified applications are incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present application relates to an apparatus for manufacturing large-area carbon nanotubes films.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Discussion of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Carbon nanotubes are very small tube-shaped structures essentially having the composition of a graphite sheet, formed as a tube. Carbon nanotubes produced by arc discharge between graphite rods were first discovered and reported in an article by Sumio Iijima, entitled &#x201c;Helical Microtubules of Graphitic Carbon&#x201d; (Nature, Vol. 354, Nov. 7, 1991, pp. 56-58).</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">A carbon nanotube film is generally composed of a number of carbon nanotubes. In the carbon nanotube film, each carbon nanotube is perpendicular to a surface of the carbon nanotube film along its axis direction. Carbon nanotube films are electrically conductive and thermally conductive along the axes direction of the carbon nanotubes, are chemically stable, have electromagnetism shield function and so on. Due to these and other properties, it has been suggested that carbon nanotube films can play an important role in fields such as microscopic electronics, materials science, biology and chemistry.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">With the development of science and technology, large-area carbon nanotube films are more and more needed. At the present, carbon nanotube films are generally made on a base using a chemical vapor deposition (CVD) method. However, a reactor chamber for growing carbon nanotube film generally has a limited dimension, and, therefore, the dimension of the produced carbon nanotube films may be limited by the reactor chamber.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Therefore, an apparatus and method for manufacturing large-area carbon nanotube films are desired.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Many aspects of the present apparatus and method can be better understood with reference to the following drawings. The components in the drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the present apparatus and method. Moreover, in the drawings, like reference numerals designate corresponding parts throughout the several views.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view of an apparatus for manufacturing large-area carbon nanotube film, in accordance with a first embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic, cross-sectional view along line II-II of a helical-shaped substrate of the apparatus of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic, cross-sectional view a cylinder-shaped substrate of an apparatus for manufacturing large-area carbon nanotube film, in accordance with a second embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Reference will now be made to the drawings to describe the preferred embodiments of the present apparatus for manufacturing large-area carbon nanotube films, in detail.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, an apparatus <b>100</b> for manufacturing a large-area carbon nanotube film, in accordance with a first embodiment, is illustrated. The apparatus <b>100</b> mainly includes a reactor chamber <b>110</b>, a substrate <b>120</b> having a smoothly curved surface and a supporter <b>130</b>. The smoothly curved surface of the substrate <b>120</b> is provided for growing a carbon nanotube film thereon. The supporter <b>130</b> is used to fix the substrate <b>120</b> in the reactor chamber <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The reactor chamber <b>110</b> receives the substrate <b>120</b> and the supporter <b>130</b> therein. The reactor chamber <b>110</b> has an inlet <b>111</b> and an outlet <b>112</b>. The inlet <b>111</b> is configured for introducing a carbon-containing gas into the reactor chamber <b>110</b>, thus producing (i.e., acting as a source of) carbon atoms for growing the carbon nanotube film (not shown). The outlet <b>112</b> is configured for allowing an exhaust gas to be evacuated/discharged therefrom. Preferably, the inlet <b>111</b> and the outlet <b>112</b> are located at opposite sidewalls of the reactor chamber <b>110</b>, and the carbon-containing gas can flow from the inlet <b>111</b> to the outlet <b>112</b> along a direct path, and thus the exhaust gas can be discharged timely.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The reactor chamber <b>110</b> may have a circular, elliptic, triangular, rectangular, other regular polygonal or irregular polygonal profile in view of a cross section along line II-II of the reactor chamber <b>110</b>. The reactor chamber <b>110</b> may, usefully, be made of a material with a high temperature resistance and chemically stable performance. For example, the reactor chamber <b>110</b> may, advantageously, be made of quartz, ceramic, stainless steel or the like. In the present embodiment, the reactor chamber <b>110</b> is a tube, and has a circular cross section.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The reactor chamber <b>110</b> generally has a predetermined dimension. As such, if the substrate <b>120</b> to be received in the reactor chamber <b>110</b> is curved, the reactor chamber <b>110</b> can hold a larger-area substrate <b>120</b> for growing the carbon nanotube film. This increase in surface area for the substrate <b>120</b> can, in part, be maximized by using a substrate with a three-dimensional curvature, such as a spiral/helix (as per <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>) or a tube (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>). Thus, in a preferred embodiment, the substrate <b>120</b> is curved and configured for growing the carbon nanotube film thereon. The curved substrate <b>120</b> may, advantageously, be a cylinder structure or a helical structure. By employing a smooth curvature within the substrate <b>120</b>, with no sharp corners, converting a three-dimensional shape (e.g., the carbon nanotube film) to an essential two-dimensional shape becomes easier to achieve (i.e., reduced opportunity for breakage of the film).</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, in the present embodiment, the curved substrate <b>120</b> is configured to be helical shape in the tube-shaped reactor chamber <b>110</b>. In detail, the helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b> is formed through twisting a long strip substrate sheet. The helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b> may be arranged inside the reactor chamber <b>110</b> along a radial direction of the reactor chamber <b>110</b>, along an axis direction of the reactor chamber, or at an angle to the axis of the tubular reactor chamber <b>110</b>. In the present embodiment, the helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b> and the tubular reactor chamber <b>110</b> are coaxially aligned, that is, an axis of the helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b> parallel with that of the tubular reactor chamber <b>110</b>. The helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b> may, e.g., be made of a porous material, such as silicon dioxide (SiO<sub>2</sub>), aluminum oxide (Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>) or the like. Also, the helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b> may, e.g., be made of metal materials, for example, stainless steel, nickel (Ni) and so on. In the present embodiment, the helical substrate <b>120</b>, advantageously, is made of porous Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The supporter <b>130</b> is configured for supporting and fixing the helical substrate <b>120</b>. The supporter <b>130</b> has a first end <b>131</b> and an opposite second end <b>132</b>. The supporter <b>130</b> may be fixed wholly inside the reactor chamber <b>110</b>. For example, the first end <b>131</b> is connected with the reactor chamber <b>110</b>, and therefore the second end <b>132</b> freely locates inside the reactor chamber <b>110</b> to support the helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b>. The first end <b>131</b> may be movably fixed on an inner wall of the reactor chamber <b>110</b>. For example, a groove <b>113</b> is defined in the inner wall of the reactor chamber <b>110</b>, and the first end <b>131</b> is arranged in the groove <b>113</b> and can move freely in the groove <b>113</b>. As the first end <b>131</b> reaches a predetermined position of the groove <b>113</b>, a suitable fixture (not shown), such as a bolt, may be provided to fix the first end <b>131</b>. As such, a location of the helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b> in the reactor chamber <b>110</b> can be controlled via adjusting the first end <b>131</b> of the supporter <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Alternatively, the supporter <b>130</b> may be fixed partly inside the reactor chamber <b>110</b>. For example, the first end <b>131</b> is fixed outside of the reactor chamber <b>110</b>, and the wall of the reactor chamber <b>110</b> defines a through hole. The second end <b>132</b> locates freely inside the reactor chamber <b>110</b> through the through hole to support the helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, an apparatus <b>200</b> for manufacturing a carbon nanotube film, in accordance with a second embodiment, is illustrated. The apparatus <b>200</b> has a similar structure with the apparatus <b>100</b> of the first embodiment except for the substrate <b>220</b> for growing carbon nanotube film. The apparatus <b>200</b> includes a reactor chamber <b>210</b>, the substrate <b>220</b> and a supporter (not shown). The reactor chamber <b>210</b> has a same structure and made of a same material as the reactor chamber <b>110</b> of the first embodiment. Similarly, the supporter has a same structure and made of a same material as the supporter <b>130</b> of the first embodiment. The substrate <b>220</b> is configured to be a tubular shape (not necessarily cylindrical) and positioned in the reactor chamber <b>210</b>. In detail, the tube-shaped substrate <b>220</b> may be formed through curving a large-area substrate sheet. Further, the free, mating edges of the tube-shaped substrate <b>220</b> may or may not be sealed after the substrate sheet is curved. As such, the present tube-shaped substrate <b>220</b> is not necessarily an absolute tube, but is a sealed or unsealed tube. In order to easily describe the shape of the substrate <b>210</b>, both of the above two types of the tube (sealed tube and unsealed tube) are considered to be a tube in the following description.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The tube-shaped substrate <b>220</b> may have, for example, a circular, elliptic, triangular, rectangular, other regular polygonal or irregular polygonal cross-section. Exactly, the cross-sectional profile of the tube-shaped substrate <b>220</b>, as shown, is unsealed. In the present embodiment, the tube-shaped substrate <b>220</b> has an unsealed pentagram (i.e., star) profile in view of a cross section of the tube-shaped substrate <b>220</b>, and is made of nickel. The tube-shaped substrate <b>220</b> and the reactor chamber <b>210</b> are coaxially aligned, that is, the axis of the tube-shaped substrate <b>220</b> parallel with that of the reactor chamber <b>210</b>. While there is an advantage to having no sharp corners, the presence of sharp corners can permit a more complex geometrical shape (e.g., the star shape of the substrate <b>220</b>) and thereby potentially allow a substrate <b>220</b> with a greater surface area per volume to be formed. The greater the surface area of the substrate <b>220</b>, the larger the effective film size that can be generated within a particular reactor chamber <b>210</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Except the above first and second embodiments, the substrates <b>120</b> and <b>220</b> may have a wave shape, zigzag shape, conical shape, a meandering shape or other not flat surface structure. In addition, in the above embodiments, each substrate advantageously has at least one smooth, continuous surface section for growing carbon nanotube film thereon, even if corners do exist between adjoining sections.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Taking the apparatus <b>100</b> in accordance with the first embodiment as an example, a method for fabricating a large-area carbon nanotube film will be described in the following. In a general first step, a catalyst film is formed on at least a surface of the helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b>. The catalyst film may, advantageously, be made of iron (Fe), nickel (Ni), cobalt (Co), or any alloy thereof. The catalyst film may, usefully, be formed on at least one surface of the helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b> by evaporation deposition, ion plating or sputtering deposition method. In the present embodiment, an iron catalyst film, about five nanometers thick, is formed on one side surface of the helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b> by electron beam evaporation. The helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b> having the iron catalyst film is then annealed in air at 300&#xb0; C. overnight. This annealing step oxidizes the surface of the helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b> and the iron catalyst film to form a thin oxide layer. In the case of porous helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b> (the helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b> is made of Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>), the resulting thin oxide layer can protect its porous structure from collapsing later in the high-temperature CVD (Chemical Vapor Deposition) process.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In a general second step, the helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b> having the iron catalyst film is fixed in the reactor chamber <b>110</b> via the supporter <b>130</b>. The helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b> and the reactor chamber <b>110</b> are coaxially aligned. In the reacting process, the carbon-containing gas can flow from the inlet <b>111</b> to the outlet <b>112</b> along a direct path and can retain a relatively stable speed, for the carbon-containing gas not being blocked or interrupted by the helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b>. Thus, a uniform and high-ordered carbon nanotube film can be grown on the helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b>. The ordered carbon nanotube film is a continuous carbon nanotubes array, which continuously grow and perpendicular to the surface of the helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b> along the length of the carbon nanotube.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Finally, the reactor chamber <b>110</b> is heated to 700&#xb0; C. in flowing an inert gas (e.g., argon, nitrogen) in the reactor chamber <b>110</b>. For example, the inert gas is introduced into the inlet <b>111</b> and is discharged from the outlet <b>112</b>. Then the carbon-containing gas (e.g., ethylene, methane, ethane, propane) is flown at about 1000 sccm (Standard Cubic Centimeters Minute) for 15 minutes to 60 minutes, approximately, after which the reactor chamber <b>110</b> is cooled to room temperature, and thus, a large-area high ordered carbon nanotube film is formed on the surface of the helical-shaped substrate <b>120</b>. A desired thickness of the ordered carbon nanotube film can be controlled by controlling the growth of the array of carbon nanotube of the ordered carbon nanotube film. For example, the thickness of the ordered carbon nanotube film can be roughly controlled, advantageously, be controlling a growth time, or other known growth factors (e.g., temperature, gas concentration, catalyst characteristics) may conjunctively or alternatively be regulated.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Alternatively, in the above-described embodiment, the reactor chamber <b>110</b> can be pumped up to a certain vacuum degree. A working gas, such as a mixture of the inert gas and the carbon-containing gas with a predetermined mixing proportion and a predetermined flowing speed is then continuously introduced into the evacuated reactor chamber <b>110</b> from the inlet <b>111</b>, and is discharged from the outlet <b>112</b> continuously. As such, the working gas can retain a flowing state in the carbon nanotube film growing process, and as thus, the carbon-containing gas in the working gas can maintain its original concentration. As a result, a large-area high quality carbon nanotube film, such as a high uniform thickness and high ordered carbon nanotube film, can be created.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">As above described, for a reactor chamber with a limited dimension, the substrate for growing carbon nanotube film is configured to be a curved, three-dimensional shape (i.e., not a flat shape, two-dimensional shape), and thus the limited dimension reactor chamber can hold a large-area substrate. Therefore, a corresponding large-area carbon nanotube film can be grown. It is to be understood a curved shape, in the context of the present apparatus, may be continuously smooth or may include distinct corners (i.e., abrupt curvature).</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">It is believed that the present embodiment and their advantages will be understood from the foregoing description, and it will be apparent that various changes may be made thereto without departing from the spirit and scope of the disclosure or sacrificing all of its material advantages, the examples hereinbefore described merely being preferred or exemplary embodiments of the disclosure. The present disclosure relates to a carbon nanotube film, a carbon nanotube film precursor, a manufacturing method thereof and a light source including the carbon nanotube film.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An apparatus for manufacturing a large-area carbon nanotube film, the apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a reactor chamber comprising an inlet and an outlet located at opposite sidewalls of the reactor chamber, wherein the inlet and the outlet are aligned with an axis of the reactor chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a helical-shaped substrate located wholly inside the reactor chamber, wherein a radius of the helical-shaped substrate gradually increases along the axis of the reactor chamber; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a supporter located wholly inside the reactor chamber and supporting the helical-shaped substrate, wherein the supporter is perpendicular to the axis of the reactor chamber.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the helical-shaped substrate and the reactor chamber are coaxially arranged.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the helical-shaped substrate is arranged in the reactor chamber at an angle to the axis of the reactor chamber.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the supporter comprises a first end and a second end, the first end is movably fixed on an inner wall of the reactor chamber, and the second end is located inside the reactor chamber attached to the helical-shaped substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the inner wall of the reactor chamber defines a groove, and the first end is movably fixed in the groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, further comprising a fixture fixing the first end when the first end reaches a predetermined position of the groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein a location of the helical-shaped substrate in the reactor chamber is movable by moving the first end of the supporter along a direction parallel to the axis of the reactor chamber.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. An apparatus for manufacturing a large-area carbon nanotube film, the apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a reactor chamber comprising an inlet and an outlet located at opposite sidewalls of the reactor chamber, wherein the inlet and the outlet are aligned along an axis of the reactor chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a helical-shaped substrate located wholly inside the reactor chamber, wherein a radius of the helical-shaped substrate gradually increases along the axis of the reactor chamber; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a supporter located wholly inside the reactor chamber, wherein the supporter is movable along the axis of the reactor chamber, and supports the helical-shaped substrate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the supporter comprises a first end and a second end, the first end is movably fixed on an inner wall of the reactor chamber, and the second end is located inside the reactor chamber attached to the helical-shaped substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the inner wall of the reactor chamber defines a groove, and the first end is movably fixed in the groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising a fixture to fix the first end when the first end reaches a predetermined position of the groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein a location of the helical-shaped substrate in the reactor chamber is controlled by moving the first end in the groove along a direction parallel to the axis of the reactor chamber.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the groove is parallel to the axis of the reactor chamber.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the reactor chamber is tubular.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the supporter is perpendicular to the axis of the reactor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. An apparatus for manufacturing a large-area carbon nanotube film, the apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a reactor chamber comprising an inlet and an outlet located at opposite sidewalls of the reactor chamber, wherein the inlet and the outlet are aligned with an axis of the reactor chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a helical-shaped substrate located wholly inside the reactor chamber; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a supporter located wholly inside the reactor chamber, wherein the supporter is moveable along the axis of the reactor chamber, supports the helical-shaped substrate, and is perpendicular to the axis of the reactor chamber.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the supporter comprises a first end and a second end, the first end is movably fixed on an inner wall of the reactor chamber, and the second end is located inside the reactor chamber attached to the helical-shaped substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the inner wall of the reactor chamber defines a groove, and the first end is movably fixed in the groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, further comprising a fixture fixing the first end when the first end reaches a predetermined position of the inner wall.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein a location of the helical-shaped substrate in the reactor chamber is moveable along a direction parallel to the axis of the reactor chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
