<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624841-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624841</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12265947</doc-number>
<date>20081106</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2008-0027062</doc-number>
<date>20080324</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>883</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>345168</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Method and apparatus for displaying touch screen keyboard</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0122313</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ashby</name>
<date>20050600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>345168</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>9</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>345168</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>16</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20090237359</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20090924</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Bo-mi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yongin-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kyung</last-name>
<first-name>Bo-hyun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yongin-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Choi</last-name>
<first-name>Myoung-soon</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yongin-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="004" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yang</last-name>
<first-name>Pil-seung</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="005" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Hark-joon</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="006" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Dae-hyun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="007" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Han</last-name>
<first-name>Sang-jun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="008" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Han</last-name>
<first-name>Kuk-hyun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Bo-mi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yongin-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kyung</last-name>
<first-name>Bo-hyun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yongin-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Choi</last-name>
<first-name>Myoung-soon</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yongin-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="004" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yang</last-name>
<first-name>Pil-seung</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="005" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Hark-joon</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="006" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Dae-hyun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="007" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Han</last-name>
<first-name>Sang-jun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="008" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Han</last-name>
<first-name>Kuk-hyun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Sughrue Mion, PLLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Mengistu</last-name>
<first-name>Amare</first-name>
<department>2695</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Rodriguez</last-name>
<first-name>Joseph G</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Provided are a method and apparatus for displaying various types of touch screen keyboards at various positions according to an information input condition of a user. The method includes recognizing a point on a touch screen which a reference finger of at least one hand of a user touches, and displaying a touch screen keyboard including keys arranged according to the recognized point. Accordingly, a user-based touch screen keyboard which can be easily used, allow information to be quickly input, and reduce touch error, can be provided.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="71.80mm" wi="120.82mm" file="US08624841-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="139.02mm" wi="119.97mm" file="US08624841-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="123.70mm" wi="123.36mm" file="US08624841-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="154.09mm" wi="88.05mm" file="US08624841-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="148.67mm" wi="98.72mm" file="US08624841-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="145.88mm" wi="120.31mm" file="US08624841-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="118.45mm" wi="77.72mm" file="US08624841-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="127.42mm" wi="82.13mm" file="US08624841-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED PATENT APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority from Korean Patent Application No. 10-2008-0027062, filed on Mar. 24, 2008, in the Korean Intellectual Property Office, the disclosure of which is incorporated herein in its entirety by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Methods and apparatuses consistent with the present invention relate to displaying a touch screen keyboard.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In general, a touch screen is an input device replacing a traditional keyboard or a mouse. Touch screen keyboards are keyboards based on touch screens. Accordingly, when a user touches a key on a touch screen keyboard by using his/her finger or a touch pen, an apparatus having a touch screen function (referred to as a touch screen apparatus hereinafter) recognizes that a signal corresponding to the touched key is input.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Conventional touch screen keyboards are based on touch screen apparatuses. Accordingly, touch screen keyboards having display positions and display sizes designated according to touch screen apparatuses are provided to users. For example, when a touch screen apparatus has a large size, a touch screen keyboard including keys each having a large touch area may be displayed, and when a touch screen apparatus has a small size, a touch screen keyboard including keys each having a small touch area may be displayed.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">As such, conventional touch screen keyboards are displayed at positions in sizes which are designated according to touch screen apparatuses, and have a similar key arrangement to that of conventional keyboards. Accordingly, when a user controls a touch screen keyboard by using his/her fingers, he/she should control the touch screen keyboard by using both his/her hands in a similar manner to that used to control a conventional keyboard.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Also, since touch areas for respective keys of the touch screen keyboard that is based on a touch screen apparatus are fixed, a touch error may be caused while using the user's fingers. For example, when the user touches a key by using his/her little finger, the little finger may fail to precisely touch a center point of a touch area of the key, thereby causing a touch error.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The present invention provides a method and apparatus for displaying a touch screen keyboard based on a user.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The present invention also provides a method and apparatus for displaying a touch screen keyboard, whereby various types of touch screen keyboards can be displayed at various positions according to an information input condition of a user.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to an aspect of the present invention, there is provided a method of displaying a touch screen keyboard, the method comprising recognizing a point on a touch screen which a reference finger of at least one hand of a user touches, and displaying a touch screen keyboard comprising keys arranged according to the recognized point.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">If the user's right hand is used, the reference finger is an index finger of the right hand, and if the user's left hand is used, the reference finger may be an index finger of the left hand.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The displaying of the touch screen keyboard may comprise displaying a first touch screen keyboard controlled by the right hand according to a first point on the touch screen which the index finger of the right hand touches; and displaying a second touch screen keyboard controlled by the left hand according to a second point on the touch screen which the index finger of the left hand touches.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">If there exists a first key having a touch area whose center point is not controlled, each of the displaying of the first touch screen keyboard and the displaying of the second touch screen keyboard may comprise adjusting the center point of the touch area of the first key.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The adjusting of the center point of the touch area of the first key may comprise if it is determined that a real touch position of the first key is closer to a touch area of a second key which the reference finger controls than the center point of the touch area of the first key, moving the center point of the touch area of the first key to a position closer to the touch area of the second key, and if it is determined that the real touch position of the first key is farther from the touch area of the second key than the center point of the touch area of the first key, enlarging a display area of the first key.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The adjusting of the center point of the touch area of the first key may comprise if it is determined that a real touch position of the first key is closer to a touch area of a second key which the reference finger controls than the center point of the touch area of the first key, moving the center point of the touch area of the first key to a position closer to the touch area of the second key, and if it is determined that the real touch position of the first key is farther from the touch area of the second key than the center point of the touch area of the first key, separating a display area of the first key from displays areas of other keys and moving the separated display area of the first key.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The first touch screen keyboard and the second touch screen keyboard may be displayed by overlapping one or more keys. The recognizing of the point may be performed by using a puck.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The changing of the displayed touch screen keyboard may comprise if the finger is moved on the basis of the puck, displaying the touch screen keyboard so as to emphasize an upper key row above a reference key row, and if the finger is moved downward on the basis of the puck, displaying the touch screen keyboard so as to emphasize a lower key row below the reference key row.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The changing of the displayed touch screen keyboard may comprise if the finger is not moved on the basis of the puck, displaying the touch screen keyboard so as to emphasize the reference key row.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The method may further comprise checking a distance between the first point and the second point, and when it is determined that the distance is less than a predetermined distance, reducing the display size of each of the first touch screen keyboard and the second touch screen keyboard.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">According to another aspect of the present invention, there is provided an apparatus for displaying a touch screen keyboard, the apparatus comprising a display unit which displays a touch screen keyboard, a touch screen which recognizes a point that a user's finger touches, a storage unit which stores touch screen keyboard information, and a control unit which displays the touch screen keyboard information read from the storage unit at a position on the display unit which is determined according to a point of a reference finger of at least one hand of the user which is recognized by the touch screen.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The above and other features and advantages of the present invention will become more apparent by describing in detail exemplary embodiments thereof with reference to the attached drawings in which:</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram of an apparatus for displaying a touch screen keyboard, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</figref> illustrate touch screen keyboards displayed on a display unit of the apparatus of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A through 3E</figref> illustrate original center points and changed center points of keys, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A and 4B</figref> illustrate a touch screen keyboard including overlapped keys, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates a touch screen keyboard including overlapped keys, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates a touch screen keyboard based on a reference point using a puck, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a diagram for explaining a method of changing a displayed touch screen keyboard as a user's finger is moved, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8A and 8B</figref> illustrate a touch screen keyboard adjusted based on a distance between two reference points, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a flowchart illustrating a method of displaying a touch screen keyboard, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF EXEMPLARY EMBODIMENTS OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">According to exemplary embodiments of the present invention, there is provided a method and apparatus for displaying various types of touch screen keyboards based on a user by varying the display position of a first touch screen keyboard including keys controlled by a user's right hand and a second touch screen keyboard including keys controlled by the user's left hand on the basis of a point of a touch screen which is recognized by an element, such as an index finger of each hand or a puck, adjusting a center point of a touch area if necessary, changing a displayed touch screen keyboard according to the movement of a finger, and reducing the sizes of the first touch screen keyboard and the second touch screen keyboard according to a detected relation between reference points.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Additionally, exemplary embodiments of the present invention provide a method and apparatus for displaying a user-based touch screen keyboard on the basis of an element, such as an index finger of a hand or a puck corresponding to the index finger of the hand.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The present invention will now be described more fully with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which exemplary embodiments of the invention are shown.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram of an apparatus <b>100</b> for displaying a touch screen keyboard, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention. The apparatus <b>100</b> may be any electronic device having a touch screen function. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the apparatus <b>100</b> includes a display unit <b>110</b>, a touch screen <b>120</b>, a control unit <b>130</b>, and a storage unit <b>140</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The display unit <b>110</b> displays a touch screen keyboard. The display unit <b>110</b> may be a liquid crystal display (LCD). The touch screen keyboard displayed on the display unit <b>110</b> may be one of a plurality of application programs which can be executed in the apparatus <b>100</b>. The display unit <b>110</b> may display not only the touch screen keyboard, but also other application programs. The display unit <b>110</b> may display the touch screen keyboard while displaying other application programs. The touch screen keyboard is displayed on the display unit <b>110</b> when the apparatus <b>110</b> is set to a touch screen keyboard display mode.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The touch screen <b>120</b> recognizes a point (or location) on the touch screen <b>120</b> which a user's finger touches. To this end, the touch screen <b>120</b> may be configured to sense a pressure applied thereto. For example, the touch screen <b>120</b> may be configured to have sensor lines reacting to a pressure, sensors located around an electrically charged surface, or touch sensors. The touch screen <b>120</b> converts the recognized touch into a point signal and outputs the point signal to the control unit <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The control unit <b>130</b> drives an application program of the apparatus <b>100</b> according to the point signal received from the touch screen <b>120</b>, and displays necessary information on the display unit <b>110</b>. In particular, when the control unit <b>130</b> receives a point signal of a reference finger of one or both hands of the user from the touch screen <b>120</b>, the control unit <b>130</b> displays touch screen keyboard information, read from the storage unit <b>140</b>, at a position on the display unit <b>110</b> which is determined by the received point signal.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">To this end, the control unit <b>130</b> may include a functional unit (not shown) receiving the point signal (or information) output from the touch screen <b>120</b>, a functional unit (not shown) analyzing the received information, and a functional unit (not shown) operating the apparatus <b>100</b> according to the analysis result. The functional unit receiving the point signal may be defined as an input/output control unit for the touch screen <b>120</b>. The apparatus <b>100</b> may be configured so that the functional unit receiving the point signal is not included in the control unit <b>130</b> but is disposed between the control unit <b>130</b> and the touch screen <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The control unit <b>130</b> may receive only a point signal of a reference point of the right hand, receive only a point signal of a reference finger of the left hand, or receive point signals of reference fingers of the right and left hands.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">When the right hand is used, the reference finger may be an index finger of the right hand. When the left hand is used, the reference finger may be an index finger of the left hand.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The control unit <b>130</b> may display on the display unit <b>110</b> a first touch screen keyboard controlled by the right hand on the basis of a first point on the touch screen <b>120</b> which the index finger of the right hand touches, and display on the display unit <b>110</b> a second touch screen keyboard controlled by the left hand on the basis of a second point on the touch screen <b>120</b> which the index finger of the left hand touches.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</figref> illustrate touch screen keyboards displayed on the display unit <b>110</b> of the apparatus <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, reference numeral <b>201</b> denotes a first point, and reference numeral <b>210</b> denotes a first touch screen keyboard. Accordingly, the first touch screen keyboard <b>210</b> is the touch screen keyboard controlled by the user's right hand. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, reference numeral <b>202</b> denotes a second point, and reference numeral <b>211</b> denotes a second touch screen keyboard. Accordingly, the second touch screen keyboard <b>211</b> is the touch screen keyboard controlled by the user's left hand. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> illustrates a touch screen keyboard displayed when the index finger of the right hand of the user touches a center point of a key corresponding to the first point <b>201</b> and the index finger of the left hand of the user touches a center point of a key corresponding to the second point <b>202</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref> illustrates a touch screen keyboard displayed when a first point <b>221</b> is recognized and a second point <b>222</b> is recognized.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</figref>, the display position of a touch screen keyboard may be varied according to a point on the touch screen <b>110</b> which a reference finger of one hand or both hands of the user touches, and the touch screen keyboard may be displayed after being divided into a first touch screen keyboard including keys controlled by the right hand and a second touch screen keyboard including keys controlled by the left hand.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Although each of the first touch screen keyboard and the second touch screen keyboard includes keys arranged in a matrix of 3 rows by 5 columns in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</figref>, the keys included in each of the first touch screen keyboard and the second touch screen keyboard may be arranged in a matrix of at least 1 row by at least 2 columns.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">When there exists at least one first key having a touch area whose center point is not controlled among keys included in the first touch screen keyboard and the second touch screen keyboard, the control unit <b>130</b> may adjust the center point of the touch area of the first key.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A through 3E</figref> illustrate original center points and changed center points of keys, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention. When keys T, R, E, W, and Q included in a touch screen keyboard displayed on the display unit <b>110</b> respectively have original center points <b>301</b>, <b>302</b>, <b>303</b>, <b>304</b>, and <b>305</b>, and a touch on the center point <b>305</b> of the key Q is not recognized, the control unit <b>130</b> divides a touch area <b>310</b> of the key Q into 9 areas as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, and counts the number of touches on each divided area for a predetermined period of time. When it is determined that the number of touches on an area <b>306</b> is the highest among the 9 areas, the control unit <b>130</b> judges that the area <b>306</b> among the divided areas of the touch area <b>310</b> of the key Q is a real touch area that the user often touches, and changes the area <b>306</b> to a center point of the key Q in order to operate the touch screen keyboard.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Although the touch area <b>310</b> is divided into 9 areas in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, the present invention is not limited thereto, and the touch area <b>310</b> may be divided into n areas where n is an integer greater than 2. The fact that the touch on the center point <b>305</b> of the key Q is not recognized means that the key Q is controlled by the user but a value recognized by the touch on the key Q on the touch screen <b>110</b> is less than a predetermined threshold value. The predetermined period of time may be set in advance.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref> illustrates that, when it is determined that the touch on the center point <b>305</b> of the key Q is not recognized, the touch area <b>310</b> of the key Q is enlarged to an area <b>311</b> by the control unit <b>130</b>. Accordingly, the center point <b>305</b> of the key Q is enlarged to a point <b>307</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3D</figref> illustrates that, when it is determined that the touch on the center point <b>305</b> of the key Q is not recognized, the touch area <b>310</b> of the key Q is separated from touch areas of the other keys and then enlarged to an area <b>312</b> by the control unit <b>130</b>. That is, the touch area <b>310</b> of the key Q is separated from the touch areas of the other keys W, E, R, and T and then enlarged to the touch area <b>312</b>. The other keys and the key Q may constitute one group. Accordingly, the center point <b>305</b> of the touch area <b>310</b> of the key Q is enlarged to a point <b>309</b>, such that the position of the center point <b>305</b> is changed.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3E</figref> illustrate that, when it is determined that touches on the center points <b>301</b>, <b>303</b>, <b>304</b>, and <b>305</b> of the keys T, E, W, and Q, respectively, are not recognized, the touch areas of the keys T, E, W, and Q are separated from the touch area of the key R by the control unit <b>130</b> such that the center points <b>301</b>, <b>303</b>, <b>304</b>, and <b>305</b> of the keys T, E, W, and Q are changed to <b>301</b>&#x2032;, <b>303</b>&#x2032;, <b>304</b>&#x2032;, and <b>305</b>&#x2032;, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">It can be seen from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A through 3E</figref> that, when there exists at least one first key whose center point is not controlled but whose touch area is controlled on the touch screen keyboard displayed on the display unit <b>110</b>, if it is determined that a real touch position of the first key is closer to a touch area of a second key that is controlled by the reference finger than the center point of the touch area of the first key, the control unit <b>130</b> may adjust the center point of the first key to move the center point of the touch area of the first key to a position closer to the touch area of the second key as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, the key Q corresponds to the first key and the key R corresponds to the second key.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">When it is determined that the real touch position of the first key is farther away from the touch area of the second key than the center point of the touch area of the first key, the control unit <b>130</b> may adjust the center point by enlarging a display area of the first key as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">When it is determined that the real touch position of the first key is farther away from the touch area of the second key than the center point of the touch area of the first key, the control unit <b>130</b> may adjust the center point by separating the display area of the first key from display areas of other keys and moving the display area of the first key as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3D</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Also, the control unit <b>130</b> may display the first touch screen keyboard and the second touch screen keyboard in such a manner that one or more keys are overlapped on the basis of touch screen keyboard information stored in the storage unit <b>140</b>. That is, when the first and second touch screen keyboards having no overlapped keys as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</figref> are stored in the storage unit <b>140</b>, the control unit <b>130</b> reads this information from the storage unit <b>140</b> and displays the information on the display unit <b>110</b>. However, when the first and second touch screen keyboards having one or more overlapped keys as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A and 4B</figref> are stored in the storage unit <b>140</b>, the control unit <b>130</b> may display the first and second touch screen keyboards having the one or more overlapped keys on the display unit <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref> illustrates one row of keys that are controlled by the left hand, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</figref> illustrates one row of keys that are controlled by the right hand, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention. Keys T and Y among the keys are overlapped in a touch area <b>401</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates a touch screen keyboard on the display unit <b>110</b>, including overlapped space bars, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, reference numeral <b>501</b> denotes a touch screen keyboard controlled by the user's left hand, and reference numeral <b>502</b> denotes a touch screen keyboard controlled by the user's right hand. Space bar keys <b>503</b> and <b>504</b> of the touch screen keyboards <b>501</b> and <b>502</b>, respectively, are overlapped because the space bar keys <b>503</b> and <b>504</b> can be pressed with either hand. Accordingly, the overlapped keys may be determined based on whether they can be pressed with either hand.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The storage unit <b>140</b> stores touch screen keyboard information on each of the first touch screen keyboard and the second touch screen keyboard. The storage unit <b>140</b> may store first touch screen keyboard information and second touch screen keyboard information so as to support all or any one of such types as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 through 5</figref> according to the user's selection.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates a touch screen keyboard <b>602</b> on the touch screen <b>120</b> based on a reference point using a puck <b>601</b>, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, since the puck <b>601</b> is located on the touch screen <b>120</b>, the same effect as if the reference finger of one or both hands touches the touch screen <b>120</b> can be achieved. That is, the puck <b>601</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> may perform the same function as that of the index finger of the left hand of the user. When the puck <b>601</b> is located on the touch screen <b>120</b>, the control unit <b>130</b> displays the touch screen keyboard <b>602</b> including keys arranged in a matrix of 3 rows by 5 columns, which are controlled by the user's left hand, on the display unit <b>110</b>. When two pucks are located on the touch screen <b>120</b>, two touch screen keyboards may be displayed on the display unit <b>110</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>. Whether the puck <b>601</b> located on the touch screen <b>120</b> corresponds to the index finger of the right hand or to the index finger of the left hand may be determined by considering the entire area of the touch screen <b>120</b> and the position of the puck <b>601</b> on the touch screen <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">When the apparatus <b>100</b> is configured so that the puck <b>601</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> detects the movement of the finger of the user and the touch screen <b>120</b> recognizes the detection result, the control unit <b>130</b> may change a touch screen keyboard displayed on the display unit <b>110</b> on the basis of a signal corresponding to the movement of the finger of the user which is transmitted from the touch screen <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a diagram for explaining a method of changing a displayed touch screen keyboard as the user's finger is moved, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, when the touch screen <b>120</b> recognizes in operation <b>701</b> that his/her finger is moved upward on the basis of the puck <b>601</b>, the control unit <b>130</b> may display the touch screen keyboard so as to emphasize an upper key row <b>710</b> above a reference key row. The emphasis may be performed by making a touch area of the upper key row <b>710</b> larger than a touch area of the reference key row or making the color of the touch area of the upper key row <b>710</b> different from that of the touch area of the reference key row.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">When the touch screen <b>120</b> recognizes in operation <b>702</b> that his/her finger is moved downward on the basis of the puck, the control unit <b>130</b> may display the touch screen keyboard so as to emphasize a lower key row <b>720</b> below the reference key row.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Also, the control unit <b>130</b> checks a distance between a first point and a second point. The first point and the second point are similar to those described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. When it is determined that the distance is less than a predetermined distance, the control unit <b>130</b> may reduce the display size of each of the first touch screen keyboard and the second touch screen keyboard and display the reduced first touch screen keyboard and the reduced second touch screen keyboard on the display unit <b>110</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8A and 8B</figref> illustrate a touch screen keyboard adjusted based on a distance between two reference points, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</figref>, when a distance d<b>1</b> between a first point p<b>1</b> and a second point p<b>2</b> is less than a predetermined distance, a first touch screen keyboard <b>801</b> and a second touch screen keyboard <b>802</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</figref> may be reduced in size to a first touch screen keyboard <b>801</b>&#x2032; and a second touch screen keyboard <b>802</b>&#x2032; of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8B</figref> and the reduced first touch screen keyboard <b>801</b>&#x2032; and the reduced second touch screen keyboard <b>802</b>&#x2032; may be displayed. Whether the distance is less than the predetermined distance may be determined by considering whether the first touch screen keyboard <b>801</b> and the second touch screen keyboard <b>802</b> are overlaid on the touch screen <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a flowchart illustrating a method of displaying a touch screen keyboard, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">In operation <b>901</b>, a point on a touch screen which a reference finger of one or both hands of a user touches is recognized. When the user's right hand is used, the reference finger may be an index finger of the right hand. When the user's left hand is used, the reference finger may be an index finger of the left hand.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">In operation <b>902</b>, a touch screen keyboard including keys arranged according to the recognized point is displayed. Operation <b>902</b> may include displaying a first touch screen keyboard controlled by the right hand according to a first point on the touch screen which the index finger of the right hand touches and displaying a second touch screen keyboard controlled by the left hand according to a second point on the touch screen which the index finger of the left hand touches.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">When there exists a first key having a touch area whose center point is not controlled, the displaying of the first touch screen keyboard and the displaying of the second touch screen keyboard may include adjusting the center point of the touch area of the first key.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The adjusting of the center point of the touch area of the first key may include, when it is determined that a real touch position of the first key is closer to a touch area of a second key controlled by the reference finger than the center point of the touch area of the first key is, moving the center point of the touch area of the first key to a position closer to the touch area of the second key, and when it is determined that the real touch position of the first key is farther away from the touch area of the second than the center point of the touch area of the first key is, enlarging a display area of the first key.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">Alternatively, the adjusting of the center point of the touch area of the first key may include, when the real touch position of the first key is closer to the touch area of the second key controlled by the reference finger than the center point of the touch area of the first key is, moving the center point of the touch area of the first key to a position closer to the touch area of the second key, and when it is determined that the real touch position of the first key is farther away from the touch area of the second key than the center point of the touch area of the first key is, separating the display area of the first key from display areas of other keys and moving the separated display area of the first key.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">The first touch screen keyboard and the second touch screen keyboard may be displayed by overlapping one or more keys as described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A and 4B</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">Operation <b>902</b> may include checking a distance between the first point and the second point and, when it is determined that the distance is less than a predetermined distance, reducing the display size of each of the first touch screen keyboard and the second touch screen keyboard. The first point, the second point, the first touch screen keyboard, and the second touch screen keyboard are similar to those as described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">Operation <b>901</b> may include recognizing the point by using a puck as described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. In this case, operation <b>902</b> may include checking the movement of the finger of the user on the basis of the puck, and changing a displayed touch screen keyboard displayed according to the checking result. That is, when the finger is moved upward on the basis of the puck as described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the touch screen keyboard may be displayed so as to emphasize an upper key row above a reference key row, when the finger is moved downward on the basis of the puck, the touch screen keyboard is displayed so as to emphasize a lower key row below the reference key row, and when the finger is not moved on the basis of the puck, the touch screen keyboard may be displayed so as to emphasize the reference key row.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">The present invention may be embodied as computer-readable codes on a computer-readable recording medium. The computer-readable recording medium is any data storage device that can store data which can be thereafter read by a computer system. Examples of the computer-readable recording medium include read-only memories (ROMs), random-access memories (RAMs), CD-ROMs, magnetic tapes, floppy disks, and optical data storage devices. The computer-readable recording medium can also be distributed over network coupled computer systems so that the compute readable code is stored and executed in a distributed fashion. Additionally, the present invention may be embodied as a computer-readable transmission medium. The computer-readable transmission medium may be carrier waves (such as data transmission through the Internet).</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">As described above, since various types of touch screen keyboards can be displayed at various positions according to an information input condition of a user, e.g., the position of an index finger of the user, a user-customized touch screen keyboard (or a user-based touch screen keyboard), which can be easily used, allow information to be quickly input, and reduce touch error, can be provided.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">While the present invention has been particularly shown and described with reference to exemplary embodiments thereof, it will be understood by those of ordinary skill in the art that various changes in form and detail may be made therein without departing from the spirit and scope of the present invention as defined by the following claims. The exemplary embodiments should be considered in a descriptive sense only and not for purposes of limitation. Therefore, the scope of the invention is defined not by the detailed description of the invention but by the appended claims, and all differences within the scope will be construed as being included in the present invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method of displaying a touch screen keyboard, the method comprising:
<claim-text>recognizing a point on a touch screen which a reference finger of at least one hand of a user touches; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying a touch screen keyboard comprising keys arranged according to the recognized point,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, when the user's right hand is used, the reference finger is an index finger of the right hand, and when the user's left hand is used, the reference finger is an index finger of the left hand,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the displaying of the touch screen keyboard comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying a first touch screen keyboard controlled by the right hand according to a first point on the touch screen which the index finger of the right hand touches; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying a second touch screen keyboard controlled by the left hand according to a second point on the touch screen which the index finger of the left hand touches;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, when there exists a first key having a touch area whose center point is not controlled, each of the displaying of the first touch screen keyboard and the displaying of the second touch screen keyboard comprises adjusting the center point of the touch area of the first key,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the adjusting of the center point of the touch area of the first key comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>when it is determined that a real touch position of the first key is closer to a touch area of a second key which the reference finger controls than the center point of the touch area of the first key, moving the center point of the touch area of the first key to a position closer to the touch area of the second key; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>when it is determined that the real touch position of the first key is farther from the touch area of the second key than the center point of the touch area of the first key, enlarging a display area of the first key.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the adjusting of the center point of the touch area of the first key comprises:
<claim-text>when it is determined that a real touch position of the first key is closer to a touch area of a second key which the reference finger controls than the center point of the touch area of the first key, moving the center point of the touch area of the first key to a position closer to the touch area of the second key; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>when it is determined that the real touch position of the first key is farther from the touch area of the second key than the center point of the touch area of the first key, separating a display area of the first key from displays areas of other keys and moving the separated display area of the first key.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A method of displaying a touch screen keyboard, the method comprising:
<claim-text>recognizing a point on a touch screen which a reference finger of at least one hand of a user touches; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying a touch screen keyboard comprising keys arranged according to the recognized point, wherein the recognizing of the point is performed by using a puck,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the displaying of the touch screen keyboard comprises:
<claim-text>checking the movement of the finger of the user on the basis of the puck; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>changing the displayed touch screen keyboard according to the checking result</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the changing of the displayed touch screen keyboard comprises:
<claim-text>when the finger is moved upward on the basis of the puck, displaying the touch screen keyboard so as to emphasize an upper key row above a reference key row; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>when the finger is moved downward on the basis of the puck, displaying the touch screen keyboard so as to emphasize a lower key row below the reference key row.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the changing of the displayed touch screen keyboard comprises:
<claim-text>when the finger is not moved on the basis of the puck, displaying the touch screen keyboard so as to emphasize the reference key row.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A method of displaying a touch screen keyboard, the method comprising:
<claim-text>recognizing a point on a touch screen which a reference finger of at least one hand of a user touches; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying a touch screen keyboard comprising keys arranged according to the recognized point,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, when the user's right hand is used, the reference finger is an index finger of the right hand, and when the user's left hand is used, the reference finger is an index finger of the left hand,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the displaying of the touch screen keyboard comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying a first touch screen keyboard controlled by the right hand according to a first point on the touch screen which the index finger of the right hand touches;</claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying a second touch screen keyboard controlled by the left hand according to a second point on the touch screen which the index finger of the left hand touches,</claim-text>
<claim-text>checking a distance between the first point and the second point; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>when it is determined that the distance is less than a predetermined distance, reducing the display size of each of the first touch screen keyboard and the second touch screen keyboard.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. An apparatus for displaying a touch screen keyboard, the apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a display unit which displays a touch screen keyboard;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a touch screen which recognizes a point that a user's finger touches;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a storage unit which stores touch screen keyboard information; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control unit which displays the touch screen keyboard information read from the storage unit at a position on the display unit which is determined according to a point of a reference finger of one or both hands of the user which is recognized by the touch screen,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, when the user's right hand is used, the reference finger is an index finger of the right hand, and when the user's left hand is used, the reference finger is an index finger of the left hand,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the control unit displays on the display unit a first touch screen keyboard controlled by the right hand according to a first point on the touch screen which the index finger of the right hand touches, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>displays on the display unit a second touch screen keyboard controlled by the left hand according to a second point on the touch screen which the index finger of the left hand touches,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the control unit checks a distance between the first point and the second point, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>when it is determined that the distance is less than a predetermined distance, reduces the display size of each of the first touch screen keyboard and the second touch screen keyboard and displays the reduced first touch screen keyboard and the reduced second touch screen keyboard on the display unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein, when there exists at least one first key having a touch area whose center point is not controlled among keys included in the first touch screen keyboard and the second touch screen keyboard,
<claim-text>the control unit adjusts the center point of the touch area of the first key.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. An apparatus for displaying a touch screen keyboard, the apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a display unit which displays a touch screen keyboard;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a touch screen which recognizes a point that a user's finger touches;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a storage unit which stores touch screen keyboard information; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control unit which displays the touch screen keyboard information read from the storage unit at a position on the display unit which is determined according to a point of a reference finger of one or both hands of the user which is recognized by the touch screen, wherein the touch screen recognizes the point using a puck located on the touch screen</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the touch screen detects movement of a finger of the user on the basis of the puck and outputs a signal corresponding to the movement of the finger, wherein the control unit changes the touch screen keyboard displayed on the display unit according to the signal corresponding to the movement of the finger,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the changing of the displayed touch screen keyboard comprises:
<claim-text>when the finger is moved upward on the basis of the puck, displaying the touch screen keyboard so as to emphasize an upper key row above a reference key row; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>when the finger is moved downward on the basis of the puck, displaying the touch screen keyboard so as to emphasize a lower key row below the reference key row.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first touch screen keyboard and the second touch screen keyboard are separate keyboards. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
