<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08621913-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08621913</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13151604</doc-number>
<date>20110602</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>320</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>M</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 73 40</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Use of hydrogen sensor to detect hydrogen storage system pressure regulator failure</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010015848</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20100100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 73 40</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120305430</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121206</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Jaeger</last-name>
<first-name>Ralf</first-name>
<address>
<city>Worms</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Jaeger</last-name>
<first-name>Ralf</first-name>
<address>
<city>Worms</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Miller</last-name>
<first-name>John A.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Miller IP Group, PLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>GM Global Technology Operations LLC</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Detroit</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Macchiarolo</last-name>
<first-name>Peter</first-name>
<department>2856</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Bellamy</last-name>
<first-name>Tamiko</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A method and system for using an existing open-environment hydrogen sensor for detecting hydrogen leaking from an atmospheric reference port of a pressure regulator. The atmospheric reference port extension tube of one or more pressure regulators in a hydrogen storage system is routed past a hydrogen sensor which is already used to monitor air around the hydrogen storage system for the presence of hydrogen. In this configuration, the open-environment hydrogen sensor can quickly and reliably detect hydrogen gas flowing from the atmospheric reference port of one of the pressure regulators in the event a pressure regulator develops an internal leak.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="174.41mm" wi="249.85mm" file="US08621913-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="250.78mm" wi="172.80mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621913-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="239.78mm" wi="179.32mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621913-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="257.56mm" wi="181.19mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621913-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="254.51mm" wi="171.11mm" file="US08621913-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This invention relates generally to detection of hydrogen gas leaking from a pressure regulator and, more particularly, to a method and system for detecting hydrogen leaking from a pressure regulator in a hydrogen storage system for a fuel cell which connects the atmospheric reference port of the pressure regulator to an existing open-environment hydrogen sensor, thus providing both the atmospheric reference pressure signal for the regulator and a means of directly detecting any hydrogen gas leakage from the regulator.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Discussion of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Fuel cell vehicles are expected to rapidly increase in popularity in the near future in the automotive marketplace. Fuel cell vehicles offer several desirable features, such as virtually pollution-free emissions, and avoiding vehicle usage of petroleum fuels. A key component of fuel cell vehicles is the hydrogen storage system, which stores the hydrogen used as a fuel by most fuel cell vehicles. Hydrogen storage systems typically consist of one or more interconnected pressure vessels for storing gaseous hydrogen, along with numerous valves, gauges, and fittings necessary for operation of the hydrogen storage system. Maximizing vehicle driving range, while fitting within packaging constraints and meeting regulatory requirements, is a key consideration in the design of hydrogen storage systems for fuel cell vehicles.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Fuel cells require a reliable source of hydrogen gas at a prescribed pressure. One or more pressure regulators are used to reduce the hydrogen gas from the high pressure at which it is stored in the vessels to the lower prescribed pressure required by the fuel cell. Although rare, it is possible that a pressure regulator could develop a leak which allows hydrogen gas to flow through an unintended path into the environment.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Existing hydrogen sensors in the exhaust stream may not be able to reliably detect the presence of unintended hydrogen, due to dilution by the exhaust flow and for other reasons. There is a need for a reliable means of detecting hydrogen gas which may leak from a pressure regulator in a hydrogen storage system.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In accordance with the teachings of the present invention, a method and system are disclosed for using an existing open-environment hydrogen sensor for detecting hydrogen leaking from an atmospheric reference port of a pressure regulator. The atmospheric reference port extension tube of one or more pressure regulators in a hydrogen storage system is routed past a hydrogen sensor which is already used to monitor air around the hydrogen storage system for the presence of hydrogen. In this configuration, the open-environment hydrogen sensor can quickly and reliably detect hydrogen gas flowing from the atmospheric reference port of one of the pressure regulators in the event a pressure regulator develops an internal leak.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Additional features of the present invention will become apparent from the following description and appended claims, taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic diagram of a typical hydrogen storage system for a fuel cell;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a simplified diagram of a pressure regulator, showing the main operational elements including the atmospheric reference port;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic diagram of a hydrogen storage system for a fuel cell which connects the atmospheric reference ports of the pressure regulators to an existing open-environment hydrogen sensor; and</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a flow chart diagram of a method for using an open-environment hydrogen sensor to detect hydrogen leaking from the atmospheric reference port of a pressure regulator.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The following discussion of the embodiments of the invention directed to use of hydrogen sensors to detect hydrogen storage system pressure regulator failure is merely exemplary in nature, and is in no way intended to limit the invention or its applications or uses. For example, the disclosed methods and systems have particular application to a hydrogen storage system for a fuel cell vehicle, but may also be applicable to detection of leakage of hydrogen or any other gas from pressure regulators in any gas storage or gas handling system.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Fuel cells can be designed to use a variety of fuels, but the fuel cells being developed for most automotive applications use hydrogen gas as a fuel. Such fuel cells require a reliable source of hydrogen gas, typically provided by a hydrogen storage system.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic diagram of a typical hydrogen storage system <b>100</b> for a fuel cell <b>130</b>. Pressure vessels <b>102</b> store hydrogen gas at a high pressure. More or fewer of the pressure vessels <b>102</b> could be used than the three shown in the hydrogen storage system <b>100</b>. A pressure sensor <b>104</b> measures the pressure at a filler line <b>106</b> which is used to fill the vessels <b>102</b> from an external supply (not shown). Shut-off valves <b>108</b> are situated just downstream from each of the pressure vessels <b>102</b>. The terms upstream and downstream are used throughout this disclosure with respect to the direction of flow from the pressure vessels <b>102</b> to the fuel cell <b>130</b> and beyond. A pressure sensor <b>110</b> measures the hydrogen pressure between the shut-off valves <b>108</b> and a pressure regulator <b>112</b>. The pressure regulator <b>112</b> is used to reduce the pressure of the hydrogen gas from the high pressure of the vessels <b>102</b> down to a lower pressure which is nearer the pressure required by the fuel cell <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">A pressure sensor <b>114</b> measures the hydrogen pressure downstream of the regulator <b>112</b> and upstream of a shut-off valve <b>116</b>. The shut-off valve <b>116</b> can be closed to completely isolate the hydrogen storage system <b>100</b> from the fuel cell <b>130</b>. A second pressure regulator <b>118</b> is used to reduce the hydrogen gas pressure down to the relatively low pressure required by the fuel cell <b>130</b>. Fuel supply line <b>120</b> connects the hydrogen storage system <b>100</b> to the fuel cell <b>130</b>. The pressure regulators <b>112</b> and <b>118</b> each have an atmospheric reference port, the function of which will be discussed in detail below. The atmospheric reference ports (ARPs) of the pressure regulators <b>112</b> and <b>118</b> are connected to an ARP line <b>122</b>, also discussed below. A controller <b>124</b> monitors conditions in, and controls operation of, the hydrogen storage system <b>100</b>. For simplicity, the details of the components of the fuel cell <b>130</b> are omitted, as are various filters, check valves, relief valves, and other components of the hydrogen storage system <b>100</b> which are not relevant to the discussion.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Exhaust gas from the fuel cell <b>130</b> flows through exhaust line <b>132</b> to diffuser <b>134</b>. A hydrogen sensor <b>136</b> is situated near the exhaust line to diffuser junction, where the sensor <b>136</b> can detect any excess concentration of hydrogen gas in the exhaust. Exhaust gas from the fuel cell <b>130</b> flows out of the diffuser <b>134</b> to the environment at line <b>138</b>. A hydrogen sensor <b>140</b> is situated within or somewhere near the hydrogen storage system <b>100</b>, such as in a compartment with the tanks <b>102</b>. The hydrogen sensor <b>140</b> is not connected to any other plumbing, but rather is able to detect hydrogen gas in the open environment, such as might be present if there was a leak from one of the tanks <b>102</b> or any of the fittings or valves in the hydrogen storage system <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The controller <b>124</b> is in communication with the pressure sensors <b>104</b>, <b>110</b> and <b>114</b>, the shut-off valves <b>108</b> and <b>116</b>, the pressure regulators <b>112</b> and <b>118</b>, and the hydrogen sensors <b>136</b> and <b>140</b>. In typical hydrogen storage system designs, a hydrogen sensor, such as the hydrogen sensor <b>140</b>, may trigger a warning if the concentration of hydrogen gas exceeds a first threshold, such as 2%, and may trigger an alarm if the concentration of hydrogen gas exceeds a second threshold, such as 4%. The controller <b>124</b> may be programmed to close the shut-off valves <b>108</b> and <b>116</b> and shut down the fuel cell <b>130</b> in the event of a hydrogen alarm from either the sensor <b>136</b> or the sensor <b>140</b>. The controller <b>124</b> may take other actions as well, such as issuing a warning to a driver of the vehicle, and/or recording a diagnostic trouble code (DTC) indicating that an unusually high hydrogen concentration has been detected.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In the hydrogen storage system <b>100</b>, the ARP line <b>122</b> is connected to the exhaust line <b>132</b> near the diffuser <b>134</b>. The ARP line <b>122</b> is a simple extension tube which provides ambient or atmospheric pressure to the atmospheric reference ports of the regulators <b>112</b> and <b>118</b>, as would be understood by one skilled in the art, and as will be discussed in detail below. However, if the pressure regulator <b>112</b> or <b>118</b> were to develop an internal leak, pure hydrogen gas could flow through the ARP line <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a simplified diagram of the pressure regulator <b>112</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The pressure regulator <b>112</b> is comprised of a lower body <b>150</b> and an upper body <b>152</b>, separated internally by a membrane <b>154</b>. The lower body <b>150</b> includes a high pressure chamber <b>156</b> which receives hydrogen gas at line <b>158</b>, where the gas at the line <b>158</b> is at a relatively high pressure, as indicated by the pressure sensor <b>110</b>. The lower body <b>150</b> also includes a low pressure chamber <b>160</b>, which is separated from the high pressure chamber <b>156</b> by a poppet valve <b>162</b>. An adjustment handle <b>164</b> is used to adjust the pressure in the low pressure chamber <b>160</b>. As the adjustment handle <b>164</b> is turned and threaded further into the upper body <b>152</b>, a spring <b>166</b> exerts more force on the upper end of the poppet valve <b>162</b>, thus forcing the valve <b>162</b> further open and allowing a higher pressure in the low pressure chamber <b>160</b>. Pressure on the membrane <b>154</b> counteracts the force from the spring <b>166</b>, such that equilibrium is reached and the pressure in the low pressure chamber <b>160</b> is based on the position of the adjustment handle <b>164</b>. Gas from the low pressure chamber <b>160</b> flows out of the pressure regulator <b>112</b> at line <b>168</b>, where the gas at the line <b>168</b> is at a lower pressure than the inlet at the line <b>158</b>, as indicated by the pressure sensor <b>114</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The membrane <b>154</b> must be able to react only to the load from the spring <b>166</b> and the pressure from the low pressure chamber <b>160</b>. Thus, it is important that the upper body <b>152</b> itself does not act as a chamber which pressurizes and depressurizes with motion of the membrane <b>154</b>. In order to keep the pressure on the upper side of the membrane <b>154</b> at a relatively constant level, irrespective of movement of the membrane <b>154</b>, it is necessary to vent the upper body <b>152</b> to the atmosphere. This venting is accomplished via atmospheric reference port <b>170</b>. As described previously in the discussion of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the atmospheric reference port <b>170</b> is connected to the ARP line <b>122</b>, which must be able to breathe air at approximately atmospheric pressure.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Pressure regulators such as the pressure regulator <b>112</b> are known in the art, and have been used successfully for many years. However, it is also known that various internal failure modes exist for the pressure regulator <b>112</b> and similar designs, which could allow hydrogen gas to flow out the atmospheric reference port <b>170</b>. One such failure mode is a crack in the membrane <b>154</b>. Another such failure mode is a leak in a gasket (not shown) which is situated around the periphery of the membrane <b>154</b>. Yet another such failure mode is possible in a different type of pressure regulator, one in which there is a piston-type member (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) which uses o-rings to seal against the upper body <b>152</b>. In any of these failure mode scenarios, hydrogen gas would leak past the membrane <b>154</b> into the upper body <b>152</b>. Because the leaked hydrogen gas in the upper body <b>152</b> would by definition be above atmospheric pressure, the leaked gas would flow out the atmospheric reference port <b>170</b> through the ARP line <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Although a hydrogen leak through an atmospheric reference port of a pressure regulator is a rare occurrence, it is nonetheless desirable to be able to reliably detect the leaking hydrogen, for a number of reasons. First, a leaking pressure regulator is normally not able to properly hold its set point pressure. Second, leaking hydrogen represents a waste of fuel, which costs the driver money and shortens the driving range of the vehicle. And third, hydrogen gas leaking into the environment where it could locally increase in concentration is not a desirable situation.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In the hydrogen storage system <b>100</b>, hydrogen gas leaking from the pressure regulators <b>112</b> and/or <b>118</b> would flow through the ARP line <b>122</b> to the exhaust line <b>132</b>. Even if the hydrogen sensor <b>136</b> is positioned very near the inlet from the ARP line <b>122</b>, the sensor <b>136</b> may not detect an abnormally high concentration of hydrogen, due to the dilution from the exhaust flow. It would be advantageous to use a hydrogen sensor which is better able to detect even a light flow of hydrogen gas through the ARP line <b>122</b>, particularly if such a sensor is already available which can be repurposed for this task.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic diagram of an improved hydrogen storage system <b>200</b>, which is able to more reliably detect a hydrogen gas leak from the pressure regulator <b>112</b> or <b>118</b>. In the hydrogen storage system <b>200</b>, the ARP line <b>122</b> is not connected to the exhaust line <b>132</b> as in the hydrogen storage system <b>100</b>. Rather, the ARP line <b>122</b> is routed to and terminated in close proximity to the hydrogen sensor <b>140</b>, which is otherwise monitoring environmental air in the vicinity of the storage tanks <b>102</b>. The hydrogen sensor <b>140</b> is situated in an unpressurized environment, and is not connected to any pipes, lines, or fittings. Thus, the ARP line <b>122</b> can provide the atmospheric reference pressure needed by the atmospheric reference port <b>170</b>, and the sensor <b>140</b> is ideally situated to detect a flow of hydrogen gas out the ARP line <b>122</b> because there is no other high-volume flow to dilute it.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The exact position of the open end of the ARP line <b>122</b> relative to the hydrogen sensor <b>140</b> can established based on packaging and performance considerations. In one embodiment, the open end of the ARP line <b>122</b> would be directed toward the hydrogen sensor <b>140</b>, and the hydrogen sensor <b>140</b> would be within about 15 mm of the open end of the ARP line <b>122</b>. Other arrangements are possible, as long as the hydrogen sensor <b>140</b> can reliably detect hydrogen gas flowing from the pressure regulators <b>112</b> and/or <b>118</b> via the ARP line <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">It is possible for the hydrogen sensor <b>140</b> to distinguish between a hydrogen leak from the tanks <b>102</b> or the adjacent fittings and a hydrogen leak from the pressure regulators <b>112</b> and/or <b>118</b> through the ARP line <b>122</b>. For example, the concentration increase rate could be a good indicator of the source of the hydrogen, where a slow concentration increase rate would be indicative of environmental hydrogen gas (leaking from the tanks <b>102</b> or fittings, for example) migrating past the hydrogen sensor <b>140</b>, and a fast concentration increase rate would be indicative of hydrogen gas flowing through the ARP line <b>122</b>. The hydrogen storage system could also include a second open-environment hydrogen sensor (not shown), positioned remote from the open end of the ARP line <b>122</b>, such that the difference between the two open-environment hydrogen sensor readings could be used to determine the source of the hydrogen gas.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In any case, both the absolute concentration of hydrogen gas and the concentration increase rate could be used to determine what action should be taken by the controller <b>124</b> in the hydrogen storage system <b>200</b>. Such actions could include recording a diagnostic trouble code (DTC), issuing an audible or visual warning to the driver, initiating certain countermeasures, and/or shutting down the hydrogen storage system <b>200</b> and the fuel cell <b>130</b> via the shut-off valves <b>108</b> and <b>116</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a flow chart diagram <b>300</b> of a method for detecting a hydrogen leak from a pressure regulator using an existing open-environment hydrogen sensor. At box <b>302</b>, the atmospheric reference port of one or more pressure regulators, such as the pressure regulators <b>112</b> and <b>118</b>, are routed via a tube or hose to an open-environment hydrogen sensor, such as the sensor <b>140</b>. At box <b>304</b>, the hydrogen sensor <b>140</b> monitors for an increased concentration of hydrogen gas. At decision diamond <b>306</b>, if there is no actionable concentration of hydrogen gas, the process loops back to continue monitoring at the box <b>304</b>. If an actionable concentration of hydrogen is detected, at decision diamond <b>306</b> the process continues to box <b>308</b>. At the box <b>308</b>, parameters are checked to determine a likely source of the hydrogen gas. For example, the rate of increase in concentration could be an indication of whether the hydrogen is present in the open environment in the vicinity of the hydrogen sensor <b>140</b>, or whether the hydrogen is coming from the pressure regulators <b>112</b> and/or <b>118</b>. At box <b>310</b>, appropriate actions are taken based on the concentration and likely source of the hydrogen gas. As discussed previously, the actions could include issuing a driver alert, initiating countermeasures, and shutting down the hydrogen storage system <b>200</b> and the fuel cell <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Using the open-environment hydrogen sensor connectivity described above, it is possible to quickly and reliably detect an internal hydrogen gas leak from a pressure regulator in a hydrogen storage system, thus enabling appropriate action to be taken. This can be done without increasing the cost of the hydrogen storage system, by using an existing open-environment hydrogen sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The foregoing discussion discloses and describes merely exemplary embodiments of the present invention. One skilled in the art will readily recognize from such discussion and from the accompanying drawings and claims that various changes, modifications and variations can be made therein without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention as defined in the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A gas storage system comprising:
<claim-text>one or more storage tanks containing a gas at an elevated pressure;</claim-text>
<claim-text>one or more pressure regulators for reducing pressure of the gas from the elevated pressure to a lower pressure at which the gas is used by a downstream device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first gas sensor for detecting an elevated concentration of the gas in atmospheric air near the storage tanks;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an extension tube with a first end connected to an atmospheric reference port of the one or more pressure regulators and a second end open to the atmospheric air near enough to the first gas sensor that the first gas sensor can detect any of the gas flowing from the extension tube; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a controller for monitoring conditions in the gas storage system and controlling operation of the gas storage system, said controller being in electronic communication with the first gas sensor and being configured to take action if the first gas sensor detects an elevated concentration of the gas.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The gas storage system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the action includes one or more of; issuing a warning, initiating countermeasures, and shutting down the gas storage system.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The gas storage system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the controller is configured to distinguish between gas present in the atmospheric air near the storage tanks and gas leaked from the atmospheric reference port of the one or more pressure regulators.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The gas storage system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref> wherein the controller uses a rate of increase of gas concentration to distinguish between gas present in the atmospheric air near the storage tanks and gas leaked from the atmospheric reference port of the one or more pressure regulators.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The gas storage system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref> wherein the action includes storing a diagnostic trouble code (DTC) in the controller that indicates whether the gas was present in the atmospheric air near the storage tanks or the gas leaked from the atmospheric reference port of the one or more pressure regulators.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The gas storage system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref> further comprising a second gas sensor for detecting an elevated concentration of the gas in the atmospheric air near the storage tanks, said second gas sensor not close enough to the second end of the extension tube to detect any of the gas flowing from the extension tube.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The gas storage system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> wherein the controller uses a difference between gas concentrations at the first and second gas sensors to distinguish between gas present in the atmospheric air near the storage tanks and gas leaked from the atmospheric reference port of the one or more pressure regulators.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The gas storage system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref> wherein the action includes storing a diagnostic trouble code (DTC) in the controller that indicates whether the gas was present in the atmospheric air near the storage tanks or the gas leaked from the atmospheric reference port of the one or more pressure regulators.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The gas storage system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the gas storage system is a hydrogen storage system and the downstream device is a fuel cell.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The gas storage system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref> wherein the hydrogen storage system and the fuel cell are used in a vehicle.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A hydrogen storage system comprising:
<claim-text>one or more storage tanks containing hydrogen gas at an elevated pressure;</claim-text>
<claim-text>one or more pressure regulators for reducing pressure of the hydrogen gas from the elevated pressure to a lower pressure at which the hydrogen gas is used by a fuel cell;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first hydrogen sensor for detecting an elevated concentration of the hydrogen gas in atmospheric air near the storage tanks;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an extension tube with a first end connected to an atmospheric reference port of the one or more pressure regulators and a second end open to the atmospheric air near enough to the first hydrogen sensor that the first hydrogen sensor can detect any of the hydrogen gas flowing from the extension tube;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second hydrogen sensor for detecting an elevated concentration of the hydrogen gas in the atmospheric air near the storage tanks, said second hydrogen sensor not being close enough to the second end of the extension tube to detect any of the hydrogen gas flowing from the extension tube; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a controller for monitoring conditions in the hydrogen storage system and controlling operation of the hydrogen storage system, said controller being in electronic communication with the first and second hydrogen sensors.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The hydrogen storage system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> wherein the controller is configured to take action if the first or second hydrogen sensor detects an elevated concentration of the hydrogen gas, where the action includes one or more of; issuing a warning, initiating countermeasures, and shutting down the hydrogen storage system.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The hydrogen storage system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> wherein the controller is configured to distinguish between hydrogen gas present in the atmospheric air near the storage tanks and hydrogen gas leaked from the atmospheric reference port of the one or more pressure regulators.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The hydrogen storage system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> wherein the controller uses a rate of increase of hydrogen gas concentration to distinguish between hydrogen gas present in the atmospheric air near the storage tanks and hydrogen gas leaked from the atmospheric reference port of the one or more pressure regulators.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The hydrogen storage system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> wherein the controller uses a difference between the hydrogen gas concentrations at the first and second hydrogen sensors to distinguish between hydrogen gas present in the atmospheric air near the storage tanks and hydrogen gas leaked from the atmospheric reference port of the one or more pressure regulators.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A method for detecting a hydrogen leak from a hydrogen storage system for a fuel cell, said method comprising:
<claim-text>routing an extension tube from an atmospheric reference port of one or more pressure regulators in the hydrogen storage system to a first open-environment hydrogen sensor, such that the first open-environment hydrogen sensor can detect hydrogen gas flowing from the extension tube;</claim-text>
<claim-text>monitoring conditions to detect an elevated concentration of hydrogen gas by the first hydrogen sensor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>evaluating hydrogen concentration parameters to determine a source of the hydrogen leak upon detecting the elevated concentration of hydrogen gas; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>taking appropriate action based on the hydrogen concentration parameters.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref> wherein evaluating hydrogen concentration parameters includes evaluating a concentration increase rate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref> wherein evaluating hydrogen concentration parameters includes comparing a hydrogen concentration at the first open-environment hydrogen sensor to a hydrogen concentration at a second open-environment hydrogen sensor which is not located near enough to an open end of the extension tube to detect hydrogen gas flowing from the extension tube.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref> wherein taking appropriate action includes one or more of; issuing warnings, initiating countermeasures, and shutting down the hydrogen storage system and the fuel cell.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref> wherein the hydrogen storage system and the fuel cell are used in a vehicle. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
