<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624563-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624563</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12847298</doc-number>
<date>20100730</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="regional">
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>09166899</doc-number>
<date>20090730</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>656</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>P</subclass>
<main-group>9</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>P</subclass>
<main-group>9</main-group>
<subgroup>10</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>P</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>322 44</main-classification>
<further-classification>322 59</further-classification>
<further-classification>322 28</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Static exciter of a field winding and method for operating the same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4426613</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Mizuno et al.</name>
<date>19840100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>322 21</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0296275</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Joho</name>
<date>20071200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>307 47</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>0 122 310</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19841000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>58-159699</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19830900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00005">
<othercit>European Search Report of EP 09 16 6899 mailed Sep. 21, 2009, 6 pages.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>11</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>322 44</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>322 20</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>322 89</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>322 59</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110050183</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110303</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ginet</last-name>
<first-name>Constantin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Cusco</city>
<country>PE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>PE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Diez-Maroto</last-name>
<first-name>Luis</first-name>
<address>
<city>Madrid</city>
<country>ES</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>ES</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ginet</last-name>
<first-name>Constantin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Cusco</city>
<country>PE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Diez-Maroto</last-name>
<first-name>Luis</first-name>
<address>
<city>Madrid</city>
<country>ES</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Buchanan Ingersoll &#x26; Rooney PC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Alstom Technology Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Baden</city>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Gonzalez</last-name>
<first-name>Julio Cesar</first-name>
<department>2833</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A static exciter of a field winding includes a rectifier connected to an electric grid and to the field winding; a unidirectional electronic switch connected in series with the rectifier; a capacitor bank; and a further switch disposed between the unidirectional electronic switch and the capacitor bank. Exciter also includes a control unit connected to the further switch and configured to close the further switch when a grid voltage drops below a first prefixed voltage value so as to connect the capacitor bank to the field winding and configured to open the further switch when the grid voltage exceeds a second prefixed voltage value so as to disconnect the capacitor bank from the field winding and so as to supply energy to the field winding from the capacitor bank for a time period.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="157.82mm" wi="119.63mm" file="US08624563-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="171.03mm" wi="142.41mm" file="US08624563-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="169.59mm" wi="130.13mm" file="US08624563-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="222.76mm" wi="148.51mm" file="US08624563-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO PRIOR APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">Priority is claimed to European Convention Application No. EP 09166899.6, filed Jul. 30, 2009, the entire disclosure of which is incorporated by reference herein.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a static exciter of a field winding and a method for operating the same.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Static exciters are widely used for feeding the field winding of electric generators.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">US2007/0296275 discloses (with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> of this document) a static exciter <b>1</b> having an exciter transformer <b>2</b> that is connected at one side to a busbar <b>3</b> of a generator <b>4</b> (i.e. to the output of the generator) and at the other side to a rectifier <b>5</b> that converts the AC voltage fed from the exciter transformer <b>2</b> into a DC voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The rectifier <b>5</b> is typically driven by an AVR (Automatic Voltage Regulator) <b>6</b> that is connected to the busbar <b>3</b> via a voltage transformer <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The DC side of the rectifier <b>5</b> is connected in series with the field winding <b>8</b> of the generator <b>4</b> and a forward biased diode <b>9</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The forward biased diode <b>9</b> is connected in parallel with a capacitor bank <b>10</b>; moreover a switch <b>11</b> is provided between the capacitor bank <b>10</b> and the diode <b>9</b>; such switch <b>11</b> can be closed to connect the capacitor bank <b>10</b> in series with the rectifier <b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">During normal operation the switch <b>11</b> is open; the AC voltage from the exciter transformer <b>2</b> is converted into a DC voltage and is fed to the field winding <b>8</b> because the diode <b>9</b> is forward biased and conducts.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In case a disturbance at the grid occurs (for example due to a short circuits in the transmission line) the voltage of the grid drops and, therefore, also the voltage of the busbar <b>3</b> and the voltage at the lower voltage side of the voltage transformer <b>7</b> drops.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">When the voltage at the lower voltage side of the voltage transformer <b>7</b> drops below a prefixed voltage value, the switch <b>11</b> is closed such that the diode <b>9</b> is reverse biased (and does not conduct anymore) and the capacitor bank <b>10</b> is connected in series with the rectifier <b>5</b> and field winding <b>8</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">This causes a considerably higher field voltage to be applied to the field winding <b>8</b> and guarantees the stability of the generator/grid system.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Nevertheless, once a disturbance occurs, the capacitor bank <b>10</b> is fully discharged, therefore if a plurality of disturbances occurs the system is not able to cope with them.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In fact (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>), even if the static exciter <b>1</b> is provided with a charging device <b>12</b> (such as a battery) that keeps the capacitor bank <b>10</b> charged, the charging device dimension is usually small and it takes minutes to hours for it to recharge the capacitor bank <b>10</b> to an acceptable charge level.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">An aspect of the present invention is therefore to provide a static exciter and a method by which the said problems of the known art are eliminated.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In an embodiment, a static exciter and a method are provided that are able to cope with a plurality of disturbances that occur in a short period time one after the other (for example few minutes).</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The technical aim, together with this and further aspects, are attained according to the invention by providing a static exciter and a method in accordance with the accompanying claims.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Further characteristics and advantages of the invention will be more apparent from the description of a preferred but non-exclusive embodiment of the static exciter and method according to the invention, illustrated by way of non-limiting example in the accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view of a static exciter according to the prior art;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic view of a static exciter according an embodiment of the invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref> are diagrams showing switch closing/opening delay time bands according to an embodiment of the invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">With reference to the figures, these show a static exciter <b>1</b> of the field winding <b>8</b> of an electric generator <b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The electric generator <b>4</b> has a busbar <b>3</b> connected to an electric grid <b>20</b> via a transformer <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The static exciter <b>1</b> comprises the rectifier <b>5</b> made of a thyristor bridge, connected to the busbar <b>3</b> via the exciter transformer <b>2</b> from one side (alternatively the voltage transformer <b>7</b> may also be connected to the grid <b>20</b>), and to the field winding <b>8</b> of the electric generator <b>1</b> from the other side.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The static exciter <b>1</b> also has a unidirectional electronic switch such as the forward biased diode <b>9</b> connected in series with the rectifier <b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In addition, the static exciter <b>1</b> also has a capacitor bank <b>10</b>, for example made of a plurality of super capacitors connected in series and parallel with each other; the capacitor bank <b>10</b> is connected in parallel with the diode <b>9</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The static exciter <b>1</b> further comprises the switch <b>11</b> between the diode <b>9</b> and the capacitor bank <b>10</b>; the switch <b>11</b> is connected to a control unit <b>22</b> that closes it when a voltage indicative of the grid voltage (that is controlled through the voltage of the busbar <b>3</b>, that is connected to the grid <b>20</b> via the transformer <b>21</b>) drops below a first prefixed voltage value V<sub>1</sub>, to connect the capacitor bank <b>10</b> to the field winding <b>8</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Advantageously, the control unit <b>22</b> opens the switch <b>11</b> when a voltage indicative of the grid voltage (that is controlled through the voltage of the busbar <b>3</b>) exceeds a second prefixed voltage value V<sub>2</sub>, to disconnect the capacitor bank <b>10</b> from the field winding <b>8</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">This lets the capacitor bank <b>10</b> supply energy to the field winding <b>8</b> only for the time needed and prevents the full discharge of the capacitor bank <b>10</b>, avoiding feeding of energy when it is not needed.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The second prefixed voltage value V<sub>2 </sub>is greater than or equal to the first prefixed voltage value V<sub>1</sub>; preferably, in order to avoid oscillating-like closings and reopenings of the switch <b>11</b>, the second prefixed voltage value V<sub>2 </sub>is greater than the first prefixed voltage value V<sub>1</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The stator exciter <b>1</b> also comprises the voltage transformer <b>7</b> that supplies the AVR <b>6</b> (Automatic Voltage Regulator) of the field winding <b>8</b>; preferably the grid voltage drop is measured at the lower voltage side of the voltage transformer <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The control unit <b>22</b> has a third prefixed voltage value V<sub>3</sub>, such that when the voltage of the capacitor bank <b>10</b> drops below the third prefixed voltage value V<sub>3 </sub>the control unit <b>22</b> opens the switch <b>11</b> (so preventing the full discharge of the capacitor bank <b>10</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In addition, the charging device <b>12</b> is also provided with a charging switch <b>32</b> protecting the charging device <b>12</b>, which works mainly as a constant voltage source, from overcurrent. In particular when the switch <b>11</b> is closed the charging switch <b>32</b> is open, and when the switch <b>11</b> is open the charging switch <b>32</b> is closed. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows the switch <b>11</b> open and the charging switch <b>32</b> closed. Alternatively the charging device produces a constant current, with an overruling voltage limitation (thus eliminating the need of a charging switch).</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The operation of the stator exciter in this embodiment of the invention is apparent from that described and illustrated and is substantially the following.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">When a disturbance at the grid <b>20</b> occurs and its voltage drops, also the voltage of the busbar <b>3</b> drops.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The control unit <b>22</b> continuously monitors the voltage of the busbar <b>3</b> (i.e. the voltage of the grid <b>20</b>) and when it detects such a drop, drives the switch <b>11</b> to close it.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Thus the capacitor bank <b>10</b> is connected in series with the rectifier <b>5</b> and feeds its energy to the field winding <b>8</b> of the generator <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">When the voltage of the grid <b>20</b> (and thus the voltage of the busbar <b>3</b>) rises again (usually it take a very short time due to the automatic protection devices of the grid), the control unit <b>22</b> detects the increased voltage of the busbar <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">When the voltage of the grid <b>20</b> (and thus the voltage of the busbar <b>3</b>) exceeds the second prefixed voltage value V<sub>2</sub>, the control unit <b>22</b> drives the switch <b>11</b> to open it.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Usually reopening of the switch <b>11</b> is so fast that the capacitor bank <b>10</b> is not fully discharged, such that if further disturbances at the grid <b>20</b> occur, the capacitor bank <b>10</b> is able to cope with them.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Moreover, in order to prevent the capacitor bank <b>10</b> from being fully discharged, when the control unit <b>22</b> detects a voltage of the capacitor bank <b>10</b> lower than the third prefixed voltage value V<sub>3</sub>, it opens the switch <b>11</b>. In fact, in this case the most severe phase of operation is already overcome, and the capacitor bank charge is saved for further disturbances in the grid <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In a different embodiment of the invention, the control unit <b>22</b> closes or opens the switch <b>11</b> with a prefixed delay.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In fact, often when a disturbance at the grid <b>20</b> occurs, the voltage drops and rises in two or more steps; for example <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows the voltage that drops in two steps and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows the voltage that rises again in two steps.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The delay time lets the capacitor bank discharge be optimised in relation to the electric power actually needed.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In particular (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>), the control unit <b>10</b> has stored a voltage drop band series (to be used when the voltage of the grid drops) and a prefixed closing delay time for the switch <b>11</b> associated to each voltage band of the voltage drop band series.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Correspondingly (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), the control unit <b>10</b> has stored a voltage rise band series (to be used when the voltage of the grid rises) and a prefixed opening delay time for the switch <b>11</b> associated to each voltage band.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows the voltage bands A, B of the voltage drop band series that have voltages greater than the V<sub>1 </sub>voltage and each voltage band A, B has associated a delay time T<sub>A</sub>, T<sub>B</sub>. These delay times progressively decrease with decreasing voltage; the delay time for a voltage lower that the V<sub>1 </sub>voltage is zero.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Correspondingly, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows the voltage bands C, D, E of the voltage rise band series that have voltages lower than the V<sub>2 </sub>voltage and each voltage band C, D, E has associated a delay time T<sub>C</sub>, T<sub>D</sub>, T<sub>E</sub>. These delay times progressively decrease with increasing voltage; the delay time for a voltage greater that the V<sub>2 </sub>voltage is zero.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">During operation the information to be transmitted to the control unit <b>22</b> is whether the voltage of the grid is dropping or rising (to select the voltage band series to be used) and the actual voltage of the grid or a voltage indicative thereof (to select the particular voltage band and thus the delay time).</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In different embodiments of the invention, the voltage drop band series and the voltage rise band series can be equal to or different from one another and the delay time associated thereto may also be equal to or different from one another.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The operation of the static exciter in this embodiment of the invention is substantially the same as that already described with reference to the first embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In particular, with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, when a disturbance occurs at the grid <b>20</b> the voltage at the grid <b>20</b> (and busbar <b>3</b>) drops.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In this respect, for example the voltage drops in two steps from the voltage <b>30</b> (100%) to a voltage <b>31</b> greater than the voltage V<sub>1</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The control unit <b>22</b> detects the voltage of the busbar <b>3</b> (that is indicative of the voltage of the grid <b>20</b>) and ascertains that it is comprised in the voltage drop band A.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">As a delay time T<sub>A </sub>corresponds to the voltage drop band A, the control unit <b>22</b> closes the switch <b>11</b> with a delay time T<sub>A </sub>(from when the voltage enters the voltage drop band A).</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">If before the closing of the switch <b>11</b> the voltage drops further, the control unit <b>22</b> detects the voltage of the busbar <b>3</b> (that is indicative of the voltage of the grid <b>20</b>) and ascertains the new voltage drop band or is it is below the voltage V<sub>1</sub>, therefore the switch <b>11</b> is closed accordingly.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">For example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> as soon as the voltage drops below the V<sub>1 </sub>voltage, the control unit <b>22</b> closes the switch <b>11</b> (the delay time is zero).</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Correspondingly, the voltage of the busbar <b>3</b> rises (because of the automatic protection device of the grid <b>20</b>) in two or more steps.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Thus the control unit <b>22</b> detects the actual voltage of the busbar <b>3</b>, ascertaining the voltage rise band to which it pertains.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">For example the voltage of the busbar <b>3</b> rises up to a level corresponding to the D voltage band.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">As to the D voltage band corresponds a delay time T<sub>D</sub>, the control unit <b>22</b> only opens the switch <b>11</b> after a delay time T<sub>D </sub>(after the voltage enters the voltage rise band D).</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Then, if the voltage rises further before the switch is opened, the control unit <b>22</b> detects the new voltage and drives the switch according to the delay time associated to it.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> as soon as the voltage exceeds the V<sub>2 </sub>voltage, the switch <b>11</b> is closed (the delay time is zero).</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The present invention also refers to a method for operating a static exciter of a field winding of an electric generator.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The method consists in closing the switch <b>11</b>, connecting the capacitor bank <b>10</b> in series with the rectifier <b>5</b>, when the voltage of the grid <b>20</b> and thus of the busbar <b>3</b> drops below a first prefixed voltage value V<sub>1</sub>, and opening the switch <b>11</b> again when the voltage of the grid <b>20</b> (and thus of the busbar <b>3</b>) exceeds a second prefixed voltage value V<sub>2</sub>, with the second prefixed voltage value V<sub>2 </sub>greater than or equal to the first prefixed voltage value V<sub>1</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Moreover, opening the switch <b>11</b> also occurs when the voltage of the capacitor bank <b>10</b> drops below a third prefixed voltage value V<sub>3</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In a different embodiment of the method, the switch <b>11</b> is closed or opened with a prefixed delay.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">In particular the control unit <b>22</b> has a plurality of voltage drop bands each associated with a prefixed closing delay time, and a delay time being zero for a voltage lower than the V<sub>1 </sub>voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">Correspondingly, the control unit <b>22</b> has a plurality of voltage rise bands each associated with a prefixed opening delay time, and a delay time being zero for a voltage greater than the V<sub>2 </sub>voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">When the grid voltage (and thus the voltage of the busbar <b>3</b>) drops, an actual voltage indicative of the actual grid voltage is measured to ascertain the voltage drop band to which the grid voltage pertains; for example the voltage at the lower voltage side of the voltage transformer <b>7</b> is measured.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">Then the switch <b>11</b> is closed with the delay time corresponding to the particular voltage drop band after the entrance of the voltage in the particular voltage drop band. If the voltage is lower than V<sub>1 </sub>the delay time is zero.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">Correspondingly, when the grid voltage (and thus the voltage of the busbar <b>3</b>) rises, an actual voltage indicative of the grid voltage is measured to ascertain the voltage rise band to which the grid voltage pertains; for example the voltage at the lower voltage side of the voltage transformer <b>7</b> is measured.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">Then the switch <b>11</b> is opened with the delay time corresponding to the particular voltage drop band after the entrance of the voltage in the particular voltage rise band. If the voltage is greater than V<sub>2 </sub>the delay time is zero.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">Naturally the features described may also be independently provided from one another.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The static exciter and the method conceived in this manner are susceptible to numerous modifications and variants, all falling within the scope of the inventive concept; moreover all details can be replaced by technically equivalent elements.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">In practice the materials used and the dimensions can be chosen at will according to requirements and to the state of the art.</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">REFERENCE NUMBERS</heading>
<p id="p-0077" num="0000">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0076"><b>1</b> static exciter</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0002" num="0077"><b>2</b> exciter transformer</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0003" num="0078"><b>3</b> busbar</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0004" num="0079"><b>4</b> generator</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0005" num="0080"><b>5</b> rectifier</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0006" num="0081"><b>6</b> AVR (Automatic Voltage Regulator)</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0007" num="0082"><b>7</b> voltage transformer</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0008" num="0083"><b>8</b> field winding of the generator</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0009" num="0084"><b>9</b> diode</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0010" num="0085"><b>10</b> capacitor bank</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0011" num="0086"><b>11</b> switch</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0012" num="0087"><b>12</b> charging device</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0013" num="0088"><b>20</b> grid</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0014" num="0089"><b>21</b> transformer</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0015" num="0090"><b>22</b> control unit</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0016" num="0091"><b>30</b> voltage</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0017" num="0092"><b>31</b> voltage</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0018" num="0093"><b>32</b> charging switch</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0019" num="0094">V<sub>1 </sub>first prefixed voltage value</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0020" num="0095">V<sub>2 </sub>second prefixed voltage value</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0021" num="0096">V<sub>3 </sub>third prefixed voltage value</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0022" num="0097">A-E voltage bands</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0023" num="0098">T<sub>A</sub>-T<sub>E </sub>delay time corresponding to the voltage bands A-E</li>
</ul>
</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A static exciter of a field winding of an electric generator comprising:
<claim-text>a rectifier connected to an electric grid and to the field winding;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a unidirectional electronic switch connected in series with the rectifier;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a capacitor bank;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a further switch disposed electrically between the unidirectional electronic switch and the capacitor bank;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control unit connected to the further switch and configured to close the further switch when a voltage indicative of a grid voltage drops below a first prefixed voltage value so as to connect the capacitor bank to the field winding so as to supply energy to the field winding from the capacitor bank and configured to interrupt current flowing between the capacitor bank and the field winding by opening the further switch when the voltage indicative of the grid voltage exceeds a second prefixed voltage value so as to disconnect the capacitor bank from the field winding, such that the capacitor bank supplies energy to the field winding only for the time needed,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the control unit is configured to open or control the further switch with a prefixed delay, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the control unit includes at least one voltage drop band associated with a prefixed closing delay time for the further switch, wherein the closing delay time is zero for a voltage lower than the first prefixed voltage value, and wherein the control unit includes at least one voltage rise band associated with a prefixed opening delay time for the further switch, wherein the opening delay time is zero for a voltage greater than the second prefixed voltage value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The static exciter as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the unidirectional electronic switch includes a forward biased diode.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The static exciter as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second prefixed voltage value is greater than or equal to the first prefixed voltage value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The static exciter as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the diode is connected in parallel with the capacitor bank.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The static exciter as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a voltage transformer having a low voltage side and configured to feed an automatic voltage regulator of the field winding, wherein a grid voltage drop is measurable at the low voltage side.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The static exciter as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the rectifier includes a thyristor bridge.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The static exciter as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the control unit is configured to open the further switch when a voltage of the capacitor bank drops below a third prefixed voltage value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A method for operating a static exciter of a field winding of an electric generator, wherein the static exciter includes a rectifier connected to an electric grid and to the field winding, a unidirectional electronic switch connected in series with the rectifier, a capacitor bank, a further switch disposed between the unidirectional electronic switch and the capacitor bank, and a control unit, the method comprising:
<claim-text>connecting the capacitor bank to the field winding by closing the further switch when a grid voltage drops below a first prefixed voltage value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>interrupting current flowing from the capacitor bank to the field winding by opening the further switch when the grid voltage exceeds a prefixed voltage value such that the capacitor bank supplies energy to the field winding only for the time needed,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the opening and the closing of the further switch is performed with a prefixed delay,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the control unit includes a plurality of voltage drop bands each associated with a prefixed closing delay time for the further switch, wherein the closing delay time is zero for a voltage lower than the first prefixed voltage value, and wherein the control unit includes a plurality of voltage rise bands each associated with a prefixed opening delay time for the further switch, wherein the opening delay time is zero for a voltage greater than the second prefixed voltage value, and further comprising:</claim-text>
<claim-text>measuring an actual voltage indicative of the grid voltage to determine to which of the plurality of voltage drop bands the grid voltage corresponds when the grid voltage drops, wherein the closing the further switch is performed according to the prefixed closing delay time after the actual voltage enters the voltage drop band; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>measuring the actual voltage indicative of the grid voltage to determine to which of the plurality of voltage rise bands the grid voltage corresponds when the grid voltage rises, wherein the opening the further switch is performed according to the prefixed opening delay time after the actual voltage enters the voltage rise band.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the unidirectional electronic switch includes a forward biased diode.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the second prefixed voltage value is greater than or equal to the first prefixed voltage value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising opening the further switch when a voltage of the capacitor bank drops below a third prefixed voltage value.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
