<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625829-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625829</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13145502</doc-number>
<date>20090121</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>162</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>25</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>381326</main-classification>
<further-classification>381322</further-classification>
<further-classification>381328</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Partially implantable hearing aid</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3764748</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Branch et al.</name>
<date>19731000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>607 57</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5814095</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Muller et al.</name>
<date>19980900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>607 57</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7289639</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Abel et al.</name>
<date>20071000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>381312</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0267549</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Della Santina et al.</name>
<date>20051200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0189841</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Pluvinage</name>
<date>20060800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>600 25</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0036375</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Jensen</name>
<date>20070200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>381312</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO-03/063542</doc-number>
<date>20030700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO-2006/045148</doc-number>
<date>20060500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00009">
<othercit>International Preliminary Report on Patentability received in International Application No. PCT/EP2009/050674 dated Aug. 4, 2011.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00010">
<othercit>International Search Report and Written Opinion received in International Application No. PCT/EP2009/050674 dated May 7, 2009.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>16</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>381312</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>381322</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>381323</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>381324</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>381326</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>381328</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>600 25</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>607 55</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>607 56</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>607 57</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>623 10</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110280426</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20111117</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bachler</last-name>
<first-name>Herbert</first-name>
<address>
<city>Zurich</city>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CH</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bachler</last-name>
<first-name>Herbert</first-name>
<address>
<city>Zurich</city>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>ALG Intellectual Property, LLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Advanced Bionics AG</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Staefa</city>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Ni</last-name>
<first-name>Suhan</first-name>
<department>2656</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/EP2009/050674</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20090121</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20110720</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2009/047370</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20090416</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A partially implantable hearing aid is provided, comprising an external audio signal unit to be worn at least in part in a user's ear canal, an implantable unit and external means for transmitting power transcutaneously to the implantable unit via an inductive link, the external audio signal unit comprising audio signal processing means for producing processed audio signals from input audio signals and means for transmitting the processed audio signals via an optical link through an ear drum to an optical receiver of the implantable unit, the implantable unit comprising an actuator for stimulating the user's hearing, a power receiving means and a driver unit for transforming the received audio signals into an input signal to the actuator.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="154.52mm" wi="193.89mm" file="US08625829-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="273.81mm" wi="191.26mm" file="US08625829-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="169.50mm" wi="175.34mm" file="US08625829-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The invention relates to a partially implantable hearing aid.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Fully implantable hearing aids are cosmetically appealing and stigma-free, so that such systems are potentially attractive despite the need for surgery and the relatively high costs involved in such systems. However, presently such fully implantable hearing aids still are not widely applied due to serious technical deficits and disadvantages encountered by the presently available systems. For example, the rechargeable batteries do not last for lifetime and hence must be replaced every couple of years by another surgery. Also, technological progress and new benefits cannot be applied after implantation, so that products get outdated rather fast. Moreover, subcutaneous microphones are rather noisy, both in terms of system noise (reduced sensitivity due to titanium membrane and package) and body noise picked-up by the microphone. The microphone position is mostly on the side of the head as opposed to the ear-canal, so that spatial information which is normally offered by the pinna is lost.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Partially implantable hearing aids, such as all currently available cochlear implants (CI), are cosmetically less appealing, but overcome some of these problems. Usually, the battery and the signal processing unit are assembled into a body worn or head worn device, which is connected via an inductive wireless link with the implanted part of the system. Typically, the external device is worn behind the ear and has a relatively large size, with the largest part of the device being covered by the battery. The reason is that the battery has to last at least one full day and that the wireless transmission of both power and data through one and the same inductive link is very inefficient. Moreover, the total power consumption is dependent on the thickness of the skin.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">EP 1 251 809 B1 relates to a partially implantable hearing aid designed as a cochlear implant, wherein the external part of the system comprises a device to be worn in the ear-canal, which device includes the microphone, the audio signal processing unit and a transmitter for transmitting the audio signals via a radio frequency (RF) link to the implanted part. The implanted part comprises a receiver located in the mastoid and the cochlear electrode. The transcutaneous power link is realized by an external charging coil and an implanted coil, with the receiver being used both in the power link and the data link.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">A similar system is described in US 2005/0267549 A1, wherein it is mentioned that the external microphone may be located in the ear canal and may be connected via an RF link to the implanted part.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">WO 2006/045148 A2 relates to a partially implantable CI-system comprising a BTE (Behind-The-Ear)&#x2014;like device including the external microphone, the battery and the audio signal processing unit. The audio signals are transmitted via a capacitive data link to the receiver which is implanted in the mastoid and which is also used in the inductive power link.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">U.S. Pat. No. 7,289,639 B2 relates to a partially implantable hearing aid comprising an implanted actuator which may be a mechanical actuator coupled to an ossicle or a cochlear electrode, and an external device which is to be worn in the ear canal and which comprises a microphone, a battery, an audio signal processing unit and an optical transmitter which is provided for establishing an optical link through the ear drum to an optical receiver implanted in the middle ear cavity. The optical link also is intended to serve as the power supply for the implanted actuator. A similar device is described in US 2006/0189841 A1.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">It is an object of the invention to provide for a partially implantable hearing aid which allows for a cosmetically appealing design by avoiding the need for bulky external parts of the system.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to the invention, this object is achieved by a partially implantable hearing aid as defined in claim <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The invention is beneficial in that, by transmitting the audio signals via an optical link to the implantable unit while power is transmitted via an inductive link to the implantable unit, the power consumption of the system can be reduced, since the power link can be optimized due to its separation from the data link. In addition, by arranging the audio signal processing means and the audio signal transmission means in an external unit to be worn at least in part in the ear canal, the size of the externally visible part of the system can be minimized.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Preferably, the actuator is a cochlear electrode. The external audio signal unit may be designed as a CIC (Completely-In-the-Canal) device. Preferably, the power transmitting means is a charging adapter and the power receiving means is a rechargeable battery which may be located in the mastoid.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Usually, the external audio signal unit will comprise at least one microphone for generating the input audio signals to the audio signal processing unit.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Further preferred embodiments are defined in the sub-claims.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Hereinafter examples of the invention will be illustrated by reference to the attached drawings, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view of an example of a partially implantable hearing aid according to the invention comprising an electromechanical actuator;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an example of a driver circuit for the actuator of the hearing aid of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an example of a partially implantable hearing aid according to the invention comprising a CI.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view of an example of a partially implantable hearing aid comprising an electro-mechanical actuator.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The system comprises an external audio signal unit <b>10</b>, which is designed as a modified CIC hearing aid and which is to be worn in the user's ear canal <b>12</b>. The external unit <b>10</b> comprises a microphone arrangement <b>14</b>, an audio signal processing unit <b>16</b>, a transmitter circuit <b>18</b> and a LED (Light Emitting Diode) <b>20</b>. The microphone arrangement <b>14</b> may comprises at least two spaced-apart microphones (not shown) in order to provide for acoustic beam forming capability. The audio signal processing unit <b>16</b> processes the audio signals provided by the microphone arrangement <b>14</b> and supplies the processed audio signals to a transmitter circuit <b>18</b> which drives the LED <b>20</b>. The external unit <b>10</b> also comprises a battery (not shown) which may be rechargeable. The audio signal processing unit <b>16</b> preferably is implemented by an ultra-low power hearing instrument DSP (Digital Signal Processor) of the type which is also used in electro-acoustic CIC hearing aids. Thus, the external part <b>10</b> is quite similar to a CIC hearing aid, with the loudspeaker being replaced by the transmitter circuit <b>18</b> and the LED <b>20</b>. Thereby, all signal processing algorithms and procedure available in CIC hearing aids may be straightforwardly applied to the external unit <b>10</b>, with only minor modifications due to the different output transducer being necessary.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The system also includes an implantable unit <b>22</b> comprising an implanted audio signal unit <b>24</b>, an electro-mechanical actuator <b>26</b> and a power management unit <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The power management unit <b>28</b> comprises a power receiving coil <b>30</b>, a power management circuitry <b>32</b> and a rechargeable battery <b>34</b>. The battery <b>34</b> is charged via transcutaneous inductive power link <b>36</b> by an external charging adapter <b>38</b> comprising a power transmission coil <b>40</b> which transmits power to the power receiving coil <b>30</b> of the power management unit <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The implantable audio signal unit <b>24</b> is located in the middle-ear cavity close to the ear drum <b>46</b> and comprises a photo diode <b>42</b> as an optical receiver for light <b>44</b> which is emitted by the LED <b>20</b> and which passes through the ear drum <b>46</b>, a decoder <b>48</b> for retrieving the audio signals from the received light <b>44</b> and a driver unit <b>50</b> for driving the actuator <b>26</b>. The implantable audio signal unit <b>24</b> may be packaged in glass.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The actuator <b>26</b> is an electro-mechanical transducer which is coupled via a coupling element <b>52</b> to a middle-ear component <b>54</b>, namely an ossicle or the cochlear wall. The actuator <b>26</b> may be designed, for example, as a floating mass transducer (FMT) fixed at one of the ossicles or a direct acoustic cochlear stimulator (DACS) directly acting on the cochlear wall, i.e. foot plate, oval window, round window or any artificial opening of the cochlea.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The rechargeable battery <b>34</b> of the power management unit <b>28</b> should be dimensioned for lasting at least a full day and it should be possible to recharge it within a few hours; charging must be feasible during normal operation of the hearing aid or at night. Preferably, the rechargeable battery <b>34</b> is designed in thin-film lithium technology.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The power management unit <b>28</b> serves as the power supply for the implantable audio signal unit <b>24</b> and the actuator <b>26</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">According to a modified embodiment, the audio signal unit <b>10</b> may be designed as a modified BTE hearing aid wherein the LED <b>20</b> is located in the ear canal <b>12</b>. In this case, the LED <b>20</b> is connected by wire to the external part of the BTE hearing aid in a manner similar to manner in which an ex-receiver is connected to a BTE hearing aid, with the external part which is located behind the user's ear comprising the microphone arrangement <b>14</b>, the audio signal processing unit <b>16</b> and the transmitter circuit <b>18</b>. In other words, according to such embodiment, the ex-receiver of a conventional BTE hearing aid would be replaced by an optical audio signal transmitter comprising the LED <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows an example of the circuitry of the implantable audio signal unit <b>24</b>, wherein the photo diode <b>42</b> triggers a H-bridge comprising four switches <b>56</b>A, <b>56</b>B, <b>56</b>C and <b>56</b>D, which drives the actuator <b>26</b> as a floating load. The driving signal of a H-bridge usually is a pulse width modulated signal or a pulse density modulated signal, i.e. a purely digital pulse-train, the analogue-to-digital conversion is done by the low-pass characteristics of the actuator <b>26</b> itself. The decoder <b>48</b> is implemented as part of the H-bridge. Thus, an extremely simple design requiring only a couple of logic gates is realized.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows an alternative embodiment of the invention, wherein the actuator is a cochlear electrode <b>60</b>. In this case, the power management unit <b>128</b> in addition to the power control <b>32</b>, the power receiving coil <b>30</b> and the rechargeable battery <b>34</b> comprises a signal decoder/driver unit <b>148</b> and a photo diode <b>42</b>. The photo diode <b>42</b> is integrated within the housing of the power management unit <b>128</b> and detects light supplied by an implanted optical fibre <b>62</b>. Light <b>44</b> which is emitted by the LED <b>20</b> of the external audio signal unit <b>10</b> and which has passed through the ear drum <b>46</b> is collected by a lens <b>64</b> and is coupled into one end of the optical fibre <b>62</b> by which it is guided to the photo diode <b>42</b>. The decoder/driver unit <b>148</b> supplies electrical stimulation signals to the cochlear electrode <b>60</b> via a wire <b>66</b>. The lens <b>64</b> is located in the middle ear cavity close to the ear drum <b>46</b>, whereas the unit <b>128</b> is implanted in the mastoid.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">According to a modified embodiment, which is not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the photo diode <b>42</b> may be located in the middle-ear cavity close to the ear drum <b>46</b> in the manner shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, with the output signal of the photo diode being supplied by wire to the unit <b>128</b>.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A partially implantable hearing aid comprising:
<claim-text>an external audio signal unit to be worn at least in part in a user's ear canal,</claim-text>
<claim-text>an implantable unit, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an external means for transmitting power transcutaneously to the implantable unit via an inductive link,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the external audio signal unit comprises an audio signal processing means for producing processed audio signals from input audio signals and means for transmitting the processed audio signals via an optical link through an ear drum to an optical receiver of the implantable unit, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the implantable unit comprises an actuator for stimulating a user's hearing, a power receiving means and a driver unit for transforming received audio signals into an input signal to the actuator.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The hearing aid of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the external means for transmitting power is a charging adapter and wherein the power receiving means comprises a rechargeable battery.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The hearing aid of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the rechargeable battery is for being located in a mastoid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The hearing aid of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the external audio signal unit comprises at least one microphone for generating the input audio signals.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The hearing aid of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the external audio signal unit is designed as a CIC device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The hearing aid of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the means for transmitting the processed audio signals comprises a LED to be located in the user's ear canal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The hearing aid of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the optical receiver comprises a photo diode to be located in a middle ear.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The hearing aid of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the actuator is a cochlear electrode.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The hearing aid of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the optical receiver comprises:
<claim-text>a photo diode,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light collecting means located in a middle ear for collecting light received from the external audio signal unit and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical fiber for passing light from the light collecting means to the photo diode.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The hearing aid of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the photo diode is for being located in a mastoid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The hearing aid of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the driver unit is for being located in a mastoid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The hearing aid of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the driver unit is located in a housing common with the rechargeable battery.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The hearing aid of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the actuator is an electromechanical transducer to be coupled to an ossicle or to a cochlear wall.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The hearing aid of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the driver unit is for being located in a middle ear.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The hearing aid of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the driver unit is designed as a H-bridge circuit triggered by a photo diode.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The hearing aid of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the photo diode and the driver unit are packaged in glass. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
