<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622610-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622610</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13391149</doc-number>
<date>20100616</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="regional">
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>09162836</doc-number>
<date>20090616</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>20</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>25</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>368148</main-classification>
<further-classification>368207</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Inverter device for a timepiece movement</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3306025</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kocher</name>
<date>19670200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>368148</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3620337</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Fluck</name>
<date>19711100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>192 36</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3838567</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Giger et al.</name>
<date>19741000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>368208</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0237035</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Helfer et al.</name>
<date>20071000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>368147</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>CH</country>
<doc-number>256922</doc-number>
<date>19490300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>CH</country>
<doc-number>331124</doc-number>
<date>19580600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>CH</country>
<doc-number>499801</doc-number>
<date>19640800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00008">
<othercit>English translation of CH331124, retrived from the internet May 5, 2013.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>19</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>368147</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>368148</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>368206-208</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>7</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120176870</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120712</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tran</last-name>
<first-name>Huy Van</first-name>
<address>
<city>La Chaux-de-Fongs</city>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CH</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Perez</last-name>
<first-name>Ludovic</first-name>
<address>
<city>Villers-le-Lac</city>
<country>FR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>FR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tran</last-name>
<first-name>Huy Van</first-name>
<address>
<city>La Chaux-de-Fongs</city>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Perez</last-name>
<first-name>Ludovic</first-name>
<address>
<city>Villers-le-Lac</city>
<country>FR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Finnegan, Henderson, Farabow, Garrett &#x26; Dunner, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Pequignet S.A.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Morteau</city>
<country>FR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Miska</last-name>
<first-name>Vit W</first-name>
<department>2833</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/EP2010/058498</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20100616</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20120217</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2010/146099</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20101223</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An inverter device for timepiece movements is disclosed which includes first and second toothed wheels intended to be driven in opposite rotation directions and coaxial with an output toothed member intended to be kinematically connected to a pivoting member of the timepiece movement. The wheels are connected to the output member by unidirectional transmission members adapted to transmit to the output member rotation in only the same one predefined rotation direction and to prevent the transmission of rotation of the output member in this predefined rotation direction to one or the other of the wheels. Each unidirectional transmission member includes two diametrically opposite teeth of asymmetrical shape and is connected to the output member in such a manner as to be constrained to rotate with it while being able to be moved between first and second extreme positions in a radial direction. Each wheel includes a plate provided with a central counterbore defining a housing for the corresponding unidirectional transmission member and the periphery of which includes n peripheral tips intended to cooperate with the teeth of the corresponding unidirectional transmission member in the predefined rotation direction, and each of which is defined by the intersection of a circular hole with the periphery, n being equal to or greater than one.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="148.76mm" wi="164.59mm" file="US08622610-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="167.98mm" wi="163.83mm" file="US08622610-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="214.71mm" wi="162.48mm" file="US08622610-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="206.42mm" wi="168.83mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622610-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="230.55mm" wi="163.07mm" file="US08622610-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="230.63mm" wi="164.34mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622610-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation application of prior International Application No. PCT/EP2010/058498, filed on Jun. 16, 2010 and claiming priority to European (EP) Patent Application No. 09162836.2, filed Jun. 16, 2009.</p>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention concerns an inverter device, intended to equip a timepiece movement, including first and second toothed wheels intended to be driven simultaneously in opposite rotation directions by a mechanism of the timepiece movement. The first and second wheels may both be coaxial with an output toothed member, intended to be connected kinematically to a pivoting member of the timepiece movement, and may be mechanically connected to the output member by first and second unidirectional transmission members, or pawls, respectively, adapted to transmit to the output member a rotation of one wheel or the other in the same single predefined rotation direction and to prevent the transmission of a rotation of the output member in the predefined rotation direction to one or the other of the wheels.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention also concerns a timepiece movement comprising such an inverter device as well as a method of manufacturing such an inverter device.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Unidirectional transmission members and inverter devices are already routinely used in automatic winding timepiece movements, notably being disposed in the automatic winding train of the barrel spring. For example, different embodiments of such devices are described in pages 180 et seq of &#x201c;Th&#xe9;orie d'horlogerie&#x201d;, by C.-A. Reymondin et al., published by F&#xe9;d&#xe9;ration des Ecoles Techniques (Suisse), ISBN 2-940025-10-X.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Two types of wheel are used in these devices, namely some intended to cooperate with a unidirectional transmission member in an axial direction and others intended to cooperate with a unidirectional transmission member in the general plane of the wheel. In the first case, the wheels have structures that are generally simpler than in the second case, but the corresponding devices have a larger overall size. However, when the cooperation between the wheel and the unidirectional transmission member occurs in the general plane of the wheel, it is necessary to machine detents or tips in the wheel, generally by complex milling operations, which can prove costly. This drawback is all the more of a problem when two wheels are necessary to produce an inverter device in the same timepiece movement.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Furthermore, the aforementioned work gives an example of an inverter device comprising two unidirectional transmission systems arranged one alongside the other, thus having a non-negligible overall size within the corresponding timepiece movement.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The patent CH 331124 gives an example of an inverter device in which two unidirectional transmission systems are arranged coaxially with each other to reduce the overall size of the inverter device. However, the structure of the components used in this device is complex and likewise their assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Moreover, it will be noted that these devices are not generally used in the manual winding train, in which a clutch mechanism is generally used, to prevent rotation of the winding stem when the barrel is driven from the automatic winding mechanism.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">A principal object of the present invention is to alleviate the drawbacks of known prior art devices by proposing such a device the manufacture and assembly of which are simplified compared to known inverter devices, the resulting overall size being small compared to that of known inverters.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">To this end, the present invention more particularly concerns an inverter device wherein each of the unidirectional transmission members may include two teeth that may be substantially diametrically opposite and may have asymmetrical shapes, and may be mechanically connected to the output member in such a manner as to be constrained to rotate therewith whilst being able to be moved between first and second extreme positions in a radial direction with reference to the output member. This inverter device may further be arranged such that each of the first and second wheels includes a plate, having a first radius R<b>10</b>, respectively R<b>100</b>, and is provided with peripheral teeth, as well as a central counterbore defining a housing for the corresponding unidirectional transmission member and the periphery of which includes n peripheral tips intended to cooperate with the teeth of the corresponding unidirectional transmission member in the predefined rotation direction, and each of which is defined by the intersection of a circular hole with the periphery, n being equal to or greater than one.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Thanks to these features, the inverter device of the present invention may be manufactured and assembled very easily and enables conversion of two opposite rotation movements of a timepiece mechanism into a single rotation movement of a mobile, in a predefined rotation direction, whilst having a small overall size relative to prior art inverter devices.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The inverter device may preferably be further arranged such that, for each of the first and second wheels, the central counterbore has a shape resulting from the combination of a substantially circular central main first hole having a second radius R<b>20</b>, respectively R<b>200</b>, with n secondary circular holes, having a third radius R<b>30</b>, respectively R<b>300</b>, less than the second radius R<b>20</b> or R<b>200</b>, and the centers C<b>30</b>, C<b>300</b> of which are situated at a distance from the center C<b>10</b>, C<b>100</b> of the corresponding wheel greater than R<b>20</b>-R<b>30</b>, respectively R<b>200</b>-R<b>300</b>. Furthermore, each of the first and second wheels may preferably include n supplementary circular holes, having a fourth radius R<b>40</b>, respectively R<b>400</b>, less than the third radius R<b>30</b> or R<b>300</b>, each of the n supplementary holes intersecting a portion of the periphery of the corresponding central counterbore defined by a single one of the secondary circular holes and each of the n supplementary holes having its center C<b>40</b>, C<b>400</b> situated on a radius other than the radius passing through the center C<b>30</b>, C<b>300</b> of the corresponding secondary hole, at a distance from the center C<b>10</b>, C<b>100</b> of the corresponding wheel greater than the second radius R<b>20</b>, respectively R<b>200</b>, in such a manner as to define the tips.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Thus all machining of the part of each wheel that is intended to cooperate with the inverter member may be effected by simple operations, notably drilling operations, or even by milling operations of reduced complexity. In the context of the present disclosure, by &#x201c;drilling&#x201d; must be understood the operation of making a circular hole, which may be a blind hole or a through-hole, using a drilling tool exerting an action on the material to be machined in the direction of its rotation axis.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">It will moreover be noted that the supplementary holes, use of which is not absolutely necessary to obtain the advantageous effects of the present invention, favor some smoothness of operation when a wheel acts on the corresponding unidirectional transmission member, to move it in a radial direction when the rotation movement of the wheel must not be retransmitted to the pivoting member via the associated unidirectional transmission member.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The first and second wheels may advantageously be disposed in such a manner that their respective counterbores face each other, the unidirectional transmission members being superposed.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The inverter device may preferably further comprise a central guide member adapted to constrain the output member and the unidirectional transmission members to rotate together. Moreover, the guide member may advantageously be fastened to the output member and comprise a bush, having two substantially parallel flats, adapted to cooperate with an opening provided in each of the unidirectional transmission members and having a width slightly greater than the distance separating the flats from each other and a length greater than the diameter of the bush, to enable the unidirectional transmission members to be moved relative to the bush guided by the flats.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The present invention also provides a method of manufacturing a wheel for such an inverter device or for a unidirectional transmission device, which may comprise the steps consisting of obtaining a plate having a first radius R<b>1</b> and providing peripheral teeth on the plate, the method including the supplementary steps of:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0002-0001" num="0018">forming a central counterbore in the plate and</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0002" num="0019">drilling n tips at the periphery of the central counterbore intended to cooperate with a unidirectional transmission member and each of which is defined by the intersection of a circular hole with the periphery, n being equal to or greater than one.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0020">The central counterbore may advantageously be formed by machining a substantially circular central first main hole having a second radius R<b>2</b>, combined with machining n secondary circular holes, having a third radius R<b>3</b> less than the second radius R<b>2</b> and the centers C<b>3</b> of which are situated at a distance from the center C<b>1</b> of the wheel greater than R<b>2</b>-R<b>3</b>. The method may include a supplementary step consisting of machining n additional circular holes having a fourth radius R<b>4</b> less than the third radius R<b>3</b>, each of the n supplementary holes intersecting a portion of the periphery of the central counterbore defined by a single one of the secondary circular holes and each of the n additional holes having its center C<b>4</b> situated on a radius other than the radius passing through the center C<b>3</b> of the corresponding secondary hole, at a distance from C<b>1</b> greater than the second radius R<b>2</b>, in such a manner as to define the tips. The supplementary holes may be machined before the other holes.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0021">The present invention further provides a timepiece movement including a unidirectional transmission device and/or an inverter device provided with such a wheel.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0022">Other features and advantages of the present invention will become more clearly apparent on reading the following detailed description of preferred embodiments given with reference to the appended drawings provided by way of nonlimiting example and in which:</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a simplified diagrammatic front view showing the manufacture of a wheel of a preferred embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a simplified perspective view of part of an inverter device intended to cooperate with a wheel similar to that shown diagrammatically in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a simplified view of a unidirectional transmission device using the elements from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> in section taken along the line III-III in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a simplified perspective view, partially as if transparent, of one example of use of the unidirectional transmission device from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a timepiece movement;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a simplified perspective view, partly as if transparent, of an inverter device of a preferred embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a simplified view of the inverter device from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> in section taken along the line VI-VI in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a simplified front view, partially as if transparent, of one example of use of the inverter device from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> in a timepiece movement.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0029" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows diagrammatically the method of manufacturing a wheel <b>1</b> of a preferred embodiment of the present invention, such a wheel being intended to equip a unidirectional transmission device or an inverter device, notably to be integrated into a manual or automatic winding train of a timepiece movement of the automatic winding type.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0031">The manufacturing process comprises the following steps, after obtaining a wheel plate <b>2</b>, with center C<b>1</b>, having a first radius R<b>1</b> and in which peripheral teeth <b>3</b> are produced.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0032">A central counterbore <b>5</b> is produced, preferably by drilling with a second radius R<b>2</b>. A plurality of secondary circular holes <b>6</b> is produced by drilling operations, with a third radius R<b>3</b>, less than the second radius R<b>2</b>. The centers C<b>3</b> of the secondary holes <b>6</b> are advantageously situated at a distance from the center C<b>1</b> of the plate <b>2</b> greater than R<b>2</b>-R<b>3</b>. The secondary holes therefore intersect the periphery of the central counterbore <b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0033">There may be provision for n secondary holes to be drilled, n being greater than or equal to one.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0034">A supplementary operation consists of drilling n supplementary circular holes <b>8</b> having a fourth radius R<b>4</b> less than the third radius R<b>3</b>. Each of the additional holes <b>8</b> intersects a portion of the periphery of the central counterbore <b>5</b> defined by a single secondary hole <b>6</b>, having its center C<b>4</b> situated on a radius other than the radius passing through the center C<b>3</b> of the corresponding secondary hole <b>6</b>, at a distance from C<b>1</b> greater than the second radius R<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0035">The intersection of each secondary hole <b>8</b> with the corresponding supplementary hole <b>6</b> defines a tip <b>10</b> intended to cooperate with a unidirectional transmission member, as will emerge from the detailed description of the subsequent figures.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0036">The secondary and supplementary holes may be blind holes or through-holes without departing from the scope of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0037">It will be noted that the chronology of executing the steps that have just been described is liable to vary as a function of the locations and radii of the various holes to be drilled. It is easier to drill a hole if the location of its center is not devoid of material.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0038">As an alternative to the method described above, it is possible to provide for the central counterbore <b>5</b> not to be produced by specific drilling but to be obtained directly by the production of the secondary holes <b>6</b>, which preferably have, in this case, a sufficient radius for all of the material at the center of the plate to be removed after all of the secondary holes have been formed.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0039">It emerges from the above description of the method that it is not necessary, as is the case in the prior art, to use complex and costly machining operations. Simple conventional drilling operations or milling operations of low complexity are sufficient to manufacture the wheel intended to equip an inverter device of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</figref>, <b>3</b> and <b>4</b> show all or part of a unidirectional transmission device incorporating a wheel similar to that which has just been described.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a simplified perspective view showing components of this device.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0042">The unidirectional transmission device includes a first toothed wheel <b>20</b> having a central opening (not visible) in which is accommodated and to which is fastened a central connecting member <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0043">The latter member comprises a bush <b>22</b> of cylindrical general shape on which two parallel flats <b>24</b> are produced.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0044">A unidirectional transmission member <b>25</b>, comprising two teeth <b>26</b> of asymmetrical shape, is engaged over the bush <b>22</b> by means of a central opening <b>27</b>. Each tooth has a front side (in the active rotation direction) that is substantially radial and a rear side having a short substantially tangential portion followed by a gentle slope, itself followed by a long portion of substantially circular shape providing the connection to the next tooth.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0045">The central opening has a substantially oblong shape with a width slightly greater than the distance separating the two flats <b>24</b> and a length greater than the diameter of the bush <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0046">It is clear from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> that the unidirectional transmission member is connected to the connecting member <b>21</b>, and thus to the first wheel <b>20</b>, in such manner that it is constrained to rotate with the first wheel, while it is able to be moved in a substantially radial direction relative to the axis of the latter wheel.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0047">It will be noted that the preferred structure of the unidirectional transmission member as described and shown enables it to be manufactured by an extremely simple method. Such a member may advantageously be obtained by stamping.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a view in section of the unidirectional transmission device with the components described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> assembled to a central shaft <b>30</b> for mounting the device on the frame (not shown) of a timepiece movement.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0049">Furthermore, a second wheel <b>32</b> assembled to the other components is coaxial with the first wheel <b>20</b> and the shaft <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0050">The second wheel <b>32</b> is obtained by the manufacturing method described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a simplified perspective view showing how the second wheel <b>32</b>, which here comprises seven tips <b>10</b>, cooperates with the unidirectional transmission member <b>25</b> and how the unidirectional transmission device may advantageously be used in a timepiece movement.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0052">It is seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> that the unidirectional transmission member <b>25</b> is accommodated in the central counterbore <b>5</b> of the second wheel and has dimensions such that its teeth <b>26</b> are able to cooperate with the tips <b>10</b> of the latter wheel</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0053">To be more precise, it is clear that the asymmetrical shape of the teeth <b>26</b> has the consequence that a tooth may cooperate with a tip in only one direction of relative rotation between the unidirectional transmission member and the second wheel, namely when the latter is driven in rotation in the anticlockwise direction as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. Note further that cooperation between the unidirectional transmission member and the second wheel involves only one tooth at a time.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0054">In the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the unidirectional transmission device is used in a manual winding train of a timepiece movement of the automatic winding type, i.e. between the winding stem (not shown) and the barrel <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0055">The winding stem is arranged in the conventional manner to drive a sliding pinion (not shown) intended to drive in rotation a mobile, here a winding pinion <b>42</b>, via Breguet teeth <b>43</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0056">The winding pinion meshes with the first wheel <b>20</b> of the unidirectional transmission device via supplementary teeth <b>44</b>. The winding pinion <b>42</b> is driven in rotation only when the winding stem is turned in the clockwise direction (as seen from the outside toward the inside), because of the conventional orientation of the Breguet teeth.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0057">The first wheel <b>20</b> is then driven in the anticlockwise rotation direction and because of this induces rotation of the unidirectional transmission member <b>25</b> in the same rotation direction.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0058">This brings about the configuration of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, in which a tooth <b>26</b> cooperates with a tip <b>10</b> of the second wheel <b>32</b> to drive the latter wheel in rotation in the same direction.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0059">The drum of the barrel <b>40</b> is therefore driven in rotation in the clockwise direction to recharge its spring (not visible).</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0060">Moreover, it will be noted that a pawl <b>45</b> has been provided to cooperate with the first wheel <b>20</b>. The pawl <b>45</b> includes a plate <b>46</b> provided with a single peripheral tooth <b>47</b> interengaged with the teeth of the first wheel <b>20</b>. The plate <b>46</b> has a flat <b>48</b> on a portion of its periphery, against which a spring <b>49</b> bears, in such a manner as to retain the plate <b>46</b> in its angular position as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. Accordingly, on each stepwise movement of the first wheel <b>20</b> in the anticlockwise direction, the plate <b>46</b> turns by one step in the clockwise direction and is immediately returned to its initial position by the action of the spring <b>49</b>. Consequently, when the winding stem is turned in the clockwise direction, an effect similar to that produced by a conventional ratchet is obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0061">Conversely, if the winding stem is turned in the anticlockwise direction, the sliding of the Breguet teeth produces a similar effect that is present in only some known timepiece calibers either of the manually wound type or of the automatically wound type, but in which no clutch device is provided in the winding train, as is the case for example of the 7750 caliber marketed by the Swiss company ETA S.A. Manufacture Horlog&#xe8;re Suisse. This ratchet effect, when present in both rotation directions of the winding stem, gives the wearer of the corresponding watch an impression of high quality when they wind it manually.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0062">Moreover, the pawl <b>45</b> advantageously provides the additional function of a ratchet for the barrel drum. The diameter of the plate <b>46</b> on one of the sides of the single tooth <b>47</b> is equal to the diameter that it has at the level of the tooth, thus preventing rotation of the first wheel <b>20</b> in the clockwise rotation direction. Such a feature, notably combined with the location of the pawl <b>45</b>, enables the efficiency of automatic winding to be improved given that the automatic winding mechanism does not need to overcome the force of the pawl <b>45</b> to wind the barrel spring, in contrast to prior art mechanisms, thanks to the provision of the unidirectional transmission device.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0063">If manual winding is not used, the barrel spring may be recharged from the automatic winding mechanism. In this case, the drum of the barrel <b>40</b> is driven by the latter in the clockwise rotation direction.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0064">This rotation movement of the barrel drum drives rotation of the second wheel <b>32</b> of the unidirectional transmission device in the anticlockwise direction. In this case, however, the tips <b>10</b> come into contact with the teeth <b>26</b> of the unidirectional transmission member on their inactive side, with the inclined side of the teeth. Thus not only does the second wheel <b>32</b> not drive the unidirectional transmission member <b>25</b> in rotation, but it pushes it back so that it is moved on the bush <b>22</b>. If the second wheel <b>32</b> turns for a certain time, the unidirectional transmission member effects to-and-fro movements between its two extreme positions, its teeth being alternately pushed back by the rear sides of the tips <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0065">Thus the rotation movement of the second wheel <b>32</b> in the anticlockwise rotation direction is not transmitted to the first wheel <b>20</b>, which remains stationary.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0066">It is therefore seen that this unidirectional transmission device has the same function as prior art clutch devices, possibly in a more efficient manner because the inversion effect is instantaneous, in contrast to some of those clutch devices (notably those not including a spring).</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0067"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 to 7</figref> show an inverter device of a preferred embodiment of the present invention using two wheels of the type the manufacturing method for which is described above, with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0068"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a simplified perspective view, partially as if transparent, of that inverter device.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0069">The latter device includes a central shaft <b>50</b> on which are mounted, free to rotate, two wheels <b>51</b> and <b>52</b> of the type for which the manufacturing process is described above, with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, that is to say each comprising a central counterbore on the periphery of which tips <b>53</b>, <b>54</b> are provided.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0070">The wheels <b>51</b> and <b>52</b> are superposed and adjacent, first and second unidirectional transmission members <b>56</b>, <b>57</b> being accommodated in their respective central counterbores. Each of the unidirectional transmission members is similar to that described above, with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, that is to say it includes two teeth <b>58</b>, <b>59</b> intended to cooperate with the tips <b>53</b> or <b>54</b> of the wheel with which it is associated.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0071">It will further be noted that one of the two unidirectional transmission members may advantageously include a plurality of bosses (at least two, not shown), which may be formed by punches when it is stamped, for example, to reduce the area of contact between the two members and prevent them sticking to each other.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0072">The central shaft <b>50</b> has a section provided with two substantially parallel flats <b>60</b> intended to define guide surfaces for central openings <b>62</b> provided in the unidirectional transmission members. Accordingly, the latter members are adapted to be moved in a radial direction with reference to the central shaft <b>50</b>, as described above, with reference to the first embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0073">It is clear from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> that the two unidirectional transmission members <b>56</b>, <b>57</b> and the wheels <b>51</b>, <b>52</b> are arranged in such a manner that each wheel drives its unidirectional transmission member only when it turns in the anticlockwise rotation direction.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0074">Conversely, when the wheels <b>51</b> and <b>52</b> are driven in the clockwise rotation direction, the tips <b>53</b>, <b>54</b> slide over the teeth <b>58</b>, <b>59</b> without driving the unidirectional transmission members in rotation, but forcing them to effect a to-and-fro movement between their two extreme positions along the flats <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0075">It will be noted with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> that the two wheel plus unidirectional transmission member assemblies are the same way up.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0076"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a simplified view of the inverter device from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> in section taken along the line VI-VI in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, from which it is seen that the central shaft <b>50</b> comprises two components, namely a main shaft <b>64</b> and a guide member <b>65</b> in which the flats <b>60</b> are provided.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0077">The main shaft is intended for fastening the inverter device to an element of the frame of the timepiece movement for which it is intended by means of a central bore <b>66</b>. Moreover, it includes a pinion <b>67</b> intended to form an output member of the inverter device, as will become clearer from the detailed description of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0078">Of course, without departing from the scope of the invention it is possible for the main shaft to carry directly pivots for mounting on the frame of the timepiece movement in place of the central bore <b>66</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0079">It will be noted that assembling the inverter device of the present invention is very simple. It suffices to place the first wheel <b>51</b> on the guide member <b>65</b>, then the two unidirectional transmission members <b>56</b> and <b>57</b>, then the second wheel <b>52</b>, before inserting the main shaft <b>64</b> in an appropriate hole <b>68</b> in the guide member, to fasten these two elements together.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0080">Of course, without departing from the scope of the invention the person skilled in the art could provide the flats <b>60</b> directly on the central shaft <b>64</b>. The latter shaft would then provide the guide member function, while the element <b>65</b> would then have a shorter bush and simply ensure that the various components are held assembled to each other.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0081">The operation of this inverter device is described next, with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, which is a simplified front view, partially as if transparent, of an example of the use of the inverter device from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> in a timepiece movement.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0082">The wheels <b>51</b>, <b>52</b> are intended to be connected to an automatic winding device to be driven in rotation by the movements of an oscillating mass (not shown for reasons of clarity).</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0083">To be more precise, the first wheel <b>51</b> meshes directly with an automatic winding wheel <b>70</b> which is connected directly or indirectly to an oscillating mass.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0084">The second wheel <b>52</b> meshes with the wheel <b>70</b> via a setting wheel <b>71</b>, so as to turn in the opposite rotation direction to the first wheel at all times.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0085">The output member of the inverter device, i.e. the pinion <b>67</b> of the main shaft <b>64</b>, meshes with a first mobile <b>72</b> of an automatic winding train, the first mobile meshing with a second mobile <b>73</b>, itself interengaged with the drum of the barrel <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0086">As indicated above, rotation of either of the wheels <b>51</b>, <b>52</b> in the anticlockwise direction drives rotation of the corresponding unidirectional transmission member in the same rotation direction, while rotation of the wheel in the clockwise direction does not drive the unidirectional transmission member.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0087">When one of the unidirectional transmission members is driven in rotation (and thus necessarily in the anticlockwise direction in the embodiment shown) it induces an identical movement of the output member of the device, namely the pinion <b>67</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0088">Accordingly, when the wheel <b>70</b> is driven in the clockwise rotation direction by the oscillating mass, it induces rotation in the same direction of the second wheel <b>52</b> and anticlockwise rotation of the first wheel <b>51</b>. In this case, the tips <b>54</b> of the second wheel slide on the teeth <b>59</b> of the corresponding unidirectional transmission member <b>57</b>, while one of the tips <b>53</b> of the first wheel snags one of the teeth <b>58</b> of the corresponding unidirectional transmission member <b>56</b> to drive it in rotation.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0089">Consequently, clockwise rotation of the wheel <b>70</b> drives anticlockwise rotation of the output pinion <b>67</b> of the inverter device of the present invention via the first wheel <b>51</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0090">Conversely, when the wheel <b>70</b> is driven in the anticlockwise rotation direction by the oscillating mass, it induces rotation in the same direction of the second wheel <b>52</b> and clockwise rotation of the first wheel <b>51</b>. In this case, one of the tips <b>54</b> of the second wheel snags one of the teeth <b>59</b> of the corresponding unidirectional transmission member <b>57</b> to drive it in rotation and the tips <b>53</b> of the first wheel slide on the teeth <b>58</b> of the corresponding unidirectional transmission member <b>56</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0091">Consequently, anticlockwise rotation of the wheel <b>70</b> also drives anticlockwise rotation of the output pinion <b>67</b> of the inverter device of the present invention via the second wheel <b>52</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0092">Consequently, the inverter device of the present invention exploits rotation of the oscillating mass, regardless of its rotation direction, to recharge the barrel spring.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0093">It will further be noted that the inverter device of the present invention also enables prevention of rotation of the barrel drum in the direction of discharging the barrel spring. In this case, the two wheels <b>51</b> and <b>52</b> are driven in the same rotation direction and tend to drive the wheel <b>70</b> in the opposite rotation direction because of the setting wheel <b>71</b>, the consequence of which is to immobilize them. Thus it is not necessary to provide a pawl for the barrel drum.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0094">It will be noted that the very simple structure of this device has the advantage of limiting its overall size compared to known prior art devices of this type. Furthermore, the small number of its components also renders its manufacture advantageous compared to known devices, enabling a significant reduction in manufacturing costs.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0095">The foregoing description is intended to describe particular embodiments by way of nonlimiting illustration and the invention is not limited to the use of certain particular features that have just been described, for example the number of holes provided in the wheels shown and described, the number of teeth of the unidirectional transmission members, or the rotation directions referred to.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0096">It will be noted that, according to the present invention, the wheel may simply be produced by providing the substantially circular central counterbore and then by drilling a single series of supplementary holes at its periphery, to define the tips intended to cooperate with a unidirectional transmission member. Even if such a solution is less efficacious than the preferred embodiment, it may prove sufficient.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0097">The person skilled in the art will encounter no particular difficulty in adapting the content of the present disclosure to its own requirements by using a wheel, an inverter device or a timepiece movement different from the embodiments described here, but in which the wheel includes a central counterbore the periphery of which has n peripheral tips intended to cooperate with a unidirectional transmission member and each of which is defined by the intersection of two circular holes, n being greater than or equal to one, without departing from the scope of the present invention. It will be noted that the unidirectional transmission device and the inverter device described may be used independently of each other or in combination in the same timepiece movement, and even with a timepiece mechanism other than the winding mechanism, notably a complication calling for a single direction of rotation of a wheel.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An inverter device, intended to equip a timepiece movement, including first and second toothed wheels intended to be driven simultaneously in opposite rotation directions by a mechanism of the timepiece movement, said first and second wheels both being coaxial with an output toothed member, intended to be kinematically connected to a pivoting member of the timepiece movement, and are mechanically connected to said output member by first and second unidirectional transmission members, respectively, adapted to transmit to said output member rotation of one wheel or the other in a single predefined rotation direction and to prevent the transmission of rotation of said output member, in said predefined rotation direction, to one or the other of said wheels,
<claim-text>wherein each of said unidirectional transmission members includes two teeth that are substantially diametrically opposite and have asymmetrical shapes, and is mechanically connected to said output member in such a manner as to be constrained to rotate therewith whilst being able to be moved between first and second extreme positions in a radial direction with reference to said output member,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of said first and second wheels includes a plate, having a first radius R<b>10</b>, respectively R<b>100</b>, and provided with peripheral teeth, as well as a central counterbore defining a housing for the corresponding unidirectional transmission member and the periphery of which includes n peripheral tips intended to cooperate with said teeth of said corresponding unidirectional transmission member in said predefined rotation direction, and each of which is defined by the intersection of a circular hole with said periphery, n being equal to or greater than one.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein, for each of said first and second wheels, said central counterbore has a shape resulting from the combination of a substantially circular central main first hole having a second radius R<b>20</b>, respectively R<b>200</b>, with n secondary circular holes, having a third radius R<b>30</b>, respectively R<b>300</b>, less than said second radius R<b>20</b> or R<b>200</b>, and the centers C<b>30</b>, C<b>300</b> of which are situated at a distance from the center C<b>10</b>, C<b>100</b> of the corresponding wheel greater than R<b>20</b>-R<b>30</b>, respectively R<b>200</b>-R<b>300</b>, and
<claim-text>wherein each of said first and second wheels further includes n supplementary circular holes, having a fourth radius R<b>40</b>, respectively R<b>400</b>, less than said third radius R<b>30</b> or R<b>300</b>, each of said n supplementary holes intersecting a portion of the periphery of said corresponding central counterbore defined by a single one of said secondary circular holes and each of said n supplementary holes having its center C<b>40</b>, C<b>400</b> situated on a radius other than the radius passing through the center C<b>30</b>, C<b>300</b> of the corresponding secondary hole, at a distance from the center C<b>10</b>, C<b>100</b> of the corresponding wheel greater than the second radius R<b>20</b>, respectively R<b>200</b>, in such a manner as to define said tips.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said first and second wheels are disposed in such a manner that their respective counterbores face each other, said unidirectional transmission members being superposed.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a central guide member adapted to constrain said output member and said unidirectional transmission members to rotate together, said guide member being fastened to said output member and comprising a bush, having two substantially parallel flats, adapted to cooperate with an opening provided in each of said unidirectional transmission members and having a width slightly greater than the distance separating said flats from each other and a length greater than the diameter of said bush, to enable said unidirectional transmission members to be moved relative to said bush guided by said flats.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein it is intended to equip an automatic winding timepiece movement, said pivoting member being a barrel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein said first and second wheels are disposed in such a manner that their respective counterbores face each other, said unidirectional transmission members being superposed.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, further comprising a central guide member adapted to constrain said output member and said unidirectional transmission members to rotate together, said guide member being fastened to said output member and comprising a bush, having two substantially parallel flats, adapted to cooperate with an opening provided in each of said unidirectional transmission members and having a width slightly greater than the distance separating said flats from each other and a length greater than the diameter of said bush, to enable said unidirectional transmission members to be moved relative to said bush guided by said flats.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, further comprising a central guide member adapted to constrain said output member and said unidirectional transmission members to rotate together, said guide member being fastened to said output member and comprising a bush, having two substantially parallel flats, adapted to cooperate with an opening provided in each of said unidirectional transmission members and having a width slightly greater than the distance separating said flats from each other and a length greater than the diameter of said bush, to enable said unidirectional transmission members to be moved relative to said bush guided by said flats.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, further comprising a central guide member adapted to constrain said output member and said unidirectional transmission members to rotate together, said guide member being fastened to said output member and comprising a bush, having two substantially parallel flats, adapted to cooperate with an opening provided in each of said unidirectional transmission members and having a width slightly greater than the distance separating said flats from each other and a length greater than the diameter of said bush, to enable said unidirectional transmission members to be moved relative to said bush guided by said flats.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein it is intended to equip an automatic winding timepiece movement, said pivoting member being a barrel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein it is intended to equip an automatic winding timepiece movement, said pivoting member being a barrel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein it is intended to equip an automatic winding timepiece movement, said pivoting member being a barrel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein it is intended to equip an automatic winding timepiece movement, said pivoting member being a barrel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein it is intended to equip an automatic winding timepiece movement, said pivoting member being a barrel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein it is intended to equip an automatic winding timepiece movement, said pivoting member being a barrel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein it is intended to equip an automatic winding timepiece movement, said pivoting member being a barrel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. A method of manufacturing a wheel for a unidirectional transmission device or for an inverter device intended to equip a timepiece movement, comprising the steps consisting of obtaining a plate having a first radius R<b>1</b> and providing peripheral teeth on said plate, further including the supplementary steps of:
<claim-text>forming a central counterbore in said plate, by machining a substantially circular central first main hole having a second radius R<b>2</b>, combined with machining n secondary circular holes, having a third radius R<b>3</b> less than the second radius R<b>2</b> and the centers C<b>3</b> of which are situated at a distance from the center C<b>1</b> of the wheel greater than R<b>2</b>-R<b>3</b>, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>drilling n tips at the periphery of said central counterbore intended to cooperate with a unidirectional transmission member and each of which is defined by the intersection of a supplementary circular hole with said periphery, n being equal to or greater than one, by machining n supplementary circular holes having a fourth radius R<b>4</b> less than said third radius R<b>3</b>, each of said n supplementary holes intersecting a portion of the periphery of said central counterbore defined by a single one of said secondary circular holes and each of said n supplementary holes having its center C<b>4</b> situated on a radius other than the radius passing through the center C<b>3</b> of the corresponding secondary hole, at a distance from C<b>1</b> greater than said second radius R<b>2</b>, in such a manner as to define said tips.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. An automatic winding type timepiece movement, including an inverter device including first and second toothed wheels intended to be driven simultaneously in opposite rotation directions by a mechanism of the timepiece movement, said first and second wheels both being coaxial with an output toothed member, intended to be kinematically connected to a pivoting member of the timepiece movement, and are mechanically connected to said output member by first and second unidirectional transmission members, respectively, adapted to transmit to said output member rotation of one wheel or the other in a single predefined rotation direction and to prevent the transmission of rotation of said output member, in said predefined rotation direction, to one or the other of said wheels,
<claim-text>wherein each of said unidirectional transmission members includes two teeth that are substantially diametrically opposite and have asymmetrical shapes, and is mechanically connected to said output member in such a manner as to be constrained to rotate therewith whilst being able to be moved between first and second extreme positions in a radial direction with reference to said output member,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of said first and second wheels includes a plate, having a first radius R<b>10</b>, respectively R<b>100</b>, and provided with peripheral teeth, as well as a central counterbore defining a housing for the corresponding unidirectional transmission member and the periphery of which includes n peripheral tips intended to cooperate with said teeth of said corresponding unidirectional transmission member in said predefined rotation direction, and each of which is defined by the intersection of a circular hole with said periphery, n being equal to or greater than one,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the timepiece movement comprising on the one hand a manual winding train operated by a winding stem and on the other hand an automatic winding mechanism for recharging a barrel spring accommodated in a barrel, wherein said first and second toothed wheels of said inverter device are intended to be driven simultaneously in opposite rotation directions by said automatic winding mechanism, said toothed output member being intended to be kinematically connected to said barrel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The timepiece movement of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, said unidirectional transmission device being provided in said manual winding train of the timepiece movement.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
