<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625385-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625385</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13438634</doc-number>
<date>20120403</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<disclaimer>
<text>This patent is subject to a terminal disclaimer.</text>
</disclaimer>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>11</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>8</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>3652331</main-classification>
<further-classification>365193</further-classification>
<further-classification>36523313</further-classification>
<further-classification>36523318</further-classification>
<further-classification>711167</further-classification>
<further-classification>713500</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e51">Data capture system and method, and memory controllers and devices</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6671787</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kanda et al.</name>
<date>20031200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7436904</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kwak</name>
<date>20081000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7661010</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>DeFazio et al.</name>
<date>20100200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>713500</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7706195</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Lee et al.</name>
<date>20100400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7888991</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Lin</name>
<date>20110200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8023358</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kim et al.</name>
<date>20110900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8049649</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Moon</name>
<date>20111100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8055930</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Bae et al.</name>
<date>20111100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0069560</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Vo</name>
<date>20110300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>21</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36523318</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>365193</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>3652331</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36523313</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>711167</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>713500</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>7</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12565655</doc-number>
<date>20090923</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8164975</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13438634</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120188828</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120726</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Vo</last-name>
<first-name>Huy</first-name>
<address>
<city>Boise</city>
<state>ID</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Vo</last-name>
<first-name>Huy</first-name>
<address>
<city>Boise</city>
<state>ID</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Dorsey &#x26; Whitney LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Micron Technology, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Boise</city>
<state>ID</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Byrne</last-name>
<first-name>Harry W</first-name>
<department>2824</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Reidlinger</last-name>
<first-name>Lance</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Embodiments of a data capture system and method may be used in a variety of devices, such as in memory controllers and memory devices. The data capture system and method may generate a first set of periodic signals and a second set of periodic signals that differs from the first set. Either the first set of periodic signals or the second set of periodic signals may be selected and used to generate a set of data capture signals. The selection of either the first set or the second set may be made on the basis of the number of serial data digits in a previously captured burst of data. The data capture signals may then be used to capture a burst of serial data digits.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="170.86mm" wi="210.99mm" file="US08625385-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="175.94mm" wi="151.55mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625385-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="231.31mm" wi="167.72mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625385-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="250.70mm" wi="146.98mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625385-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="213.53mm" wi="185.50mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625385-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="222.76mm" wi="187.79mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625385-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="219.79mm" wi="189.15mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625385-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="199.31mm" wi="184.83mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625385-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION(S)</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 12/565,655, filed Sep. 23, 2009, U.S. Pat. No. 8,164,975, which application and patent are herein by reference, in their entirety, for any purpose.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Embodiments of this invention relate to digital integrated circuits, and, more particularly, to systems and methods for correctly capturing serial data bursts in an integrated circuit device.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Digital data is often coupled to integrated circuit devices, such as memory devices, in the form of one or more bursts of serial data. For example, memory devices may have 4 or 8 data bus terminals, each of which transmits or receives a specific number of data bits at the same time the other data bus terminals transmit or receive corresponding bits. For example, a first set of 8 write data bits may be applied to the 8 data bus terminals in parallel, followed by a second set of 8 bits, and so forth, until an eighth and final set of 8 write data bits have been applied to the data bus terminals.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">As each burst of 8 write data bits is applied to the data bus terminals, the data bits are stored in respective latches responsive to a DQS signal, which is normally applied to the memory device along with the write data. Each bit of the write data may be applied to the data bus terminals at the same frequency as, and in synchronism with, a system clock signal. The transitions of the DQS signal are normally offset 90 degrees from the system clock signal so that the transitions of the DQS signal occur midway between the transitions of the system clock, and can be used to capture the write data in the memory device.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">As the data bandwidth of memory devices has continued to increase, the need to transfer data at a faster rate has resulted in the development of memory devices that apply more than one write data bit to each data bus terminal during each period of the system clock signal. For example, memory devices known as double data rate (&#x201c;DDR&#x201d;) devices may capture write data on both the rising and falling edge transitions of the DQS signal. As a result, two write data bits can be captured at each data bus terminal during each period of the system clock signal.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Although the use of DDR techniques has been successful in significantly increasing the data bandwidth of memory devices, the need exists to transfer data at rates that are even faster than the rate at which data can be received and transmitted by DDR memory devices. As a result, DDR2 and DDR3 memory devices have been developed that receive and transmit data at even faster speeds. However, as clock speeds and resulting data rates have increased, the &#x201c;data eye&#x201d; during which the write data can be properly captured by a DQS signal transmitted to a memory device along with the write data has continued to decrease, thus making it more difficult to properly capture write data. One approach that has been proposed is to frequency divide the DQS signal and then generate multiple phases of the frequency-divided signal, such as 4 phases to generate DQS<b>0</b>-<b>3</b> signals.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In operation of a memory device, write data capture may begin a specific latency period after a write command has been applied to a memory device in synchronism with the system clock signal. For example, the latency may be 6 transitions of the system clock signal. After the latency period has expired, a write signal may become active in synchronism with the system clock signal. Write data capture may then begin on the first rising edge of the DQS<b>0</b>-<b>3</b> signal following the write signal becoming active. The first rising edge of one of the DQS<b>0</b>-<b>3</b> signals is not necessarily a rising edge of the DQS<b>0</b> signal. Instead, any one of the four DQS signals can be the first to transition high after the write signal becomes active. As a result, the first data bit that is captured in the memory device may be other than the DQ<b>0</b> bit.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Despite the data bandwidth increases resulting from the transition from DDR to DDR2 and from DDR2 to DDR3, the need exists for still higher data bandwidths. Yet, significant problems can be encountered in attempting to transfer data at a faster rate, some of which are discussed below. Furthermore, although this discussion of the need to increase data bandwidth has been in the context of memory devices, a similar need exists for other types of digital electronic devices. Thus, there is a need for a technique for transferring data at an even faster rate.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a timing diagram illustrating how serial data bits may be captured by respective phases of a frequency divided strobe signal.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a timing diagram showing signals that may be present in a data capture system.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a timing diagram showing other signals that may be present in a data capture system.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a block diagram of a data capture system according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a timing diagram showing signals that are present in a data capture system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a block diagram of an embodiment of a memory device using an embodiment of a data capture system.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a block diagram of an embodiment of a memory system using a memory controller containing an embodiment of a data capture system.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">One approach to increasing the data bandwidth beyond that achieved by DDR3 is to use data strobe signals having a higher frequency than the system clock frequency. For example, if the DQS signal had twice the frequency of the system clock signal, then 4 write data bits could be applied to each data bus terminal during each period of the system clock signal. Memory devices using this technique may be referred to as DDR4 memory devices. However, increases in the frequency of system clock signals may result in the &#x201c;data eye&#x201d; becoming too short to accurately capture the write data bits. Therefore, increasing system clock frequencies may make it difficult or impossible to accurately capture write data.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">One approach to allowing use of DQS signals that are twice the frequency of the system clock signal may be used in DDR4 memory devices to divide the DQS signals by 2 and then generate 4 phases of the resulting half frequency signal. This approach results in 4 PH<b>0</b>-<b>3</b> signals having the same frequency as the system clock signal, and it therefore provides the same internal &#x201c;data eye&#x201d; as the DQS signals in DDR3 memory devices. However, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, each transition of the double frequency DQS signal still coincides with the rising edge of one of the PH<b>0</b>-<b>3</b> signals so that a data bit is captured during each transition of the DQS signal.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Although using 4 PH<b>0</b>-<b>3</b> signals having half the frequency of the DQS signal may reduce the problem of an excessively short &#x201c;data eye,&#x201d; it can create other problems. With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, capturing 64 bits of write data (i.e., 8 bits at each of 8 data bus terminals) followed by capturing another 64 bits of write data does not result in any problem because the PH<b>0</b> signal will capture the first bit DQ<b>0</b> of the second burst of 8-bits immediately after the PH<b>3</b> signal captures the seventh bit DQ<b>7</b> of the first burst of 8-bits. Thus the PH<b>0</b>-<b>3</b> signals can correctly store the DQ<b>0</b>-<b>7</b> bits of the second burst in a latch after the DQ<b>0</b>-<b>7</b> bits of the first burst have been stored in the latch.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Although <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref> illustrate the lack of any problems when write data are applied to the data bus terminals in serial bursts of 4 bits and multiples of 4 bits, such as 8 data bits, a problem may exist if write data are applied to the data bus terminals in serial bursts of other than 4 bits. For example, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, some memory devices may receive write data in bursts of either 8 write data bits applied to each data bus terminal or 10 write data bits applied to each data bus terminal. When 10 write data bits are applied to each data bus terminal, the first 4 bits may be captured during the first system clock period, and the second 4 bits may be captured during the second system clock period. However, 4 write data bits may also be captured during the third system clock period even though the first two of these captured bits are the last two bits of the first burst of write data bits, and the last two of these captured bits are the first two bits of the second burst of write data bits. Therefore, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the first rising edge of the PH<b>0</b> signal captures the DQ<b>0</b> bit at the start of the period when the write signal is active and stores the data bit in the DQ<b>0</b> bit location of the latch. Similarly, the third rising edge of the PH<b>1</b> signal captures the DQ<b>9</b> bit and correctly stores it in a DQ<b>9</b> bit location of the latch just before the DQ<b>0</b> bit for the next burst of write data are applied to the respective data bus terminals. As a result, the rising edge of the PH<b>2</b> signal that immediately follows the rising edge of the PH<b>1</b> signal will capture the DQ<b>0</b> bit of the next burst of data and improperly store the data in the DQ<b>2</b> bit location of the latch. This situation may present a problem since the location of the latch (not shown) that should store the DQ<b>2</b> bit will then be storing the DQ<b>0</b> bit. Additionally, the bit location of the latch that should store the DQ<b>3</b> bit will instead store the DQ<b>1</b> bit, the bit location of the latch that should store the DQ<b>4</b> bit will instead store the DQ<b>2</b> bit, and so forth.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">One example of a system <b>100</b> for solving this problem is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. The system <b>100</b> includes a sequencer <b>110</b> that receives the DQS signal and divides the DQS signal by two and generates signals PH<b>0</b>-<b>3</b> that are at four phases of the divided signal. However, the sequencer <b>110</b> also generates signals PH<b>0</b>-<b>3</b>* that are at four phases of the complement of the PH<b>0</b>-<b>3</b> signals, respectively. The sequencer <b>100</b> applies both the PH<b>0</b>-<b>3</b> and the PH<b>0</b>-<b>3</b>* signals to a selector <b>120</b>. The selector <b>120</b> under control of a controller <b>124</b> selects either the PH<b>0</b>-<b>3</b> or the PH<b>0</b>-<b>3</b>* signals, and generates write latch signals W<b>0</b>-<b>3</b> corresponding to the selected signals. In the event a burst of 10 data bits is applied to each of the eight data bus terminals, the <b>120</b> selector initially applies W<b>0</b>-<b>3</b> signals corresponding to the PH<b>0</b>-<b>3</b> signals to each of a set of eight 10-bit write latches <b>130</b><i>a</i>-<i>h</i>. After the first 10 bits have been captured from each data bus terminal DQ, the selector <b>120</b> applies W<b>0</b>-<b>3</b> signals corresponding to the PH<b>0</b>-<b>3</b>* signals to the latches <b>130</b><i>a</i>-<i>h </i>to capture the data in the next 8-bit or 10-bit burst. Thus, the first bit of the first burst is captured as the first bit location and is output as bit DIN&#x3c;0&#x3e; in each of the latches <b>130</b><i>a</i>-<i>h</i>, and the first bit of the second burst is also correctly captured as the first bit location and is output as bit DIN&#x3c;0&#x3e; in each of the latches <b>130</b><i>a</i>-<i>h</i>. If the selector <b>120</b> did not switch from using the PH<b>0</b>-<b>3</b> signals to using the PH<b>0</b>-<b>3</b>* signals to generate the W<b>0</b>-<b>3</b> signals, the first bit of the second burst would be incorrectly captured at the third bit location and it would be output as bit DIN&#x3c;2&#x3e; in each of the latches <b>130</b><i>a</i>-<i>h. </i></p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the first rising edge of the W<b>0</b> signal corresponding to PH<b>0</b> signal captures the first bit D<b>0</b> of the first burst of 10 data bits, and the third rising edge of the W<b>1</b> signal corresponding to the PH<b>1</b> signal captures the last bit D<b>9</b> of the first burst of 10 data bits. The selector <b>120</b> then selects the PH<b>0</b>-<b>3</b>* signals for use as the W<b>0</b>-<b>3</b> signals at a time designated by the line SW in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. The first rising edge of the W<b>0</b> signal corresponding to PH<b>0</b>* signal therefore captures the first bit D<b>0</b> of the second burst of 10 data bits, and the third rising edge of the W<b>1</b> signal corresponding to the PH<b>1</b>* signal captures the last bit D<b>9</b> of the second burst of 10 data bits. Thus, unlike in the example shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, since the first bit D<b>0</b> of the second burst of 10 data bits is captured by the PH<b>0</b>* signal, it is stored in the correct location in the latch for receiving the D<b>0</b> bit.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Although the principle embodied in the data capture system <b>100</b> is illustrated with each of the latches <b>130</b><i>a</i>-<i>h </i>configured to capture 10 data bits using 4 data capture signals having respective phases, it can be generalized to any data capture system in which latches are configured to capture M data bits using N data capture signals having respective phases, where M and N are each a positive integer. If M/N is an integer, then it may not be necessary for the controller <b>124</b> to generate a control signal that causes the selector <b>120</b> to switch from selecting one of the sets of periodic signals PH<b>0</b>-<b>3</b> or PH<b>0</b>-<b>3</b>* to the other of the sets of periodic signals PH<b>0</b>-<b>3</b>* or PH<b>0</b>-<b>3</b>, respectively. However, if M/N is not an integer, then it may be necessary for the selector <b>120</b> to switch from selecting one set of periodic signals to the other so that the first bit of the subsequent burst will be correctly stored in the first location in the respective latch <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The data capture system <b>100</b> or a data capture system according to some other embodiment may be used in a wide variety of applications. For example, data capture system embodiments may be used in data input buffers, such as data input buffers used in a memory device as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. The memory device may be a conventional double data rate dynamic random access memory (&#x201c;DDR DRAM&#x201d;) <b>200</b> including a command decoder <b>204</b> for controlling its operation responsive to high-level command signals received on a control bus <b>206</b>. The command decoder <b>204</b> may generate a sequence of command signals responsive to the high level command signals to carry out the function (e.g., a read or a write) designated by each of the high level command signals. The DDR DRAM may also include a clock generator <b>208</b> configured to generate a system clock signal CLK.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The DDR DRAM <b>200</b> may include an address register <b>212</b> that may receive row addresses and column addresses through an address bus <b>214</b>. The address bus <b>214</b> may be coupled to a memory controller (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>). A row address may first be received by the address register <b>212</b> and applied to a row address multiplexer <b>218</b>. The row address multiplexer <b>218</b> may couple the row address to a number of components associated with either of two memory banks <b>220</b>, <b>222</b> depending upon the state of a bank address bit forming part of the row address. A respective row address latch <b>226</b> may be associated with each of the memory banks <b>220</b>, <b>222</b> for storing the row address. A row decoder <b>228</b> may decode the row address and apply corresponding signals to one of the banks <b>220</b> or <b>222</b>. The row address multiplexer <b>218</b> may also couple row addresses to the row address latches <b>226</b> for the purpose of refreshing the memory cells in the banks <b>220</b>, <b>222</b>. The row addresses may be generated for refresh purposes by a refresh counter <b>230</b>, which may be controlled by a refresh controller <b>232</b>. The refresh controller <b>232</b> may, in turn, be controlled by the command decoder <b>204</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">After the row address has been applied to the address register <b>212</b> and stored in one of the row address latches <b>226</b>, a column address may be applied to the address register <b>212</b>. The address register <b>212</b> may couple the column address to a column address latch <b>240</b>. Depending on the operating mode of the DDR DRAM <b>200</b>, the column address may be either coupled through a burst counter <b>242</b> to a column address buffer <b>244</b>, or to the burst counter <b>242</b>, which may apply a sequence of column addresses to the column address buffer <b>244</b> starting at the column address output by the address register <b>212</b>. In either case, the column address buffer <b>244</b> may apply a column address to a column decoder <b>248</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Data to be read from one of the banks <b>220</b>, <b>222</b> may be coupled in parallel form to column circuitry <b>250</b>, <b>252</b>, which may include sense amplifiers, I/O gating, DQM &#x26;WPB mask logic, block write col/byte mask logic for one of the arrays <b>220</b>, <b>222</b>, respectively. The data bits developed by the sense amplifiers may then be coupled in parallel form to a data output buffer <b>256</b>. The data output buffer <b>256</b> may include a serializer <b>268</b> configured to convert a plurality of sets of parallel data bits to corresponding bursts of serial data bits, and to apply each burst of serial data bits to each of several data bit terminals <b>258</b>. The serializer <b>268</b> may also receive the CLK signal from the clock generator <b>208</b> for serializing the read data. Data to be written to one of the arrays <b>220</b>, <b>222</b> may be coupled from each of the data bus terminals <b>258</b> to the data input buffer <b>260</b> in serial form. The data input buffer <b>260</b> may capture the serial input data using a data capture system <b>262</b>, which may be the data capture system <b>100</b> or a data capture system according to another embodiment. The data capture system <b>262</b> also receives an externally applied DQS signal. The serial write data applied to each of the data bit terminals <b>258</b> is thus converted to a set of corresponding parallel data to be coupled to the banks <b>220</b>, <b>222</b> in parallel form.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">An embodiment of a memory system <b>300</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>. The memory system <b>300</b> includes a memory device <b>310</b>, which may be the memory device <b>200</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, a memory device according to some other embodiment or a conventional memory device. The memory device <b>310</b> may be coupled through a command bus <b>320</b>, address bus <b>330</b> and data bus <b>340</b> to a memory controller <b>350</b>. The memory controller <b>350</b> may include a command circuit <b>354</b> configured to output memory commands, and an addressing circuit <b>356</b> configured to output memory addresses. The memory controller <b>350</b> may also include an output buffer <b>360</b> configured to output write data to the data bus <b>340</b>, and a data input buffer <b>370</b> configured to receive read data from the data bus <b>340</b>. The data input buffer <b>370</b> may include a read data capture system <b>380</b> configured to capture a burst of serial read data bits at each of a plurality of terminals of the data bus <b>340</b>. The read data capture system <b>380</b>, which may also receive an externally applied DQS signal, may be the data capture system <b>100</b> or a data capture system according to another embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Although the present invention has been described with reference to the disclosed embodiments, persons skilled in the art will recognize that changes may be made in form and detail without departing from the invention. For example, the term &#x201c;bit&#x201d; is used herein to describe a single binary digit. However, in other embodiments digits other than binary digits may be used. Such modifications are well within the skill of those ordinarily skilled in the art. Accordingly, the invention is not limited except as by the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>We claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A system, comprising:
<claim-text>a sequencer configured to generate a first set of signals having respective phases relative to a clock signal and a second set of signals having different respective phases relative to the clock signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a selector configured to select either the first or second set of signals to capture write data; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a controller coupled to the selector and configured to control the selector to select one of the first or second sets of signals to capture a first burst of write data and to select the other of the first or second sets of signals to capture a second burst of write data.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second set of signals are complementary to the first set of signals.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the sequencer is configured to generate the first set of signals from a divided signal having a frequency that is one-half a frequency of the clock signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the sequencer is configured to generate the first set of signals including four signals and to generate the second set of signals having four signals.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the selector is configured to alternate between the first and second sets of signals to capture write data.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the sequencer is configured to generate the first set of signals to have respective phases evenly divided over two clock periods of the clock signal and configured to generate the second set of signals to have respective phases evenly divided over two clock periods of the clock signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the sequencer is configured to generate the first set of signals to have respective phases corresponding to transitions of the clock signal over two clock periods.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the sequencer is configured to generate the first set of signals to have N signals, and wherein the N signals are used to capture M data bits of write data and (M/N) is not an integer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the controller is configured to cause the selector to switch between the first and second sets of signals to capture the M data bits of write data when (M/N) is not an integer and further configured to not cause the selector to switch between the first and second sets of signals to capture the M data bits of write data when (M/N) is an integer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A system, comprising
<claim-text>a sequencer configured to provide a plurality of periodic signals and a corresponding plurality of complementary periodic signals;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a selector coupled to the sequencer and configured to provide latch signals based at least in part on the plurality of periodic signals or based at least in part on the plurality of complementary periodic signals; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a controller coupled to the sequencer and the selector, the controller configured to cause the selector to provide latch signals based at least in part on the plurality of periodic signals or to provide latch signals based at least in part on the plurality of complementary periodic signals.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the controller is configured to cause the selector to provide latch signals based at least in part on the plurality of periodic signals or to provide latch signals based at least in part on the plurality of complementary periodic signals based on a number of bits of write data to be captured by the latch signals.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the controller is configured to cause the selector to alternate between providing latch signals based at least in part on the plurality of periodic signals and providing latch signals based at least in part on the plurality of complementary periodic signals responsive to the number of bits of write data to be captured by the latch signals not being a multiple of number of latch signals provided by the selector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising latches configured to receive the latch signals and capture write data responsive thereto.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the sequencer is configured to provide the plurality of periodic signals having respective phases that differ equally from each other over two clock cycles of a data strobe signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein rising edges of the plurality of periodic signals correspond to transitions of the data strobe signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A method of operating a data capture circuit, comprising:
<claim-text>capturing first write data responsive to a first set of periodic signals or a second set of periodic signals, wherein the second set of periodic signals are the complement of the first set of periodic signals; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>switching to the other set of periodic signals to capture second write data.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second sets of periodic signals are based at least in part on a data strobe signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the first set of periodic signals includes signals that are at four phases over two clock cycles of the data strobe signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein switching to the other set of period signals comprises alternating between the first and second sets of periodic signals to capture sequentially provided write data.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>dividing a frequency of a data strobe signal by two to provide a divided signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating signals that are at four phases of the divided signal for the first set of periodic signals.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, wherein switching to the other set of periodic signals to capture second write data is responsive to (M/N) not being an integer, wherein M is a number of bits of the first write data and N is a number of signals in the first set of periodic signals. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
