<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624623-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624623</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13340674</doc-number>
<date>20111230</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>19</main-group>
<subgroup>003</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>19</main-group>
<subgroup>173</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>326  9</main-classification>
<further-classification>326 14</further-classification>
<further-classification>326 46</further-classification>
<further-classification>326 93</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Apparatus having error detection in sequential logic</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0223386</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Mudge et al.</name>
<date>20041100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>365202</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0315601</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Priel et al.</name>
<date>20091200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>327161</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0165767</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lin et al.</name>
<date>20100700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>365203</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>25</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>326  9- 13</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>326 46</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130169360</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130704</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gupta</last-name>
<first-name>Navneet</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ghaziabad</city>
<country>IN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>IN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Dubey</last-name>
<first-name>Prashant</first-name>
<address>
<city>Greater Noida</city>
<country>IN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>IN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Saha</last-name>
<first-name>Kaushik</first-name>
<address>
<city>Delhi</city>
<country>IN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>IN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="004" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kashyap</last-name>
<first-name>AtulKumar</first-name>
<address>
<city>Noida</city>
<country>IN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>IN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gupta</last-name>
<first-name>Navneet</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ghaziabad</city>
<country>IN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Dubey</last-name>
<first-name>Prashant</first-name>
<address>
<city>Greater Noida</city>
<country>IN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Saha</last-name>
<first-name>Kaushik</first-name>
<address>
<city>Delhi</city>
<country>IN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="004" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kashyap</last-name>
<first-name>AtulKumar</first-name>
<address>
<city>Noida</city>
<country>IN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Graybeal Jackson LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>STMicroelectronics International N.V.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Amsterdam</city>
<country>NL</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Richardson</last-name>
<first-name>Jany</first-name>
<department>2819</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">According to an embodiment, an apparatus includes: a first node configured to receive a data input signal of a data latch; a second node configured to receive a data output signal of the data latch; process and hold circuitry configured to process a difference between a value of the data input signal received at the first node and a value of the data output signal received at the second node and hold respective values at the first and second nodes responsive to the difference; and comparison circuitry configured to compare the value held at the first node and a value of the data output signal of the data latch; wherein the process and hold circuitry is configured to be biased toward the signal received at one of the first node and the second node.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="149.78mm" wi="249.17mm" file="US08624623-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="231.99mm" wi="152.48mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624623-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="224.96mm" wi="142.92mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624623-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="222.33mm" wi="160.19mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624623-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="237.07mm" wi="165.35mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624623-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="258.91mm" wi="164.68mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624623-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="216.58mm" wi="154.43mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624623-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="258.91mm" wi="162.73mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624623-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="249.94mm" wi="166.62mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624623-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">An embodiment relates to error detection. Particularly, but not exclusively, an embodiment may relate to detection of errors in sequential logic.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Sequential logic such as flip-flops or data latches may output and hold a value corresponding to a data input signal. This may be in response to an operable clock edge. In order for a value to be output correctly, a data input signal should adhere to a certain conditions, for example, set-up and hold time for the latch. The set-up time is the period of time prior to the operable clock edge that the data input signal should hold its value in order to be clocked out correctly. The hold time is the period of time after an operable clock edge the data signal input should hold its value in order to be clocked out correctly.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Sequential logic, for example, data latches, may be implemented in systems where dynamic scaling is used. In such systems, a system voltage and/or frequency may be adjusted until the system is close to failure in order to attain a performance payoff, for example power savings. In such systems, a frequency and or voltage, directly or indirectly provided to the latch, may be adjusted such that the set-up and hold times of a data input signal are as close as possible to minimum set-up and hold times of a latch.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In some systems, the sequential logic may be monitored to detect a failure. In some systems, this monitoring may be implemented as a shadow latch in conjunction with the sequential logic clocking the data through. The shadow latch may be made closer to failure than the sequential logic under similar conditions. For example, minimum set-up and hold times of the shadow latch may be longer than the minimum set-up and hold times of the sequential logic. The shadow latch may indicate that it has failed, and the system may stop scaling the voltage and or frequency to prevent the failure of the sequential logic.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In these systems, the minimum set-up and hold times of the shadow latch may be set according to a limit as to how close to failure the sequential logic may be driven. Additionally, such shadow latches consume power and take up space.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">According to an embodiment, an apparatus includes: a first node configured to receive a data input signal of a data latch; a second node configured to receive a data output signal of the data latch; process and hold circuitry configured to process a difference between a value of the data input signal received at the first node and a value of the data output signal received at the second node and hold respective values at the first and second nodes responsive to the difference; and comparison circuitry configured to compare the value held at the first node and a value of the data output signal of the data latch; wherein the process and hold circuitry is configured to be biased toward the signal received at one of the first node and the second node.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The process and hold circuitry may be configured to determine the value held at the first node in response to the value of the signal received at the biased-toward node. The value held at the first node may be determined by the value of the signal received at the biased-toward node when the value of the data input signal received at the first node and the value of the data output signal received at the second node correspond to one another.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The process and hold circuitry may include: a first inverter having an input coupled to the first node and an output coupled to the second node; and a second inverter having an input coupled to the second node and an output coupled to the first node; wherein one of the first and second inverter is stronger than the other one of the second and first inverter. The process and hold circuitry may be biased towards the signal received at the node corresponding to the input of the stronger inverter.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The comparison circuit may be further configured to generate an error signal based on the comparison. The process and hold circuit may be configured to operate in response to a clock signal. The process and hold circuit may be configured to operate in response to an operable clock edge.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The first and second nodes may follow the data input and output signals respectively for a first part of a clock cycle, and may be held at their respective values by the process and hold circuitry for a second part of the clock cycle. The comparison circuitry may be configured to carry out the comparison in the second part of the clock cycle.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The apparatus may be a shadow latch. The data input signal may be a differential data input signal.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to an embodiment, a method includes: receiving a data input signal of a data latch at a first node; receiving a data output signal of the data latch at a second node; processing a difference between a value of the data input signal at the first node and a value of the data output signal at the second node and holding respective values at the first and second nodes responsive to the difference with process and hold circuitry; and comparing the value held at the first node and a value of the data output signal of the data latch; wherein the process and hold circuitry is biased toward the signal received at one of the first node and the second node.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The method may further include: determining the value held at the first node responsive to the value of the biased-toward signal. The method may include: determining the value held at the first node responsive to the value of the signal received at the biased-toward node when the value of the data input signal received at the first node and the value of the data output signal received at the second node correspond to one another.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The method may include: holding a value at the second node corresponding to an inverted value of the first node; and holding a value at the first node corresponding to an inverted value of the second node.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The method may further include when the data input signal received at the first node and the data output signal received at the second node correspond to one another: holding the value of the biased toward signal at the one of the first node and second node corresponding to the biased toward signal; and holding a value opposite to the value of the biased toward signal at the other one of the second node and first node.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The method may further include: generating an error signal based on the comparison. The method may further include: processing the difference between the value of the data input signal at the first node and the value of the data output signal at the second node and holding the respective first and second nodes at a value responsive to the difference in response to a clock signal. The method may further include: processing the difference between the value of the data input signal at the first node and the value of the data output signal at the second node and holding the respective first and second node at a value responsive to the difference in response to an operable clock edge.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The method may further include: following the data input and output signals at the first and second nodes respectively for a first part of a clock cycle; and holding the respective values at the first and second nodes for a second part of the clock cycle. The method may further include: carrying out the comparison in the second part of the clock cycle.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">According to an embodiment, an apparatus includes: a first latch configured to clock a value of a data input signal out to provide a value on a data output signal; and a second latch coupled to the first latch, the second latch including: a first node for receiving the data input signal; a second node for receiving the data output signal; process and hold circuitry configured to process a difference between a value of the data input signal received at the first node and a value of the data output signal received at the second node and hold respective values at the first and second nodes responsive to the difference; and comparison circuitry configured to compare a value held at the first node and a value of the data output signal; wherein the process and hold circuitry is configured to be biased toward the signal received at one of the first node and the second node.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">According to an embodiment, an apparatus includes: first input means for receiving a data input signal of a data latch; second input means for receiving a data output signal of the data latch; process and hold means for processing a difference between a value of the data input signal received at the first node and a value of the data output signal received at the second node and holding respective values at the first and second nodes responsive to the difference; and comparison means for comparing a value held at the first node and a value of the data output signal of the data latch; wherein the process and hold means is biased toward the signal received at one of the first node and the second node.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">One or more embodiments will now be described in a non-limiting manner with reference to the following drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram of a system according to an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a more-detailed diagram of the system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> according to an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram of a system including circuitry of a shadow latch according to an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref><i>a </i>is a diagram of a system including circuitry of an error detection circuit according to an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref><i>b </i>is a diagram of a system including circuitry of an error detection circuit according to another embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref><i>c </i>is a diagram of a system including circuitry of an error detection circuit according to yet another embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a </i>is a signal diagram for when a data signal transitions from 0 to 1 corresponding to an embodiment; and</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>b </i>is a signal diagram for when a data signal transitions from 1 to 0 corresponding to an embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Described are one or more embodiments of a shadow latch that may be implemented in conjunction with sequential logic and may detect when an error has occurred. An embodiment may use this detection to correct the error. In an embodiment the sequential logic may be a data latch.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In an embodiment, the shadow latch may be configured to compare a value that a data output signal of the sequential logic should have if there has been no error to a value of the data output signal.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The shadow latch may compare a value held at a first node and a value of a data output signal of the sequential logic to determine if an error has occurred. The value held at the first node may correspond to a value of a data input signal of the sequential logic at an operation of the sequential logic. The operation may be clocking out a value of the data input signal to the data output signal. In an embodiment, the operation may be carried out in response to a clock edge.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In an embodiment, a first node of the shadow latch may receive a data input signal Din and hold a value corresponding to the value of the data input signal Din at a time of operation of the sequential logic.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In an embodiment, the held value may be determined by processing and holding a difference between a value at the first node and a value at a second node of the shadow latch. The second node may receive a data output signal Dout of the sequential logic. The value of the data output signal Dout may correspond to a value of the data input signal Din at a preceding operation of the sequential logic.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The shadow latch may be biased towards an input at the first node or be biased towards an input at the second node. For example, when the first and the second inputs are the same, the shadow latch may hold a value of the first node in accordance with the first input or in accordance with the second input depending on the biasing.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In some embodiments, the first node and the second node may follow the data input signal and the data output signal during a first part of a clock cycle, and a value may be held at the first node during a second part of the clock cycle. In an embodiment, the first part of the clock cycle may be before an operation of the sequential logic and the second part of the clock cycle may be after the operation of the sequential logic.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">It is appreciated that the shadow latch may be implemented in a variety of manners. Example implementations of the shadow latch and circuitry in accordance with one or more embodiments are described below with reference to the accompanying figures.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram of an example system in which an embodiment may be implemented.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a data latch <b>101</b>, which receives a data input signal Din and outputs a data output signal Dout. The signal Dout corresponds to a value of the data input signal Din output on an operable edge of a clock signal (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). It is appreciated that the operable edge may be a rising edge and/or a falling edge of the clock signal. The data latch <b>101</b> may be any form of suitable sequential logic and, in an embodiment, forms part of a sequential logic path for propagating data. In an embodiment, the data latch <b>101</b> may form part of a critical path.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> also shows a shadow latch <b>102</b>. The shadow latch <b>102</b> may be coupled to the data input signal Din and may be coupled to the data output signal Dout. The shadow latch <b>102</b> may provide an output to an error detection or comparison circuit <b>103</b>. The error detection circuit <b>103</b> may receive a further input from the data output signal Dout from the data latch <b>101</b>. The error detection circuit <b>103</b> may provide an error output.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In operation, the data latch <b>101</b> may receive the data input signal Din. The data flip-flop may clock out a data value D of the data input signal Din at an operable clock edge to provide the data output signal Dout. The data output signal Dout may hold a value Q&#x2212;1 corresponding to the data value D&#x2212;1 of the data input signal Din at a previous operable clock edge. The data value may be clocked out correctly to provide a value on the data output signal Dout, in which case the value of the data output signal will correspond to the data value on the data input signal at the operable clock edge, or the data value may be clocked out erroneously, in which case the value of the data output signal Dout may not correspond to the data value of the data input signal D at the operable clock edge.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The shadow latch <b>102</b> may also receive the data input signal Din at a first node. In an embodiment, the first node of the shadow latch <b>102</b> may follow a data value D of the data input signal Din during a first part of a clock cycle. The shadow latch <b>102</b> may also provide the data output signal Dout at a second node. The second node may follow a data value (Q&#x2212;1) of the data output signal Dout for the first part of the clock cycle.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">It is appreciated that in an embodiment, the first part of the clock cycle may be before an operable clock edge, and the value (Q&#x2212;1) of the data output signal Dout may correspond to a value D&#x2212;1 of the data input signal Din at a preceding operable clock edge.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In an embodiment, the shadow latch <b>102</b> may amplify and hold a difference between a value D of the data signal Din received at the first node and a value (Q&#x2212;1) of the data input signal Dout received at a second node. This may take place in a second part of a clock cycle. The data input signal Din and data output signal Dout may provide initial values at the first and second nodes. The amplify and hold circuit may amplify a difference between these initial values and hold the first and second nodes at values corresponding to the amplified difference.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In an embodiments, the value D of the data signal Din and the value (Q&#x2212;1)) of the data output signal Dout may be passed to the amplify and hold circuitry of the shadow latch <b>102</b> at the second part of the clock cycle. In an embodiment, the values may be passed to the shadow latch <b>102</b> at an operable clock edge. In an embodiment, because the shadow latch <b>102</b> amplifies and holds a difference between the initial value of the first node and initial value of the second node, the shadow latch may be less likely to fail than the data latch.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">For example, in an embodiment, if the data signal D transitions very closely to the operable clock edge, and the initial value passed to the shadow latch is only half way through the transition, then the shadow latch amplifies the difference and may provide an output equivalent to the fully transitioned data signal. The shadow latch <b>102</b> may be faster than the data latch <b>101</b>. In an embodiment, this may be due to the amplify and hold circuitry of the shadow latch <b>102</b>. In an embodiment, the minimum set-up and hold margins of the shadow latch <b>102</b> may be less than the set-up and hold margins of the data latch <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The shadow latch <b>102</b> may be imbalanced. In an embodiment, the shadow latch <b>102</b> may be biased towards either the input at the first node or the input at the second node. For example, when the inputs at the first and second nodes are the same, the shadow latch may hold a value at the first node determined by the input biased towards. For example, if the shadow latch is biased towards the input at the first node, then the shadow latch may hold the first node at a value corresponding to the input value. If the shadow latch is biased towards the input at the second node, then the shadow latch may hold a value at the second node corresponding to the input at the second node and hold a value at the first node at a value determined by the input at the second node.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The imbalance of the shadow latch may be considered to have the biased toward node as stronger than the other node. For example, in a case where the value D of the data input signal Din and the value (Q&#x2212;1) of the data output signal Dout corresponding to the previously clocked out value (D&#x2212;1) of the data input signal Din are the same, then the initial values at the first and second node are the same. The shadow latch may be imbalanced such that in this case, one node will be the stronger input and force the other node to an opposite value. For example if both nodes are initially a high, the stronger node may flip the weaker node to a low. It will be appreciated that either node may be set as the stronger node.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">For example, in a case where the value (Q&#x2212;1) of the data output signal Dout and the value D of the data input signal Din correspond, i.e., equal, one another, the shadow latch may invert the second node. This may occur, for example, where the value of the data input signal Din remains the same over two or more clock cycles and the first node is the stronger input.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">It is appreciated that in an embodiment, the shadow latch and/or data latch may be a differential latch. For example, the data latch may receive a differential data input signal and clock out a differential data output signal. In an embodiment, the shadow latch may receive the differential data input signal(s) at first nodes and the differential data output signal(s) at second nodes. The shadow latch may be imbalanced, for example, such that it is biased towards the input at the first nodes or the input at the second nodes.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">It is appreciated that the shadow latch may be biased through various means. For example, the circuitry of the shadow latch may be made imbalanced&#x2014;for example, transistors of the shadow latch may be different sizes. Alternatively or additionally, capacitance may be introduced into the shadow latch and/or a charge may be injected into the shadow latch during a process and hold operation to bias toward one input.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The shadow latch <b>102</b> may provide an output to an error detection or comparison circuit <b>103</b>. The output may be coupled to the first node. The shadow latch may provide a value of the first node held by the shadow latch <b>102</b>, for example, a value corresponding to a value D of the data input signal Din at the operable clock edge. The error detection circuit <b>103</b> may compare the output of the shadow latch <b>102</b> with the data output signal Dout output from the data latch <b>101</b>. It is appreciated that the value (Q&#x2212;1) of the data output signal Dout may change to a value Q at the clock edge as the value D of the data input signal Din is clocked through the data latch <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">As the shadow latch <b>102</b> may be less likely to fail than the data latch <b>101</b>, the output from the shadow latch <b>102</b> may represent a correct value D of the data output signal Dout (in other words the value that the data output signal should have if the data has been clocked out without error), and the data output signal Dout from the data latch <b>101</b> may provide an actual value Q clocked out by the data latch <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The error detection circuit <b>103</b> may compare the output of the shadow latch <b>102</b> to the data output signal Dout and determine whether or not an error has occurred. An error signal may be generated in response to this determination. In an embodiment, the error signal may be provided to further circuitry for correcting the error and/or the error signal may be used to record information about the behavior of the circuit. In an embodiment, the error signal may be used in the control of dynamic scaling of the circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">It is appreciated that the data latch <b>101</b> and the shadow latch <b>102</b> may receive a common clock signal and be clocked on a common clock edge. It is also appreciated that an embodiment may be implemented in systems with frequency and voltage scaling. In other words, an embodiment may be used in systems in which a frequency and/or voltage of the system is adjusted until the system is close to failure.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">It is appreciated that the shadow latch <b>102</b> may be implemented as an imbalanced differential amplifier. Furthermore, it is appreciated that the error detection circuit <b>103</b> may be implemented in a variety of ways. Various embodiments and implementations of the shadow latch <b>102</b> and error detection circuitry <b>103</b> are described below.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a diagram of an embodiment of an implementation of the circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a data latch <b>101</b>, a shadow latch <b>102</b>, and an error detection circuit <b>103</b>. It is appreciated that the data latch <b>101</b>, shadow latch <b>102</b>, and error detection circuit <b>103</b> may correspond to those in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The data latch <b>101</b> receives a clock signal. In an embodiment, the shadow latch <b>102</b>, error detection circuit <b>103</b>, and data latch <b>101</b> may operate in accordance with a common clock signal.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The shadow latch <b>102</b> may include a first switch <b>201</b> with a first connection coupled to the data input signal Din. A second connection of the first switch <b>201</b> may be coupled to a first node X<b>1</b>. The first node X<b>1</b> may be coupled to a first connection of a second switch <b>202</b> as well as to a first input of the error detection circuit <b>103</b>. A second connection of the second switch <b>202</b> may be coupled to amplify and hold circuitry <b>205</b>. In an embodiment, the amplify and hold circuitry <b>205</b> may be an imbalanced differential amplifier.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The amplify and hold circuitry <b>205</b> may be coupled to a first connection of a third switch <b>204</b>. A second connection of the third switch <b>204</b> may be coupled to a second node Y<b>1</b>. The second node Y<b>1</b> may be further coupled to a first connection of a fourth switch <b>203</b>. A second connection of the fourth switch <b>203</b> may be coupled to the data output signal Dout of the data latch <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The data output signal Dout of the data latch <b>101</b> may form a second input to the error detection circuit <b>103</b>. The error detection circuit <b>103</b> may provide an output fail signal. It is appreciated that the output fail signal may be any suitable indication, for example, an indication, alert, signal, and/or setting of a flag.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In operation, the first and second switches <b>201</b> and <b>202</b> may be controlled so that the first node X<b>1</b> is coupled to the data input signal Din and uncoupled from the amplify and hold circuitry <b>205</b> during a first part of a clock cycle. This may be, for example. for at least part of a period when the clock signal is low. The first node X<b>1</b> may further be coupled to the amplify and hold circuitry <b>205</b> and uncoupled from the data input signal Din by the first and second switches <b>201</b> and <b>202</b> during a second part of a clock cycle. This may be, for example, for at least part of when the clock signal is high.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Similarly, the third and fourth switches <b>204</b> and <b>203</b> may be controlled so that the second node Y<b>1</b> may be coupled to the data output signal Dout and uncoupled from the amplify and hold circuitry <b>205</b> during the first part of the clock cycle, and uncoupled from the data output signal Dout and coupled to the amplify and hold circuitry <b>205</b> during the second part of the clock cycle.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The first <b>201</b>, second <b>202</b>, third <b>204</b>, and fourth <b>203</b> switches may operate in accordance with the below table.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00001" num="00001">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="98pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="98pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="3" rowsep="1">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>CLK</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>S1</entry>
<entry>ON </entry>
<entry>OFF</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>S2</entry>
<entry>OFF</entry>
<entry>ON</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>S3</entry>
<entry>OFF</entry>
<entry>ON</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>S4</entry>
<entry>ON</entry>
<entry>OFF</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The above example of the operation of the first <b>201</b>, second <b>202</b>, third <b>204</b> and fourth <b>203</b> switches is according to a rising edge of the clock signal being the operable clock edge. It is appreciated that for an operable falling edge of the clock or operable dual clock edge, the switch operation may be modified accordingly.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Additionally, the switches may be respectively on and off for only at least part of the first and second parts of the clock cycle, for example, for only a part of the time for which the clock signal is high and/or low.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The circuitry of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> may operate in accordance with an embodiment, for example, when the data input signal Din transitions from low to high. In this case, the data input signal Din will go high before an operable rising clock edge. In order for the data latch <b>101</b> to clock a data value D on the data input signal Din out correctly, the presence of the data value D must adhere to a set-up margin of the data latch. On the operable rising edge of the clock signal, the high value D of the data input signal Din may be clocked out to provide the data output signal Dout of the data latch <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">Before the rising edge of the clock, the clock signal is low and the first switch <b>201</b> couples the data value D on the data input signal Din to the first node X<b>1</b>. The first node may follow the value D on the data input signal Din while the clock signal is low. When the data input signal Din goes high, the first node X<b>1</b> goes high. On the rising edge of the clock the first switch <b>201</b> turns off and the second switch <b>202</b> turns on. This couples the first node X<b>1</b> to the amplify and hold circuitry <b>205</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">It is appreciated that the first switch <b>201</b> and the second switch <b>202</b> may not operate instantaneously, and on the operable rising edge of the clock, the value of the data input signal Din at the rising edge will be coupled to the input of the amplify and hold circuitry <b>205</b>. On the operable clock edge, the amplify and hold circuitry <b>205</b> may receive an initial value D on the first node X<b>1</b> that corresponds to the data value D on the data input signal Din at the rising edge of the clock.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">Similarly, when the clock signal is low, the fourth switch <b>203</b> may couple the second node Y<b>1</b> to the data output signal Dout of the data latch <b>101</b>. It is appreciated that a value (Q&#x2212;1) of the data output signal Dout may correspond to a data value (D&#x2212;1) of the data input signal Din clocked out by the data latch <b>101</b> at the preceding rising edge of the clock. The second node Y<b>1</b> may follow the data value (D&#x2212;1) clocked out of the data latch <b>101</b> at the preceding rising edge of the clock.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">At the rising edge of the clock, the fourth switch <b>203</b> turns off and the third switch <b>204</b> turns on, thus coupling the second node Y<b>1</b> to the amplify and hold circuitry <b>205</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">It is appreciated that the data latch <b>101</b> may not instantaneously clock out the new value D of the data input signal Din at an operable clock edge, and the value (Q&#x2212;1) of the second node corresponding to a value (D&#x2212;1) of the data input signal Din clocked out by the data latch <b>101</b> at the preceding operable clock edge is initially received by the amplify and hold circuitry <b>205</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">After the rising edge of the clock, the first node X<b>1</b> and the second node Y<b>1</b> may be uncoupled from the data input signal Din and the data output signal Dout, and, therefore, and will no longer follow them.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">The amplify and hold circuitry <b>205</b> may take the initial value of the first node X<b>1</b> and the initial value of the second node Y<b>1</b> and amplify and hold a difference between the values at the first node X<b>1</b> and second node Y<b>1</b>. For example, in an embodiment where the data signal transitions from a low to a high, the value at the rising edge of the clock at the first node X<b>1</b> will initially be high while the data value at the second node Y<b>1</b> will initially be low. The amplify and hold circuitry <b>205</b> may amplify and hold this difference and hold the first node X<b>1</b> high and the second node Y<b>1</b> low.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The value held at the first node X<b>1</b> may be input into the error detection circuit <b>103</b> and compared to the data output signal Dout. If the data latch <b>101</b> has erroneously clocked out the value of the data input signal D, then the value Q of the data signal output will not correspond to the value of the first node X<b>1</b>. A fail signal may be set to indicate a detected error. But if the data latch <b>101</b> has correctly clocked out the value D of the data input signal Din, then the value Q of the data signal output Dout will correspond to the value of the first node X<b>1</b>, and the fail signal may indicate that no error has occurred.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">It is appreciated that the fail signal may be the setting of a flag or interrupt. Furthermore in an embodiment, the fail signal may be set to indicate only an error or that no error has occurred.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">The amplify and hold circuitry <b>205</b> may be imbalanced. For example, the first node X<b>1</b> may provide a stronger input. For example, in the case when the data signal remains high for two clock cycles, at a second rising edge the value at the first node X<b>1</b> will be high and the value at the second node Y<b>1</b> will be high. The high value at the first node X<b>1</b> may provide a stronger input and force the value of the second node Y<b>1</b> low.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">It is appreciated that the circuit behaves similarly in the case where the data signal transitions from a high to low.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram of an example of circuitry for the shadow latch <b>102</b>. It is appreciated that the data input signal Din, the clock signal CLK, the data latch <b>101</b>, the data output signal Dout, the nodes X<b>1</b>, Y<b>1</b>, error detection circuit <b>103</b>, and fail signal may be similar to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">The shadow latch <b>102</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> may include a first switch <b>301</b> that receives the clock signal as a control input. The first switch <b>301</b> may be coupled between the data input signal Din and the first node X<b>1</b>. The shadow latch <b>102</b> may further include a second switch <b>302</b>, which receives the clock signal as a control input and is coupled between the data output signal Dout and the second node Y<b>1</b>. It is appreciated that switches <b>301</b> and <b>302</b> may correspond to the first switch <b>201</b> and the fourth switch <b>203</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">The shadow latch <b>102</b> may further include a first p-channel transistor <b>303</b> with a source terminal coupled to a voltage source, a drain terminal coupled to a differential amplifier <b>205</b>, and a gate terminal coupled to an inverted clock signal. The shadow latch <b>102</b> may further include a first n-channel transistor <b>308</b> with a source terminal coupled to a ground, a drain terminal coupled to the differential amplifier <b>205</b>, and a gate terminal coupled to the clock signal.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">It is appreciated that the transistors <b>303</b> and <b>308</b> may correspond to the second <b>202</b> and third <b>204</b> switches of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. In other words, the transistors <b>303</b> and <b>308</b> may enable and/or disable the differential amplifier <b>205</b> based on the clock signal.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">It is also further appreciated that in an embodiment, the clock signal may be replaced by a clock pulse.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">The imbalanced differential amplifier <b>205</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> may include a second p-channel transistor <b>304</b>, a second n-channel transistor <b>305</b>, a third p-channel transistor <b>306</b>, and a third n-channel transistor <b>307</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">The drain terminal of the first p-channel transistor <b>303</b> may be coupled to a source terminal of the second p-channel transistor <b>304</b> and a source terminal of the third p-channel transistor <b>306</b>. The drain terminal of the first n-channel transistor <b>308</b> may be coupled to a source terminal of the second n-channel transistor <b>305</b> and a source terminal of the third n-channel transistor <b>307</b>. A gate terminal of the second p-channel transistor <b>304</b> may be coupled to a gate terminal of the second n-channel transistor <b>305</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">A drain terminal of the second p-channel transistor <b>304</b> may be coupled to a drain terminal of the second n-channel transistor <b>305</b>, and may be coupled to the first node X<b>1</b> and to respective gate terminals of the third p-channel transistor <b>306</b> and the third n-channel transistor <b>307</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">A drain terminal of the third p-channel transistor <b>306</b> may be coupled to a drain terminal of the third n-channel transistor <b>307</b>, which may be coupled to the second node Y<b>1</b> and to respective gate terminals of the second p-channel transistor <b>304</b> and the second n-channel transistor <b>305</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">The operation of the shadow latch of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> will be described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5</figref><i>a </i>and <b>5</b><i>b</i>. It is appreciated that in an embodiment, the operation of the circuitry of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> may be in line with the operation of the circuitry of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5</figref><i>a </i>and <b>5</b><i>b </i>are timing diagrams of the signals of the circuitry of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> according to an embodiment. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a </i>shows the signals corresponding to the data input signal Din transitioning from 0 to 1 on an operable clock edge, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>b </i>shows the signals corresponding to the data signal transitioning from 1 to 0 on an operable clock edge.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a </i>shows the clock signal CLK, the data input signal Din, the data output signal Dout, the signal at the first node Y<b>1</b>, the signal at the second node X<b>1</b>, and the fail signal FAIL. In an embodiment per <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a</i>, the rising edge of the clock is considered the operable clock edge; however, it is appreciated that this is by way of example only.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">When the clock signal CLK is low, the switches <b>301</b> and <b>302</b> are closed and the first node X<b>1</b> is coupled to the data input signal Din and the second node Y<b>1</b> is coupled to the data output signal Dout.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">When the clock signal CLK is low, the first node X<b>1</b> follows the data input signal Din, and the second node Y<b>1</b> follows the data output signal Dout. The inverted low clock signal is input to the gate terminal of the first p-channel transistor <b>303</b>, and the low clock signal is input to the gate terminal of the first n-channel transistor <b>308</b>. The first p-channel <b>303</b> and first n-channel <b>308</b> transistors are off, and the differential amplifier <b>205</b> is disabled.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a</i>, the data input signal Din is shown to transition from 0 to 1 on the rising edge of the clock signal CLK. In this example, the data transition of the data signal D may be too close to the rising clock edge to satisfy the set-up time of the data latch <b>101</b>, and the data latch <b>101</b> may clock out the data input signal Din in error.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a</i>, when the clock signal CLK transitions from 0 to 1, the data latch <b>101</b> clocks out the value D of the data input signal Din erroneously as a low, and a value Q of the data output signal Dout is low for that clock cycle. For example at 0.5 &#x3bc;s, the clock signal CLK transitions from low to high and the data latch <b>101</b> clocks out the value D of the data signal at 0.5 &#x3bc;s erroneously.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">At the rising edge of the clock CLK, the switches <b>301</b> and <b>302</b> turn off and uncouple the first X<b>1</b> and second Y<b>1</b> nodes from the data input signal Din and the data output signal Dout, respectively. The inverted clock signal goes low at the gate of the first p-channel transistor <b>303</b>, and the first p-channel transistor <b>303</b> turns on. Similarly the clock signal at the gate of the first n-channel transistor <b>308</b> goes high, and the first n-channel transistor <b>308</b> turns on.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">The sources of the second p-channel transistor <b>304</b> and the third p-channel transistor <b>306</b> are pulled high, while the sources of the second and third n-channel transistors <b>305</b> and <b>307</b> are pulled low. During the time period for the switches <b>301</b> and <b>302</b> to turn off and while the first p-channel transistor <b>303</b> and the first n-channel transistor <b>308</b> are on, the value of the first node X<b>1</b> corresponds to the value D of the data signal Din and the value of the second node Y<b>1</b> corresponds to the value (Q&#x2212;1)_of the data output signal Dout. It is appreciated that the value (Q&#x2212;1) of the second node Y<b>1</b> corresponds to the value (D&#x2212;1) of the data input signal Din clocked through the data latch <b>101</b> at the preceding operable clock edge.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a</i>, the value at the first node X<b>1</b> is high while the value at the second node Y<b>1</b> is low. The high value of the first node X<b>1</b> is input to the gates of the third p-channel transistor <b>306</b> and the third n-channel transistor <b>307</b>, which turns the third p-channel transistor <b>307</b> off while turning the third n-channel transistor <b>307</b> on. The low value at the second node Y<b>1</b> pulls the gate of the second p-channel transistor <b>304</b> and the gate of the second n-channel transistor <b>305</b> low, which turns the second n-channel transistor <b>305</b> off and the second p-channel transistor <b>304</b> on. The second p-channel transistor <b>304</b> pulls the first node X<b>1</b> high while the third n-channel transistor <b>307</b> pulls the second node Y<b>1</b> low.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">In this manner, the difference between the initial values of X<b>1</b> and Y<b>1</b> at the operable clock edge is amplified and held.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">For example, because the data input signal Din transitions so close to the clock edge, the value at node X<b>1</b> may be half-way through the transition and may be for example half of the high value. The differential amplifier <b>205</b> will amplify the difference between the half-high value of X<b>1</b> and the low value of Y<b>1</b> pulling the first node X<b>1</b> high and the second node Y<b>1</b> low.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">The value of the first node X<b>1</b> is passed to the error detection circuit <b>103</b> along with the erroneously clocked out value Q of the data output signal Dout. The error detection circuit <b>103</b> may compare the value of the first node X<b>1</b> and the value Q of the data signal output Dout and determine that an error has occurred. The fail signal FAIL may go high to indicate that an error has been detected.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">Similarly, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>b </i>is a signal timing diagram of the clock signal CLK, the data input signal Din, the data output signal Dout, the signal at the second node Y<b>1</b>, the signal at the first node X<b>1</b>, and the fail signal FAIL for the case where the data input signal D transitions from a 1 to a 0 on an operable clock edge. Similarly to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a</i>, the proximity of the data input signal Din transition to the operable clock edge results in a higher likelihood of the data latch <b>101</b> clocking out the value D of the data input signal Din incorrectly.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">The switches <b>301</b> and <b>302</b>, the first p-channel transistor <b>303</b>, and the first n-channel transistor <b>308</b> may operate according to the clock signal similarly to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a</i>. On an operable clock edge, the value at the first node X<b>1</b> is a 0 while the value at the second node Y<b>1</b> corresponding to the value (D&#x2212;1) of the data input signal Din clocked out at a preceding clock edge may be 1.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">The low value at the first node X<b>1</b> pulls the gates of the third p-channel transistor <b>306</b> and the third n-channel transistor <b>307</b> low, turning the third n-channel transistor <b>307</b> off and the third p-channel transistor <b>306</b> on. The high value at the second node Y<b>1</b> pulls the gate of the second p-channel transistor <b>304</b> and the second n-channel transistor <b>305</b> high, turning the second n-channel transistor <b>305</b> on and the second p-channel transistor <b>304</b> off. The on second n-channel transistor <b>305</b> pulls the first node X<b>1</b> to ground while the on third p-channel transistor <b>306</b> pulls the second node Y<b>1</b> to a high value. The difference between the values at the nodes X<b>1</b> and Y<b>1</b> is amplified and held by the differential amplifier <b>205</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">A case may occur where the data value D of the data input signal Din does not transition before a clock edge. For example the value of the data input signal Din may remain as a high value for two clock cycles. In this case, at an operable clock edge around which there are no transitions, the first node X<b>1</b> will be high corresponding to the value D of the data input signal Din. The value (Q&#x2212;1) of the data output signal Dout corresponding to the value (D&#x2212;1) of the data input signal Din clocked through the data latch at the preceding operable clock edge may also be high, such that the value at the second node Y<b>1</b> may also be high.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">The high value at the first node X<b>1</b> may attempt to pull the gates of the third p-channel transistor <b>306</b> and the third n-channel transistor <b>307</b> high while the high value at the second node Y<b>1</b> may try to pull the gates of the second p-channel transistor <b>304</b> and the second n-channel transistor <b>308</b> high.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">In an embodiment, the differential amplifier <b>205</b> may be provided as an imbalanced circuit with an input from either the first or second node being the stronger input. In an embodiment, the differential amplifier <b>205</b> may be imbalanced to set a default input. For example, the differential amplifier or amplify and hold circuitry may include a first inverter configured to invert a value held at the first node to provide a value at the second node, and a second inverter configured to invert a value of the second node to provide a value at the first node. When the initial values at the first and second nodes are different, the inverters may amplify and hold the difference. However, when the initial values are the same, the amplify and hold circuit may be imbalanced with one of the inverters being a stronger inverter associated with one of the nodes, and the stronger inverter flips the other node to an opposite value.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">For example, the differential amplifier <b>205</b> may be provided as an imbalanced differential amplifier, with the value of the first node X<b>1</b> being the stronger input. In this case, the first node X<b>1</b> pulls the gates of the third p-channel transistor <b>306</b> and the third n-channel transistor <b>307</b> high, turning the third n-channel transistor <b>307</b> on and the third p-channel transistor <b>306</b> off.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">The third n-channel transistor <b>307</b> pulls the second node Y<b>1</b> low, which pulls the gates of the second p-channel transistor <b>304</b> and the second n-channel transistor <b>305</b> low, thus turning the second p-channel transistor <b>304</b> on and pulling the value of the first node X<b>1</b> high. Although the initially high value at the second node Y<b>1</b> may attempt to pull the gates of the second p-channel <b>304</b> and second n-channel <b>305</b> transistors high, this is overridden by the value at the first node X<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">Similarly, if the data input signal Din is low for two clock cycles, then the first node X<b>1</b> is kept low while the second node Y<b>1</b> becomes high.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111">In an embodiment, a clock pulse may also be generated. The clock pulse may cause the comparison of the first node output and the data output signal to occur when the first and second nodes are uncoupled from the data input and output signals, and/or allow a settling time for the first node output.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">In an embodiment, the clock pulse may enable the operation of error detection to ensure that error detection only occurs for a period after an operable clock edge. This may be to ensure that an error is not detected when the first node is following the data input. In an embodiment, the clock pulse may be generated to allow a stabilizing time for the first node X<b>1</b>. For example, X<b>1</b> may settle into a high or low value, and error detection may occur once the value of the node has settled.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">In an embodiment, such a clock pulse may be input at the gates of the first p-channel <b>303</b> and n-channel transistors <b>308</b>, and be used to enable the differential amplifier. In an embodiment, the clock pulse may correspond to an operable edge of a clock signal, and may be active for a period thereafter. In an embodiment, the clock pulse may be generated for varying lengths of time, and may be generated according to a hold margin of the data latch.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">It is appreciated that the duration of the pulse may differ in embodiments. For example, the pulse may be high for only part of the period for which the clock is high.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">Examples of the use of the clock signal, clock pulse, and implementation of the error detection circuitry are discussed below.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref><i>a </i>is a diagram that includes an embodiment of the detection circuit <b>103</b>. It is appreciated that the circuitry of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref><i>a </i>is similar to the circuitry of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> except that the gate terminal of the p-channel transistor <b>303</b> receives an inverted pulse signal, and the gate terminal of the first n-channel transistor <b>308</b> receives a pulse signal at its gate. The circuitry may further include a pulse generator <b>401</b>, which receives the clock signal as its input and generates the pulse signal <b>403</b> at its output.</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0117">The pulse generator <b>401</b> may generate a pulse <b>403</b> from the clock signal. In an embodiment, the pulse signal is generated for a period in response to an operable clock edge. For example, the start of the pulse signal may be triggered by an operable clock edge, and the pulse may be held for a predetermined period. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref><i>a</i>, the differential amplifier <b>205</b> may be enabled, and the difference between the first node X<b>1</b> and the second node Y<b>1</b> amplified and held for the duration of the pulse. It is appreciated that in an embodiment, the pulse may be asserted for a period corresponding to at least part of the period for which the clock signal is high.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0118">The operation of the circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref><i>a </i>is similar to that as described by <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5</figref><i>a </i>and <b>5</b><i>b</i>, except that the differential amplifier is enabled for the duration of the pulse instead of for the duration of the clock signal being high. In an embodiment, the differential amplifier may only be enabled for part of the period for which the clock signal is high. It is appreciated that in another embodiment, the falling edge of the clock may be the operable clock edge, and a pulse may be generated corresponding thereto. The pulse may correspond to a period associated with an operable clock edge.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0119">The period for which the clock pulse is asserted may be predetermined. In an embodiment, the period may correspond to the period for which the clock signal is high or low (depending on the operable clock edge). Alternatively the period may be only part thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0120">It is appreciated that the duration of the pulse may be set in accordance with the requirements of specific implementations of the circuit, for example, characteristics of circuit components, timing margins required and/or settling times required for the circuitry.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0121">Similar to the circuitry of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the first node X<b>1</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref><i>a </i>may provide a value corresponding to a value D of the data input signal Din at an operable clock edge for the duration of the pulse. In an embodiment per <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref><i>a</i>, the error detection circuit <b>103</b> includes an XOR gate <b>402</b>, which receives a first input from the first node X<b>1</b> and a second input from the data output signal Dout of the data latch <b>101</b>. The XOR gate <b>402</b> compares the first and second input and generates the fail signal corresponding to a difference between the inputs.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0122">In an embodiment, a fail signal may only be captured during the duration of the pulse, or at a predetermined time after an operable clock edge, to allow settling of the signals from the amplify and hold circuit <b>205</b> and data latch <b>101</b>. This may prevent capture of the fail signal when the first node X<b>1</b> is following the data input signal Din. Additionally or alternatively, in an embodiment, the detection circuit <b>103</b> may only be enabled and/or active during a period for which the fail signal is valid. It is appreciated that the capturing of the fail signal may be dependent on a specific implementation of the circuitry in an embodiment. For example, the fail signal may be captured at predetermined times corresponding to when the comparison is made between the data input to a data latch <b>101</b> at a clock edge and the data subsequently output from the data latch <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0123"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref><i>b </i>is a diagram that includes another embodiment of the error detection circuit <b>103</b>. In this embodiment, a shadow latch <b>102</b> is similar to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, and the first p-channel transistor <b>303</b> and first n-channel transistor <b>308</b> may receive an inverted clock signal and clock signal at their respective gates. A clock pulse generator <b>401</b> may generate a clock pulse <b>403</b> similarly to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0124">The error detection circuit <b>103</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref><i>b </i>may include an XOR gate <b>410</b>, which receives the pulse signal <b>403</b> as a control input. An output of the XOR gate <b>410</b> is coupled to a first connection of a switch <b>412</b>. The switch <b>412</b> may receive an inverted pulse signal as a control input. A second connection of the switch <b>412</b> may be coupled to an input of a first inverter <b>413</b> and an output of a second inverter <b>414</b>. The input of the first inverter <b>413</b> may be further coupled to the output of the second inverter <b>414</b> and the input of the second inverter <b>414</b> may be coupled to the output of the first inverter <b>413</b>. The second inverter <b>414</b> may receive the pulse signal as a control input.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0125">In operation, the pulse signal may enable the XOR gate <b>410</b>. For the duration of the pulse, the XOR gate may compare the value at the first node X<b>1</b> and the data signal output Dout and generate an output indicating a detected difference. While the pulse is asserted, the switch <b>412</b> may be off. When the pulse is de-asserted, the switch <b>412</b> may turn on and couple the output of the XOR gate <b>410</b> to the inverter circuit. The first <b>413</b> inverter may hold the initial value from the output of the XOR gate <b>410</b> to provide the fail signal. When the pulse is asserted, the second inverter <b>414</b> may become active, and the first inverter <b>413</b> and second inverter <b>414</b> may act as a latch to hold the value of the fail signal when the switch <b>412</b> is off.</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0126">The XOR gate <b>410</b>, switch <b>412</b>, and inverters <b>413</b> and <b>414</b> may form domino logic. In an embodiment, a timing requirement for the capture of the comparison of the value at node X<b>1</b> and value of the data output signal Q&#x2212;1 may be set by the pulse. In an embodiment, the timing requirement may be less than a settling time of the data output signal. The error detection circuit <b>103</b> may determine whether the data latch <b>101</b> outputs a correct value within the given time requirement.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0127">Alternatively, as described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref><i>c</i>, the error detection circuitry may be implemented with a metastability detector.</p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0128"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref><i>c </i>is a diagram that includes an embodiment of circuitry for the error detection circuit <b>103</b>. A shadow latch of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref><i>c </i>may be similar to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> and in this embodiment, a clock pulse may not be generated. The error detection circuit <b>103</b> may include an XOR gate <b>421</b>, which receives a first input from the first node X<b>1</b> and a second input of the data output signal Dout. An output of the XOR gate <b>421</b> may provide a first input to an OR gate <b>423</b>. The output of the OR gate <b>423</b> may provide the fail signal. The first node X<b>1</b> may be coupled to an input of a metastability detector <b>422</b>. The output of the metastability detector <b>422</b> may provide a second input to the OR gate <b>423</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0129">In operation, the XOR gate <b>421</b> receives the value at the first node X<b>1</b> and the value Q&#x2212;1 of data output signal Dout and compares them. The result of the comparison is input into the OR gate <b>423</b>. The metastability detector <b>422</b> detects whether or not the value at the first node X<b>1</b> has settled yet, or if it is in a state of metastability. The OR gate <b>423</b> asserts the fail signal if the output from the XOR gate <b>421</b> indicates that the value at the first node X<b>1</b> and the data latch output are different and the metastability detector <b>422</b> indicates that the value at the first node X<b>1</b> is stable.</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0130">In an embodiment, it is appreciated that the error detection circuit <b>103</b> may only be enabled during at least part of a period in which the amplify and hold circuitry <b>205</b> is enabled. Alternatively or additionally, further circuitry may be configured to capture the fail signal from the error detection circuitry <b>103</b> at valid times to prevent the capture of a fail signal generated based on the first node following the data input signal Din. It is appreciated that suitable clocking instants and duration may be chosen accordingly.</p>
<p id="p-0132" num="0131">In an embodiment, a system may include more than one data latch. Some data latches may form part of a critical path, and the shadow latch may be implemented with these critical path latches. In an embodiment, a shadow latch may be provided for each critical path latch, while in others a shadow latch may be provided with only some of the critical path latches.</p>
<p id="p-0133" num="0132">It is appreciated that throughout the detailed description, the term latch has been used to refer to data path sequential logic. It is appreciated that this is for clarity in reading the disclosure only, and the term latch may encompasses flip-flops or other types of latches and/or equivalent circuit components.</p>
<p id="p-0134" num="0133">It is appreciated that the shadow latch and error detection circuitry have been described as being separate circuitry. It is appreciated that in an embodiment, the error detection circuitry may form part of the shadow latch. It is also appreciated that in an embodiment, the shadow latch may not be separate from the sequential logic. For example, the circuitry of the foregoing may be integrated onto a single integrated circuit or may form multiple integrated circuits.</p>
<p id="p-0135" num="0134">It is also be appreciated that while some embodiments describe n-channel and p-channel MOSFETs, other types or topologies of transistors may be used in the implementation of an embodiment. For example, n-channel or p-channel transistors may be replaced by respective p-channel or n-channel transistors with minor modification to the circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0136" num="0135">It is appreciated that the fail signal may be passed to further circuitry that may correct the error and/or provide information of the error to circuitry such as adaptive scaling circuitry. The fail signal in an embodiment may be used to record information and instances of an error.</p>
<p id="p-0137" num="0136">It is appreciated that an embodiment may be implemented in systems making use of dynamic voltage scaling. In an embodiment, system parameters may be scaled in order to bring the system as close to failure as possible in order to achieve, for example, power savings or improved system speed. In an embodiment, the system may be scaled such that the system is in semi-failure. For example, some latches may fail in the system. This may lead to improved power savings if, for example, the power required to recover from the failure is less than the extra power required to prevent failure in all the latches. A failure or error detected in a latch may be used to recover from the error. In an embodiment, the failure signals from all or some latches in the system may be used to determine whether the level of failure in the system is acceptable (for example, the recovery power does not exceed the extra power required for no failure). For example, a system may be set to have 10 failing flip-flops in 100 if the failure recovery power is less than the power saved by having 10 flip-flops in failure instead of zero flip-flops in failure.</p>
<p id="p-0138" num="0137">In an embodiment, an integrated circuit may include an embodiment of the circuitry of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, <b>3</b>, <b>4</b><i>a</i>, <b>4</b><i>b</i>, or <b>4</b><i>c</i>, and such an integrated circuit may be coupled to another integrated circuit (which may or may not include an embodiment of the circuitry of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, <b>3</b>, <b>4</b><i>a</i>, <b>4</b><i>b</i>, or <b>4</b><i>c</i>) to form a system. The integrated circuits may be disposed on the same die or on respective dies, and one of the integrated circuits may be a controller such as a microprocessor or microcontroller. Examples of such a system include a computer system, smart phone, or other electronic system.</p>
<p id="p-0139" num="0138">From the foregoing it will be appreciated that, although specific embodiments have been described herein for purposes of illustration, various modifications may be made without deviating from the spirit and scope of the disclosure. Furthermore, where an alternative is disclosed for a particular embodiment, this alternative may also apply to other embodiments even if not specifically stated.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An apparatus, comprising:
<claim-text>a logic circuit configured to receive an input signal having an input value and to generate an output signal having an output value that corresponds to the input value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an error detector having:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparator configured to compare the input value to the output value and configured to indicate whether the output value corresponds to the input value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an amplifier having a first node configured to receive the input signal and a second node configured to receive the output signal, the amplifier configured to amplify a difference between the input value and the output value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the logic circuit includes a sequential logic circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the logic circuit includes a latch.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the logic circuit is configured to generate the output signal in response to an edge of a clock signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the logic circuit is configured to generate the output signal having an output value that approximately equals the input value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein:
<claim-text>the logic circuit is configured to generate the output signal in response to an edge of a clock signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the error detector is configured to indicate that the output value does not correspond to the input value if the input signal transitions to the input value less than a set-up time of the logic circuit before the edge of the clock.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the amplifier comprises a differential amplifier having a first amplifier node coupled to receive the input signal and a second amplifier node coupled to receive the output signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the amplifier comprises a differential amplifier having a first amplifier node coupled to receive the input signal and a second amplifier node coupled to receive the output signal, the differential amplifier being unbalanced in favor of the first amplifier node.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein:
<claim-text>the amplifier is configured to receive the input signal while a clock has a first level and configured to receive the output signal while the clock has the first level, the amplifier configured to amplify a signal across the first and second amplifier nodes while the clock has a second level; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the comparator having a first input node coupled to the first amplifier node, having a second input node configured to receive the output signal, and the comparator configured to generate a signal that indicates whether the output value corresponds to the input value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein:
<claim-text>the amplifier is configured to receive the input signal while a clock has a first level, and configured to receive the output signal while the clock has the first level, the amplifier configured to amplify a signal across the first and second amplifier nodes for a time that is less than a time during which the clock has a second level; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the comparator having a first input node coupled to the first amplifier node, having a second input node configured to receive the output signal, and the comparator configured to generate a signal that indicates whether the output value corresponds to the input value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein:
<claim-text>the amplifier is configured to receive the input signal while a clock has a first level and configured to receive the output signal while the clock has the first level, the amplifier configured to amplify a signal across the first and second amplifier nodes while the clock has a second level; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the error detector further comprises an exclusive-or gate having a first input node coupled to the first amplifier node, having a second input node configured to receive the output signal, and the exclusive-or gate configured to generate a signal that indicates whether the output value corresponds to the input value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein:
<claim-text>the amplifier is configured to receive the input signal while a clock has a first level, and configured to receive the output signal while the clock has the first level, the amplifier configured to amplify a signal across the first and second amplifier nodes while the clock has a second level; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the comparator circuit having a first input node coupled to the first amplifier node, having a second input node configured to receive the output signal, a stability detector configured to determine whether a signal on the first amplifier node is stable, and the comparator circuit configured to generate a signal that indicates whether the output value corresponds to the input value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. An apparatus, comprising:
<claim-text>a logic circuit configured to receive an input signal having an input value and to generate an output signal having an output value that corresponds to the input value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an error detector configured to indicate whether the output value corresponds to the input value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the error detector includes:</claim-text>
<claim-text>an intermediate node;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparator having a first comparator-input node coupled to receive the output signal, having a second comparator-input node, and configured to generate a signal that indicates whether the output value corresponds to the input value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a differential amplifier having first and second amplifier nodes;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first switch configured to couple the input signal to the second comparator-input node while a clock signal has a first level and to uncouple the input signal from the second comparator-input node while the clock signal has a second level;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second switch configured to couple the second comparator-input node to the first amplifier node while the clock signal has the second level and to uncouple the second comparator-input node from the first amplifier node while the clock signal has the first level;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third switch configured to couple the output signal to the intermediate node while the clock signal has the first level and to uncouple the input signal from the intermediate node while the clock signal has the second level; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth switch configured to couple the intermediate node to the second amplifier node while the clock signal has the second level and to uncouple the intermediate node from the second amplifier node while the clock signal has the first level.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. An integrated circuit, comprising:
<claim-text>a logic circuit configured to receive an input signal having an input value and to generate an output signal having an output value that corresponds to the input value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an error detector having:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparator configured to compare the input value to the output value and configured to indicate whether the output value corresponds to the input value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an amplifier having a first node configured to receive the input signal and a second node configured to receive the output signal, the amplifier configured to amplify a difference between the input value and the output value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A system, comprising:
<claim-text>a first integrated circuit, including:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a logic circuit configured to receive an input signal having an input value and to generate an output signal having an output value that corresponds to the input value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an error detector having:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparator configured to compare the input value to the output value and configured to indicate whether the output value corresponds to the input value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an amplifier having a first node configured to receive the input signal and a second node configured to receive the output signal, the amplifier configured to amplify a difference between the input value and the output value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second integrated circuit coupled to the first integrated circuit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref> wherein one of the first and second integrated circuits includes a controller.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref> wherein the first and second integrated circuits are disposed on a same die.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref> wherein the first and second integrated circuits are disposed on respective dies.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A method, comprising:
<claim-text>causing an output signal to have an output value in response to an input signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>comparing the output signal to the input signal through an imbalanced differential amplifier; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining whether the output value corresponds to an input value of the input signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref> wherein causing the output signal to have the output value includes causing the output signal to have the output value in response to a transition of a clock signal from a clock level to another clock level.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref> wherein determining whether the output value corresponds to the input value of the input signal includes determining whether the output value approximately equals the input value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref> wherein determining whether the output value corresponds to the input value of the input signal includes determining whether the output value corresponds to the input value approximately during a time that a clock signal transitions from a clock level to another clock level.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref> wherein determining whether the output value corresponds to the input value of the input signal includes:
<claim-text>amplifying the input signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining whether the output value corresponds to a value of the amplified input signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref> wherein determining whether the output value corresponds to the input value of the input signal includes:
<claim-text>amplifying a difference between the input signal and a previous output value of the output signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining whether the output value corresponds to a value of the amplified difference.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text>25. An apparatus, comprising:
<claim-text>a logic circuit configured to receive an input signal having an input value and to generate an output signal having an output value that corresponds to the input value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first switch coupled to receive the input signal and configured to generate a clocked input signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second switch coupled to receive the output signal and configured to generate a clocked output signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparator having a first comparator-input node coupled to receive the clocked output signal, having a second comparator-input node coupled to receive the clocked input signal, and configured to generate a signal that indicates whether the output value corresponds to the input value. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
