<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624327-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624327</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13710377</doc-number>
<date>20121210</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>21</main-group>
<subgroup>70</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257369</main-classification>
<further-classification>257334</further-classification>
<further-classification>257379</further-classification>
<further-classification>257410</further-classification>
<further-classification>257411</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Integrated semiconductor structure for SRAM and fabrication methods thereof</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5135882</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Karniewicz</name>
<date>19920800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6573134</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Ma et al.</name>
<date>20030600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0045965</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lin et al.</name>
<date>20050300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0250258</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Metz et al.</name>
<date>20051100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438142</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0105515</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Amos et al.</name>
<date>20060500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0040225</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yang</name>
<date>20070200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0048946</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ramaswamy et al.</name>
<date>20070300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0029822</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Tsuchiya et al.</name>
<date>20080200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0321843</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Waite et al.</name>
<date>20091200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0198699</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hung et al.</name>
<date>20110800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>9</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12706809</doc-number>
<date>20100217</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8330227</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13710377</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130146987</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130613</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company, Ltd</orgname>
<address>
<city>Hsin-Chu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hung</last-name>
<first-name>Sheng Chiang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsinchu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Huang</last-name>
<first-name>Huai-Ying</first-name>
<address>
<city>Jhonghe</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wang</last-name>
<first-name>Ping-Wei</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsinchu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Haynes and Boone, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company, Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Hsin-Chu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Lee</last-name>
<first-name>Kyoung</first-name>
<department>2895</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A SRAM device with metal gate transistors is provided. The SRAM device includes a PMOS structure and an NMOS structure over a substrate. Each of the PMOS and the NMOS structure includes a p-type metallic work function layer and an n-type metallic work function layer. The p-type work metallic function layer and the n-type metallic work function layer form a combined work function for the PMOS and the NMOS structures.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="157.73mm" wi="175.34mm" file="US08624327-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="153.16mm" wi="183.39mm" file="US08624327-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="132.84mm" wi="179.66mm" file="US08624327-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="137.41mm" wi="175.77mm" file="US08624327-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="140.21mm" wi="178.65mm" file="US08624327-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="157.82mm" wi="175.51mm" file="US08624327-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="137.08mm" wi="179.32mm" file="US08624327-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="133.27mm" wi="178.39mm" file="US08624327-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="151.55mm" wi="177.46mm" file="US08624327-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="164.68mm" wi="176.70mm" file="US08624327-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">PRIORITY DATA</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present application is a divisional application of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 12/706,809, filed Feb. 17, 2010, which is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure is related to the following commonly-assigned U.S. patent applications, the entire disclosures of which are incorporated herein by reference: U.S. Application No. 61/186,628 for &#x201c;METAL GATE TRANSISTOR, INTEGRATED CIRCUITS, SYSTEMS, AND FABRICATION METHODS THEREOF&#x201d;.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present disclosure relates generally to the field of semiconductor devices, and more particularly, to metal gate transistors, integrated circuits, systems, and fabrication methods thereof.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The semiconductor integrated circuit (IC) industry has experienced rapid growth. Technological advances in IC materials and design have produced generations of ICs where each generation has smaller and more complex circuits than the previous generation. However, these advances have increased the complexity of processing and manufacturing ICs and, for these advances to be realized, similar developments in IC processing and manufacturing are needed.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In the course of IC evolution, functional density (i.e., the number of interconnected devices per chip area) has generally increased while geometry size (i.e., the smallest component (or line) that can be created using a fabrication process) has decreased. This scaling down process generally provides benefits by increasing production efficiency and lowering associated costs. Such scaling-down also produces a relatively high power dissipation value, which may be addressed by using low power dissipation devices such as complementary metal-oxide-semiconductor (CMOS) devices.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">During the scaling trend, various materials have been implemented for the gate electrode and gate dielectric for CMOS devices. CMOS devices have typically been formed with a gate oxide and polysilicon gate electrode. There has been a desire to replace the gate oxide and polysilicon gate electrode with a high dielectric constant (high-k) gate dielectric and metal gate electrode to improve device performance as feature sizes continue to decrease.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The present disclosure is best understood from the following detailed description when read with the accompanying figures. It is emphasized that, in accordance with the standard practice in the industry, various features are not drawn to scale and are used for illustration purposes only. In fact, the dimensions of the various features may be arbitrarily increased or reduced for clarity of discussion.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic cross-sectional view illustrating an exemplary integrated circuit including a P-type transistor and an N-type transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A-2H</figref> are schematic cross-sectional views illustrating an exemplary gate-last process flow for forming an integrated circuit including a CMOS transistor.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Conventionally, techniques for forming the metal gate electrode can be cataloged as gate-first processes and gate-last processes. For a gate-first process, the metal gate electrode is formed before formation of source/drain regions of the transistors. A gate-last process forms the source/drain regions within the substrate and a dummy gate within an interlayer dielectric (ILD). The dummy gate is removed and an opening is formed within the ILD. The metal gate electrode is then filled within the opening. The gate-first and gate-last processes can be used to form metal gate complementary metal-oxide-semiconductor (CMOS) transistors in logic devices and/or static random access memory (SRAM) devices.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">A logic device comprise a metal gate CMOS transistor including a metal gate PMOS transistor and a metal gate NMOS transistor. The metal gate PMOS transistor in a logic device includes an n-type work function material disposed on the p-type work function material. The metal gate NMOS transistor in a logic device includes a single n-type work function material by removing the previously formed p-type work function material. A SRAM device, following the same design of the metal gate PMOS and NMOS transistors, comprises metal gate PMOS and NMOS transistors with different work functions because of the different work function materials therein. A conductive material may be formed on the CMOS transistor for an electrical transmission.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">As noted, the gate-last process removes the dummy gates for forming recesses for accommodating the metal gate electrodes. The p-type work function material is formed within the recesses of metal gate PMOS and NMOS transistors. Thereafter, before depositing an n-type work function material, the part of p-type work function material in the metal gate NMOS transistor is removed by patterning and etching processes. It is found that SRAM device has a tighter process constrain than in logic device. Hence, the step of removal of the p-type work function material in NMOS transistor increases process complexity and/or uncertainty. If the fabrication technique shrinks, e.g., about 22 nm manufacturing process or less, it is found difficult to ensure well process control on the step of removing p-type work function material in NMOS transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Additionally, there is a need of high implantation dosages for formation of well and/or halo regions in the SRAM devices with different work function materials in metal gate PMOS and NOMS transistors. The higher implantation dosages may induce heavy channeling effect. Moreover, the higher implantation dosages may increase the non-uniform of dopant distribution within device and increases the fluctuation of threshold voltage (Vt) of device.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">It is understood that the following disclosure provides many different embodiments, or examples, for implementing different features of the invention. Specific examples of components and arrangements are described below to simplify the present disclosure. These are, of course, merely examples and are not intended to be limiting. In addition, the present disclosure may repeat reference numerals and/or letters in the various examples. This repetition is for the purpose of simplicity and clarity and does not in itself dictate a relationship between the various embodiments and/or configurations discussed. Moreover, the formation of a feature on, connected to, and/or coupled to another feature in the present disclosure that follows may include embodiments in which the features are formed in direct contact, and may also include embodiments in which additional features may be formed interposing the features, such that the features may not be in direct contact. In addition, spatially relative terms, for example, &#x201c;lower,&#x201d; &#x201c;upper,&#x201d; &#x201c;horizontal,&#x201d; &#x201c;vertical,&#x201d; &#x201c;above,&#x201d; &#x201c;below,&#x201d; &#x201c;up,&#x201d; &#x201c;down,&#x201d; &#x201c;top,&#x201d; &#x201c;bottom,&#x201d; etc. as well as derivatives thereof (e.g., &#x201c;horizontally,&#x201d; &#x201c;downwardly,&#x201d; &#x201c;upwardly,&#x201d; etc.) are used for ease of the present disclosure of one features relationship to another feature. The spatially relative terms are intended to cover different orientations of the device including the features.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic cross-sectional view illustrating an exemplary integrated circuit including a logic device <b>100</b> and/or a SRAM device <b>110</b>. The logic device <b>100</b> includes a N-type transistor (NMOS) <b>100</b><i>a </i>and a P-type transistor (PMOS) <b>100</b><i>b</i>, and the SRAM device <b>110</b> includes a N-type transistor (NMOS) <b>110</b><i>a </i>and a P-type transistor (PMOS) <b>110</b><i>b</i>, over a substrate <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In some embodiments, the substrate <b>101</b> can include an elementary semiconductor including silicon or germanium in crystal, polycrystalline, or an amorphous structure; a compound semiconductor including silicon carbide, gallium arsenic, gallium phosphide, indium phosphide, indium arsenide, and indium antimonide; an alloy semiconductor including SiGe, GaAsP, AlInAs, AlGaAs, GaInAs, GaInP, and GaInAsP; any other suitable material; or combinations thereof. In one embodiment, the alloy semiconductor substrate may have a gradient SiGe feature in which the Si and Ge composition change from one ratio at one location to another ratio at another location of the gradient SiGe feature. In another embodiment, the alloy SiGe is formed over a silicon substrate. In another embodiment, a SiGe substrate is strained. Furthermore, the semiconductor substrate may be a semiconductor on insulator, such as silicon on insulator (SOI), or a thin film transistor (TFT). In some examples, the semiconductor substrate may include a doped epi layer or a buried layer. In other examples, the compound semiconductor substrate may have a multilayer structure, or the substrate may include a multilayer compound semiconductor structure.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the logic device <b>100</b> and the SRAM device <b>110</b> each includes a P-well region <b>102</b> and a N-well region <b>103</b> formed within the substrate <b>101</b>. The P-well regions <b>102</b> and the N-well regions <b>103</b> can be configured to provide channel regions of the NMOS <b>100</b><i>a</i>/<b>110</b><i>a </i>and the PMOS <b>100</b><i>b</i>/<b>110</b><i>b</i>. The P-well regions <b>102</b> and the N-well regions <b>103</b> in the logic device <b>100</b> and the SRAM device <b>110</b> can have a dopant concentration less than 5.7&#xd7;10<sup>13 </sup>atoms/cm<sup>2</sup>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The logic device <b>100</b> and the SRAM device <b>110</b> each includes an isolation structure <b>104</b> disposed between the NMOS <b>100</b><i>a</i>/<b>110</b><i>a </i>and the PMOS <b>100</b><i>b</i>/<b>110</b><i>b</i>, respectively. The isolation structures <b>104</b> can insulate the NMOS <b>100</b><i>a</i>/<b>110</b><i>a </i>from the PMOS <b>100</b><i>b</i>/<b>110</b><i>b</i>, respectively. In some embodiments, the isolation structures <b>104</b> can be shallow trench isolation (STI) structures, local oxidation of silicon (LOCOS) structures, or other isolation structures.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In some embodiments, the PMOS <b>100</b><i>b</i>/<b>110</b><i>b </i>each includes silicon-germanium (SiGe) structures <b>105</b><i>a </i>and <b>105</b><i>b </i>disposed adjacent to p-type source/drain regions <b>107</b><i>a </i>and <b>107</b><i>b</i>, respectively. The p-type source/drain regions <b>107</b><i>a </i>and <b>107</b><i>b </i>can be disposed adjacent to the channel regions of the PMOS <b>100</b><i>b</i>/<b>110</b><i>b</i>. The NMOS <b>100</b><i>a</i>/<b>110</b><i>a </i>each includes n-type source/drain regions <b>106</b><i>a </i>and <b>106</b><i>b </i>disposed adjacent to the channel regions of the NMOS <b>100</b><i>a</i>/<b>110</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In some embodiments, the n-type source/drain regions <b>106</b><i>a </i>and <b>106</b><i>b </i>can have dopants such as Arsenic (As), Phosphorus (P), other group V element, or the combinations thereof. The p-type source/drain regions <b>107</b><i>a </i>and <b>107</b><i>b </i>can have dopant such as Boron (B) or other group III element. In other embodiments, the source/drain regions can include silicide for low resistances. The silicide may comprise materials such as nickel silicide (NiSi), nickel-platinum silicide (NiPtSi), nickel-platinum-germanium silicide (NiPtGeSi), nickel-germanium silicide (NiGeSi), ytterbium silicide (YbSi), platinum silicide (PtSi), iridium silicide (IrSi), erbium silicide (ErSi), cobalt silicide (CoSi), other suitable silicide compounds, and/or combinations thereof. The materials utilized to create the silicide may be deposited using PVD such as sputtering and evaporation; plating; CVD such as plasma enhanced CVD (PECVD), atmospheric pressure CVD (APCVD), low pressure CVD (LPCVD), high density plasma CVD (HDPCVD) and atomic layer CVD (ALCVD); other suitable deposition processes; and/or combinations thereof. After deposition, the salicidation process may continue with a reaction between the deposited material and the doped regions at an elevated temperature that is selected based on the specific material or materials. This is also referred to as annealing, which may include an RTP. The reacted silicide may be formed by a one-step RTP or multiple-step RTPs.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, at least one dielectric layer <b>108</b> can be disposed over the substrate <b>101</b>. The dielectric layer <b>108</b> may include materials such as oxide, nitride, oxynitride, low-k dielectric material, ultra low-k dielectric material, extreme low-k dielectric material, other dielectric material, and/or combinations thereof. The dielectric layer <b>108</b> may be formed by, for example, a CVD process, a HDP CVD process, a HARP, a spin-coating process, other deposition process, and/or any combinations thereof. In some embodiments, the dielectric layer <b>108</b> can be referred to as an interlayer dielectric (ILD). In other embodiments, additional dielectric layer (not shown) can be formed below or over the dielectric layer <b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In some embodiments, spacers <b>109</b><i>a </i>and <b>109</b><i>b </i>can be disposed adjacent to gate structures of the NMOS <b>100</b><i>a</i>/<b>110</b><i>a </i>and PMOS <b>100</b><i>b</i>/<b>110</b><i>b</i>, respectively. The spacers <b>109</b><i>a </i>and <b>109</b><i>b </i>may include materials such as oxide, nitride, oxynitride, and/or other dielectric material.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">As described above, the logic device <b>100</b> includes the NMOS <b>100</b><i>a </i>and the PMOS <b>100</b><i>b </i>over the P-well region <b>102</b> and the N-well region <b>103</b>, respectively. The NOMS <b>100</b><i>a </i>can include a gate dielectric <b>111</b><i>a </i>disposed over the P-well region <b>102</b>. A metal gate G<b>1</b> can be disposed over the gate dielectric <b>111</b><i>a</i>. The metal gate G<b>1</b> includes a first work function metallic layer <b>130</b><i>a </i>which can be configured to adjust a work function value of the metal gate G<b>1</b>. The first work function metallic layer <b>130</b><i>a</i>, for example, is an n-type work function metallic layer. The PMOS <b>100</b><i>b </i>can include a gate dielectric <b>111</b><i>b </i>disposed over the N-well region <b>103</b>. A metal gate G<b>2</b> can be disposed over the gate dielectric <b>111</b><i>b</i>. The metal gate G<b>2</b> includes a second work function metallic layer <b>120</b><i>a </i>disposed under the first work function metallic layer <b>130</b><i>a</i>. The second work function metallic layer <b>120</b><i>a</i>, for example, is a p-type work function metallic layer. The first and the second work function metallic layers <b>130</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>a </i>can form a combined work function to adjust a work function value of the metal gate G<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">As described above, the SRAM device <b>110</b> includes the NMOS <b>110</b><i>a </i>and the PMOS <b>110</b><i>b </i>over the P-well region <b>102</b> and the N-well region <b>103</b>, respectively. The NMOS <b>110</b><i>a </i>can include a gate dielectric <b>112</b><i>a </i>disposed over the P-well region <b>102</b>. A metal gate G<b>3</b> can be disposed over the gate dielectric <b>112</b><i>a</i>. The metal gate G<b>3</b> includes a third work function metallic layer <b>130</b><i>b </i>over a fourth work function metallic layers <b>120</b><i>b</i>. The PMOS <b>110</b><i>b </i>can include a gate dielectric <b>112</b><i>b </i>disposed over the N-well region <b>103</b>. A metal gate G<b>4</b> can be disposed over the gate dielectric <b>112</b><i>b</i>. The metal gate G<b>4</b>, in one embodiment, comprises the third work function metallic layer <b>130</b><i>b </i>over the fourth work function metallic layers <b>120</b><i>b</i>. The third and the fourth work function metallic layers <b>130</b><i>b</i>, <b>120</b><i>b </i>can form a combined work function to adjust work function values of the third metal gate G<b>3</b> and the fourth metal gate G<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In one embodiment, the third work function metallic layers <b>130</b><i>b </i>is an n-type work function metallic layer and the fourth work function metallic layer <b>120</b><i>b </i>is a p-type work function metallic layer. In another embodiment, the third work function metallic layers <b>130</b><i>b </i>is a p-type work function metallic layer and the fourth work function metallic layer <b>120</b><i>b </i>is an n-type work function metallic layer.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In one embodiment, the material of the first work function metallic layer <b>130</b><i>a </i>is the same as the material of the third work function metallic layer <b>130</b><i>b</i>. In yet another embodiment, the material of second work function metallic layer <b>120</b><i>a </i>is the same as the material of the fourth work function metallic layer <b>120</b><i>b</i>. In other embodiment, the materials of the first and the second work function metallic layers <b>130</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>a </i>are the same as the materials of the third and the fourth work function metallic layers <b>130</b><i>b</i>, <b>120</b><i>a</i>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Conductor structures <b>140</b><i>a</i>, <b>140</b><i>b</i>, <b>140</b><i>c</i>, and <b>140</b><i>d </i>can be disposed over the first, the second, the third, and the fourth metal gates G<b>1</b>, G<b>2</b>, G<b>3</b>, and G<b>4</b>, respectively. The conductor structures <b>140</b><i>a</i>, <b>140</b><i>b</i>, <b>140</b><i>c</i>, and <b>140</b><i>d </i>can be configured to provide an electrical transmission. In some embodiments, the conductor structures <b>140</b><i>a</i>, <b>140</b><i>b</i>, <b>140</b><i>c</i>, and <b>140</b><i>d </i>can include structures, such as lines, bulks, plug, and/or other shape of structures. The conductor structures <b>140</b><i>a</i>, <b>140</b><i>b</i>, <b>140</b><i>c</i>, and <b>140</b><i>d </i>can include metal (e.g., Al) or silicide such as nickel silicide (NiSi), nickel-platinum silicide (NiPtSi), nickel-platinum-germanium silicide (NiPtGeSi), nickel-germanium silicide (NiGeSi), ytterbium silicide (YbSi), platinum silicide (PtSi), iridium silicide (IrSi), erbium silicide (ErSi), cobalt silicide (CoSi), titanium silicide (TiSi), other suitable materials, and/or the combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, each of the gate dielectrics <b>111</b><i>a</i>, <b>111</b><i>b</i>, <b>112</b><i>a</i>, and <b>112</b><i>b </i>can be a single layer or a multi-layer structure. In some embodiments, each of the gate dielectrics <b>111</b><i>a</i>, <b>111</b><i>b</i>, <b>112</b><i>a</i>, and <b>112</b><i>b </i>can include an interfacial layer, e.g., a silicon oxide layer and a high-k dielectric layer disposed over the interfacial layer. In some embodiments, the high-k dielectric layer may include hafnium oxide (HfO<sub>2</sub>), hafnium silicon oxide (HfSiO), hafnium silicon oxynitride (HfSiON), hafnium tantalum oxide (HfTaO), hafnium titanium oxide (HfTiO), hafnium zirconium oxide (HfZrO), other suitable high-k dielectric materials, and/or combinations thereof. The high-k material may further be selected from metal oxides, metal nitrides, metal silicates, transition metal-oxides, transition metal-nitrides, transition metal-silicates, oxynitrides of metals, metal aluminates, zirconium silicate, zirconium aluminate, silicon oxide, silicon nitride, silicon oxynitride, zirconium oxide, titanium oxide, aluminum oxide, hafnium dioxide-alumina (HfO<sub>2</sub>&#x2014;Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>) alloy, other suitable materials, and/or combinations thereof. The high-k dielectric layer may be formed by any suitable process, such as atomic layer deposition (ALD), chemical vapor deposition (CVD), physical vapor deposition (PVD), remote plasma CVD (RPCVD), plasma enhanced CVD (PECVD), metal organic CVD (MOCVD), sputtering, plating, other suitable processes, and/or combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The first and the third work function metallic layers <b>130</b><i>a </i>and <b>130</b><i>b </i>can include materials such as metal, metal carbide, metal nitride, or other suitable materials. In some embodiments, the first and the third work function metallic layers <b>130</b><i>a </i>and <b>130</b><i>b </i>can include materials such as hafnium, zirconium, titanium, tantalum, aluminum, metal carbides, other suitable materials, or the combinations thereof. In other embodiments, the first and the third work function metallic layers <b>130</b><i>a </i>and <b>130</b><i>b </i>can include TiAl. The first and the third work function metallic layers <b>130</b><i>a </i>and <b>130</b><i>b </i>are capable of providing a work function value of about 4.4 eV or less. In some embodiments, the first and the third work function metallic layers <b>130</b><i>a </i>and <b>130</b><i>b </i>can have a bottom thickness of about 30 &#x212b;.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The second and the fourth work function metallic layers <b>120</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>b </i>can include materials such as metal, metal carbide, metal nitride, other materials that can provide a desired work function for transistors. In some embodiments, the second and the fourth work function metallic layers <b>120</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>b </i>can include a conductive metal, such as ruthenium, palladium, platinum, cobalt, nickel, conductive metal oxides, e.g., ruthenium oxide, other suitable materials, or the combinations thereof. In other embodiments, the second and the fourth work function metallic layers <b>120</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>b </i>can include TiN. The second and the fourth work function metallic layers <b>120</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>b </i>are capable of providing a work function value of about 4.8 eV or more. In some embodiments, the second and the fourth work function metallic layers <b>120</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>b </i>can have a bottom thickness of about 100 &#x212b; or less. In other embodiments using a 25-nm technique, the second and the fourth work function metallic layers <b>120</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>b </i>can have a bottom thickness of about 30 &#x212b;.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The first and the second work function metallic layers <b>130</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>a </i>may form a combined work function value for the metal gate G<b>2</b>. The third and the fourth work function metallic layers <b>130</b><i>b</i>, <b>120</b><i>b </i>may form a combined work function value for the 20 metal gates G<b>3</b> and G<b>4</b>. The combined work function values of the metal gates G<b>2</b>, G<b>3</b>, and G<b>4</b> are ranging from about 4.4 eV to about 4.8 eV. In some embodiments, each combined work function value of the metal gates G<b>2</b>, G<b>3</b>, and/or G<b>4</b> is adjusted to be about 4.6 eV. Further, in at least one embodiment that the integrated circuit includes a logic device <b>100</b> (or a CMOS device) and a SRAM device <b>110</b>, a work function of the PMOS <b>110</b><i>b </i>of the SRAM device <b>110</b> is the same as a work function of the NMOS <b>110</b><i>a </i>of the SRAM device <b>110</b>, and a work function of the PMOS <b>100</b><i>b </i>of the logic device <b>100</b> is different from a work function of the NMOS <b>100</b><i>a </i>of the logic device <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">It is noted that the structure described above in conjunction with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is merely exemplary. An interconnect structure (not shown) can be formed over the dielectric layer <b>108</b> for an electrical connection. The interconnect structure can include various dielectric materials, via structures, metallic lines, single damascene structure, dual damascene structure, passivation, other desired semiconductor structure, and/or combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A-2H</figref> are schematic cross-sectional views illustrating an exemplary process flow for forming a gate-last CMOS transistor. Items of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A-2H</figref> that are the same items in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> are indicated by the same reference numerals, increased by 100.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, a logic device <b>200</b> includes a NMOS <b>200</b><i>a </i>and a PMOS <b>200</b><i>b</i>, and a SRAM device <b>210</b> includes a NMOS <b>210</b><i>a </i>and a PMOS <b>210</b><i>b</i>, over a substrate <b>201</b>. The NMOS <b>200</b><i>a</i>, the PMOS <b>200</b><i>b</i>, the NMOS <b>210</b><i>a</i>, and the PMOS <b>210</b><i>b </i>each has a dummy gate <b>213</b><i>a</i>, <b>213</b><i>b</i>, <b>214</b><i>a</i>, and <b>214</b><i>b </i>formed over a gate dielectric <b>211</b><i>a</i>, <b>211</b><i>b</i>, <b>212</b><i>a</i>, and <b>212</b><i>b</i>, respectively. In some embodiments, the dummy gates <b>213</b><i>a</i>, <b>213</b><i>b</i>, <b>214</b><i>a</i>, and <b>214</b><i>b </i>can include materials such as silicon, polysilicon, amorphous silicon, and other material that has a desired etch rate with respect to 10 a dielectric material <b>208</b> and spacers <b>209</b><i>a </i>and <b>209</b><i>b</i>. The dummy gates <b>213</b><i>a</i>, <b>213</b><i>b</i>, <b>214</b><i>a</i>, and <b>214</b><i>b </i>can be formed by deposition, photolithography patterning, etching processes, and/or combinations thereof. The deposition processes may include CVD, ALD, other suitable methods, and/or combinations thereof. The photolithography patterning processes may include photoresist coating (e.g., spin-on coating), soft baking, mask aligning, exposure, post-exposure baking, developing the photoresist, rinsing, drying (e.g., hard baking), other suitable processes, and/or combinations thereof. The photolithography exposing process may also be implemented or replaced by other proper methods such as maskless photolithography, electron-beam writing, ion-beam writing, and molecular imprint. The etching processes may include dry etching, wet etching, and/or other etching methods (e.g., reactive ion etching). The etching process may also be either purely chemical (plasma etching), purely physical (ion milling), and/or combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>, the dummy gates <b>213</b><i>a</i>, <b>213</b><i>b</i>, <b>214</b><i>a</i>, and <b>214</b><i>b </i>(shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>) can be substantially removed to form openings <b>215</b><i>a</i>, <b>215</b><i>b</i>, <b>216</b><i>a</i>, and <b>216</b><i>b</i>, respectively. In some embodiments, the dummy gates <b>213</b><i>a</i>, <b>213</b><i>b</i>, <b>214</b><i>a</i>, and <b>214</b><i>b </i>can be removed by, for example, a wet etch process, a dry etch process, other removing process, and/or combinations thereof. In some embodiments, the gate dielectrics <b>211</b><i>a</i>, <b>211</b><i>b</i>, <b>212</b><i>a</i>, and <b>212</b><i>b </i>can include at least one cap layer (not shown) disposed over the high-k dielectric materials. The cap layer is capable of substantially protecting the high-k dielectric materials from being damaged by the process for removing the dummy gates <b>213</b><i>a</i>, <b>213</b><i>b</i>, <b>214</b><i>a</i>, and <b>214</b><i>b</i>. In some embodiments, the cap layer can include materials such as TiN, TaN, other suitable material that can resist the removing process, and/or combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2C</figref>, a protection layer (not shown) and a p-type work function material <b>220</b> can be formed over the structure shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>. The protection layer, for example TaN, may protect the underlying structure during a later process of defining the p-type work function metallic layer <b>220</b><i>a</i>. In some embodiments, the p-type work function material <b>220</b>, for example titanium nitride, tantalum nitride, or cobalt, can contribute to desired work function values for gate electrodes of the PMOS <b>200</b><i>b</i>, the NMOS <b>210</b><i>a</i>, and the PMOS <b>210</b><i>b</i>. The protection material and the p-type work function material <b>220</b> can be formed by any suitable process, such as atomic layer deposition (ALD), chemical vapor deposition (CVD), physical vapor deposition (PVD), remote plasma CVD (RPCVD), plasma enhanced CVD (PECVD), metal organic CVD (MOCVD), sputtering, plating, other suitable processes, and/or combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2D</figref>, a dielectric material <b>221</b><i>a</i>, e.g. spin-on-glass (SOG), can be formed, covering regions of the PMOS <b>200</b><i>b</i>, the NOMS <b>210</b><i>a</i>, the PMOS <b>210</b><i>b</i>, and filling the openings <b>215</b><i>b</i>, <b>216</b><i>a</i>, and <b>216</b><i>b </i>(shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2C</figref>). A photoresist <b>221</b><i>b </i>can be defined over the dielectric material <b>221</b><i>a</i>. The dielectric material <b>221</b><i>a </i>and/or the photoresist <b>221</b><i>b </i>can be provided for patterning the p-type work function material <b>220</b> for the PMOS <b>200</b><i>b</i>, the NOMS <b>210</b><i>a</i>, and the PMOS <b>210</b><i>b</i>. The dielectric material <b>221</b><i>a </i>and the photoresist <b>221</b><i>b </i>can be defined by, for example, a spin-on process, a photolithographic process, and an etch process.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2E</figref>, a portion of the p-type work function material <b>220</b> that is not covered by the dielectric material <b>221</b><i>a </i>and the photoresist <b>221</b><i>b </i>(shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2D</figref>) can be removed, defining the p-type work function metallic layer <b>220</b><i>a</i>. After defining the p-type work function metallic layer <b>220</b><i>a</i>, the dielectric material <b>221</b><i>a </i>and the photoresist <b>221</b><i>b </i>can be removed by a wet etch process, a dry etch process, and/or combinations thereof, exposing the p-type work function metallic layer <b>220</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2F</figref>, an n-type work function material <b>230</b> can be formed over the structure shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2E</figref>. The n-type work function material <b>230</b>, for example titanium, tantalum, aluminum, titanium alloy, tantalum alloy, or aluminum alloy, can provide a desired work function value for the gate electrode of the NMOS <b>200</b><i>a</i>, and contribute to desired work function values for gate electrodes of the PMOS <b>200</b><i>b</i>, the NMOS <b>210</b><i>a</i>, and the PMOS <b>210</b><i>b</i>. The n-type work function material <b>230</b> can be formed by any suitable process, such as atomic layer deposition (ALD), chemical vapor deposition (CVD), physical vapor deposition (PVD), remote plasma CVD (RPCVD), plasma enhanced CVD (PECVD), metal organic CVD (MOCVD), sputtering, plating, other suitable processes, and/or combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2G</figref>, a conducting material <b>240</b>, e.g., metal (e.g., Al) or silicide such as nickel silicide (NiSi), nickel-platinum silicide (NiPtSi), nickel-platinum-germanium silicide (NiPtGeSi), nickel-germanium silicide (NiGeSi), ytterbium silicide (YbSi), platinum silicide (PtSi), iridium silicide (IrSi), erbium silicide (ErSi), cobalt silicide (CoSi), titanium silicide (TiSi), other suitable materials, and/or the combinations thereof, can be formed over the NOMS <b>200</b><i>a</i>, the PMOS <b>200</b><i>b</i>, the NOMS <b>210</b><i>a</i>, the PMOS <b>210</b><i>b</i>, and filling the openings <b>215</b><i>a</i>, <b>215</b><i>b</i>, <b>216</b><i>a</i>, and <b>216</b><i>b </i>(shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2F</figref>). The conducting material <b>240</b> can be formed by a PVD process or a CVD process such as high-density plasma CVD (HDPCVD), atomic layer CVD (ALCVD), or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2H</figref>, a removing process <b>250</b> can remove a portion of the conducting material <b>240</b> such that top surfaces (not labeled) of conducting bulks <b>240</b><i>a</i>, <b>240</b><i>b</i>, <b>240</b><i>c</i>, and <b>240</b><i>d </i>can be substantially level with a top surface <b>208</b><i>a </i>of the dielectric material <b>208</b>. The conducting bulks <b>240</b><i>a</i>, <b>240</b><i>b</i>, <b>240</b><i>c</i>, and <b>240</b><i>d </i>can provide electrical transmission. The removing process <b>250</b> can include a chemical-mechanical polish (CMP) process, a dry etch process, a wet etch process, and/or combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">It is noted that the method described above in conjunction with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A-2H</figref> is merely exemplary. One of skill in the art can modify the flow of the method to achieve desired metal gate transistors. For example, the process forming and defining the dielectric material <b>221</b><i>a </i>can be saved if solely using the photoresist <b>221</b><i>b </i>to define the p-type work function metallic layer <b>220</b><i>a </i>is desired.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In other embodiments, the PMOS <b>200</b><i>b </i>is free from including the n-type work function metallic layer <b>230</b>. In the embodiments, additional photolithographic process, etch process, and/or cleaning process may be used to merely leave the n-type work function metallic layer <b>230</b> in the NMOS <b>200</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The foregoing outlines features of several embodiments so that those skilled in the art may better understand the aspects of the present disclosure. Those skilled in the art should appreciate that they may readily use the present disclosure as a basis for designing or modifying other processes and structures for carrying out the same purposes and/or achieving the same advantages of the embodiments introduced herein. Those skilled in the art should also realize that such equivalent constructions do not depart from the spirit and scope of the present disclosure, and that they may make various changes, substitutions, and alterations herein without departing from the spirit and scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A semiconductor device comprising:
<claim-text>a NMOS structure, comprising,
<claim-text>a first gate dielectric overlying a substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first metal gate overlying the first gate dielectric;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second metal gate overlying the first metal gate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first conductor overlying the second metal gate; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a PMOS structure, comprising,
<claim-text>a second gate dielectric overlying the substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third metal gate overlying the second gate dielectric;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth metal gate overlying the third metal gate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second conductor overlying the fourth metal gate,</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first metal gate is the same as the third metal gate and the second metal gate layer is the same as the fourth metal gate, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a work function of the NMOS structure and the PMOS structure is a combined work function resulted by a p-type work function and an n-type work function.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The semiconductor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the device is static random access memory (SRAM).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The semiconductor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first and the third metal gates are p-type work function layers.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The semiconductor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the p-type work function layers are titanium nitride, tantalum nitride, or cobalt.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The semiconductor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second and the fourth metal gates are n-type work function layers.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The semiconductor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the n-type work function layers are titanium, tantalum, aluminum, or combinations thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The semiconductor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the PMOS structure has a combined work function ranging from about 4.4 eV to about 4.8 eV.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The semiconductor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the NMOS structure has a combined work function ranging from about 4.4 eV to about 4.8 eV.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The semiconductor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the PMOS and the NMOS structures have combined work functions being about 4.6.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A semiconductor device comprising:
<claim-text>a SRAM cell having a first PMOS and a first NMOS; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a CMOS cell having a second PMOS and a second NMOS,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a work function of the first PMOS is the same as a work function of the first NMOS and a work function of the second PMOS is different from a work function of the second NMOS.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The semiconductor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the first PMOS and the first NMOS comprise a p-type work function layer and an n-type work function layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The semiconductor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the second NMOS does not comprise a p-type work function layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A device comprising:
<claim-text>a NMOS structure that includes:
<claim-text>a first metal gate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second metal gate overlying the first metal gate;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a PMOS structure that includes:
<claim-text>a third metal gate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth metal gate overlying the third metal gate; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a work function of the NMOS structure and the PMOS structure is a combined work function resulted by a p-type work function and an n-type work function.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the first and third metal gates have the p-type work function and the second and fourth metal gates have the n-type work function.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the first and third metal gates have the n-type work function and the second and fourth metal gates have the p-type work function.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further comprising a CMOS cell having another PMOS structure and another NMOS structure, wherein a work function of the another PMOS structure is the same as the work function of the NMOS structure and a work function of the another PMOS structure is different from the work function of the NMOS structure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the PMOS structure has a combined work function ranging from about 4.4 eV to about 4.8 eV, and
<claim-text>wherein the NMOS structure has a combined work function ranging from about 4.4 eV to about 4.8 eV.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further comprising a first conductor overlying the second metal gate and a second conductor overlying the fourth metal gate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the first, second, third, and fourth metal gates are formed from at least one of titanium nitride, tantalum nitride, cobalt, titanium, tantalum, aluminum, or combinations thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The semiconductor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a work function of the NMOS structure and the PMOS structure is a combined work function resulted by a p-type work function and an n-type work function. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
