<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622299-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622299</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13308168</doc-number>
<date>20111130</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>83</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>10</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>235454</main-classification>
<further-classification>235435</further-classification>
<further-classification>235439</further-classification>
<further-classification>23546201</further-classification>
<further-classification>23547201</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Apparatus, method and system for determining the source of an optical code presentated to an optical code scanner</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6223988</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Batterman et al.</name>
<date>20010500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>23547201</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2002/0070278</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hung et al.</name>
<date>20020600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>23547201</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>235440</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>23547201</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>235435</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>235439</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>23546201</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>23546206</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130134217</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130530</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Crooks</last-name>
<first-name>John</first-name>
<address>
<city>Duluth</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Mason</last-name>
<first-name>Timothy Edward</first-name>
<address>
<city>Buford</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kleppinger</last-name>
<first-name>Michael A.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Buford</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Crooks</last-name>
<first-name>John</first-name>
<address>
<city>Duluth</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Mason</last-name>
<first-name>Timothy Edward</first-name>
<address>
<city>Buford</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kleppinger</last-name>
<first-name>Michael A.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Buford</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Stevens, III</last-name>
<first-name>Harden E.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>NCR Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Duluth</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Paik</last-name>
<first-name>Steven S</first-name>
<department>2887</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Brown</last-name>
<first-name>Claude J</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A device, method and system is provided for determining if an optical code is presented to an optical code scanner in either a printed form or on the display of an electronic device. Certain presentation characteristics of an optical code are different depending on whether the optical code is presented in printed form or on the display of an electronic device. The changes in the presentation characteristics require changes to certain parameters of the optical code scanner for the optical code to be read.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="164.68mm" wi="242.74mm" file="US08622299-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="218.52mm" wi="168.15mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622299-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="177.88mm" wi="161.12mm" file="US08622299-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="181.19mm" wi="156.72mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622299-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="243.76mm" wi="163.58mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622299-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="274.91mm" wi="184.23mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622299-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates generally to an optical code scanner. More particularly, but not exclusively, the invention relates to determining whether an optical code being read by an optical code scanner is being presented in a printed form or being displayed on a portable display device.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Any discussion of prior art throughout the specification should in no way be considered as an admission that such prior art is widely known or forms part of common general knowledge in the field.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Point of sale (POS) terminals are used throughout the retail industry to process purchase transactions. A POS terminal typically includes a personal computer (PC) core in a chassis, one or more displays, an optical code scanner with weigh scale, a cash drawer, a magnetic stripe reader (MSR), keyboard and a printer. The POS terminals can either be self-service or assisted service.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The optical code scanner includes an imaging scanner and may also include a laser scanner. The two scanners use different technologies to independently read optical codes such as barcodes presented to the scanner. The laser scanner reads a barcode by sweeping a beam of laser light across a barcode, capturing data representing the reflected laser light, and then processing the captured data to recover information encoded in the barcode. An imaging scanner reads a barcode by capturing a complete image of the barcode and then processing the image to recover information encoded in the barcode.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Optical codes, such as barcodes, are generally affixed to or printed on items being presented to a POS terminal for purchase or identification. The optical codes include information about the item they are affixed to or printed on. Some retailers have experienced a type of fraud where a customer presents a barcode for a lesser priced item to a POS terminal for scanning however they place a more expensive item on a security weigh scale of the POS terminal. The customer is charged for the lesser item but receives the more expensive item. For the fraud to be successful, the weight of the two items must be the same or relatively close to each other. So the customer does not have to actually present the lesser priced item for scanning, the customer presents the barcode for the lesser priced item to the POS terminal on the display of an electronic device, such as a smart phone.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Therefore, to prevent the above fraud, as well as other related frauds, there is a need to determine if an optical code that is being presented to a POS terminal is in a printed form on an item or being displayed on the display of an electronic device.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">It is an object of the present invention to overcome or ameliorate at least one of the disadvantages of the prior art, or to provide a useful alternative.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Among its several aspects, one embodiment of the present invention recognizes the need to identify the presentation method used to present an optical code to an optical code scanner which includes an imaging scanner. The presentation methods include printed and displayed on an electronic device. One aspect of the present invention determines the presentation method of the optical code by analyzing the settings of a plurality of adjustable parameters of the imaging scanner after the optical code is successfully read. Different settings optimize the imaging scanner to read optical codes presented in one of the presentation methods. Determining which settings caused the optical code to be read, determines which presentation method was used to present the optical code for reading.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In another embodiment, the optical code scanner is a hybrid optical code scanner and includes the imaging scanner and a laser scanner.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In accordance with an embodiment of the present invention, there is provided an optical code scanner for reading an optical code and determining the optical code is presented in printed form or displayed on an electronic device. The optical code scanner comprising: an imaging scanner where the imaging scanner reads the optical code by capturing an image of the optical code and where the imaging scanner includes a plurality of adjustable parameters that affect the ability to successfully read the optical code; and where the optical code scanner determines the optical code is presented in printed form by determining that the setting of one of the plurality of adjustable parameters matches a first predetermined setting for the one adjustable parameter and determines the optical code is presented by displaying the optical code on the electronic device by determining that the setting of the one of the plurality of adjustable parameters matches a second predetermined setting for the one adjustable parameter.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">A more complete understanding of the present invention, as well as further features and advantages of the invention, will be apparent from the following Detailed Description and the accompanying Drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The aspects of the claimed invention can be better understood with reference to the Drawings and the Detailed Description. The Drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale. Throughout the Drawings, like element numbers are used to describe the same parts throughout the various drawing, figures and charts.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a high-level block diagram illustrating an exemplar embodiment of a point-of-sale system.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a high-level drawing illustrating an exemplar embodiment of a hybrid optical code scanner.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a high-level cross-sectional drawing further illustrating the exemplar embodiment of the hybrid optical code scanner.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a high-level flow chart illustrating an exemplar method of determining the source of an optical code presented to an imaging scanner.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a high-level flow chart illustrating an exemplar method of determining the source of an optical code presented to a hybrid optical code scanner.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In the following description, numerous details are set forth to provide an understanding of the claimed invention. However, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that the claimed invention may be practiced without these details and that numerous variations or modifications from the described embodiments are possible.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The term optical code, as used herein, includes both one and two dimensional barcodes. In addition, two dimensional barcodes include Quick Response (QR) codes and data matrix codes. The term optical code is not intended to be limited to just these examples but include machine readable codes that provide unique information or identification.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, there is provided a high-level block diagram illustrating an exemplar embodiment of a point of sale (POS) system <b>100</b>. The POS system <b>100</b> can be either an assisted or self-checkout system. The POS system <b>100</b> includes a hybrid optical code scanner (&#x201c;hybrid scanner&#x201d;) <b>105</b> connected over a data connection <b>160</b> to a POS terminal <b>110</b>. The hybrid optical code scanner <b>105</b> includes a processor module <b>115</b>, a laser scanner <b>145</b>, an imaging scanner <b>150</b>, an illumination device <b>135</b> and a communications controller <b>155</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Within the processor module <b>115</b>, there is included a processor <b>120</b>, a memory <b>125</b> and control circuitry <b>130</b>. The memory <b>125</b> includes both volatile and non-volatile memory. Software stored in the memory <b>125</b> is executed by the processor <b>120</b> and causes the processor <b>125</b> to control the devices and operation of the hybrid optical code scanner <b>105</b>. The control circuitry <b>130</b> provides an interface between the processor <b>120</b> and the memory <b>125</b> and between the processor <b>120</b> a data bus <b>140</b> used to communicate with other devices that comprise the hybrid optical code scanner <b>105</b> including but not limited to the laser scanner <b>145</b>, imaging scanner <b>150</b> and communications controller <b>155</b>. In some embodiments, all or a portion of the memory <b>125</b> is connected directly to the processor <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The communications controller <b>155</b> includes hardware and software required to communicate with external devices over the data connection <b>160</b>. In some embodiments, the data connection <b>160</b> is implemented using an industry standard USB bus to connect the hybrid optical code scanner <b>105</b> to the POS terminal <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Turning to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, there is provided a high-level drawing illustrating an exemplar embodiment of the hybrid optical code scanner <b>105</b>. The hybrid optical code scanner <b>105</b> includes a housing <b>200</b> comprising a vertical housing component <b>210</b> and horizontal housing component <b>205</b>. The vertical housing component <b>210</b> includes a vertical scanning window <b>220</b> and the horizontal housing component <b>205</b> includes a horizontal scanning window <b>215</b>. The vertical scanning window <b>220</b> faces the front <b>225</b> of the hybrid optical code scanner <b>105</b>. An operator/user of the hybrid optical code scanner <b>105</b> stands in front <b>225</b> of the hybrid optical code scanner <b>105</b> facing the vertical scanning window <b>220</b> and moves optical codes (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, <b>300</b>) for scanning through a first volume of space (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, <b>370</b>) generally above the horizontal scanning window <b>215</b> and in front of the vertical scanning window <b>220</b>. The optical code <b>300</b> can be printed or fixed on an item or displayed on the display of an electronic device.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, there is provided a high-level cross-sectional drawing further illustrating the exemplar embodiment of the hybrid optical code scanner <b>105</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The laser scanner <b>145</b> includes a laser generation device <b>350</b>, a laser beam directing device <b>360</b> for directing a laser beam <b>355</b> generated by the laser generation device <b>350</b> and a photo-detector <b>365</b> for detecting laser light reflected from an optical code back to the laser scanner <b>145</b>. The laser scanner <b>145</b> additionally includes a pattern mirror <b>325</b> used to direct a laser beam <b>340</b> reflected by the laser beam directing device <b>360</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The pattern mirror <b>325</b> is one of a plurality of pattern mirrors (not shown). The pattern mirror <b>325</b> receives the laser beam <b>340</b> from the laser beam directing device <b>360</b> and reflects a laser beam <b>345</b> through the vertical scanning window <b>220</b> to an area in front of the vertical scanning window <b>220</b> and generally over the horizontal scanning window <b>215</b>. In some embodiments, the area the laser beam <b>345</b> is directed to may extend beyond the area directly above the horizontal scanning window <b>215</b>. The laser beam directing device <b>360</b> causes the laser beam <b>345</b> to move so that it scans the volume of space <b>370</b>. As the laser beam <b>345</b> strikes and moves across an optical code <b>300</b>, the reflected laser light is directed back to the laser scanner <b>145</b> (optics not shown) where the laser light is captured by the photo-detector <b>365</b>. The processor <b>120</b> processes the captured data and reads the information encoded in the optical code <b>300</b>. The laser scanner <b>145</b> additionally generates laser beams that are directed through the horizontal scanning window <b>215</b> to read optical codes oriented downward. Laser scanners, in general, are best suited to read one dimensional (1D) barcodes (which are included as an optical code).</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">During the reading of the optical code <b>300</b> by the laser scanner <b>145</b>, the processor <b>120</b> determines a signal to noise ratio of the reflected laser light. A high signal to noise ratio means the optical code <b>300</b> has clear, high contrast symbols making it likely that the laser scanner <b>145</b> will read the optical code <b>300</b> on the first try. A low signal to noise ratio means the optical code <b>300</b> is not clear and has low contrast symbols making difficult for the laser scanner <b>145</b> to read the optical code <b>300</b> even when multiple attempts are made.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The imaging scanner <b>150</b> is shown as part of the vertical housing component <b>210</b>. In some embodiments, the imaging scanner <b>150</b> is removable from the vertical housing component <b>210</b> and is operated as a hand held device to read optical codes not presented directly to the hybrid scanner <b>105</b>. However, when the imaging scanner <b>150</b> is docked in the vertical housing component <b>210</b> it reads optical codes as depicted in this figure. In other embodiments, the imaging scanner <b>150</b> is positioned in different locations within the hybrid scanner <b>105</b> and maybe fixed or removable.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The imaging scanner <b>150</b> includes an image capture device such as a CMOS image sensor. When the optical code <b>300</b> is presented to the hybrid optical code scanner <b>105</b>, the optical code <b>300</b> is illuminated by one or more illumination devices <b>135</b>. Each illumination device <b>135</b> generates light directed toward <b>375</b> the scan volume <b>370</b> to illuminate a optical code within the scan volume <b>370</b>. The intensity of the light generated by the illumination device <b>135</b> is controlled by the processor <b>120</b>. Each illumination device <b>135</b> can be turned off or to full intensity or to numerous intensities in between off and full intensity. The reflected image travels along a first path <b>320</b> to a mirror <b>315</b> where the image is directed along a second path <b>310</b> to the imaging scanner <b>150</b>. The processor <b>120</b> commands the imaging scanner <b>150</b> to capture an image of the optical code <b>300</b> and then the processor <b>120</b> receives and processes the captured image to recover information encoded in the optical code <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The imaging scanner <b>150</b> has number of other parameters also controlled by the processor <b>120</b>. These parameters include shutter open or exposure time and aperture setting. The shutter of the imaging scanner <b>150</b> can be implemented as either a mechanical or electronic shutter. The aperture setting controls the amount of light transmitted to the imaging scanner <b>150</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">If the processor <b>120</b> fails to recover optical code information from a captured image, it will adjust one or more of the imaging scanner's <b>150</b> parameters, including the illumination intensity, and repeat the process of capturing and processing a captured image until the optical code is read. When the optical code is successfully read, each of the parameter settings is known or can be read by the processor <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The hybrid scanner <b>105</b> uses a number of different methods to determine whether an optical code <b>300</b> is being presented in printed form or electronic form from an electronic device. Some methods rely just on the imaging scanner <b>150</b> and others use both the imaging scanner <b>150</b> and the laser scanner <b>145</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">For example, when the imaging scanner <b>150</b> is reading a printed optical code <b>300</b>, the highest first time reads are achieved when the illumination intensity from the illumination device <b>135</b> is near to or at a maximum level. Whereas, optical codes <b>300</b> presented on the display of an electronic device are best read by the imaging scanner <b>150</b> when the illumination intensity from the illumination device <b>135</b> is zero or near zero. If the imaging scanner <b>150</b> fails to read an optical code <b>300</b> when the illumination intensity is at or near to a maximum level but is able to read the optical code <b>300</b> when the illumination intensity is zero or near zero, the optical code <b>300</b> is being displayed on an electronic device. If the imaging scanner <b>150</b> fails to read an optical code <b>300</b> when the illumination intensity is zero or near zero but is able to read the optical code <b>300</b> when the illumination intensity is at or near a maximum intensity, the optical code <b>300</b> is being presented in a printed form.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In addition to the illumination intensity setting, the shutter time and aperture setting of the imaging scanner <b>150</b> also are used to indicate which form the optical code <b>300</b> is presented in. Optical codes <b>300</b> presented to the imaging scanner <b>150</b> on an electronic device are best read using short shutter times and larger aperture openings. Whereas, optical codes <b>300</b> presented in printed form are best read using longer shutter times and smaller aperture openings.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In some embodiments, one or more of the three parameters (intensity, shutter time, and aperture openings) may remain fixed while the others are changed until the optical code <b>300</b> is successfully read. Therefore, the processor <b>120</b> can determine whether an optical code <b>300</b> is presented in printed form or on an electronic device by determining the settings for each parameter of the imaging scanner <b>150</b> that caused the optical code <b>300</b> to be successfully read.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In general, the laser scanner <b>145</b> has great difficultly reading an optical code <b>300</b> being displayed on an electronic device. Even when the laser scanner <b>145</b> is able to read an optical code <b>300</b> being displayed on an electronic device, the signal to noise ratio is very low. Conversely, the imaging scanner <b>150</b> is usually able to read optical codes <b>300</b> being displayed on an electronic device. Therefore, the processor <b>120</b> can determine whether an optical code <b>300</b> is presented in printed form or on an electronic device by determining if the optical code <b>300</b> was read by the imaging scanner <b>150</b> and not by the laser scanner <b>145</b>. When the laser scanner <b>145</b> is able to read the optical code <b>300</b>, a very low signal to noise ratio indicates that the optical code <b>300</b> is being displayed on an electronic device.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The imaging scanner <b>150</b> captures an image of the optical code which is processed to read the optical code. The image usually includes additional information about the area around the optical code. This additional information can be processed by the processor <b>120</b> to determine if the optical code is being displayed on an electronic device such as a cell phone or if the optical code is printed on a product or a coupon. By processing this additional information, the processor <b>120</b> can determine if the optical code is being presented in printed form or on an electronic device.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Turning to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, there is provided a high-level flow chart illustrating an exemplar method of determining the source of an optical code presented to an imaging scanner <b>150</b> that is part of an optical code scanner <b>105</b>. Certain methods that determine the form in which an optical code is being presented to an optical code scanner require that the optical code scanner include both a laser and imaging scanner. Other methods will determine the form in which an optical code is being presented using just an imaging scanner <b>150</b>. The method depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> only requires an imaging scanner <b>150</b> to be present. However, the presence of a laser scanner <b>145</b> does not diminish the effectiveness of the method.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In step <b>400</b>, one adjustable parameter of the imaging scanner <b>150</b> is set to a first predetermined value associated with the one adjustable parameter. The imaging scanner <b>150</b> includes a plurality of adjustable parameters and the one adjustable parameter is one of the plurality of adjustable parameters. The plurality of adjustable parameters control how the imaging scanner <b>150</b> reads an optical code and includes parameters that control illumination of the optical code, shutter time and aperture size.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In step <b>405</b>, the imaging scanner <b>150</b> captures an image of an optical code <b>300</b> being presented to imaging scanner <b>150</b> for reading. In step <b>410</b>, the captured image is processed to read the optical code <b>300</b>. In some cases, the optical code <b>300</b> cannot be read from the captured image. A failure to read a properly presented optical code <b>300</b> is usually due to one or more of the adjustable parameters being set to a setting that is not optimized for the method of presentation being used to present the optical code <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In step <b>415</b>, if the optical code <b>300</b> was read, control is transferred to step <b>425</b>. If the optical code <b>300</b> was not read, control passes to step <b>420</b> where the one adjustable parameter is set to a second predetermined value associated with the one adjustable parameter and control is transferred to step <b>405</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Each of the plurality of adjustable parameter has an associated first and second predetermined value. Each first predetermined value when applied to its associated adjustable parameter causes the imaging scanner <b>150</b> to be optimally configured to read optical codes that are presented in printed form. Each second predetermined value, when applied to its associated adjustable parameter, causes the imaging scanner <b>150</b> to be optimally configured to read optical codes that are presented from a display of an electronic device.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In step <b>425</b>, it is determined if the one of the plurality of adjustable parameters is set to its first predetermined value associated with the one adjustable parameter and if it is, control is transferred to step <b>430</b>. Otherwise, control is transferred to step <b>435</b>. In step <b>430</b>, a first signal is generated that indicates the optical code was presented in printed form to the imaging scanner <b>150</b>. This signal can then be further processed to determine is a fraudulent action has occurred.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">If control is transferred to step <b>435</b>, it is assumed that the one of the plurality of adjustable parameter is set to the second predetermined value associated with the one adjustable parameter. In step <b>435</b>, a second signal is generated that indicates the optical code <b>300</b> was presented on a display of an electronic device to the imaging scanner <b>150</b>. This signal can then be further processed to determine is a fraudulent action has occurred. For example, it is appropriate to scan optical codes from the display of an electronic device when the optical codes represent coupons or loyalty cards. However, it is not appropriate to scan an optical code for a product for purchase from the display of an electronic device. This action would indicate a possible fraudulent transaction.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> depicts a high-level flow chart illustrating an exemplar method of determining the source of an optical code presented to a hybrid optical code scanner <b>105</b>. In this embodiment, both an imaging scanner <b>150</b> and a laser scanner <b>145</b> are used to determine if an optical code <b>300</b> is being presented in printed form or on the display of an electronic device. The operation of the imaging scanner <b>150</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is the same as described in the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In step <b>500</b>, one adjustable parameter of the plurality of adjustable parameters is set to a first predetermined value associated with the one adjustable parameter. In step <b>505</b>, the imaging scanner <b>150</b> captures an image of an optical code <b>300</b> being presented to the imaging scanner <b>150</b> for reading.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In step <b>510</b>, the laser scanner <b>145</b> captures laser data from the optical code <b>300</b>. The laser scanner <b>145</b> generates laser scan lines that sweep through the scan volume <b>370</b>. Laser light reflected from a scanned optical code <b>300</b> is directed back to the laser scanner <b>145</b> and captured. In step <b>515</b>, the captured laser data is processed to read the optical code <b>300</b>. An optical code cannot always be read by processing the captured laser data. As discussed above, it is very difficult for a laser scanner <b>145</b> to read an optical code <b>300</b> presented from a display of an electronic device.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In step <b>520</b>, the captured image from the imaging scanner <b>150</b> is processed to read the optical code <b>300</b>. In some cases, the optical code <b>300</b> cannot be read from the captured image. A failure to read a properly presented optical code <b>300</b> is usually due to one or more of the adjustable parameters being set to a setting that is not optimized for the method of presentation being used to present the optical code <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In step <b>525</b>, if the optical code <b>300</b> was read by the imaging scanner <b>150</b>, control is transferred to step <b>535</b>. If the optical code <b>300</b> was not read by the imaging scanner <b>150</b>, control passes to step <b>530</b> where the one adjustable parameter is set to a second predetermined value associated with the one adjustable parameter and control is transferred to step <b>505</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In step <b>535</b>, control is transferred to step <b>540</b> if the one adjustable parameter is set to the first predetermined value and the laser scanner <b>145</b> also read the optical code <b>300</b>. Otherwise, control passes to step <b>545</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In step <b>540</b>, a first signal is generated that indicates the optical code was presented in printed form to the hybrid optical code scanner <b>105</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In step <b>545</b>, control is transferred to step <b>550</b> if the one adjustable parameter is set to the second predetermined value associated with the one adjustable parameter and the laser scanner <b>145</b> fails read the optical code <b>300</b>. Otherwise, control is transferred to step <b>500</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In step <b>550</b>, a second signal is generated that indicates the optical code <b>300</b> was presented on a display of an electronic device to the imaging scanner <b>150</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Although particular reference has been made to an embodiment that includes a hybrid optical code scanner and examples have been provided illustrating the invention in combination with a laser and imaging scanner, certain other embodiments, variations and modifications are also envisioned within the spirit and scope of the following claims. For example, there are embodiments where the invention is used in scanners having only an imaging scanner. In still other embodiments, after the optical code is read by the imaging scanner <b>150</b>, the captured image of an optical code is further processed to identify the environment surrounding the optical code. In this embodiment, the further processing identifies either an electronic device or the product that the optical code identifies. This information is then used to determine the method of presentation for the optical code.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>We claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An optical code scanner for reading an optical code and determining the optical code is presented in printed form or displayed on an electronic device, the optical code scanner comprising:
<claim-text>an imaging scanner where the imaging scanner reads the optical code by capturing an image of the optical code and where the imaging scanner includes a plurality of adjustable parameters that affect the ability to successfully read the optical code; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>where the optical code scanner determines the optical code is presented in printed form by determining that the setting of one of the plurality of adjustable parameters matches a first predetermined setting for the one adjustable parameter and determines the optical code is presented by displaying the optical code on the electronic device by determining that the setting of the one of the plurality of adjustable parameters matches a second predetermined setting for the one adjustable parameter.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The optical code scanner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further including a laser scanner where the laser scanner generates at least one laser scan beam and reads the optical code presented to the optical code scanner by detecting laser light reflected from the optical code when it is scanned by the least one laser scan beam.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The optical code scanner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, where the optical code scanner further determines the optical code is presented in printed form by determining that both the laser scanner and imaging scanner successfully read the optical code.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The optical code scanner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, where the optical code scanner further determines the optical code is presented by displaying the optical code on the electronic device by determining that the imaging scanner successfully reads the optical code and that the laser scanner is unsuccessful at reading the optical code.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The optical code scanner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, where the optical code scanner further determines the optical code is presented by displaying the optical code on the electronic device by determining that the optical code is read by both the imaging scanner and the laser scanner but the signal to noise ratio from the laser scanner is low.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The optical code scanner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, where the optical code scanner further determines the optical code is presented in printed form by determining that the optical code is read by both the imaging scanner and the laser scanner but the signal to noise ratio from the laser scanner is high.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The optical code scanner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, where the one of the plurality of adjustable parameters is an illumination level for the imaging scanner and the first predetermined setting represents a maximum illumination level and the second predetermined setting represents a minimum illumination level.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The optical code scanner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, where the one of the plurality of adjustable parameters is a shutter time for the imaging scanner and the first predetermined setting represents a shutter time that is longer than a shutter time for the second predetermined setting.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The optical code scanner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, where the one of the plurality of adjustable parameters is an aperture opening for the imaging scanner and the first predetermined setting represents a smaller aperture opening and the second predetermined setting represents a larger aperture opening.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A computer implemented method for use by an optical code scanner to determine the presentation source of an optical code being presented for reading by the optical code scanner, the method comprising:
<claim-text>a) setting one of a plurality of adjustable parameters of an imaging scanner to a first predetermined value where the imaging scanner is a component of the optical code scanner;</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) capturing an image of an optical code using the imaging scanner;</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) processing the captured image to read the optical code if possible;</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) determining the optical code cannot be read and setting the one of the plurality of adjustable parameters to a second predetermined value and repeating steps b through c;</claim-text>
<claim-text>e) generating a first signal indicating the optical code was presented in a printed form when the optical code is read by processing the image data and the one of the plurality of adjustable parameters is set to the first predetermined value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>f) generating a second signal indicating the optical code was presented on a display of an electronic device when the optical code is read and the one of a plurality of adjustable parameters is set to the second predetermined value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the one of the plurality of adjustable parameters is an illumination parameter that controls the amount of light produced and directed at the optical code and wherein the first predetermined value causes the maximum illumination to be produced and wherein the second predetermined value causes the minimum illumination to be produced.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the one of the plurality of adjustable parameters is an exposure parameter that controls the amount of time a shutter on the imaging scanner is open and wherein the first predetermined value causes the shutter time to be set to a minimum exposure time and wherein the second predetermined value causes the shutter time to be set to a maximum exposure time.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the one of the plurality of adjustable parameters is an aperture parameter that controls the size of the aperture opening on the imaging scanner and wherein the first predetermined value causes the aperture to be set to a minimum opening and wherein the second predetermined value causes the aperture opening to be set to a maximum opening.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising the steps:
<claim-text>b.2) capturing laser data using a laser scanner where the laser data represents reflected laser light from the optical code; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>b.3) processing the captured laser data to read the optical code if possible.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein step &#x201c;e&#x201d; further includes generating the first signal when the optical code is also read by processing the laser data.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein step &#x201c;f&#x201d; further includes generating the second signal when processing the laser data fails to read the optical code.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. A point of sale system including:
<claim-text>a point of sale terminal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a hybrid optical code scanner for reading an optical code and determining the optical code is presented in printed form or displayed on an electronic device, the hybrid optical code scanner comprising:
<claim-text>an imaging scanner where the imaging scanner reads the optical code by capturing an image of the optical code and where the imaging scanner includes a plurality of adjustable parameters that affect the ability to successfully read the optical code;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a laser scanner where the laser scanner generates at least one laser scan beam and reads the optical code presented to the hybrid optical code scanner by detecting laser light reflected from the optical code when it is scanned by the least one laser scan beam; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>where the hybrid optical code scanner determines the optical code is presented in printed form by determining that the setting of one of the plurality of adjustable parameters matches a first predetermined setting for the one adjustable parameter and determines the optical code is presented by displaying the optical code on the electronic device by determining that the setting of the one of the plurality of adjustable parameters matches a second predetermined setting for the one adjustable parameter.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, where the one of the plurality of adjustable parameters is an illumination level for the imaging scanner and the first predetermined setting represents a maximum illumination level and the second predetermined setting represents a minimum illumination level.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, where the one of the plurality of adjustable parameters is a shutter time for the imaging scanner and the first predetermined setting represents a shutter time that is longer than a shutter time for the second predetermined setting.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, where the one of the plurality of adjustable parameters is an aperture opening for the imaging scanner and the first predetermined setting represents a smaller aperture opening and the second predetermined setting represents a larger aperture opening. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
