<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626648-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626648</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13717665</doc-number>
<date>20121217</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20120101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>Q</subclass>
<main-group>40</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>705 38</main-classification>
<further-classification>705 39</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Method and system for user signup by a network service provider</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0208681</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hammad et al.</name>
<date>20080800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>705 13</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>705 35- 40</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gopalakrishnan</last-name>
<first-name>Subha</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fremont</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gopalakrishnan</last-name>
<first-name>Subha</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fremont</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Haynes and Boone, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Ebay Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Havan</last-name>
<first-name>Thu Thao</first-name>
<department>3695</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A system and a method for performing purchase transactions over a network are provided. The system includes a server controlled by a service provider, including a link to a network; a processor circuit, the processor circuit configured to receive purchase requests from a mobile phone, and to transfer funds from a user account to a vendor account; and a memory circuit storing a plurality of mobile phone numbers and a plurality of personal identification numbers (PINs), wherein each mobile phone number and PIN is associated with a user account. A non-transitory machine-readable medium may include a plurality of machine-readable instructions which when executed by one or more processors of a server controlled by a service provider are adapted to cause the server to perform a method as above.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="146.98mm" wi="201.59mm" file="US08626648-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="262.89mm" wi="196.34mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626648-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="233.60mm" wi="176.95mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626648-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="228.68mm" wi="180.59mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626648-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="220.39mm" wi="166.71mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626648-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Embodiments disclosed herein relate generally to the field of user signup for a private account service provider over a network. More particularly, embodiments disclosed herein relate to the field of user signup for a private account service provider using a mobile phone.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Private account service providers over a network have proliferated in the past few years. Typically, signing up to become a user of a private account service provider involves providing detailed personal information from the user to the private account service provider. For example, in a first step the user may be prompted to provide a personal bank account number, and a routing number for that bank account. In a second step, the private account service provider may verify the validity of the information provided by the new user by performing a small deposit in the bank account provided, using the routing number. For example, the service provider deposits a small and variable amount into the bank account, by wire transfer. Once the deposit amount is verified by the user and the private account service provider, a new account may be opened for the user with the private account service provider. The drawback of the above approach is the long time it takes for a bank account to process and post a deposit made by wire transfer. Furthermore, although the wire transfer amounts to a small deposit, it is an up-front capital loss for the private account service provider. Accrued over a large number of new users, it may become a significant burden for the service provider, especially since these funds need to be readily available.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">What is needed is a method for providing user signup into a private account service provider that is simple to operate, is highly secure, and reduces up-front expenses for a private account service provider.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">These and other embodiments of the present invention will be described in further detail below with reference to the following drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a system for providing commercial transactions through a network service provider, according to some embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a fund transfer in a system for providing commercial transactions through a network service provider, according to some embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a flow chart for a method to register a user in a network service provider according to some embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a flow chart for a method to perform commercial transactions through a network service provider according to some embodiments.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In the figures, elements having the same reference number have the same or similar functions.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to embodiments disclosed herein a system for performing purchase transactions over a network may include a server controlled by a service provider, wherein the server includes a link to a network; a processor circuit, wherein the processor circuit is configured to receive purchase requests from a mobile phone via a network carrier; and the processor circuit is configured to transfer funds from a user account to a vendor account when a purchase request is received; and a memory circuit storing a plurality of mobile phone numbers and a plurality of personal identification numbers (PINs), wherein each mobile phone number and PIN is associated with a user account.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to some embodiments, a non-transitory machine-readable medium may include a plurality of machine-readable instructions which when executed by one or more processors of a server controlled by a service provider are adapted to cause the server to perform a method including: obtaining a user mobile phone number; verifying the user mobile phone number; selecting a user personal identification number (PIN); creating a user account in the service provider; and sending a message to the user confirming the creation of the account.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In some embodiments, a method for performing purchase transactions over a network by a service provider having a processor circuit and a memory circuit may include: receiving a request for a purchase transaction from a user; verifying the user mobile phone number; transferring funds to a vendor account; and placing a charge to an account in a network carrier, the account associated to the user mobile phone number.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">As mobile phone usage becomes more prevalent, so does a desire to use the mobile phone as an identification device to access personal information and funds at any point in time, anywhere. In fact, in most commercial environments today, a person is as likely to carry a personal mobile phone as to carry an identification card (ID) such as a driver's license or a credit card. In some circumstances, a person may not carry a wallet, and still carry a cell phone or a mobile phone that is able to access the internet through a network carrier. Accordingly, embodiments disclosed herein take advantage of the availability of mobile phones closely related to users carrying them. In some embodiments, a mobile phone is used as an identification device and a network accessible device to open an account for a new user with a private account service provider.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Accordingly, the user may access the private account service provider through a network carrier that provides service to the mobile phone. The network carrier has personal information for the user, such as billing address, name, and even mobility habits. Thus, the private account service provider may safely rely on the network carrier's authentication of the user via the mobile phone number. Furthermore, in many instances even when the user switches the network carrier servicing its mobile phone, the mobile phone number may remain the same. Thus, the private account service provider may rely on the mobile phone number to authenticate the user's identity through a new network carrier.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Embodiments as disclosed herein are desirable for a private account network provider, as no up-front costs are induced for opening a new user account. Furthermore, reliance on a previous contract relation between the user and a network carrier servicing the mobile phone is a guaranty for the private account service provider of the trustworthiness of the user. Embodiments disclosed herein may be desirable for the user, since access to funds in an account with a service provider may be effective almost immediately. Also, the user may find it convenient to lump the costs of transactions through private account service provider together with the costs of servicing the mobile phone through the network carrier, in a single bill. A network carrier that specializes in servicing mobile phones may also find embodiments disclosed herein desirable, as an added fee may be included to all transactions involving the private account service provider. Furthermore, offering the ability to host an account for the private account service provider may be a perk to attract new users to a network carrier servicing mobile phones.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a system <b>100</b> for providing commercial transactions through a network service provider <b>110</b>, according to some embodiments. Service provider <b>110</b> includes server <b>115</b>. Server <b>115</b> includes processor circuit <b>111</b> and memory circuit <b>112</b>. Server <b>115</b> is coupled to a network <b>150</b> through a link <b>163</b>. According to embodiments disclosed herein, network service provider <b>110</b> may be a private account service provider handling private funds accounts for registered users and enterprises, such as PayPal, Inc. of San Jose, Calif.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">A user <b>101</b> carries a mobile phone <b>105</b> coupled to network <b>150</b> through a network carrier <b>120</b> providing a link <b>161</b> to network <b>150</b>. In other embodiments, devices different than a mobile phone may be used, such as a computing tablet or other suitable device capable of wireless communication through network <b>150</b>. User <b>101</b> and service provider <b>110</b> interchange data <b>171</b> and data <b>173</b> through network <b>150</b> and network carrier <b>120</b>. System <b>100</b> may also include a plurality of vendors <b>102</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>102</b>-<b>2</b>, and <b>102</b>-<b>3</b> (collectively referred hereinafter as vendors <b>102</b>). Each one of vendors <b>102</b> is coupled to network <b>150</b> through links <b>162</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>162</b>-<b>2</b>, and <b>162</b>-<b>3</b> (collectively referred hereinafter as links <b>162</b>). Each one of links <b>161</b>, <b>162</b>, and <b>163</b> may be part of a network. For example, links <b>161</b>, <b>162</b>, and <b>163</b> may be included in a cell phone network, a wireless network, an Ethernet network, or any combination of the above. Data <b>171</b> may include information received by user <b>101</b> from service provider <b>110</b>. Data <b>173</b> may include information provided by user <b>101</b> to service provider <b>110</b>. For example, data <b>171</b> may be a request for a password, a PIN code, or some other account identifier. Data <b>173</b> may include a mobile phone number and other user personal address, such as name and address, and name of network carrier <b>120</b>. Data <b>173</b> may also include an e-mail address for the user, so that service provider <b>110</b> may send messages directly to the user.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">According to some embodiments, network carrier <b>120</b> may service mobile phone <b>105</b> for user <b>101</b> in a post-pay configuration. That is, a long term contract may link user <b>101</b> to network carrier <b>120</b>. Thus, some embodiments may link the newly created user account in service provider <b>110</b> to the contract between user <b>101</b> and network carrier <b>120</b>. Such a configuration is desirable because the pre-existence of a contract between user <b>101</b> and network carrier <b>120</b> is a guaranty for service provider <b>110</b> that the user is a trustworthy customer.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In some embodiments, mobile phone <b>105</b> may be under a pre-paid contract with network provider <b>120</b>. In such configuration, further verification from service provider <b>110</b> of the authenticity of user <b>101</b> may be used. For example, service provider <b>110</b> may request an e-mail address for user <b>101</b> to exchange verification messages. Thus, service provider <b>110</b> may send an e-mail message to user <b>101</b>, requesting a response. Upon receiving a user response, service provider <b>110</b> may open an account for user <b>101</b> temporarily linked to mobile phone <b>105</b>. The account thus created may be set to expire as soon as the pre-paid contract for mobile phone <b>105</b> terminates. While the account in service provider <b>110</b> is active, and prior to expiration, service provider <b>110</b> may request user <b>101</b> to provide further personal information such as a bank account and a routing number, so that an account may be created for the user with service provider <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In some embodiments, service provider <b>110</b> may determine that the user has a pre-paid connection. Such a pre-paid connection may be for example an AT&#x26;T $100 pre-paid card. Prior to, or at the time of the pre-paid card expiration, service provider <b>110</b> may then use verification channels such as performing random deposits in a user's bank account. This approach ensures that user <b>101</b> gets an account with service provider <b>110</b>, preventing any loss of revenue after the contract between user <b>101</b> and network carrier <b>120</b> expires.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In some embodiments, having a user's mobile phone number may enable service provider <b>110</b> to access detailed personal information from the user, through network carrier <b>120</b>. Thus, data <b>173</b> may be provided by network carrier <b>120</b> to service provider <b>110</b>, and may include for example a user account number with network carrier <b>120</b>. Data <b>173</b> may further include the user's billing address, and other user personal information. For example, in some embodiments, data <b>173</b> may include a user mobile trajectory for a period of time. Data <b>171</b> may be provided to network carrier <b>120</b> by service provider <b>110</b> in order for network carrier <b>120</b> to prepare a bill for user <b>101</b>. For example, data <b>171</b> may include a list of invoices related to purchases by user <b>101</b> with vendors <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Furthermore, embodiments consistent with the present disclosure enable tracking frequently travelled locations of user <b>101</b>, and have a record of these locations. The record may be stored in memory <b>112</b>. Server <b>110</b> may use the stored track data of user <b>101</b> to detect fraud or user account abuse. For example, server <b>110</b> may issue an alert when an attempt to access a user account originates from a not-so-regular location, or a location not recorded on track. In some embodiments, having a mobile number associated to a user account is desirable to enhance account verification. Account verification through a mobile phone account may be used in lieu of, or in addition to using a third party identity and credit verification system (e.g., Lexis Nexis, Targus, or other). Use of third party account verification includes a cost for service provider <b>110</b> since calls to the third party are charged. Using account verification through a mobile phone account with network carrier <b>120</b> may reduce or eliminate altogether account verification costs.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">According to some embodiments, user <b>101</b> may interact with vendors <b>102</b> directly, to perform a purchase transaction. For example, user <b>101</b> may be at a store location, physically proximal to a vendor <b>102</b>. With mobile phone <b>105</b>, user <b>101</b> is able to complete the purchase transaction on location, using a personal account and a vendor account with service provider <b>110</b>. In some embodiments, user <b>101</b> may interact with vendors <b>102</b> through network <b>150</b>. For example, user <b>101</b> may perform a purchase transaction on a vendor webpage in network <b>150</b>. User <b>101</b> may access network <b>150</b> through network carrier <b>120</b>, and any one of vendors <b>102</b> may access network <b>150</b> through the corresponding link <b>162</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Vendors <b>102</b> may have private or enterprise accounts with service provider <b>110</b>. Thus, for every commercial transaction between user <b>101</b> and vendors <b>102</b>, service provider <b>110</b> may transfer funds from a user account to the respective vendor account, in the amount of the transaction. In some embodiments, a vendor <b>102</b> may not have an account with service provider <b>110</b>. In such cases, a commercial transaction may still take place, and service provider <b>110</b> may contact vendor <b>102</b> through network <b>150</b> in order to provide funds to cover the transaction. For example, service provider <b>110</b> may request vendor <b>102</b> to provide bank account information and a routing number, in order to transfer the funds for the transaction. Further, in some embodiments, service provider <b>110</b> may take the opportunity to offer a vendor <b>102</b> opening an account with service provider <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In some embodiments, vendor <b>102</b> may not have an account with service provider <b>110</b>. In such configuration, user <b>101</b> may associate an account in service provider <b>110</b> as one of the funding sources in the transaction with vendor <b>102</b>. When user <b>101</b> makes a transaction with vendor <b>102</b>, service provider <b>110</b> may transfer any remaining dues directly to vendor <b>102</b>. For example, service provider <b>110</b> may request a bank account and a routing number from vendor <b>102</b> to make the fund transfer. Service provider <b>110</b> may also send a check or money order to an address provide by vendor <b>102</b>. Accordingly, one of ordinary skill would recognize other options for service provider <b>110</b> to transfer funds due to vendor <b>102</b> after a transaction with user <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a fund transfer <b>200</b> in system <b>100</b> for providing commercial transactions through network service provider <b>110</b>, according to some embodiments. Accordingly, upon a purchase transaction between user <b>101</b> and one of vendors <b>102</b>, service provider <b>110</b> transfers funds to vendor <b>102</b> and charges network carrier <b>120</b> in a similar amount. Network carrier <b>120</b> in turn charges user <b>101</b> for the transaction, and pays service provider <b>110</b> in the transaction amount. User <b>101</b> pays network carrier <b>120</b> for the transaction. For example, user <b>101</b> pays for the transaction as part of a regularly scheduled payment for the carrier services provided by network carrier <b>120</b> to mobile device <b>105</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a flow chart for a method <b>300</b> to register a user in a network service provider according to some embodiments (e.g., user <b>101</b> and service provider <b>110</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). Steps in method <b>300</b> may be partially performed by a processor circuit upon executing commands and using data stored in a memory circuit. The processor circuit and the memory circuit may be included in the service provider (e.g., processor circuit <b>111</b> and memory circuit <b>112</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). The user may communicate to the service provider in method <b>300</b> with a mobile phone coupled to a network through a network carrier (e.g., user <b>101</b>, network <b>150</b>, and network carrier <b>120</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). Furthermore, data exchanged between the user and the service provider in method <b>300</b> may be exchanged through a network carrier servicing the user's mobile phone (e.g., data <b>171</b> and data <b>173</b>, cf. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In step <b>310</b>, the user mobile number is obtained. Step <b>310</b> may include obtaining the user mobile number from the network when a user starts an application program in the mobile phone.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In step <b>320</b>, the user mobile number is verified. Step <b>320</b> may include obtaining user account information from a network carrier providing the mobile phone service to the user. Service provider <b>110</b> may exchange data with the network carrier through links <b>161</b> and <b>163</b> to network <b>150</b>, in step <b>320</b>. Accordingly, in step <b>320</b>, the service provider may request information to the network carrier to obtain a user e-mail and a user address. Furthermore, in step <b>320</b>, the service provider may verify whether the mobile number is associated to a pre-paid account or a post-paid account. In some embodiments, a private account for the user in the service provider may not be created if the mobile number is associated with a pre-paid account. In some embodiments, a temporary private account for the user may be created if the mobile number is associated with a pre-paid account.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In step <b>330</b>, a personal identification number (PIN) is selected for the user. Step <b>330</b> may include requesting the user to input a selected PIN number, and verify the PIN number. In some embodiments, step <b>330</b> may include performing an identity check and a credit check for the user. To perform an identity check and a credit check, the service provider may use access to the network. In some embodiments, the service provider may use a third party service to perform user identity check, or credit check, through a link to the network.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In step <b>340</b>, a user account is created. Step <b>340</b> may include storing user's personal information in the memory circuit. Step <b>340</b> may include exchange of data between the service provider and the network carrier through the network (e.g., data <b>171</b> and <b>173</b>, cf. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). In some embodiments, step <b>340</b> may include receiving details of a user's account with the network carrier. Accordingly, when the service provider processes a transaction request from the user, the service provider may associate the user's mobile phone number and PIN to an account in the network carrier. Furthermore, the service provider may associate an e-mail address to the user account.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In some embodiments, step <b>340</b> may include notifying the user that an account with the service provider has been created. For example, the service provider may send a message to the user's mobile phone, or may send an e-mail message to the user's e-mail. Further according to some embodiments, service provider may offer the user the possibility to have an account that may be operable independently of the network carrier. For example, the service provider may create an account for the user that may be accessed without a mobile phone. In some embodiments, an independent user account may be separated from the user account linked to the mobile phone. In such configuration, a user may be required to provide bank account information to create the independent account. Moreover, in some embodiments the service provider may charge the user account through the network carrier when the user performs a purchase transaction using the mobile phone. And the service provider may charge the independent account when the user performs the purchase transaction without using the mobile phone.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The service provider may pay the network carrier (e.g., AT&#x26;T or Verizon) for the network services in the payment transaction between the user and the vendor. In some embodiments the network carrier may charge the user for this additional cost (e.g., in a monthly bill). In some embodiments, the network carrier may absorb the cost of providing network services through the transaction. Even if the network carrier charges a fee (either to the user or to the service provider), the amount may be less than, or comparable to charges to the service provider for fund transfers from banks or credit card companies. Thus, embodiments consistent with the present disclosure may be beneficial for the user, the service provider, and the network carrier.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a flow chart for a method <b>400</b> to perform commercial transactions through a network service provider according to some embodiments. Steps in method <b>400</b> may be partially performed by a processor circuit upon executing commands and using data stored in a memory circuit. The processor circuit and the memory circuit may be included in the service provider (e.g., processor circuit <b>111</b> and memory circuit <b>112</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In step <b>410</b>, a request from a user is received. In some embodiments, the request is received from a mobile phone that identifies a user account with the service provider (e.g., mobile device <b>105</b>, user <b>101</b>, and service provider <b>110</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). For example, the user may be at a store location, finalizing a purchase transaction using a mobile phone. By starting a network application running in the mobile phone, the user may be able to place a request for a payment using the private account with the service provider. The mobile phone may use a network carrier to access a network through a link (e.g., network carrier <b>120</b>, link <b>161</b>, and network <b>150</b>). The service provider may perform step <b>410</b> using a link to a network (e.g., link <b>163</b> and network <b>150</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In step <b>420</b>, the user mobile number is verified. Step <b>420</b> may include comparing the mobile number with a list of mobile numbers registered with the service provider. If the mobile number is in the list of mobile numbers registered with the service provider, step <b>420</b> may further request verification from the user, to authenticate the transaction. For example, step <b>420</b> may request from the user to input a PIN or a password or passcode, associated with the user account. Thus, even if a user loses a mobile phone, or the mobile phone is stolen, malicious abuse of the payment system may be averted.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In step <b>430</b>, funds are transferred to a vendor's account when the user's account is verified. For example, a service provider may have an account for a vendor (e.g., vendor <b>102</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>), and an account for the user. Thus, the service provider may transfer the funds from the user's account to the vendor's account.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In step <b>440</b>, a charge is placed to a user account in the network carrier. Step <b>440</b> may include receiving from the network carrier the purchase transaction amount. The network carrier may then charge an account for the user's mobile phone in the amount of the purchase transaction, or a similar amount. For example, the network carrier may add a transaction fee to the charges for the user, in addition to the purchase transaction amount.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Embodiments of the invention described above are exemplary only. One skilled in the art may recognize various alternative embodiments from those specifically disclosed. Those alternative embodiments are also intended to be within the scope of this disclosure. As such, the invention is limited only by the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A system for performing purchase transactions over a network, the system comprising:
<claim-text>a server controlled by a service provider, wherein the server comprises a link to a network;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a processor circuit, wherein the processor circuit is configured to receive purchase requests from a mobile phone via a network carrier; and
<claim-text>the processor circuit is configured to transfer funds from a user account to a vendor account when a purchase request is received; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a memory circuit storing a plurality of mobile phone numbers and a plurality of personal identification numbers (PINs), wherein each mobile phone number and PIN is associated with a user account.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the processor circuit is further configured to provide an invoice with a plurality of charges from the user account to the network carrier servicing the mobile phone number associated with the user account.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the vendor account is an account with the service provider.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the vendor account is a bank account.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the memory circuit stores a track of frequently travelled locations of the user based on data from the mobile phone.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A non-transitory machine-readable medium comprising a plurality of machine-readable instructions which when executed by one or more processors of a server controlled by a service provider are adapted to cause the server to perform a method comprising:
<claim-text>obtaining a user mobile phone number;</claim-text>
<claim-text>verifying the user mobile phone number;</claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting a user personal identification number (PIN);</claim-text>
<claim-text>creating a user account in the service provider; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending a message to the user confirming the creation of the account.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The non-transitory machine-readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the verifying the user mobile phone number comprises requesting user information to a network carrier servicing the user mobile phone.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The non-transitory machine-readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the requesting user information to a network carrier comprises obtaining a user e-mail and a user address.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The non-transitory machine-readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the verifying the user mobile phone number comprises verifying whether the mobile number is associated with one of the group consisting of a post-paid network carrier account or a pre-paid network carrier account.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The non-transitory machine-readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the method further comprises sending a message to the user requesting a bank account number and a routing number to transfer funds into the user account in the service provider.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The non-transitory machine-readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the method further comprises storing track information comprising travelled locations of the user based on data from the mobile phone.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The non-transitory machine-readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the method further comprises performing an identity check for the user and a credit check for the user over a network.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A method for performing purchase transactions over a network by a service provider having a processor circuit and a memory circuit, the method comprising:
<claim-text>receiving a request for a purchase transaction from a user;</claim-text>
<claim-text>verifying the user mobile phone number;</claim-text>
<claim-text>transferring funds to a vendor account; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>placing a charge to an account in a network carrier, the account associated to the user mobile phone number.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the verifying the user mobile phone number comprises requesting a personal identification number (PIN) from the user.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> further comprising performing an identity check for the user and a credit check for the user over the network.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the transferring funds to a vendor account comprises transferring funds to a vendor account within the service provider.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the transferring funds to a vendor account comprises requesting a bank account number and a routing number to the vendor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further comprising requesting an account number from the vendor to transfer funds to a vendor account.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further comprising storing track information comprising travelled locations of the user based on data from the mobile phone.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, further comprising creating an alert when the requests for the purchase transaction originates from a location not included in the stored track information. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
