<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08621947-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08621947</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13265381</doc-number>
<date>20100330</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10 2009 002 545</doc-number>
<date>20090421</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>140</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>30</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 738665</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Assembly device for a measuring probe for measuring process variables in a process</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4346611</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Welker</name>
<date>19820800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4928517</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Fitts</name>
<date>19900500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 73105</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>CH</country>
<doc-number>521 657</doc-number>
<date>19720400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>G 86 33 674.6</doc-number>
<date>19870400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>41 40 286</doc-number>
<kind>C2</kind>
<date>19980600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10 2006 022 979</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20071100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10 2006 022 981</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20071100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>0 590 290</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19940400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>0 882 896</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19981200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1 156 323</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20011100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1 248 102</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20021000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00012">
<othercit>English translation of International Preliminary Report on Patentability of PCT/EP2010/054209.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>8</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120036948</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120216</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Schlereth</last-name>
<first-name>Rainer</first-name>
<address>
<city>Neuss</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Oppermann</last-name>
<first-name>Hans-Joachim</first-name>
<address>
<city>Gemmrigheim</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Schlereth</last-name>
<first-name>Rainer</first-name>
<address>
<city>Neuss</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Oppermann</last-name>
<first-name>Hans-Joachim</first-name>
<address>
<city>Gemmrigheim</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Bacon &#x26; Thomas, PLLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Endress + Hauser Conducta Gesellschaft f&#xfc;r Mess&#x2014;und Regeltechnik mbH + Co. KG</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Gerlingen</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Raevis</last-name>
<first-name>Robert R</first-name>
<department>2856</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/EP2010/054209</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20100330</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20111020</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2010/121893</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20101028</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An assembly device, especially a retractable assembly, for a measuring probe for measuring process variables in a process, comprising: an assembly housing with a connection system for connecting the assembly device to a process container; a tubular holder for a measuring probe, wherein the tubular holder is guided in the assembly housing axially displaceably between a measuring position in the process container and a maintenance position outside of the process container; and a damping system to damp axial shifting of the tubular holder. The damping system comprises a fluid filled, damping cylinder within the assembly housing, and a damping piston unit guided within the damping cylinder (<b>15</b>) in operative connection with the tubular holder.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="200.32mm" wi="92.03mm" file="US08621947-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="244.26mm" wi="182.71mm" file="US08621947-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="267.63mm" wi="210.06mm" file="US08621947-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The invention relates to an assembly device, especially a retractable assembly, for a measuring probe for measuring process variables in a process.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND DISCUSSION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Assembly systems, especially retractable assemblies, which are also referred to as push rod assemblies, are widely distributed in analytical measurements technology. They serve to introduce or withdraw measuring probes, e.g. sensors, into a process without interrupting the process. For this, the measuring probe is usually accommodated in a tubular holder, which is shiftably accommodated within an assembly housing of the assembly device and is guided between a measuring position and a maintenance position. The shifting of the tubular holder with the measuring probe can occur manually or automatically, for example, with the assistance of a pneumatic drive system. A pneumatic drive system for shifting the holder for the measuring probe can comprise a pneumatic cylinder and a movable, compressed air driven, piston therein, with which the tubular holder for the measuring probe is connected directly or via one or more connecting parts.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The assembly housing has a connection system, for example, a flange, to connect the assembly device to a process container. A calibration and/or cleaning chamber, into which the measuring probe can be drawn to a maintenance position, can be provided within the assembly housing in order to clean and/or calibrate the measuring probe.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In order to seal off the calibration and/or cleaning chamber from the process to be monitored, internal sealing rings are frequently arranged on the guide of the tubular holder in the region of the calibration chamber in the assembly housing; the sealing rings lie against smooth sealing surfaces on the process side end of the tubular holder.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Here and in the following, the side of the assembly device, on which the connection system for connecting to a process container is placed, is referred to as &#x201c;process side&#x201d;. Correspondingly, the direction along the central longitudinal axis of the assembly device toward the connection system is referred to as &#x201c;on the process side&#x201d;. The direction set counter to the process side direction is referred to as &#x201c;facing away from the process.&#x201d;</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The firm of Endress+Hauser offers such assembly systems under the &#x201c;Cleanfit&#x201d; mark, examples of these are CleanFit S, CPA 471, CPA 472 and 472D, CPA 473, CPA 474 and CPA 475. The movement of the holder for the measuring probe occurs in an axial direction in these assembly systems, i.e. along a central axis of the assembly device. The movement occurs via a pneumatic drive automatically or by means of a manual actuation. In order to achieve a smooth approach of the retractable assembly to the particular position and especially to avoid damage to the measuring probe by too abrupt stopping in the measuring position or maintenance position, the axial movement of the measuring probe holder is damped with the assistance of a supplemental throttle element, which is mounted in the air supply of the pneumatic drive of the respective desired movement direction, namely in the measuring position or the maintenance position in assemblies with pneumatic drive systems.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">As a supplemental component, such a throttle element is, however, on one hand, relatively expensive, especially because a throttle element is required for each movement direction, and on the other hand, has the disadvantage that it is only suitable in connection with the pneumatic drive for damping the movement of the measuring probe or the measuring probe holder.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">It is the object of the invention to provide an assembly device of the type initially named that avoids the disadvantages of the state of the art. The shifting movement of the holder for the measuring probe should especially be effectively damped with as simple a construction of the assembly device and the damping means as possible.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">This object is achieved by an assembly device, especially a retractable assembly, for a measuring probe for measuring process variables in a process, comprising:</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">an assembly housing with a connection system for connecting the assembly device to a process container; a tubular holder for a measuring probe, wherein the tubular holder is guided in the assembly housing axially displaceably between a measuring position in the process container and a maintenance position outside of the process container; and
<br/>
a damping system to damp axial shifting of the tubular holder, wherein the damping system comprises a fluid filled, damping cylinder within the assembly housing, and a damping piston unit guided within the damping cylinder in operative connection with the tubular holder. An operative connection between the damping piston unit and the holder is here understood to mean that a damping piston unit and a holder are mechanically coupled in such a manner that with a movement, especially a shifting, of the tubular holder, the damping piston unit mandatorily moves likewise, especially is shifted within the damping cylinder. The operative connection can especially be a rigid connection between the damping piston unit and the holder, especially via one or a number of connecting parts.
</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Through the operative connection between the damping piston unit and the axially shiftable, tubular holder in the assembly housing, the movement of the damping piston unit within the fluid filled, damping cylinder thus is directly coupled to the axial movement of the holder for the measuring probe when shifting the measuring probe between a measuring position and a maintenance position. Since the damping piston unit is guided within a fluid filled, damping cylinder, a damping effect results due to the flow resistance of the fluid counteracting the movement of the damping piston unit; the damping effect, in turn, affects the movement of the holder directly through the operative connection between the damping piston unit and the measuring probe holder. In this way, an effective damping of the axial shifting movement of the tubular holder is achieved. Thus, no additional components, such as for example, one or a number of throttles acting on a pneumatic drive of the assembly device, are required for damping the shifting movement. Since the damping effect is not achieved by means of such a throttling of a pneumatic control as in the state of the art, the damping system described here is suitable for both automatically, especially pneumatically, operated assembly systems as well as for manually operated assembly systems. Furthermore, only one damping system is required for the shifting movement in both directions since the damping effect due to the flow resistance of the fluid occurring with the movement of the damping piston unit occurs in both directions.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In a preferred embodiment, the damping piston unit has a fluid passageway, which connects a first volume of the damping cylinder to a second volume of the damping cylinder. In this way, fluid from the first volume can flow into the second volume or in the reverse direction with the movement of the damping piston unit through the damping cylinder. The fluid passageway preferably has a significantly smaller cross section, at least sectionally, than the damping cylinder so that through the braking action of the fluid flowing through this cross sectional restriction, a noticeable damping of a stroke movement of the damping piston unit is achieved. The cross sectional ratio, depending on the viscosity of the fluid in the damping cylinder can be set in order to achieve the desired damping effect.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In an alternative embodiment, a fluid passageway extending within the damping piston unit can be omitted by having the damping piston unit only partially seal fluid tightly on its periphery with the inner wall of the damping cylinder so that fluid from the first volume can flow to the second volume between the damping piston unit and the inner wall of the damping cylinder surrounding the damping piston unit.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The cross section of the fluid passageway can be adjusted by means of a valve element in order to set the flow resistance, with which the fluid opposes the movement of the damping piston unit in a transition from the first to the second volume or a transition from the second to the first volume. In this way, the damping effect on the movement of the damping piston unit within the damping cylinder can be varied and set as desired.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The damping piston unit can comprise a damping piston rod with a first diameter and an adjacent piston with a second diameter on a process side end of the damping piston rod, wherein the first diameter is smaller than the second diameter, and wherein the first volume borders the process side, end face of the piston and the second volume borders the rear side of the piston facing away from the process.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The valve element mentioned can be formed by a bore section, especially a constricted bore section of a bore, especially a cylindrical bore, extending axially within the damping piston unit and a spindle, especially an at least sectionally cone or frustoconically shaped spindle, which is at least sectionally continuously tapering, protruding into the bore section, wherein the spindle closes the bore section except for an annular opening, which is also referred to as an annular gap in the following, wherein the cross section of the annular opening is adjustable by shifting the spindle into the bore section or out of the bore section.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The bore section can be a constricted section of the axial bore extending within the damping piston unit, for example. If the axial bore constricts in a stepwise fashion, for example, i.e. abruptly from a first to a second, smaller, cross section, the conical spindle can be so arranged that its continuously tapering section protrudes from the bore section with the first cross section into the constricted bore section with the smaller cross section. An annular gap is formed between the edge surface of the spindle, which, for example, can be embodied as a conical surface or a frustoconical surface, and the step formed by the constriction of the bore, referred to as a &#x201c;step shaped constriction&#x201d; in the following for purposes of simplicity.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The spindle can be placed on a process side end of a pin guided within the damping piston rod, for example, extending in the axial bore within the damping piston unit, wherein the pin or a pin extension is secured to the damping piston rod by an external thread, which interacts with an internal thread of the damping piston rod. The screw thread connection between the pin or the pin extension and the damping piston rod permits a shifting of the spindle in an axial direction. By turning the pin in the process side direction, the spindle is shifted, for example, into the constricted bore section within the damping piston, which leads to a reduction of the annular opening and therewith to a decrease of the fluid passage cross section. Turning the pin in a direction away from the process leads correspondingly to a shifting of the spindle out of the constricted bore section, which leads to an increase in the annular opening and correspondingly an increase in the cross section of the fluid passageway.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The first volume of the damping cylinder can be connected to the second volume of the damping cylinder via the axial bore within the damping piston and via a radial bore, which has a first exit into the axial bore and a second exit into the second volume of the damping cylinder.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">An operative connection between the damping piston unit and the tubular holder for the measuring probe can be achieved, for example, in that the tubular holder or a holder extension connected to the tubular holder in an end region has a connecting piece, e.g. a plate with a first passageway, in which the tubular holder is secured, and which has a second passageway opposite the first shifted in a radial direction relevant to the central axis of the assembly device, which coincides with the longitudinal axis of the tubular holder; the damping piston rod or an extension of the damping piston rod is secured in the second passageway. Through the radial offset of the damping piston unit relative to the tubular holder for the measuring probe, the damping piston unit simultaneously acts as a twist preventer for the measuring probe. Since the damping piston unit is tightly held in an end region of said plate and in the damping cylinder at its other end region, a twist of the tubular holder around its rotational axis is suppressed. This is especially advantageous when the measuring probe held in the assembly device is not rotationally symmetric, when thus its orientation relative to the rotational axis of the probe holder plays a role in the quality of the measurement results. This is the case, for example, with ISFET-pH sensors or other semiconductor sensors as well as with rotationally asymmetric optical probes, such as, for example, turbidity sensors or photometric measuring sensors. Especially for the case when one of these measuring probes is arranged in a flowing medium, its orientation relative to the flow direction plays an important role in the quality of the measurement results.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The invention will now be explained in greater detail based on the example of an embodiment shown in the drawing, the figures of which show as follows:</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an assembly device with a measuring probe holder in the maintenance position;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows the assembly device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> with the measuring probe holder in the measuring position;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an enlarged representation of section A of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, in which the process side, end region of the damping piston unit is seen in a stop position in the end region of the damping cylinder facing away from the process;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is an enlarged representation of section B of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, in which the process side, end region of the damping piston unit is seen in a stop position in the process side, end region of the damping piston unit;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an enlarged representation of section C of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, in which the end region of the damping piston unit facing away from the process is seen.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DISCUSSION IN CONJUNCTION WITH THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows an assembly device <b>1</b> with an assembly housing <b>3</b>; the measuring probe (not presented) is located in the maintenance position within a cleaning and calibration chamber within assembly housing <b>3</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows same assembly device <b>1</b> in the measuring position with holder <b>11</b> for the measuring probe (not shown) extended. Calibration or cleaning liquid can be transferred through the input and output <b>5</b> into and back out of the calibration or cleaning chamber.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Assembly device <b>1</b> has a flange as a connection system <b>9</b>; assembly device <b>1</b> can be fixed to a process vessel (not illustrated), a pipe for example, by the flange. Holder <b>11</b> for the measuring probe is secured to a holder extension <b>13</b> by a screwed connection or a bayonet closure (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>), for example. Holder <b>11</b>, as well as holder extension <b>13</b>, are axially, i.e. in the direction of the central axis Z of assembly device <b>1</b>, displaceably guided into assembly housing <b>3</b>. Central axis Z coincides with the longitudinal axis of holder <b>11</b> or holder extension <b>13</b>. The assembly housing <b>3</b>, probe holder <b>11</b> and holder extension <b>13</b> can be constructed in a known manner, such as described, for example, in DE 102006010810 A1, DE 102007035918 B3 or DE 102006022981 A1.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">A damping cylinder <b>15</b>, which can be embodied, for example, as a blind bore in the wall of assembly housing <b>3</b>, is arranged within assembly housing <b>3</b>. A damping piston unit <b>17</b> is applied in damping cylinder <b>15</b> in such a manner that it can execute stroke movements along the central axis M of damping cylinder <b>15</b>. Holder extension <b>13</b> is accommodated in a first passageway <b>21</b> of the plate <b>19</b>. Plate <b>19</b> has a second passageway <b>23</b>, which is shifted in a radial direction relative to the first passageway <b>21</b>, i.e. in a direction perpendicular to central axis Z. Damping piston unit <b>17</b> is secured in this second passageway <b>23</b>. In this manner, an operative connection in the form of a rigid mechanical coupling between holder <b>11</b> for the measuring probe and damping piston unit <b>17</b> results via holder extension <b>13</b>. If holder extension <b>13</b> is shifted, together with holder <b>11</b>, in the direction of central axis Z of assembly device <b>1</b> within assembly housing <b>3</b>, an unavoidable simultaneous movement of damping piston unit <b>17</b> in the same direction, in which holder extension <b>13</b> and, thus, holder <b>11</b> for the measuring probe move, along its central axis M, which is parallel to central axis Z, occurs.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows an enlargement of section A of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows an enlargement of section B of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The end of damping cylinder <b>15</b> facing away from the process as well as the process side region of damping piston unit <b>17</b> with the measuring probe retracted to the maintenance position are shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows the process side end of damping cylinder <b>15</b> as well as the process side region of damping piston unit <b>17</b> abutting the measuring position of the measuring probe on the process side end of damping cylinder <b>15</b>. Damping cylinder <b>15</b> has a fluid filled hollow space, which is sealed fluid tightly against the environment by means of the sealing rings <b>25</b>, <b>27</b> and <b>29</b>. The fluid contained in damping cylinder <b>15</b> cannot escape into the environment. Damping piston unit <b>17</b> comprises a damping piston rod <b>38</b> and a piston <b>36</b> on the process side, end region of the piston rod. Piston <b>36</b> is provided with an annular groove for accommodating the sealing ring <b>25</b>. Sealing ring <b>25</b> lies fluid tightly against the smooth inner wall of damping cylinder <b>15</b>. Piston of damping piston unit <b>17</b> divides, thus, the internal volume of damping cylinder <b>15</b> into a first volume <b>33</b> between the process side cylindrical base surface of damping cylinder and the process side, end face of piston <b>36</b> and into a second volume <b>35</b> on the side of piston <b>36</b> lying opposite, which is bordered by the end of damping cylinder <b>15</b> facing away from the process with seal <b>29</b>, the inner wall of damping cylinder <b>15</b>, the cylinder lateral surface of damping piston rod <b>38</b>, and the rear side of piston <b>36</b> extending radially around damping piston rod <b>38</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Damping piston unit <b>17</b> has a traversing axial bore <b>37</b>, i.e. extending along central axis M of damping piston unit <b>17</b>; a pin <b>41</b> is guided within bore <b>37</b>; pin <b>41</b> transforms into a spindle <b>43</b> of frustoconical geometry in its process side, end region. In the region of piston <b>36</b> of damping piston unit <b>17</b>, axial bore <b>37</b> has a stepped constriction <b>39</b>, i.e. axial bore goes abruptly from a bore section with a first cross section to a second bore section <b>40</b> with a smaller cross section. The frustoconical shaped spindle <b>39</b> protrudes into tapered bore section <b>40</b> of axial bore <b>37</b> in such a manner that only a narrow annular gap remains between step <b>39</b> and the cone wall of the spindle <b>43</b>. On the side of the piston facing away from the process, axial bore <b>37</b> is connected to the second volume <b>35</b> of damping cylinder <b>15</b> by a radial, i.e. extending perpendicularly to central axis M, bore <b>45</b>. Pin <b>41</b> has an annular groove, in which sealing ring <b>31</b> is accommodated, above radial bore <b>45</b>. Sealing ring <b>31</b> lies against the smooth inner wall of axial bore <b>37</b> and so seals the bore interior fluid tightly against the environment.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">With a movement of damping piston unit <b>17</b> in the process side direction, i.e. into damping cylinder <b>15</b>, fluid is squeezed from first volume <b>33</b> and flows into second volume <b>35</b> of damping cylinder <b>15</b> on the side of piston <b>36</b> facing away from the process via axial bore <b>37</b>, via the annular gap formed between stepped constriction <b>39</b> and the conical surface of spindle <b>43</b> and via radial bore <b>45</b>. Due to the small cross section of the annular gap between spindle <b>43</b> and step like constriction <b>39</b>, the fluid opposes the movement of damping piston unit <b>17</b> with a high flow resistance, which brakes the movement of damping piston unit <b>17</b>. With a movement of the damping piston unit in the opposite direction fluid is correspondingly squeezed from second volume <b>35</b> of damping cylinder <b>15</b> into first volume <b>33</b> of damping cylinder <b>15</b> via radial bore <b>45</b>, the annular gap between spindle <b>43</b> and stepped constriction <b>39</b> and via axial bore <b>37</b>. Again, there results a damping of the stroke movement of damping piston unit <b>17</b> due to the high flow resistance, with which the fluid opposes the piston movement due to the annular gap.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The cross section of the annular gap can be varied in the example of an embodiment shown here and selected depending on the viscosity of the fluid and the desired damping intensity.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows an enlargement of section C of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, in which a section of plate <b>19</b> and of damping piston unit <b>17</b> secured therein, is presented. Pin <b>41</b> guided within damping piston rod <b>38</b> is accommodated in a pin extension <b>47</b> on its end facing away from the process. Pin extension <b>47</b> is provided with a knurled nut <b>49</b> on its end facing away from the process. Pin extension <b>47</b> has, moreover, an external thread <b>51</b>, which interacts with an internal thread <b>53</b> of damping piston rod <b>38</b>. By rotating knurled nut <b>49</b>, pin extension <b>43</b> can correspondingly be rotated out from damping piston rod <b>38</b> or rotated into damping piston rod <b>38</b>. This effects an axial movement of pin <b>41</b> into axial bore <b>37</b>, i.e. a movement in the process side direction or a movement out from axial bore <b>37</b>, i.e. a movement in a direction facing away from the process. Correspondingly, the distance between the conical surface of spindle <b>43</b> and step like constriction <b>39</b> decreases in a movement of pin <b>41</b> into the axial bore or increases in a movement out from the axial bore. The cross section of the annular gap between spindle <b>43</b> and stepped constriction <b>39</b> correspondingly lessens with a decreasing separation; the cross section of the annular gap correspondingly enlarges with an increase in the separation. In this way, the strength of the flow resistance, which counteracts a movement of damping piston unit <b>17</b> within damping cylinder <b>15</b>, can be set.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Many liquids and gases are suitable as the fluid, in principle. In the simplest case, air from the environment under atmospheric conditions is enclosed in the construction of the damping cylinder and the damping piston unit. However, a damping liquid can equally be enclosed in the damping cylinder during manufacture.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An assembly device, for a measuring probe for measuring process variables in a process, comprising:
<claim-text>an assembly device housing with a connection system for connecting the assembly device to a process container;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a tubular holder for a measuring probe, wherein said tubular holder is guided in said assembly device housing axially displaceably between a measuring position in the process container and a maintenance position outside of the process container; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a damping system to damp axial shifting of said tubular holder, wherein:</claim-text>
<claim-text>said damping system comprises a fluid filled, damping cylinder within said assembly device housing, and a damping piston unit guided within said damping cylinder in operative connection with said tubular holder.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The assembly device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>shifting of said tubular holder simultaneously effects shifting of said damping piston unit within said damping cylinder through the operative connection between said tubular holder and said damping piston unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The assembly device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said damping piston unit has a fluid passageway, which connects a first volume of said damping cylinder to a second volume of said damping cylinder.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The assembly device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the cross section of said fluid passageway is adjustable by means of a valve element in order to set the amount of fluid flow from said first volume to said second volume.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The assembly device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said valve element comprises an at least sectionally continuously tapering spindle, wherein said fluid passageway comprises a bore section of a bore extending axially within said damping piston unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said spindle protrudes into said bore section and closes this except for an annular opening in said fluid passageway; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the cross section of said annular opening is adjustable by shifting said spindle into said bore section or out from said bore section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The assembly device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said damping piston unit comprises a damping piston rod;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said spindle is placed on an end of a guided pin in said axial bore within said damping piston rod; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said pin or a pin extension has a first screw thread, which interacts with a second screw thread, complementary to the first screw thread, of said damping piston rod.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The assembly device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said first volume of said damping cylinder is connected to said second volume of said damping cylinder via said axial bore within said damping piston rod and via a radial bore, which has a first exit into said axial bore and a second exit into said second volume of said damping cylinder, therefore defining said fluid passageway.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The assembly device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said tubular holder or a holder extension connected to said tubular holder is secured in a first passageway of a connecting piece; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said connecting piece has a second passageway shifted relative to the first passageway in a radial direction relative to the longitudinal axis of said tubular holder and said damping piston rod or an extension of said damping piston rod is secured in said second passageway.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
