<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624130-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624130</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13140091</doc-number>
<date>20091130</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10 2008 062 516</doc-number>
<date>20081216</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>229</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>11</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>H</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>0278</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>174261</main-classification>
<further-classification>174262</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Circuit board having grown metal layer in a flexible zone</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4604799</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Gurol</name>
<date>19860800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 29847</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0116932</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Van Der Tempel</name>
<date>20070500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0277998</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Suzuki et al.</name>
<date>20071200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0281499</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Muro et al.</name>
<date>20071200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0093110</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Bagung</name>
<date>20080400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>174254</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0186247</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Cotte et al.</name>
<date>20080800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>343841</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>44 05 228</doc-number>
<kind>C1</kind>
<date>19950700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>102005012404</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20060900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2005236205</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20050900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006015602</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20060100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>2005/033787</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20050400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>2007/064138</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20070600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>10</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>174254</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>174261</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>174262</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257777</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257778</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257783</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 29852</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-cpc-text>H05K 1/0278</classification-cpc-text>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110284275</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20111124</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bagung</last-name>
<first-name>Detlev</first-name>
<address>
<city>Bernhardswald</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bagung</last-name>
<first-name>Detlev</first-name>
<address>
<city>Bernhardswald</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Greenberg</last-name>
<first-name>Laurence A.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Stemer</last-name>
<first-name>Werner H.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="03" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Locher</last-name>
<first-name>Ralph E.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Continental Automotive GmbH</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Hannover</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Semenenko</last-name>
<first-name>Yuriy</first-name>
<department>2835</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/EP2009/066054</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20091130</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20110712</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2010/072516</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20100701</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A circuit board has a grown metal layer in a flexible zone. A circuit board has a first part, a second part and a recess in the circuit board that is arranged between the first part and the second part. A thickness of the circuit board reduced in the region of the recess. The first part can be pivoted relative to the second part as a result of the recess. The flexibility of the circuit board is improved in the range of the recess by a metal layer applied on a surface section of the circuit board in the recess by deposition. Furthermore, EMC problems can be reduced by the metal layer on a side wall of the recess and electrical contacts to conductor path metallization layers can be created.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="87.21mm" wi="162.56mm" file="US08624130-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="253.07mm" wi="176.70mm" file="US08624130-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="267.72mm" wi="159.26mm" file="US08624130-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The invention relates to a circuit board, and to a method for producing a circuit board.</p>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">DE 10 2005 102 404 B4 discloses a circuit board having a first, a second and a third rigid region and a first and a second flexible region. The flexible regions are made thinner than the rigid regions perpendicularly to the sides of the circuit board, wherein the flexible regions are formed by depth milling of the circuit board. The flexible region comprises a layer for conductor tracks, a protective layer above the layer for conductor tracks, and a residual layer of circuit board material on a side of the layer for conductor tracks which is opposite to the protective layer.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The flexibility of the flexible region is restricted by the circuit board material conventionally used.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">WO 2007/064138 A1 discloses a circuit board having a first and a second part, wherein a depression is arranged between the first and second parts. A metal layer is applied on the surface of the circuit board by means of a sputtering process.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">DE 44 05 228 C1 and WO 2005/033787 A1 likewise disclose circuit boards having a plurality of sections, wherein at least one section has a depression.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The invention is based on the object of providing a circuit board and a method for producing said circuit board, wherein the circuit board has improved characteristics.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">This object is achieved by means of the subjects of the independent patent claims. Advantageous embodiments of the present invention are described in the dependent claims.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In accordance with a first aspect of the subjects disclosed herein, a circuit board is provided, which has a first part, a second part and a depression, wherein the depression is arranged between the first part and the second part and reduces a thickness of the circuit board in the region of the depression, and wherein, on account of the depression, the first part is pivotable relative to the second part. A grown metal layer is arranged on a surface section of the circuit board in the depression. The first and second parts thus defined are also designated as rigid regions, while the region of the depression is also designated as flexible region.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In accordance with the first aspect, the metal layer is applied by being grown onto the surface section of the circuit board in the depression. In this case, the growth can be effected by any suitable method, e.g. by growth from a solution, for example electroless or electrical plating, chemical deposition, vapor deposition, cathode sputtering, etc. It goes without saying that the metal layer, in addition to the surface section mentioned, can also be grown onto regions outside the depression. In accordance with one embodiment for depositing the metal layer, the entire circuit board is dipped into a corresponding solution, as a result of which, depending on the method, the metal layer is deposited on the entire surface of the circuit board or on electrically biased surface sections of the circuit board. The circuit board has at least one contact hole in the circuit board, e.g. in the first or the second part. A metal layer is arranged in the contact hole, wherein the metal layer in the at least one contact hole and the metal layer on the surface section in the depression are formed from the same material.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In accordance with one embodiment, a contact hole is formed in at least one of the two parts of the circuit board. By way of example, the circuit board can have at least two electrical conductors which are arranged at a distance from one another in a direction perpendicular to a board plane of the relevant part, wherein the metal layer in the at least one contact hole electrically conductively connects the at least two electrical conductors.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In accordance with a further embodiment, the circuit board has an insulation layer composed of an electrically insulating material. By way of example, the insulation layer can be formed from FR4 material. In accordance with a further embodiment, the depression extends into the insulation layer and insulating material of the insulation layer extends below the depression between the first part and the second part. In other words, the depression does not extend completely through the insulation layer, but rather only into a specific depth into the insulation layer. In accordance with one embodiment, the insulating material below the depression can form at least one part of the surface section in the depression on which the metal layer is grown.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In accordance with one embodiment, the metal layer covers a bottom of the depression. Furthermore, the metal layer can also cover a part or the entirety of the side walls of the depression.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The metal layer grown on the bottom of the depression improves the flexibility of the circuit board in the region of the depression, that is to say in the flexible region. This is possibly attributable to a good covering of cracks and fractures by the metal layer. Furthermore, fracture of fibers in or near the surface of the circuit board is evidently reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Furthermore, by growing the metal layer on a surface section of a side wall of the depression, it is possible to reduce problems of electromagnetic compatibility (EMC problems) or to improve the EMC. Furthermore, by growing the metal layer on a surface section of a side wall, it is possible to produce electrical contacts to conductor track metallization layers.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In one embodiment, the metal layer is formed from copper. In accordance with a further embodiment, the metal layer contains copper.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In accordance with a further embodiment, a covering layer for covering the metal layer is arranged above the metal layer.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In accordance with a second aspect of the subjects disclosed herein, a method for producing a circuit board is provided, said method comprising: (i) producing a depression in a circuit board and thereby defining a first part and a second part of the circuit board, wherein, on account of the depression, the first part is pivotable relative to the second part, and (ii) growing a metal layer in the depression. Furthermore, the method comprises producing at least one contact hole in the circuit board, wherein applying the metal layer into the depression and into the at least one contact hole is effected simultaneously by the same process sequence. In this case, applying the metal layer can consist of a single process step, or can consist of a plurality of steps, for example, as explained above, applying an electrically conductive layer that is subsequently plated. Additionally or alternatively, the process sequence can comprise e.g. applying adhesion promoting layers, seed layers, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In accordance with one embodiment of the method, a starting circuit board, in which the depression is produced, can already have a preliminary stage of the depression, e.g. a premilled portion. In accordance with a further embodiment, in the premilled portion it is possible to arrange a circuit board element, for example a conductor track metallization layer, which is then removed by step (i), that is to say by producing the depression in the region of the depression.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">One embodiment of the method in accordance with a second aspect furthermore comprises applying an electrically conductive layer to the surface section in the depression, wherein growing the metal layer comprises plating the electrically conductive layer.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In a further embodiment of the method in accordance with the second aspect, prior to growing the metal layer, the circuit board has, on at least one of the first part and the second part, an outer conductor track metallization layer. The conductor track metallization layer can be, for example, a film applied on an insulation layer of the circuit board. The conductor track metallization layer can already be patterned before the growth of the metal layer in the depression. Alternatively, the conductor track metallization layer can be unpatterned upon the growth of the metal layer in the depression. In accordance with a further embodiment, the circuit board already has the outer conductor track metallization layer before the depression is produced.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In accordance with a further embodiment, the conductor track metallization layer is arranged on a first side of the circuit board and the depression is likewise arranged on the first side of the circuit board, that is to say that the conductor track metallization layer and the depression are arranged on the same side of the circuit board.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In accordance with a further embodiment, the depression in the circuit board is produced by mechanical processing, e.g. by milling, grinding, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Further advantages and features of the present invention will become apparent from the following exemplary description of currently preferred embodiments. The individual figures of the drawings of this application should be regarded merely as schematic and as not true to scale.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a sectional view of a circuit board in a first production stage.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a sectional view of the circuit board from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in a further advanced production stage in accordance with illustrative embodiments of the subjects disclosed herein.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows the circuit board from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> in a first bending state.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows the circuit board from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> in a second bending state.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows a sectional view of a circuit board in accordance with illustrative embodiments of the subjects disclosed herein.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In the drawings, identical, functionally identical or mutually corresponding components and features are provided with the same reference symbols, or with reference symbols which differ from one another in their first digit or an appended letter, and are not explained in detail again.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a sectional illustration of a circuit board <b>100</b> in a first production stage in accordance with illustrative embodiments of the subjects disclosed herein. The circuit board <b>100</b> herein has an insulation layer <b>102</b> composed of an electrically insulating material. A typical material for the electrically insulating material is a composite composed of fibers and a binder such as, for example, resin, for example glass fibers and resin, such as FR4. In accordance with an embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the insulation layer <b>102</b> is formed as a circuit board core. On a top side <b>104</b> of the circuit board <b>100</b>, there is arranged on the insulation layer <b>102</b> an inner upper conductor track metallization layer <b>106</b><i>a</i>, thereon an upper insulation layer <b>108</b><i>a </i>and thereon in turn an outer upper conductor track metallization layer <b>106</b><i>b</i>. In accordance with one embodiment, the conductor track metallization layers <b>106</b><i>a</i>, <b>106</b><i>b </i>are formed from metal films, for example copper films, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. In accordance with one embodiment, the upper insulation layer <b>108</b><i>a </i>between the upper conductor track metallization layers <b>106</b><i>a </i>and <b>106</b><i>b </i>is a prepreg (preimpregnated fiber) layer. An underside <b>110</b> of the circuit board <b>100</b> is constructed analogously to the top side <b>104</b> and comprises on the insulation layer <b>102</b> an inner lower conductor track metallization layer <b>106</b><i>c</i>, thereon a lower insulation layer <b>108</b><i>b </i>and thereon in turn an outer lower conductor track metallization layer <b>106</b><i>d</i>. The designations &#x201c;upper&#x201d; and &#x201c;lower&#x201d; serve here merely for explanation with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and should not be interpreted as restrictive in any regard whatsoever.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In accordance with one embodiment, the circuit board <b>100</b> in the first production stage, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, forms the basis for further production steps in accordance with the subjects disclosed herein.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a sectional illustration of the circuit board <b>100</b> in a further advanced production stage in accordance with illustrative embodiments of the subjects disclosed herein. In the production stage illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a depression <b>112</b> is formed in the circuit board <b>100</b>, for example by depth milling known per se.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The depression <b>112</b> defines two parts of the circuit board, a first part <b>113</b><i>a </i>and a second part <b>113</b><i>b </i>on both sides of the depression. The depression <b>112</b> reduces the thickness of the circuit board <b>100</b> to a value d, as a result of which a flexible region of the circuit board <b>100</b> is formed in the region of the depression <b>112</b>, such that the first part <b>113</b><i>a </i>is pivotable relative to the second part <b>113</b><i>b</i>. It goes without saying that the circuit board in accordance with other embodiments can have two or more depressions and hence two or more flexible regions. In this way it is possible to realize virtually any desired and very complex geometries with the circuit board.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In the circuit board <b>100</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, contact holes <b>114</b><i>a</i>, <b>114</b><i>b </i>were furthermore formed. In accordance with one embodiment, a (first) contact hole <b>114</b><i>a </i>is embodied as a blind hole that does not completely penetrate through the circuit board <b>100</b>. In accordance with a further embodiment, a (second) contact hole <b>114</b><i>b </i>is embodied as a through-hole. In accordance with one embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the circuit board has two electrical conductors, namely the upper conductor track metallization layers <b>106</b><i>a </i>and <b>106</b><i>b</i>, which are arranged at a distance from one another in a direction perpendicular to a board plane of the relevant first part <b>113</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In accordance with a further embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the circuit board has four electrical conductors, namely the upper and lower conductor track metallization layers <b>106</b><i>a</i>, <b>106</b><i>b</i>, <b>106</b><i>c</i>, <b>106</b><i>d</i>, which are arranged at a distance from one another in a direction perpendicular to a board plane of the relevant first part <b>113</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In accordance with one embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the metal layer <b>116</b> also covers that side <b>110</b> of the circuit board <b>100</b> which is remote from the depression, in the present case the outer conductor track metallization layer <b>106</b><i>d</i>. This can occur during electroless plating, for example, if the circuit board <b>100</b> is completely immersed in the plating solution. In accordance with another embodiment, the surfaces or surface sections of the circuit board <b>100</b>, at least the surfaces or the surface section <b>118</b> in the depression <b>112</b>, are selectively coated with the metal layer <b>116</b>, for example by electroplating.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In accordance with a further embodiment, the surface section <b>118</b> forming the depression <b>112</b> is covered with a metal layer by the metal layer being grown on the surface section <b>118</b>. In accordance with one embodiment, the metal layer <b>116</b> on the surface section in the depression <b>112</b> is the same metal layer <b>116</b> that is also formed in the contact holes <b>114</b><i>a</i>, <b>114</b><i>b </i>for making electrical contact with the relevant electrical conductors <b>106</b><i>a</i>, <b>106</b><i>b</i>, <b>106</b><i>c</i>, <b>106</b><i>d</i>, that is to say that the metal layer <b>116</b> in the contact holes and the metal layer <b>116</b> in the depression <b>112</b> are produced by means of the same process sequence. The thickness of the metal layer in the depression can assume, for example, a value of between 10 micrometers (&#x3bc;m) and 80 micrometers or, in accordance with another embodiment, a value of between 25 micrometers and 50 micrometers. Depending on the growth method, the layer thickness can be smaller in the contact hole than in the depression.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In accordance with one embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the metal layer <b>116</b> also covers that side <b>110</b> of the circuit board <b>100</b> which is remote from the depression, in the present case the outer conductor track metallization layer <b>106</b><i>d</i>. This can occur during electroless plating, for example, if the circuit board <b>100</b> is completely immersed in the plating solution. In accordance with another embodiment, surface sections of the circuit board <b>100</b>, at least the surface section <b>118</b> in the depression <b>112</b>, are selectively coated with the metal layer <b>116</b>, for example by electroplating.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In accordance with one embodiment, the depression <b>112</b> extends into an insulation layer, in the present case the insulation layer <b>102</b>, wherein insulation material of the insulation layer <b>102</b> remains in a region <b>120</b> below the depression <b>112</b>. This has the advantage that the inner lower conductor track <b>106</b><i>c </i>is insulated from the metal layer <b>116</b> without further measures.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a part (without contact holes <b>114</b><i>a</i>, <b>114</b><i>b</i>) of the sectional view of the circuit board <b>100</b> from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> in a bent state in which the first part <b>113</b><i>a </i>is pivoted relative to the second part <b>113</b><i>b </i>into a first pivoted position, wherein the top sides <b>104</b> of the two parts <b>113</b><i>a</i>, <b>113</b><i>b </i>are pivoted toward one another. In accordance with one embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a bottom <b>115</b> of the depression <b>112</b> is concavely flexible or bent.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a part (without contact holes <b>114</b><i>a</i>, <b>114</b><i>b</i>) of the sectional view of the circuit board <b>100</b> from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> in a bent state in which the first part <b>113</b><i>a </i>is pivoted relative to the second part <b>113</b><i>b </i>into a second pivoted position, wherein the undersides <b>110</b> of the two parts <b>113</b><i>a</i>, <b>113</b><i>b </i>are pivoted toward one another. In accordance with one embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the bottom <b>115</b> of the depression <b>112</b> is convexly flexible or bent.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In accordance with one embodiment, the conductor track metallization layers lie on an outer side of the bending radius (as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>). The metal layer <b>116</b> surprisingly improves the flexibility in this case. Opposite bending (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) can give rise to the risk of fracture as a result of the spreading of milled glass node points. This risk of fracture is eliminated or at least reduced by the metal layer <b>112</b> in the depression. By virtue of the metal layer <b>116</b> in the depression <b>112</b>, it is therefore also possible to effect bending in the other direction, such that the conductor track metallization layers lie on an inner side of the bending radius, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Consequently, the flexibility of the bottom <b>115</b> of the depression <b>112</b> is improved by the metal layer <b>116</b> on the bottom <b>115</b>. In accordance with one embodiment, therefore, at least the bottom <b>115</b> of the depression is covered with the metal layer <b>116</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In accordance with a further embodiment, at least one wall section <b>117</b> of the depression, that is to say a surface or surface section extending transversely with respect to a board plane or an edge of the depression <b>112</b>, is covered with the metal layer. This has the advantage of improved EMC protection. Furthermore, the metal layer <b>112</b> on the at least one wall section <b>117</b> can serve as an electrical contact, e.g. as an electrical ground link. For this purpose, a side wall of the depression can be completely or partly covered with the metal layer. A complete covering has the advantage that the entire circuit board can be processed without the metal layer <b>116</b> having to be deposited selectively on the at least one wall section <b>117</b>. In this case, in particular, the metal layer in the depression and the metal layer in the contact holes are produced together, that is to say by means of the same process sequence.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In accordance with one embodiment, the metal layer <b>116</b> on a wall section <b>117</b> of the depression <b>112</b> can make electrical contact with one or more conductor track metallization layers, e.g. outer conductor track metallization layers <b>106</b><i>b </i>and/or inner conductor track metallization layers <b>106</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">It goes without saying that the conductor track metallization layers <b>106</b><i>a</i>, <b>106</b><i>b</i>, <b>106</b><i>c</i>, <b>106</b><i>d </i>and, in particular, also the outer conductor track metallization layers <b>106</b><i>b</i>, <b>106</b><i>d </i>and the metal layer <b>116</b> possibly deposited thereon have been or are suitably patterned in accordance with the desired electrical connections to be produced. By way of example, for a corresponding electrical interconnection to the metal layer <b>116</b> on the wall section <b>117</b>, the outer upper conductor track metallization layer <b>106</b><i>b </i>and the metal layer <b>116</b> can be suitably patterned by patterning methods known per se (not illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>). In accordance with one embodiment, the metal layer (<b>116</b>) can be patterned not only in the region of the conductor track metallization layers <b>106</b><i>b</i>, <b>106</b><i>d</i>, but also in the depression (<b>112</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">By way of example, in accordance with one embodiment, inner conductor track metallization layers <b>106</b><i>a</i>, <b>106</b><i>c </i>are patterned before the insulation layer <b>108</b><i>a</i>, <b>108</b><i>b </i>and subsequent conductor track metallization layers <b>106</b><i>b</i>, <b>106</b><i>d </i>are arranged on the inner conductor track metallization layers.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In accordance with one embodiment, the outer conductor track metallization layers <b>106</b><i>b</i>, <b>106</b><i>d </i>are patterned only after the application of the metal layer <b>116</b>, and hence together with the metal layer <b>116</b>. In accordance with one embodiment, the outer conductor track metallization layers <b>106</b><i>b</i>, <b>106</b><i>d </i>are patterned before the metal layer <b>116</b> is deposited. The deposition, that is to say the growth of the metal layer <b>116</b>, can in this case be effected efficiently by electrical plating, for example, such that the metal layer <b>116</b> is deposited selectively only on the remaining sections of the conductor track metallization layer and on the correspondingly prepared surface section <b>118</b> of the depression <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The remaining reference numerals presented in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> and in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> designate the same features as the corresponding reference numerals in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, and the description of these features will not be repeated here.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Protective layers such as soldering resist, for example, are not illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. However, the person skilled in the art recognizes that one or a plurality of such layers can be applied on the circuit board, in particular on the metal layer (<b>116</b>), without departing from the principles of the subjects disclosed herein.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows, in a sectional illustration, a part of a circuit board <b>200</b> in a depression <b>212</b>, which, apart from the difference explained below, is embodied identically to the depression <b>112</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the details of which will not be repeated here.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">While in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> the metal layer was grown directly on the insulation layer <b>102</b> by a suitable method, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows an embodiment in which firstly a preliminary layer <b>222</b> was applied to a surface section <b>218</b> of the insulation layer <b>202</b> in the depression <b>212</b>, which supports the growth of the metal layer <b>216</b>. By way of example, the preliminary layer <b>222</b> can be an adhesion promoting layer. In accordance with a further embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the preliminary layer is an electrically conductive layer that enables the metal layer <b>216</b> to be grown by electrical plating (electroplating). It goes without saying that, in embodiments in which the metal layer <b>216</b> also covers contact holes (not illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>), the contact holes can also have the preliminary layer <b>222</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Depending on its composition, the preliminary layer <b>222</b> is applied by suitable methods known to those skilled in the art, for example by chemical deposition.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Furthermore in contrast to the circuit board <b>100</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the circuit board illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, in accordance with one embodiment, has at least one covering layer <b>224</b> above the metal layer <b>216</b>. The covering layer <b>224</b> is illustrated only in the region of the depression <b>212</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. It goes without saying that the covering layer can be applied on the entire circuit board or, in accordance with another embodiment, can be applied merely in partial regions of the circuit board. The covering layer <b>224</b> can be designed, for example, to protect the metal layer <b>216</b> against corrosion. In accordance with other embodiments, the covering layer can be any other suitable layer, for example a metallic or organic layer. In particular, the covering layer <b>224</b> can be a layer that fulfils a specific function, for example an Ni/Au layer, a soldering resist or OSP.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Embodiments of the subjects disclosed herein make it possible, through the metal layer <b>116</b> in the depression <b>112</b>, to bend the circuit board <b>100</b> in both directions, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, or to increase the bending angle.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">It is pointed out that the embodiments described here merely constitute a limited selection of possible embodiment variants of the invention. Thus, it is possible to combine the features of individual embodiments with one another in a suitable manner, such that, with the embodiment variants explicit here, a multiplicity of different embodiments should be regarded as being disclosed in an obvious manner to the person skilled in the art. Furthermore, the features illustrated in the drawings should be understood merely by way of example for elucidating principles and advantages of the subjects disclosed herein. Thus, by way of example, a circuit board can have more or fewer conductor track metallization layers than illustrated in the drawings. Furthermore, by way of example, the circuit board in which the depression is formed, in a departure from exemplary embodiments disclosed herein, can be formed in any manner desired. Furthermore, it should be mentioned that terms such as &#x201c;one&#x201d; or &#x201c;a&#x201d; do not preclude a plurality. Terms such as &#x201c;containing&#x201d; or &#x201c;having&#x201d; do not preclude further features or method steps.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">To summarize, it should be emphasized that:</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">A circuit board contains a first part, a second part and a depression in the circuit board, which is arranged between the first part and the second part and reduces a thickness of the circuit board in the region of the depression, wherein, on account of the depression, the first part is pivotable relative to the second part. A metal layer applied on a surface section of the circuit board in the depression by growth improves the flexibility of the circuit board in the region of the depression. Furthermore, the metal layer on a side wall of the depression makes it possible to reduce EMC problems and to produce electrical contacts to conductor track metallization layers.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A circuit board, comprising: a first part; a second part; a depression in the circuit board formed between said first part and said second part, said depression reducing a thickness of the circuit board in a region of said depression, and rendering said first part pivotable relative to said second part; a metal layer grown on a surface of the circuit board in said depression; the circuit board having at least one contact hole formed therein; a metal layer in said at least one contact hole; wherein said metal layer in said at least one contact hole and said metal layer on the surface in said depression are formed from a common material,
<claim-text>wherein: said metal layer in said at least one contact hole and said metal layer on the surface in said depression are electrically conductively connected.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The circuit board according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the circuit board further comprises an insulation layer composed of an electrically insulating material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said depression extends into said insulation layer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an insulating material of said insulation layer extends below the depression between said first part and said second part and forms at least one part of the surface in said depression on which said metal layer is grown.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The circuit board according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said metal layer on the surface in said depression covers a bottom of said depression.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The circuit board according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein said metal layer on the surface in said depression further covers side walls of said depression.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The circuit board according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said metal layer on the surface in said depression consists of copper.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The circuit board according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said metal layer on the surface in said depression contains copper.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A method of producing a circuit board, the method which comprises: forming a depression in a circuit board to thereby define a first part of the circuit board and a second part of the circuit board, wherein, on account of the depression the first part is pivotable relative to the second part; forming at least one contact hole in the circuit board; and growing a metal layer in the depression and applying a metal layer in the at least one contact hole in one and the same process sequence,
<claim-text>which comprises: performing the step of growing the metal layer in the depression and applying the metal layer in the at least one contact hole such that the metal layer in the depression and the metal layer in the at least one contact hole are electrically conductively connected.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, which comprises:
<claim-text>applying an electrically conductive layer to a surface in the depression; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein growing the metal layer comprises plating the electrically conductive layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>prior to growing the metal layer, the circuit board has, on at least one of the first part and the second part, an outer conductor track metallization layer on the circuit board; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the outer conductor track metallization layer is disposed on a first side of the circuit board and the depression is likewise disposed on the first side of the circuit board.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the step of forming the depression in the circuit board comprises producing the depression by mechanical processing. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
