<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622758-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622758</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13556362</doc-number>
<date>20120724</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2012 2 0083223 U</doc-number>
<date>20120307</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>44</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439131</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e61">Rotatable plug and power supply device having the rotatable plug</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5494449</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Chioo</name>
<date>19960200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439 761</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5628641</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hahn</name>
<date>19970500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439131</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6275002</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Chen</name>
<date>20010800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>320111</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7001196</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Huang</name>
<date>20060200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439320</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>15</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439131</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>14</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>20</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130237073</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130912</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hsu</last-name>
<first-name>Chia-Tsang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chu</last-name>
<first-name>Chien-Hua</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hsu</last-name>
<first-name>Chia-Tsang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chu</last-name>
<first-name>Chien-Hua</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Rosenberg, Klein &#x26; Lee</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Lite-On Electronics (Guangzhou) Limited</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Guangzhou</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Lite-On Technology Corp.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Harvey</last-name>
<first-name>James</first-name>
<department>2833</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A rotatable plug includes a casing unit having a first casing part and a second casing part with a pair of receiving spaces, a pair of conductive terminals respectively having conductive sections, and a rotatable unit including a pivot shaft, a pair of conductive prongs connected transversely to the pivot shaft, and a pair of conductive protrusions protruding out from the pivot shaft. The rotatable unit is rotatable relative to the casing unit between non-use and use positions, where the conductive prongs are accommodated in and extend out of the receiving spaces, respectively. Each conductive protrusion has at least two points of contact with the conductive section of a respective conductive terminal.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="109.90mm" wi="66.63mm" file="US08622758-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="199.31mm" wi="182.03mm" file="US08622758-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="131.40mm" wi="124.97mm" file="US08622758-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="161.46mm" wi="99.31mm" file="US08622758-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="250.53mm" wi="180.68mm" file="US08622758-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="227.50mm" wi="128.78mm" file="US08622758-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="223.69mm" wi="108.97mm" file="US08622758-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="228.09mm" wi="106.34mm" file="US08622758-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="245.45mm" wi="153.16mm" file="US08622758-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="234.53mm" wi="124.29mm" file="US08622758-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="123.44mm" wi="68.24mm" file="US08622758-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="214.71mm" wi="80.77mm" file="US08622758-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="164.68mm" wi="167.89mm" file="US08622758-20140107-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="173.06mm" wi="171.11mm" file="US08622758-20140107-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00014" num="00014">
<img id="EMI-D00014" he="164.68mm" wi="171.70mm" file="US08622758-20140107-D00014.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority to Chinese Patent Application No. 201220083223.5, filed on Mar. 7, 2012.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The invention relates to a rotatable plug, more particularly to a rotatable plug that can be stored conveniently when not in use and a power supply device having the rotatable plug.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">A plug of a conventional power supply device includes a plug body and two conductive terminals protruding outwardly from the plug body. When the power supply device is not in use, because the conductive terminals protrude from the plug body, they are likely to be hit by an external force that may result in the bending and even breakage thereof. Further, it is difficult to store the conventional power supply device. Therefore, devices with rotatable plugs have been currently developed to resolve the aforesaid issues.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>2</b> and <b>3</b>, a conventional power supply device having a rotatable plug includes a housing <b>11</b>, a rotatable plug <b>12</b> and a fixing element <b>13</b>. The housing <b>11</b> includes a housing body <b>111</b>, a holding seat <b>112</b> formed on an end of the housing body <b>111</b>, and a receiving hole <b>113</b> extending through the holding seat <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The rotatable plug <b>12</b> includes a rotating support body <b>121</b> inserted into the receiving hole <b>113</b>, two conductive prongs <b>122</b> fixed on the rotating support body <b>121</b>, two metal pivot studs <b>123</b> protruding outwardly and respectively from two opposite ends of the rotating support body <b>121</b>, two conductive plates <b>124</b> respectively pivoted to the pivot studs <b>123</b>, and three projections <b>125</b>, <b>126</b> projecting from the rotating support body <b>121</b> opposite to the conductive prongs <b>122</b>. Two conductive wires (not shown) may be respectively inserted through the conductive plates <b>124</b> to connect electrically with a circuit board (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The fixing element <b>13</b> fixes the rotatable plug <b>12</b> to the holding seat <b>112</b>, and includes a fixing main body <b>131</b>, two stop bosses <b>132</b> disposed on one side of the fixing main body <b>131</b> and extending towards the housing body <b>111</b>, a stepped portion formed in the middle of the fixing main body <b>131</b> and having a first part <b>133</b> and a second part <b>134</b>, and two spaced-apart slots <b>135</b> formed in the fixing main body <b>131</b>. The conductive plates <b>124</b> extend respectively through the slots <b>135</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The housing <b>11</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) is removed in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref> to facilitate description of the rotating mechanism of the rotatable plug <b>12</b>. With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, when the conductive prongs <b>122</b> of the rotatable plug <b>12</b> are in a use or extended position, the projection <b>125</b> abuts against the first and second parts <b>133</b>, <b>134</b> of the stepped portion and is positioned thereat. When a force is applied on the conductive prongs <b>122</b> to rotate the same in a direction of an arrow (R<b>1</b>), through the resiliency of the stepped portion, the projection <b>125</b> can slide over the second part <b>134</b>. As such, the conductive prongs <b>122</b> can drive the rotating support body <b>121</b> to rotate relative to the holding seat (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the projection <b>126</b> is blocked by the stop boss <b>132</b> and is positioned thereat. At this state, the conductive prongs <b>122</b> are disposed in a non-use or folded position. By applying a force again on the conductive prongs <b>122</b> to rotate the same in a direction of an arrow (R<b>2</b>), the conductive prongs <b>122</b> are restored to their use position.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">However, the above-mentioned device is not modular so that a new mold must be opened in respond to different sizes of housing <b>11</b>. Moreover, three projections <b>125</b>, <b>126</b> are needed to position the rotatable plug <b>12</b> in the use and non-use positions. Finally, because the rotatable plug <b>12</b> is connected to the fixing element <b>13</b> through insertion of the conductive plates <b>124</b> into the slots <b>135</b>, the conductive plates <b>124</b> are likely to separate from the fixing element <b>13</b> due to frequent use which may cause poor electrical contact.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Therefore, an object of the present invention is to provide a rotatable plug that can provide a stable and reliable electrical connection.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Another object of the present invention is to provide a power supply device having a rotatable plug that can provide a stable and reliable electrical connection.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to one aspect of this invention, a rotatable plug comprises a casing unit, a pair of conductive terminals and a rotatable unit.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The casing unit includes a first casing part, and a second casing part connected to the first casing part and formed with a pair of receiving spaces. The conductive terminals are insert molded into the first casing part. Each of the conductive terminals has a conductive section. The rotatable unit includes a pivot shaft, a pair of conductive prongs connected to and extending transversely from the pivot shaft, and a pair of conductive protrusions protruding out from the pivot shaft. The rotatable unit is disposed in the casing unit and is rotatable relative to the casing unit between a non-use and folded position, where the conductive prongs are respectively accommodated in the receiving spaces, and a use or extended position, where the conductive prongs respectively extend out of the receiving spaces. Each of the conductive protrusions is disposed on and has at least two points of contact with the conductive section of a respective one of the conductive terminals when the rotatable unit is in the use position.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Preferably, the conductive section of each of the conductive terminals has a depressed contact surface.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Each of the conductive protrusions has the at least two points of contact with the depressed contact surface.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Preferably, the first casing part includes a pair of first support posts each having a slotted surface. Each of the conductive terminals further has a conductive end protruding from the slotted surface. The pivot shaft includes two outer conductive shaft sections respectively connected to the prongs, and an insulated middle shaft section between the outer conductive shaft sections. The outer conductive shaft sections are respectively in contact with the conductive ends of the conductive terminals when the rotatable unit is in the use and non-use positions.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Preferably, the first casing part includes a pair of second support posts supporting the pivot shaft.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Preferably, the first casing part has a positioning portion formed with a positioning groove. The rotatable unit further includes a first protuberance and a second protuberance protruding from the pivot shaft between the conductive protrusions and perpendicular to each other. The first protuberance is positioned in the positioning groove when in the non-use position, and the second protuberance is positioned in the positioning groove when in the use position.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Preferably, each of the conductive terminals further has a conductive extension disposed externally of the casing unit.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Preferably, the conductive extensions of the conductive terminals have different lengths.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">According to another aspect of this invention, a power supply device comprises a housing unit, a circuit unit and a rotatable plug.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The housing unit includes a first housing element having two parallel slots, and a second housing element connected to and cooperating with the first housing element to define a chamber. The circuit unit is disposed in the chamber. The rotatable plug is disposed in the chamber and includes a casing unit, a pair of conductive terminals and a rotatable unit.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The casing unit includes a first casing part, and a second casing part connected to the first casing part and formed with a pair of receiving spaces. The conductive terminals are insert molded into the first casing part and are connected electrically to the circuit unit. Each of the conductive terminals has a conductive section. The rotatable unit includes a pivot shaft, a pair of conductive prongs connected transversely to the pivot shaft, and a pair of conductive protrusions protruding out from the pivot shaft. The rotatable unit is disposed in the casing unit and is rotatable relative to the casing unit between a non-use or folded position, where the conductive prongs are respectively accommodated in the receiving spaces and the slots, and a use or extended position, where the conductive prongs respectively extend out of the receiving spaces and the slots. Each of the conductive protrusions is disposed on and has at least two points of contact with the conductive section of a respective one of the conductive terminals when the rotatable unit is in the use position.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Preferably, each of the receiving spaces includes a cover-receiving section, and a prong-receiving section communicating spatially with said cover-receiving section. Each of the slots has a length greater than or equal to a length of a corresponding receiving space and a width greater than or equal to a width of a corresponding prong-receiving section.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The effect of this invention resides in that because each arcuate conductive protrusion has at least two points of contact with the depressed contact surface of the corresponding conductive section, the rotatable plug of the present invention has a good effect of conduction. Further, the conductive terminals are insert molded into the first casing part so that only the conductive sections and the conductive ends thereof protrude inwardly from the inner surface of the first casing part, the fixing method thereof is stable and the electrical connection process thereof is reliable. Finally, with only the first and second protuberances cooperating alternately with the positioning groove to position the rotatable unit in the non-use and use positions, and with the connection of the first and second casing parts, the present invention can be modular.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Other features and advantages of the present invention will become apparent in the following detailed description of the preferred embodiment with reference to the accompanying drawings, of which:</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an exploded perspective view of a conventional power supply device having a rotatable plug;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a fragmentary perspective view of the conventional power supply device, illustrating a conductive prong in a use position;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a view similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, but illustrating the conductive prong in a non-use position;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is an exploded perspective view of a power supply device having a rotatable plug according to the preferred embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective view of a first casing part of the rotatable plug;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a perspective view of a pair of conductive terminals of the rotatable plug;</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a perspective view of a second casing part of the rotatable plug;</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a perspective view of a rotatable unit of the rotatable plug;</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a perspective view of a pair of conductive prongs of the rotatable plug;</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is an assembled perspective view of the rotatable plug in a non-use position;</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a perspective view of the rotatable plug in the non-use position with the second casing part thereof removed for clarity's sake;</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a view similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, but with the rotatable plug in a use position;</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a perspective view of the rotatable plug in the use position with the second casing part thereof removed for clarity's sake;</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is a schematic top view of the rotatable plug in the use position with the second casing part thereof removed;</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is a sectional view of the rotatable plug taken along line A-A of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref> is a view similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref>, but showing a conductive protrusion in two points of contact with a V-shaped conductive section;</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</figref> is a sectional view of the rotatable plug taken along line B-B of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</figref> is a perspective view of the power supply device with a second housing element thereof being removed to illustrate how the rotatable plug is disposed in a first housing element thereof;</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</figref> is a view similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</figref>, but with the conductive prongs of the rotatable plug being rotated from the non-use position to the use position; and</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</figref> is a view similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</figref>, but with the second housing element of the power supply device being coupled to the first housing element thereof.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The above-mentioned and other technical contents, features, and effects of this invention will be clearly presented from the following detailed description of a preferred embodiment in coordination with the reference drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 to 20</figref>, a power supply device according to the preferred embodiment of the present invention comprises a housing unit <b>5</b>, a circuit unit, and a rotatable plug <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The housing unit <b>5</b> includes a first housing element <b>51</b> and a second housing element <b>52</b> connected to and cooperating with the first housing element <b>51</b> to define a chamber <b>53</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</figref>). The first housing element <b>51</b> has a base wall <b>511</b>, a surrounding wall <b>512</b> extending transversely from the base wall <b>511</b>, and two parallel slots <b>513</b> formed in the surrounding wall <b>512</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 18 and 19</figref>, the circuit unit <b>6</b> and the rotatable plug <b>200</b> are disposed in the chamber <b>53</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, the rotatable plug <b>200</b> includes a casing unit <b>2</b>, a pair of conductive terminals <b>3</b> and a rotatable unit <b>4</b>. The casing unit <b>2</b> includes a first casing part <b>21</b> and a second casing part <b>22</b> connected to the first casing part <b>21</b>. The first casing part <b>21</b> includes a plate-shaped body <b>211</b>, a pair of first support posts <b>212</b> extending inwardly and respectively from two opposite sides of the plate-shaped body <b>211</b>, a pair of second support posts <b>213</b> disposed between the first support posts <b>212</b>, and a positioning portion <b>214</b> extending inwardly from the plate-shaped body <b>211</b> and disposed between the second support posts <b>213</b>. Specifically, each first support post <b>212</b> is hollow, extends from an inner surface of the plate-shaped body <b>211</b> at the two opposite sides thereof, and has an arcuate slotted surface <b>216</b> distal from the plate-shaped body <b>211</b>. The positioning portion <b>214</b> is formed with a central positioning groove <b>217</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The conductive terminals <b>3</b> are insert molded into the first casing part <b>21</b> and are connected electrically to the circuit unit <b>6</b>. Each of the conductive terminals <b>3</b> has a conductive section <b>31</b> disposed between one of the first support posts <b>212</b> and a corresponding second support post <b>213</b>, a conductive end <b>32</b> protruding from the slotted surface <b>216</b> of a respective first support post <b>212</b>, and a conductive extension <b>33</b> opposite to the conductive end <b>32</b> and extending from an outer surface of the plate-shaped body <b>211</b>. The conductive section <b>31</b> has a depressed contact surface <b>311</b>. The conductive end <b>32</b> is arcuate.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The configuration of each conductive terminal <b>3</b> before being insert molded into the first casing part <b>21</b> is as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. The conductive section <b>31</b> of each conductive terminal <b>3</b> is substantially U-shaped, and includes a bight portion having the depressed contact surface <b>311</b>, and two arms extending transversely from two opposite ends of the bight portion. Each conductive terminal <b>3</b> further has a first conductive plate <b>34</b> and a second conductive plate <b>35</b> respectively connected to and extending horizontally from the two opposite arms of the conductive section <b>31</b>, and a third conductive plate <b>36</b> that is substantially J-shaped and that has one end connected to the bight portion and another end having the arcuate conductive end <b>32</b>. The conductive extension <b>33</b> extends from one end of the first conductive plate <b>34</b> that is distal from the conductive section <b>31</b>. To easily distinguish the positive and negative polarities of the conductive terminals <b>3</b>, the two conductive extensions <b>33</b> have different lengths. The conductive extension <b>33</b> has a through hole <b>37</b>. Two conductive wires (not shown) can be soldered to the through holes <b>37</b> in the conductive extensions <b>33</b> of the conductive terminals <b>3</b> to connect electrically with the conductive extensions <b>33</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 7</figref>, the second casing part <b>22</b> includes a casing body <b>221</b>, and a pair of parallel receiving spaces <b>222</b> formed in the casing body <b>221</b>. Each of the receiving spaces <b>222</b> includes a cover-receiving section <b>223</b>, and a prong-receiving section <b>224</b> communicating spatially with the cover-receiving section <b>223</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</figref>, the rotatable unit <b>4</b> includes a pivot shaft <b>41</b>, and a pair of parallel conductive prongs <b>42</b> connected transversely to the pivot shaft <b>41</b>. The pivot shaft <b>41</b> includes two outer conductive shaft sections <b>43</b> respectively connected to the prongs <b>42</b>, an insulated middle shaft section <b>411</b> between the outer conductive shaft sections <b>43</b>, and two cover sections <b>412</b> disposed respectively on two opposite ends of the middle shaft section <b>411</b>. Each of the cover sections <b>412</b> covers a junction of the outer conductive shaft sections <b>43</b> and a respective prong <b>42</b>. A first protuberance <b>45</b> and a second protuberance <b>46</b> protrude outwardly from the middle shaft section <b>411</b>, are perpendicular to each other, and are made of insulated materials. A pair of conductive protrusions <b>44</b> respectively protrudes out from the cover sections <b>412</b> of the pivot shaft <b>41</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In actual applications, the rotatable unit <b>4</b> has the prongs <b>42</b>, which are made of metal, insert molded to the pivot shaft <b>41</b> such that the cover sections <b>412</b> of the pivot shaft <b>41</b> cover partially the prongs <b>42</b>. Before the prongs <b>42</b> are insert molded to the pivot shaft <b>41</b>, the configuration thereof is as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>. Each of the prongs <b>42</b> includes an elongated insert section <b>421</b>, and a connecting section <b>422</b> opposite to the insert section <b>421</b>. The conductive protrusions <b>44</b> protrude outwardly and respectively from the connecting sections <b>422</b> of the prongs <b>42</b>, and are disposed externally of the cover sections <b>412</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref>, <b>5</b>, <b>8</b> and <b>10</b>, to assemble the rotatable plug of the present invention, the rotatable unit <b>4</b> is first connected to the second casing part <b>22</b> by inserting the cover sections <b>412</b> of the pivot shaft <b>41</b> into the corresponding cover-receiving sections <b>223</b> of the receiving spaces <b>222</b> and the prongs <b>42</b> into the corresponding prong-receiving sections <b>224</b> of the receiving spaces <b>222</b>. At this time, a portion of the insert section <b>421</b> of each prong <b>42</b> extends out of the corresponding prong-receiving section <b>224</b>, and the outer conductive shaft sections <b>43</b> are exposed from lateral sides of the casing body <b>221</b> (only one is visible in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>). The second casing part <b>22</b> and the rotatable unit <b>4</b> are then integrated with the first casing part <b>21</b> such that the middle shaft section <b>411</b> of the pivot shaft <b>41</b> abuts against the second support posts <b>213</b> and the outer conductive shaft sections <b>43</b> abut against and electrically coupled to the conductive ends <b>32</b> of the conductive terminals <b>3</b>. Finally, because the first casing part <b>21</b> further includes a plurality of welding spots <b>218</b> arranged on a periphery of the inner surface of the plate-shaped body <b>211</b>, the first and second casing parts <b>21</b>, <b>22</b> are integrated together using an ultrasonic welding process.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 to 13</figref>, the rotatable unit <b>4</b> is disposed in the casing unit <b>2</b> and is rotatable relative to the same between a non-use or folded position and a use or extended position. The second casing part <b>22</b> is removed in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11 and 13</figref> to facilitate description of the positioning mechanism of the rotatable unit <b>4</b> during the non-use and use positions.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 and 11</figref>, when the rotatable unit <b>4</b> is in the non-use position, the insert sections <b>421</b> of the prongs <b>42</b> are respectively accommodated in the prong-receiving sections <b>224</b> with the portions thereof protruding from the corresponding prong-receiving sections <b>224</b>, and the first protuberance <b>45</b> is positioned in the positioning groove <b>217</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>). When the insert sections <b>421</b> of the prongs <b>42</b> are rotated in the direction of an arrow (I) to extend out of the prong-receiving sections <b>224</b>, the second protuberance <b>46</b> is positioned in the positioning groove <b>217</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12 to 14</figref>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref>, the conductive protrusion <b>44</b> is disposed on the conductive section <b>31</b>. Since the conductive section <b>31</b> has the depressed contact surface <b>311</b> and the conductive protrusion <b>44</b> is arcuate, the conductive protrusion <b>44</b> has at least two points of contact with the conductive section <b>31</b> so that it has a large area of contact with the same to thereby enhance the effect of conduction. The conductive section <b>31</b> is not limited to having the depressed contact surface <b>311</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref>, the conductive section <b>31</b> may have a substantially V-shaped contact surface <b>311</b>&#x2032;, so that the conductive protrusion <b>44</b> has two points of contact with the conductive section <b>31</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, when the insert sections <b>421</b> of the prongs <b>42</b> are rotated in the direction of an arrow (II), the rotatable unit <b>4</b> is rotated back to the non-use position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 and 11</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</figref>, the outer conductive shaft section <b>43</b> is in constant contact with the conductive end <b>32</b> whether the rotatable unit <b>4</b> is in the non-use or use position. Hence, in the use position, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, the conductive terminals <b>3</b> and the rotatable unit <b>4</b> are electrically coupled to each other through the aforesaid two methods, so that reliability of electrical connection can be enhanced. Further, referring once again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref>, <b>8</b> and <b>10</b>, the cover-receiving section <b>223</b> of each receiving space <b>222</b> has a width (W<b>1</b>), the prong-receiving section <b>224</b> of each receiving space <b>222</b> has a width (W<b>2</b>), each cover section <b>412</b> of the pivot shaft <b>41</b> has a thickness (T<b>1</b>), and each prong <b>42</b> has a thickness (T<b>2</b>). In the non-use position, because the width (W<b>2</b>) of the prong-receiving section <b>224</b> is smaller than the width (W<b>1</b>) of the cover-receiving section <b>223</b>, and the thickness (T<b>2</b>) of each prong <b>42</b> is smaller than the thickness (T<b>2</b>) of each cover section <b>412</b>, the insert sections <b>421</b> of the prongs <b>42</b> can be stably received in the prong-receiving sections <b>224</b> of the second casing part <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Referring back to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11</figref>, <b>12</b> and <b>13</b>, more particularly, because the conductive sections <b>31</b> have elasticity, when the conductive sections <b>31</b> are in contact with or separated from the conductive protrusions <b>44</b>, the wearing thereof caused by repeated rotation between the non-use and use positions can be reduced. Further, by using the ultrasonic welding method to integrate the first and second casing parts <b>21</b>, <b>22</b>, the separation of the first and second casing parts <b>21</b>, <b>22</b> due to the frequent switching between the non-use and use positions can be prevented.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 18 and 19</figref>, in combination with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, each of the slots <b>513</b> in the housing unit <b>5</b> has a length slightly longer than or equal to that of the corresponding receiving space <b>222</b>, and a width larger than or equal to that of the corresponding prong-receiving section <b>224</b>. The outer surface of the casing body <b>221</b> of the second casing part <b>22</b> abuts against inner surfaces of the base wall <b>511</b> and the surrounding wall <b>512</b> and is proximate to the two slots <b>513</b>, so that the cover-receiving sections <b>223</b> and the prong-receiving sections <b>224</b> of the receiving spaces <b>222</b> are in spatial communication with the slots <b>513</b> to facilitate rotation of the insert sections <b>421</b> of the prongs <b>42</b> in and out of the housing unit <b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 18</figref>, <b>19</b> and <b>20</b>, the rotatable unit <b>4</b> is similarly rotatable relative to the casing unit <b>2</b> between the non-use or folded position and the use or extended position as described above. The difference resides in that the insert sections <b>421</b> of the prongs <b>42</b> of the rotatable unit <b>4</b> can be rotatably received in the respective slots <b>513</b> of the first housing element <b>51</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">In the non-use position, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</figref>, the insert sections <b>421</b> of the prongs <b>42</b> are accommodated in the slots <b>513</b>. When the insert sections <b>421</b> are rotated in the direction of the arrow (I), as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 19 and 20</figref>, the insert sections <b>421</b> are moved to extend out of the respective slots <b>513</b>. When the insert sections <b>421</b> are rotated in the direction of the arrow (II), the insert sections <b>421</b> are moved back to the position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In summary, because each arcuate conductive protrusion <b>44</b> has at least two points of contact with the depressed contact surface <b>311</b> of the corresponding conductive section <b>31</b>, the rotatable plug of the present invention has a good effect of conduction. Further, the conductive terminals <b>3</b> are insert molded into the first casing part <b>21</b> so that only the conductive sections <b>31</b> and the conductive ends <b>32</b> thereof protrude inwardly from the inner surface of the first casing part <b>21</b>, the fixing method thereof is stable and the electrical connection thereof is reliable. Finally, with only the first and second protuberances <b>45</b>, <b>46</b> cooperating alternately with the positioning groove <b>217</b> to position the rotatable unit <b>4</b> in the non-use and use positions, and through the connection of the first and second casing parts <b>21</b>, <b>22</b>, the present invention can be modular. Hence, the objects of the present invention can be realized.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">While the present invention has been described in connection with what is considered the most practical and preferred embodiment, it is understood that this invention is not limited to the disclosed embodiment but is intended to cover various arrangements included within the spirit and scope of the broadest interpretation so as to encompass all such modifications and equivalent arrangements.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A rotatable plug comprising:
<claim-text>a casing unit including a first casing part, and a second casing part connected to said first casing part and formed with a pair of receiving spaces;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of conductive terminals insert molded into said first casing part, each of said conductive terminals having a conductive section; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a rotatable unit including a pivot shaft, a pair of conductive prongs connected transversely to said pivot shaft, and a pair of conductive protrusions protruding out from said pivot shaft, said rotatable unit being disposed in said casing unit and being rotatable relative to said casing unit between a non-use or folded position, where said conductive prongs are respectively accommodated in said receiving spaces, and a use or extended position, where said conductive prongs respectively extend out of said receiving spaces, each of said conductive protrusions being disposed on and having at least two points of contact with said conductive section of a respective one of said conductive terminals when said rotatable unit is in said use position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The rotatable plug as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said conductive section of each of said conductive terminals has a depressed contact surface, each of said conductive protrusions having the at least two points of contact with said depressed contact surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The rotatable plug as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said first casing part includes a pair of first support posts each having a slotted surface, each of said conductive terminals further having a conductive end protruding from said slotted surface, said pivot shaft including two outer conductive shaft sections respectively connected to said prongs, and an insulated middle shaft section between said outer conductive shaft sections, said outer conductive shaft sections being respectively in contact with said conductive ends of said conductive terminals when said rotatable unit is in said use and non-use positions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The rotatable plug as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said first casing part includes a pair of second support posts supporting said pivot shaft.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The rotatable plug as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said first casing part has a positioning portion formed with a positioning groove, said rotatable unit further including a first protuberance and a second protuberance protruding from said pivot shaft between said conductive protrusions and perpendicular to each other, said first protuberance being positioned in said positioning groove when in said non-use position, said second protuberance being positioned in said positioning groove when in said use position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The rotatable plug as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of said conductive terminals further has a conductive extension disposed externally of said casing unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The rotatable plug as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein said conductive extensions of said conductive terminals have different lengths.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A power supply device comprising:
<claim-text>a housing unit including a first housing element having two parallel slots, and a second housing element connected to and cooperating with said first housing element to define a chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a circuit unit disposed in said chamber; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a rotatable plug disposed in said chamber and including
<claim-text>a casing unit including a first casing part, and a second casing part connected to said first casing part and formed with a pair of receiving spaces;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of conductive terminals insert molded into said first casing part and connected electrically to said circuit unit, each of said conductive terminals having a conductive section; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a rotatable unit including a pivot shaft, a pair of conductive prongs connected transversely to said pivot shaft, and a pair of conductive protrusions protruding out from said pivot shaft, said rotatable unit being disposed in said casing unit and being rotatable relative to said casing unit between a non-use or folded position, where said conductive prongs are respectively accommodated in said receiving spaces and said slots, and a use or extended position, where said conductive prongs respectively extend out of said receiving spaces and said slots, each of said conductive protrusions being disposed on and having at least two points of contact with said conductive section of a respective one of said conductive terminals when said rotatable unit is in said use position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The power supply device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein said conductive section of each of said conductive terminals has a depressed contact surface, each of said conductive protrusions having the at least two points of contact with said depressed contact surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The power supply device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein said first casing part includes a pair of first support posts each having a slotted surface, each of said conductive terminals further having a conductive end protruding from said slotted surface, said pivot shaft including two outer conductive shaft sections respectively connected to said prongs, and an insulated middle shaft section between said outer conductive shaft sections, said outer conductive shaft sections being respectively in contact with said conductive ends of said conductive terminals when said rotatable unit is in said use and non-use positions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The power supply device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein said first casing part includes a pair of second support posts supporting said pivot shaft.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The power supply device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein said first casing part has a positioning portion formed with a positioning groove, said rotatable unit further including a first protuberance and a second protuberance protruding from said pivot shaft between said conductive protrusions and perpendicular to each other, said first protuberance being positioned in said positioning groove when in said non-use position, said second protuberance being positioned in said positioning groove when in said use position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The power supply device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein each of said conductive terminals further has a conductive extension disposed externally of said casing unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The power supply device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein said conductive extensions of said conductive terminals have different lengths.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The power supply device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein each of said receiving space includes a cover-receiving section, and a prong-receiving section communicating spatially with said cover-receiving section, each of said slots having a length greater than or equal to a length of a corresponding said receiving space and a width greater than or equal to a width of a corresponding said prong-receiving section. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
