<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622001-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622001</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13187624</doc-number>
<date>20110721</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>42</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>12</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>102494</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Kinetic energy fragmenting warhead and projectile incorporating same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>1305967</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hawks</name>
<date>19190600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>102494</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3954060</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Haag et al.</name>
<date>19760500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>102494</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0054047</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Burri</name>
<date>20060300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>102494</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>102491</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>102492</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>102493</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>102494</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>102495</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>102496</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>102506</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>102514</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>11</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Patel</last-name>
<first-name>Umang R.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Mansfield</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cannon</last-name>
<first-name>Jesse R.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Grand Prairie</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Patel</last-name>
<first-name>Umang R.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Mansfield</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cannon</last-name>
<first-name>Jesse R.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Grand Prairie</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Slater &#x26; Matsil, L.L.P.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Lockheed Martin Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Grand Prairie</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Clement</last-name>
<first-name>Michelle</first-name>
<department>3641</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Cooper</last-name>
<first-name>John D</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A kinetic energy fragmenting warhead includes a penetrator, a plurality of fragments disposed about the penetrator, and a sleeve disposed about at least some of the plurality of fragments. A projectile includes a body and a kinetic energy fragmenting warhead disposed in the body. The kinetic energy fragmenting warhead includes a penetrator, a plurality of fragments disposed about the penetrator, and a sleeve disposed about at least some of the plurality of fragments.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="250.02mm" wi="143.09mm" file="US08622001-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="249.85mm" wi="159.00mm" file="US08622001-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="261.11mm" wi="213.36mm" file="US08622001-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="249.17mm" wi="169.42mm" file="US08622001-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="194.82mm" wi="191.69mm" file="US08622001-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="242.65mm" wi="181.36mm" file="US08622001-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="249.85mm" wi="170.94mm" file="US08622001-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="249.85mm" wi="194.82mm" file="US08622001-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="255.78mm" wi="134.20mm" file="US08622001-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates generally to kinetic energy warheads and projectiles incorporating kinetic energy warheads.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">It is common in combat situations for an adversary to shield personnel, equipment, munitions, and the like within protective buildings, armored vehicles, or other such enclosures. Historically, primitive munitions were effective in penetrating such enclosures but were ineffective in neutralizing the adversary's assets housed therein. In response to this need, projectiles were developed that employ kinetic energy, a forward-firing shaped charge, or the like for penetrating and entering such enclosures and, once inside the enclosure, an explosive is detonated via a time-delay fuze to disperse fragments to defeat the adversary's assets housed within the enclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The use of explosives, however, can present difficulties and dangers. For example, special facilities must be employed in which the explosive-containing projectiles are manufactured. Special care must be provided during the manufacturing process to ensure that the explosives used are not inadvertently detonated. Projectiles that contain explosives must be carefully handled during transportation to storage or combat areas and, once in these locations, must be stored in such ways that the explosive neither becomes degraded nor is inadvertently detonated. Moreover, such conventional warheads and projectiles typically require complex structure and control systems, which are often costly.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">There are many designs of projectiles well known in the art that can penetrate enclosures and defeat assets disposed therein; however, considerable shortcomings remain.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The novel features believed characteristic of the invention are set forth in the appended claims. However, the invention itself, as well as, a preferred mode of use, and further objectives and advantages thereof, will best be understood by reference to the following detailed description when read in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a side, elevational view of an illustrative embodiment of a kinetic energy fragmenting warhead;</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, taken along the line <b>2</b>-<b>2</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, taken along the line <b>3</b>-<b>3</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, taken along the line <b>4</b>-<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, taken along the line <b>5</b>-<b>5</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a perspective view depicting an illustrative use of the warhead embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a cross-sectional view, corresponding to the view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, depicting an illustrative use of the warhead embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a cross-sectional view, corresponding to the view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, depicting an alternative, illustrative embodiment of a kinetic energy fragmenting warhead;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</figref> are cross-sectional views, corresponding to the view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, depicting yet another alternative, illustrative embodiment of a kinetic energy fragmenting warhead; and</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a side, elevational view of an illustrative embodiment of a projectile incorporating the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, or the like.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">While the invention is susceptible to various modifications and alternative forms, specific embodiments thereof have been shown by way of example in the drawings and are herein described in detail. It should be understood, however, that the description herein of specific embodiments is not intended to limit the invention to the particular forms disclosed, but on the contrary, the intention is to cover all modifications, equivalents, and alternatives falling within the spirit and scope of the invention as defined by the appended claims.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Illustrative embodiments of the invention are described below. In the interest of clarity, not all features of an actual implementation are described in this specification. It will of course be appreciated that in the development of any such actual embodiment, numerous implementation-specific decisions must be made to achieve the developer's specific goals, such as compliance with system-related and business-related constraints, which will vary from one implementation to another. Moreover, it will be appreciated that such a development effort might be complex and time-consuming but would nevertheless be a routine undertaking for those of ordinary skill in the art having the benefit of this disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Reference will now be made in detail to the present exemplary embodiments of the invention, examples of which are illustrated in the accompanying drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">A kinetic energy fragmenting warhead includes a penetrator, a plurality of fragments disposed about the penetrator, and a sleeve disposed about at least some of the plurality of fragments. A projectile includes a body and a kinetic energy fragmenting warhead disposed in the body.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-5</figref> depict a first illustrative embodiment of a kinetic energy fragmenting warhead <b>101</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a side, elevational view of warhead <b>101</b>. FIGS. <b>2</b>-<b>5</b> are cross-sectional views of warhead <b>101</b>, as referenced in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. In the illustrated embodiment, warhead <b>101</b> comprises a penetrator <b>103</b> including a tapered nose <b>105</b>, a base <b>107</b>, and a shaft <b>201</b> extending between nose <b>105</b> and base <b>107</b>. In one embodiment and referring in particular to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a forward face <b>108</b> of nose <b>105</b> defines a taper angle A, configured to minimize a decrease in velocity of warhead <b>101</b> as warhead <b>101</b> penetrates an enclosure, such as an armored enclosure. Taper angle A, however, is implementation specific depending upon, for example, the type of material that is to be penetrated by warhead <b>101</b>, the configuration of material that is to be penetrated by warhead <b>101</b>, the angle at which warhead <b>101</b> is expected to impact a target, and/or design parameters of a projectile housing warhead <b>101</b>, such as space available in the warhead, the material of penetrator <b>103</b>, the anticipated velocity of warhead <b>101</b> when impacting a target and/or the like. Accordingly, the present invention contemplates many different configurations for nose <b>105</b>, including taper angle A. Still referring in particular to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, base <b>107</b> exhibits an outer transverse dimension D<sub>1 </sub>that is greater than a maximum transverse dimension D<sub>2 </sub>of nose <b>105</b>, so that forward motion of penetrator <b>103</b> is generally halted or substantially inhibited after nose <b>105</b> penetrates an enclosure, as is discussed in greater detail herein.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-5</figref>, a plurality of sets of fragments is disposed about shaft <b>201</b>, between nose <b>105</b> and base <b>107</b>. In the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-5</figref>, warhead <b>101</b> comprises a first set <b>109</b> of fragments <b>111</b> disposed proximate nose <b>105</b> and a second set <b>301</b> of fragments <b>303</b> disposed proximate base <b>107</b>. It should be noted that the scope of the present invention encompasses embodiments incorporating more than two sets of fragments and sets of fragments comprising more than eight fragments. In the illustrated embodiment, first set <b>109</b> of fragments <b>111</b> generally abuts second set <b>301</b> of fragments <b>303</b>. Warhead <b>101</b> further comprises a sleeve <b>113</b> disposed about second set <b>301</b> of fragments <b>303</b> and disposed about at least a portion of first set <b>109</b> of fragments <b>111</b> to retain fragments <b>111</b> and <b>303</b> proximate penetrator <b>103</b>. While sleeve <b>113</b> extends generally about an entirety of second set <b>301</b> of fragments <b>303</b>, sleeve <b>113</b> extends over first set <b>109</b> of fragments <b>111</b> by a dimension X, which is sufficient to retain fragments <b>111</b> proximate penetrator <b>103</b>. Sleeve <b>113</b> comprises a body <b>115</b> and a flange <b>117</b> extending from a first end <b>119</b> of body <b>115</b>. A second end <b>121</b> of sleeve <b>113</b> generally abuts a face <b>123</b> of base <b>107</b> or is proximate face <b>123</b> of base <b>107</b>. Sleeve <b>113</b> does not freely slide along sets <b>109</b> and <b>301</b> of fragments <b>111</b> and <b>303</b>, respectively, but is retained in place generally abutting face <b>123</b> of base <b>107</b> or proximate face <b>123</b> of base <b>107</b>, such as by friction between sleeve <b>113</b> and second set <b>301</b> of fragments <b>303</b> or the like. Flange <b>117</b> of sleeve <b>113</b> exhibits an outer transverse dimension D<sub>3 </sub>that is greater than a maximum transverse dimension D<sub>2 </sub>of nose <b>105</b> and body <b>115</b> of sleeve <b>113</b> is configured by at least the material chosen for sleeve <b>113</b> and/or a thickness T (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) of body <b>115</b>, so that sleeve <b>113</b> is crumpled, is deformed, is compressed, fails, structurally fails, or the like to release sets <b>109</b> and <b>301</b> of fragments <b>111</b> and <b>303</b>, respectively when impacting an enclosure through which penetrator <b>103</b> has pierced, as is discussed in greater detail herein. It should be noted that the meanings of terms &#x201c;crumple&#x201d; or &#x201c;crumpled&#x201d;, as used herein, include being deformed, compressed, failed, structurally failed, or the like. Thickness T of sleeve <b>113</b> is sufficiently thick to retain fragments <b>111</b> and <b>303</b> up to and including initial penetration into a target but is thin enough to crumple as warhead <b>101</b> enters the target. In one embodiment, sleeve <b>113</b> comprises aluminum or an aluminum alloy. The scope of the present invention is not so limited, however. For example, sleeve <b>113</b> may comprise metals other than aluminum or an aluminum alloy and may comprise a polymeric material.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Referring in particular to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, an aft surface <b>501</b> of nose <b>105</b> is generally conical in nature and exhibits an angle B that allows set <b>109</b> of fragments <b>111</b> to be outwardly deployed away from shaft <b>201</b> when sleeve <b>113</b> is crumpled, deformed, compressed, or the like, as a result of impacting an enclosure. In the illustrated embodiment, a forward surface <b>503</b> of each of fragments <b>111</b> of set <b>109</b> exhibits an angle C corresponding to angle B of aft surface <b>501</b>, which allows fragments <b>111</b> of set <b>109</b> to be freely radially deployed when sleeve <b>113</b> is crumpled, deformed, compressed, or the like, as a result of impacting an enclosure. Similarly, an aft surface <b>505</b> of each of fragments <b>111</b> of set <b>109</b> exhibits an angle D that allows set <b>301</b> of fragments <b>303</b> to be outwardly deployed away from shaft <b>201</b> when sleeve <b>113</b> is crumpled, deformed, compressed, or the like, as discussed above. In the illustrated embodiment, a forward surface <b>507</b> of each of fragments <b>303</b> of set <b>301</b> exhibits an angle E corresponding to angle D of aft surfaces <b>505</b>, which allows fragments <b>303</b> of set <b>301</b> to be freely radially deployed when sleeve <b>113</b> is crumpled, deformed compressed, or the like. The particular value of angle B employed in a particular embodiment, however, is implementation specific. Angles B-D affect the outward or radial velocities of fragments <b>111</b> and <b>303</b>, which can be varied according to the present invention based at least upon the implementation of warhead <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> depicts warhead <b>101</b> in an exemplary use. Specifically, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> depicts certain portions of warhead <b>101</b> after penetrator <b>105</b> has penetrated an enclosure <b>601</b>. As penetrator <b>105</b> penetrates enclosure <b>601</b>, an opening <b>603</b> is formed. Sleeve <b>113</b> exhibits a dimension, as discussed herein, that prohibits or at least inhibits sleeve <b>113</b> from passing through opening <b>603</b>. Sleeve <b>113</b> becomes crumpled, deformed, compressed, or the like, as a result of impacting enclosure <b>601</b> and being compressed between enclosure <b>601</b> and base <b>107</b> of penetrator <b>103</b>, thus releasing penetrators <b>111</b> and <b>303</b>. Forward motion of penetrator <b>105</b> is halted or at least is substantially decreased by interaction between base <b>107</b> and enclosure <b>601</b>, which results in relative motion between moving fragments <b>111</b> and <b>303</b> and generally stationary penetrator <b>105</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> depicts this action particularly well. In the particular implementation of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, sleeve <b>113</b> and penetrator <b>103</b> do not pass through an opening <b>701</b> produced in an enclosure structure <b>703</b> by nose <b>105</b> of penetrator <b>103</b>. Fragments <b>111</b> and <b>303</b> are not constrained, however, resulting in relative motion between fragments <b>111</b> and <b>303</b> and penetrator <b>103</b>. Cooperation between of aft surface <b>501</b> (exhibiting angle B, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) of nose <b>105</b> and forward surfaces <b>503</b> (exhibiting angle C, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) of fragments <b>111</b> and cooperation between aft surfaces <b>505</b> (exhibiting angle C, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) of fragments <b>111</b> of set <b>109</b> and forward surfaces <b>507</b> (exhibiting angle D, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) of fragments <b>303</b> of set <b>301</b> in combination with the relative motion of fragments <b>111</b> and <b>303</b> with respect to penetrator <b>103</b>, as indicated by an arrow <b>705</b>, causes fragments <b>111</b> and <b>303</b> to be radially dispersed away from penetrator <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">It should be noted, however, that the present invention contemplates embodiments wherein one or more sets of fragments, corresponding to, for example, sets <b>109</b> and <b>301</b>, do not exhibit tapered angles, such as angles C-E, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. In such embodiments, one or more sets of fragments exhibit generally square ends. One such embodiment is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, which comprises a first set <b>801</b> of fragments <b>803</b> disposed proximate nose <b>105</b> and a second set <b>805</b> of fragments <b>807</b> disposed proximate base <b>107</b>. It should be noted that the scope of the present invention, as discussed herein concerning the previous embodiment, encompasses embodiments incorporating more than two sets of fragments and sets of fragments comprising more than eight fragments. As in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-7</figref>, aft surface <b>501</b> of nose <b>105</b> is generally conical in nature and exhibits angle B that allows set <b>801</b> of fragments <b>803</b> to be outwardly deployed away from shaft <b>201</b> when sleeve <b>113</b> is crumpled, deformed, compressed, or the like, as a result of impacting an enclosure. Also, corresponding to the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-7</figref>, forward surface <b>809</b> of each of fragments <b>803</b> of set <b>801</b> exhibits an angle C corresponding to angle B of aft surface <b>501</b>, which allows fragments <b>803</b> of set <b>801</b> to be freely radially deployed when sleeve <b>113</b> is crumpled, deformed, compressed, or the like, as a result of impacting an enclosure. An aft surface <b>811</b> of each fragment <b>803</b> of set <b>801</b> and a forward surface <b>813</b> of each fragment <b>807</b> of set <b>805</b>, however, exhibit generally &#x201c;square&#x201d; or right-angle configurations, rather than exhibiting tapered angles as in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-7</figref>. In such an embodiment, fragments <b>807</b> are not substantially radially dispersed away from shaft <b>201</b> until they encounter aft surface <b>501</b> of nose <b>105</b>, which alters the radial dispersion pattern and timing of fragments <b>807</b>. It should be noted that either or both of fragments <b>803</b> and <b>807</b> may exhibit end surfaces that exhibit generally square configurations.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In the embodiments of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-5</figref>, <b>7</b>, and <b>8</b>, set <b>109</b> includes fragments <b>111</b> disposed about a substantially complete circumference of shaft <b>201</b>. Thus, when sleeve <b>113</b> is crumpled, deformed, compressed, or the like as a result of impacting an enclosure, fragments <b>111</b> are outwardly deployed generally uniformly radially away from warhead <b>101</b>. The scope of the present invention, however, is not limited to this configuration. Rather, the sets of fragments can include configurations wherein one or more fragments are radially outwardly but non-uniformly deployed away from warhead <b>101</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</figref> depict illustrative embodiments of such configurations, in which some of the fragments <b>111</b> of the embodiments of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-5</figref>, <b>7</b>, and <b>8</b> are replaced with spacers <b>901</b> made from one or more materials not suitable for fragments, such as one or more polymeric materials. In the particular illustrative embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, fragments <b>111</b> and spacers <b>901</b> are arranged such that fragments <b>111</b> are dispersed only in directions generally corresponding to arrows <b>903</b>, <b>905</b>, and <b>907</b>. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, fragments <b>111</b> and spacers <b>901</b> are arranged such that fragments <b>111</b> are dispersed only in directions generally corresponding to arrows <b>1001</b>, <b>1003</b>, <b>1005</b>, <b>1007</b>, <b>1009</b>, and <b>1011</b>. It should be noted that such fragment and spacer configurations may also be utilized in set <b>301</b>. The scope of the present invention includes any combination of fragments <b>111</b> or <b>303</b> and spacers <b>901</b> (or the like). Sets <b>109</b> and <b>301</b> may include the same configurations of fragments and spacers or may exhibit different configurations of fragments and spacers. It should also be noted that the present invention contemplates other ways wherein the fragments are outwardly deployed in only one predetermined direction or in a plurality of predetermined directions away from shaft <b>201</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> depicts an illustrative embodiment of a projectile <b>1101</b> comprising warhead <b>101</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, projectile <b>1101</b> comprises a body <b>1103</b> in which warhead <b>101</b> is disposed. Projectile <b>1101</b> is configured to propel warhead <b>101</b> to a target, such as an enclosure, and to impact the target such that warhead <b>101</b> is effective in breaching the enclosure or target and dispersing fragments thereof within the enclosure or target. It should be noted that any embodiment of warhead <b>101</b> shown and described herein or encompassed by the present invention may be utilized in projectile <b>1101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The present invention provide significant advantages including, but not limited to, (1) providing a warhead that is capable of penetrating an enclosure and dispersing fragments within the enclosure without the use of explosive materials; and (2) providing a warhead that is capable of penetrating an armored enclosure and dispersing fragments within the enclosure without the use of explosive materials.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The particular embodiments disclosed above are illustrative only, as the invention may be modified and practiced in different but equivalent manners apparent to those skilled in the art having the benefit of the teachings herein. Furthermore, no limitations are intended to the details of construction or design herein shown, other than as described in the claims below. It is therefore evident that the particular embodiments disclosed above may be altered or modified and all such variations are considered within the scope and spirit of the invention. Accordingly, the protection sought herein is as set forth in the claims below. It is apparent that an invention with significant advantages has been described and illustrated. Although the present invention is shown in a limited number of forms, it is not limited to just these forms, but is amenable to various changes and modifications without departing from the spirit thereof.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A kinetic energy fragmenting warhead, comprising:
<claim-text>a single-piece penetrator, wherein the penetrator comprises a nose, a base, and a shaft extending between the nose and the base;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of fragments disposed about the penetrator, wherein the nose includes an aft generally conical surface configured for outward deployment of the plurality of fragments, and wherein the kinetic energy fragmenting warhead is configured to disperse the plurality of fragments without the use of explosive materials; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sleeve disposed about at least some of the plurality of fragments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The kinetic energy fragmenting warhead of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of fragments is disposed about the shaft.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The kinetic energy fragmenting warhead of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of fragments comprises a first set of fragments, disposed proximate the nose, and a second set of fragments, disposed proximate the base.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The kinetic energy fragmenting warhead of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the sleeve extends from proximate the base, over the second set of fragments, and partially over the first set of fragments.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The kinetic energy fragmenting warhead of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the base exhibits a transverse dimension larger than a maximum transverse dimension of the nose.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The kinetic energy fragmenting warhead of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of fragments comprises a first set of fragments disposed proximate a second set of fragments.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The kinetic energy fragmenting warhead of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the sleeve extends over the second set of fragments and partially over the first set of fragments.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The kinetic energy fragmenting warhead of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the sleeve is configured to crumple when impacting a target.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The kinetic energy fragmenting warhead of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the warhead is configured to deploy the fragments generally uniformly radially away from the warhead.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The kinetic energy fragmenting warhead of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the warhead is configured to deploy the fragments generally non-uniformly radially away from the warhead.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A projectile comprising:
<claim-text>a body; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a kinetic energy fragmenting warhead disposed in the body, the kinetic energy fragmenting warhead comprising:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a single-piece penetrator, wherein the penetrator comprises a nose, a base, and a shaft extending between the nose and the base;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of fragments disposed about the penetrator, wherein the nose comprises an aft, generally conical surface configured for outward deployment of the plurality of fragments, and wherein the kinetic energy fragmenting warhead is configured to disperse the plurality of fragments without the use of explosive materials; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sleeve disposed about at least some of the plurality of fragments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The projectile of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of fragments is disposed about the shaft.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The projectile of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of fragments comprises a first set of fragments, disposed proximate the nose, and a second set of fragments, disposed proximate the base.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The projectile of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the sleeve extends from proximate the base, over the second set of fragments, and partially over the first set of fragments.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The projectile of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the base exhibits a transverse dimension larger than a maximum transverse dimension of the nose.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The projectile of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of fragments comprises a first set of fragments disposed proximate a second set of fragments.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The projectile of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the sleeve extends over the second set of fragments and partially over the first set of fragments.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The projectile of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the sleeve is configured to crumple when impacting a target.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The projectile of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the warhead is configured to deploy the fragments generally uniformly radially away from the warhead.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The projectile of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the warhead is configured to deploy the fragments generally non-uniformly radially away from the warhead.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
