<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624828-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624828</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13090605</doc-number>
<date>20110420</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-100232</doc-number>
<date>20100423</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>184</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>09</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>36</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>345102</main-classification>
<further-classification>345 76</further-classification>
<further-classification>345 77</further-classification>
<further-classification>345 78</further-classification>
<further-classification>345 82</further-classification>
<further-classification>345 87</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Control circuit for switching power supply</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0087675</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ayres</name>
<date>20050400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>250214 R</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0136389</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Uchimoto et al.</name>
<date>20080600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>323282</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0170012</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>S et al.</name>
<date>20080700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>345 82</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006-114324</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20060400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>6</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>345102</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>345 76</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>345 77</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>345 78</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>345 82</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>345 87</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120120342</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120517</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Uchimoto</last-name>
<first-name>Daisuke</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kyoto</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kikuchi</last-name>
<first-name>Hiroki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kyoto</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Uchimoto</last-name>
<first-name>Daisuke</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kyoto</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kikuchi</last-name>
<first-name>Hiroki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kyoto</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Cantor Colburn LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Rohm Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Boddie</last-name>
<first-name>William</first-name>
<department>2699</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Elnafia</last-name>
<first-name>Saifeldin</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A control IC controls a switching power supply configured to supply a driving voltage Vout to one terminal of an LED string to be intermittently driven. In the on period of the LED string, a pulse modulator generates a pulse signal having a duty ratio adjusted such that a detection voltage V<sub>LED </sub>that corresponds to the output voltage Vout of the switching power supply matches a predetermined reference voltage Vref. A driver drives a switching transistor included in the switching power supply according to the pulse signal. After transition from the on period to the off period, the pulse modulator reduces the duty ratio of the pulse signal over time.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="169.76mm" wi="235.20mm" file="US08624828-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="197.78mm" wi="157.40mm" file="US08624828-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="239.18mm" wi="183.64mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624828-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="242.91mm" wi="178.82mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624828-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a light emitting apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In recent years, as a backlight of a liquid crystal panel or as an illumination device, a light emitting apparatus is employed, which is configured using a light emitting element such as an LED (light emitting diode) or the like. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a circuit diagram which shows an example configuration of a light emitting apparatus according to a comparison technique. A light emitting apparatus <b>1003</b> includes multiple LED strings <b>1006</b>_<b>1</b> through <b>1006</b><sub>&#x2014;</sub><i>n, </i>a switching power supply <b>1004</b>, and a current driving circuit <b>1008</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Each LED string <b>1006</b> includes multiple LEDs connected in series. The switching power supply <b>1004</b> boosts an input voltage Vin, and supplies a driving voltage Vout to one terminal of each of the LED strings <b>1006</b>_<b>1</b> through <b>1006</b><sub>&#x2014;</sub><i>n. </i></p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The current driving circuit <b>1008</b> includes current sources CS<sub>1 </sub>through CS<sub>n </sub>which are respectively provided to the LED strings <b>1006</b>_<b>1</b> through <b>1006</b><sub>&#x2014;</sub><i>n. </i>Each current source CS supplies, to the corresponding LED string <b>1006</b>, a driving current I<sub>LED </sub>that corresponds to the target luminance level.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The switching power supply <b>1004</b> includes an output circuit <b>1102</b> and a control IC <b>1100</b>. The output circuit <b>1102</b> includes an inductor L<b>1</b>, a switching transistor M<b>1</b>, a rectifier diode D<b>1</b>, and an output capacitor C<b>1</b>. The control IC <b>1100</b> controls the on/off duty ratio of the switching transistor M<b>1</b> so as to adjust the driving voltage Vout.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">RELATED ART DOCUMENTS</heading>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">Patent Documents</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">[Patent Document 1]</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Japanese Patent Application Laid Open No. 2006-114324</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">With such a light emitting apparatus <b>1003</b>, in some cases, in order to adjust the luminance level of each LED string <b>1006</b>, a PWM (Pulse Width Modulation) control operation is performed on the driving current I<sub>LED</sub>. Specifically, a PWM controller <b>1009</b> of the current driving circuit <b>1008</b> generates pulse signals PWM<sub>1 </sub>through PWM<sub>n </sub>each having a duty ratio that corresponds to the luminance level so as to perform a switching control operation on the respective current sources CS<sub>1 </sub>through CS<sub>n</sub>. Such a control operation is also referred to as the &#x201c;burst dimming control operation&#x201d; or &#x201c;burst control operation&#x201d;.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The inventors have investigated such a light emitting apparatus, and has come to recognize the following problems.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The load current (output current) lout of the switching power supply <b>1004</b> is the sum of the LED currents. The PWM driving operation for the LED strings <b>1006</b> involves the switching of the load current Iout. A sudden change in the load current Iout means that there is a sudden change in the coil current I<sub>L1 </sub>that flows through the inductor L<b>1</b>. This becomes a cause of acoustic noise (which is also referred to as a &#x201c;rumbling sound&#x201d;) that occurs in the coil. This noise is within the audible band, which is uncomfortable for the user of the electronic device. It should be noted that the above-described consideration is by no means within the scope of common and general knowledge in the field of the present invention. Furthermore, it can be said that the present applicant has been the first to arrive at this consideration.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The present invention has been made in order to solve such a problem. Accordingly, it is an exemplary purpose of an embodiment of the present invention to provide a control circuit which is capable of suppressing acoustic noise that occurs in the coil in the PWM driving operation.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">An embodiment of the present invention relates to a control circuit for a switching power supply configured to supply a driving voltage to one terminal of a light emitting element to be intermittently driven. The control circuit comprises: a pulse modulator configured to generate a pulse signal having a duty ratio adjusted such that a detection voltage that corresponds to the output voltage of the switching power supply matches a predetermined reference voltage in an on period of the light emitting element; and a driver configured to drive a switching element included in the switching power supply, according to the pulse signal. After transition of the light emitting element from the on period to the off period, the pulse modulator reduces the duty ratio of the pulse signal over time.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">With such an embodiment, the length of the on period of the switching element is reduced over time immediately following transition from the on period to the off period. Thus, such an arrangement is capable gradually reducing the coil current, thereby reducing acoustic noise that occurs in the coil.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Also, the pulse modulator may comprise: a feedback terminal via which a phase compensation capacitor and a phase compensation resistor are to be connected; an error amplifier configured to generate a current that corresponds to the difference between the detection voltage and the reference voltage, and to supply the current thus generated to the feedback terminal, in the on period of the light emitting element; a pulse generator configured to receive a voltage that occurs at the feedback terminal, and to generate a pulse signal having a duty ratio that corresponds to the voltage thus received; and a soft-off circuit configured to change the voltage to be input to the pulse generator such that the duty ratio of the pulse signal is reduced after transition of the light emitting element from the on period to the off period.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The pulse generator may be configured as a pulse width modulator, or may be configured as a pulse voltage modulator.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Also, the soft-off circuit may comprise: a soft-off capacitor arranged between an input terminal of the pulse generator and a fixed voltage terminal, and configured to be charged by a voltage that occurs at the feedback terminal in the on period; and a discharge circuit configured to discharge the soft-off capacitor in the off period.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Also, the discharge circuit may be configured to generate a current which is turned on and off according a control signal having the same frequency as that of the pulse signal.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">With such an arrangement, the soft-off capacitor can be discharged using a pulse discharge current. Thus, such an arrangement is capable of adjusting the time constant according to the duty ratio of the control signal. Furthermore, such an arrangement is capable of reducing the duty ratio with each cycle in which the switching transistor M<b>1</b> is switched on and off.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Also, the pulse modulator may further comprise: a first switch arranged between an output terminal of the error amplifier and the feedback terminal, and configured to switch on in the on period and to switch off in the off period; and a second switch arranged between an input terminal of the pulse generator and the feedback terminal, and configured to switch on in the on period and to switch off in the off period.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">With such an arrangement, in the off period in which the first switch and the second switch are turned off, the feedback terminal is set to the high-impedance state, thereby maintaining the voltage at the feedback terminal. Accordingly, when the next transition occurs to the on period, such an arrangement is capable of resuming the feedback control operation with the start point voltage at the feedback terminal being the same voltage as that in the previous on period. Thus, such an arrangement reduces the period of time required to stabilize the feedback operation.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Also, the detection voltage that corresponds to the output voltage of the switching power supply may be a voltage that occurs at the other terminal of the light emitting element. Alternatively, the detection voltage may be a voltage obtained by dividing the output voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Another embodiment of the present invention relates to a light emitting apparatus. The light emitting apparatus comprises: a light emitting element; a switching power supply configured to supply a driving voltage to one terminal of the light emitting element; and a current driving circuit connected to the other terminal of the light emitting element, and configured to supply an intermittent driving current that corresponds to a target luminance. The switching power supply comprises: an output circuit comprising a switching element; and a control circuit according to any one of the aforementioned embodiments, configured to drive the switching element.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Yet another embodiment of the present invention relates to an electronic device. The electronic device comprises: a liquid crystal panel; and the aforementioned light emitting apparatus arranged as a backlight of the liquid crystal panel.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">It is to be noted that any arbitrary combination or rearrangement of the above-described structural components and so forth is effective as and encompassed by the present embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Moreover, this summary of the invention does not necessarily describe all necessary features so that the invention may also be a sub-combination of these described features.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Embodiments will now be described, by way of example only, with reference to the accompanying drawings which are meant to be exemplary, not limiting, and wherein</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">like elements are numbered alike in several Figures, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a circuit diagram which shows an example configuration of a light emitting apparatus according to a comparison technique;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a circuit diagram which shows a configuration of an electronic device including a switching power supply according to an embodiment; and</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a waveform diagram which shows the operation of the light emitting apparatus shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The invention will now be described based on preferred embodiments which do not intend to limit the scope of the present invention but exemplify the invention. All of the features and the combinations thereof described in the embodiment are not necessarily essential to the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In the present specification, the state represented by the phrase &#x201c;the member A is connected to the member B&#x201d; includes a state in which the member A is indirectly connected to the member B via another member that does not substantially affect the electric connection therebetween, or that does not damage the functions or effects of the connection therebetween, in addition to a state in which the member A is physically and directly connected to the member B.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Similarly, the state represented by the phrase &#x201c;the member C is provided between the member A and the member B&#x201d; includes a state in which the member A is indirectly connected to the member C, or the member B is indirectly connected to the member C via another member that does not substantially affect the electric connection therebetween, or that does not damage the functions or effects of the connection therebetween, in addition to a state in which the member A is directly connected to the member C, or the member B is directly connected to the member C.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a circuit diagram which shows a configuration of an electronic device including a switching power supply according to an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">An electronic device <b>2</b> is configured as a battery-driven device such as a laptop PC, a digital still camera, a digital video camera, a cellular phone terminal, a PDA (Personal Digital Assistant), or the like. The electronic device <b>2</b> includes a light emitting apparatus <b>3</b> and an LCD (Liquid Crystal Display) panel <b>5</b>. The light emitting apparatus <b>3</b> is arranged as a backlight of the LCD panel <b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The light emitting apparatus <b>3</b> includes LED strings <b>6</b>_<b>1</b> through <b>6</b><sub>&#x2014;</sub><i>n </i>each configured as a light emitting element, a current driving circuit <b>8</b>, and a switching power supply <b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Each LED string <b>6</b> includes multiple LEDs connected in series. The switching power supply <b>4</b> is configured as a step-up DC/DC converter. The switching power supply <b>4</b> is configured to boost the input voltage (e.g., battery voltage) Vin input to an input terminal P<b>1</b>, and to output an output voltage (driving voltage) Vout via an output terminal P<b>2</b>. One terminal (anode) of each of the multiple LED strings <b>6</b>_<b>1</b> through <b>6</b><sub>&#x2014;</sub><i>n </i>is connected to the output terminal P<b>2</b> so as to form a common anode terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The switching power supply <b>4</b> includes a control IC <b>100</b> and an output circuit <b>102</b>. The output circuit <b>102</b> includes an inductor L<b>1</b>, a rectifier diode D<b>1</b>, a switching transistor M<b>1</b>, and an output capacitor C<b>1</b>. The output circuit <b>102</b> has a typical topology, and accordingly, description thereof will be omitted. The present invention is not restricted to such a topology. Also, various modifications may be made with respect to such a topology, which can be understood by those skilled in this art.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">A switching terminal P<b>4</b> of the control IC <b>100</b> is connected to the gate of the switching transistor M<b>1</b>. The control IC <b>100</b> adjusts the on/off duty ratio of the switching transistor M<b>1</b> by means of a feedback control operation so as to provide the output voltage Vout required to turn on the LED strings <b>6</b>. It should be noted that the switching transistor M<b>1</b> may be configured as a built-in component of the control IC <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The current driving circuit <b>8</b> is connected to the other terminal (cathode) of each of the multiple LED strings <b>6</b>_<b>1</b> through <b>6</b><sub>&#x2014;</sub><i>n. </i>The current driving circuit <b>8</b> respectively supplies, to the LED strings <b>6</b>_<b>1</b> through <b>6</b><sub>&#x2014;</sub><i>n, </i>intermittent driving currents I<sub>LED1 </sub>through I<sub>LEDn </sub>that correspond to the respective target luminance levels. Specifically, the current driving circuit <b>8</b> includes multiple current sources CS<sub>1 </sub>through CS<sub>n </sub>respectively provided to the LED strings <b>6</b>_<b>1</b> through <b>6</b><sub>&#x2014;</sub><i>n, </i>and a PWM controller <b>9</b>. The i-th current source CS<sub>i </sub>is connected to the cathode of the corresponding i-th LED string <b>6</b><sub>&#x2014;</sub><i>i. </i>The current source CS<sub>i </sub>is configured to be capable of switching its state between an operating (active) state &#x3c6;<sub>ON </sub>in which it outputs a driving current I<sub>LEDi </sub>and an off state &#x3c6;<sub>OFF </sub>in which the supply of the driving current I<sub>LEDi </sub>is stopped. The PWM controller <b>9</b> generates control signals PWM<sub>i </sub>through PWM<sub>n </sub>each having a duty ratio that corresponds to the corresponding target luminance level, and outputs the control signals thus generated to the current sources CS<sub>1 </sub>through CS<sub>n</sub>. In a period of time (on period T<sub>ON</sub>) in which the control signal PWM<sub>i </sub>is asserted (set to high level, for example), the corresponding current source CS<sub>i </sub>enters the operating state &#x3c6;<sub>ON</sub>, thereby turning on the LED string <b>6</b><sub>&#x2014;</sub><i>i. </i>In a period of time (off period T<sub>OFF</sub>) in which the control signal PWM<sub>i </sub>is negated (set to low level, for example), the corresponding current source CS<sub>i </sub>is set to the off state &#x3c6;<sub>OFF</sub>, thereby turning off the LED string <b>6</b><sub>&#x2014;</sub><i>i. </i>By controlling the time ratio between the on period T<sub>ON </sub>and the off period T<sub>OFF</sub>, such an arrangement is capable of controlling the effective value (time average) of the driving current I<sub>LED </sub>that flows through the LED string <b>6</b><sub>&#x2014;</sub><i>i, </i>thereby allowing the luminance level to be adjusted. The frequency of the PWM control operation of the current driving circuit <b>8</b> is on the order of several ten to several hundred Hz.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The control IC <b>100</b> and the current driving circuit <b>8</b> are integrated on separate chips. Also, such components may be configured as a single package (module) or may be configured as separate packages. Alternatively, the control IC <b>100</b> and the current driving circuit <b>8</b> may be integrated on a single chip.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The above is the overall configuration of the light emitting apparatus <b>3</b>. Next, description will be made regarding the configuration of the control IC <b>100</b>. The control IC <b>100</b> includes LED terminals LED<sub>1 </sub>through LED<sub>n </sub>respectively provided to the LED strings <b>6</b>_<b>1</b> through <b>6</b><sub>&#x2014;</sub><i>n. </i>Each LED terminal LED<sub>i </sub>is connected to the cathode terminal of the corresponding LED string <b>6</b><sub>&#x2014;</sub><i>i. </i>It should be noted that there is not necessarily a need to provide such multiple LED strings. Also, the light emitting apparatus <b>3</b> may include a single LED string.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The control IC <b>100</b> mainly includes a pulse modulator <b>19</b> and a driver <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The pulse modulator <b>19</b> generates a pulse signal Spwm having a duty ratio adjusted such that a detection voltage that corresponds to the output voltage Vout matches a predetermined reference voltage Vref in the on period T<sub>ON </sub>of the LED strings <b>6</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the detection voltage is the lowest of the voltages (LED terminal voltages) V<sub>LED1 </sub>through V<sub>LEDn </sub>that occur at the cathode terminals of the LED strings <b>6</b>, and will be represented by V<sub>LED </sub>hereafter. It should be noted that, in another embodiment, a different voltage, e.g., a voltage obtained by dividing the output voltage Vout may be used as the detection voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The driver <b>28</b> drives the switching transistor M<b>1</b> according to the pulse signal Spwm.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In the on period T<sub>ON</sub>, the control IC <b>100</b> adjusts the output voltage Vout of the switching power supply <b>4</b> such that it has the optimum voltage level for driving the LED strings <b>6</b>_<b>1</b> through <b>6</b><sub>&#x2014;</sub><i>n. </i></p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In the off period T<sub>OFF</sub>, the driving currents I<sub>LED1 </sub>through I<sub>LEDn </sub>supplied to the respective LED strings <b>6</b>_<b>1</b> through <b>6</b><sub>&#x2014;</sub><i>n </i>become zero, i.e., the switching power supply <b>4</b> enters the no-load state. Accordingly, the control IC <b>100</b> sets the switching transistor M<b>1</b> to the off state.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">When the LED strings <b>6</b> transit from the on period T<sub>ON </sub>to the off period T<sub>OFF</sub>, the pulse modulator <b>19</b> reduces the duty ratio of the pulse signal Spwm over time. If the off period T<sub>OFF </sub>is sufficiently long, the duty ratio of the pulse signal Spwm eventually becomes zero, and the switching transistor M<b>1</b> is set to the off state.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Next, description will be made regarding an example configuration of the pulse modulator <b>19</b> which is capable of providing the aforementioned function.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The pulse modulator <b>19</b> includes an error amplifier <b>22</b>, a pulse generator (pulse width modulator) <b>20</b>, a feedback terminal (FB terminal), a soft-off circuit <b>40</b>, a first switch SW<b>10</b><i>a</i>, and a second switch SW<b>10</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">A phase compensation capacitor C<b>3</b> and a phase compensation resistor R<b>7</b> are arranged between the FB terminal and an external fixed voltage terminal (ground terminal).</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The error amplifier <b>22</b> is a so-called gm amplifier. In the on period of the LED strings <b>6</b>, the error amplifier <b>22</b> generates a current that corresponds to the difference between the detection voltage V<sub>LED </sub>and the reference voltage Vref, and supplies the current thus generated to the FB terminal. A feedback voltage V<sub>FB</sub>, which corresponds to the difference between the detection voltage V<sub>LED </sub>and the reference voltage Vref, occurs at the FB terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Specifically, the error amplifier <b>22</b> includes multiple inverting input terminals (&#x2212;) and a single non-inverting input terminal (+). The LED terminal voltages V<sub>LED1 </sub>through V<sub>LEDn </sub>are input to the respective multiple inverting input terminals, and the reference voltage Vref is input to the non-inverting input terminal. The error amplifier <b>22</b> outputs a current that corresponds to the difference between the lowest LED terminal voltage (detection voltage) V<sub>LED </sub>and the reference voltage Vref.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The first switch SW<b>10</b><i>a </i>is arranged between the output terminal of the error amplifier <b>22</b> and the FB terminal. The second switch SW<b>10</b><i>b </i>is arranged between the input terminal P<b>5</b> of the pulse width modulator <b>20</b> and the FB terminal. The first switch SW<b>10</b><i>a </i>and the second switch SW<b>10</b><i>b </i>are turned on in the on period T<sub>ON</sub>, and are turned off in the off period T<sub>OFF</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The pulse generator <b>20</b> is configured as a pulse width modulator, for example, and is configured to receive the voltage V<sub>FB </sub>that occurs at the FB terminal, and to generate a pulse signal Spwm having a duty ratio that corresponds to the voltage V<sub>FB </sub>thus received. Specifically, as the feedback voltage V<sub>FB </sub>becomes higher, the duty ratio of the pulse signal Spwm becomes larger.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The pulse width modulator <b>20</b> includes an oscillator <b>24</b> and a PWM comparator <b>26</b>. The oscillator <b>24</b> generates a cyclic voltage V<sub>OSC </sub>having a triangle waveform or a sawtooth waveform. Furthermore, the oscillator <b>24</b> outputs a control clock signal CLK that is in synchronization with the cyclic voltage V<sub>OSC</sub>. The high level (low level) period of the control clock signal CLK is preferably adjustable.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The PWM comparator <b>26</b> compares the feedback voltage V<sub>FB </sub>with the cyclic voltage V<sub>OSC</sub>, and generates the PWM signal Spwm having a level that corresponds to the comparison result. It should be noted that a pulse frequency modulator or the like may be employed as the pulse generator <b>20</b>. The frequency of the PWM signal Spwm is sufficiently higher than that of the PWM driving operation of the current driving circuit <b>8</b>. Specifically, the frequency of the PWM signal Spwm is on the order of several hundred kHz (e.g., 600 kHz).</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">When transition occurs from the on period T<sub>ON </sub>to the off period T<sub>OFF</sub>, the soft-off circuit <b>40</b> changes the voltage V<sub>FB</sub>&#x2032; to be input to the pulse width modulator <b>20</b> over time, such that the duty ratio of the pulse signal Spwm is reduced over time. Specifically, the soft-off circuit <b>40</b> reduces the voltage V<sub>FB</sub>&#x2032; over time.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The soft-off circuit <b>40</b> includes a soft-off capacitor C<b>4</b> and a discharge circuit <b>42</b>. The soft-off capacitor C<b>4</b> is arranged between the input terminal P<b>5</b> of the pulse width modulator <b>20</b> and a fixed voltage terminal (ground terminal). In the on period T<sub>ON</sub>, the soft-off capacitor C<b>4</b> is charged by the voltage V<sub>FB </sub>at the FB terminal. That is to say, in the on period T<sub>ON</sub>, the voltage V<sub>FB</sub>&#x2032; input to the pulse modulator <b>19</b> is equal to the voltage V<sub>FB </sub>at the FB terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In the off period T<sub>OFF</sub>, the discharge circuit <b>42</b> discharges the soft-off capacitor C<b>4</b>. Thus, the voltage V<sub>FB</sub>&#x2032; to be input to the pulse width modulator <b>20</b> is reduced over time. The discharge circuit <b>42</b> generates a discharge current I<sub>DIS </sub>which is turned on and off according to a control signal CLK having the same frequency as that of the pulse signal S<sub>PWM</sub>, which is drawn from the soft-off capacitor C<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The discharge circuit <b>42</b> includes a current source <b>44</b> and transistors M<b>4</b> through M<b>6</b>. The current source <b>44</b> generates a constant current Ic. The transistors M<b>4</b> and M<b>5</b> form a current mirror circuit, which is configured to duplicate the constant current Ic with a mirror ratio K, thereby generating the discharge current I<sub>DIS</sub>=K&#xd7;Ic. The switch M<b>6</b> is arranged between the gate and the source of the transistor M<b>5</b>. The control clock signal CLK is input to the gate of the switch M<b>6</b>. When the control clock signal CLK is high level, the switch M<b>6</b> is turned on. In this state, the transistors M<b>4</b> and M<b>5</b> are turned off, and the discharge current I<sub>DIS </sub>thus becomes zero. When the control clock signal CLK is low level, the switch M<b>6</b> is turned off, whereby the discharge current I<sub>DIS </sub>flows.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The above is the configuration of the control IC <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Next, description will be made regarding the operation of the light emitting apparatus <b>3</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a waveform diagram which shows the operation of the light emitting apparatus <b>3</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. From the top and in the following order, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows the control signal PWM, the feedback voltage V<sub>FB </sub>(line of dashes and dots), the input voltage V<sub>FB</sub>&#x2032; of the pulse modulator <b>19</b> (solid line), the pulse signal Spwm (solid line), the output voltage Vout, and the coil current I<sub>L1 </sub>(solid line). The vertical axis and the horizontal axis shown in the waveform diagrams and time charts in the present specification are expanded or reduced as appropriate for ease of understanding. Also, each waveform shown in the drawings is simplified for ease of understanding.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In the on period T<sub>ON </sub>before the time point t<b>1</b>, the output voltage Vout is stabilized so as to satisfy the relation Vout=V<sub>LED</sub>+Vf. Vf represents the voltage drop that occurs at the LED string <b>6</b> in a state in which the driving current I<sub>LED </sub>flows.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">At the time point t<b>1</b>, the pulse signal PWM is switched from high level to low level, whereby transition occurs from the on period T<sub>ON </sub>to the off period T<sub>OFF</sub>. At this timing, the first switch SW<b>10</b><i>a </i>and the second switch SW<b>10</b><i>b </i>are turned off, and thus, the voltage V<sub>FB </sub>at the FB terminal is maintained at a constant voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">When the off period T<sub>OFF </sub>is initiated, the soft-off circuit <b>40</b> reduces the input voltage V<sub>FB</sub>&#x2032; of the pulse modulator <b>19</b> over time. This gradually reduces the duty ratio of the PWM signal Spwm, thereby gradually reducing the coil current I<sub>L1</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">As described above, the soft-off circuit <b>40</b> reduces the voltage V<sub>FB</sub>&#x2032; in synchronization with the PWM signal Spwm. Thus, such an arrangement is capable of gradually reducing the duty ratio of the PWM signal Spwm with each cycle. Furthermore, the amount of change in the duty ratio of the PWM signal Spwm can be adjusted according to the constant current It and the duty ratio of the control clock signal CLK.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">Immediately after transition to the off period T<sub>OFF</sub>, there is a slight rise in the output voltage Vout. This is because there is a slight flow of the coil current I<sub>L1 </sub>when the switching power supply <b>4</b> is in the no-load state.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">When the duty ratio of the PWM signal Spwm becomes zero in the off period T<sub>OFF</sub>, the switching operation of the switching transistor M<b>1</b> stops.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">When the pulse signal PWM transits from the low-level state to the high-level state at the time point t<b>2</b>, the period becomes the on period T<sub>ON</sub>. At this timing, the first switch SW<b>10</b><i>a </i>and the second switch SW<b>10</b><i>b </i>are turned on, thereby returning the input voltage V<sub>FB</sub>&#x2032; of the pulse modulator <b>19</b> to a level that is the same as that of the voltage V<sub>FB </sub>at the FB terminal. As a result, the switching operation of the switching transistor M<b>1</b> is resumed with the pulse signal Spwm having a duty ratio that is approximately the same as that used in the previous on period T<sub>ON</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The above is the operation of the light emitting apparatus <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a waveform diagram showing the waveforms obtained with a conventional circuit, which are represented by the lines of dashes and dots. With conventional techniques, the PWM signal Spwm is fixed to low level immediately after transition to the off period T<sub>OFF</sub>, thereby immediately stopping the switching operation of the switching transistor M<b>1</b>. This leads to a sudden decrease in the coil current I<sub>L1</sub>, which becomes a cause of acoustic noise.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">In contrast, with the light emitting apparatus <b>3</b> according to the embodiment, by gradually reducing the coil current I<sub>L1 </sub>in the off period T<sub>OFF</sub>, such an arrangement is capable of reducing acoustic noise that occurs in the inductor L<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">Description has been made regarding the prevent invention with reference to the embodiments. The above-described embodiments have been described for exemplary purposes only, and are by no means intended to be interpreted restrictively. Rather, various modifications may be made by making various combinations of the aforementioned components or processes. Description will be made below regarding such modifications.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">Description has been made in the embodiment regarding a non-isolated switching power supply employing an inductor. Also, the present invention can be applied to an isolated switching power supply employing a transformer.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">Description has been made in the embodiment regarding an electronic device as an application of the light emitting apparatus <b>3</b>. However, the application of the light emitting apparatus <b>3</b> is not restricted in particular. Also, the light emitting apparatus <b>3</b> can be applied to an illumination device and so forth.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">Description has been made in the embodiment regarding an arrangement in which the soft-off capacitor C<b>4</b> is discharged using the pulse current I<sub>DIS</sub>. Also, the soft-off capacitor C<b>4</b> may be discharged using a continuous current I<sub>DIS</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">The settings of the logical signals, such as the high-level state and the low-level state of the signals, have been described in the present embodiment for exemplary purposes only. The settings can be freely modified by inverting the signals using inverters or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">While the preferred embodiments of the present invention have been described using specific terms, such description is for illustrative purposes only, and it is to be understood that changes and variations may be made without departing from the spirit or scope of the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A control circuit for a switching power supply configured to supply a driving voltage to one terminal of a light emitting element to be intermittently driven, the control circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a pulse modulator configured to generate a pulse signal having a duty ratio adjusted such that a detection voltage that corresponds to an output voltage of the switching power supply matches a predetermined reference voltage in an on period of the light emitting element; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a driver configured to drive a switching element included in the switching power supply, according to the pulse signal,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, after transition of the light emitting element from the on period to an off period, the pulse modulator gradually reduces the duty ratio of the pulse signal over time, and wherein
<claim-text>(i) in the on period, the driver drives the switching element according to the pulse signal such that the detection voltage matches the predetermined reference voltage, and (ii) in the off period, the driver drives the switching element according to the pulse signal having a reduced duty ratio, and wherein the pulse modulator comprises:</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a feedback terminal via which a phase compensation capacitor and a phase compensation resistor are to be connected;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an error amplifier configured to generate a current that corresponds to a difference between the detection voltage and the reference voltage and to supply the current thus generated to the feedback terminal, in the on period of the light emitting element;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pulse generator configured to receive a feedback voltage that occurs at the feedback terminal, and to generate a pulse signal having a duty ratio that corresponds to the feedback voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a soft-off circuit configured to change the feedback voltage gradually such that the duty ratio of the pulse signal is gradually reduced after transition of the light emitting element from the on period to the off period;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first switch arranged between an output terminal of the error amplifier and the feedback terminal, and configured to switch on in the on period and to switch off in the off period; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second switch arranged between an input terminal of the pulse generator and the feedback terminal, and configured to switch on in the on period and to switch off in the off period.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A control circuit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the soft-off circuit comprises:
<claim-text>a soft-off capacitor arranged between an input terminal of the pulse generator and a fixed voltage terminal, and configured to be charged by a voltage that occurs at the feedback terminal in the on period; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a discharge circuit configured to discharge the soft-off capacitor in the off period.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A control circuit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the discharge circuit is configured to generate a current which is turned on and off according a control signal having the same frequency as that of the pulse signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A control circuit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the detection voltage that corresponds to the output voltage of the switching power supply is a voltage that occurs at another terminal of the light emitting element.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A light emitting apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a light emitting element;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a switching power supply configured to supply a driving voltage to one terminal of the light emitting element; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a current driving circuit connected to another terminal of the light emitting element, and configured to supply an intermittent driving current that corresponds to a target luminance,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the switching power supply comprises:
<claim-text>an output circuit comprising a switching element; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control circuit configured to drive the switching element, wherein</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>the control circuit comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pulse modulator configured to generate a pulse signal having a duty ratio adjusted such that a detection voltage that corresponds to an output voltage of the switching power supply matches a predetermined reference voltage in an on period of the light emitting element; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a driver configured to drive a switching element included in the switching power supply, according to the pulse signal,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, after transition of the light emitting element from the on period to an off period, the pulse modulator gradually reduces the duty ratio of the pulse signal over time, and wherein
<claim-text>(i) in the on period, the driver drives the switching element according to the pulse signal such that the detection voltage matches the predetermined reference voltage, and (ii) in the off period, the driver drives the switching element according to the pulse signal having a reduced duty ratio, and wherein the pulse modulator comprises:</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a feedback terminal via which a phase compensation capacitor and a phase compensation resistor are to be connected;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an error amplifier configured to generate a current that corresponds to a difference between the detection voltage and the reference voltage, and to supply the current thus generated to the feedback terminal, in the on period of the light emitting element;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pulse generator configured to receive a feedback voltage that occurs at the feedback terminal, and to generate a pulse signal having a duty ratio that corresponds to the feedback voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a soft-off circuit configured to change the feedback voltage gradually such that the duty ratio of the pulse signal is gradually reduced after transition of the light emitting element from the on period to the off period;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first switch arranged between an output terminal of the error amplifier and the feedback terminal and configured to switch on in the on period and to switch off in the off period; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second switch arranged between an input terminal of the pulse generator and the feedback terminal, and configured to switch on in the on period and to switch off in the off period.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. An electronic device comprising:
<claim-text>a liquid crystal panel; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light emitting apparatus as a backlight of the liquid crystal panel, wherein the light emitting apparatus comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light emitting element;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a switching power supply configured to supply a driving voltage to one terminal of the light emitting element; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a current driving circuit connected to the other terminal of the light emitting element, and configured to supply an intermittent driving current that corresponds to a target luminance,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the switching power supply comprises:
<claim-text>an output circuit comprising a switching element; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control circuit configured to drive the switching element, wherein</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>the control circuit comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pulse modulator configured to generate a pulse signal having a duty ratio adjusted such that a detection voltage that corresponds to an output voltage of the switching power supply matches a predetermined reference voltage in an on period of the light emitting element; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a driver configured to drive a switching element included in the switching power supply, according to the pulse signal,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, after transition of the light emitting element from the on period to an off period, the pulse modulator gradually reduces the duty ratio of the pulse signal over time, and wherein
<claim-text>(i) in the on period, the driver drives the switching element according to the pulse signal such that the detection voltage matches the predetermined reference voltage, and (ii) in the off period, the driver drives the switching element according to the pulse signal having a reduced duty ratio, and wherein the pulse modulator comprises:</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a feedback terminal via which a phase compensation capacitor and a phase compensation resistor are to be connected;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an error amplifier configured to generate a current that corresponds to a difference between the detection voltage and the reference voltage, and to supply the current thus generated to the feedback terminal, in the on period of the light emitting element;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pulse generator configured to receive a feedback voltage that occurs at the feedback terminal, and to generate a pulse signal having a duty ratio that corresponds to the feedback voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a soft-off circuit configured to change the feedback voltage gradually such that the duty ratio of the pulse signal is gradually reduced after transition of the light emitting element from the on period to the off period;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first switch arranged between an output terminal of the error amplifier and the feedback terminal and configured to switch on in the on period and to switch off in the off period; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second switch arranged between an input terminal of the pulse generator and the feedback terminal, and configured to switch on in the on period and to switch off in the off period. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
