<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08621938-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08621938</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13466386</doc-number>
<date>20120508</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>22</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 73862</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Motion conversion system</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3040136</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Grado</name>
<date>19620600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5535047</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hornbeck</name>
<date>19960700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5652671</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Knipe et al.</name>
<date>19970700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5739941</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Knipe et al.</name>
<date>19980400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6533947</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Nasiri et al.</name>
<date>20030300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6647164</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Weaver et al.</name>
<date>20031100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6736521</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Turner</name>
<date>20040500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6867897</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Patel et al.</name>
<date>20050300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6935759</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Staker et al.</name>
<date>20050800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7119940</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Knipe</name>
<date>20061000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7302132</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Miller et al.</name>
<date>20071100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>385 18</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>12</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 73862</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>12</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11963072</doc-number>
<date>20071221</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8171804</doc-number>
<date>20120508</date>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13466386</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>60871588</doc-number>
<date>20061222</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120216637</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120830</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Knipe</last-name>
<first-name>Richard Lee</first-name>
<address>
<city>McKinney</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Knipe</last-name>
<first-name>Richard Lee</first-name>
<address>
<city>McKinney</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Franz</last-name>
<first-name>Warren L.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Brady, III</last-name>
<first-name>Wade J.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="03" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Telecky, Jr.</last-name>
<first-name>Frederick J.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Texas Instruments Incorporated</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Dallas</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Caputo</last-name>
<first-name>Lisa</first-name>
<department>2856</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Davis-Hollington</last-name>
<first-name>Octavia</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A motion conversion system is described. The motion conversion system comprises a first torsional member operative for rotating in a first direction. A second torsional member is offset a distance from the first torsional member, wherein the second torsional member is operative for rotating in a direction opposite from the first direction. And, a lateral member has a lower surface connected to the first and second torsional members. Wherein, translational movement of the lateral member results from rotational movement of the first and second torsional members.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="72.98mm" wi="180.93mm" file="US08621938-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="261.45mm" wi="183.56mm" file="US08621938-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="272.03mm" wi="188.72mm" file="US08621938-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="263.14mm" wi="186.01mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621938-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="264.75mm" wi="183.22mm" file="US08621938-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a division of application Ser. No. 11/963,072, filed Dec. 21, 2007, which claims the benefit of Provisional Application No. 60/871,588, filed Dec. 22, 2006, the entireties of both of which are hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF RELATED ART</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">With the evolution of electronic devices, there is a continual demand for enhanced speed, capacity and efficiency in various areas including electronics, communications, and machinery. Many modern devices include moving components. Efficient operation of these devices may depend upon effectively measuring movement of their components. Techniques for measuring movement may differ depending upon the type of system used. Some systems may have rotational movement that needs to be measured. A microelectromechanical system (MEMS) is usually a system that has electrically controllable micromachines (e.g., a motor, gear, optical modulating element) formed monolithically on a semiconductor substrate using integrated circuit techniques. Measuring movement within a MEMS system may differ substantially from a non-MEMS system. In addition, there are few motion conversion systems that are applicable to various kinds of electrical, mechanical, or electromechanical devices. Moreover, any motion conversion system that is applicable to various environments must also be reliable, robust, and cost effective. Consequently, there remain unmet needs relating to motion conversion systems.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The invention may be better understood with reference to the following figures. The components within the figures are not necessarily to scale, emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the invention. Moreover, in the figures, like reference numerals designate corresponding parts or blocks throughout the different views.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an environmental drawing illustrating a variety of devices that may incorporate a motion conversion system.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A-2D</figref> are block diagrams illustrating various implementations of a motion conversion system.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A-3C</figref> are perspective views of the cooperative movement of a pair of the motion conversion devices.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a detailed view of the pair of motion conversion devices.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross-sectional view of a two-layer implementation of a pair of motion conversion devices.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a cross-sectional view of a one-layer implementation of a pair of motion conversion devices.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a flow chart for a motion conversion technique.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">While the motion conversion system is susceptible to various modifications and alternative forms, specific embodiments have been shown by way of example in the drawings and subsequently are described in detail. It should be understood, however, that the description herein of specific embodiments is not intended to limit the motion conversion system to the particular forms disclosed. In contrast, the intention is to cover all modifications, equivalents, and alternatives falling within the spirit and scope of the motion conversion as defined by this document.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">As used in the specification and the appended claim(s), the singular forms &#x201c;a,&#x201d; &#x201c;an&#x201d; and &#x201c;the&#x201d; include plural referents unless the context clearly dictates otherwise. Similarly, &#x201c;optional&#x201d; or &#x201c;optionally&#x201d; means that the subsequently described event or circumstance may or may not occur, and that the description includes instances where the event or circumstance occurs and instances where it does not.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Torsion generally refers to motion resulting from twisting one end of an object in one direction about a longitudinal axis, while the other end is held motionless or twisted in the opposite direction. Torsional stiffness is an inertial force that may hinder an object from torsional movement. When this stiffness is overcome, torsion may be used to measure movement (e.g., road movement) even when the movement is irregular, or non-uniform.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The present motion conversion system may measure movement by converting rotational motion to translational motion. In general, this system provides a reliable, efficient conversion of rotational motion into translational motion enabling a wide range of applications, such as sensor applications. To accomplish this, the motion conversion system utilizes a hinge architecture that is space-efficient and compact with a high degree of design control and optimization. Furthermore, this motion conversion system may be easily implemented in a wide variety of cost-effective commercial semiconductor fabrication processes. In one implementation, the motion conversion system includes two motion conversion devices, or torsion hinge elements, offset by a finite, fixed distance. The torsional rigidity across a motion conversion device, or torsion hinge element, is independent of deposition stresses and variances. Thus it is uniform. Since the motion conversion system, or dual torsion hinge, is in an offset relationship, this renders the separation distance of the offset torsion hinges an optimizable (or tunable) design parameter. The rigidity of each torsion hinge element within a design may be individually adjusted to provide a desired effect. As a result, the physical relationship of these hinge elements convert rotational movement of an assembly into a linear translational motion, without reliance on complicated, multi-component assemblies.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">This motion conversion system may be integrated into a host of devices. Turning now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, this is an illustrative environmental drawing of a variety of devices that may incorporate a motion conversion system <b>100</b>, such as MEMS device <b>110</b>. This device may have freely moving elements that may move translationally, rotationally, or a combination of these. Often, the translational movement of an individual sensing element within this type of MEMS device <b>110</b> is dependent upon the effective conversion of the rotational motion of these freely moving elements. Since the MEMS device <b>110</b> includes the motion conversion system <b>100</b>, this device may more easily extrapolate and process movement data. Examples of these kinds of MEMS devices may include pressure sensors, accelerometers, inertial sensors, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">More specifically, the fabrication of MEMS device <b>110</b> may begin with the fabrication of a complete complementary metal-oxide semiconductor (CMOS) circuit. Since the motion conversion system <b>100</b> uses torsional motion, the same fabrication processes may be used for the remaining portions of this MEMS device. In other words, these portions, or the MEMS superstructure, may use the same CMOS fabrication process, which enables harmonization between the underlying circuitry and the superstructure. This harmonization reduces effects associated with transitioning from one material to another. More components can be within a same area. As a result, the implementation of a single chip module becomes more likely.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Returning to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the motion conversion system <b>100</b> may also be integrated into other devices. These devices may include a microphone <b>120</b>, speaker <b>130</b>, electromechanical device <b>140</b>, and the like. In fact, the motion conversion system <b>100</b> may be implemented in any kind of system where translational motion is desired, such as variable capacitor <b>150</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The motion conversion system <b>100</b> may be implemented in various configurations as more clearly shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A-2D</figref>. Each of the illustrated motion conversion systems includes one pair of complementary motion conversion devices, such as motion conversion devices <b>205</b>, <b>207</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> illustrates a motion conversion system <b>210</b> that only includes the motion conversion devices <b>205</b>, <b>207</b>. Additional details regarding these complementary motion conversion devices are described in additional detail with regard to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. Each of these motion conversion devices may be a torsional hinge element. The complementary motion conversion devices <b>205</b>, <b>207</b> may be collectively referred to as a dual-offset torsion hinge. In addition, either one, or both, of the motion conversion devices that form the dual-offset torsion hinge may be stationary. For the sake of illustration, neither of the motion conversion devices <b>205</b>, <b>207</b> is shown as stationary. In contrast, the motion conversion system <b>220</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref> includes one stationary, or fixed, motion conversion device and one non-stationary motion conversion device. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2C</figref> illustrates a motion conversion system <b>230</b> that includes two stationary, or fixed, motion conversion devices and one non-stationary motion conversion device. This implementation illustrates that a motion conversion system may include either an even or an odd number of motion conversion devices.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2D</figref> depicts a motion conversion system <b>240</b> that has four dual-offset torsion hinges. While this system includes four of these hinges, the number of hinges included in a motion conversion system <b>240</b> may be 6, 3, 10, or some other suitable number. In fact, the number of hinges may be selected to achieve some overall design objective. In the motion conversion system <b>240</b>, each dual torsion hinge includes one stationary motion conversion device <b>243</b> and one non-stationary motion conversion device <b>245</b>. As described in greater detail with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, rotational movement of the motion conversion devices <b>243</b> may cause a corresponding translation movement of the motion conversion devices <b>245</b>. Since these devices are not stationary, they may freely move vertically or horizontally. When a lateral member <b>247</b> (e.g., a layer, lamina, or the like) is attached to the motion conversion devices <b>245</b>, these devices may collectively displace the lateral member <b>247</b> vertically or horizontally when they are working in concert. For example, the motion conversion devices <b>245</b> may vertically displace the lateral member <b>247</b>. The amount of this displacement may be customized by altering the number of dual-offset torsion hinges, the relative positions of the dual-offset torsion hinges, the types of motion conversion devices (e.g., fixed motion conversion device) within these hinges, the relative positions of these motion conversion devices within each dual offset hinge, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Turning now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, this figure illustrates the cooperative movement between motion conversion devices within a motion conversion system, such as an offset torsion hinge <b>300</b>. As mentioned with regard to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A-2D</figref>, a motion conversion system (e.g., motion conversion system <b>230</b>) may include at least two motion conversion devices that operate cooperatively. Similarly, the offset torsion hinge <b>300</b> may include multiple motion conversion devices, such as 3, 6, 11, or some other suitable number of motion conversion devices. As an example, the offset torsion hinge <b>300</b> includes two motion conversion devices labeled <b>310</b>, <b>320</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The offset torsion hinge <b>300</b> includes a stationary motion conversion device and a nonstationary motion conversion device. The stationary motion conversion device has a stationary hinge support <b>310</b>; the nonstationary motion conversion device has a movable hinge support <b>320</b>. A lever <b>330</b> is pivotably connected to the stationary support <b>310</b> and fixably attached to the movable support <b>320</b>. A lateral member <b>340</b> extends from the lever <b>330</b>, with a tongue portion of the lever <b>330</b> captured between a bifurcated portion vertically spaced from a cross portion extending between the bifurcations of the bifurcated portion. When this lever pivots about a hinge axis defined by the stationary support <b>310</b>, the lever <b>330</b> vertically displaces the movable support <b>320</b>, which correspondingly displaces the lateral member <b>340</b>. This movement is more clearly seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3B-3C</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref> illustrates how this lever's pivoting in the direction shown by the arrow causes downward displacement of the movable support <b>320</b>. This downward displacement produces a corresponding downward displacement of the lateral member <b>340</b>. Similarly, pivoting the lever <b>330</b> in the opposite direction causes an upward displacement of the movable support <b>320</b> and the lateral member <b>340</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A-3C</figref>, the offset torsion hinge effectively converts rotational motion to translational motion. More specifically, the pivoting motion of the lever <b>330</b> produces a translational displacement of the movable support <b>320</b>. This correspondingly produces a translational displacement of the lateral member <b>340</b>. These displacements may depend on several factors, which enable this displacement to be customized. For example, the displacement may depend on the distance between the stationary support <b>310</b> and the movable support <b>320</b>. Additional information regarding customizing the displacement is described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a detailed view of a motion conversion system <b>400</b> when implemented in a MEMS device, such as MEMS device <b>110</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). Though some aspects of this motion conversion device are described with reference to the MEMS device <b>110</b>, the motion conversion device <b>300</b> may be integrated into many other types of devices as described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a motion conversion system <b>400</b> is implemented in a dual-offset torsion hinge architecture. This motion conversion system includes a first segment <b>401</b> that has a first MEMS component <b>402</b> coupled to a second MEMS component <b>404</b> by a hinge element <b>406</b>. Though not shown, the motion conversion system <b>400</b> may include numerous other motion conversion devices, as described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A-2C</figref>. For purposes of explanation and illustration, the MEMS component <b>402</b> may be a freely moving MEMS structure (e.g., an inertial sensor component) and the MEMS component <b>404</b> may be considered a fixed support structure.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The relation among the first MEMs component <b>402</b>, the second MEMS component <b>404</b>, and the hinge component <b>406</b> is described in greater detail. A first end <b>408</b> of the hinge element <b>406</b> is coupled to the component <b>404</b> at a first attachment portion <b>410</b> and a second attachment portion <b>412</b>. The attachment portions <b>410</b>, <b>412</b> are in opposing relation to one another on opposite sides of the end <b>408</b>. They are also offset by a distance <b>414</b>. A second end <b>416</b> of the hinge element <b>406</b> is coupled to the component <b>402</b> at a first attachment portion <b>418</b> and a second attachment portion <b>420</b>. Like the attachment portions <b>410</b>, <b>412</b>, the attachment portions <b>418</b>, <b>420</b> are also in opposing relation to one another on opposite sides of the end <b>416</b>. They are offset by a distance <b>422</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Within the motion conversion device <b>400</b>, the range of motion may be customized for optimal performance. There is a clearance distance <b>424</b> between the component <b>402</b> and the component <b>404</b>. Together this clearance distance and the length of the element <b>406</b> may be selected produce a desired range of motion. More specifically, the distance <b>426</b> between the ends <b>410</b> and the end <b>418</b> may vary the desired range of motion. The desired range of motion corresponds to the displacement described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A-3C</figref>. In other words, the clearance distance <b>424</b>, the length of the component <b>404</b>, or the distance <b>426</b>, may be selected such that a desired displacement, or range of motion, is achieved.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> merely illustrates one design of the illustrated components, though numerous alternatives may result from varying this illustration. For example, the form factor and geometry of the hinge element <b>406</b> may be varied greatly for performance reasons. In the embodiment depicted, the hinge element <b>406</b> includes a central offset portion <b>428</b> that extends symmetrically and orthogonally from the central section of the hinge element <b>406</b>. This current implementation can impact this element's flexion properties, such as properties that limit a rotational range of motion. Altering these properties for the hinge element <b>406</b> may affect its movement. To change the flexion properties, many aspects of the hinge element <b>406</b> can be altered. For example, the central offset portion <b>428</b> may be smaller, have a different geometry, or the like. Even still, the central offset portion <b>428</b> can be completely eliminated, such that the hinge element <b>406</b> only includes a central beam section. In the embodiment depicted, the geometries of the constituent parts of the hinge element <b>406</b> (e.g., end <b>408</b>, end <b>416</b>, and central offset portion <b>428</b>) utilize right-angled junctions; these parts of the hinge element <b>406</b> are also symmetric in nature. In alternative embodiments, however, these parts may utilize acute angles, obtuse angles, combinations of acute and obtuse angles, or various curvatures at element junctions. Alternatively, these parts or portions of these parts may have completely asymmetric geometries, partially asymmetric geometries, or the like. Any of these variations can impact the flexion properties and correspondingly impact the movement.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Returning to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the MEMS component <b>402</b>, the MEMS component <b>404</b>, and the hinge element <b>406</b> are coplanar structures with identical thicknesses. In an alternative embodiment, they may not be coplanar structures. Moreover, the thickness of one or more of them may be different. For example, the hinge element <b>406</b> may have a smaller thickness than the MEMS component <b>402</b>; this MEMS component may have a smaller thickness than the MEMS component <b>404</b>. In another alternative embodiment, the MEMS component <b>402</b>, the MEMS component <b>404</b>, and the hinge element <b>406</b> may be formed from different materials or from the same material. For example, they may be formed from semi-conducting materials. In another alternative embodiment, these MEMS components may be formed from a semi-conducting material and the hinge element <b>406</b> may be formed from a different material.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The hinge element <b>406</b> converts rotational movement to translational movement. More specifically, the hinge element <b>406</b> is designed and formed such that it converts rotational movement about an axis (B-B) <b>431</b> (analogous to rotational movement about the axis of stationary support <b>310</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A-3C</figref>) into translational movement in a direction orthogonal to axis <b>431</b> and also orthogonal to a shared axis (A-A) <b>430</b> along which the MEMS components <b>402</b>, <b>404</b>, <b>406</b> are aligned. For example, a device (not shown) may have the MEMS component <b>404</b> fixed for rotation about an axis (B-B) within it. Movement of this device may elicit a rotational movement in the direction of the arrow <b>432</b> about the axis <b>431</b> at the end <b>408</b>. Since the MEMS component <b>404</b> is fixed, the dimensions and geometry of the hinge element <b>406</b> causes a corresponding, complementary rotational movement <b>434</b> about an axis (C-C) <b>433</b> at the end <b>416</b>. A net effect is translational movement depicted by the arrow <b>436</b> in a direction orthogonal to the rotational axes (B-B) <b>431</b> and (C-C) <b>433</b>, and also orthogonal to the shared alignment axis <b>430</b>. While only briefly described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a detailed description of this type of motion was described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A-3C</figref>. The complementary rotational movement <b>434</b> of the first MEMS component will then similarly elicit a corresponding, complementary rotational movement in the next MEMS component, and so on, until a rotational movement <b>438</b> depicted by arrow <b>438</b> about an axis (D-D) <b>435</b> is elicited in a last motion conversion device aligned along axis (A-A) <b>430</b>. (The rotational direction <b>438</b> indicated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> which is the same as direction <b>434</b> assumes an even number of MEMS components in the depicted system <b>400</b>.)</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The design of the hinge element <b>406</b> facilitates customization of the motion conversion device <b>400</b>. In effect, stretching, or flexing, portions of the hinge element <b>406</b> increases the torsional stress of that element. As this element rigidity increases, there is a greater resistance to additional movement. This resistance is self-limiting. The self-limiting properties of this hinge element are particularly evident as the ends <b>408</b>, <b>416</b> are flexed. Therefore, one can select the material, design, and geometry of the hinge element <b>406</b>, such that a desired goal (e.g., a designated amount of translational movement) is accomplished using the self-limiting properties of this hinge element.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">While the self-limiting properties of the hinge element <b>406</b> is described with reference to a motion conversion system <b>400</b> within a MEMS device, these concepts are equally applicable to the motion conversion systems described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3C</figref>. In fact, the motion conversion system <b>400</b> is applicable to variations and adaptations depending upon specific MEMS design or operational objectives. This motion conversion system may be easily integrated in most high-volume commercial semiconductor fabrication processes. To optimize it for a particular system, any one of above-mentioned factors can be adjusted including the self-limiting properties.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross-sectional view of a two-layer implementation of a motion conversion system <b>500</b>. In this embodiment, the MEMS device <b>402</b> and the MEMS device <b>404</b> are formed in a first device layer, such as metal layer M<b>4</b>. In contrast, the hinge element <b>406</b> with ends <b>408</b>, <b>416</b> is formed in a parallel and adjoining device layer, such as metal layer M<b>5</b>. Metal layer M<b>5</b> is positioned above the metal layer M<b>4</b>. As mentioned above, the same material may be selected for both metal layer M<b>4</b> and metal layer M<b>5</b>. Alternatively, different materials may be selected for these layers. The selection of the material for each layer as well as other factors, such as the thickness of the layer, may be done to achieve design goals.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Turning now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, this figure is a cross-sectional view of a one-layer implementation of a motion conversion system <b>600</b>. In other words, this embodiment depicts a hinge element <b>406</b> that is coplanar with the MEMS device <b>402</b> and the MEMS device <b>404</b>. This hinge element is in parallel, but adjoining, planar relation with these MEMS devices.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Turning now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, this figure is a flow chart <b>700</b> for a motion conversion technique that can be accomplished with any of the previously discussed motion conversion devices. This technique effectively converts rotational motion to translational motion. Any process descriptions or blocks in flow charts can be understood as representing modules, or segments, which may include one or more executable instructions for implementing specific logical functions or blocks in the process. Alternative implementations are included within the scope of the invention in which functions may be executed out of order from that shown or discussed, including substantially concurrently or in reverse order, depending on the functionality involved, as can be understood by those reasonably skilled in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The motion conversion technique of flow chart <b>700</b> begins at block <b>710</b> by positioning a first support. This first support may be either a stationary support, movable support, or the like. In fact, this support may be a support within any of the motion conversion devices described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-6</figref>. Selecting the position for this support may be based upon certain system related assessments, such as the area available and amount of movement desired. For example, the position for this support member may differ when it is within the microphone <b>120</b> than when it is within a MEMS device <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Block <b>710</b> is followed by block <b>720</b>. In this block a first lever is pivotably coupled to the first support. In other words, this lever is coupled to the first support in a manner that enables the lever to pivot about the first support. The physical properties of this lever as well as the manner in which it is coupled to the first support may be selected to comply with design objectives, system constraints, or performance objectives. An example of this lever may be lever <b>330</b> described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> or the hinge element <b>406</b> described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4-6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Block <b>730</b> follows block <b>720</b>. In an alternative embodiment (not shown), block <b>720</b> and block <b>730</b> may be completed contemporaneously. In block <b>730</b>, a second support is positioned at an offset distance from the first support. Like the first support, the second support may be a stationary support, movable support, or the like. In addition, the offset distance between the first support and the second support may be selected to generate design constraints. For example, the offset distance between these supports may be selected to produce a certain amount of translational motion from rotational motion.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Block <b>740</b> follows block <b>730</b>. In an alternative embodiment, block <b>730</b> and block <b>740</b> may be completed contemporaneously. Block <b>750</b> follows block <b>740</b>. These blocks work together to help facilitate the conversion of rotational motion to translational motion. As the lever pivots, it correspondingly moves an extender coupled to the lever. Moving the extender displaces a translational member coupled to the extender. The extender and translational member can be jointly referred to as the lateral member <b>340</b> described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. Selecting the physical properties of the extender and the translational member may also be based on design constraints. For example, the dimensions of these members may be customized in light of a desired amount of translational motion.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">While various embodiments of the motion conversion system have been described, it may be apparent to those of ordinary skill in the art that many more embodiments and implementations are possible that are within the scope of this system. Although certain aspects of the motion conversion system may be described in relation to specific techniques or structures, the teachings and principles of the present system are not limited solely to such examples. All such modifications are intended to be included within the scope of this disclosure and the present motion conversion system and protected by the following claim(s).</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A microelectromechanical system (MEMS) device, comprising:
<claim-text>a first hinge support;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first lever supported on the first hinge support for pivotal movement about a first hinge axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second hinge support laterally spaced from the first support;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second lever supported on the second hinge support for pivotal movement about a second hinge axis; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lateral member having a first end supported on a first end of the first lever for pivotal movement about a third hinge axis, and having a second end supported on a first end of the second lever for pivotal movement about a fourth hinge axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first hinge support, first lever, second hinge support, second lever and lateral member being relatively configured and dimensioned so that movement of second ends of the first and second levers in a direction will pivot the first ends of the first and second levers to cause movement of the lateral member in an opposite direction.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first, second, third and fourth hinge axes are horizontal axes, and the movement of the second ends of the first and second levers in a vertical direction will cause movement of the lateral member in an opposite vertical direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein each of the first and second ends of the lateral member includes a bifurcated portion vertically spaced from a cross portion extending between bifurcations of the bifurcated portion; and each of the first and second levers includes a tongue portion captured between the respective bifurcated and cross portions of the first and second ends of the lateral member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A microelectromechanical system (MEMS) device, comprising:
<claim-text>a first hinge support fixed in stationary position;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first lever having first and second ends, the second end supported on the first hinge support for pivotal movement about a first hinge axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second hinge support laterally spaced from the first hinge support, the second hinge support being movable relative to the semiconductor substrate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lateral member having a first end supported on the first end of the first lever for pivotal movement about a second hinge axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first hinge support, first lever, second hinge support and lateral member being relatively configured and dimensioned so that movement of a second end of the first lever in a direction will pivot the first end of the first lever to cause movement of the lateral member in an opposite direction.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second hinge axes are horizontal axes, and the movement of the second end of the first lever in a vertical direction will cause movement of the lateral member in an opposite vertical direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the first end of one of the first lever and the lateral member includes a bifurcated portion vertically spaced from a cross portion extending between bifurcations of the bifurcated portion; and the other of the first lever and the lateral member includes a tongue portion captured between the respective bifurcated and cross portions of the first end of the one of the first lever and lateral member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the one of the first lever and the lateral member is the lateral member, and the other of the first lever and the lateral member is the first lever.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the second hinge support is defined by the cross portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the first hinge support is fixed on a substrate comprising a semiconductor material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the substrate includes integrated circuit components.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the first hinge support, first lever, second hinge support and lateral member are formed as a MEMS superstructure over underlying complementary metal-oxide semiconductor (CMOS) integrated circuit components.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the device comprises at least one of a pressure sensor, a speaker, an accelerometer, a variable capacitor or a microphone. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
