<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625373-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625373</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13324550</doc-number>
<date>20111213</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>70</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>11</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>365205</main-classification>
<further-classification>365203</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Voltage shifting sense amplifier for SRAM VMIN improvement</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6141259</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Scott et al.</name>
<date>20001000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36518906</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7889574</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Byeon et al.</name>
<date>20110200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36518906</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8339872</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Yun et al.</name>
<date>20121200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36518911</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0233754</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kwon</name>
<date>20041100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>365205</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0133809</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Goel et al.</name>
<date>20110600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>327307</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0141830</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Chi et al.</name>
<date>20110600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36518911</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2012/0275251</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Jin et al.</name>
<date>20121100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>365203</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00008">
<othercit>Suzuki, T., et al. &#x201c;ISSCC 2005/Session 26/Static Memory/26.6,&#x201d; 2005 IEEE International Solid-State Circuits Conference, 2005, pp. 484-485 and 612.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>18</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>365203</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>365205</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>7</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130148452</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130613</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Schreiber</last-name>
<first-name>Russell J.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Austin</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Schreiber</last-name>
<first-name>Russell J.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Austin</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Abel Law Group, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Advanced Micro Devices, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Sunnyvale</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Mai</last-name>
<first-name>Son</first-name>
<department>2827</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A sense amplifier for a SRAM device includes a PMOS differential pair and an NMOS differential pair to support operation with bit line precharge voltage as low as a few hundred millivolts without performance degradation, and generates a full rail output signal without any additional level shifter circuits. The PMOS differential amplifier includes tail current device coupled to a voltage higher than the bit line precharge voltage, and the NMOS differential amplifier includes tail current device coupled to a voltage lower than the bit line precharge voltage.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="125.73mm" wi="179.24mm" file="US08625373-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="225.47mm" wi="192.11mm" file="US08625373-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="243.16mm" wi="141.73mm" file="US08625373-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="259.50mm" wi="157.40mm" file="US08625373-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="256.12mm" wi="182.54mm" file="US08625373-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="122.60mm" wi="169.59mm" file="US08625373-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to sense amplifier circuits for memory devices, and more particular relates to sense amplifier circuits for static random access memory (SRAM) integrated circuit devices.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a block diagram for an SRAM memory device <b>100</b>. A memory array <b>102</b> includes a plurality of word lines <b>105</b> (also frequently referred to as &#x201c;row lines&#x201d; or &#x201c;rows&#x201d;) and a plurality of complementary bit line pairs <b>110</b> (also frequently referred to as &#x201c;column lines&#x201d; or &#x201c;columns&#x201d;). One such word line <b>132</b> is shown, which is also labeled as WLx. One such complementary bit line pair <b>136</b>, <b>134</b> is shown, which includes a true bit line <b>136</b> (also labeled as BLxT) and a complement bit line <b>134</b> (also labeled as BLxC). The memory array <b>102</b> includes a plurality of memory cells (such as memory cell <b>130</b>) each coupled to an associated word line (such as word line <b>132</b>) and coupled to an associated complementary bit line pair (such as bit line pair <b>136</b>, <b>134</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">A row decoder <b>104</b> receives and decodes a plurality M of row addresses <b>106</b> to generate the plurality 2<sup>M </sup>of word lines <b>105</b>, one of which is selected and driven to an active level during a memory operation (e.g., a read or write), and the remaining word lines are unselected and driven or maintained at an inactive level. The word line <b>130</b> may be viewed as the selected word line, which is typically driven to an active level equal to the VDD voltage, while unselected word lines <b>105</b> are typically held at an inactive level equal to the ground reference voltage (i.e., typically &#x201c;held at ground&#x201d;).</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">A column decoder and multiplexer <b>112</b> receives and decodes a plurality N of column addresses <b>108</b> to select one or more of the plurality 2<sup>N </sup>of complementary bit line pairs <b>110</b>, and couple the selected bit line pairs via interconnections <b>113</b> to a group of sense amplifiers <b>114</b>. In a read operation, the respective output from each sense amplifier <b>114</b> is coupled via interconnections <b>116</b> to a respective one of a group of input/output circuits <b>118</b> to drive the respective inputs/outputs <b>120</b>. In a write operation, data to be written is presented to the inputs/outputs <b>120</b>, buffered by the input/output circuits <b>118</b> and conveyed to the sense amplifiers/write drivers <b>114</b>, and coupled through the column decoder and multiplexer <b>112</b> to the one or more selected complementary bit line pairs <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">A control circuit <b>122</b> serves to control the operation of the various components of the SRAM memory device <b>100</b> in its various modes of operation, such as a read mode, a write mode, and a standby mode, in response to one or more control signal inputs (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a common six-transistor CMOS memory cell <b>130</b>, and a traditional sense amplifier <b>114</b> are shown for such a SRAM memory device <b>100</b>. The memory cell <b>130</b> includes a pair of cross-coupled inverters, and a pair of passgate transistors (also known as &#x201c;access transistors&#x201d;). One such inverter is formed by P-channel transistor <b>144</b> and N-channel transistor <b>146</b>, and the other inverter is formed by P-channel transistor <b>145</b> and N-channel transistor <b>147</b>. The two cross-coupled nodes <b>141</b>, <b>143</b> are coupled respectively to bit lines <b>136</b>, <b>134</b> by respective access transistors <b>140</b>, <b>142</b> whose gate terminals are coupled to the word line <b>132</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">If selected in a read mode of operation, the bit line pair <b>136</b>, <b>134</b> is coupled through the column multiplexer <b>112</b> to nodes <b>152</b>, <b>154</b> of sense amplifier <b>114</b>. The three P-channel transistors <b>164</b>, <b>165</b>, <b>166</b> together form an equilibration circuit to equilibrate the internal sense amplifier nodes <b>154</b>, <b>156</b> and to precharge both such nodes to VDD when enabled by an active-low precharge signal PCX conveyed on node <b>168</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Transistors <b>156</b>, <b>158</b>, <b>160</b>, <b>162</b>, <b>163</b> together form a latching differential amplifier which is enabled by asserting an active-high enable signal SAEN on node <b>172</b>. Since the internal sense amplifier nodes <b>152</b>, <b>154</b> are equilibrated to VDD between sensing operations, when sensing begins both P-channel transistors <b>156</b>, <b>158</b> are turned off. The two N-channel transistors <b>160</b>, <b>162</b> form a differential pair, and transistor <b>163</b> serves to provide the tail current for transistors <b>160</b>, <b>162</b>. The sense amplifier node <b>152</b>, <b>154</b> having the lower voltage (as a result of the data state of memory cell <b>130</b>) is driven to ground, and the other sense amplifier node <b>152</b>, <b>154</b> having the higher voltage is driven to (or maintained at) VDD.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">When bit lines are precharged to a relatively &#x201c;high&#x201d; VDD voltage, a selected memory cell may experience a read stability failure due to the voltage divider formed by the passgate transistor and the inverter pull-down transistor in the bitcell. For example, if a logic &#x201c;1&#x201d; is stored in the memory cell <b>130</b>, internal bitcell node <b>141</b> is high (VDD) and internal bitcell node <b>143</b> is low (ground). Both bit lines <b>136</b>, <b>134</b> are precharged to VDD before the read operation begins. When the selected word line <b>132</b> is driven to VDD, transistors <b>142</b> and <b>147</b> form a voltage divider that tends to raise the voltage of internal node <b>143</b> from ground to a voltage higher than ground, since the gate terminals of both transistors <b>142</b> and <b>147</b> are at VDD, the drain terminal of transistor <b>142</b> is at VDD, and the source terminal of transistor <b>147</b> is at ground. Node <b>143</b> may easily rise in voltage to a significant fraction of the VDD voltage, depending upon the ratio of transistors <b>142</b> and <b>147</b>. If the voltage of node <b>143</b> is raised high enough, it may cause instability in the cross-coupled latch and cause the memory cell <b>130</b> to flip states, thereby causing an error in the memory array.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">However, if bit lines are precharged to a voltage lower than VDD, the common-mode voltages of the true and complement sense amplifier nodes (which largely follows the common-mode voltage of the selected bit line pair) may be too low to &#x201c;steer&#x201d; the N-channel differential amplifier (i.e., transistors <b>160</b>, <b>162</b>, and <b>163</b>) when enabled by the SAEN signal, or at best may cause the N-channel differential amplifier to function very slowly. In addition, a short-circuit current (i.e., &#x201c;crowbar&#x201d; current) may flow through the sense amplifier output inverters as a result of the non-rail input voltage of such inverters. In this context, VDD is the voltage to which the selected word line is driven, and which is used to power the memory cells in the array.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">As process technology improvement has steadily reduced the critical line widths and feature sizes, the VDD operating window has become smaller, and proper circuit operation has become more difficult to obtain.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF EMBODIMENTS OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Precharging bit lines in an SRAM to a voltage lower than VDD (e.g., between VDD and VDD-V<sub>TN </sub>of the memory cell passgate transistors) can dramatically improve the read stability dependent V<sub>MIN </sub>of the memory cell. However, doing so has historically caused sense amplifier problems because the common-mode bit line voltage is too low and causes the sense amplifier circuit to malfunction, or function very slowly.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">An improved sense amplifier for a SRAM device includes a PMOS differential pair and an NMOS differential pair to support operation with bit line precharge voltage as low as a few hundred millivolts without performance degradation, and generates a full rail output signal without any additional level shifter circuits. The PMOS differential amplifier includes tail current device coupled to a voltage higher than the bit line precharge voltage, and the NMOS differential amplifier includes tail current device coupled to a voltage lower than the bit line precharge voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In one aspect, the invention provides a sensing circuit. An exemplary sensing circuit includes a first sense amplifier circuit that includes: a cross-coupled pair of PMOS transistors cross-coupling a first node and a second node to a PMOS common-source node; a cross-coupled pair of NMOS transistors cross-coupling the first node and the second node to an NMOS common-source node; a precharge circuit configured to precharge the first and second nodes to a first voltage; a PMOS tail transistor responsive to an active-low sense enable signal and coupling the PMOS common-source node to a second voltage higher in magnitude than said first voltage; and an NMOS tail transistor responsive to an active-high sense enable signal and coupling the NMOS common-source node to a third voltage lower in magnitude than said first voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In another aspect, the invention provides a computer-readable storage medium encoding of such a sensing circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In another aspect, the invention provides a memory device including such a sensing circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In another aspect, the invention provides a method for sensing a differential signal in a SRAM device. An exemplary method includes: precharging a first node and a second node to a first voltage; then developing a differential signal on the first and second nodes; then enabling a tail current for a cross-coupled PMOS differential transistor pair coupled to the first and second nodes, to drive a common source node of the cross-coupled PMOS differential transistor pair toward a second voltage higher than the first voltage; and enabling a tail current for a cross-coupled NMOS differential transistor pair coupled to the first and second nodes, to drive a common source node of the cross-coupled NMOS differential transistor pair toward a third voltage lower than the first voltage; wherein the cross-coupled PMOS differential transistor pair and the cross-coupled NMOS differential transistor pair cooperate to drive one of the first and second nodes to the second voltage, and the other of the first and second nodes to the third voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In another aspect, the invention provides a method for making an integrated circuit product that incorporates a sensing circuit. An exemplary method includes: providing a first sense amplifier circuit comprising: a cross-coupled pair of PMOS transistors cross-coupling a first node and a second node to a PMOS common-source node; a cross-coupled pair of NMOS transistors cross-coupling the first node and the second node to an NMOS common-source node; a precharge circuit configured to precharge the first and second nodes to a first voltage; a PMOS tail transistor responsive to an active-low sense enable signal and coupling the PMOS common-source node to a second voltage higher in magnitude than said first voltage; and an NMOS tail transistor responsive to an active-high sense enable signal and coupling the NMOS common-source node to a third voltage lower in magnitude than said first voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The inventive aspects described herein are specifically contemplated to be used alone as well as in various combinations. The invention in several aspects is contemplated to include circuits (including integrated circuits), related methods of operation, methods for making such circuits, systems incorporating same, and computer-readable storage media encodings of such circuits and methods and systems, all as described herein in greater detail and as set forth in the appended claims.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The foregoing is a summary and thus contains, by necessity, simplifications, generalizations and omissions of detail. Consequently, those skilled in the art will appreciate that the foregoing summary is illustrative only and is not intended to be in any way limiting of the invention. It is only the claims, including all equivalents, in this or any application claiming priority to this application, that are intended to define the scope of the inventions supported by this application.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, labeled prior art, is a block diagram of an SRAM memory device.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, labeled prior art, is a schematic diagram of a SRAM memory cell and sense amplifier.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic diagram of a sense amplifier in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a waveform diagram illustrating the operation of the sense amplifier depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a schematic diagram of a sense amplifier in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a schematic diagram of a sense amplifier in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a block diagram showing a group of sense amplifiers in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The use of the same reference symbols in different drawings indicates similar or identical items.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, an improved sense amplifier <b>150</b> includes a P-channel &#x201c;tail current&#x201d; device <b>178</b> whose source terminal is coupled to a VSENSEP voltage. Such a P-channel device <b>178</b> may also be viewed as a &#x201c;head current&#x201d; device <b>178</b> since it is coupled to a higher voltage. A precharge circuit <b>151</b> is enabled by precharge signal PCX to precharge and equilibrate the complementary sense amplifier nodes <b>152</b>, <b>154</b> to a precharge voltage VPC that is less than the VSENSEP voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">As before, the N-channel transistors <b>160</b>, <b>162</b>, <b>163</b> form a differential amplifier, with transistor <b>163</b> providing the tail current for transistors <b>160</b>, <b>162</b> when enabled by the SAEN signal. However, the P-channel transistors <b>156</b>, <b>158</b>, <b>178</b> now form a second differential amplifier, with transistor <b>178</b> providing the tail current for PMOS transistors <b>156</b>, <b>158</b> when enabled by the SAENX signal (i.e., an active-low enable signal).</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Operation of this circuit is illustrated by the voltage waveforms shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. The internal sense amplifier nodes <b>152</b>, <b>154</b> and the complementary bit lines BLT/BLC are equilibrated at the VPC voltage before a read operation begins. The precharge signal PCX is de-asserted to turn off the precharge circuit <b>151</b>, then the selected word line is driven to its active voltage to cause the selected memory cell to begin to discharge one of the true or complement bit lines, and hence the true and complement sense amplifier nodes <b>152</b>, <b>154</b>. When the sense amplifier <b>150</b> is enabled by asserting both the active-high SAEN signal and the active-low SAENX signal, one or both of the PMOS and NMOS differential amplifiers provide gain. If the VPC voltage is relatively high (relative to the VSENSEP voltage), the respective voltages on the true and complement sense amplifier nodes <b>152</b>, <b>154</b> are high enough to &#x201c;steer&#x201d; the N-channel differential amplifier (i.e., transistors <b>160</b>, <b>162</b>, and <b>163</b>) with reasonable speed, but may not be low enough (relative to the VSENSEP voltage) to effectively &#x201c;steer&#x201d; the P-channel differential amplifier since transistors <b>156</b>, <b>158</b> may be turned off (although when node <b>152</b> or <b>154</b> reaches the VSENSEN voltage, transistor <b>158</b> or <b>156</b> is turned on to drive node <b>154</b> or <b>152</b> to the VSENSEP voltage). Conversely, if the VPC voltage is relatively low (relative to the VSENSEP voltage), the respective voltages on the true and complement sense amplifier nodes <b>152</b>, <b>154</b> may not be high enough to effectively &#x201c;steer&#x201d; the N-channel differential amplifier, but are low enough to &#x201c;steer&#x201d; the P-channel differential amplifier (i.e., transistors <b>156</b>, <b>158</b>, and <b>178</b>) with reasonable speed (although when node <b>152</b> or <b>154</b> reaches the VSENSEP voltage, transistor <b>162</b> or <b>160</b> is turned on to drive node <b>154</b> or <b>152</b> to the VSENSEN voltage). Consequently, the sense amplifier <b>150</b> functions as a latching amplifier that also includes a voltage shift function. In other words, the internal sense amplifier nodes <b>152</b>, <b>154</b> are established at an intermediate voltage (relative to VSENSEP and VSENSEN), but during sensing the sense amplifier node having the higher voltage is driven to the VSENSEP voltage, and the sense amplifier node having the lower voltage is driven to the VSENSEN voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The SAEN and SAENX signals are preferably asserted at about the same time so that, to amplify the differential voltage between the internal sense amplifier nodes <b>152</b>, <b>154</b>, there is both a path to VSENSEN through the NMOS differential amplifier and a path to VSENSEP through the PMOS differential amplifier. In some embodiments, the VSENSEP voltage may be the VDD voltage, the VSENSEN voltage may be ground, and the VPC voltage may be an intermediate voltage between VDD and ground. In certain embodiments, the VPC voltage may be the VDD voltage, the VSENSEN voltage may be ground, and the VSENSEP voltage may be a voltage greater than VDD, such as boosted voltage from a charge pump, or from another external power supply.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, a sense amplifier <b>200</b> is shown in which the VSENSEP voltage is VDD, the VSENSEN voltage is ground, and the VPC voltage is an intermediate voltage between VDD and ground. The P-channel transistors <b>164</b>, <b>165</b>, <b>166</b> form a precharge circuit enabled by an active-low sense amplifier precharge signal SAPCX. A driver circuit <b>190</b> includes an inverter circuit <b>182</b>, <b>184</b> that is enabled by an active-high driver enable signal DRVEN coupled to transistor <b>186</b>, to drive an output node <b>188</b> with a complement read data signal RDDATAX. The DRVEN signal may be asserted when the SAEN/SAENX signals are asserted, or slightly after the sense amplifier enable signals are asserted. This prevents the mid-rail voltage of the sense amplifier nodes from causing a current spike (i.e., a &#x201c;crowbar current&#x201d;) through the inverter <b>182</b>, <b>184</b> by enabling the driver circuit no earlier than a full-rail signal is developed on the sense amplifier node <b>152</b>. It may be appreciated that such a driver circuit <b>190</b> could alternatively be coupled to the complement sense amplifier node <b>154</b> to drive an output node <b>188</b> with a true read data signal RDDATA (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, a sense amplifier <b>220</b> is shown in which the VSENSEP voltage is VDD, the VSENSEN voltage is ground, and the VPC voltage is an intermediate voltage between VDD and ground, in this case a VDDLOW voltage. Such a VDDLOW voltage is preferably set to a value equal to VDD-VTN (of the bitcell passgate transistor) to provide for good operating margins, although other values are also contemplated.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The precharge circuit includes a P-channel transistor <b>174</b> to precharge the common-source node <b>170</b> for the P-channel differential pair to the VDDLOW voltage, and the source terminal of transistors <b>164</b>, <b>166</b> are coupled to node <b>170</b>, which node forms a virtual VDD node for precharging the sense amplifier <b>220</b> as well as other bit line, multiplexer, and &#x201c;keeper&#x201d; circuits (not shown). The precharge transistor <b>174</b> is enabled by an inactive level on the SAEN signal, and is disabled when the SAEN signal is asserted to enable the sense amplifier <b>220</b>. The remaining precharge transistors <b>164</b>, <b>165</b>, <b>166</b> are enabled by an active-low sense amplifier precharge signal SAPCX. Splitting these two precharge enable signals provides for independent timing control, and allows transistors <b>164</b>, <b>165</b>, <b>166</b> to be turned off just before the selected word line is turned on, while keeping transistor <b>174</b> turned on until the sense amplifier <b>220</b> is enabled.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">A driver circuit <b>222</b> includes the inverter <b>182</b>, <b>184</b> and gating transistor <b>186</b>, as in the driver circuit <b>190</b> above, but also includes another gating transistor <b>180</b> to isolate the output node <b>188</b> from VDD when the driver circuit <b>222</b> is not enabled. Since the gating transistor <b>186</b> isolates the output node <b>188</b> from ground when the driver circuit <b>222</b> is not enabled, the output node <b>188</b> is thus &#x201c;tri-stated&#x201d; and may be connected to other sense amplifier driver circuit output nodes.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In this embodiment the driver circuit is enabled using the same enable signals as the sense simplifier itself. The active-high SAEN signal is coupled to both the gate terminal of transistor <b>163</b> and the gate terminal of transistor <b>186</b>, and the active-low SAENX signal is coupled to both the gate terminal of transistor <b>178</b> and the gate terminal of transistor <b>180</b>, which eliminates the necessity of routing separate driver enable signals to each sense amplifier circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates such a tri-state arrangement <b>250</b>. Four instantiations of sense amplifier <b>220</b> are shown, each for sensing a respective complementary pair of bit lines BL<b>3</b>C/BL<b>3</b>T (also labeled <b>252</b>, <b>254</b>), BL<b>2</b>C/BL<b>2</b>T (also labeled <b>134</b>, <b>136</b>), BL<b>1</b>C/BL<b>1</b>T (also labeled <b>256</b>, <b>258</b>), and BL<b>0</b>C/BL<b>0</b>T (also labeled <b>260</b>, <b>262</b>). The enable signal SAEN for each sense amplifier <b>220</b> is decoded so that, at most, only one of the four sense amplifiers is enabled at the same time, and the output node <b>188</b> is common to all four sense amplifiers. A decoded SAEN[3:0] bus <b>270</b> is shown traversing past all four sense amplifiers, but each sense amplifier receives one of the four decoded SAEN signals from this bus <b>270</b>. The sense amplifier for bit lines BL<b>3</b>C/BL<b>3</b>T is enabled by SAEN[3] conveyed on bus line <b>271</b>, the sense amplifier for bit lines BL<b>2</b>C/BL<b>2</b>T is enabled by SAEN[2] conveyed on bus line <b>272</b>, the sense amplifier for bit lines BL<b>1</b>C/BL<b>1</b>T is enabled by SAEN[1] conveyed on bus line <b>273</b>, and the sense amplifier for bit lines BL<b>0</b>C/BL<b>0</b>T is enabled by SAEN[0] conveyed on bus line <b>274</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">For clarity, only one decoded enable signal bus <b>270</b> is shown in this figure, but it should be recognized that the bus <b>270</b> may represent an active-high decoded enable signal bus for enabling both the sense amplifier and the driver circuit, or may represent an active-low decoded enable signal bus for enabling both the sense amplifier and the driver circuit, or may represent both an active-high decoded enable signal bus and an active-low decoded enable signal bus for both the sense amplifier and the driver circuit. In embodiments which use a separate driver enable signal, the bus <b>270</b> may represent a decoded driver enable signal bus, and the one or more sense amplifier enable signals may or may not be decoded.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">As used herein, a tail current serves to drive a common source node for a differential amplifier toward a bias voltage, and may provide a constant current or a non-uniform current driving the common source node to the bias voltage. A tail current may refer to either an N-channel differential amplifier or a P-channel differential amplifier, although in the case of a P-channel amplifier it may also be referred to as a &#x201c;head current&#x201d; (and the corresponding device also referred to as a &#x201c;head current&#x201d; device).</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">As used herein, a transistor control terminal corresponds to the gate terminal of a MOSFET. A transistor that is coupled between two nodes refers to the current-carrying terminals of the transistor rather than the control terminal, unless the context so requires. For a MOSFET, the current-carrying terminals are the source and drain terminals, which are usually viewed as being interchangeable in most low-voltage technologies. As used herein, the word &#x201c;coupled&#x201d; includes both directly coupled and indirectly coupled.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">As used herein, a crowbar current is one that flows from one power supply node to another power supply node through a series string of devices, such as an inverter in which both the PMOS and NMOS devices are turned on. As used herein, a circuit &#x201c;floats&#x201d; a node thereof when no current path exists to any power rail, so that the voltage of such floating node may be driven by another circuit that has not floated that node. As used herein, references to a particular voltage may include a circuit node conveying the particular voltage. As used herein, a PMOS transistor or device is used interchangeably with a P-channel MOSFET, and an NMOS transistor or device is used interchangeably with an N-channel MOSFET.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">While circuits and physical structures are generally presumed, it is well recognized that in modern semiconductor design and fabrication, physical structures and circuits may be embodied in computer readable descriptive form suitable for use in subsequent design, test or fabrication stages as well as in resultant fabricated semiconductor integrated circuits. Accordingly, claims directed to traditional circuits or structures may, consistent with particular language thereof, read upon computer readable encodings and representations of same to allow fabrication, test, or design refinement of the corresponding circuits and/or structures. The invention is contemplated to include circuits, related methods of operation, related methods for making such circuits, and computer-readable storage medium encodings of such circuits and methods, all as described herein, and as defined in the appended claims. As used herein, a computer-readable storage medium may include a disk, tape, or other magnetic, optical, semiconductor (e.g., flash memory cards, ROM), or electronic storage medium. An encoding of a circuit may include circuit schematic information, physical layout information, behavioral simulation information, and/or may include any other encoding from which the circuit may be represented or communicated.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">References in the claims to a numbered item, such as a &#x201c;third&#x201d; transistor, are for clarity only, and do not necessarily imply that lower-numbered items of the same type are also included in the recited claim.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The foregoing detailed description has described only a few of the many possible implementations of the present invention. For this reason, this detailed description is intended by way of illustration, and not by way of limitations. Variations and modifications of the embodiments disclosed herein may be made based on the description set forth herein, without departing from the scope of the invention. It is only the following claims, including all equivalents, that are intended to define the invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A sensing circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a first sense amplifier circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a cross-coupled pair of PMOS transistors cross-coupling a first node and a second node to a PMOS common-source node;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cross-coupled pair of NMOS transistors cross-coupling the first node and the second node to an NMOS common-source node;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a precharge circuit configured to precharge the first and second nodes to a first voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a PMOS tail transistor responsive to an active-low sense enable signal and coupling the PMOS common-source node to a second voltage higher in magnitude than said first voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an NMOS tail transistor responsive to an active-high sense enable signal and coupling the NMOS common-source node to a third voltage lower in magnitude than said first voltage; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first driver circuit responsive to one of the first and second nodes and responsive to a driver enable signal, being configured to generate a read data signal on an output node when enabled by the driver enable signal, and configured to decouple the output node from one of the second voltage and the third voltage when not enabled by the driver enable signal to thereby prevent crowbar current flow irrespective of the voltage on said one of the first and second nodes.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The sensing circuit as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the precharge circuit is further configured to precharge the PMOS common-source node to the first voltage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The sensing circuit as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>
<claim-text>wherein said first driver circuit is enabled only if the sense amplifier circuit is enabled.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The sensing circuit as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref> wherein:
<claim-text>the first driver circuit is further configured to decouple the output node from both the second voltage and the third voltage when not enabled by the driver enable signal to thereby float the output node irrespective of the voltage on said one of the first and second nodes.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The sensing circuit as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>a second sense amplifier circuit comprising a second driver circuit responsive to a second driver enable signal, being configured to generate a corresponding read data signal on a second output node when enabled by the second driver enable signal, and configured to decouple the second output node from both the first voltage and the second voltage when not enabled by the second driver enable signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first output node and the second output node are coupled together; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein at most only one of the first and second driver enable signals is enabled.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The sensing circuit as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref> wherein the first driver circuit comprises:
<claim-text>first and second PMOS transistors coupled in series between the second voltage and the output node;</claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second NMOS transistors coupled in series between the output node and the third voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said first PMOS transistor having a gate terminal coupled to the active low sense enable signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said second PMOS transistor having a gate terminal coupled to said one of the first and second nodes;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said first NMOS transistor having a gate terminal coupled to said one of the first and second nodes;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said second NMOS transistor having a gate terminal coupled to the active high sense enable signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the driver enable signal comprises the active high sense enable signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The sensing circuit as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> wherein:
<claim-text>the precharge circuit comprises:
<claim-text>a third PMOS transistor coupled between the first voltage and the PMOS common source node, having a gate terminal coupled to a first active low precharge signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth PMOS transistor coupled between the PMOS common source node and the first node, having a gate terminal coupled to a second active low precharge signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fifth PMOS transistor coupled between the PMOS common source node and the second node, having a gate terminal coupled to the second active low precharge signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sixth PMOS transistor coupled between the first node and the second node, having a gate terminal coupled to the second active low precharge signal;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the PMOS tail transistor is coupled between the second voltage and the PMOS common source node, having a gate terminal coupled to the active low sense enable signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second voltage is a VDD power supply voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the third voltage is ground; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first voltage is an intermediate voltage between VDD and ground.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A computer-readable storage medium encoding of the sensing circuit recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A memory device comprising the sensing circuit recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A method for sensing a differential signal in a SRAM device, said method comprising:
<claim-text>precharging a first node and a second node to a first voltage; then</claim-text>
<claim-text>developing a differential signal on the first and second nodes; then</claim-text>
<claim-text>enabling a tail current for a cross-coupled PMOS differential transistor pair coupled to the first and second nodes, to drive a common source node of the cross-coupled PMOS differential transistor pair toward a second voltage higher than the first voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>enabling a tail current for a cross-coupled NMOS differential transistor pair coupled to the first and second nodes, to drive a common source node of the cross-coupled NMOS differential transistor pair toward a third voltage lower than the first voltage; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>before enabling the aforementioned PMOS and NMOS tail currents, decoupling a driver output node from one of the second voltage and the third voltage to thereby prevent crowbar current flow irrespective of the voltage on said one of the first and second nodes;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the cross-coupled PMOS differential transistor pair and the cross-coupled NMOS differential transistor pair cooperate to drive one of the first and second nodes to the second voltage, and the other of the first and second nodes to the third voltage.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref> wherein:
<claim-text>the first voltage and the third voltage differ by less than the threshold voltage of a memory cell passgate transistor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>enabling the tail current for the cross-coupled PMOS differential transistor pair at the same time as enabling the tail current for the cross-coupled NMOS differential transistor pair.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>before developing the signal on the first and second nodes, precharging the common source node of the cross-coupled PMOS differential transistor pair to the first voltage.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>after enabling the aforementioned PMOS and NMOS tail currents, generating an output signal on the driver output node responsive to one of the first and second nodes.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>before enabling the aforementioned PMOS and NMOS tail currents, floating the driver output node of the driver circuit so that another sense amplifier circuit coupled to the same driver output node may drive a corresponding output signal onto the driver output node.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A method for making an integrated circuit product that incorporates a sensing circuit, said method comprising:
<claim-text>providing a first sense amplifier circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a cross-coupled pair of PMOS transistors cross-coupling a first node and a second node to a PMOS common-source node;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cross-coupled pair of NMOS transistors cross-coupling the first node and the second node to an NMOS common-source node;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a precharge circuit configured to precharge the first and second nodes to a first voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a PMOS tail transistor responsive to an active-low sense enable signal and coupling the PMOS common-source node to a second voltage higher in magnitude than said first voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an NMOS tail transistor responsive to an active-high sense enable signal and coupling the NMOS common-source node to a third voltage lower in magnitude than said first voltage; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first driver circuit responsive to one of the first and second nodes and responsive to a driver enable signal, being configured to generate a read data signal on an output node when enabled by the driver enable signal, and configured to decouple the output node from one of the first voltage and the second voltage when not enabled by the driver enable signal to thereby prevent crowbar current flow irrespective of the voltage on said one of the first and second nodes.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref> wherein:
<claim-text>the first driver circuit is further configured to decouple the output node from both the second voltage and the third voltage when not enabled by the driver enable signal to thereby float the output node irrespective of the voltage on said one of the first and second nodes.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>providing a second sense amplifier circuit comprising a second driver circuit responsive to a second driver enable signal, being configured to generate a corresponding read data signal on a second output node when enabled by the second driver enable signal, and configured to decouple the second output node from both the second voltage and the third voltage when not enabled by the second driver enable signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first output node and the second output node are coupled together; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first and second driver enable signals are decoded so that at most only one is enabled. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
