<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626859-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626859</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13420246</doc-number>
<date>20120314</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>141</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>16</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>709206</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Custom message presentation</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5324922</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Roberts</name>
<date>19940600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>235375</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8015059</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Walker et al.</name>
<date>20110900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>705 1411</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8306512</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Dixon et al.</name>
<date>20121100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4554141</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0297559</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Davis</name>
<date>20111200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>206  51</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2012/0316948</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Shipley et al.</name>
<date>20121200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>705 1423</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>709206</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130246539</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130919</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Davis</last-name>
<first-name>Robert</first-name>
<address>
<city>Springville</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Davis</last-name>
<first-name>Robert</first-name>
<address>
<city>Springville</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Lim</last-name>
<first-name>Krisna</first-name>
<department>2453</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">For custom message presentation, an identification module identifies an optical code as not communication ready. A message module generates a custom message indexed to the optical code in response to identifying the optical code as not communication ready. The message module further makes the optical code communication ready in response to generating the custom message. In addition, the message module communicates the custom message in response to receiving the optical code and identifying the optical code as communication ready.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="205.57mm" wi="170.52mm" file="US08626859-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="221.40mm" wi="194.82mm" file="US08626859-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="226.23mm" wi="100.58mm" file="US08626859-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="254.42mm" wi="190.33mm" file="US08626859-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="230.72mm" wi="190.33mm" file="US08626859-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="231.99mm" wi="181.36mm" file="US08626859-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="156.97mm" wi="89.75mm" file="US08626859-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The subject matter disclosed herein relates to message presentation and more particularly relates to custom message presentation.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">Description of the Related Art</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Products and services are often exchanged. It is desirable to include a message with the product or service.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">A method for custom message presentation is disclosed. An identification module identifies an optical code as not communication ready. A message module generates a custom message indexed to the optical code in response to identifying the optical code as not communication ready. The message module further makes the optical code communication ready in response to generating the custom message. In addition, the message module communicates the custom message in response to receiving the optical code and identifying the optical code as communication ready. An apparatus and computer program product also perform the functions of the method.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In order that the advantages of the embodiments of the invention will be readily understood, a more particular description of the embodiments briefly described above will be rendered by reference to specific embodiments that are illustrated in the appended drawings. Understanding that these drawings depict only some embodiments and are not therefore to be considered to be limiting of scope, the embodiments will be described and explained with additional specificity and detail through the use of the accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic block diagram illustrating one embodiment of a custom message presentation system;</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic block diagram illustrating one embodiment of a computer;</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic block diagram illustrating one embodiment of a message presentation apparatus;</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a drawing illustrating one embodiment of a message generation interface;</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a schematic block diagram illustrating one embodiment of a custom message presentation database;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a schematic block diagram illustrating one embodiment of an optical code data store;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a schematic flow chart diagram illustrating one embodiment of a custom message presentation method; and</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a schematic flow chart diagram illustrating one embodiment of an optical code generation method.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Reference throughout this specification to &#x201c;one embodiment,&#x201d; &#x201c;an embodiment,&#x201d; or similar language means that a particular feature, structure, or characteristic described in connection with the embodiment is included in at least one embodiment. Thus, appearances of the phrases &#x201c;in one embodiment,&#x201d; &#x201c;in an embodiment,&#x201d; and similar language throughout this specification may, but do not necessarily, all refer to the same embodiment, but mean &#x201c;one or more but not all embodiments&#x201d; unless expressly specified otherwise. The terms &#x201c;including,&#x201d; &#x201c;comprising,&#x201d; &#x201c;having,&#x201d; and variations thereof mean &#x201c;including but not limited to&#x201d; unless expressly specified otherwise. An enumerated listing of items does not imply that any or all of the items are mutually exclusive and/or mutually inclusive, unless expressly specified otherwise. The terms &#x201c;a,&#x201d; &#x201c;an,&#x201d; and &#x201c;the&#x201d; also refer to &#x201c;one or more&#x201d; unless expressly specified otherwise.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Furthermore, the described features, advantages, and characteristics of the embodiments may be combined in any suitable manner. One skilled in the relevant art will recognize that the embodiments may be practiced without one or more of the specific features or advantages of a particular embodiment. In other instances, additional features and advantages may be recognized in certain embodiments that may not be present in all embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">These features and advantages of the embodiments will become more fully apparent from the following description and appended claims, or may be learned by the practice of embodiments as set forth hereinafter. As will be appreciated by one skilled in the art, aspects of the present invention may be embodied as a system, method, and/or computer program product. Accordingly, aspects of the present invention may take the form of an entirely hardware embodiment, an entirely software embodiment (including firmware, resident software, micro-code, etc.) or an embodiment combining software and hardware aspects that may all generally be referred to herein as a &#x201c;circuit,&#x201d; &#x201c;module,&#x201d; or &#x201c;system.&#x201d; Furthermore, aspects of the present invention may take the form of a computer program product embodied in one or more computer-readable medium(s) having computer-readable program code embodied thereon.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Many of the functional units described in this specification have been labeled as modules, in order to more particularly emphasize their implementation independence. For example, a module may be implemented as a hardware circuit comprising custom VLSI circuits or gate arrays, off-the-shelf semiconductors such as logic chips, transistors, or other discrete components. A module may also be implemented in programmable hardware devices such as field programmable gate arrays, programmable array logic, programmable logic devices or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Modules may also be implemented in software for execution by various types of processors. An identified module of computer-readable program code may, for instance, comprise one or more physical or logical blocks of computer instructions which may, for instance, be organized as an object, procedure, or function. Nevertheless, the executables of an identified module need not be physically located together, but may comprise disparate instructions stored in different locations which, when joined logically together, comprise the module and achieve the stated purpose for the module.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Indeed, a module of computer-readable program code may be a single instruction, or many instructions, and may even be distributed over several different code segments, among different programs, and across several memory devices. Similarly, operational data may be identified and illustrated herein within modules, and may be embodied in any suitable form and organized within any suitable type of data structure. The operational data may be collected as a single data set, or may be distributed over different locations including over different storage devices, and may exist, at least partially, merely as electronic signals on a system or network. Where a module or portions of a module are implemented in software, the computer-readable program code may be stored and/or propagated on in one or more computer-readable medium(s).</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The computer-readable medium may be a tangible computer-readable storage medium storing the computer-readable program code. The computer-readable storage medium may be, for example, but not limited to, an electronic, magnetic, optical, electromagnetic, infrared, holographic, micromechanical, or semiconductor system, apparatus, or device, or any suitable combination of the foregoing.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">More specific examples of the computer-readable storage medium may include but are not limited to a portable computer diskette, a hard disk, a random access memory (RAM), a read-only memory (ROM), an erasable programmable read-only memory (EPROM or Flash memory), a portable compact disc read-only memory (CD-ROM), a digital versatile disc (DVD), an optical storage device, a magnetic storage device, a holographic storage medium, a micromechanical storage device, or any suitable combination of the foregoing. In the context of this document, a computer-readable storage medium may be any tangible medium that can contain, and/or store computer-readable program code for use by and/or in connection with an instruction execution system, apparatus, or device.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The computer-readable medium may also be a computer-readable signal medium. A computer-readable signal medium may include a propagated data signal with computer-readable program code embodied therein, for example, in baseband or as part of a carrier wave. Such a propagated signal may take any of a variety of forms, including, but not limited to, electrical, electro-magnetic, magnetic, optical, or any suitable combination thereof. A computer-readable signal medium may be any computer-readable medium that is not a computer-readable storage medium and that can communicate, propagate, or transport computer-readable program code for use by or in connection with an instruction execution system, apparatus, or device. Computer-readable program code embodied on a computer-readable signal medium may be transmitted using any appropriate medium, including but not limited to wireline, optical fiber, Radio Frequency (RF), or the like, or any suitable combination of the foregoing</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In one embodiment, the computer-readable medium may comprise a combination of one or more computer-readable storage mediums and one or more computer-readable signal mediums. For example, computer-readable program code may be both propagated as an electro-magnetic signal through a fiber optic cable for execution by a processor and stored on RAM storage device for execution by the processor.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Computer-readable program code for carrying out operations for aspects of the present invention may be written in any combination of one or more programming languages, including an object oriented programming language such as Java, Smalltalk, C++, PHP or the like and conventional procedural programming languages, such as the &#x201c;C&#x201d; programming language or similar programming languages. The computer-readable program code may execute entirely on the user's computer, partly on the user's computer, as a stand-alone software package, partly on the user's computer and partly on a remote computer or entirely on the remote computer or server. In the latter scenario, the remote computer may be connected to the user's computer through any type of network, including a local area network (LAN) or a wide area network (WAN), or the connection may be made to an external computer (for example, through the Internet using an Internet Service Provider).</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The computer program product may be shared, simultaneously serving multiple customers in a flexible, automated fashion. The computer program product may be standardized, requiring little customization and scalable, providing capacity on demand in a pay-as-you-go model.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The computer program product may be stored on a shared file system accessible from one or more servers. The computer program product may be executed via transactions that contain data and server processing requests that use Central Processor Unit (CPU) units on the accessed server. CPU units may be units of time such as minutes, seconds, hours on the central processor of the server. Additionally the accessed server may make requests of other servers that require CPU units. CPU units are an example that represents but one measurement of use. Other measurements of use include but are not limited to network bandwidth, memory usage, storage usage, packet transfers, complete transactions etc.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">When multiple customers use the same computer program product via shared execution, transactions are differentiated by the parameters included in the transactions that identify the unique customer and the type of service for that customer. All of the CPU units and other measurements of use that are used for the services for each customer are recorded. When the number of transactions to any one server reaches a number that begins to affect the performance of that server, other servers are accessed to increase the capacity and to share the workload Likewise when other measurements of use such as network bandwidth, memory usage, storage usage, etc. approach a capacity so as to affect performance, additional network bandwidth, memory usage, storage etc. are added to share the workload.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The measurements of use used for each service and customer are sent to a collecting server that sums the measurements of use for each customer for each service that was processed anywhere in the network of servers that provide the shared execution of the computer program product. The summed measurements of use units are periodically multiplied by unit costs and the resulting total computer program product service costs are alternatively sent to the customer and or indicated on a web site accessed by the customer which then remits payment to the service provider.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In one embodiment, the service provider requests payment directly from a customer account at a banking or financial institution. In another embodiment, if the service provider is also a customer of the customer that uses the computer program product, the payment owed to the service provider is reconciled to the payment owed by the service provider to minimize the transfer of payments.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The computer program product may be integrated into a client, server and network environment by providing for the computer program product to coexist with applications, operating systems and network operating systems software and then installing the computer program product on the clients and servers in the environment where the computer program product will function.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In one embodiment software is identified on the clients and servers including the network operating system where the computer program product will be deployed that are required by the computer program product or that work in conjunction with the computer program product. This includes the network operating system that is software that enhances a basic operating system by adding networking features.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In one embodiment, software applications and version numbers are identified and compared to the list of software applications and version numbers that have been tested to work with the computer program product. Those software applications that are missing or that do not match the correct version will be upgraded with the correct version numbers. Program instructions that pass parameters from the computer program product to the software applications will be checked to ensure the parameter lists match the parameter lists required by the computer program product. Conversely parameters passed by the software applications to the computer program product will be checked to ensure the parameters match the parameters required by the computer program product. The client and server operating systems including the network operating systems will be identified and compared to the list of operating systems, version numbers and network software that have been tested to work with the computer program product. Those operating systems, version numbers and network software that do not match the list of tested operating systems and version numbers will be upgraded on the clients and servers to the required level.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In response to determining that the software where the computer program product is to be deployed, is at the correct version level that has been tested to work with the computer program product, the integration is completed by installing the computer program product on the clients and servers.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Furthermore, the described features, structures, or characteristics of the embodiments may be combined in any suitable manner. In the following description, numerous specific details are provided, such as examples of programming, software modules, user selections, network transactions, database queries, database structures, hardware modules, hardware circuits, hardware chips, etc., to provide a thorough understanding of embodiments. One skilled in the relevant art will recognize, however, that embodiments may be practiced without one or more of the specific details, or with other methods, components, materials, and so forth. In other instances, well-known structures, materials, or operations are not shown or described in detail to avoid obscuring aspects of an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Aspects of the embodiments are described below with reference to schematic flowchart diagrams and/or schematic block diagrams of methods, apparatuses, systems, and computer program products according to embodiments of the invention. It will be understood that each block of the schematic flowchart diagrams and/or schematic block diagrams, and combinations of blocks in the schematic flowchart diagrams and/or schematic block diagrams, can be implemented by computer-readable program code. The computer-readable program code may be provided to a processor of a general purpose computer, special purpose computer, sequencer, or other programmable data processing apparatus to produce a machine, such that the instructions, which execute via the processor of the computer or other programmable data processing apparatus, create means for implementing the functions/acts specified in the schematic flowchart diagrams and/or schematic block diagrams block or blocks.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The computer-readable program code may also be stored in a computer-readable medium that can direct a computer, other programmable data processing apparatus, or other devices to function in a particular manner, such that the instructions stored in the computer-readable medium produce an article of manufacture including instructions which implement the function/act specified in the schematic flowchart diagrams and/or schematic block diagrams block or blocks.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The computer-readable program code may also be loaded onto a computer, other programmable data processing apparatus, or other devices to cause a series of operational steps to be performed on the computer, other programmable apparatus or other devices to produce a computer implemented process such that the program code which executed on the computer or other programmable apparatus provide processes for implementing the functions/acts specified in the flowchart and/or block diagram block or blocks.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The schematic flowchart diagrams and/or schematic block diagrams in the Figures illustrate the architecture, functionality, and operation of possible implementations of apparatuses, systems, methods and computer program products according to various embodiments of the present invention. In this regard, each block in the schematic flowchart diagrams and/or schematic block diagrams may represent a module, segment, or portion of code, which comprises one or more executable instructions of the program code for implementing the specified logical function(s).</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">It should also be noted that, in some alternative implementations, the functions noted in the block may occur out of the order noted in the Figures. For example, two blocks shown in succession may, in fact, be executed substantially concurrently, or the blocks may sometimes be executed in the reverse order, depending upon the functionality involved. Other steps and methods may be conceived that are equivalent in function, logic, or effect to one or more blocks, or portions thereof, of the illustrated Figures.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Although various arrow types and line types may be employed in the flowchart and/or block diagrams, they are understood not to limit the scope of the corresponding embodiments. Indeed, some arrows or other connectors may be used to indicate only the logical flow of the depicted embodiment. For instance, an arrow may indicate a waiting or monitoring period of unspecified duration between enumerated steps of the depicted embodiment. It will also be noted that each block of the block diagrams and/or flowchart diagrams, and combinations of blocks in the block diagrams and/or flowchart diagrams, can be implemented by special purpose hardware-based systems that perform the specified functions or acts, or combinations of special purpose hardware and computer-readable program code.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The description of elements in each figure may refer to elements of proceeding figures. Like numbers refer to like elements in all figures, including alternate embodiments of like elements.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic block diagram illustrating one embodiment of a custom message presentation system <b>100</b>. The system <b>100</b> includes one or more electronic devices <b>105</b>, a network <b>110</b>, an optical code <b>120</b>, and a server <b>125</b>. The system <b>100</b> may also include a product <b>115</b> and point-of-sale server <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The electronic device <b>105</b> may be a tablet computer, a cellular telephone, an e-book reader, a notebook computer, a computer workstation, a personal digital assistant, a net book computer, or the like. The electronic device <b>105</b> includes an imaging device. The imaging device may be a camera, a video recorder, a scanner, or the like. The electronic device <b>105</b> may employ the imaging device to capture an image of a physical rendition of the optical code <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In the past, the electronic device <b>105</b> scanned the optical code <b>120</b> and used the optical code <b>120</b> to retrieve a generic message. The embodiments described herein generate and present a custom message in response to scan in the optical code <b>120</b> as will be described hereafter.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The optical code <b>120</b> may be rendered physically as a QR code, a barcode, an alphanumeric code accompanied by a distinctive design, an alphanumeric string, or combinations thereof. In addition, the optical code <b>120</b> may be rendered digitally as an alphanumeric string, an array of digits, and combinations thereof. The digital rendition of the optical code <b>120</b> may include a Universal Resource Locator (URL), an Internet address, one or more custom codes, or combinations thereof. The captured optical code <b>120</b> may be converted from the image of the physical rendition of the optical code <b>120</b> to a digital rendition of the optical code <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The physical rendition of the optical code <b>120</b> may be incorporated in packaging of the product <b>115</b>. The packaging may be a box, a clamshell, an envelope, shrink wrap, a card, a certificate, or the like. For example, the optical code <b>120</b> may be printed onto the packaging of the product <b>115</b>. Alternatively, the optical code <b>120</b> may be incorporated on the product <b>115</b>. For example, the optical code <b>120</b> may be silkscreened onto the product <b>115</b>. In one embodiment, the optical code <b>120</b> may be printed on a certificate. The certificate may be a postcard, a letter, and Email, or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In one embodiment, the optical code <b>120</b> is combined with the product <b>115</b> by a user. For example, the user may purchase the optical code <b>120</b> separately from the product <b>115</b>. The optical code <b>120</b> may be printed on an adhesive sticker, a card, a tape roll, or the like. The user may then combine the optical code <b>120</b> with the product <b>115</b> such as by applying a sticker with the optical code <b>120</b> to the product <b>115</b> or product packaging.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The network <b>110</b> may communicate with the electronic device <b>105</b>, the server <b>125</b>, and the point-of-sale server <b>130</b>. The network <b>110</b> may be the Internet, a Wide Area Network, a Local Area Network, a cellular telephone network, a Wi-Fi network, or combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The point-of-sale server <b>130</b> may receive the optical code <b>120</b> through the network <b>110</b>. In addition, the point-of-sale server <b>130</b> may communicate whether the optical code <b>120</b> is activated through the network <b>110</b> as will be described hereafter.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The electronic device <b>105</b> may communicate the optical code <b>120</b> through the network <b>110</b> to the server <b>125</b>. In one embodiment, the electronic device <b>105</b> employs an address embedded in the optical code <b>120</b> to direct the optical code <b>120</b> to the server <b>125</b>. In a certain embodiment, the optical code <b>120</b> includes a URL and a custom identifier. The URL may communicate the custom identifier to the server <b>125</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The server <b>125</b> may identify the optical code <b>120</b> as not communication ready. As used herein, communication ready refers to an optical code <b>120</b> for which a custom message is available for communication. If the optical code <b>120</b> is not communication ready, the custom message may not have been generated. Alternatively, the optical code <b>120</b> may not be communication ready before a specified date.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In a prophetic example, the optical code <b>120</b> may be generated. The optical code <b>120</b> may then be affixed to a product <b>115</b>. The product <b>115</b> may be purchased and the optical code <b>120</b> may be activated. A user in the role of a sender may scan the optical code <b>120</b> and the optical code <b>120</b> may be sent to the server <b>125</b>. Because the optical code <b>120</b> is not communication ready, the server <b>125</b> may generate a custom message for the sender. In addition, the server <b>125</b> may make the optical code <b>120</b> communication ready in response to generating the custom message.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The server <b>125</b> may subsequently receive the optical code <b>120</b> again, such as when a second user in the role of a recipient receives the product <b>115</b> and scans the optical code <b>120</b>. The server <b>125</b> may further communicate the custom message to the recipient in response to receiving the optical code <b>120</b> and identifying that the optical code <b>120</b> is communication ready. Thus the custom message is generated for the optical code <b>120</b> when the optical code <b>120</b> is not communication ready and the custom message is communicated if the optical code <b>120</b> is communication ready.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic block diagram illustrating one embodiment of a computer <b>150</b>. The computer <b>150</b> may be the server <b>125</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. Alternatively, the computer <b>150</b> may be the electronic device <b>105</b> and/or the point-of-sale server <b>130</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The computer <b>150</b> includes a processor <b>205</b>, a memory <b>210</b>, and communication hardware <b>215</b>. The memory <b>210</b> may store computer-readable program code. The memory <b>210</b> may be a semiconductor storage device, a hard disk drive, and optical storage device, and/or combinations thereof. The processor <b>205</b> may execute the computer-readable program code. The computer <b>150</b> may communicate with other devices through the communication hardware <b>215</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic block diagram illustrating one embodiment of a message presentation apparatus <b>200</b>. The apparatus <b>200</b> may be embodied in the computer <b>150</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. In a certain embodiment, the apparatus <b>200</b> is embodied in the server <b>125</b>. The apparatus <b>200</b> includes an identification module <b>220</b> and a message module <b>225</b>. The identification module <b>220</b> and the message model <b>225</b> may be embodied in computer-readable program code. The computer-readable program code may be stored in a computer-readable storage medium such as the memory <b>210</b> and executed by the processor <b>205</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The apparatus <b>200</b> also includes the custom message <b>250</b>. The custom message <b>250</b> may be an address such as a URL or in Internet address. Alternatively, the custom message <b>250</b> may be a digital file. The digital file may include one or more video files, one or more audio files, text data, an address and/or pointer to a video file, an address and/or pointer to an audio file, an address and/or pointer to a text file, and combinations thereof. In one embodiment, the custom message <b>250</b> is formatted as an HTML5 file.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The identification module <b>220</b> may identify that the optical code <b>120</b> is not communication ready. The message module <b>225</b> may generate the custom message <b>250</b> indexed to the optical code <b>120</b> in response to identifying that the optical code is not communication ready. The message module <b>225</b> may further make the optical code <b>120</b> communication ready in response to generating the custom message <b>250</b>. In addition, the message module <b>225</b> may communicate the custom message <b>250</b> in response to receiving the optical code <b>120</b> and the identification module <b>220</b> identifying that the optical code <b>120</b> is communication ready.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a drawing illustrating one embodiment of a message generation interface <b>370</b>. The message generation interface <b>370</b> may be displayed on the electronic device <b>105</b> using a browser, a custom application, and the like. In one embodiment, a user such as the sender may employ the message generation interface <b>370</b> to establish an account. In addition, the user may employ the message generation interface <b>370</b> to generate the custom message <b>250</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The user may enter user information such as a name <b>372</b>, an Email address <b>374</b>, and a password <b>376</b> into the message generation interface <b>370</b> to establish the account. In addition, the user may upload a file <b>378</b> such as a video file, select music <b>380</b>, and enter text <b>382</b> for the custom message <b>250</b> through the message generation interface <b>370</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">In one embodiment, the user may select a record audio message icon <b>394</b> to record an audio message for inclusion in the custom message <b>250</b>. Alternatively the user may select a record video message icon <b>396</b> to record a video message for inclusion in the custom message <b>250</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">In one embodiment, an arrangement of the custom message <b>250</b> is displayed in a preview window <b>390</b>. The preview window <b>390</b> may display material of the custom message <b>250</b> such as a video <b>384</b>, formatted message text <b>386</b>, and campaign space <b>388</b>. The campaign space <b>388</b> may be filled with client generated content such as an advertisement, a coupon, a certificate, and the like. The user may arrange the material to generate the custom message <b>250</b>. For example, the user may specify a location of the video <b>384</b>, a location of the message text <b>386</b>, colors, fonts, and the like. In a certain embodiment the user may specify the location of the campaign space <b>388</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">In one embodiment, when the custom message <b>250</b> is communication ready, the user may select the ready to present icon <b>392</b> to indicate that the custom message <b>250</b> is communication ready. The message module <b>225</b> may make the optical code <b>120</b> communication ready in response to the activation of the ready to present icon <b>392</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a schematic block diagram illustrating one embodiment of a custom message presentation database <b>300</b>. The database <b>300</b> may be stored on the server <b>125</b>. Alternatively, the database <b>300</b> may be accessed by the server <b>125</b>. The database <b>300</b> includes an optical code data store <b>305</b>, a user data store <b>310</b>, a message data store <b>315</b>, a message elements data store <b>320</b>, a client data store <b>325</b>, and a campaign data store <b>330</b>. A data store may be a table in the database <b>300</b>, a linked list of data structures, flat files, a discrete database, or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The optical code data store <b>305</b> stores the optical codes <b>120</b>. The optical code data store <b>305</b> will be described in more detail hereafter.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The user data store <b>310</b> stores user information about users. The users may be at least on of senders and recipients. The user information may be received from the message generation interface <b>370</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">In one embodiment, the user data store <b>310</b> may store account information as part of the user information. The account information may include a name <b>372</b>, a username, a personal identifier, a social media address, an email address <b>374</b>, a phone number, a password <b>376</b>, security questions and answers, a physical address, and the like. The user data store <b>310</b> may also store profile information about each user. The profile information may include purchase histories, responses to questions about purchase preferences, gender, age, educational background, income, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The message data store <b>315</b> stores the custom messages <b>250</b>. The custom messages <b>250</b> are created by the sender, generated by the message module <b>225</b>, and stored in the message data store <b>315</b>. The custom message <b>250</b> may include at least one of a URL, a video file, an audio file, an image file, a video transmission, an audio transmission, text, a video selection, an audio selection, an image selection, a text selection, and combinations thereof. For example, the custom message <b>250</b> may include an audio selection such as the music selection <b>380</b> of the message generation interface <b>370</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The sender may communicate the video file, the audio file, the image file, and the text to the server <b>125</b>. For example, the message module <b>225</b> may upload the video file and store the video file in the message data store <b>315</b> using the file upload <b>378</b> of the message generation interface <b>370</b>. The sender may also transmit the video transmission and the audio transmission to the server <b>125</b>. The message module <b>225</b> may record and store the video transmission and the audio transmission in the message data store <b>315</b>. The message module <b>225</b> may generate a URL for the optical code <b>120</b>. The URL may access a custom message <b>250</b> in the message data store <b>315</b>. Alternatively the user may provide the URL.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The message elements data store <b>320</b> may include message elements such as video files, image files, audio files, fonts, and the like. In one embodiment, the sender may select one or more message elements from the message elements data store <b>320</b> for inclusion with the sender's custom message <b>250</b>. For example, the sender may use the music selection <b>380</b> of the message generation interface <b>370</b> to select an audio file from the message elements data store <b>320</b> for inclusion in the custom message <b>250</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">The client data store <b>325</b> may store client information for a client. In one embodiment, a client creates a campaign that uses the optical codes <b>120</b> to allow the sender to send the custom message <b>250</b> to the recipient. The client data store <b>325</b> may include the client's name, email address, password, and billing information.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The campaign store <b>330</b> may store campaign information for one or more campaigns for each client. The campaign information may include promotional messages and identifiers of the client. The promotional messages may include video, audio, text, and formatting that may be presented with the custom message <b>250</b> such as in the campaign space <b>388</b>. The identifiers may include logos, trade dress, color schemes, fonts, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">In one embodiment, the client enters the client information and the campaign information into the client data store <b>325</b> and the campaign store <b>330</b> respectively using a client interface. The client interface may be a web browser application, a mobile device application, or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a schematic block diagram illustrating one embodiment of an optical code data store <b>305</b>. The optical code data store <b>305</b> is the optical code data store <b>305</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. The optical code data store <b>305</b> includes a plurality of entries <b>355</b>. Each entry <b>355</b> may include the optical code <b>120</b>, an address <b>340</b>, an identifier <b>345</b>, a communication ready value <b>350</b>, a premature scan value <b>360</b>, an activated value <b>365</b>, and a user account <b>362</b>. The address <b>340</b> may be a URL. In one embodiment, a specified URL is common to all optical codes <b>120</b> for a specified campaign. The identifier <b>345</b> may be unique to each optical code <b>120</b>. In one embodiment, the identifier are <b>345</b> is appended to the address <b>340</b> to form the optical code <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The communication ready value <b>350</b> indicates whether the optical code <b>120</b> is communication ready. The communication ready values <b>350</b> may be a flag, a percent complete, and the like. For example, the communication ready value <b>350</b> may be set to true when a custom message <b>250</b> is communication ready. Alternatively, the communication ready value <b>350</b> may be increased as elements are added to a custom message <b>250</b>. The custom message <b>250</b> may be communication ready when the customer value <b>350</b> exceeds a specified threshold. In one embodiment, the communication ray value <b>350</b> is initialized to a not communication ready value.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The activated value <b>365</b> may indicate that the optical code <b>120</b> is activated by the point-of-sale server <b>130</b>. For example, if the optical code <b>120</b> and/or the product <b>115</b> with the optical code <b>120</b> is sold and activated by merchant, the merchant's point-of-sale server <b>130</b> may communicate the activation to the server <b>125</b>. The server <b>125</b> may then set the activated value <b>365</b> to true. The premature scan value <b>360</b> may indicate that the optical code <b>120</b> has been received before the optical code <b>120</b> is activated. The user account value <b>362</b> may reference a user account in the user data store <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a schematic flow chart diagram illustrating one embodiment of a custom message presentation method <b>500</b>. The method <b>500</b> may perform the functions of the system and apparatus described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-6</figref>. In one embodiment, the method <b>500</b> is performed by a computer readable storage medium such as the memory <b>210</b> storing computer readable program code that when executed by the processor <b>205</b> performs a function of the method <b>500</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The method <b>500</b> starts, and the identification module <b>220</b> receives <b>505</b> the optical code <b>110</b>. In one embodiment, the electronic device <b>105</b> scans the optical code <b>120</b> and generates a digital representation of the optical code <b>110</b>. The identification module <b>220</b> may receive <b>505</b> the optical code <b>120</b> multiple times. The embodiments described herein determine a proper course of action each time the optical code <b>120</b> is received <b>505</b>, either generating the custom message <b>250</b> or communicating in the custom message <b>250</b> to a recipient.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">In one embodiment, the identification module <b>220</b> determines <b>510</b> if the optical code <b>120</b> is activated. In a certain embodiment, the identification module <b>220</b> checks the activation value <b>365</b> to determine <b>510</b> if the optical code <b>120</b> is activated. If the optical code <b>220</b> is not activated, the identification module <b>220</b> may set <b>550</b> the premature scanned value <b>360</b> for the optical code <b>120</b> to true. The identification module <b>220</b> may then continue to receive <b>505</b> the optical code <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">If the optical code <b>120</b> is activated <b>510</b>, the identification module <b>220</b> may determine <b>515</b> if the optical code <b>120</b> is communication ready. In one embodiment, the identification module <b>220</b> accesses the communication ready value <b>350</b> to determine <b>515</b> if the optical code <b>120</b> is communication ready.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">The message module <b>225</b> may collect <b>520</b> user information for the sender or sender information in response to identifying that the optical code is not communication ready. The message module <b>225</b> may receive the user information from the message generation interface <b>370</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">The message module <b>225</b> may generate <b>252</b> a custom message <b>250</b> indexed to the optical code <b>120</b> in response to identifying that the optical code is not communication ready. The message module <b>225</b> may receive material from the message generation interface <b>370</b>. In addition, the message module <b>225</b> may receive an arrangement of the material and generate the customer message from the material, the arrangement, and combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">The optical code <b>120</b> may be communication ready if the optical code <b>120</b> is received <b>505</b> for a first time. Alternatively, the optical code <b>120</b> may be communication ready if the optical code <b>120</b> is received <b>505</b> for a first time after activation. In one embodiment, the optical code <b>120</b> is communication ready if a user account is associated with the optical code <b>120</b>. The user account may be associated with the optical code <b>120</b> if there is a valid user account value <b>362</b> in the optical code data store <b>305</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">In a certain embodiment, the optical code <b>120</b> is made communication ready in response to a user command. For example, the user may indicate that the optical code <b>120</b> is communication ready by selecting the ready to present icon <b>392</b> on the message generation interface <b>370</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">If the optical code <b>120</b> is not communication ready, the message generation interface <b>370</b> may be displayed and collect <b>520</b> sender information. In one embodiment, the message module <b>225</b> may receive the sender information, store the sender information in the user data store <b>310</b>, and establish an account for the sender.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">The message module <b>225</b> may further generate <b>525</b> the custom message <b>250</b>. In one embodiment, the message module <b>225</b> generates <b>525</b> the custom message <b>250</b> from the information received from the message generation interface <b>370</b> and stored in the message data store <b>315</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">The message module <b>225</b> may further make <b>530</b> the optical code <b>220</b> communication ready. The optical code <b>120</b> may be made communication ready in response to the optical code <b>120</b> being received for the first time, in response to the optical code <b>120</b> being associated with the user account, in response to completion of the custom message <b>250</b>, and/or in response to a user command such as the user selecting the ready to present icon <b>392</b>. In one embodiment, the message module <b>225</b> makes <b>530</b> the optical code <b>120</b> communication ready by setting the communication ready value <b>350</b> to true. The identification module <b>220</b> may then monitor for and receive <b>505</b> the optical code <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">If the optical code <b>120</b> is communication ready, the message module <b>225</b> may send <b>535</b> a notification to the recipient. The notification may be sent through a channel selected from the group consisting of a mobile device application, a browser, an email message, a text message, and a phone message. The notification may notify the recipient of the custom message <b>250</b>. In addition, the notification may give the recipient the opportunity to provide user information in the form of recipient information. For example, the recipient may provide a name, an email address, a phone number, an address, a social media address, and the like. In a certain embodiment, the recipient may establish an account.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">The message module <b>225</b> may collect <b>540</b> the recipient information. In addition, the message module <b>225</b> may store the recipient information in the user data store <b>310</b>. In one embodiment, the message module <b>225</b> establishes an account for the recipient.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">The message module <b>225</b> communicates <b>545</b> the custom message <b>250</b> to the recipient and the method <b>500</b> ends. The custom message <b>250</b> may be communicated <b>545</b> through a channel selected from the group consisting of a mobile device application, a browser, an email message, a text message, and a phone message. For example, the custom message <b>250</b> may be communicated to a browser of a mobile telephone electronic device <b>105</b>. In one embodiment, the custom message <b>250</b> is communicative <b>545</b> through multiple channels.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">The custom message <b>250</b> may be communicated <b>545</b> with an advertisement. In one embodiment, the advertisement is customized based on user information. The custom message <b>250</b> may also be communicated with a coupon. The coupon may be customized based on the user information.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a schematic flow chart diagram illustrating one embodiment of an optical code generation method <b>600</b>. The method <b>600</b> may generate client information stored in the client data store <b>325</b> and campaigns stored in the campaign data store <b>330</b>. In one embodiment, the method <b>600</b> is performed by a computer readable storage medium such as the memory <b>210</b> storing computer readable program code that when executed by the processor <b>205</b> performs a function of the method <b>600</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">The method <b>600</b> starts and the message module <b>220</b> creates <b>605</b> a client account. The message module <b>220</b> may employ a message generation interface <b>370</b> on electronic device <b>105</b> to collect client information. The message module <b>220</b> may receive the client information and store the client information that may include the client account in the client data store <b>325</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">The message module <b>220</b> may further generate <b>610</b> a client campaign. In one embodiment, the message module <b>220</b> receives material and an arrangement of the material from the message generation interface <b>370</b> on the electronic device <b>105</b>. The message module <b>220</b> may store the material and the arrangement of the material in the campaign data store <b>330</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">The message module <b>220</b> may further generate <b>610</b> optical codes <b>120</b> for the campaign. Each optical code <b>120</b> may have a common address <b>340</b> and a unique identifier <b>345</b>. In one embodiment, the message module <b>220</b> charges the client for each optical code <b>120</b> that is created.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">In one embodiment, the message module <b>220</b> stores each optical code <b>120</b> in the optical code data store <b>305</b>. The message module <b>220</b> may further initialize the communication ready value <b>350</b>, the premature scanned value <b>360</b>, the activated value <b>365</b>, and the user account <b>362</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">The message module <b>220</b> may incorporate <b>620</b> the optical codes <b>120</b> into a product <b>115</b>, a sticker, or the like, and the method <b>600</b> ends. Alternatively, the message module <b>220</b> may provide the optical codes <b>120</b> to the client for incorporation <b>620</b> in the product <b>115</b>, product packaging, or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">The embodiments allow a custom message <b>250</b> to be generated for each optical code <b>120</b> or communicated to a recipient as appropriate. When the optical code <b>120</b> is not communication ready, the custom message <b>250</b> is generated in response to receiving the optical code <b>120</b>. When the optical code is communication ready, the custom message is communicated to the recipient.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">The embodiments may be practiced in other specific forms. The described embodiments are to be considered in all respects only as illustrative and not restrictive. The scope of the invention is, therefore, indicated by the appended claims rather than by the foregoing description. All changes which come within the meaning and range of equivalency of the claims are to be embraced within their scope.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method for custom message presentation comprising:
<claim-text>identifying, by use of a processor, an optical code as not communication ready, wherein the optical code is not communication ready if the optical code is activated by a merchant in response to a purchase of the optical code by a sender and if the sender has not generated a custom message indexed to the optical code, and the optical code is a Quick Response (QR) code;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating, by use of a processor, the custom message indexed to the optical code from custom message material selected by the sender in response to identifying the optical code as not communication ready;</claim-text>
<claim-text>making, by use of a processor, the optical code communication ready in response to generating the custom message; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>communicating, by user of a processor, the custom message in response to receiving the optical code and identifying the optical code as communication ready.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising collecting, by use of a processor, user information wherein the user is selected from the group consisting of the sender and a recipient.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein collecting the user information comprises establishing an account for the sender to create the custom message.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the user information comprises an email address, a social media address, a phone number, an address, and a personal identifier.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the optical code is not communication ready if the optical code is received for a first time.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the optical code is communication ready if a user account is associated with the optical code.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the optical code is made communication ready in response to a user command.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the custom message material comprises material selected from at least one of the group consisting of a Universal Resource Locator (URL), a video file, an audio file, an image file, a video transmission, an audio transmission, text, a video selection, an audio selection, an image selection, a text selection, and a composite selection.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein generating the custom message further comprises arranging the custom message material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the custom message is communicated through a channel selected from the group consisting of a mobile device application, a browser, an email message, a text message, and a phone message.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the custom message is communicated with a promotional message and identifiers of a client.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the custom message is communicated with at least one of an advertisement and a coupon.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one of the advertisement and the coupon is customized based on user information.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the optical code is incorporated in packaging of a product for purchase.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the optical code is incorporated on a product.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the optical code is combined with a product by a user.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>determining if the optical code is activated; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>setting a premature scan value for the optical code in response to determining that the optical code is not activated.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the optical code is activated at a point-of-sale terminal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. An apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a non-transitory computer-readable storage medium storing computer-readable program code executable by a processor, the computer-readable program code comprising:</claim-text>
<claim-text>an identification module identifying an optical code as not communication ready, wherein the optical code is not communication ready if the optical code is activated by a merchant in response to a purchase of the optical code by a sender and if the sender has not generated a custom message indexed to the optical code; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a message module generating the custom message indexed to the optical code in response to identifying the optical code as not communication ready, making the optical code communication ready in response to generating the custom message, and communicating the custom message in response to receiving the optical code and identifying the optical code as communication ready.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. A computer program product for custom message presentation, the computer program product comprising:
<claim-text>a non-transitory computer-readable storage medium having computer-readable program code embodied therein, the computer-readable program code configured to:</claim-text>
<claim-text>identify an optical code as not communication ready, wherein the optical code is not communication ready if the optical code is activated by a merchant in response to a purchase of the optical code by a sender and if the sender has not generated a custom message indexed to the optical code;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generate the custom message indexed to the optical code in response to identifying the optical code as not communication ready;</claim-text>
<claim-text>make the optical code communication ready in response to generating the custom message; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>communicate the custom message in response to receiving the optical code and identifying the optical code as communication ready.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
