<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08627241-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08627241</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13447857</doc-number>
<date>20120416</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>17</main-group>
<subgroup>50</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>716 53</main-classification>
<further-classification>716 50</further-classification>
<further-classification>716 54</further-classification>
<further-classification>716 55</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Pattern correction with location effect</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8381153</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Chiang et al.</name>
<date>20130200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0076891</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Pierrat</name>
<date>20040400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>430  5</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0081179</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Melvin</name>
<date>20050400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>716 20</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0301611</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Word et al.</name>
<date>20081200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>716  9</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0064274</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Grimm</name>
<date>20100300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>716 21</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>18</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>716 53</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>716 50</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>716 54</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>716 55</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130275925</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20131017</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wang</last-name>
<first-name>Hung-Chun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taichung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chih</last-name>
<first-name>Ming-Hui</first-name>
<address>
<city>Luzhou</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tsai</last-name>
<first-name>Cheng Kun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsinchu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="004" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Huang</last-name>
<first-name>Wen-Chun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tainan</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="005" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liu</last-name>
<first-name>Ru-Gun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Zhubei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wang</last-name>
<first-name>Hung-Chun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taichung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chih</last-name>
<first-name>Ming-Hui</first-name>
<address>
<city>Luzhou</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tsai</last-name>
<first-name>Cheng Kun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsinchu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="004" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Huang</last-name>
<first-name>Wen-Chun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tainan</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="005" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liu</last-name>
<first-name>Ru-Gun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Zhubei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Haynes and Boone, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company, Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Hsin-Chu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Siek</last-name>
<first-name>Vuthe</first-name>
<department>2825</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Dimyan</last-name>
<first-name>Magid</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present disclosure provides one embodiment of an integrated circuit (IC) method. The method includes receiving an IC design layout having a plurality of IC regions each including an IC pattern; performing a dissection process to the IC design layout; and performing a correction process to the IC design layout using a correction model that includes proximity effect and location effect. The correction process includes performing a first correction step to a first IC region of the IC regions, resulting in a first corrected IC pattern in the first IC region; and performing a second correction step to a second IC region of the IC regions, starting with the first corrected IC pattern, resulting in a second corrected IC pattern.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="201.25mm" wi="270.85mm" file="US08627241-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="241.38mm" wi="181.61mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627241-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="232.83mm" wi="197.36mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627241-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="135.47mm" wi="144.27mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627241-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="278.72mm" wi="197.02mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627241-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="270.26mm" wi="200.15mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627241-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The integrated circuit (IC) design is more challenging when semiconductor technologies are continually progressing to smaller feature sizes, such as 65 nanometers, 45 nanometers, and below. The performance of a chip design is seriously influenced by the control of resistance/capacitance (RC), timing, leakage, and topology of the metal/dielectric inter-layers. Those are further related to resolution of the lithography patterning and the imaging accuracy.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">To enhance the imaging effect when a design pattern is transferred to a wafer, an optical proximity correction (OPC) to minimize the proximity effect is indispensable. The design pattern is adjusted to generate an image on the wafer with improved resolution.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">However, along with the progress of the lithography patterning, some other imaging effect are unavoidable and those imaging factors are location related. Those other imaging factors are not fully considered and not effectively corrected or efficiently corrected. For N28 nodes and below, the severity of main feature distortion caused by those imaging effect generates many side effects with significant impact, which is unacceptable in term of device performance, quality and reliability.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Therefore, what is needed is a method for IC design and mask making to effectively and efficiently tuning IC pattern to address the above issue.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Aspects of the present disclosure are best understood from the following detailed description when read in association with the accompanying figures. It is noted that, in accordance with the standard practice in the industry, various features in the drawings are not drawn to scale. In fact, the dimensions of illustrated features may be arbitrarily increased or decreased for clarity of discussion.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a flowchart of an embodiment of an integrated circuit (IC) method constructed according to aspects of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a flowchart of a model-based correction of the IC method in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> constructed according to aspects of the present disclosure in one embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic view of an IC design pattern constructed according to aspects of the present disclosure in one embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates one embodiment of a main feature of the IC design layout of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an IC design flow constructed according to aspects of the present disclosure in one embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an IC design flow constructed according to aspects of the present disclosure in another embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">It is understood that the following disclosure provides many different embodiments, or examples, for implementing different features of the invention. Specific examples of components and arrangements are described below to simplify the present disclosure. These are, of course, merely examples and are not intended to be limiting. The present disclosure may repeat reference numerals and/or letters in the various examples. This repetition is for the purpose of simplicity and clarity and does not in itself dictate a relationship between the various embodiments and/or configurations discussed.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a flowchart of a method <b>100</b> for integrated circuit (IC) designing constructed according to various aspects of the present disclosure in one or more embodiments. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a flowchart of a model-based correction of the IC design method <b>100</b> in one embodiment. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic view of an IC design pattern constructed according to aspects of the present disclosure in one embodiment. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates an exemplary main feature of the IC design layout according to one embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The disclosed method <b>100</b> provides an IC design approach to collectively consider both proximate effect and location effect, and effectively tune/modify the IC design layout accordingly for improved imaging during a lithography process. The proximate effect refers to an imaging effect during a lithography process that an imaging variation is introduced by approximate features. For example, a pattern feature in an environment with a dense pattern and an identical feature in an isolated environment would result in images with different critical dimensions (CDs). The IC design layout can be tuned by resizing, reshaping, adding assist features, adding scattering bars or combinations according to the proximate effect to improve the image. This method is referred to as optical proximate correction (OPC).</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The location effect refers to the imaging effect during a lithography process that an imaging variation is introduced by and is associated with the location of the respective pattern feature in the IC design layout. For example, when the lithography process uses an extreme ultraviolet (EUV) light, the EUV beam is tilted to the optical axis of the lithography system, such as with a tilt angle of about 6 degree. A shadow effect is introduced by the tilt illumination and causes an image distortion that is dependent on the location of the pattern feature to be imaged. In different perspective, the proximate effect is related to a local environment on the IC design layout while the location effect is related to a global location on the IC design layout. The location effect can be reduced by tuning the IC design layout, including resizing, reshaping, adding assist features, adding scattering bars or combinations. This method is referred to as location effect correction (LEC). Particularly, the location of the pattern feature in the IC design layout is a factor to be considered during LEC.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In one embodiment where lithography process uses an EUV lithography, the location effect includes shadow effect, flare effect, border effect, resist heating effect, baking effect, develop effect or combinations thereof. In another embodiment where the lithography process uses electron beam (or e-beam) direct write (EBDW), the location effect includes fogging effect, flare effect, resist heating effect, baking effect, develop effect or combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The method <b>100</b> is described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 4</figref>. The method <b>100</b> begins at step <b>102</b> by receiving an IC design layout (or IC design pattern) from a designer. In one example, the designer can be a design house. In another example, the designer is a design team separated from a semiconductor manufacturer assigned for making IC products according to the IC design layout. In various embodiments, the semiconductor manufacturer is capable for making photomasks, semiconductor wafers, or both. The IC design layout includes various geometrical patterns designed for an IC product and based on the specification of the IC product.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The IC design layout is presented in one or more data files having the information of geometrical patterns. In one example, the IC design layout is expressed in a &#x201c;gds&#x201d; format known in the art. The designer, based on the specification of the product to be manufactured, implements a proper design procedure to carry out the IC design layout. The design procedure may include logic design, physical design, and place and route. As an example, a portion of the IC design layout includes various IC features (also referred to as main features), such as active region, gate electrode, source and drain, metal lines or via of the interlayer interconnection, and openings for bonding pads, to be formed on a semiconductor substrate (such as a silicon wafer) or on various material layers disposed over the semiconductor substrate. The IC design layout may include certain additional features, such as those features for imaging effect, processing enhancement, and/or mask identification information.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">An exemplary IC design layout <b>120</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> for illustration. In one embodiment, the IC design layout <b>120</b> is defined with in a plurality of regions <b>122</b> each including a same IC pattern <b>124</b>, as illustrated in two IC regions. In one example, each IC region <b>122</b> defines an IC die and the IC pattern <b>124</b> in the IC die. The IC design layout <b>120</b> includes multiple IC regions <b>122</b>, disposed in different places of the IC design layout <b>120</b> and labeled as 1, 2, 3, . . . , i, (i+1), . . . , and N, respectively. In the present example, the IC design layout <b>120</b> includes 35 IC regions <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The IC design layout <b>120</b> or the IC pattern <b>124</b> in each region <b>122</b> includes a plurality of main features. A main feature is a pattern that defines an IC feature, such as contact/via hole, to be formed on a semiconductor substrate. One exemplary main feature <b>130</b> is a square feature defined by its edges <b>132</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The method <b>100</b> may proceed to step <b>103</b> by providing a coordinate table associated with the IC design layout. The coordinate table includes the coordinates of the IC regions <b>122</b> in the IC design layout <b>120</b>. With the IC pattern and the coordinates of each IC region, the IC design layout <b>120</b> is well defined since the location of each IC region is given by the respective coordinates and the pattern in the IC region is the IC pattern <b>124</b>. In one particular example, the coordinates of i-th IC region include two numbers Xi and Yi, representing its location relative to X axis and Y axes.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The method <b>100</b> proceeds to step <b>104</b> by performing a dissection process to the IC design layout. In one example, the dissection process is applied to each of the main features in the IC design layout. The dissection process includes dissecting edges of a main feature into a plurality of segments such that each segment can be independently adjusted during the subsequent steps for OPC and LEC. More segments dissected from a main feature, more freedom to tune the pattern of the main feature but more time cost as well.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Take the main feature <b>130</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> as an example. The dissection is applied to the main feature <b>130</b> to generate multiple segments <b>134</b> defined by dissection points (or stitching points) <b>136</b>, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. In one embodiment, the dissection points or a subset thereof are assigned to the corners of the main feature <b>130</b>. In another embodiment, the dissection points or a subset thereof are assigned to one edge of the main feature such that the edge is dissected into two or more segments.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Various targets <b>138</b> are further assigned to the main feature <b>130</b> for simulation verification or other design purposes. The targets are virtual points and represent spatial locations relative to the main features. The targets <b>138</b> are used as reference to verify that the modified IC design layout is properly imaged such that the imaged main features hit or close to the targets. Particularly, when a simulated contour <b>139</b> of the main feature <b>130</b> is generated in a later step by simulation, the targets assigned to the corresponding main feature <b>130</b> are checked to verify if the targets hit or are close to the simulated contour <b>139</b> of the main feature <b>130</b>. The contour <b>139</b> is a simulated image of the main feature <b>130</b> when the main feature <b>130</b> is transferred to a product substrate, such as a semiconductor wafer by a lithography process.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The method <b>100</b> also includes a step <b>106</b> by performing a retargeting process to the IC design layout <b>120</b>. The retargeting process is a rule-based approach to modify the IC design layout based on various rules (referred to as retarget rules) to improve the imaging when the IC design layout is transferred to a wafer. At the present step, the IC design layout <b>120</b> is modified/adjusted according to various retarget rules. In various examples, the retargeting process includes repositioning, resizing, reshaping, adding assist features, adding scattering features, or combinations thereof. In another example, the retargeting process is applied to the main feature <b>130</b> such that a subset of the segments of the main feature <b>130</b> are adjusted, respectively, according to the retarget rules. The adjustment to a main feature includes moving/relocating the dissected edge segments such that the main feature is reshaped.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The retarget rules include various rules. In one embodiment, the retarget rules include OPC rules used to tune the IC design layout for reduced proximity effect. As noted, the proximity effect is an imaging effect wherein the imaging of a main feature is impacted by other features approximate to that main feature. Rule-based OPC approach includes extracting various OPC rules according to the proximate effect and applying those OPC rules to tune the IC design layout.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In another embodiment, the retarget rules includes LEC rules used to tune the IC design layout for reduced location effect. As noted above, the location effect is related to a global location on the IC design layout. The location effect can be reduced by tuning the IC design layout using rule-based LEC that includes resizing, reshaping, adding assist features, adding scattering bars or combinations. The location of the pattern feature is a factor to be considered during LEC. Rule-based LEC approach includes extracting various LEC rules according to the location effect and applying those LEC rules to tune the IC design layout.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In another embodiment, the retarget rules include design rules. The IC design layout <b>120</b> is adjusted according to various design rules, referred to as design rule check (DRC). The various design rules can be extracted from the semiconductor manufacturer in consideration of the manufacturing capability. The IC design follows the design rules in order to generate producible circuit patterns.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In one particular example, the IC design layout <b>120</b> is adjusted through a logic operation. In the semiconductor manufacturer, various manufacturing modules convert the manufacturing constraints into a set of rules that the IC design layout <b>120</b> has to meet. Otherwise, the IC design layout <b>120</b> will be modified accordingly such that the modified IC design layout meets these rules. Such modification is implemented by a logic operation.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In yet another embodiment, the retarget rules includes a combination or a subset of the OPC rules, LEC rules and design rules. In one example, the retarget rules are applied to the IC pattern <b>122</b> to tune the IC pattern accordingly, generating a modified IC pattern by the retargeting process. This modified IC pattern is referred to as retargeted IC pattern. Then, the retargeted IC pattern is used to replace the IC pattern in each IC region <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The method <b>100</b> may proceed to step <b>107</b> by providing or generating a correction sequence table. The correction sequence table includes a list of the IC regions <b>122</b> arranged in a certain order or sequence. The correction sequence table provides an order that the subsequent correction process is sequentially applied to each IC region of the IC design layout <b>120</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates one example how the IC regions <b>122</b> are arranged in the correction sequence table. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the IC design layout <b>120</b> includes a number (35 in this example) of IC regions configured in an array. The IC regions are labeled with numerals in compliance with the correction sequence table. Particularly, the correction sequence table starts from the IC region &#x201c;1&#x201d;, then &#x201c;2&#x201d;, &#x201c;3&#x201d;, . . . , (i+1), . . . and &#x201c;34&#x201d;, and ends at &#x201c;35&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The correction sequence table is arranged in a way such that adjacent IC regions <b>122</b> have less difference in term of the location effect or close sensitivity of the location effect. For example, IC regions <b>18</b> and <b>19</b> are arranged as adjacent elements in the correction sequence table since those two IC regions have similar or close sensitivity of the location effect. The sensitivity of the location effect is related to or represents the correction quantity by the correction process that considers the location effect. For one example, the sensitivity of the location effect increases along the X direction and decreases along the Y direction.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The correction sequence table may be arranged in different orders. In an alternative example, the sequence may start from 14, 15, 28 or 29.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The method <b>100</b> proceeds to step <b>108</b> by performing a correction process to the IC design layout <b>120</b>. The correction process is a model-based approach to tune IC design layout <b>120</b>, using a simulation model, referred to as correction model. The correction process and the correction model include the location effect. In the present embodiment, the correction process is applied to each IC region <b>122</b> of the IC design layout <b>120</b> in a sequence defined by the correction sequence table. For example, the correction process is applied to the IC region 1, 2, 3, . . . , and N.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">When the correction process is applied to each IC region, the IC pattern in the IC region is adjusted by various measures that include repositioning, resizing, reshaping, adding assist features, adding scattering features, or combinations thereof. Then the correction model is applied to the adjusted IC pattern in the IC region to generate a contour. The contour is evaluated to check if the contour satisfies the targets (or target points), which means that the contour hits the targets or is close to the targets within a predefined range. If the targets are not satisfied by the contour, another adjustment is applied to the adjusted IC pattern in the respective IC region. Then another simulation using the correction model is applied to the newly adjusted IC pattern, generating another contour. The generated contour is further checked to see if the targets are satisfied. This correction process is iterated until the assigned targets are satisfied. The final adjusted IC pattern is referred to as corrected IC pattern. Similarly, the final adjusted IC design layout by the correction process is referred to as the corrected IC design layout.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In one embodiment, when the correction process is applied to an IC region, it may applied to each main feature in that IC region, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Particularly, the correction model used to simulate the contour include an OPC model such that the proximate effect can be effectively simulated. In other words, the contour simulated by the model reflects the impact of the proximate effect to the contour. The correction model also include an LEC model such that the location effect can be effectively simulated. In other words, the contour simulated by the model reflects the impact of the location effect to the contour.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The correction process <b>108</b> is further described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, which is a flowchart of the correction process <b>108</b> constructed according to one embodiment. The correction process <b>108</b> begins at step <b>114</b> by inputting the coordinates of &#x201c;i&#x201d; (or i-th) IC region from the coordinate table. Therefore, the correction process can be applied to the respective IC region of the IC design layout according to the coordinates. In one example, the coordinates of an IC region represent a reference location, such as the center, of the IC region. The IC design layout <b>120</b> includes a plurality of IC regions <b>122</b> arranged in the sequence of the correction sequence table. Those arranged IC regions are sequentially labeled as 1, 2, 3, . . . , i, (i+1), . . . , (N&#x2212;1) and N.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The correction process <b>108</b> includes a step <b>116</b> by performing a correction to the i-th IC region. The correction applied to the i-th IC region includes adjusting the IC pattern in the i-th IC region, simulating the contour of the IC pattern in the i-th IC region, and evaluating if the contour satisfies the assigned targets. If not, the above procedure is iterated as many time as needed until the assigned targets are satisfied. In the iteration procedure, the adjusted IC pattern is further adjusted. State differently, the adjusted IC pattern in the previous cycle is used as an input to the next cycle.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The correction process <b>108</b> includes a step <b>118</b> by copying the corrected IC pattern of the i-th IC region to the (i+1)-th IC region, which means the correction process to the (i+1)-th IC region will use the corrected IC pattern of the i-th IC region as the input. It is more efficient since the adjacent IC regions have similar sensitivity of the location effect. Thus, the correction to the (i+1)-th IC region converges more fast with less iteration cycles.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The correction process <b>108</b> then goes back to the step <b>114</b> by inputting the coordinates of the (i+1)-th IC region, then step <b>116</b> by applying the correction to the (i+1)-th IC region. The initial IC pattern to be used in the (i+1)-th IC region is the corrected IC pattern of the i-th IC region. The correction process <b>108</b> including steps <b>114</b>, <b>116</b> and <b>118</b> thus is applied to each IC regions sequentially according to the correction sequence table until all IC regions in the IC design layout are exhausted.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The first IC region (IC region &#x201c;1&#x201d;) in the correction sequence table may take more cycles since the initial IC pattern for the first IC region cannot take the advantages of the previous IC region as the first one in the queue. In the present embodiment, the initial IC pattern of the first IC pattern is the retargeted IC pattern. The correction process to the first IC region uses the retargeted IC pattern as the input. Accordingly, the retargeting result is incorporated into the first IC region and the rest IC region through step <b>118</b> since each subsequent IC region has an input from the preceding IC region. Thus, a corrected IC design layout <b>120</b> is generated by the correction process.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Referring back to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the method <b>100</b> may further include a step by performing a mask rule check (MRC) to the corrected IC design layout <b>120</b>. At this step, the corrected IC design layout <b>120</b> is checked by one or more mask rules and is further modified accordingly. In one embodiment, various mask rules are extracted from the mask fabrication. Various mask making data are collected from the mask fabrication and extracted into a set of rules that the IC design layout, as the pattern to be imaged to a mask, should follow. In one embodiment, the mask rules are applied to various segments of the main features. Those segments that fail one or more mask rules are modified according to the corresponding mask rules.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In another embodiment where the EBDW is used, no mask is fabricated. The IC design layout is directly used in e-beam writing for wafer fabrication. In this case, some other rules may be extracted from the e-beam direct writing, referred to as EBDW rules. Instead of performing the mask rule check, the IC design layout is checked according to the EBDW rules and may be modified according to the EBDW rules such that the EBDW can be properly implemented according to the modified IC design layout.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the method <b>100</b> may proceed to step <b>110</b> by generating a tape-out of the modified IC design layout for mask making or e-beam writing. The tape-out represents a format of the IC design layout that can be used for mask making or e-beam writing. At this step, the IC design layout may be fractured into a plurality of polygons (or trapezoids). The tape-out is formed based on the IC design layout modified by the correction process.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Other steps may follows. In one embodiment, the method <b>100</b> may further proceed to a step for the fabrication of a mask or a group of masks based on the tape-out of the modified IC design layout <b>120</b>. In one embodiment, an e-beam or a mechanism of multiple e-beams is used to form a pattern on a mask (photomask or reticle) based on the IC design layout. The mask can be formed in various suitable technologies. In one embodiment, the mask is formed using the binary technology. In this case, the mask pattern includes opaque regions and transparent regions. In one example, the binary mask includes a transparent substrate (e.g., fused quartz), and an opaque material (e.g., chromium) coated in the opaque regions of the mask. In another embodiment, the mask is formed using a phase shift technology. In the phase shift mask (PSM), various features in the pattern formed on the mask are configured to have proper phase difference to enhance the resolution and imaging quality. In various examples, the PSM can be an attenuated PSM or an alternating PSM known in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In another embodiment, a semiconductor wafer is fabricated using a mask or a set of masks formed by the above method. The semiconductor wafer includes a silicon substrate or other proper substrate and material layers formed thereon. In this case, an EUV lithography may be used to form semiconductor wafers using the mask(s).</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In yet another embodiment, the tape-out of the IC design layout is directly used to pattern a semiconductor wafer by an EBDW lithography apparatus. In either situation (EUV or EBDW), both the proximate effect and the location effect are considered in the correction process, the imaging quality is substantially improved. Other embodiments and modifications may be implemented without departing from the spirit of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an IC design (flow) method <b>150</b> constructed according to aspects of the present disclosure in one embodiment. The IC design method <b>150</b> is one embodiment or an alternative of the IC design method <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. Similar descriptions are omitted for simplicity. The method <b>150</b> includes a step <b>152</b> by receiving an IC design layout as an input. In one example, the IC design layout is in GDS format.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The method <b>150</b> proceeds to a step <b>154</b> by providing or receiving a coordinate table that includes the coordinates of the all dies (or IC regions) in the IC design layout.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The method <b>150</b> proceeds to a step <b>156</b> by performing dissection and retarget to the IC design layout.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The method <b>150</b> proceeds to a step <b>158</b> by providing or generating a correction sequence table of the dies (or IC regions) of the IC design layout.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The method <b>150</b> proceeds to a step <b>160</b> by performing correction to the IC design layout using a correction model that includes location effect. The correction process <b>160</b> includes an iteration procedure that corrects each die sequentially according to the correction sequence table. When the correction is applied to each die, it further includes a first step <b>164</b> for i-th die coordinate input, and a second step <b>166</b> for correcting the IC pattern in that i-th die using the correction model <b>162</b>. The second step <b>166</b> includes another iteration procedure to adjust the IC pattern many times until the contour of the IC pattern in that die satisfies the assigned targets. The correction process <b>160</b> further includes a third step by copying the corrected IC pattern of the i-th die to the i-th layer of the IC design layout. In another words, the corrected IC pattern of the i-th die is used as an input to the (i&#x2212;1)-th die for its correction. When the correction is applied to the (i+1)-th die, the initial IC pattern is the corrected IC pattern of the i-th die, which is taken from the i-th layer.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The method <b>150</b> ends with a modified IC design layout to form a tape-out of the IC design layout.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an IC design (flow) method <b>180</b> constructed according to aspects of the present disclosure in another embodiment. The IC design method <b>180</b> is one embodiment or an alternative of the IC design method <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The method <b>180</b> is similar to the method <b>150</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> but includes an additional correction step <b>182</b> using a correction model <b>184</b> that does not include the location effect. In one example, the correction model <b>184</b> includes an OPC model. The correction step <b>182</b> is implemented before the correction step <b>160</b>. Since the correction step <b>182</b> does not consider the location effect, all dies have the same correction. The correction <b>182</b> may be applied to one die and copy the corrected results to the rest dies.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Thus, the present disclosure provides an integrated circuit (IC) method. The IC design method includes receiving an IC design layout having a plurality of IC regions each including an IC pattern; performing a dissection process to the IC design layout; and performing a correction process to the IC design layout using a correction model that includes proximity effect and location effect. The correction process includes performing a first correction step to a first IC region of the IC regions, resulting in a first corrected IC pattern in the first IC region; and performing a second correction step to a second IC region of the IC regions, starting with the first corrected IC pattern, resulting in a second corrected IC pattern.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In one embodiment of the IC method, the performing a correction process to the IC design layout includes performing a third correction step to a third IC region of the IC regions starting with the second corrected IC pattern, resulting in a third corrected IC pattern.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">In another embodiment, the IC method further includes providing a correction sequence table of the IC regions; and performing a respective correction step to other IC regions of the IC regions in a sequence defined in the correction sequence table, using a corrected IC pattern from a preceding IC region as an input.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">In yet another embodiment, the performing a second correction step to a second IC region includes performing the second correction step in an iteration mode until the second corrected IC pattern is acceptable according a predefined criteria.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">In yet another embodiment, the IC method further includes providing a coordinate table of the IC regions, wherein the performing a correction process to the IC design layout includes applying the correction process to each IC region of the IC regions using the model and respective coordinates of the IC region in the coordinate table of the IC regions.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">In yet another embodiment, the IC method further includes performing a retargeting process to the IC design layout using a set of retarget rules before the performing a correction process and after the performing a dissection process.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In yet another embodiment, the performing a retargeting process to the IC design layout includes performing the retargeting process to the IC pattern to generate a retargeted IC pattern and replace the IC pattern in each of the IC region by the retargeted IC pattern.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">In yet another embodiment, the performing a first correction step to a first IC region of the IC regions includes performing the first correction step to the first IC region of the IC regions using the retargeted IC pattern as an input.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">In yet another embodiment, the retarget rules include a first set of rules associated with the proximity effect and a second set of rules associated with the location effect.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">In yet another embodiment, each of the plurality of IC regions is associated with one IC die and the IC pattern in each of the IC regions is identical.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In yet another embodiment, the IC method further includes performing another correction process to the IC design layout using another model associated only with proximate effect before the performing a correction process to the IC design layout.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The present disclosure also provides another embodiment of an IC method that includes receiving an IC design layout having a plurality of IC regions each including an IC pattern; performing dissection to the IC design layout; performing a retargeting process to the IC design layout in a rule-based mode; providing a correction sequence table that arranges the IC regions in a sequence; and performing a correction process to the IC design layout using a correction model that includes proximity effect and location effect. The correction process includes applying a first correction to a preceding IC region of the IC regions, resulting in a first correct IC pattern in the IC region; and applying a second correction to a succeeding IC region of the IC regions in the sequence using the first corrected IC pattern as an input, resulting in a second corrected IC pattern.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">In one embodiment of the IC method, the performing a correction process to the IC design layout includes performing the correction process to rest of the IC regions according to the sequence until the IC regions are exhausted.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">In another embodiment, the IC method further includes providing a coordinate table that includes a set of coordinates associated with the IC regions, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">In yet another embodiment, the performing a retargeting process to the IC design layout includes applying the retargeting process to the IC pattern to generate a retargeted IC pattern; and replacing the IC pattern in each IC region with the retargeted IC pattern.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">In yet another embodiment, the applying the correction process to the succeeding IC region includes applying the correction process to the succeeding IC region according to respective set of coordinates associated with the succeeding IC region.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">In yet another embodiment, the applying the correction process to a succeeding IC region of the IC regions includes correcting the first corrected IC pattern according to the location effect and respective set of coordinates, resulting in a modified IC pattern; simulating the modified IC pattern using the correction model to generate a contour of the modified IC pattern; evaluating the contour of the modified IC pattern if the contour is acceptable according to a criteria; and correcting the modified IC pattern according to the location effect and the respective set of coordinates if the contour is unacceptable.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">In yet another embodiment, the correction sequence table arranges IC regions in a way such that adjacent IC regions have similar sensitivity of the location effect.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">In yet another embodiment, the IC method further includes performing another correction process to the IC design layout using another correction model that includes the proximate effect and does not include the location effect, prior to the performing a correction process to the IC design layout using the correction model that includes the proximity effect and location effect.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">The present disclosure also provides another embodiment of an IC method. The IC method includes receiving an IC design layout having a plurality of IC regions each including an identical IC design pattern; providing a coordinate table that includes a set of coordinates associated with the IC regions, respectively; performing dissection to the IC design layout such that the IC design pattern is segmented; performing a retargeting process to the IC design layout in a rule-based mode; performing a first correction process to the IC design layout using a first model that includes proximate effect but does not include location effect; providing a correction sequence table that arranges the IC regions in a sequence; and performing a second correction process to the IC design layout using a second model that includes the proximity effect and the location effect. The performing a second correction process includes applying the correction process to a preceding IC region of the IC regions, resulting in a first corrected IC pattern in the preceding IC region; and applying the correction process to a succeeding IC region of the IC regions in the sequence using the first corrected IC pattern as an input, resulting in a second corrected IC pattern to the succeeding IC region.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The foregoing has outlined features of several embodiments so that those skilled in the art may better understand the detailed description that follows. Those skilled in the art should appreciate that they may readily use the present disclosure as a basis for designing or modifying other processes and structures for carrying out the same purposes and/or achieving the same advantages of the embodiments disclosed herein. Those skilled in the art should also realize that such equivalent constructions do not depart from the spirit and scope of the present disclosure, and that they may make various changes, substitutions and alterations herein without departing from the spirit and scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An integrated circuit (IC) method comprising:
<claim-text>receiving an IC design layout having a plurality of non-overlapping IC regions, each of the IC regions including a same initial IC pattern, and wherein each of the plurality of IC regions is associated with a different IC die;</claim-text>
<claim-text>performing a dissection process to the IC design layout;</claim-text>
<claim-text>performing a correction process to the IC design layout using a correction model that includes proximity effect and location effect, wherein the correction process includes:
<claim-text>performing a first correction step to a first IC region of the plurality of IC regions, thereby modifying the initial IC pattern to result in a first corrected IC pattern in the first IC region,</claim-text>
<claim-text>copying the first corrected IC pattern to a second IC region of the plurality of IC regions, thereby replacing the initial IC pattern of the second IC region with the first corrected IC pattern; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>after copying, performing a second correction step to the second IC region of the plurality of IC regions, wherein the performing the second correction step includes starting with the copied first corrected IC pattern and resulting in a second corrected IC pattern; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>taping-out the second corrected IC pattern to provide a taped-out pattern accessible by at least one of a mask making tool and an e-beam lithography tool.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The IC method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the performing the correction process to the IC design layout includes copying the second corrected IC pattern to a third IC region of the plurality of IC regions, and performing a third correction step to the third IC region of the plurality of IC regions starting with the second corrected IC pattern, and resulting in a third corrected IC pattern.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The IC method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>providing a correction sequence table of the plurality of IC regions, wherein the correction sequence table identifies the first and second IC regions; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>performing a respective correction step to each of the plurality of IC regions in a sequence defined in the correction sequence table.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The IC method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the performing the second correction step to the second IC region includes performing the second correction step in an iteration mode until the second corrected IC pattern is acceptable according a predefined criteria.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The IC method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising providing a coordinate table including of coordinates for each of the plurality IC regions, wherein the performing the correction process to the IC design layout includes applying the correction process to each of the plurality of IC regions using the model and respective coordinates of a selected IC region provided in the coordinate table of the plurality of IC regions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The IC method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising performing a retargeting process to the IC design layout using a set of retarget rules before the performing the correction process and after the performing the dissection process.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The IC method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the retarget rules include a first set of rules associated with the proximity effect and a second set of rules associated with the location effect.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The IC method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the performing the retargeting process to the IC design layout includes performing the retargeting process to the IC pattern to generate the initial.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The IC method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising performing another correction process to the IC design layout using another model associated only with the proximity effect before the performing the correction process to the IC design layout.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A method comprising:
<claim-text>receiving an integrated circuit (IC) design layout having a plurality of non-overlapping IC regions, each of the plurality of IC regions including a first IC pattern having a plurality of main features;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a correction sequence table that arranges the plurality of IC regions in a sequence, wherein the sequence designates a first IC region and an adjacent second IC region of the plurality of IC regions;</claim-text>
<claim-text>after generating the correction sequence table, performing a correction process to the IC design layout using a correction model that includes proximity effect and location effect, wherein the correction process includes:
<claim-text>applying a first correction to the designated first IC region of the IC regions, resulting in a first corrected IC pattern in the first IC region, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a second correction to the designated second IC region of the plurality of IC regions using the first corrected IC pattern as an input, resulting in a second corrected IC pattern; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>using at least one of the first corrected IC pattern and the second corrected IC pattern to pattern a semiconductor wafer to provide plurality of features on the semiconductor wafer defined by the second corrected IC pattern.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the performing the correction process to the IC design layout includes performing the correction process to rest of the plurality of IC regions according to the sequence until the plurality of IC regions are exhausted.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising providing a coordinate table that includes a set of coordinates associated with each of the IC regions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising, prior to performing the correction process, performing a retargeting process to the IC design layout in a rule-based mode, wherein the performing the retargeting process to the IC design layout includes:
<claim-text>applying the retargeting process to the IC pattern to generate a retargeted IC pattern; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>replacing the IC pattern in each of the plurality of IC regions with the retargeted IC pattern.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the applying the correction process to the designated second IC region includes applying the correction process to the designated second IC region according to a respective set of coordinates associated with the designated second IC region.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the applying the correction to the designated second IC region of the IC regions includes:
<claim-text>correcting the first corrected IC pattern according to the location effect and respective set of coordinates, resulting in a modified IC pattern;</claim-text>
<claim-text>simulating the modified IC pattern using the correction model to generate a contour of the modified IC pattern;</claim-text>
<claim-text>evaluating the contour of the modified IC pattern if the contour is acceptable according to a criteria; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>correcting the modified IC pattern according to the location effect and the respective set of coordinates if the contour is unacceptable.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the correction sequence table sequences the plurality of IC regions such that adjacent IC regions have similar sensitivity of the location effect.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising performing another correction process to the IC design layout using another correction model that includes the proximity effect and does not include the location effect, prior to the performing the correction process to the IC design layout using the correction model that includes the proximity effect and location effect.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. A method comprising:
<claim-text>receiving an IC design layout having a plurality of IC regions, each of the IC regions including an identical IC design pattern;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a coordinate table that includes a set of coordinates associated with each of the plurality of IC regions, respectively;</claim-text>
<claim-text>performing a first correction process to the IC design layout using a first model that includes proximity effect but does not include location effect, wherein the first correction process is applied to the plurality of IC regions;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a correction sequence table that assigns each of the plurality of IC regions a sequence order designation, wherein the assignment is based on a similarity of a location effect for each of the plurality of IC regions; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>performing a second correction process to the IC design layout using a second model that includes the proximity effect and the location effect, wherein the performing the second correction process includes:
<claim-text>using the correction sequence table to identify a first IC region of the plurality of IC regions;</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a first adjustment process to the identified first IC region of the plurality of IC regions, resulting in a first corrected IC pattern in the first IC region,</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying a second IC region of the plurality of IC regions using the correction sequence table;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>copying the first IC region to applying the correction process to the identified second IC region, resulting in a second corrected IC pattern in the second IC region; and
<claim-text>taping-out the IC layout including the second corrected IC pattern to provide a taped-out pattern accessible by at least one of a mask making tool and an e-beam lithography tool. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
