<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625352-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625352</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13099791</doc-number>
<date>20110503</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>282</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>11</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>34</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36518518</main-classification>
<further-classification>365 51</further-classification>
<further-classification>365 63</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Method and apparatus for sharing internal power supplies in integrated circuit devices</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6031760</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Sakui et al.</name>
<date>20000200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36518521</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7154790</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Han et al.</name>
<date>20061200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7549097</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Momohara</name>
<date>20090600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>714724</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7590023</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kim</name>
<date>20090900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>365226</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8400781</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Gillingham</name>
<date>20130300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>361790</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0050320</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Gillingham et al.</name>
<date>20110300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>CA</country>
<doc-number>2675561</doc-number>
<date>20080800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>0498336</doc-number>
<date>19920200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00009">
<othercit>&#x201c;Low Power Double Data Rate 2 (LPDDR2)&#x201d;, JEDEC Standard, JESD209-2B, JEDEC Solid State Technology Association, 238 pages, Feb. 2010.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>34</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36518518</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>365 51</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>365 63</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>61416437</doc-number>
<date>20101123</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120127798</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120524</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gillingham</last-name>
<first-name>Peter B.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kanata</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CA</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gillingham</last-name>
<first-name>Peter B.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kanata</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Auerback</last-name>
<first-name>Harvey</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Mosaid Technologies Incorporated</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Ottawa, Ontario</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Dinh</last-name>
<first-name>Son</first-name>
<department>2824</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A method, system and apparatus for sharing internal power supplies in integrated circuit devices is described. A multiple device integrated circuit <b>200</b> including multiple integrated circuits <b>202</b>-<b>205</b> each having internal power supplies is contained in an enclosure <b>201</b>. Integrated circuits <b>202</b>-<b>205</b> are described showing how to make external connection to internal power supplies. Connections <b>208</b>-<b>212</b> are provided to the internal power supplies of each of devices <b>202</b>-<b>205</b>. Another embodiment <b>500</b> of the system provides for disablement of regulators in multiple integrated circuits <b>502, 503</b>, and <b>504</b> by another integrated circuit <b>501</b> for power consumption reduction. The method FIG. <b>6</b> includes providing devices and connecting the internal power supplies together. An integrated circuit <b>501</b> with a power supply <b>400</b> adapted to the system and method with additional circuitry <b>308, 404</b> and <b>402</b> for disabling a regulator <b>306</b> is described.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="175.01mm" wi="181.69mm" file="US08625352-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="212.60mm" wi="189.57mm" file="US08625352-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="198.04mm" wi="184.23mm" file="US08625352-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="159.26mm" wi="172.38mm" file="US08625352-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="162.73mm" wi="181.19mm" file="US08625352-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="187.28mm" wi="188.04mm" file="US08625352-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="235.63mm" wi="175.77mm" file="US08625352-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates generally to integrated circuit devices and in particular to integrated circuit devices having internal power supplies.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Integrated Circuit devices such as DRAM (Dynamic Random Access Memory) and Flash (electrically erasable/programmable non-volatile memory) typically require for operation a number of voltages for separate operations including storing, reading, and erasing data. These voltages are internally generated by using an externally supplied voltage source often referred to as V<sub>dd</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">A conventional DRAM device may have a V<sub>pp </sub>supply for providing a high voltage for driving a wordline above the V<sub>dd </sub>level stored in a memory cell, a V<sub>dd</sub>/2 supply for driving the cell plate to a mid-rail potential, and a V<sub>bb </sub>supply for providing a negative back bias potential to the memory cell substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A conventional NAND Flash device may have pump circuits for generating V<sub>pass </sub>for application to unselected wordlines in a selected block during page read operations, V<sub>pgm </sub>for applying to selected wordlines in page program operations, and V<sub>ers </sub>for applying to wordlines in a selected block during block erase operations.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">These internal voltage supply circuits occupy significant chip area and increase the die size and cost, this is particularly the case if capacitive pump circuits are used which require large pump and reservoir capacitors. The voltage supply circuits may also limit performance. For example, in a NAND Flash device the V<sub>pgm </sub>voltage must be pulsed and applied repeatedly to a wordline in alternation with verify read operations. The time that it takes to charge the wordline adds overhead to each program/verify read cycle and can extend the program time parameter t<sub>PROG </sub>which is a critical factor in NAND Flash performance.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In some integrated circuit devices, for example LPDDR2 (Low-Power Double Data Rate 2) DRAM as described in JEDEC (Joint Electron Device Engineering Council) specification JESD209-2B, the number of banks that can be activated within a given time window depends of t<sub>FAW </sub>(Four bank Activate Window) which is specified as 50 ns for the higher speed grades. Although commands to activate all 8 banks could be issued to the device within this period of time, the t<sub>FAW </sub>restriction limits the current drive requirements on the internal V<sub>pp </sub>generator, and perhaps other internal voltage generators as well, by forcing the user to activate a maximum of four banks in the rolling t<sub>FAW </sub>window. This restriction allows a size of the V<sub>pp </sub>generator to be reduced from that required for unrestricted bank activation, thereby saving die area and cost.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">When a number of memory devices are combined to provide a larger memory subsystem, they are often connected to a common shared bus. In this case there may not be sufficient command bandwidth to exercise all devices to their maximum capabilities. For example, in the case of eight LPDDR2 DRAM devices connected to a shared command bus operating at 400 MHz, it is impossible to issue four bank activate commands to each device within a 50 ns t<sub>FAW </sub>window. One command requires two edges of the clock or 2.5 ns. Therefore at least some of the devices will not be fully utilizing the capabilities of their internal V<sub>pp </sub>generators. It is not practical for DRAM manufacturers to offer different variants of memory products with a range of internal voltage generator drive capabilities and optimized die size. Memory product manufacturers rely on high volume of standardized product to drive costs down.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The invention provides a method and apparatus for connecting the internal voltages of multiple integrated circuits together. This allows shared use of otherwise idle resources resulting in greater capacity and reduced size. The invention is adaptable to single or multiple voltage sharing. The apparatus includes an integrated circuit with a connection to the internal power supply from the external environment. Additional embodiments provide access to several internal supplies. The method includes the process of making access available and connecting multiple integrated circuits internal voltages and control.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">An additional embodiment allows one integrated circuit to control the internal power supply of another similar integrated circuit. This is illustrated by the ability to disable the regulator in the power supply of the controlled integrated circuit resulting in reduced power consumption and more efficient allocation of resources.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The system includes multiple integrated circuits connected together sharing power supplies.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Further features and advantages of the present invention will become apparent from the following detailed description, taken in combination with the appended drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram of a conventional MCP (Multi-Chip Package) enclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram of an MCP enclosure containing embodiments of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a block diagram of a conventional power supply;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a block diagram of a switchable power supply suitable for a third embodiment of the invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is another block diagram of an MCP enclosure incorporating a third embodiment of the invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flowchart of the method of the invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">It will be noted that throughout the appended drawings, like features are identified by like reference numerals.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Memory die may be stacked and packaged together on a single substrate to achieve higher volumetric efficiency. Interconnection between memory devices in the package and terminals on the package may be accomplished with wire bonds or TSVs (Through Silicon Via). U.S. patent application Ser. No. 12/757,540, filed Apr. 9, 2010, describes chip selection and bus configurations for stacked memory devices. As with discrete packaged memory devices, multiple die within a MCP (Multi-Chip Package) enclosure are often connected to the same bus.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, in a conventional configuration, assume that 4 LPDDR DRAM die having the t<sub>FAW </sub>specification described hereinabove are packaged together in a single MCP <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Address and command inputs on all four die are wired together and connected to MCP address/command terminals. Likewise, bidirectional databus terminals (DQ) are connected in common to each die. Separate chip enable pins (CE<sub>1 </sub>. . . CE<sub>4</sub>) allow commands to be directed towards individual LPDDR2 die within the MCP. Clocks are not specifically shown but are included as part of the address/command and data busses. Power supplies (V<sub>dd</sub>, V<sub>ss</sub>, V<sub>ddq</sub>, and V<sub>ssq</sub>) are also provided in common to all four die. This configuration shares the same drawbacks as a board level memory subsystem comprising discrete individually packaged memory devices. Bank activation in each die is limited by the t<sub>FAW </sub>specification and beyond a certain number of die there is insufficient command bandwidth to exercise each die to the t<sub>FAW </sub>limit.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, in an embodiment of the invention <b>200</b> assume that 4 die having LPDDR2 functionality <b>202</b>, <b>203</b>, <b>204</b> and <b>205</b> all having the same t<sub>FAW </sub>specification as the conventional MCP <b>100</b> are packaged together in a single MCP <b>201</b>. These die have been modified by the addition of a wire bond pad or TSV bump connection <b>212</b>, <b>213</b>, <b>214</b> and <b>215</b> respectively to the internal V<sub>pp </sub>voltage supply via a common bus <b>207</b>. A second embodiment provides connections to other internal voltage supplies such as V<sub>bb </sub>or V<sub>dd</sub>/2 in a similar manner. The result can be a reduction in the size of circuit components when all of die <b>202</b>, <b>203</b>, <b>204</b> and <b>205</b> power supplies are in parallel.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Within the MCP enclosure or encapsulation the internal V<sub>pp </sub>supply nodes <b>212</b>, <b>213</b>, <b>214</b> and <b>215</b> for each of the die <b>202</b>, <b>203</b>, <b>204</b> and <b>205</b> are wired together to bus <b>207</b>. Assuming each of die <b>202</b>, <b>203</b>, <b>204</b> and <b>205</b> is capable of providing sufficient V<sub>pp </sub>current to activate 4 banks within a 50 ns t<sub>FAW </sub>window, the four die stack <b>200</b> can support 16 bank activations within the t<sub>FAW </sub>window, regardless of the distribution of the 16 banks among the four die. This can result in significant increases in performance without any additional die area penalty for larger internal supplies.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a block diagram of a conventional V<sub>pp </sub>pump circuit <b>300</b>. A capacitive pump circuit draws current from the V<sub>dd </sub>supply and boosts the level to a potential higher than V<sub>dd</sub>. A simple form of the circuit can achieve a V<sub>pp </sub>level close to double that of V<sub>dd</sub>. More complex circuits are known in the art for achieving voltage levels higher than 2&#xd7;V<sub>dd</sub>. A V<sub>bb </sub>pump (not shown) has a similar structure.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">An oscillator generates <b>302</b> a clock signal to control the capacitive pump <b>304</b>. On each clock cycle, a quantity of charge is delivered to the output to increase the V<sub>pp </sub>level. Often, a reservoir capacitor is connected to the output for holding the charge and attenuating a voltage step caused by dumping charge on each clock cycle such capacitors can become quite large and occupy substantial space on the integrated circuit chip. A regulator <b>306</b> senses the level of V<sub>pp </sub>to determine when V<sub>pp </sub>has reached the desired level. When this occurs the regulator <b>306</b> output goes low to disable the oscillator <b>302</b> and pump <b>304</b>. The V<sub>pp </sub>supply can be enabled or disabled with the EN input signal. In a deep power down mode when data in the memory does not have to be maintained the EN input signal can be brought low to disable the regulator <b>306</b> directly and turn off the oscillator <b>302</b> and pump <b>304</b> with an AND gate <b>308</b>. In operation when the V<sub>pp </sub>level is below the desired level all three blocks <b>302</b>, <b>304</b> and <b>306</b> consume power. When V<sub>pp </sub>reached the desired level only the regulator <b>306</b> consumes power. In the deep power down mode the regulator <b>306</b> is completely turned off by the EN input signal to save power.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In a third embodiment, a regulator in only one of the die is enabled while the remaining regulators are disabled. This can significantly reduce the power in self-refresh data retention mode which is particularly important in handheld portable devices such as cell phones.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a block diagram of a switchable power supply <b>400</b> suitable for the third embodiment of the invention. V<sub>pp </sub>supply <b>400</b> has an additional input EN<sub>R </sub><b>407</b> to enable regulator <b>306</b>. If EN<sub>R </sub><b>407</b> is at a high level (1) the circuit functions identically to the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> V<sub>pp </sub>supply. In this embodiment regulator <b>306</b> may be disabled by a low level signal (0) on EN<sub>R </sub>input <b>407</b>. Input EN<sub>R </sub><b>407</b> is connected to one input on AND gate <b>402</b> the result is disabling regulator <b>306</b> when the signal (0) is on EN<sub>R</sub>. Additionally, externally provided regulator input R<sub>IN </sub><b>406</b> is connected through a multiplexor <b>404</b> to control oscillator <b>302</b> and pump <b>304</b>. V<sub>pp </sub>supply <b>400</b> also provides the local regulator output on the R<sub>OUT </sub>terminal <b>408</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> a third embodiment of the invention incorporating the power supply of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. As in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> the internal V<sub>pp </sub>supply nodes <b>212</b>, <b>213</b>, <b>214</b> and <b>215</b> for each of the die <b>501</b>, <b>502</b>, <b>503</b> and <b>504</b> are wired together to bus <b>207</b> in a MCP <b>500</b>. In this embodiment however, LPDDR2 die #<b>1</b> <b>501</b> has an enabled regulator so as a result of a logic high (1) <b>511</b> or V<sub>dd </sub>level applied to the EN<sub>R </sub>input <b>512</b>, while LPDDR2 die #<b>2</b> <b>502</b>, #<b>3</b> <b>503</b>, and #<b>4</b> <b>504</b> have disabled regulators as a result of a logic low (0) on lines <b>521</b>, <b>531</b> and <b>541</b> respectively or V<sub>ss </sub>level applied to the corresponding EN<sub>R </sub>inputs <b>522</b>, <b>532</b> and <b>542</b>. The regulator output R<sub>OUT </sub><b>513</b> on die #<b>1</b> is connected to the regulator inputs <b>523</b>, <b>533</b> and <b>543</b> R<sub>IN </sub>on die #<b>2</b> <b>502</b>, #<b>3</b> <b>503</b>, and #<b>4</b> <b>504</b> respectively. As a result only one regulator (the one on LPDDR2 die #<b>1</b> <b>501</b>) within MCP <b>500</b> is enabled and power consumption is reduced. As before, all V<sub>pp </sub>pumps on dies <b>501</b>, <b>502</b>, <b>503</b> and <b>504</b> can be activated when necessary to meet the current drive requirements on V<sub>pp </sub>as when multiple banks are activated within a short period of time. This technique can also be applied to other supplies in MCP DRAM such as the V<sub>bb </sub>substrate bias supply. It can also be applied to internal supplies on NAND Flash devices in MCP configurations such as V<sub>prog </sub>or V<sub>ers </sub>charge pumps.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Pumped supplies such as V<sub>pp </sub>can be ganged together without problem. In the case where each device has its own regulator enabled, due to variations from device to device each regulator may disable the pump at a slightly different voltage. Essentially the regulator with the highest threshold will determine the overall V<sub>pp </sub>of the combined system. Since the regulator in a V<sub>pp </sub>supply typically does not drain off excess charge to establish a voltage at exactly the threshold point, no power is wasted by having some variation in regulator threshold levels.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flowchart of the method of the invention. As described above the first step is providing terminals on the individual memory devices connected to the internal power supply. In prior art devices these connections are inaccessible to other components. As described this method will work with such diverse devices as DRAM, flash memory including NAND flash, NOR flash, PCRAM (Phase Change Random Access Memory) and any memory element which includes an internal power supply.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The next step is connecting the terminals of the devices together allowing the devices to share power supplies. In the simplest embodiment as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> ends. The same process can be continued to connect other voltages internal to the memory devices such supplies in MCP DRAM such as the V<sub>bb </sub>substrate bias supply. It can also be applied to internal supplies on NAND Flash devices in MCP configurations such as V<sub>prog </sub>or V<sub>ers </sub>charge pumps.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The process continues in devices having internal regulators in their internal power supply. In such cases the devise can be provided with a regulator input and/or a regulator output connection. The regulator output connection of the first device is connected to the regulator input of at least one and frequently several devises. As described above this allow the first device to switch off and on the regulators of the other devices to save power and reduce heat buildup.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Although the figures show only sharing of V<sub>pp </sub>supply, any combination of internal supplies or all of the internal supplies can be shared within an MCP enclosure to improve performance, reduce power consumption, and optimize the die area within each individual die. These techniques can be applied to DRAM, flash memory including NAND flash and NOR flash, as well as other forms of memory such as PCRAM (Phase Change Random Access Memory) and other emerging memory technologies.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A multichip package comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of memory dies,</claim-text>
<claim-text>each memory die comprising an internal supply voltage generator connected to an internal supply voltage terminal, wherein said internal supply voltage terminals of each memory die are connected together within the multichip package.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The multichip package as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said memory dies are DRAM dies.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The multichip package as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein said internal supply voltage generator is a wordline supply voltage generator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The multichip package as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein said internal supply voltage generator is a substrate bias supply voltage generator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The multichip package as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said memory dies are flash memory dies.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The multichip package as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein said flash dies are NAND flash dies.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The multichip package as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein said internal supply voltage generator is a page program supply voltage generator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The multichip package as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein said internal supply voltage generator is a block erase supply voltage generator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A multichip package comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of memory devices,</claim-text>
<claim-text>each memory device further comprising an internal supply voltage generator connected to an internal supply voltage terminal, wherein said internal supply voltage terminals of each memory device are connected together within the multichip package,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said internal supply voltage generator further comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a regulator connected to a regulator output terminal, a regulator input terminal, and a regulator enable terminal, wherein said regulator enable terminal of said first memory device is connected within the multichip package to a first voltage for enabling said regulator in said first device, and said regulator enable terminal of a second memory device is connected within the multichip package to a second voltage for disabling said regulator in the second device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The multichip package as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein said regulator output terminal of the first memory device is connected to said regulator input terminal of a second memory device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A method for constructing a multichip package comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>providing a plurality of memory dies, each memory die having an internal supply voltage generator connected to an internal supply voltage terminal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>connecting the internal supply voltage terminals of each memory die together within the multichip package.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method for constructing a multichip package as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein said memory dies are DRAM dies.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method for constructing a multichip package as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein said internal supply voltage generator is a wordline supply voltage generator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method for constructing a multichip package as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein said internal supply voltage generator is a substrate bias supply voltage generator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method for constructing a multichip package as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein said memory dies are flash memory dies.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method for constructing a multichip package as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein said flash dies are NAND flash dies.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method for constructing a multichip package as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein said internal supply voltage generator is a page program supply voltage generator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method for constructing a multichip package as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein said internal supply voltage generator is a block erase supply voltage generator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A method for constructing a multichip package comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>providing a plurality of memory devices, each memory device having an internal supply voltage generator connected to an internal supply voltage terminal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>connecting the internal supply voltage terminals of each memory device together within the multichip package,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said internal supply voltage generator further includes a regulator connected to a regulator output terminal, a regulator input terminal, and a regulator enable terminal, comprising the further step of connecting the regulator enable terminal of said first memory device within the multichip package to a first voltage for enabling said regulator in said first device, and connecting the regulator enable terminals of a second memory device within the multichip package to a second voltage for disabling the regulator in the second device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method for constructing a multichip package as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, comprising the further step of connecting the regulator output terminal of the first memory device to the regulator input terminal of the second memory device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. An integrated circuit die with an internal power supply adapted for sharing said internal power supply with at least one other integrated circuit die in a common package, the adaption comprising a first external connection to the internal power supply.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The integrated circuit die with an internal power supply as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein said first external connection is selected from the group of wire bond pads and TSV bumps.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. An integrated circuit device with an internal power supply adapted for sharing said internal power supply with at least one other integrated circuit device in a common package, the adaption comprising a first external connection to the internal power supply,
<claim-text>further comprising a second connection to said internal power supply having a different potential than said first connection.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. An integrated circuit device with an internal power supply adapted for sharing said internal power supply with at least one other integrated circuit device in a common package, the adaption comprising a first external connection to the internal power supply, further comprising:
<claim-text>a regulator in said power supply; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second connection to said internal power supply for disabling the regulator in another similar integrated circuit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text>25. A system comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of memory dies in a multichip package, each memory die comprising an internal supply voltage generator connected to an internal supply voltage terminal, wherein said internal supply voltage terminals of each memory die are connected together within the multichip package.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text>26. The system as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00023">claim 23</claim-ref>, wherein said memory dies are DRAM dies.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text>27. The system as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00024">claim 24</claim-ref>, wherein said internal supply voltage generator is a wordline supply voltage generator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text>28. The system as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00024">claim 24</claim-ref>, wherein said internal supply voltage generator is a substrate bias supply voltage generator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029" num="00029">
<claim-text>29. The system as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00024">claim 24</claim-ref>, wherein said memory dies are flash memory dies.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030" num="00030">
<claim-text>30. The system as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00027">claim 27</claim-ref>, wherein said flash dies are NAND flash dies.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031" num="00031">
<claim-text>31. The system as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00028">claim 28</claim-ref>, wherein said internal supply voltage generator is a page program supply voltage generator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032" num="00032">
<claim-text>32. The system as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00028">claim 28</claim-ref>, wherein said internal supply voltage generator is a block erase supply voltage generator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033" num="00033">
<claim-text>33. A system comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of memory devices in a multichip package, each memory device further comprising an internal supply voltage generator connected to an internal supply voltage terminal, wherein said internal supply voltage terminals of each memory device are connected together within the multichip package;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said internal supply voltage generator further comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a regulator connected to a regulator output terminal, a regulator input terminal, and a regulator enable terminal, wherein said regulator enable terminal of said first memory device is connected within the multichip package to a first voltage for enabling said regulator in said first device, and said regulator enable terminal of a second memory device is connected within the multichip package to a second voltage for disabling said regulator in the second device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034" num="00034">
<claim-text>34. The system as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00033">claim 33</claim-ref>, wherein said regulator output terminal of the first memory device is connected to said regulator input terminal of the second memory device. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
