<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625372-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625372</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12643520</doc-number>
<date>20091221</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>IN</country>
<doc-number>2935/DEL/2008</doc-number>
<date>20081224</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>173</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>11</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>365205</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Noise tolerant sense circuit</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7072235</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Casper et al.</name>
<date>20060700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>365204</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7701785</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Sanjeevarao et al.</name>
<date>20100400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36518909</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0198666</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Nygren</name>
<date>20080800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36518524</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0003107</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Riho et al.</name>
<date>20090100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>365203</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>5</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>365205</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20100157708</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20100624</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kumar</last-name>
<first-name>Ashish</first-name>
<address>
<city>Greater Noida</city>
<country>IN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>IN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Patel</last-name>
<first-name>Manish Umedlal</first-name>
<address>
<city>Greater Noida</city>
<country>IN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>IN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kumar</last-name>
<first-name>Ashish</first-name>
<address>
<city>Greater Noida</city>
<country>IN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Patel</last-name>
<first-name>Manish Umedlal</first-name>
<address>
<city>Greater Noida</city>
<country>IN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hogan Lovells US LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>STMicroelectronics International N.V.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Amsterdam</city>
<country>NL</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Tran</last-name>
<first-name>Anthan</first-name>
<department>2827</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A device and a method for a sense circuit have been disclosed. In an implementation, the sense circuit includes a sense amplifier and at least one decoupling device. The decoupling device is coupled to the sense amplifier through at least one reference line. The sense amplifier reads a data value and the decoupling device decouples the sense amplifier from a power supply during a read operation.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="182.46mm" wi="251.04mm" file="US08625372-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="256.37mm" wi="200.66mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625372-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="254.68mm" wi="187.11mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625372-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="257.30mm" wi="187.79mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625372-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="231.99mm" wi="193.04mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625372-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present application claims priority of Indian Patent Application No. 2935/DEL/2008 filed Dec. 24, 2008, which is incorporated herein in its entirety by this reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The subject matter described herein, in general, relates to a sense circuit for a memory and, in particular, relates to a noise tolerant sense circuit.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">RELEVANT BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Memory, for example, static random access memory (SRAM) or read only memory (ROM), includes a number of memory cells. A memory cell is coupled to a word line and to one or more bit lines and can store one bit of data. The bit lines coupled to the memory cells are called primary bit lines. The primary bit lines are coupled to pass transistors and undergo various levels of multiplexing to provide multiplexed bit lines, called secondary bit lines.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Generally, the multiplexed or secondary bit lines are coupled to two sensing nodes of a sense amplifier such as a single-ended sense amplifier and a double-ended sense amplifier. The sense amplifier can be of different types: a balanced sense amplifier and an unbalanced sense amplifier. In case of an unbalanced, single-ended sense amplifier, for example, one sensing node is coupled to a multiplexed bit line, while the other node is directly coupled to a power supply. The sense amplifier determines the difference in voltages on these sensing nodes to read a value of data stored in a memory cell.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In a typical read operation, a particular primary bit line is selected by activating a coupled pass transistor, which is supplied with the power supply. The power supply may get coupled to a multiplexed bit line corresponding to the primary bit line due to the inherent coupling between the pass transistor and the multiplexed bit line. Since such a power-supply coupled bit line, i.e., the multiplexed bit line, and the power supply are coupled to the two sensing nodes of a single-ended sense amplifier, any noise or fluctuation in the power supply can get coupled to these sensing nodes. As a result, an error may get introduced in an output of the single-ended sense amplifier.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">A noise or fluctuation in the power supply may occur due to a variety of reasons, for example, due to charging and discharging of components including capacitors and transistors during read and write operations of the memory. To prevent these fluctuations, various methods have been implemented including increasing noise margins of the sense amplifiers, coupling a large capacitor to a power mesh, etc. However, these methods slow down the operation of the sense amplifiers and also impose an additional area penalty, which can become more pronounced for a large number of word lines in a memory.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">This summary is provided to introduce concepts related to a noise tolerant sense circuit, which are further described below in the detailed description. This summary is not intended to identify essential features of the claimed subject matter, nor is it intended for use in determining the scope of the claimed subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In an implementation, a noise tolerant sense circuit includes a sense amplifier and at least one decoupling device. The decoupling device is coupled to the sense amplifier through at least one reference line. The sense amplifier reads a data value and the decoupling device decouples the sense amplifier from a power supply during a read operation.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The detailed description is described with reference to the accompanying figures. In the figures, the left-most digit(s) of a reference number identifies the figure in which the reference number first appears. The same numbers are used throughout the drawings to reference like features and components.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a typical single-ended sense circuit for a memory.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates an exemplary noise tolerant sense circuit for a memory, according to one embodiment of the present subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates an exemplary block diagram of a memory chip implementing the exemplary noise tolerant sense circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, according to one embodiment of the present subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates an exemplary simulation result for the exemplary noise tolerant sense circuit, according to one embodiment of the present subject matter.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">A noise tolerant single-ended sense circuit, hereinafter referred to as the noise tolerant sense circuit, can be implemented in a memory such as read only memory (ROM), static random access memory (SRAM), and dynamic random access memory (DRAM). Devices that can implement the memory having the noise tolerant sense circuit include, but are not limited to, set-top boxes, computing devices, televisions, mobile phones, laptops, personal digital assistants (PDAs), and so on. These devices can be employed in a variety of applications, such as streaming, conferencing, data processing, and surveillance applications.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The noise tolerant sense circuit can be used to prevent an unreliable read operation in the memory due to the noise in the power supply and without putting an additional space constraint on a memory chip. Additionally, there is no or minimal effective increase in power consumption due to the noise tolerant sense circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a typical single-ended sense circuit <b>100</b> for a memory. The single-ended sense circuit <b>100</b> includes a first set of primary bit lines <b>102</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>102</b>-<b>2</b>, . . . , <b>102</b>-N, collectively referred to as primary bit lines <b>102</b>; and a second set of primary bit lines <b>104</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>104</b>-<b>2</b>, . . . , <b>104</b>-N, collectively referred to as primary bit lines <b>104</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The single-ended sense circuit <b>100</b> also includes a first set of pass transistors and a second set of pass transistors. The first set of pass transistors are implemented using p-channel MOSFETs <b>106</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>106</b>-<b>2</b>, . . . , <b>106</b>-N, hereinafter collectively referred to as pMOSs <b>106</b>. Drains of the pMOSs <b>106</b> are coupled to the primary bit lines <b>102</b>. Similarly, the second set of pass transistors are implemented using pMOSs <b>108</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>108</b>-<b>2</b>, . . . , <b>108</b>-N, hereinafter collectively referred to as pMOSs <b>108</b>. Drains of the pMOSs <b>108</b> are coupled to the primary bit lines <b>104</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The sources of the pMOSs <b>106</b> and <b>108</b> can be multiplexed to provide corresponding secondary bit lines <b>110</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>110</b>-<b>2</b>, collectively referred to as secondary bit lines <b>110</b>. The secondary bit line <b>110</b>-<b>1</b> is coupled to a source of one of the pMOS <b>106</b>, for example, the pMOS <b>106</b>-<b>1</b>. Due to an inherent capacitive coupling between the gate and the source of a typical pMOS. In the present case, a parasitic capacitance C<sub>GS1 </sub><b>112</b> is induced between gate of the pMOS <b>106</b>-<b>1</b> and the secondary bit line <b>110</b>-<b>1</b>. Similarly, a parasitic capacitance C<sub>GS2 </sub><b>114</b> is induced between the gate of the pMOS <b>108</b>-<b>1</b> and the secondary bit line <b>110</b>-<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The single-ended sense circuit <b>100</b> also includes a third set of pass transistors implemented using pMOSs <b>116</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>116</b>-<b>2</b> and pre-charge devices realized using pMOSs <b>118</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>118</b>-<b>2</b>, collectively referred to as pMOSs <b>118</b>. The secondary bit line <b>110</b>-<b>1</b> is coupled to a drain of the pMOS <b>116</b>-<b>1</b> and a source of the pMOS <b>118</b>-<b>1</b>, while the secondary bit line <b>110</b>-<b>2</b> is coupled to a drain of the pMOS <b>116</b>-<b>2</b> and a source of the pMOS <b>118</b>-<b>2</b>. Sources of the pMOSs <b>116</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>116</b>-<b>2</b> are multiplexed to provide a tertiary bit line <b>120</b>, hereinafter referred to as bit line <b>120</b>. Further, the pMOSs <b>118</b> are supplied with control signals <b>121</b>, such as pre-charge signals, at their gates for operation.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The single-ended sense circuit <b>100</b> further includes a single-ended sense amplifier <b>122</b>, hereinafter referred to as sense amplifier <b>122</b>; sense amplifier pass transistors implemented using pMOSs <b>124</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>124</b>-<b>2</b>; and an n-channel MOSFET <b>126</b>, hereinafter referred to as nMOS <b>126</b>. The sense amplifier <b>122</b> is similar to a latch circuit and can be realized using two cross-coupled complementary metal oxide semiconductor (CMOS) inverters.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">A first CMOS inverter is implemented using a pMOS <b>128</b>-<b>1</b> and an nMOS <b>130</b>-<b>1</b> and a second CMOS inverter is implemented using a pMOS <b>128</b>-<b>2</b> and an nMOS <b>130</b>-<b>2</b>. Drains of the pMOSs <b>128</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>128</b>-<b>2</b> are coupled to each other and to a supply voltage Vs <b>131</b>. Drains of the nMOSs <b>130</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>130</b>-<b>2</b> are also coupled to each other but are grounded via the nMOS <b>126</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Sources of the pMOS <b>128</b>-<b>2</b> and the nMOS <b>130</b>-<b>2</b> are coupled to each other at a first sensing node <b>132</b>, hereinafter referred to as sense amplifier false (SAF) node <b>132</b>. The SAF node <b>132</b> is further coupled to a source of the pMOS <b>124</b>-<b>2</b> and to gates of the pMOS <b>128</b>-<b>1</b> and the nMOS <b>130</b>-<b>1</b> at a node <b>134</b>, hereinafter referred to as first input node <b>134</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Similarly, sources of the pMOS <b>128</b>-<b>1</b> and the nMOS <b>130</b>-<b>1</b> are coupled to each other at a second sensing node <b>136</b>, hereinafter referred to as sense amplifier true (SAT) node <b>136</b>. The SAT node <b>136</b> is coupled to the bit line <b>120</b> through the pMOS <b>124</b>-<b>1</b>. In particular, the SAT node <b>136</b> is coupled to a source of the pMOS <b>124</b>-<b>1</b> and a drain of the pMOS <b>124</b>-<b>1</b> is coupled to the bit line <b>120</b>. The SAT node <b>136</b> is also coupled to gates of the pMOS <b>128</b>-<b>2</b> and the nMOS <b>130</b>-<b>2</b> at a node <b>138</b>, hereinafter referred to as a second input node <b>138</b>. It is to be noted that the sense amplifier <b>122</b> is an unbalanced sense amplifier in which the size of the nMOS <b>130</b>-<b>2</b> is greater than that of the nMOS <b>130</b>-<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Further, gates of the pMOSs <b>124</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>124</b>-<b>2</b>, and the nMOS <b>126</b> are coupled to a control signal <b>140</b>, while a power supply <b>142</b>, hereinafter referred to as VDD <b>142</b>, is applied at drains of the pMOSs <b>118</b> and <b>124</b>-<b>2</b>. The VDD <b>142</b>, when at the drain of the pMOS <b>124</b>-<b>2</b>, acts as a reference voltage for a voltage on the bit line <b>120</b>. In normal state, the VDD <b>142</b> is also applied at gates of the pMOSs <b>106</b>, <b>108</b>, <b>116</b>-<b>1</b>, and <b>116</b>-<b>2</b> through outputs of the respective multiplexer drivers (not shown in the figure).</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In operation, for example, in a read &#x2018;1&#x2019; case, when the control signal <b>140</b> having a low voltage is applied at the gates of the pMOSs <b>124</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>124</b>-<b>2</b> and the nMOS <b>126</b>, the pMOSs <b>124</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>124</b>-<b>2</b> are activated and the nMOS <b>126</b> is deactivated. Accordingly, the bit line <b>120</b> discharges to provide a low voltage on the SAT node <b>136</b> through the pMOS <b>124</b>-<b>1</b>. The phase during which the bit line <b>120</b> discharges is called discharge phase.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">It is to be noted that the read &#x2018;1&#x2019; case refers to an instance when a voltage level higher than the pre-charge voltage is available on a memory cell. This high voltage is replicated on an associated bit line and corresponds to data at logic level &#x2018;1&#x2019;. Similarly, a read &#x2018;0&#x2019; case refers to an instance when the data stored in the memory cell is at low voltage or logic level zero. As a result, the bit line remains at the pre-charge voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Simultaneous to the appearance of the low voltage at the SAT node <b>136</b> in the read &#x201c;1&#x201d; case, the VDD <b>142</b> is applied at the SAF node <b>132</b> through the pMOS <b>124</b>-<b>2</b>. Subsequently, during an evaluation phase, the control signal <b>140</b> having a high voltage is applied at the gates of the pMOSs <b>124</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>124</b>-<b>2</b> and the nMOS <b>126</b> so that the pMOSs <b>124</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>124</b>-<b>2</b> are deactivated and the nMOS <b>126</b> is activated. The evaluation phase refers to a time duration in which the sense amplifier <b>122</b> performs the read operation.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The activated nMOS <b>126</b> further activates the sense amplifier <b>122</b> to read data value in the memory cell. The sense amplifier <b>122</b> senses a differential voltage, which should be constant during the discharge and the evaluation phases, between the SAT node <b>136</b> and the SAF <b>132</b> node. The discharge phase and the evaluation phase together constitute a read operation performed by the sense amplifier <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">During such a read or sense operation, inductive and capacitive reactance (LCR) oscillations and noise fluctuations may get coupled to the VDD <b>142</b> and can cause an unwanted change in the voltage of the VDD <b>142</b> applied at the SAF node <b>132</b>. Consequently, the voltage at the SAT node <b>136</b> may also start to fluctuate on account of the inherent coupling between the SAT node <b>136</b> and the SAF node <b>132</b>. As a result, the sense amplifier <b>122</b> may sense an erratic differential voltage across the SAT node <b>136</b> and the SAF node <b>132</b>. This erratic differential voltage could interfere with the reliable read or sense operation of the sense amplifier <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Moreover, as the VDD <b>142</b> is applied to the pMOSs <b>106</b> and <b>108</b> at their respective gates through CMOS multiplexer drivers, the disturbance in the VDD <b>142</b> may also get introduced in the secondary bit lines <b>110</b> due to the parasitic capacitances C<sub>GS1 </sub><b>112</b> and C<sub>GS2 </sub><b>114</b>. From the secondary bit lines <b>110</b>, the disturbance may get forwarded to the SAT node <b>136</b> through the bit line <b>120</b>. This may cause an unreliable differential voltage between the SAT node <b>136</b> and the SAF node <b>132</b>. In this way, the oscillations or fluctuations in the VDD <b>142</b> may get transferred to the SAT node <b>136</b> and the SAF node <b>132</b> and increase susceptibility of the single-ended sense circuit <b>100</b> to failure and unreliability.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates an exemplary noise tolerant sense circuit for a memory, according to one embodiment of the present subject matter. The same numbers, as mentioned in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, are used throughout <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> to reference like features and components. The components include primary bit lines <b>102</b> and <b>104</b>, secondary bit lines <b>110</b>, tertiary bit line <b>120</b>, pass transistors <b>106</b>, <b>108</b>, <b>116</b>, <b>124</b>, and <b>126</b>, pre-charge devices <b>118</b>, and sense amplifier <b>122</b> having the SAT node <b>136</b> and the SAF node <b>132</b>. The components individually operate in a manner as described in the description of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. In an implementation, the sense amplifier <b>122</b> is an unbalanced sense amplifier in which the size of the nMOS <b>130</b>-<b>2</b> is greater than that of the nMOS <b>130</b>-<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In the embodiment, the noise tolerant sense circuit <b>200</b> further includes a first reference line <b>202</b>, a second reference line <b>204</b>, a first decoupling device, a second decoupling device, a first sampling device, and a second sampling device. The first decoupling device can be implemented using a pMOS <b>206</b>, while the second decoupling device can be realized with the help of a pMOS <b>208</b>. The first sampling device can be implemented using a pMOS <b>210</b>, while the second sampling device can be realized with the help of a pMOS <b>212</b>. The first reference line <b>202</b> can be coupled to sources of the pMOSs <b>206</b> and <b>210</b> and the drain of the pMOS <b>124</b>-<b>2</b>. The second reference line <b>204</b> can be coupled to sources of the pMOSs <b>208</b> and <b>212</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The noise tolerant sense amplifier <b>200</b> further includes a first set of complementary metal oxide semiconductor (CMOS) multiplexer drivers in which each CMOS multiplexer driver, for example, a CMOS inverter circuit <b>214</b>, provides an output that is applied at the corresponding gates of the pMOSs <b>106</b> and <b>108</b>. In an implementation, the CMOS inverter circuit <b>214</b>, realized with the help of a pMOS <b>216</b> and an nMOS <b>218</b>, can provide an output signal <b>220</b> as input to the drain of the pMOS <b>106</b>-<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The first set of CMOS multiplexer drivers are coupled to the second reference line <b>204</b> and receive input signals from a first column decoder (not shown in the figure) of the memory. In said implementation, the CMOS inverter circuit <b>214</b> is coupled to the second reference line <b>204</b> and receives an input signal <b>222</b> from the first column decoder. The power supply <b>142</b>, hereinafter referred to as VDD <b>142</b>, is applied at the drains of the pMOSs <b>118</b>, <b>206</b>, <b>208</b>, <b>212</b>, and <b>210</b>. The supply voltage Vs <b>131</b> is applied to the sense amplifier <b>122</b> as described in the description of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Similarly, a second set of multiplexer drivers (not shown in the figure) can provide input signals to the gates of the pMOSs <b>116</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>116</b>-<b>2</b>. The second set of multiplexer drivers can be provided with input signals from a second column decoder (not shown in the figure). However, these multiplexer drivers are not coupled to the second reference line <b>204</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Generally, a clock generation circuitry (not shown in the figure) provides two alternate clock signals: PCH_SEN_ON signal and PCH_SEN_OFF signal. The rising edge of the PCH_SEN_ON signal refers to a pre-charge ON signal and the falling edge of the PCH_SEN_ON signal corresponds to a sense ON signal. Similarly, the rising edge of the PCH_SEN_OFF signal refers to a pre-charge OFF signal and the falling edge of the PCH_SEN_OFF corresponds to the sense OFF signal. The pre-charge ON signal and the pre-charge OFF signal, collectively referred to as pre-charge signals <b>224</b>, are applied to the pMOSs <b>118</b>. The sense ON signal and the sense OFF signal, collectively referred to as sense signals <b>226</b>, are applied to the pMOSs <b>124</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>124</b>-<b>2</b>, collectively referred to as pMOSs <b>124</b>, and to the nMOS <b>126</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In an implementation, the order in which these signals are applied is the pre-charge ON signal, the pre-charge OFF signal, the sense ON signal, and the sense OFF signal. The order of application of these signals is controlled by the clock generation circuitry. In an example, the pre-charge ON signal has a low voltage, the pre-charge OFF signal has a high voltage, the sense ON signal has a high voltage, and the sense OFF signal has a low voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In operation, the pre-charge signals <b>224</b>, which include the pre-charge ON signal and the pre-charge OFF signal, are applied at the gates of the pMOSs <b>118</b>, <b>208</b>, and <b>206</b>. The pre-charge ON signal, having a low voltage, activates the pMOSs <b>118</b>, <b>208</b>, and <b>206</b>. Accordingly, the first reference line <b>202</b>, the second reference line <b>204</b>, and the secondary bit lines <b>110</b> are pre-charged. When the sense OFF signal in the sense signals <b>226</b> is applied at the gates of the pMOSs <b>124</b> and nMOS <b>126</b>, the pMOSs <b>124</b> are activated while the nMOS <b>126</b> is deactivated.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">To activate a particular bit line amongst the primary bit lines <b>102</b> and <b>104</b>, a multiplexer driver corresponding to the particular bit line is activated. For example, in order to activate the primary bit line <b>102</b>-<b>1</b>, the CMOS inverter circuit <b>214</b> is activated based on an input signal from the first column decoder, such as the input signal <b>222</b>, and the VDD <b>142</b> from the second reference line <b>204</b>. Simultaneously, the second set of multiplexer drivers can be activated to either activate the pMOS <b>116</b>-<b>1</b> or the pMOS <b>116</b>-<b>2</b> to activate the corresponding secondary bit lines <b>110</b>. Accordingly, the bit line <b>120</b> is activated.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Subsequent to activation of the bit line <b>120</b>, the pre-charging of the first reference line <b>202</b>, the second reference line <b>204</b>, and the secondary bit lines <b>110</b> is stopped by applying a pre-charge OFF signal at the gates of the pMOSs <b>118</b>, <b>208</b>, and <b>206</b>. Depending on the presence of data on the activated bit line, such as the bit line <b>102</b>-<b>1</b>, the bit line <b>120</b> discharges. For example, in the read &#x2018;1&#x2019; case corresponding to the presence of data on the bit line <b>120</b>, the bit line <b>120</b> discharges, otherwise the bit line <b>120</b> remains at voltage of the VDD <b>142</b>. The voltage of the bit line <b>120</b> appears at the SAT node <b>136</b> of the sense amplifier <b>122</b> and the VDD <b>142</b> is applied as a reference voltage at the SAF node <b>132</b> of the sense amplifier <b>122</b> from the first reference line <b>202</b> through the pMOS <b>124</b>-<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">To perform a read operation, the clock generation circuitry generates the sense ON signal having a high voltage at the sense signal <b>226</b>. This signal is applied at the gates of the pMOSs <b>124</b> and the nMOS <b>126</b> so that the pMOSs <b>124</b> are deactivated while the nMOS <b>126</b> is activated. Accordingly, the sense amplifier <b>122</b> is activated to perform the read operation.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Since the pMOS <b>206</b> was deactivated before the read operation by the pre-charge OFF signal applied as the pre-charge signal <b>224</b>, the VDD <b>142</b> is decoupled from the first reference line <b>202</b>. As a result, disturbance or fluctuation in the VDD <b>142</b> gets decoupled from the SAF node <b>132</b> of the sense amplifier <b>122</b>. However, this decoupling of the VDD <b>142</b> from the SAF node <b>132</b> may reduce the capacitance at the SAF node <b>132</b>. Consequently, once a bit line such as bit line <b>120</b> discharges, a coupling between the SAT node <b>136</b> and the SAF node <b>132</b> can decrease the voltage at the SAF node <b>132</b>, which is required to be constant. Such decrease in the voltage at the SAF node <b>132</b> hampers the stable operation of the sense amplifier <b>122</b>. To resolve this issue, a large capacitor can be coupled with the SAF node <b>132</b>. However, addition of a large capacitor cannot be located locally with a single input and output (IO) unit including a sense amplifier, multiplexer drivers, etc., due to space constraints.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In an implementation, the first reference line <b>202</b> is shared across various IO units of the memory to increase capacitance of the first reference line <b>202</b>. This increases the capacitance associated with the SAF node <b>132</b> in the sense amplifier <b>122</b>. The sharing of the first reference line <b>202</b> between various IO units allows the first reference line <b>202</b> to be extended globally over to the control block, which will be discussed later.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In this way, a significant amount of capacitance, without any area penalty, can be contributed to the SAF node <b>132</b> through the first reference line <b>202</b>. Now, a large capacitor (not shown in the figure) can also be coupled to the first reference line <b>202</b> in a control block of the memory chip to increase the capacitance of the first reference line <b>202</b>. The control block has an unused area that can be used to place the large capacitor coupled to the first reference line <b>202</b>. Thus, the overall capacitance of the first reference line <b>202</b> increases and by the virtue of this increase, when the pMOS <b>124</b>-<b>2</b> is active, i.e., during the discharge phase, the capacitance of the SAF node <b>132</b> also increases. Also, the injection of disturbances from the VDD <b>142</b> to the SAF node <b>132</b> is also controlled.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">On the other hand, the SAT node <b>136</b> also suffers from the disturbances in the VDD <b>142</b> on account of coupling of the output of the multiplexer drivers, for example, the CMOS inverter circuit <b>214</b>, with the pMOSs <b>106</b> and <b>108</b>. Generally, the size of the pMOSs <b>106</b> and <b>108</b> is large enough to speed-up their operation. The large size of the pMOSs <b>106</b> and <b>108</b> increases the strength of coupling between the output of multiplexer drivers and the pMOSs <b>106</b> and <b>108</b>. A slight disturbance in the VDD <b>142</b> can get strongly coupled to the bit lines <b>110</b>, thus causing capacitance of the bit lines to build up and go out of an acceptable required range. Such capacitance, which is not within the acceptable range, can lead to improper functioning of the sense amplifier <b>122</b> during the read operation. Otherwise, in the absence of disturbances in the VDD <b>142</b>, since the VDD <b>142</b> applied at the gates of the pMOSs <b>106</b> and <b>108</b> is same as the voltage level of the pre-charged secondary bit lines <b>110</b>, the capacitance of the secondary bit lines <b>110</b> remains within the acceptable range.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In order to perform a reliable read operation, in an implementation, after the second reference line <b>204</b> is pre-charged and the required primary bit line, for example, the primary bit line <b>102</b>-<b>1</b>, has been selected, the pre-charge OFF signal in the pre-charge signals <b>224</b> is applied at the gate of the pMOS <b>208</b> to deactivate the pMOS <b>208</b>. Due to this, the second reference line <b>204</b> and therefore the CMOS multiplexer drivers, for example, CMOS inverter circuit <b>214</b>, get isolated from the VDD <b>142</b>. This blocks the disturbances in the VDD <b>142</b> from transmitting to the bit lines <b>102</b>, <b>104</b>, <b>110</b>, and <b>120</b> and correspondingly to the SAT node <b>136</b> of the sense amplifier <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In this way, the capacitance of the bit lines <b>110</b> can be kept within the acceptable range as now there is no effective coupling between the bit lines <b>110</b> and the VDD <b>142</b> due to isolation of the bit lines <b>110</b> from the VDD <b>142</b>. As explained for the first reference line <b>202</b>, the second reference line <b>204</b> can also be extended globally across various IO units and can be taken to the control block. Also, like the first reference line <b>202</b>, the second reference line <b>204</b> can be coupled to a large capacitor in the control block to increase the capacitance at the SAT node <b>136</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Additionally, the first reference line <b>202</b> and the second reference line <b>204</b> are charged simultaneously with the help of respective pMOSs <b>206</b> and <b>208</b>. The pMOSs <b>206</b> and <b>208</b> ensure that the first reference line <b>202</b> and the second reference line <b>204</b> are pre-charged to the same voltage level. In an implementation, a matched structure of pMOSs similar to the pMOSs <b>208</b> and <b>206</b> can also be coupled to the second reference line <b>204</b> and the first reference line <b>202</b> in the control block to ensure same pre-charge level on both the first reference line <b>202</b> and the second reference line <b>204</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Further, the activated sense amplifier <b>122</b> senses a differential voltage across the SAT node <b>136</b> and the SAF node <b>132</b>. In case there is no differential voltage across the SAT node <b>136</b> and the SAF node <b>132</b>, i.e., in the read &#x2018;0&#x2019; case when both the SAT node <b>136</b> and the SAF node <b>132</b> are at the voltage of VDD <b>142</b>, the SAF node <b>132</b> and the SAT node <b>136</b> are pulled down. The pull-down of the SAF node <b>132</b> is faster than the SAT node <b>136</b> due to greater size of the nMOS <b>130</b>-<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The SAT node <b>136</b> is now at a relatively higher voltage than the SAF node <b>132</b>, which represents that the data available on the bit line <b>120</b> is at logic level zero. On the other hand, in the read &#x2018;1&#x2019; case, the bit line <b>120</b> discharges to conduct a low voltage at the SAT node <b>136</b>. Therefore, the SAT node <b>136</b> is at a lower voltage than a voltage at the SAF node <b>132</b>, which represents that the data available on the bit line is at a logic level one. Further, an output of the sense amplifier <b>122</b> is sent to an output buffer (not shown in the figure) of the memory. Subsequently, the sense OFF signal of the sense signals <b>226</b> is applied at the gate of the nMOS <b>126</b> to deactivate the sense amplifier <b>122</b> to end a read operation.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The time period after the completion of the read operation, i.e., after the application of the sense OFF signal, and before the start of the next pre-charging cycle, i.e., before the generation of the next pre-charge ON signal, is called as idle time. At the end of the idle time, the first reference line <b>202</b> and the second reference line <b>204</b> may lose their charge and may not get charged up to a required voltage level during the next pre-charging cycle. This may lead to an unreliable read operation.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In an implementation, to ensure that the first reference line <b>202</b> and the second reference line <b>204</b> remain coupled to the VDD <b>142</b> during a time interval other than during the discharge phase and evaluation phase, the pMOSs <b>210</b> and <b>212</b> can be coupled to the first reference line <b>202</b> and the second reference line <b>204</b>, respectively. The pMOSs <b>212</b> and <b>210</b> are operated by a delayed sense OFF signal <b>230</b>, also referred to as OFF_bb signal <b>230</b>, applied at the gates of the pMOSs <b>212</b> and <b>210</b>. The OFF_bb signal <b>230</b> is derived from the PCH_SEN_OFF signal provided by the clock generation circuitry.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Further, the pMOSs <b>212</b> and <b>210</b> are deactivated by the pre-charge OFF signal in the PCH_SEN_OFF signal. In this way, the first reference line <b>202</b> and the second reference line <b>204</b> can be prevented against discharging to an unacceptable voltage level during the idle time by using the respective pMOSs <b>210</b> and <b>212</b>. It is to be noted that a supply voltage, for example, supply voltage Vs <b>131</b> if fluctuating in nature and applied to sense amplifier will not interfere with the read operation of the sense amplifier, provided the sense amplifier, for example, sense amplifier <b>122</b>, is symmetrical in nature. When a supply voltage such as supply voltage Vs <b>131</b> is applied to both the sensing nodes such as the SAT node <b>136</b> and the SAF node <b>132</b> of the sense amplifier, then the sense amplifier is said to be symmetrical in nature.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates an exemplary block diagram of a memory chip <b>300</b> implementing the exemplary noise tolerant sense circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, according to one embodiment of the present subject matter. In an implementation, the memory chip <b>300</b> includes core arrays <b>302</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>302</b>-<b>2</b>, a dummy decoder <b>304</b>, a bank decoder <b>306</b>, a decoder <b>308</b>, and input-output units <b>310</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>310</b>-<b>2</b>. The core arrays <b>302</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>302</b>-<b>2</b>, collectively referred to as core arrays <b>302</b>, include memory cells and primary bit lines, for example, the primary bit lines <b>102</b> and <b>104</b>. The dummy decoder <b>304</b>, the bank decoder <b>306</b>, and the decoder <b>308</b> are used to access the memory cells in a way known in the art. The input-output units <b>310</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>310</b>-<b>2</b> can be collectively referred to as input-output units <b>310</b> and include various IO lines in addition to other components such as sense amplifiers, multiplexer drivers, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The memory chip <b>300</b> further includes output buffers <b>312</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>312</b>-<b>2</b>, output lines <b>314</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>314</b>-<b>2</b>, the first reference line <b>202</b>, the second reference line <b>204</b>, a control block <b>316</b> including a required pre-decoder control logic, a first capacitor <b>318</b>-<b>1</b> and a second capacitor <b>318</b>-<b>2</b>, collectively referred to as capacitors <b>318</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In the present implementation, to provide sufficient capacitance at the SAF node <b>132</b> during discharge and evaluation phases, the first capacitor or gate loading capacitor <b>318</b>-<b>1</b> can be coupled to the first reference line <b>202</b>. It is to be noted that coupling of such a large capacitor, for example, the first capacitor <b>318</b>-<b>1</b>, to the first reference line <b>202</b> locally with a single IO unit is restricted due to space constraints. Therefore, the first reference line <b>202</b> is extended globally across various IO units and is taken to the control block <b>316</b> where the first capacitor or gate loading capacitor <b>318</b>-<b>1</b> can be coupled to the first reference line <b>202</b>. The placement of the first capacitor <b>318</b>-<b>1</b> in the control block <b>316</b> is possible on account of unused space, typically, available in the control block <b>316</b>. Similarly, the second reference line <b>204</b> can also be extended globally across various IO units and can be taken to the control block <b>316</b> where the second capacitor <b>318</b>-<b>2</b> can be coupled to the second reference line <b>204</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The coupling of the large capacitors, such as the capacitors <b>318</b>, to the first reference line <b>202</b> and the second reference line <b>204</b> such that the capacitors get coupled with an activated gate of a pMOS amongst pMOSs <b>106</b> and <b>108</b>. Such coupling of the capacitors is known as gate loading. The gate loading increases the capacitances on both the first reference line <b>202</b> and the second reference line <b>204</b>. Such an implementation assures charge holding capability of the first reference line <b>202</b> and the second reference line <b>204</b> against leakage and de-coupling of the first reference line <b>202</b> and the second reference line <b>204</b> from the VDD <b>142</b>. Moreover, the first reference line <b>202</b> and the second reference line <b>204</b> are kept separate to prevent transfer of charge between the two due to charge leakage.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates an exemplary simulation result <b>400</b> for the exemplary noise tolerant sense circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, according to one embodiment of the present subject matter. In general, any read operation of a sense amplifier can be divided into three phases, namely a pre-charge phase, a discharge phase, and an evaluation phase. The simulation result <b>400</b> as shown represents a variation in voltage level with respect to time.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">In an implementation, plot <b>402</b> corresponds to a voltage level of the bit line <b>120</b>, the VDD <b>142</b>, the SAT node <b>136</b>, and the SAF node <b>132</b>, whereas plot <b>404</b> shows corresponding voltage levels of the clock signals PCH_SEN_ON and PCH_SEN_OFF signals. The rising edge of the PCH_SEN_ON signal corresponds to the pre-charge ON signal <b>406</b>, and the falling edge of the PCH_SEN_ON signal corresponds to the sense ON signal <b>408</b>. Similarly, the rising edge of the PCH_SEN_OFF signal corresponds to the pre-charge OFF signal <b>410</b>, and the falling edge of the PCH_SEN_OFF signal corresponds to the sense OFF signal <b>412</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">During the pre-charge phase, the pre-charge ON signal <b>406</b> activates the pMOSs <b>118</b>, <b>208</b>, and <b>206</b>. The pre-charge ON signal <b>406</b> thus facilitates pre-charging of the secondary bit lines <b>110</b>, the first reference line <b>202</b>, and the second reference line <b>204</b>. At the end of the pre-charge phase, the pre-charge OFF signal <b>410</b> is applied at the gates of the pMOSs <b>118</b>, <b>208</b>, and <b>206</b>, and this stops pre-charging of the secondary bit lines <b>110</b>, the first reference line <b>202</b>, and the second reference line <b>204</b>. In the plot <b>402</b>, the pre-charging of the secondary bit lines <b>110</b> has been shown by a line <b>414</b>-<b>1</b> and voltage level of the VDD <b>142</b> has been represented by a line <b>416</b>. At the end of the pre-charge phase, the discharge phase begins. The discharge phase lasts for the duration between the pre-charge OFF signal <b>410</b> and the sense ON signal <b>408</b>, depicted in the plot <b>404</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">During the discharge phase, the bit line <b>120</b> is allowed to discharge through the memory cell. In this case, since a &#x2018;0&#x2019; value is being read, the SAF node <b>132</b> is expected to remain at VDD <b>142</b>. However, during the discharge phase, the VDD <b>142</b> coupled to the SAT node <b>136</b> and the SAF node <b>132</b> can experience induced noise, which can be reduced by isolating the SAT node <b>136</b> and the SAF node <b>132</b> of the sense amplifier <b>122</b> from the VDD <b>142</b>. The voltage level of the VDD <b>142</b> has been shown by line <b>418</b> in the plot <b>402</b> during the discharge phase.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Due to effective decoupling through the first and second decoupling devices <b>206</b> and <b>208</b>, the SAT node <b>136</b> and the SAF node <b>132</b> can be kept at a relatively constant voltage level, as represented by line <b>420</b>. The simulation result <b>400</b> clearly shows isolation of the SAT node <b>136</b> and the SAF node <b>132</b> from the fluctuating VDD <b>142</b> such that the SAT node <b>136</b> and the SAF node <b>132</b> are at a relatively constant voltage level, represented by the line <b>420</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">After the discharge phase, the evaluation phase begins. The evaluation phase is the phase between the sense ON signal <b>408</b> and the sense OFF signal <b>412</b> in the plot <b>404</b>. The sense ON signal <b>408</b> activates the nMOS <b>126</b>. Accordingly, the sense amplifier <b>122</b> is activated and depending on the voltage level at the SAT node <b>136</b> and the SAF node <b>132</b>, the sense amplifier <b>122</b> either senses a logic level &#x2018;1&#x2019; or a logic level &#x2018;0&#x2019;. As shown, even during the evaluation phase, the voltages of the bit line <b>120</b> and differential voltages appearing at the SAT node <b>136</b> and the SAF node <b>132</b> are at a relatively constant value.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">In a read &#x2018;0&#x2019; case, during the evaluation phase, the unbalanced nature of the sense amplifier <b>122</b> causes the SAF node <b>132</b> to be pulled down to a lower voltage level <b>422</b>-<b>1</b>, while the SAT node <b>136</b>, though pulled down, is at a relatively higher voltage level <b>422</b>-<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Further, as the sense OFF signal <b>412</b> deactivates the sense amplifier <b>122</b> by turning off the nMOS <b>126</b>, the voltage level at the SAF node <b>132</b> rises and reaches to a voltage level of the VDD <b>142</b>, as represented by line <b>422</b>-<b>3</b>. On the other hand, since the SAT node <b>136</b> is also pulled down by the end of the evaluation phase, a voltage level at the SAT node <b>136</b> is completely pulled down as represented by a line <b>414</b>-<b>2</b> at the end of the evaluation phase. The simulation result <b>400</b> reinforces that effective decoupling of the sense amplifier <b>122</b> from the VDD <b>142</b> through the first reference line <b>202</b> and the second reference line <b>204</b> results in a noise-free read operation.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">Although embodiments for a noise tolerant sense circuit have been described in language specific to structural features and/or methods, it is to be understood that the invention is not necessarily limited to the specific features or methods described. Rather, the specific features and methods are disclosed as exemplary implementations for the noise tolerant sense circuit.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>We claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A device comprising:
<claim-text>a memory cell;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a bit line coupled to the memory cell; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a circuit comprising,
<claim-text>a sense amplifier having a first sensing node and a second sensing node, wherein the second sensing node is coupled to the bit line; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a power supply coupled to the first sensing node through a first reference line, and to activate the bit line through a second reference line, wherein the power supply is decoupled from the first sensing node using a first decoupling device, and from activating the bit line using a second decoupling device during a read operation of the sense amplifier, further wherein the first reference line remains coupled to the first sensing node and the second reference line is used to activating the bit line for a part of the read operation,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second reference line is not a bit line, nor an input/output lines, nor input to the sense amplifier.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first reference line is coupled to a first capacitor in a control block.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second reference line is coupled to a second capacitor in a control block.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of the first reference line and the second reference line is shared between multiple input and output units.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the sense amplifier is a single-ended sense amplifier. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
