<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626004-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626004</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13110419</doc-number>
<date>20110518</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-238002</doc-number>
<date>20101022</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>295</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>399 15</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Detecting apparatus and image forming apparatus</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6898381</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Maebashi et al.</name>
<date>20050500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>399 15</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6961526</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Tezuka et al.</name>
<date>20051100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>399 15</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0189447</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ishizuka et al.</name>
<date>20100700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>399 15</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-114498</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20100500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>12</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>399 15</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>399 60</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>399 74</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>9</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>11</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120097872</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120426</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ito</last-name>
<first-name>Masao</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ashigarakami-gun</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Furusawa</last-name>
<first-name>Fumio</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yokohama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ito</last-name>
<first-name>Masao</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ashigarakami-gun</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Furusawa</last-name>
<first-name>Fumio</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yokohama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Sughrue Mion, PLLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Fuji Xerox Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Brase</last-name>
<first-name>Sandra</first-name>
<department>2852</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A detecting apparatus includes: a transmission member that is provided facing a conveying path on which a medium is conveyed and that transmits light from the medium being conveyed on the conveying path; a detecting section that detects the medium or an image on the medium from the light which is transmitted through the transmission member, wherein the light is received by a light-receiving member of the detection section; an opposing member that is provided on an opposite side of the conveying path from the transmission member and has at least a first opposing surface that faces the transmission member; and a guide member provided at a downstream side of the opposing member in the conveying direction, and guides the medium downstream in the conveying path. The opposing surface is closer to the detecting section at a downstream side than at an upstream side thereof in the conveying direction.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="172.55mm" wi="265.85mm" file="US08626004-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="267.72mm" wi="181.44mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626004-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="265.01mm" wi="186.86mm" file="US08626004-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="276.35mm" wi="183.22mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626004-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="262.97mm" wi="118.19mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626004-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="239.86mm" wi="180.09mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626004-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="252.05mm" wi="109.39mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626004-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="235.12mm" wi="180.76mm" file="US08626004-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="257.56mm" wi="167.81mm" file="US08626004-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="124.38mm" wi="159.34mm" file="US08626004-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is based on and claims priority under 35 USC 119 from Japanese Patent Application No. 2010-238002 filed on Oct. 22, 2010.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">Technical Field</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a detecting apparatus and an image forming apparatus.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">A detecting apparatus according to a first aspect of the present invention includes: a transmission member that is provided facing a conveying path on which a medium is conveyed and that transmits light from the medium being conveyed on the conveying path; a detecting section that detects the medium or an image on the medium from the light which is transmitted through the transmission member, wherein the light is received by a light-receiving member of the detection section; an opposing member that is provided on an opposite side of the conveying path from the transmission member and has at least a first opposing surface that faces the transmission member; and a guide member that is provided at a downstream side of the opposing member in the conveying direction, and guides the medium downstream in the conveying path, wherein the opposing surface is closer to the detecting section at a downstream side than at an upstream side thereof in the conveying direction.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Exemplary embodiments of the present invention will be described in detail based on the following figures, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an overall view of an image forming apparatus concerning the exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic diagram of the image forming unit concerning the exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic diagram of the inline sensor concerning the exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is an explanatory diagram showing the state of sending air into the substrate chamber concerning the exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross-sectional view which magnified the conveying path part of the recording medium in the inline sensor concerning the exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a schematic diagram of the composite test surface concerning the exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</figref> is a cross-sectional view showing a position relationship of a detecting surface and a evacuation surface concerning the exemplary embodiment of the present invention, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</figref> is an exemplary diagram showing the outer shape of the reference roll concerning the exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8B</figref> are explanatory diagrams showing the state where the recording medium P with downward curling is conveyed in the inline sensor concerning the exemplary embodiment of the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is an explanatory diagram showing the state where the recording medium P with upward curling is conveyed in the inline sensor concerning the exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">An example of a detecting apparatus and an image forming apparatus in an exemplary embodiment of the present invention will be described.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">(Overall Configuration)</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows the image forming apparatus <b>10</b>. The image forming apparatus <b>10</b> is for forming a color image or a monochrome image and has a first processing unit <b>10</b>A which is located on the left-hand side in anterior view and a second processing unit <b>10</b>B which is located on the right-hand side and can be attached to and detached from the first processing unit <b>10</b>A. Casings of the first processing unit <b>10</b>A and the second processing unit <b>10</b>B are formed by plural frame members. Moreover, in the following description, a length direction of the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> (sub-scanning direction (slow scanning direction)), which is a conveying direction of a recording medium P, which is an example of a medium) is described as the X direction, a height direction of the apparatus is described as the Y direction and a depth direction of the apparatus (main-scanning direction (fast scanning direction)) is described as the Z direction.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Toner cartridges <b>14</b>V, <b>14</b>W, <b>14</b>Y, <b>14</b>M, <b>14</b>C, <b>14</b>K which respectively house each of toners of a first custom color (V), a second custom color (W), yellow (Y), magenta (M), cyan (C) and black (K) are provided so as to be exchangeable at an upper part of the first processing unit <b>10</b>A along a horizontal direction.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Here, the first custom color and the second custom color are arbitrarily selected from the colors (which include transparent color) other than yellow, magenta, cyan and black. Moreover, in the following description, in a case of distinguishing the first custom color (V), the second custom color (W), yellow (Y), magenta (M), cyan (C) and black (K), it will be explained with any one of alphabets V, W, Y, M, C, K added after the numerical references and, in a case of not distinguishing the first custom color (V), the second custom color (W), yellow (Y), magenta (M), cyan (C) and black (K), the alphabets V, W, Y, M, C, K will be omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Further, at a lower side of the toner cartridges <b>14</b>, image forming units <b>16</b> as an example of six image forming units corresponding to the toners of each of colors are provided along the X direction so as to correspond with each of toner cartridges <b>14</b>. An exposure device <b>40</b> which is provided for each image forming unit <b>16</b> is configured such that it receives image data which is applied an image processing by an image signal processing unit <b>13</b> provided at an upper part of the second processing unit <b>10</b>B and, illuminates an optical beam L modulated according to the image data to a photoreceptor <b>18</b> (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) which will be described below.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, each image forming unit <b>16</b> has a photoreceptor <b>18</b> rotary driven in a direction of an arrow R (clockwise direction as shown). On each photoreceptor <b>18</b>, an electrostatic latent image is formed by illuminating the optical beam L from each exposure device <b>40</b>. Here, the exposure device <b>40</b> scans with the light emitted from a light source (not shown) using a polygon mirror <b>43</b>, and illuminates with the optical beam L to outer circumference surface of the photoreceptor <b>18</b> by plural optical components <b>45</b> which respectively include a f&#x3b8; lens and a reflecting mirror, thus performs exposures.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Around each photoreceptor <b>18</b>, a scorotron charging device <b>20</b> is provided, which is corona discharge type (contactless charge type) and for charging the photoreceptor <b>18</b>, a developing device <b>22</b> is provided, which develops the electrostatic latent image formed on the photoreceptor <b>18</b> by the exposure device <b>40</b> using a developer (toner), a blade <b>24</b> is provided, as a removal member, which removes the developer remaining on the photoreceptor <b>18</b> after a primarily transfer, and an erasing apparatus <b>26</b> is provided, which illuminates with the light to the photoreceptor <b>18</b> after being removed the developer by the blade <b>24</b> to perform erasing. The scorotron charging device <b>20</b>, the developing device <b>22</b>, the blade <b>24</b> and the erasing apparatus <b>26</b> are located in this order from the upstream side of a rotation direction of the photoreceptor <b>18</b> to the downstream side thereof, facing the surface of the photoreceptor <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The developing device <b>22</b> is configured so as to include a developer housing member <b>22</b>A which houses the developer G including the toner and, a developing roll <b>22</b>B which provides the developer G housed in the developer housing member <b>22</b>A to the photoreceptor <b>18</b>. The developer housing member <b>22</b>A connects to the toner cartridge <b>14</b> (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) via a toner providing path (not shown), and the toner is provided from the toner cartridge <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Meanwhile, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a transfer unit <b>32</b> is provided at a lower side of each image forming unit <b>16</b>. The transfer unit <b>32</b> is configured so as to include a circular intermediate transfer belt <b>34</b> of which outer circumference surface contacts with the outer circumference surface of each photoreceptor <b>18</b>, and a primarily transfer roll <b>36</b> as a primarily transfer member for multiply transferring the toner images formed on each of photoreceptors <b>18</b> to the intermediate transfer belt <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The intermediate transfer belt <b>34</b> is wound to a driving roll <b>38</b> which is driven by a motor (not shown), a tension applying roll <b>41</b> which applies tensional force to the intermediate transfer belt <b>34</b>, a opposite roll <b>42</b> which is opposite to the secondary transfer roll <b>62</b> described below, and plural winding rolls <b>44</b>. The intermediate transfer belt <b>34</b> is circularly moved in one direction (counterclockwise direction in the figure) by the driving roll <b>38</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Each primarily transfer roll <b>36</b> is arranged opposite to the photoreceptor <b>18</b> of each image forming unit <b>16</b> corresponding thereto across the intermediate transfer belt <b>34</b>. Moreover, a transferring bias voltage which has polarity opposite to toner polarity is applied to the primarily transfer roll <b>36</b> by a power feeding unit (not shown). This configuration allows the toner image formed on the photoreceptor <b>18</b> to transfer the intermediate transfer belt <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">At the opposite side of the intermediate transfer belt <b>34</b> from the driving roll <b>38</b>, a removal device <b>46</b> is provided, which causes the blade to contact the outer circumferential surface of the intermediate transfer belt <b>34</b> to remove residual toner and paper dust or the like from the intermediate transfer belt <b>34</b>. Moreover, at a lower part of the transfer unit <b>32</b>, two recording medium housing units <b>48</b> are provided, which respectively house recording media such as paper along the horizontal direction.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Each recording medium housing unit <b>48</b> can be drawn out toward a front side in the Z direction from the first processing unit <b>10</b>A. Moreover, at an upper part of one end side (right side in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of each recording medium housing unit <b>48</b>, a feed roll is provided <b>52</b> which sends the recording medium P from the respective recording medium housing units <b>48</b> to a conveying path <b>60</b>, which is an example of a conveying path. Further, a bottom plate <b>50</b> is provided on which the recording medium P is placed in each recording medium housing unit <b>48</b>. The bottom plate <b>50</b> is lowered in accordance with an instruction from a controlling device (not shown) when the recording medium housing unit <b>48</b> is drawn from the first processing unit <b>10</b>A. The lowering of the bottom plate <b>50</b> forms a space for a user to refill the recording medium P in the recording medium housing unit <b>48</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">When the recording medium housing unit <b>48</b> which has been drawn from the first processing unit <b>10</b>A is attached to the first processing unit <b>10</b>A, the bottom plate <b>50</b> rises in accordance with an instruction from the controlling device. Then, due to the bottom plate <b>50</b> rising, the topmost recording medium P placed on the bottom plate <b>50</b> contacts the feed roll <b>52</b>. Moreover, a separating roll <b>56</b> is provided which separates any overlapping recording medium P sent from the recording medium housing unit <b>48</b> into single sheets, at the downstream side of the feed roll <b>52</b> in the a conveying direction of the recording medium (hereinafter, sometimes simply referred to as the downstream side). Plural conveying rolls <b>54</b> are provided at the downstream side of the separating roll <b>56</b>, which convey the recording medium P to the downstream side in the conveying direction.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">A conveying path <b>60</b> extends toward a transferring position T between the secondary transfer roll <b>62</b> and the opposite roll <b>42</b> such that the recording medium P sent from the recording medium housing unit <b>48</b> is turned to the left side in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> at a first turning part <b>60</b>A, further is turned to the right side in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> at a second turning part <b>60</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The secondary transfer roll <b>62</b> is configured such that a transferring bias voltage which has polarity opposite to toner polarity is applied thereto by a power feeding portion (not shown). It is configured such that toner images of each of colors multiply-transferred on the intermediate transfer belt <b>34</b> are secondary transferred, by the secondary transfer roll <b>62</b>, to the recording medium P conveyed along the conveying path <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Moreover, an auxiliary path <b>66</b> is provided, which extends from the left side surface of the first processing unit <b>10</b>A so as to join the second turning part <b>60</b>B of the conveying path <b>60</b>. The recording medium P sent from another recording medium housing unit (not shown) adjacently located on a left side of the first processing unit <b>10</b>A enter into the conveying path <b>60</b> through the auxiliary path <b>66</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Meanwhile, at the downstream side of the transferring position T on the conveying path <b>60</b> in the first processing unit <b>10</b>A, plural conveying belts <b>70</b> are provided, as an example of a conveying section, which conveys the recording medium P transferred the toner images thereon to the second processing unit <b>10</b>B. Moreover, a conveying belt <b>80</b> is provided, as an example of a conveying section, which conveys the recording medium P conveyed by the conveying belts <b>70</b> to the downstream side in the second processing unit <b>10</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Each of the plurality of conveying belts <b>70</b> and the conveying belt <b>80</b> are circularly formed and wound on a pair of winding rolls <b>72</b>. The pair of winding rolls <b>72</b> are respectively arranged at the upstream side and the downstream side of the recording medium P in the conveying direction. Due to one of the winding rolls <b>72</b> being rotary driven, the conveying belts <b>70</b> and the conveying belt <b>80</b> are circularly moved in one direction (clockwise direction in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). At the downstream side of the conveying belt <b>80</b>, a fixing unit <b>82</b> is provided which fixes the toner images transferred (image-formed) to the surface of the recording medium P to the recording medium P by heat and pressure.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The fixing unit <b>82</b> has a fixing belt <b>84</b> which is arranged at an upper side of the conveying path <b>60</b> (image forming surface side of the recording medium P), and a pressure roll <b>88</b> which is arranged so as to contact the fixing belt <b>84</b> from underneath sandwiching the conveying path <b>60</b>. A fixing part N is formed for fixing the toner image to the recording medium P by pressing and heating between the fixing belt <b>84</b> and the pressure roll <b>88</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The fixing belt <b>84</b> is formed in a circular shape and is wound to a driving roll <b>89</b> and a driven roll <b>90</b> which are arranged one above the other. The driving roll <b>89</b> is opposed to the pressure roll <b>88</b> from above and, the driven roll <b>90</b> is arranged on the upper side of the driving roll <b>89</b>. Moreover, a heating unit such as a halogen heater is embedded in the driving roll <b>89</b> and the driven roll <b>90</b> respectively. Due to this, the fixing belt <b>84</b> is heated.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">At the downstream side of the fixing unit <b>82</b>, a conveying belt <b>108</b> is provided, as an example of a conveying section, which conveys the recording medium P sent from the fixing unit <b>82</b> to the downstream side. The conveying belt <b>108</b> has a configuration similar to those of the conveying belts <b>70</b>. Moreover, a cooling unit <b>110</b> is provided, which cools down the recording medium P heated by the fixing unit <b>82</b> at the downstream side of the conveying belt <b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The cooling unit <b>110</b> is configured so as to include an absorbing device <b>112</b> which absorbs heat of the recording medium, and a pressing device <b>114</b> which presses the recording medium P to the absorbing device <b>112</b>. The absorbing device <b>112</b> is arranged on one side of the conveying path <b>60</b> (upper side in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>), and the pressing device <b>114</b> is arranged on the other side (lower side in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The absorbing device <b>112</b> has a circular absorbing belt <b>116</b> which is in contact with the recording medium P and absorbs the heat of the recording medium P. The absorbing belt <b>116</b> is wound to a driving roll <b>120</b> which transmits driving force to the absorbing belt <b>116</b> and plural winding rolls <b>118</b>. Moreover, at an inner circumferential side of the absorbing belt <b>116</b>, a heatsink <b>122</b> is provided which is made of an aluminum material and is in surface-contact with the absorbing belt <b>116</b> and releases heat absorbed by the absorbing belt <b>116</b>. Further, at a reverse side of the second processing unit <b>10</b>B (back side of the paper in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>), a fan <b>128</b> is provided for externally discharging hot air generated by the heat release of the heatsink <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The pressing device <b>114</b> has a circular pressing belt <b>130</b> as an example of conveying section which conveys the recording medium P while pressing the recording medium P to the absorbing belt <b>116</b>. The pressing belt <b>130</b> is wound to plural winding rolls <b>132</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Moreover, at the downstream side of the cooling unit <b>110</b> on the conveying path <b>60</b>, a correcting device <b>140</b> is provided, which sandwiches and conveys the recording medium P, and corrects a curvature (curling) of the recording medium P. At the downstream side of the correcting device <b>140</b> on the conveying path <b>60</b>, an inline sensor <b>200</b> is provided, as an example of detecting apparatus, which detects toner density defect, image defect, image position defect of the toner image fixed to the recording medium P and, a position and shape and the like of the recording medium P. The inline sensor <b>200</b> will be described in detains in the followings.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">At the downstream side of the inline sensor <b>200</b> on the conveying path <b>60</b>, a discharging roll <b>198</b> is provided, which discharges the recording medium P on which the image is formed on one side to a discharging unit <b>196</b> attached to a side surface of the second processing unit <b>10</b>B. Meanwhile, it is configured such that, in a case that images are formed both side of the recording medium P, the recording medium P sent from the inline sensor <b>200</b> is conveyed to an inversion path <b>194</b> provided at the downstream side of the inline sensor <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">On the inversion path <b>194</b>, a branching path <b>194</b>A is provided which branches from the conveying path <b>60</b>, a sheet conveying path <b>194</b>B is provided which conveys the recording medium P conveyed along the branching path <b>194</b>A toward the first processing unit <b>10</b>A side, and an inversion path <b>194</b>C is provided in which the recording medium P conveyed along the sheet conveying path <b>194</b>B is turned over in the opposite direction to perform a switchback conveyance, thereby turning the medium upside-down. Due to this configuration, the recording medium P that switch-back conveyed by the inversion path <b>194</b>C is conveyed toward the first processing unit <b>10</b>A, and enters the conveying path <b>60</b> provided at an upper part of the recording medium housing unit <b>48</b> and is sent to the transfer position T again.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">An image forming process of the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> will be explained in the followings.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, image data processed by the image signal processing unit <b>13</b> are sent to each of the exposure devices <b>40</b>. Then, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, each of the exposure devices <b>40</b> emits each light beam L according to the image data and exposes the outer surface of each photoreceptor <b>18</b> electrically charged by the scorotron charging device <b>20</b>, and thus electrostatic latent images are formed. Furthermore, the electrostatic latent images formed on the photoreceptors <b>18</b> are developed by the developing device <b>22</b>, and then toner images with respective colors of the first custom color (V), the second custom color (W), yellow (Y), magenta (M), cyan (C) and black (K) are formed.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Subsequently, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, toner images of respective colors formed on the photoreceptors <b>18</b> (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) of the image forming units <b>16</b>V, <b>16</b>W, <b>16</b>Y, <b>16</b>M, <b>16</b>C and <b>16</b>K are multiply transferred to the intermediate transfer belt <b>34</b> sequentially, using six primary transfer rolls <b>36</b>V, <b>36</b>W, <b>36</b>Y, <b>36</b>M, <b>36</b>C and <b>36</b>K. Then the toner images of respective colors multiply-transferred to the intermediate transfer belt <b>34</b> are secondary transferred using the secondly transfer roll <b>62</b> onto the recording medium P conveyed from the recording medium housing unit <b>48</b>. Furthermore, the recording medium P transferred the toner images thereon is conveyed by the conveying belt <b>70</b> to the fixing unit <b>82</b> which is equipped inside the second processing unit <b>10</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Subsequently, the toner images of the respective colors on the recording medium P are fixed thereon at the fixing unit <b>82</b> by application of heat and pressure. Then, the recording medium P to which the toner images are fixed is cooled while passing through the cooling unit <b>110</b>, after which the recording medium P is conveyed into the correcting device <b>140</b>, and any curling that has occurred at the recording medium P is corrected. Further, the recording medium P with curling corrected is discharged to the discharging unit <b>196</b> by the discharging roll <b>198</b> after image defects or the like have been detected by the inline sensor <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">On the other hand, when forming images on a non-image surface of the recording medium P on which images have not been formed (double-sided printing), the recording medium P is turned over at the inversion path <b>194</b> after passing through the inline sensor <b>200</b>, and further is sent to the conveying path <b>60</b> provided above the recording medium housing unit <b>48</b>. Thus, toner images are formed on the back side according to the process described above.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In addition, in the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> according to this exemplary embodiment, components for forming images of the first custom color and the second custom color (the image forming units <b>16</b>V and <b>16</b>W, the exposure devices <b>40</b>V and <b>40</b>W, the toner cartridges <b>14</b>V and <b>14</b>W, and the primary transfer rolls <b>36</b>V and <b>36</b>W) are configured such that these components can be attached to and removed from the first processing unit <b>10</b>A as optional units by user's choice. Therefore, the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> may be configured in a form without having units for forming both the first custom color and the second custom color, and also may be configured in a form having only units for forming images of either one of the first custom color and the second custom color.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Next, the inline sensor <b>200</b> will be explained.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">(Fundamental Configuration of the Inline Sensor <b>200</b>)</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the inline sensor <b>200</b> is equipped with an illuminating unit <b>202</b> that emits light to the recording medium P having recorded the images, an imaging unit <b>208</b> having the imaging optical system <b>206</b> forming images on the CCD sensor <b>204</b> as an example of a light-receiving member receiving the light emitted from the illuminating unit <b>202</b> and reflected by the recording medium P, and a setting unit <b>210</b> where various criteria are set for the case that the inline sensor <b>200</b> is in use and for the case of calibration and the like. The CCD sensor <b>204</b> is configured to receive the light reflected by the recording medium P, and to detect images or the recording medium P according to the intensity of the light.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Here, the light from the recording medium P described herein includes the reflected light which has been reflected by the recording medium P and the transmitted light which has transmitted through the recording medium P, and in broader way, it is the light by which information concerning the images formed on the recording medium P, and positions or shapes of the recording medium P can be detected. Besides, the transmission described herein includes that the light passes through an imaging lens or the like, in addition to that the light passes through a window glass or the like. Furthermore, the detection of the recording medium P described herein includes detection of the position and the shape of the recording medium P.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The illuminating unit <b>202</b> is placed on the upper side of the conveying path <b>60</b> of the recording medium P and contains a pair of lamps <b>212</b> emitting the light toward the recording medium P. Each lamp <b>212</b> is a xenon lamp which is longitudinal in the Z direction. The length of the illumination range is larger than the largest width of the recording medium P to be carried. The pair of lamps <b>212</b> is placed symmetrically about the optical axis OA (design optical axis) of the light reflected by the recording medium P and traveling toward the imaging unit <b>208</b>. More specifically, each of lamps <b>212</b> is placed symmetrically with respect to the optical axis OA such that respective illumination angle thereof to the recording medium P is between 45 degrees to 50 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In details, the pair of lamps <b>212</b> is equipped with a first lamp <b>212</b>A provided at the upstream side in conveying direction of the recording medium P, and a second lamp <b>212</b>B provided at the opposite side of the first lamp <b>212</b>A across the optical axis OA. Here, a detector <b>207</b> is configured to include the CCD sensor <b>204</b>, the lamps <b>212</b> and a window glass <b>286</b> as an example of a transmission member which will be described below. The images on the conveyed recording medium P is detected by the detecting unit <b>207</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The imaging optical system <b>206</b> is equipped, as main components thereof, with a first mirror <b>214</b> that reflects light guided along the optical axis OA in the X direction (in this exemplary embodiment, toward the downstream side in the conveying direction of the recording medium P), a second mirror <b>216</b> that reflects light reflected by the first mirror <b>214</b> upward, a third mirror <b>218</b> that reflects light reflected by the second mirror <b>216</b> to the upstream side in the conveying direction of the recording medium P, and lens <b>220</b> that focuses the light reflected by the third mirror <b>218</b> on the CCD sensor <b>204</b> (forming an image). The CCD sensor <b>204</b> is placed at the upstream side in the conveying direction of the recording medium P with respect to the optical axis OA.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The length of the first mirror <b>214</b> along the Z direction is formed to be larger than the maximum width of the recording medium P. Furthermore, the first mirror <b>214</b>, the second mirror <b>216</b> and the third mirror <b>218</b> are configured to respectively reflect the light that is reflected by the recording medium P and has entered the imaging optical system <b>206</b>, while narrowing down the light in the Z direction (main-scanning direction). This configuration allows incidence of the reflected light from each part in the width direction of the recording medium P onto the lens <b>220</b>, which has a substantially cylindrical shape.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">According to the configuration described above, in the inline sensor <b>200</b>, the CCD sensor <b>204</b> is configured to output (feed back) signals in accordance with the light which has formed image, namely image density, toward the control device <b>192</b> (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) provided in the first processing unit <b>10</b>A of the image forming apparatus <b>10</b>. The control device <b>192</b> is configured to correct the image formed at the image forming unit <b>16</b> based on the signal from the inline sensor <b>200</b>. Furthermore, in the image forming apparatus <b>10</b>, the intensity of the illuminated light by the exposure device <b>40</b>, an image forming position and the like are corrected based on the signal from the inline sensor <b>200</b>, as an example.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">A light amount aperture unit (diaphragm unit) <b>224</b> is provided between the third mirror <b>218</b> and the lens <b>220</b> in the imaging optical system <b>206</b>. The light amount aperture unit <b>224</b> is configured to be able to narrow down (stop down) the amount of the light, which forms image on the CCD sensor <b>204</b> across an optical path in the Z direction, in the Y direction (the direction intersecting with the main-scanning direction), and to adjust the light amount to be stopped down by operation from outside. With respect to the light amount by the light amount aperture unit <b>224</b>, it is configured such that the amount of the light forming images on the CCD sensor <b>204</b> is adjusted to be a predetermined value, even if the amount of luminescence by each lamp <b>212</b> is changed with time.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Meanwhile, the setting unit <b>210</b> has a reference roll <b>226</b> which is longitudinal in the Z direction. The reference roll <b>226</b> has a detection reference surface <b>228</b> which is directed to face the conveying path <b>60</b> side when performing image detection of the recording medium P, an evacuation surface <b>230</b> which is directed to face the conveying path <b>60</b> side when not performing the image detection of the recording medium P by the inline sensor <b>200</b>, white reference surfaces <b>232</b>, a color reference surface <b>234</b> on which a multi-color pattern is formed along the longitudinal direction, and a composite test surface <b>236</b> on which plural test patterns are formed. In this exemplary embodiment, the reference roll <b>226</b> is formed in a polygonal column shape on which eight or more surfaces are formed in a circumferential direction. The detection reference surface <b>228</b>, the evacuation surface <b>230</b>, the color reference surface <b>234</b> and the composite test surface <b>236</b> are each provided as only one surface, and the two white reference surfaces <b>232</b> are provided.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Moreover, the reference roll <b>226</b> is configured so that it switches the surface facing the conveying path <b>60</b> by being rotated about the rotation axis <b>226</b>A. The switching of the surface of the reference roll <b>226</b> is achieved by the control circuit (not shown) provided in a circuit substrate <b>262</b> which will hereinafter be described. Further, due to the reference roll <b>226</b> being formed in the polygonal column shape with at least eight sides, the difference between the distance from the center in a circumferential direction of each surface and from the corner parts between the surfaces with respect to the center of rotation of the reference roll <b>226</b> is kept small. Therefore, while the distance between each surface of the reference roll <b>226</b> and the illuminating position of each lamp <b>212</b> (window glass <b>286</b> which will hereinafter be described) is made small, the corner parts between the surfaces of the reference roll <b>226</b> do not interfere with the illuminating unit <b>202</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">With respect to the detection reference surface <b>228</b>, the width thereof in a circumferential direction is smaller than that of the other surface, and is smaller than the width of the window glass <b>286</b> in the conveying direction of the recording medium P. The surfaces of both side in the circumferential direction is defined as guide surfaces <b>238</b> which do not have a function as each reference described above. Moreover, the detection reference surface <b>228</b> is defined as a position reference surface for positioning the surface to be detected (to be read) of the conveyed recording medium P to a illumination position by each lamp <b>212</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">With respect to the evacuation surface <b>230</b>, the width thereof in a circumferential direction is larger than that of the other surfaces. When not performing image detection of the recording medium P with the inline sensor <b>200</b>, the evacuation surface <b>230</b> is a guide surface which guides the recording medium P, and a distance between the evacuation surface <b>230</b> and an axial center of the rotation axis <b>226</b>A is smaller than in the case of the detection reference surface <b>228</b>. Accordingly, when not performing image detection of the recording medium P with the inline sensor <b>200</b>, a conveying path is formed which has a wider space between the illuminating unit <b>202</b> (the window glass <b>286</b>) and the evacuation surface <b>230</b> than when performing image detection of the recording medium P with the inline sensor <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The white reference surfaces <b>232</b> are for calibration of the imaging optical system <b>206</b>, and are configured with a reference white film attached thereto, for outputting a predetermined signal from the imaging optical system <b>206</b>. The color reference surface <b>234</b> is for calibration of the imaging optical system <b>206</b>, and is configured with a film attached thereto that is applied with patterns of reference colors corresponding to the respective colors.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the composite test surface <b>236</b> is formed so that a position alignment pattern <b>240</b> for calibrating the position of the reference roll <b>226</b> in a rotation direction (conveying direction of the recording medium P), a focus detecting pattern <b>242</b>, and a depth detecting pattern <b>244</b> are arranged in a same surface.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The position alignment pattern <b>240</b> is configured with a white background film attached thereto, on which a black N-shaped pattern is formed so that the vertical line of the N is along the conveying direction of the recording medium P. The focus detecting pattern <b>242</b> is configured with a white background film attached thereto, on which a ladder pattern is formed, the ladder pattern being like a pattern having a number of black straight lines in parallel along the conveying direction of the recording medium P.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The depth detecting pattern <b>244</b> is configured with a pattern in which three white surfaces <b>244</b>A, <b>244</b>B and <b>244</b>C to which distances from the rotation axis <b>226</b>A (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) of the reference roll <b>226</b> are different are arranged in a staircase pattern in a longitudinal direction of the composite test surface <b>236</b>, and is formed by attaching a sheet member on which the patterns is formed.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Here, at least one position alignment pattern <b>240</b> is provided on each end in the longitudinal direction of the composite test surface <b>236</b>. The focus detecting pattern <b>242</b> is arranged adjacent to a center side in the longitudinal direction of the composite test surface <b>236</b> with respect to the position alignment pattern <b>240</b> provided on each end. A total of three depth detecting patterns <b>244</b> are provided on each end side in the longitudinal direction of the composite test surface <b>236</b> and a center part. Further, in this exemplary embodiment, one position alignment pattern <b>240</b> and one focus detecting pattern <b>242</b> are arranged between the depth detecting patterns <b>244</b> arranged at the center and the depth detecting pattern <b>244</b> arranged at one end in the longitudinal direction.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">Next, a procedure of the calibration of the CCD sensor <b>204</b> will be described.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, first, the white reference surface <b>232</b> is directed to face the conveying path <b>60</b> of the recording medium P. Then, the CCD sensor <b>204</b> outputs a shading compensation signal for compensating distribution of light amount in the Z direction (main-scanning direction). Subsequently, the composite test surface <b>236</b> is directed to face the conveying path <b>60</b> of the recording medium P, and a detecting position in the conveying direction of the recording medium P by the CCD sensor <b>204</b> is automatically adjusted due to the position alignment pattern <b>240</b> (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>). That is, by detecting the N-shaped pattern across in the Z direction (main-scanning direction), the diagonal part <b>240</b>B between the two straight line parts <b>240</b>A, <b>240</b>C is detected as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. Then, the reference roll <b>226</b> is rotated so that a distance between the straight line part <b>240</b>A and the diagonal part <b>240</b>B equals to a distance between the straight line part <b>240</b>C and the diagonal part <b>240</b>B, and the detecting position is adjusted.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">Subsequently, after the detecting position in the conveying direction of the recording medium P is adjusted, a focal point of the CCD sensor <b>204</b> is confirmed due to the focus detecting pattern <b>242</b> (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>), and an illumination depth is confirmed due to the depth detecting pattern <b>244</b>. Further, the color reference surface <b>234</b> is directed to face the conveying path <b>60</b> of the recording medium P. Then, the CCD sensor <b>204</b> is automatically adjusted so that signals of predetermined intensities are output for each of colors.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">As described above, the calibration of the CCD sensor <b>204</b> is performed when the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> is powered on (about once a day), for example. Further, the calibration of the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> based on signals from the CCD sensor <b>204</b> is performed, for example, each time a job is finished in which at least a predetermined number of images is formed on the recording medium P (about ten times a day).</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">(Divided Configuration of the Inline Sensor <b>200</b>)</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the inline sensor <b>200</b> described above is configured so as to be dividable into three parts: a center unit <b>246</b>, of which the main component is the illuminating unit <b>202</b>; an upper unit <b>248</b>, of which the main component is the imaging unit <b>208</b>; and a lower unit <b>250</b>, of which the main component is the setting unit <b>210</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The upper unit <b>248</b> is configured to be attachable to and detachable from the second processing unit <b>10</b>B (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> by sliding in the Z direction. The center unit <b>246</b> is configured to be attachable to and detachable from the upper unit <b>248</b> by sliding in the Z direction. The lower unit <b>250</b> is configured to be attachable to and detachable from the center unit <b>246</b> and the upper unit <b>248</b> by sliding in the Z direction. The lower unit <b>250</b> which is located below the conveying path <b>60</b> of the recording medium P is supported by a lower side drawer (not shown) which is drawn toward the front side in the Z direction from the second processing unit <b>10</b>B in order to relieve jamming of the recording medium P. The lower unit <b>250</b> is detached from and attached to the center unit <b>246</b> and the upper unit <b>248</b> by taking this lower side drawer in and out. Each configuration will be described in detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">(Configuration of the Upper Unit <b>248</b>)</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The upper unit <b>248</b> has an upper housing <b>254</b>. The upper housing <b>254</b> houses the imaging unit <b>208</b> and a circuit substrate <b>262</b> described below, and configures a cooling duct <b>265</b> or the like. The upper housing <b>254</b> is configured so as to include the imaging system housing <b>256</b> which houses the CCD sensor <b>204</b> and the imaging optical system <b>206</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">The imaging system housing <b>256</b> is formed nearly rectangle box shape and longitudinal in the X direction when viewed from the Z direction, and houses the CCD sensor <b>204</b> at one end part in the X direction (in this exemplary embodiment, an end part of the upstream side in the conveying direction of the recording medium P). Moreover, a second mirror <b>216</b> and a third mirror <b>218</b> are arranged at the other part of the imaging system housing <b>256</b> in the X direction. At nearly center part in the X direction of the imaging system housing <b>256</b>, a window portion <b>256</b>A on which light is incident along an optical axis OA is formed. The imaging system housing <b>256</b> is provided with the optics chamber <b>205</b>, which houses the CCD sensor <b>204</b> or the like and, inside of which is made sealed (airtight) space due to closing the window portion <b>256</b>A by light transmissive window glass <b>258</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">Moreover, the upper housing <b>254</b> has an upper cover <b>260</b> which covers the imaging system housing <b>256</b> from the upper side. As a result, a substrate chamber <b>264</b> is formed in which a circuit substrate <b>262</b> is housed between the upper cover <b>260</b> and an upper wall <b>256</b>U of the imaging system housing <b>256</b>. Moreover, the upper housing <b>254</b> has a duct cover <b>268</b> which forms a duct <b>265</b> outside one end part in the X direction of the imaging system housing <b>256</b> where the CCD sensor <b>204</b> is located. The duct cover <b>268</b> covers the one end part of the imaging system housing <b>256</b> from the upstream side and the downstream side in the conveying direction of the recording medium P, and forms the duct <b>265</b> which is L-shaped in X-Y cross-section.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">The upper end of the duct <b>265</b> is regarded as an air inlet <b>266</b>A, and the end part opposed to the air inlet <b>266</b>A of the duct <b>265</b> is regarded as a connecting port <b>266</b>B to connect the duct <b>308</b> of a lamp housing <b>284</b> which is described below. In the duct <b>265</b>, it is located a fan <b>270</b> which causes airflow in the duct <b>265</b> from the upper side to the lower side. Moreover, in the duct <b>265</b>, it is located a fan <b>272</b> which takes air into the optics chamber <b>205</b> (causes the inside of the optics chamber <b>205</b> to be positive pressure) provided in the imaging system housing <b>256</b>. Further, in the duct <b>265</b>, it is located a fan <b>274</b> (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) which takes air into the substrate chamber <b>264</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">Furthermore, the upper housing <b>254</b> has a cover <b>275</b> which covers the imaging system housing <b>256</b> from the second mirror <b>216</b> side and the third mirror <b>218</b> side. An insulating space <b>276</b> is formed between the imaging system housing <b>256</b> and the cover <b>275</b>. In the upper housing <b>254</b>, sliders <b>278</b> are provided which are elongate in the Z direction. In this exemplary embodiment, a pair of sliders <b>278</b> is provided in parallel in the X arrow direction on the upper cover <b>260</b>. Each of the sliders <b>278</b> can be fitted to a rail provided on the frame (not shown) of the second processing unit <b>10</b>B. As a result, each of the sliders <b>278</b> moves while being guided by the rail, such that the upper unit <b>248</b> is moved in the Z direction with respect to the second processing unit <b>10</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">(Configuration of the Center Unit <b>246</b>)</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the center unit <b>246</b> has a lamp housing <b>284</b> which houses the pair of lamps <b>212</b>, a window glass <b>286</b> through which the light illuminated from the lamps <b>212</b> toward the recording medium P is penetrated, and a window cover <b>288</b> which holds the window glass <b>286</b>. The window glass <b>286</b> is located between the conveying path <b>60</b> of the recording medium P and the lamps <b>212</b>, and provided facing the conveying path <b>60</b>. Moreover, the lamp housing <b>284</b> is formed in box shape which opens top and bottom thereof, the opening end of the upper side thereof being closed by the upper housing <b>254</b> and the opening end of the lower side thereof being closed by the window cover <b>288</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">The illuminating unit <b>202</b> is configured such that the light emitted by each lamp <b>212</b> is illuminated to the recording medium P through the window glass <b>286</b>, and the light reflected on the recording medium P is incident into the lamp housing <b>284</b> through the window glass <b>286</b> along the optical axis OA. It is configured such that the reflected light which is from the recording medium P and incident into the lamp housing <b>284</b> is led to the imaging unit <b>208</b> through the window glass <b>258</b> of the imaging system housing <b>256</b> which configures the imaging unit <b>208</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">The lamp housing <b>284</b> has a pair of sliders <b>290</b> which project in the X arrow direction in a flange shape from an opening edge at the upper side, and which are elongate in the Z direction. The sliders <b>290</b> are fitted to the rail <b>292</b> formed on the upper housing <b>254</b>. This allows each slider <b>290</b> to move while being guided by the rail <b>292</b> such that the lamp housing <b>284</b> is attached to and detached from the upper housing <b>254</b> (the upper unit <b>248</b>) in the Z direction.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">The window cover <b>288</b> is configured such that the edge thereof and the edge of the window glass <b>286</b> do not face the upstream side in conveying direction of the recording medium P. The window glass <b>286</b> is pressed against the window cover <b>288</b> at both ends in a longitudinal direction by attachment springs (not shown), in a closed posture of the window part <b>288</b>A formed on the window cover <b>288</b>. That is, the window glass <b>286</b> is configured so as to allow it to be attached to and detached from the window cover <b>288</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">Moreover, the window cover <b>288</b> is configured so as to allow it to be attached to and detached from the lamp housing <b>284</b>. Specifically, the window cover <b>288</b> is configured so that its cross-sectional shape taken along X-Y is a U-shaped form which opens at an upper side, and is provided with a pair of sliders <b>298</b> at the opening edge part. The sliders <b>298</b> are fitted to the rail <b>300</b> formed on the lamp housing <b>284</b>. This allows each slider <b>298</b> to move while being guided by the rail <b>300</b> such that the window cover <b>288</b> is attached to and detached from the window glass <b>286</b> in the Z direction. As a result, in the inline sensor <b>200</b>, it is possible to exchange and clean the window cover <b>288</b> with a single part.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">While not illustrated in the drawings, the center unit <b>246</b> and the upper unit <b>248</b> are configured so as to be positioned with a high degree of accuracy in each of the X, Y and Z directions, by holes and pins to be inserted and removed according to relative movement in the Z direction. Moreover, the upper unit <b>248</b> and the casing of the second processing unit <b>10</b>B (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) are configured so as to be positioned with a high degree of accuracy in each of directions of X, Y and Z, by holes and pins to be inserted and removed according to relative movement in the Z direction.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">(Configuration of the Lower Unit <b>250</b>)</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the lower unit <b>250</b> has a lower housing <b>302</b> which houses the reference roll <b>226</b> and a motor (not shown) driving the reference roll <b>226</b>. The lower housing <b>302</b> is supported by a lower side drawer as described above, and is positioned in the Z direction by the lower side drawer. Moreover, the lower unit <b>250</b> and the center unit <b>246</b>, the upper unit <b>248</b> are configured so as to be positioned with a high degree of accuracy in each of directions of X and Y, by holes and pins to be inserted and removed according to relative movement in the Z direction. Due to this configuration, the position of the lower unit <b>250</b> in each of directions of X, Y and Z with respect to the center unit <b>246</b> and the upper unit <b>248</b> is determined, the conveying path <b>60</b> of the recording medium P being located between the center unit <b>246</b> and the lower unit <b>250</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">(Countermeasure Against Stray Light)</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, in the lamp housing <b>284</b>, a baffle <b>304</b> is provided so that the optical axis OA is surrounded in the upper part of the pair of lamps <b>212</b> (<b>212</b>A, <b>212</b>B). As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the baffle <b>304</b> is configured so as to have a pair of sidewalls <b>304</b>S and the bottom wall <b>304</b>B at least. In this exemplary embodiment, the pair of sidewalls <b>304</b>S are connected with a pair of front and back walls (not shown) which are opposed in the Z direction. Moreover, it is formed a lower side window <b>304</b>W into which an optical axis OA enters in the bottom wall <b>304</b>B. The upper opening end of the baffle <b>304</b> surrounds the window part <b>256</b>A of the imaging system housing <b>256</b>. Therefore, the light which travels along optical axis OA enters into the imaging unit <b>208</b> via the inside of the baffle <b>304</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">With respect to the baffle <b>304</b>, the dimensions and shape thereof are set so that light emitted from the back side of each lamp <b>212</b> may not reach the window portion <b>256</b>A. That is, with respect to the lower side window <b>304</b>W, the position of the opening edge is set so that light emitted from the back side of each lamp <b>212</b> may not reach the window portion <b>256</b>A directly. Moreover, with respect to the side wall <b>304</b>S, the angle of inclination with respect to the optical axis is set so that light emitted from the back side of each lamp <b>212</b> does not reach the window portion <b>256</b>A even if the light is reflected once.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">On the other hand, in the imaging system housing <b>256</b>, plural partition walls <b>306</b> are provided, which divide a part other than a optical waveguide by the imaging optical system <b>206</b>. Each partition wall <b>306</b> has an aperture <b>306</b>A, the size (upper limit) of an light transit portion being decided in so far as not narrowing down (stopping down) the diffusion light reflected by the recording medium P in the Y direction and the Z direction, according to the diffusion angle of the light reflected by the recording medium P.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">(Airflow)</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, in the lamp housing <b>284</b>, the duct <b>308</b> is formed by one of the side walls <b>304</b>S thereof (in this exemplary embodiment, the upstream side in the conveying direction of the recording medium P), and the peripheral wall of the lamp housing <b>284</b>. The upper opening end of the duct <b>308</b> is connected to the duct <b>265</b> through the connection port <b>266</b>B in a state where the lamp housing <b>284</b> is fit to the upper housing <b>254</b>. Due to this structure, the airflow in the lamp housing <b>284</b> is generated by an operation of the fan <b>270</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">An air outlet <b>310</b> is formed at a part which is positioned at an opposite side to the duct <b>308</b> side in the X direction of the peripheral wall of the lamp housing <b>284</b>. Therefore, the airflow from the duct <b>265</b> flows through the first lamp <b>212</b>A at the upstream side in the conveying direction of the recording medium P and the second lamp <b>212</b> B at the downstream side thereof while being guided by the peripheral wall of the lamp housing <b>284</b> and the window cover <b>288</b>, and is discharged outside of the lamp housing <b>284</b> through the air outlet <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">Moreover, an overhang portion <b>312</b> for suppressing that the light emitted from the back side of the first lamp <b>212</b>A reaches the lower side window <b>304</b>W is projected from the lower end of the sidewall <b>304</b>S which configures the duct <b>308</b>. The projection amount of the overhang portion <b>312</b> is set so that the cooling effect of the pair of lamps <b>212</b> by the airflow to the pair of lamps <b>212</b> becomes equivalent.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">(Light Amount Aperture Unit)</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the light amount aperture unit <b>224</b> has a sidewall <b>224</b>S, an upper wall <b>224</b>U and a lower wall <b>224</b>L, and the cross-section shape taken along X-Y thereof is U-shaped form which opens toward the third mirror <b>218</b> side. A substantially rectangle shaped opening part <b>314</b> is formed in the sidewall <b>224</b>S of the light amount aperture unit <b>224</b>. Moreover, a rib <b>316</b> is drooped from a free end part of the upper wall <b>224</b>U. Thereby, the light amount aperture unit <b>224</b> is configured so as to cut the light from the recording medium P at a lower edge <b>314</b>L of the opening part <b>314</b> and at a lower end <b>316</b>L of the rib <b>316</b> and to narrow down the light amount in the Y direction.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">One end in the longitudinal direction of the light amount aperture unit <b>224</b> reaches a wall at the front side of the imaging system housing <b>256</b>, and an adjusting lever (not shown) is attached to the one end in the longitudinal direction of the light amount aperture unit <b>224</b> through an operation hole formed in the wall. The light amount aperture unit <b>224</b> is configured so as to rotate in accordance with operation of the adjusting lever and to move from an initial position in which the light amount is most narrowed down to postures in which the amount of narrowing down is gradually decreased.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">(Jamming Suppression Structure)</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the conveying path <b>60</b> between the center unit <b>246</b> (the illuminating unit <b>202</b>) and the lower unit <b>250</b> (the setting unit <b>210</b>) is configured such that the position thereof becomes higher toward the downstream side in the conveying direction of the recording medium P. For each corner part of the first window cover <b>288</b> and the lower housing <b>302</b>, a chamfering or a rounding processing is carried out. Thereby, an entrance chute <b>320</b> which is an inducing part facing the upstream side in the conveying direction of the recording medium P is formed at a position upstream side from the window glass <b>286</b> in the inline sensor <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">The upper chute <b>320</b>U which structures the upper part of the entrance chute <b>320</b> is configured with a smooth curved surface which is downwardly convex. Here, if it assumes the extension line of the detection reference surface <b>228</b> as IL, when viewed from the Z direction in a state in which the detection reference surface <b>228</b> of the reference roll <b>226</b> faces to the conveying path <b>60</b> side of the recording medium P, the dimension and shape of the upper chute <b>320</b>U is set so as to interfere with the extension line IL (so that a projected end of the upper chute <b>320</b>U is positioned lower side of the extension line IL).</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">The lower chute <b>320</b>L which configures the lower part of the entrance chute <b>320</b> is close to the reference roll <b>226</b> by a lower chute member <b>324</b> fixed to a flange <b>302</b>F which is extended inward from the opening end of the lower housing <b>302</b>. Further, the downstream end in the conveying direction of the recording medium P in the lower chute member <b>324</b> is configured as a round part <b>324</b>A rounded so as to become a convex upward.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">An exit chute <b>326</b> is formed between a downstream side part in the conveying direction of the recording medium P in the convex part <b>322</b>, and the lower housing <b>302</b>. The lower chute <b>326</b>L which forms the lower part of the exit chute <b>326</b> is configured by fixing a lower chute member <b>328</b> to the flange <b>302</b>F which is extended outward from the opening end of the lower housing <b>302</b>. Further, the downstream end in the conveying direction of the recording medium P in the lower chute member <b>324</b> is configured as a round part <b>328</b>A that is upwardly convex.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">Moreover, when detecting the image by the CCD sensor <b>204</b>, the detection reference surface <b>228</b> of the reference roll <b>226</b> is configured so as to be directed to face the recording medium P side with the posture nearly parallel to the window glass <b>286</b>. Each guide surface <b>238</b> provided in the both sides of this detection reference surface <b>228</b> receives the recording medium P from the entrance chute <b>320</b>, and guides the recording medium P toward the exit chute <b>326</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">On the other hand, when not detecting the image with the CCD sensor <b>204</b>, the evacuation surface <b>230</b> of the reference roll <b>226</b> is directed to face the recording medium P side in a posture (un-parallel posture) in which the evacuation surface <b>230</b> becomes closer to the window glass <b>286</b> the further downstream it extends in the conveying direction of the recording medium P. Moreover, the evacuation surface <b>230</b> is configured as a wide surface which extends from the round part <b>324</b>A of the lower chute member <b>324</b> to the vicinity of the exit chute <b>326</b>. The evacuation surface <b>230</b> receives the recording medium P from the entrance chute <b>320</b> in the above-mentioned posture, and guides the recording medium P toward the exit chute <b>326</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">(Function of the Inline Sensor <b>200</b>)</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the inline sensor <b>200</b> illuminates the recording medium P which passes through between the illuminating unit <b>202</b> and the setting unit <b>210</b> with light by the pair of lamps <b>212</b>. Then, the light reflected by the recording medium P is led to the imaging unit <b>208</b> along the optical axis OA, and is imaged on the CCD sensor <b>204</b> by the imaging optical system <b>206</b> of the imaging unit <b>208</b>. Subsequently, the CCD sensor <b>204</b> outputs the signal according to an image density for every position of the image to the control device <b>192</b> (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of the image forming apparatus <b>10</b>. Then, in the control device <b>192</b>, the image density and an image forming position or the like are corrected based on the signal from the CCD sensor <b>204</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">On the other hand, when performing the calibration of the CCD sensor <b>204</b> which configures the inline sensor <b>200</b>, first, the motor of the lower unit <b>250</b> operates and the white reference surface <b>232</b> is directed to face the conveying path <b>60</b> of the recording medium P. Then, the CCD sensor <b>204</b> is adjusted so as to output a predetermined signal.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111">Subsequently, composite test surface <b>236</b> (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>) is directed to face the conveying path <b>60</b> of the recording medium P, and the detection position of the CCD sensor <b>204</b> is adjusted so that an interval between a diagonal part <b>240</b>B and a straight line part <b>240</b>A, and an interval between the diagonal part <b>240</b>B and a straight line part <b>240</b>C, of a position alignment pattern <b>240</b> (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>) become equal. Next, the focus state of the CCD sensor <b>204</b> is checked using the focus detecting pattern <b>242</b>. Moreover, the illumination depth is checked using the depth detecting pattern <b>244</b>. Furthermore, the color reference surface <b>234</b> (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>) is directed to face the conveying path <b>60</b> of the recording medium P. For each color, the CCD sensor <b>204</b> is adjusted so as to output the predetermined signal.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">(Configuration of the Main Part)</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">Next, details of the detecting unit <b>207</b> of the inline sensor <b>200</b> and the reference roll <b>226</b> will be explained.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</figref>, the detecting unit <b>207</b> of the inline sensor <b>200</b> has the window cover <b>288</b> for supporting the window glass <b>286</b>, and the exposed part to the image side of the recording medium P (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</figref>) in the lower surface of the window glass <b>286</b> is made as a detecting surface <b>286</b>A as an example.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">On the other hand, in the inline sensor <b>200</b>, the reference roll <b>226</b> as an example of an opposing member having plural surfaces in the conveying direction of the recording medium P is provided at the opposite side of the detecting surface <b>286</b>A so as to face it, across the conveying path <b>60</b> (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) of the recording medium P.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116">The reference roll <b>226</b> has the evacuation surface <b>230</b>, which is an example of a first opposing surface which is one surface among the plural surfaces, and the evacuation surface <b>230</b> is located opposite the detecting surface <b>286</b>A. Moreover, the opposing surface is changed by rotating the reference roll <b>226</b> so that the detecting surface <b>286</b>A and the detection reference surface <b>228</b> (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>), which is an example of a second opposing surface are disposed opposite to each other when performing image detection of the recording medium P using the detecting unit <b>207</b> (at the time of detection), and the detecting surface <b>286</b>A and the evacuation surface <b>230</b> are disposed opposite to each other when not performing image detection (at the time of non-detection).</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0117">Here, when a distance (spacing) between a part (an end portion) at the upstream side in the conveying direction of the recording medium P and the detecting surface <b>286</b>A is defined as d<b>1</b>, and a distance (spacing) between a part (an end portion) at the downstream side and the detecting surface <b>286</b>A is defined as d<b>2</b>, the evacuation surface <b>230</b> is inclined so as to satisfy d<b>1</b>&#x3e;d<b>2</b>. That is, in the evacuation surface <b>230</b>, the downstream side thereof in the conveying direction is closer to the detection surface <b>286</b>A than the upstream side thereof in the conveying direction. Moreover, the evacuation surface <b>230</b>, as a whole, is positioned at a side further separated from the detection surface <b>286</b>A than the extension line IL of the detection reference surface <b>228</b> (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0118">Moreover, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</figref>, in the reference roll <b>226</b>, the end portion <b>237</b> at the upstream side of the evacuation surface <b>230</b> and the end portion <b>239</b> at the downstream side thereof are configured to be a round shape, as an example of a curved shape, which is convex outward. The read position P<b>1</b> for reading the image information of the recording medium P is set on the detecting surface <b>286</b>A, and a position P<b>2</b> of the end portion at the upstream side of the evacuation surface <b>230</b> in the reference roll <b>226</b> is positioned at the upstream side of the read position P<b>1</b> of the detecting surface <b>286</b>A in the conveying direction. The read position P<b>1</b> is a position at which the optical axis OA intersects with the detecting surface <b>286</b>A when viewing the window glass <b>286</b> from a direction perpendicular to the conveying direction.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0119">On the other hand, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</figref>, the lower chute member <b>328</b> as an example of a guide member for guiding the recording medium P to the downstream side, is provided at the downstream side of the detecting surface <b>286</b>A in the conveying direction and at the downstream side of the reference roll <b>226</b>, as described above. With respect to the lower chute member <b>328</b>, an end portion thereof at the downstream side in the conveying direction is configured as a round part <b>328</b>A as an example of a curved shape which is curved toward a direction away from the recording medium P. Moreover, a gap d<b>3</b> is formed between the end surface <b>328</b>B at the upstream side of the lower chute member <b>328</b> and the reference roll <b>226</b>, so that the reference roll <b>226</b> does not contact the lower chute member <b>328</b> at the time of rotation for changing the plural surfaces.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0120">Next, the operation of the present exemplary embodiment will be explained.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0121">First of all, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</figref>, it will be explained a case that the front part of the recording medium P conveyed to the inline sensor <b>200</b> is curled in a convex shape (a shape in which the front part is curved obliquely downward toward the conveying direction) when viewed from a direction perpendicular to the conveying direction.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0122">The recording medium P conveyed to the inline sensor <b>200</b> contacts the lower chute member <b>324</b> at the upstream side and moves upward, since the front part thereof is inclined downward. At this time, since the end portion at the downstream side of the lower chute member <b>324</b> is configured as the round part <b>324</b>A, the end surface of the lower chute member <b>324</b> does not contact the recording medium P, whereby the occurrence of scratching of the recording medium P is suppressed.</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0123">Subsequently, the front part of the recording medium P moved downstream in the conveying direction from the position of the lower chute member <b>324</b> contacts an upstream side part of the evacuation surface <b>230</b>, and is gradually guided obliquely upward along the evacuation surface <b>230</b>. That is, the front end part of the recording medium P is gradually pressed upward to the detecting surface <b>286</b>A side. Then, the front end part of the recording medium P is conveyed at a position that is separated from the end surface <b>328</b>B at the upstream side of the lower chute member <b>328</b> on the downstream side.</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0124">As a result, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8B</figref>, even if the front end part of the recording medium P, which has passed the reference roll <b>226</b>, is bent downward by its own weight, a contact position thereof with the lower chute member <b>328</b> is at the downstream side of the end surface <b>328</b>B, whereby the recording medium P is prevented from entering the gap d<b>3</b> between the reference roll <b>226</b> and the lower chute member <b>328</b>. Moreover, since the end portion at the downstream side of the lower chute member <b>328</b> is formed as the round part <b>328</b>A, there is no contact between the end surface of the lower chute member <b>324</b> and the recording medium P, and the occurrence of scratching of the recording medium P is suppressed.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0125">Further, in the inline sensor <b>200</b>, since the end portion <b>237</b> at the upstream side of the evacuation surface <b>230</b> and the end portion <b>239</b> at the downstream side thereof (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</figref>) are formed in a curved shape in the reference roll <b>226</b>, the occurrence of scratching of the recording medium P is suppressed in comparison with a configuration in which both end parts are linearly angled. Moreover, since the evacuation surface <b>230</b> is disposed at a side that is further from the detection surface <b>286</b>A than the extension line IL of the detection reference surface <b>228</b>, the space between the detecting surface <b>286</b>A and the reference roll <b>226</b> is broadened, and the resistance force which acts on the recording medium P by contact with the reference roll <b>226</b> is weakened. Thereby, conveyance of the recording medium P is performed properly.</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0126">In addition, in the inline sensor <b>200</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</figref>, since the position P<b>2</b> of the end portion at the upstream side of the evacuation surface <b>230</b> is positioned at the upstream side of the read position P<b>1</b> of the detecting surface <b>286</b>A in the conveying direction, the recording medium P is spaced apart from the detecting surface <b>286</b>A at a region at the upstream side of the read position P<b>1</b> of the detecting surface <b>286</b>A. As a result, conveying resistance against the recording medium P caused by contact of the reference roll <b>226</b> with the recording medium P decreases. Moreover, in the inline sensor <b>200</b>, since the evacuation surface <b>230</b> is located so as to face the detecting surface <b>286</b>A when not detecting the image on the recording medium P, it is possible to reduce a contact area between the opposing member and the recording medium, in comparison with a configuration in which distances from the detecting surface <b>286</b>A to the end portion at the upstream side of the opposing surface and the end portion at downstream side thereof in the conveying direction are identical.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0127">On the other hand, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, in a case where the front end part of the recording medium P conveyed to the inline sensor <b>200</b> is curled in a concave shape (a shape in which the front part is inclined upward along the conveying direction) when viewed from a direction perpendicular to the conveying direction, when the front end part of the recording medium P passes beyond the reference roll <b>226</b>, the front end part contacts the lower chute member <b>328</b>. Thus, the front end part of the recording medium P does not enter the gap d<b>3</b> (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</figref>) between the reference roll <b>226</b> and the lower chute member <b>328</b>. In addition, when conveying a recording medium P without any curling, since this corresponds to a case in which the size of curling at the front part of the recording medium P is small in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8B</figref> and the operation is similar to that with respect to downward curling, explanation is omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0128">The present invention is not limited to the above-mentioned exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0129">An image detection may be performed using a contact-type sensor substituted for the window glass <b>286</b>, or using contact-type sensors as an optical sensor part including the CCD sensor <b>204</b> while the window glass <b>286</b> is in that condition. Moreover, one of the end portion <b>237</b> at the upstream side of the evacuation surface <b>230</b> and the end portion <b>239</b> at the downstream side thereof may has a curved shape. Further, a fixed opposing member may be used in place of the reference roll <b>226</b> which is rotatable. In addition, although the light is given from the front surface side of the recording medium P in this exemplary embodiment, the light may be given from the back surface side of the recording medium P, in a case of using the recording medium P or the like which transmits the light.</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0130">The foregoing description of the exemplary embodiments of the present invention has been provided for the purposes of illustration and description. It is not intended to be exhaustive or to limit the invention to the precise forms disclosed. Obviously, many modifications and variations will be apparent to practitioners skilled in the art. The exemplary embodiments were chosen and described in order to best explain the principles of the invention and its practical applications, thereby enabling others skilled in the art to understand the invention for various embodiments and with the various modifications as are suited to the particular use contemplated. It is intended that the scope of the invention be defined by the following claims and their equivalents.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A detecting apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a transmission member that is provided facing a conveying path on which a medium is conveyed and that transmits light from the medium being conveyed on the conveying path;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a detecting section that detects the medium or an image on the medium from the light which is transmitted through the transmission member, wherein the light is received by a light-receiving member of the detection section;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an opposing member that is provided on an opposite side of the conveying path from the transmission member and has at least an opposing surface that faces the transmission member; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a guide member that is provided at a downstream side of the opposing member in the conveying direction, and guides the medium downstream in the conveying path,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the opposing surface is closer to the detecting section at a downstream side than at an upstream side thereof in the conveying direction.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the opposing member has a first opposing surface and a second opposing surface and is rotated to switch between the first opposing surface and a second opposing surface depending on whether or not detection is performed by the detecting section, and the first opposing surface faces the transmission member when detection is not performed by the detecting section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of an end portion at the upstream side or an end portion at the downstream side of the opposing surface in the conveying direction is formed in a curved shape.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein an end portion at the downstream side of the guide member is curved in a direction diverging from the conveying path.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. An image forming apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>an image forming section that forms an image on a medium;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a conveying section that conveys the medium on which the image is formed by the image forming section; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, that detects the image on the medium conveyed by the conveying section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A detecting apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a transmission member that is provided facing a conveying path on which a medium is conveyed and that transmits light from the medium being conveyed on the conveying path;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a detecting section that detects the medium or an image on the medium from the light which is transmitted through the transmission member;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an opposing member that is provided on an opposite side of the conveying path from the transmission member and has a plurality of opposing surfaces which are capable of facing the transmission member; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a guide member that is provided at a downstream side of the opposing member in the conveying direction, and guides the medium downstream in the conveying path,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein when detection is not performed by the detecting section, a first opposing surface of the plurality of opposing surfaces faces the transmission member, and is closer to the detecting section at a downstream side than at an upstream side thereof in the conveying direction.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the opposing member is rotatably supported, and the first opposing surface is positioned to face the transmission member when detection is not performed by the detecting section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the first opposing surface is formed with a substantially flat surface, and the first opposing surface is inclined with respect to a transmission surface of the transmission member in a state in which the first opposing surface is in a position facing the transmission member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the first opposing surface is formed so as to diverge further from a transmission surface of the transmission member than another opposing surface in a state in which the first opposing surface or the another opposing surface is in a position facing the transmission member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of an end portion at the upstream side or an end portion at the downstream side of the first opposing surface in the conveying direction is formed in a curved shape.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein in a state in which the first opposing surface is in a position facing the transmission member, an end portion at the upstream side of the guide member is positioned further apart from the conveying path than an end portion at the downstream side in the conveying direction of the first opposing surface, and is curved in a direction diverging from the conveying path.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. An image forming apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>an image forming section that forms an image on a medium;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a conveying section that conveys the medium on which the image is formed by the image forming section; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, that detects the image on the medium conveyed by the conveying section. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
