<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626416-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626416</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13427059</doc-number>
<date>20120322</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2011-067338</doc-number>
<date>20110325</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>107</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>60</class>
<subclass>T</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>12</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>701 85</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Traction controlling apparatus</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4858715</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Tominaga</name>
<date>19890800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>180170</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4942950</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Watanabe et al.</name>
<date>19900700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>477 87</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4947952</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kajiwara</name>
<date>19900800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>180178</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5241478</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Inoue et al.</name>
<date>19930800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>701 91</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5329453</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Tsuyama et al.</name>
<date>19940700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>701 83</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>06-229263</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19940800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>19</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>701 85</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120245818</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120927</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Miki</last-name>
<first-name>Kotaro</first-name>
<address>
<city>Wako</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Abe</last-name>
<first-name>Takeru</first-name>
<address>
<city>Wako</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nakamura</last-name>
<first-name>Masanori</first-name>
<address>
<city>Wako</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Miki</last-name>
<first-name>Kotaro</first-name>
<address>
<city>Wako</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Abe</last-name>
<first-name>Takeru</first-name>
<address>
<city>Wako</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nakamura</last-name>
<first-name>Masanori</first-name>
<address>
<city>Wako</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Squire Sanders (US) LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Honda Motor Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Cheung</last-name>
<first-name>Mary</first-name>
<department>3667</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Brushaber</last-name>
<first-name>Frederick</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A traction controlling apparatus is configured such that if a slip of a driving wheel is detected, then a throttle valve opening is reduced to a first predetermined value. If failure is detected while the throttle valve opening is reduced to the first predetermined value, then the throttle valve opening is further reduced to a second predetermined value. If the acceleration grip is manipulated to a fully closed position while the throttle valve opening is reduced to the second predetermined value, then the control is ended and throttle control by a direct manipulation of the acceleration grip is enabled.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="161.88mm" wi="246.21mm" file="US08626416-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="237.24mm" wi="171.96mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626416-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="247.73mm" wi="160.78mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626416-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="171.87mm" wi="160.95mm" file="US08626416-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="180.00mm" wi="171.70mm" file="US08626416-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="145.80mm" wi="165.69mm" file="US08626416-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="161.80mm" wi="152.48mm" file="US08626416-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="157.14mm" wi="169.67mm" file="US08626416-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="143.59mm" wi="146.90mm" file="US08626416-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a traction controlling apparatus, and particularly to a traction controlling apparatus capable of rapidly coping with recovery from failure which occurs during traction control.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In a motorcycle or a four-wheeled vehicle, traction control for preventing slippage of a tire upon starting or upon acceleration is known, and also a countermeasure where failure occurs during traction control has been investigated. For example, in Patent Document 1 (Japanese Patent Laid-Open No. Hei 06-229263), a fail-safe apparatus is proposed in which, where failure of a traction controlling system is detected upon autonomous traveling wherein throttle control is carried out without depending upon an acceleration pedal operation, current to a throttle valve (sub throttle valve) for traction control is blocked so that the sub throttle valve is closed. In the fail-safe apparatus, after the sub throttle valve is closed, the opening of the throttle valve is recovered by a switching off manipulation for an autonomous traveling selection switch by the user.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The fail safe apparatus disclosed in Patent Document 1 has a configuration in which, when failure occurs, the throttle valve is operated in a closing direction to secure necessary and minimum driving by an idling controlling system. However, in the apparatus of Patent Document 1, recovery from an idling controlling mode to a normal throttle controlling mode cannot be achieved before the user carries out a switching off manipulation of the autonomous traveling selection switch. In such conventional control as just described, for example, even if one of wheel rotational speed sensors fails and traction control is disabled, if the failure is failure in which driving in the normal throttle controlling mode can be carried out, then the throttle valve opening remains in a fully closed state and inconvenient traveling or manipulation by excessive coping with the failure is imposed on the user. Particularly with a motorcycle which is likely to be influenced by an ignition noise or the like, there is a subject that, even if a temporary fail state of a sensor occurs, driving is excessively restricted by continuation of such a fail safe mode that a power supply is blocked upon fail detection of the traction controlling system.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">It is an object of the present invention to provide a traction controlling apparatus which can quickly enter normal throttle valve control without excessively restricting the traveling state when failure occurs during traction control.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In order to attain the object described above, according to embodiments of the present invention, a traction controlling apparatus includes a transmission or transmission means for transmitting a manipulation of an acceleration grip to a throttle valve through an electromagnetic connection unit. An accelerator opening sensor is configured to detect a manipulation opening of the acceleration grip. A throttle-by-wire controlling unit is configured to drive, in a state in which the electromagnetic connection unit is placed in a de-energization state to disconnect the transmission, an actuator in response to the manipulation opening of the acceleration grip to control an opening of the throttle valve. A slip detection unit is configured to detect a slip state of a driving wheel, and a fail detection unit is configured to detect failure of an engine controlling system. A throttle reduction unit is configured to reduce the throttle valve opening to a first predetermined value by the throttle-by-wire controlling unit in response to detection of a slip state and traction fail controlling unit configured to decrease, when failure of the engine controlling system is detected while the throttle valve opening is reduced to the first predetermined value, the throttle valve opening to a second predetermined value lower than the first predetermined value by the throttle-by-wire controlling unit. If it is detected that the acceleration grip is manipulated to a fully closed position during a traction fail process in which the throttle valve opening is reduced to the second predetermined value by the traction fail controlling unit, then the traction fail process is ended and the electromagnetic connection unit is energized to place the transmission into a connection state and throttle control based on the throttle valve opening in response to the acceleration manipulation opening is enabled.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Further, according to embodiments of the present invention, the second predetermined value can be an idling throttle valve opening.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Further, according to embodiments of the present invention, a traction indicator for indicating that the driving power is being suppressed and the traction fail process is being carried out is provided.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Further, according to embodiments of the present invention, the traction indicator is provided in a meter apparatus which indicates a driving state of a vehicle and is configured from a traction on indicating lamp which flickers during traction control but is turned off during stopping of the traction control and a traction off indicating lamp which is turned off during the traction control but is turned on during stopping of the traction control, and, during the traction fail process, the traction on indicating lamp is turned on and the traction off indicating lamp is turned off.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Further, according to embodiments of the present invention, the predetermined closing manipulation is a manipulation of the acceleration grip to a fully closed position.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Further, according to embodiments of the present invention, the traction controlling apparatus further includes transmission means for transmitting a manipulation of the acceleration grip to a throttle valve through electromagnetic connection means, and if it is detected that the predetermined closing manipulation is carried out for the acceleration grip during the traction process in which the throttle valve opening is reduced to the second predetermined value, then the traction fail process is stopped and the electromagnetic connection means is biased to place the transmission means into a connected state to enable throttle control based on the throttle valve opening in response to the acceleration manipulation opening.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Further, according to embodiments of the present invention, throttle valve opening control is executed when a slip ratio of the driving wheel is lower than a predetermined value. If the slip ratio becomes equal to or higher than the predetermined value, then fuel injection reduction control irrespective of the throttle valve opening is executed in addition to the throttle valve opening control, and, where the traction fail process is executed in a state in which the slip ratio is equal to or higher than the predetermined value, the fuel injection reduction control is ended and fuel injection control in response to the throttle valve opening is carried out.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">According to certain of these embodiments, even if failure in which throttle control by normal acceleration operation can be carried out occurs during traction control, throttle control is enabled by carrying out a manipulation for fully closing the acceleration grip. Therefore, it is possible to prevent a burden by excessive coping with the failure such as a manipulation for restarting the system from being imposed on the driver. Particularly, also it is possible to overcome the subject of the conventional technique that, when failure occurs, the engine can be driven only with the idling speed.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In certain embodiments, the engine can be maintained at the idling speed if the acceleration opening is not placed into the fully closed stage when failure occurs.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Also in certain embodiments, since the driver can recognize a situation in which the output power is suppressed by traction control and the traction fail process, it can be eliminated that a sense of incongruity by deceleration is given to the driver, and it is possible to urge the driver to transit to throttle control by a manipulation of the acceleration grip.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In some embodiments, since the fail indicator is formed by using the two displaying lights, the visibility of the indicator can be enhanced.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In certain embodiments, since the idling opening of the throttle and the opening of the acceleration grip can be associated with each other, a manipulation of the throttle valve opening in response to a manipulation of the acceleration grip can thereafter be carried out quickly.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In certain embodiments, since fuel injection in response to the throttle valve opening is carried out before a closing manipulation of the acceleration grip is carried out, air fuel ratio control can be entered quickly in accordance with throttle valve opening control after the fail process comes to an end.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a left side elevational view of a motorcycle having a traction controlling apparatus according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an enlarged view of a front portion of the motorcycle having the traction controlling apparatus according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a wiring diagram between an engine and peripheral apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a block diagram showing functions of essential part of an ECU for a fail process during traction control.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an operation timing chart relating to a traction fail process.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flow chart of a process (TCS fail process) ready for a traction fail operation.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a front elevational view of a meter apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a view illustrating lighting conditions of a traction fail controlling indicator.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In the following, an embodiment of the present invention is described with reference to the drawings. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a left side elevational view of a motorcycle having a traction controlling apparatus according to an embodiment of the present invention, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an enlarged view of a front portion of the motorcycle. The motorcycle <b>1</b> has a water-cooled four-cycle V type four-cylinder engine <b>2</b>, and power of the engine <b>2</b> is transmitted to a rear wheel WR which is a driving wheel by a shaft drive mechanism, built in a swing arm <b>4</b>, through a speed change gear <b>3</b>. The speed change gear <b>3</b> can change over between an automatic mode and a manual manipulation mode, and a hydraulic pressure type speed change mechanism having a plurality of clutches, for example a twin clutch, is adopted. A hydraulic system <b>5</b> of the speed change gear <b>3</b> is provided between cylinders of the engine <b>2</b> disposed in a state in which they are opened forwardly and rearwardly in a V shape. Between the front and rear cylinders provided in the engine <b>2</b>, a throttle body <b>6</b> for accommodating a throttle valve <b>6</b><i>a </i>is provided above the hydraulic system <b>5</b>. The throttle body <b>6</b> includes an actuator <b>57</b>, such as a throttle motor, for the throttle valve <b>6</b><i>a </i>and a throttle valve opening sensor for detecting the opening of the throttle valve <b>6</b><i>a </i>in addition to the throttle valve <b>6</b>. A fuel injection valve <b>56</b> is attached to the upstream side of the throttle valve <b>6</b><i>a</i>, that is, to the air cleaner side. An air cleaner <b>7</b> for cleaning air to be supplied to the engine <b>2</b> through the throttle body <b>6</b> is provided further above the throttle body <b>6</b>. An ECU <b>41</b> is disposed in a recess formed at a front portion of the air cleaner <b>7</b>. Exhaust pipes <b>8</b> led out from the front cylinders and the rear cylinders of the engine <b>2</b> are connected to a muffler <b>9</b> disposed at a vehicle body rear portion. A radiator <b>10</b> in which engine cooling water is circulated is provided in front of the engine <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">A vehicle body frame <b>11</b> for supporting the engine <b>2</b>, speed change gear <b>3</b>, swing arm mechanism <b>4</b>, hydraulic system <b>5</b>, throttle body <b>6</b>, air cleaner <b>7</b>, exhaust pipes <b>8</b>, muffler <b>9</b> described above and so forth is provided. The vehicle body frame <b>11</b> includes a head pipe <b>12</b> provided at a vehicle body front portion and extending in an upward and downward direction in a rearwardly inclined posture, a pair of left and right main frames <b>13</b> joined to the head pipe <b>12</b> and extending in a vehicle body rearward direction, and a seat frame <b>14</b> coupled to the main frame <b>13</b> and extending in a vehicle body rearward direction. The engine <b>2</b> and so forth are suspended on the main frame <b>13</b>, and the swing arm <b>4</b> which has a shaft drive mechanism built therein is supported at a front portion thereof on the main frame <b>13</b> by a pivot <b>15</b> and is supported at an intermediate portion thereof on the seat frame <b>14</b> through a rear cushion <b>16</b>. The rear wheel WR is supported at a rear portion of the swing arm <b>4</b>. A side stand <b>17</b> and a main stand <b>18</b> are provided at a lower portion of the main frame <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">A front fork <b>19</b> is coupled to a lower portion of a steering shaft (not shown) which extends upwardly and downwardly through the head pipe <b>12</b>, and a steering handle bar <b>20</b> is coupled to a top ridge <b>80</b> provided at an upper end portion of the front fork <b>19</b>. Hydraulic master cylinders <b>81</b>L and <b>81</b>R for front and rear brakes are provided at left and right portions of the steering handle bar <b>20</b>, respectively, and an ignition switch <b>82</b> is disposed at a front portion of the center of the steering handle bar <b>20</b>. A front wheel WF is supported for rotation at a lower end of the front fork <b>19</b>. A brake disk <b>21</b> is provided for the front wheel WF, and a brake caliper <b>22</b> which hydraulically applies a braking action to the brake disk <b>21</b> is fixed to the front fork <b>19</b>. Further, the front fork <b>19</b> supports a front fender <b>23</b> for covering an upper portion of the front wheel WF.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Grips <b>24</b>L and <b>24</b>R are provided at left and right ends of the steering handle bar <b>20</b>, respectively, and the right side grip <b>24</b>R is configured as an acceleration grip which can be rotated for an acceleration operation. An accelerator opening sensor for detecting a rotational angle or accelerator opening of the grip <b>24</b>R is provided in a right side switch case <b>25</b>R. The detected accelerator opening is transmitted as a throttle valve opening instruction to an ECU hereinafter described through a harness <b>75</b> and is utilized for control of the engine <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">A left side switch case <b>25</b>L and the right side switch case <b>25</b>R are provided adjacent the grips <b>24</b>L and <b>24</b>R, respectively. Mirrors <b>26</b>L and <b>26</b>R are provided uprightly on the switch cases <b>25</b>L and <b>25</b>R, respectively. The knuckle guards <b>27</b>L and <b>27</b>R which cover the left and right grips <b>24</b>L and <b>24</b>R, respectively, are provided.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">A fuel tank <b>28</b> is placed on the main frame <b>13</b>, and a seat <b>29</b> which can include a driver's seat and a passenger seat integrated with each other is placed on the seat frame <b>14</b>. A rear fender <b>30</b> which is positioned above the rear wheel WR is attached to a lower portion of the seat frame <b>14</b>, and a tail lamp assembly <b>31</b> including a tail lamp, a rear winker or turn signal, a license lamp, and so forth, is attached to the rear fender <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">To the vehicle body frame <b>11</b>, a front cowl <b>32</b> and a rear cowl <b>33</b> which cover the outer side of the vehicle body frame <b>11</b> are attached. A front portion of the front cowl <b>32</b> is protected by a guard pipe <b>34</b> attached to the main frame <b>13</b>. A pair of left and right stays <b>35</b> extend forwardly from the head pipe <b>12</b>, and a head lamp <b>36</b>, a windshield <b>37</b>, front turn signals or winkers <b>38</b>L and <b>38</b>R and a meter apparatus <b>70</b> are attached by the stays <b>35</b>. The front cowl <b>32</b> is expanded at a front portion thereof so as to configure a head lamp cover portion <b>39</b> which protects the head lamp <b>36</b> from below. The meter apparatus <b>70</b> can be disposed between the left and right stays <b>35</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The front cowl <b>32</b> is configured such that it connects leftwardly and rightwardly rearwardly from the head lamp cover portion <b>39</b> and extends round from the left and the right to an upper portion of the front fork <b>19</b>. A traction control mode off switch (TCS off switch) is provided on an upper face of a site <b>32</b>L of the front cowl <b>32</b> below the handle bar forwardly of the left side switch case <b>25</b>L and the fuel tank <b>28</b> (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). The TCS off switch <b>40</b> is provided with an upper face thereof exposed from the site <b>32</b>L and is disposed for pushing manipulation. While the TCS off switch <b>40</b> is kept depressed by a rider, it controls a TCS input port to the ECU <b>41</b> to the low level to stop operation of traction control.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a wiring diagram between an engine ECU and peripheral apparatus. The ECU <b>41</b> includes a microcomputer and carries out traction control, ignition control, fuel injection control (FI control), throttle-by-wire control, meter displaying communication control, ABS control and so forth.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Various sensors to be used for control are provided. First, as sensors relating to the traction control, a grip opening sensor <b>42</b> for detecting a manipulation amount (accelerator opening) of the grip <b>24</b>R, a front wheel rotational speed sensor (FR sensor) <b>43</b> and a rear wheel rotational speed sensor (RR sensor) <b>44</b> are provided. The front and rear wheel rotational speed sensors <b>43</b> and <b>44</b> are attached to the front wheel WF and the rear wheel WR, respectively, and each detects a plurality of slits formed in a pulser ring which rotates in synchronism with the wheel and outputs an on-off signal (or a high-low signal) using the detection signal as a trigger. The wheel rotational speeds detected by the front and rear wheel rotational speed sensors <b>43</b> and are used also for the ABS control. As regards the traction control, the TCS off switch <b>40</b> for inhibiting the traction control is provided as described hereinabove.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">As sensors relating to the ignition and FI controls, an atmospheric air pressure sensor (PA sensor) <b>45</b>, an intake air negative pressure sensor (PB sensor) <b>46</b>, an intake air temperature sensor (TA sensor) <b>47</b>, a cooling water temperature sensor (TW sensor) <b>48</b>, an oxygen concentration sensor (O2 sensor) <b>49</b>, a crank angle sensor <b>50</b>, a shift stage sensor (gear position sensor) <b>51</b>, a knock sensor <b>52</b> and so forth are provided.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">For the throttle-by-wire control, not only the grip opening sensor <b>42</b> but also a throttle valve opening sensor <b>53</b> for detecting the throttle valve opening are provided.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The various controls carried out by the ECU <b>41</b> are not independent of each other but are carried out in an associated relationship; therefore, the sensors are not necessarily provided for exclusive use for the individual controls but detection information of the sensors can be utilized commonly among plural ones of the controls.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Further, as the peripheral apparatus which operate in accordance with an instruction outputted from the ECU <b>41</b> based on the detection information of the sensors, a fuel pump <b>54</b>, an ignition system <b>55</b>, a fuel injection valve <b>56</b>, a throttle motor (a DC brushless motor is used) <b>57</b>, and the meter apparatus <b>70</b> described hereinabove are provided.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">A fail process in the traction control carried out by the ECU <b>41</b> is described. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a block diagram showing principal functions of the ECU <b>41</b> for the fail control in the traction control. A slip ratio decision section <b>60</b> normally calculates a difference (that is, a slip ratio) between the rotational speeds of the front wheel WF and the rear wheel WR detected by the front and rear wheel rotational speed sensors <b>43</b> and <b>44</b>, respectively, and urges, when the slip ratio exceeds a permissible slip ratio set in advance, a throttle reduction section <b>59</b> to cause a throttle-by-wire (TBW) controlling section <b>61</b> to carry out motor driving control instruction for reducing the throttle valve opening.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The throttle-by-wire controlling section <b>61</b> drives the throttle opening/closing motor <b>57</b> so that the slip ratio converges to the permissible slip ratio thereby to carry out torque suppression. If the slip ratio is extremely high, then the time between fuel injections may be subtracted to assist torque suppression.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">A traction fail controlling section <b>62</b> detects abnormality of the various sensors (integrally indicated as &#x201c;sensors SS&#x201d; in the figure) to carry out a traction fail process. In the traction fail process, if failure of any sensor is detected during traction control, then the throttle valve opening is reduced to an idling speed opening. A accelerator full close decision section <b>63</b> detects that a fully closed state of the accelerator opening is detected by the grip opening sensor <b>42</b> in a state in which a fail process of reducing the throttle valve opening is being carried out, and inputs a traction fail stopping instruction to a fail mode selection section <b>64</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The fail mode selection section <b>64</b> changes over the processing by the traction fail controlling section <b>62</b> to processing by a normal fail controlling section <b>65</b> in response to the traction fail stopping instruction. The normal fail controlling section <b>65</b> carries out a normal fail process different from the traction fail process. In particular, in the normal fail process, the throttle-by-wire process is stopped but normal throttle control is carried out. More particularly, an electromagnetic clutch <b>66</b> is provided as turning on/off means for disconnecting a throttle cable, which transmits rotation of the acceleration grip <b>24</b>R to the throttle valve, in the throttle-by-wire control but connecting the throttle cable in the normal throttle control. The electromagnetic clutch <b>66</b> may be disposed such that it can connect and disconnect the throttle cable in the throttle body <b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Then, in the normal fail process, the electromagnetic clutch <b>66</b> is operated to the connection position to connect the throttle cable provided between the acceleration grip <b>24</b>R and the throttle valve to carry out ordinary throttle control wherein the throttle valve is opened or closed in response to the manipulation opening of the acceleration grip <b>24</b>R through the throttle cable. An indicator controlling section <b>67</b> carries out turning on, flickering and turning off control of a traction indicator <b>68</b> provided on the meter apparatus <b>70</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In the normal fail process, if any of the front and rear wheel rotational speed sensors <b>43</b> and <b>44</b>, PB sensor <b>46</b>, TA sensor, TW sensor <b>48</b> and shift stage sensor fails, then the normal throttle control is carried out, but if any of the fuel pump <b>54</b>, a return spring of the throttle valve and a throttle-by-wire relay (a relay for supplying operation power from a vehicle-carried battery to the throttle-by-wire controlling apparatus) is placed into a failed state, then the traction control is stopped and the throttle valve opening is controlled to a scheduled low opening (for example, the idling opening). Failure of the return spring is a state in which the throttle valve does not return to the fully closed position, and a decision of the failure can be made depending upon the output of the throttle valve opening sensor <b>53</b>. Meanwhile, failure of the throttle-by-wire relay can be decided from an abnormal voltage between positions across the relay.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an operation timing chart relating to the traction fail process. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the axis of abscissa is the time axis, and the axis of ordinate indicates the acceleration opening and the throttle valve opening. After the traction control is started (timing t<b>0</b>), the throttle valve opening &#x3b8;TH is limited to a TCS throttle valve opening &#x3b8;THTCS smaller than a throttle valve opening &#x3b8;A determined from the accelerator opening &#x3b1;A irrespective of the grip opening &#x3b1;A. While the acceleration grip <b>24</b>R remains open, this TCS throttle valve opening &#x3b8;THTCS is maintained. If failure occurs during this traction control (timing t<b>1</b>), then the TCS throttle valve opening &#x3b8;THTCS is reduced to the idling opening &#x3b8;THidle. At this time, it is indicated by the traction indicator <b>68</b> that failure has occurred and the throttle valve opening is being suppressed. If the user manipulates the acceleration grip <b>24</b>R to a position at which the throttle valve opening &#x3b1;A is the fully closed state in response to the indication (timing t<b>2</b>), then changeover from the traction fail control to the normal fail control is carried out, and control for converging the throttle valve opening to the throttle valve opening &#x3b8;TH corresponding to the accelerator opening &#x3b1;A is carried out.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flow chart of a process (TCS fail process) corresponding to the traction fail operation of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, at step S<b>1</b>, it is decided whether or not failure has occurred. If it is decided that failure has occurred, then the processing advances from step S<b>1</b> to step S<b>2</b>, at which it is decided whether or not traction control is being executed. If traction control is being executed, then the processing advances from step S<b>2</b> to step S<b>3</b>, at which traction control of reducing the throttle valve opening &#x3b8;TH to the idling opening &#x3b8;THidle is carried out. If traction control is not being executed, then the processing advances from step S<b>2</b> to step S<b>5</b>, at which normal fail control is carried out. At step S<b>4</b>, it is determined whether the acceleration grip <b>24</b>R is in the fully closed state (whether the accelerator opening is fully closed) or not. If the acceleration grip <b>24</b>R is in the fully closed state, then the processing advances from step S<b>4</b> to step S<b>5</b>, at which normal fail control is carried out. If the acceleration grip <b>24</b>R is not in the fully closed state, the processing of this flow chart is ended, and the processing returns to a main routine.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a front elevational view of the meter apparatus <b>70</b> and shows also an enlarged view of essential part. The meter apparatus <b>70</b> includes, in addition to the traction indicator <b>68</b>, a vehicle speedometer <b>71</b>, an engine tachometer <b>72</b>, a shift stage display unit <b>73</b>, left and right direction indicators <b>74</b>L and <b>74</b>R and so forth. The traction indicator <b>68</b> includes a traction-on (TCS) indicator <b>68</b><i>a </i>and a traction-off (TCS-OFF) indicator <b>68</b><i>b </i>each configured from an indicator such as an LED.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a view illustrating lighting conditions of the traction fail control indicator <b>68</b>. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, before the ignition switch is manipulated into an on state and a predetermined initial diagnosis of the system is completed, both of the TCS indicator <b>68</b><i>a </i>and the TCS-OFF indicator <b>68</b><i>b </i>are on, and during ordinary traveling of the motorcycle <b>1</b>, both of the TCS indicator <b>68</b><i>a </i>and the TCS-OFF indicator <b>68</b><i>b </i>are off. Then, during traction control, the TCS indicator <b>68</b><i>a </i>is on and the TCS-OFF indicator <b>68</b><i>b </i>is off, but if the TCS off switch <b>40</b> is depressed, then the TCS indicator <b>68</b><i>a </i>is turned off and the TCS-OFF indicator <b>68</b><i>b </i>is turned on. Further, during traction fail control or when disconnection failure of the communication line between the ECU <b>38</b> and the meter apparatus <b>70</b> occurs, the TCS indicator <b>68</b><i>a </i>is turned on and the TCS-OFF indicator <b>68</b><i>b </i>is turned off. It is to be noted that, if the TCS off switch <b>40</b> is manipulated in a state in which traction control can be operated, the operation state of the traction control changes to a state in which traction control is rendered inoperative. However, if the TCS off switch <b>40</b> is manipulated while the traction control is in an inoperative state, then the traction control is placed into an operable state and the TCS indicator <b>68</b><i>a </i>and the TCS-OFF indicator <b>68</b><i>b </i>are turned off.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">If a mark having a pattern same as a mark added to the TCS-OFF indicator <b>68</b><i>b </i>is added to a manipulation portion (depression portion) of the TCS off switch <b>40</b>, then an incorrect manipulation can be prevented.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF REFERENCE SYMBOLS</heading>
<p id="p-0054" num="0000">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0002-0001" num="0053"><b>1</b> . . . Motorcycle, <b>24</b>R . . . Acceleration grip, <b>40</b> . . . TCS off switch, <b>42</b> . . . Grip opening sensor, <b>57</b> . . . Actuator, <b>59</b> . . . Throttle reduction section, <b>60</b> . . . Slip ratio decision section, <b>61</b> . . . Throttle-by-wire controlling section, <b>68</b> . . . Indicator</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A traction controlling apparatus, comprising:
<claim-text>a grip opening sensor configured to detect a manipulation opening of an acceleration grip;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a throttle-by-wire controlling unit configured to drive an actuator in response to the manipulation opening of the acceleration grip to control an opening of a throttle valve;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a slip detection unit configured to detect a slip state of a driving wheel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fail detection unit configured to detect failure of an engine controlling system;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a throttle reduction unit configured to reduce the throttle valve opening to a first predetermined value by the throttle-by-wire controlling unit in response to detection of a slip state; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a traction fail controlling unit configured to decrease, by the throttle-by-wire controlling unit, lower than the first predetermined value, when failure of the engine controlling system is detected while the throttle valve opening is reduced to the first predetermined value, wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>when it is detected that predetermined closing manipulation is carried out for the acceleration grip during a traction fail process in which the throttle valve opening is reduced to the second predetermined value by the traction fail controlling unit, the traction fail process is ended and throttle control based on the throttle valve opening in response to the acceleration manipulation opening is enabled.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The traction controlling apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second predetermined value comprises an idling throttle valve opening.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The traction controlling apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a traction indicator configured to indicate that the driving power is being suppressed and the traction fail process is being carried out.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The traction controlling apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the traction indicator is provided in a meter apparatus which is configured to indicate a driving state of a vehicle and is configured from a traction ON indicating lamp which flickers during traction control and is turned off during stopping of the traction control and a traction OFF indicating lamp which is turned off during the traction control but is turned on during stopping of the traction control, and, during the traction fail process, the traction ON indicating lamp is turned on and the traction OFF indicating lamp is turned off.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The traction controlling apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the predetermined closing manipulation is a manipulation of the acceleration grip to a fully closed position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The traction controlling apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a transmission unit configured to transmit a manipulation of the acceleration grip to a throttle valve through an electromagnetic connection unit,
<claim-text>wherein when it is detected that the predetermined closing manipulation is carried out for the acceleration grip during the traction fail process in which the throttle valve opening is reduced to the second predetermined value, the traction fail process is stopped and the electromagnetic connection unit is biased to place the transmission unit into a connected state to enable throttle control based on the throttle valve opening in response to the acceleration manipulation opening.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The traction controlling apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein throttle valve opening control is executed when a slip ratio of the driving wheel is lower than a predetermined value, and if the slip ratio becomes equal to or higher than the predetermined value, then fuel injection reduction control irrespective of the throttle valve opening is executed in addition to the throttle valve opening control, and where the traction fail process is executed in a state in which the slip ratio is equal to or higher than the predetermined value, the fuel injection reduction control is ended and fuel injection control in response to the throttle valve opening is carried out.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A traction controlling apparatus, comprising:
<claim-text>sensor means for detecting a manipulation opening of an acceleration grip;</claim-text>
<claim-text>throttle-by-wire controlling means for driving an actuator in response to the manipulation opening of the acceleration grip to control an opening of a throttle valve;</claim-text>
<claim-text>slip detection means for detecting a slip state of a driving wheel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>fail detection means for detecting failure of an engine controlling system;</claim-text>
<claim-text>throttle reduction means for reducing the opening of the throttle valve to a first predetermined value by the throttle-by-wire controlling means in response to detection of a slip state; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>traction fail controlling means for decreasing, by the throttle-by-wire controlling means, the opening of the throttle valve to a second predetermined value, lower than the first predetermined value, when failure of the engine controlling system is detected while the throttle valve opening is reduced to the first predetermined value,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein when it is detected that predetermined closing manipulation is carried out for the acceleration grip during a traction fail process in which the opening of the throttle valve is reduced to the second predetermined value by the traction fail controlling means, the traction fail process is ended and throttle control based on the opening of the throttle valve in response to the acceleration manipulation opening is enabled.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The traction controlling apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the second predetermined value comprises an idling throttle valve opening.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The traction controlling apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising traction indicator means for indicating that the driving power is being suppressed and the traction fail process is being carried out.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The traction controlling apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the traction indicator means is provided in a meter means for indicating a driving state of a vehicle, and is configured from a traction ON indicating lamp which flickers during traction control but is turned off during stopping of the traction control and a traction OFF indicating lamp which is turned off during the traction control but is turned on during stopping of the traction control, and during the traction fail process, the traction ON indicating lamp is turned on and the traction OFF indicating lamp is turned off.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The traction controlling apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the predetermined closing manipulation is a manipulation of the acceleration grip to a fully closed position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The traction controlling apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising transmission means for transmitting a manipulation of the acceleration grip to a throttle valve through an electromagnetic connection means,
<claim-text>wherein when it is detected that the predetermined closing manipulation is carried out for the acceleration grip during the traction process in which the opening of the throttle valve is reduced to the second predetermined value, the traction fail process is stopped and the electromagnetic connection unit is biased to place the transmission unit into a connected state to enable throttle control based on the opening of the throttle valve in response to the acceleration manipulation opening.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The traction controlling apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the throttle valve opening control is executed when a slip value of the driving wheel is lower than a predetermined value, and if the slip ratio becomes equal to or higher than the predetermined value, then fuel injection reduction control irrespective of the opening of the throttle valve is executed in addition to the throttle valve opening control, and, where the traction fail process is executed in a state in which the slip ratio is equal to or higher than the predetermined value, the fuel injection reduction control is ended and the fuel injection control in response to the opening of the throttle valve is carried out.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A traction controlling method, comprising:
<claim-text>detecting a manipulation opening of an acceleration grip;</claim-text>
<claim-text>driving an actuator in response to the manipulation opening of the acceleration grip, to control an opening of a throttle valve;</claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting a slip state of a driving wheel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting failure of an engine controlling system;</claim-text>
<claim-text>reducing the throttle valve opening to a first predetermined value in response to detection of a slip state;</claim-text>
<claim-text>decreasing, when failure of the engine controlling system is detected while the throttle valve opening is reduced to the first predetermined value, the throttle valve opening to a second predetermined value, lower than the first predetermined value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>ending a traction fail process when it is detected that predetermined closing manipulation is carried out for the acceleration grip during the traction fail process in which the throttle valve opening is reduced to the second predetermined value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>enabling throttle control based on the throttle valve opening in response to the manipulation opening.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The traction controlling method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, further comprising indicating that the driving power is being suppressed and the traction fail process is being carried out.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The traction controlling method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, further comprising indicating a driving state of a vehicle with a traction ON indicating lamp which flickers during traction control and is turned off during stopping of the traction control and a traction OFF indicating lamp which is turned off during the traction control but is turned on during stopping of the traction control, and wherein during the traction fail process, the traction ON indicating lamp is turned on and the traction OFF indicating lamp is turned off.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The traction control method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the detecting of the manipulation opening of the acceleration grip comprises detecting a transmitted manipulation of the acceleration grip to a throttle valve through an electromagnetic connection unit, and wherein when it is detected that the predetermined closing manipulation is carried out for the acceleration grip during the traction fail process in which the throttle valve opening is reduced to the second predetermined value, the traction fail process is stopped and the electromagnetic connection unit is biased to place the transmission unit into a connected state to enable throttle control based on the throttle valve opening in response to the acceleration manipulation opening.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The traction controlling method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein throttle valve opening control is executed when a slip ratio of the driving wheel is lower than a predetermined value, and if the slip ratio becomes equal to or higher than the predetermined value, then fuel injection reduction control irrespective of the throttle valve opening is executed in addition to the throttle valve opening control, and where the traction fail process is executed in a state in which the slip ratio is equal to or higher than the predetermined value, the fuel injection reduction control is ended and fuel injection control in response to the throttle valve opening is carried out. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
