<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08621978-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08621978</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12672293</doc-number>
<date>20080625</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>FR</country>
<doc-number>07 05899</doc-number>
<date>20070820</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>930</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>15</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>26</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 92 23</main-classification>
<further-classification> 92 29</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Actuator for opening an aircraft engine nacelle cowl</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2887991</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Driskel</name>
<date>19590500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3022771</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Chace</name>
<date>19620200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3583288</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Nepp</name>
<date>19710600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6227485</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Porte</name>
<date>20010500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7216581</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>McAuley</name>
<date>20070500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 92 24</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0168010</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Cleland</name>
<date>20050800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>AU</country>
<doc-number>438013</doc-number>
<date>19730700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>FR</country>
<doc-number>2882087</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20060800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00009">
<othercit>International Search Report PCT/FR2008/000895; Dated May 11, 2009.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>5</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 92 15</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 92 23</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 92 24</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 92 25</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 92 26</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 92 29</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 92 30</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 92114</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120125191</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120524</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Moradell-Casellas</last-name>
<first-name>Pierre</first-name>
<address>
<city>Saint Georges des Groseillers</city>
<country>FR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>FR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lederle</last-name>
<first-name>Stephane</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fontainebleau</city>
<country>FR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>FR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Moradell-Casellas</last-name>
<first-name>Pierre</first-name>
<address>
<city>Saint Georges des Groseillers</city>
<country>FR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lederle</last-name>
<first-name>Stephane</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fontainebleau</city>
<country>FR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Brinks Gilson &#x26; Lione</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Aircelle</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Gonfreville l'Orcher</city>
<country>FR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Leslie</last-name>
<first-name>Michael</first-name>
<department>3745</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/FR2008/000895</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20080625</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20100205</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2009/024666</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20090226</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Actuator (V) for opening an aircraft nacelle cowl (<b>7</b>), comprising a dead travel device (<b>19</b>), characterized in that it comprises means (<b>42</b><i>a, </i><b>42</b><i>b, </i><b>43</b>) for blocking the dead travel device (<b>19</b>) when this actuator (V) is extended.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="205.32mm" wi="84.07mm" file="US08621978-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="181.36mm" wi="159.34mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621978-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="236.14mm" wi="163.66mm" file="US08621978-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The disclosure relates to an actuator for opening an aircraft engine nacelle cowl and to a nacelle equipped with at least one such actuator.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">As is known per se, an aircraft engine nacelle comprises at least one cowl able to move between a service position, in which this cowl covers the engine, and a maintenance position, in which this cowl is distanced from the engine and thus allows the technician to work on the engine or on the underside of the cowl, to carry out maintenance operation.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Given the high weight of such a cowl, particularly on large nacelles such as those used on the Airbus A380, it is absolutely essential that means for assisting the opening of this cowl be provided.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">These assistance means, often known even in other languages by their English-language abbreviation PCOS (which stands for &#x201c;Powered Cowl Operating System&#x201d;), generally comprise at least one hydraulic or electric actuator which can be made to open or to close the cowl.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">As is known per se, an actuator such as this comprises, at its end collaborating with the cowl, a device often known, even in other languages, by its English name as &#x201c;free play&#x201d; device, which always allows the end of this actuator a small additional travel for a given extension of the actuator.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The purpose of this free play is, on the one hand, to avoid compression/tension forces being transmitted to the actuator in a flight situation as the cowl experiences deformation associated with particular pressure profiles and, on the other hand, to allow easy manual closure of the cowl at the end of the maintenance operations in spite of the friction generated by the tolerances on the various components which interact.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">A jury strut or prop is also provided so as to block the cowl in the open position and relieve the actuator of the weight of this cowl. This jury strut is fitted by hand, by the technician, and removed by the same just before the cowl is closed.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In practice, just after having opened the cowl using the actuator and after having fitted the jury strut, the technician causes the actuator to retract slightly so as to make sure that the weight of the cowl is indeed being borne by the jury strut, rather than by the actuator: when this is done, the free play device extends at least partially.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Now, the jury strut may sometimes break under the weight of the cowl and/or of the loads applied by the actuator instructed to close by the operator; because of the presence of the free play device which is initially in an at least partially extended position, there will be a veritable dropping of the cowl onto the actuator, from a height that corresponds to the extension of the free play device.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">This drop comes as a great shock to the technician working between the cowl and the engine, and may even injure him. In addition, this sudden sharp transfer of the weight of the cowl onto the actuator may damage this actuator because of the additional dynamic effect introduced.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The disclosure provides an actuator for opening an aircraft nacelle cowl comprising a free play device, notable in that it comprises means to block this free play device when this actuator is extended.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Thanks to these blocking means, the free play device will form just one entity with the body of the actuator, which means that there is no longer any risk of the cowl suddenly dropping and generating a dynamic effect if the jury strut should break.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to optional features of the actuator according to the invention, considered alone or in combination:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0002-0001" num="0014">said blocking means are designed to block said free play device in the retracted position: such blocking means make it possible to prevent any extension of the free play device during the slight retraction of the actuator performed once the jury strut has been fitted; hence, the weight of the cowl can be transferred directly to the actuator, rather than to the means that block the free play device;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0002" num="0015">said actuator comprises a cylinder and said free play device comprises a yoke mounted such that it can slide axially at the end of said cylinder;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0003" num="0016">said cylinder is telescopically mounted on an inner rod, said blocking means comprise a core and means of locking said yoke with respect to said cylinder, this core being mounted such that it can slide inside said yoke against the action of elastic means interposed between this yoke and this core, and being able to deactivate said locking means when it is pushed by said rod inside said yoke, and to activate these locking means when it is no longer being pushed by said rod;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0004" num="0017">said locking means comprise a ball latch comprising cylindrical housings formed in said yoke, an annular housing formed in a plug mounted at the end of said cylinder and having a radial thickness smaller than the diameter of said balls and a chamfered part secured to said core, able to push said balls from said cylindrical housings toward said annular housing when said core emerges from said yoke under the action of said elastic means so that said balls block the outward sliding of said yoke with respect to said plug;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0005" num="0018">said blocking means comprise a stud connected fixedly to said cylinder and able to engage with a fitting secured to said cowl once said cowl has opened through a certain angle, this engagement having the effect of keeping said yoke and said cylinder in the retracted position relative to one another;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0006" num="0019">said actuator is electric,</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0007" num="0020">said actuator is hydraulic.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0021">The present invention also relates to an aircraft engine nacelle notable in that it is equipped with an actuator in accordance with the forgoing.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0022">Other features and advantages of the present invention will become apparent in the light of the description which will follow, and from studying the attached figures in which:</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of an aircraft engine and nacelle assembly, the cowls of this nacelle being depicted in the maintenance position;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> schematically depicts the actuator V used to open the cowl of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, in the retracted position;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> depicts a first alternative form of this actuator equipped with a device for blocking the &#x201c;free play&#x201d;, shown in axial section through the end of this actuator that collaborates with the cowl;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> schematically depicts a second alternative form of this actuator equipped with a device for block the &#x201c;free play&#x201d;, in the extended position; and</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective depiction of that part of this actuator which collaborates with the cowl, firstly in the retracted position and secondly in the extended position.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0028">Reference is made to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> which shows an aircraft turbojet engine placed inside a nacelle of which the front part <b>3</b>, a cowl <b>5</b> of the intermediate part, and a cowl <b>7</b> of the rear part of this nacelle are visible.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0029">The cowls <b>5</b> and <b>7</b> are depicted in the maintenance position, that is to say in a position where they open upward, providing access for a technician to the turbojet engine <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0030">As is known per se, the cowl <b>5</b> is designed to cover that part of the engine <b>1</b> which comprises a fan, and the cowl <b>7</b> may comprise thrust reversal means, such as a cascade-type thrust reverser.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0031">The cowls <b>5</b> and <b>7</b> are in fact half-cowls, that is to say that they each surround just half the circumference of the turbojet engine <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0032">Actuating the cowl <b>7</b> from its operating position in which it covers the rear of the turbojet engine <b>1</b>, to its open position visible in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, is done by means of at least one electric or hydraulic actuator V that the technician can operate.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0033">When this actuator V is in the extended position, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the cowl <b>7</b> is open and can be kept in this position by means of a jury strut C, positioned by hand by the technician between the turbojet engine <b>1</b> and the cowl <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0034">Reference is now made to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, in which the actuator V is depicted in the retracted position, and it may be seen that this actuator V collaborates with the cowl <b>7</b> via a yoke <b>9</b> mounted such that it can slide at the end of this actuator.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0035">In the special case in which the actuator <b>2</b> is an electric actuator, the layout of the various components situated in the end of this actuator which collaborates with the cowl <b>7</b> can be appreciated by studying <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0036">That figure shows that the actuator V comprises an outer cylinder <b>11</b> mounted such that it can slide with respect to a rod <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0037">More specifically, the rod <b>13</b> is a threaded rod, able to be turned by an electric motor secured to the turbojet engine <b>1</b> (not depicted).</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0038">Mounted on this threaded rod is a nut (not depicted) which is prevented from rotating with respect to this rod and prevented from effecting any axial translational movement relative to the cylinder <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0039">As can therefore be appreciated, the turning of the rod <b>13</b> has the effect of causing an axial translational movement of said nut, and therefore of the cylinder <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0040">This electric device for extending and retracting the actuator V is often known as a &#x201c;ball screw&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0041">The cylinder <b>11</b> is blanked off, at its end situated near the cowl <b>7</b>, by a plug <b>17</b> in which there is slidingly mounted a yoke <b>19</b> comprising an eye <b>21</b>, via which the actuator can be attached to the cowl <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0042">In its part <b>23</b> able to penetrate inside the plug <b>17</b>, the yoke <b>19</b> comprises cylindrical housings <b>25</b> in which the balls <b>27</b> are located.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0043">Facing these cylindrical housings when the yoke <b>19</b> is in its retracted position visible in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, there is an annular housing <b>29</b> formed in the plug <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0044">In its upper part, that is to say in its part closest to the depicted end of the actuator V, the annular housing <b>29</b> has a chamfered part <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0045">A core <b>33</b> is mounted inside the yoke <b>19</b> such that it can slide against the action of a spring <b>35</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0046">This core <b>33</b> itself comprises a chamfered part <b>37</b> able to collaborate with the balls <b>27</b> in a way which will be explained later.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0047">It may be noted that the core <b>33</b> passes through an orifice <b>39</b> formed in the plug <b>17</b>, via which it can collaborate with the end <b>41</b> of the threaded rod <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0048">The way in which this first alternative form of the actuator V works is as follows.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0049">The position of the actuator V depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> corresponds to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, that is to say that this actuator is in the retracted position: this position is the position that corresponds to the cowl <b>7</b> being in the closed position.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0050">In this position, the rod <b>13</b> is practically in abutment against the plug <b>17</b>, and exerts a thrusting force on the core <b>33</b> against the action of the elastic means <b>35</b>; the chamfer <b>37</b> does not collaborate with the balls <b>27</b>, and these balls remain in the annular housing <b>25</b> of the yoke <b>19</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0051">In this configuration, these balls <b>27</b> therefore do not in any way block the sliding of the yoke <b>19</b> inside the plug <b>17</b>: this yoke <b>19</b> can therefore slide freely inside this plug, thus allowing the cowl <b>7</b> a certain amount of play relative to the actuator V.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0052">This play on the one hand allows the deformation forces inherent to particular pressure profiles in flight to be transferred to this actuator V and on the other hand allows the cowl to be closed correctly in spite of the tolerances on the various components involved during this closure.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0053">When a technician wishes to open the cowl <b>7</b> so as to gain access to the turbojet engine <b>1</b>, he operates the electric motor which turns the threaded rod <b>13</b>, this turning having the effect of causing the cylinder <b>11</b> to slide relative to this rod, and therefore of bringing the actuator V into its extended position.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0054">As this happens, the end <b>41</b> of the rod <b>13</b> moves away from the plug <b>17</b>, by virtue of which the core <b>33</b> moves away from the yoke <b>19</b> toward the inside of the cylinder <b>11</b>, under the action notably of the spring <b>35</b>, and does so until the chamfered part <b>37</b> of this core <b>33</b> pushes radially on the balls <b>27</b> to cause these balls to move from the cylindrical housings <b>25</b> of the yoke <b>19</b> toward the annular housing <b>29</b> of the plug <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0055">The radial width of the annular housing <b>29</b> is smaller than the diameter of the balls <b>27</b>, which means that these balls cannot completely leave the cylindrical housings <b>25</b> formed in the yoke <b>19</b>: these balls therefore continue to straddle these two housings, thus blocking the outward sliding movement of the yoke <b>19</b> with respect to the plug <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0056">Thus, when the panel <b>7</b> is fully open, the yoke <b>19</b> is locked in terms of translational movement with respect to the actuator <b>11</b>: these two components then act as a single one-piece component.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0057">Thus, when the technician comes to position the safety jury strut C between the turbojet engine <b>1</b> and the panel <b>7</b>, and retracts the actuator V slightly, there will be no possibility of any travel of the yoke <b>19</b> with respect to the cylinder <b>11</b>, nor will there any longer be any risk of the cowl <b>7</b> dropping suddenly and sharply should this jury strut break.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0058">In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, the yoke <b>19</b> is blocked in the retracted position relative to the cylinder <b>11</b> by simplified mechanical means.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0059">It will be noted that, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the references a and b relate to the actuator V when respectively in the retracted position (that is to say the cowl <b>7</b> closed position) and in the extended position (that is to say the cowl <b>7</b> open position), the two positions of this actuator being depicted simultaneously in this figure.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0060">As may be seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, the cylinder <b>11</b> is equipped, in its part situated near the yoke <b>19</b>, with a finger <b>42</b> able to collaborate with a fitting <b>43</b> secured to the cowl <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0061">More specifically, the geometry of the assembly is such that when the cowl <b>7</b> is closed, the finger <b>42</b> is distant from the fitting <b>43</b>, thus allowing the small translational movements of the yoke <b>19</b> with respect to the cylinder V.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0062">By contrast, when the cowl <b>7</b> opens, the finger <b>42</b> engages with the fitting <b>43</b>, and this prevents any relative sliding of the yoke <b>19</b> with respect to the cylinder <b>11</b>, thus providing the blocking desired for maintenance operations.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0063">Of course, the present invention is not in any way restricted to the embodiments described and depicted, which have been provided simply by way of example.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An actuator for opening an aircraft nacelle cowl comprising:
<claim-text>a cylinder;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a free play device comprising a yoke mounted such that it can slide axially at an end of said cylinder; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>blocking means of the free play device positioned in a retracted position when the actuator is extended,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said cylinder is telescopically mounted on an inner rod, wherein said blocking means comprise a core and locking means of said yoke with respect to said cylinder, wherein the core is mounted such that it can slide inside said yoke against action of elastic means interposed between the yoke and the core, and wherein the core is able to deactivate said locking means when it is pushed by said rod inside said yoke, and to activate the locking means when it is no longer being pushed by said rod.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The actuator as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said locking means comprise a ball latch comprising cylindrical housings formed in said yoke, an annular housing formed in a plug mounted at the end of said cylinder and having a radial thickness smaller than a diameter of said balls and a chamfered part secured to said core, able to push said balls from said cylindrical housings toward said annular housing when said core emerges from said yoke under action of said elastic means so that said balls block an outward sliding of said yoke with respect to said plug.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The actuator as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said blocking means comprise a stud connected fixedly to said cylinder and able to engage with a fitting secured to said cowl once said cowl has opened through a certain angle, this engagement keeping said yoke and said cylinder in a retracted position relative to one another.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The actuator as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein it is electric.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. An aircraft engine nacelle, wherein it comprises at least one actuator as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
