<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624390-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624390</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13514610</doc-number>
<date>20101208</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="regional">
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>09252759</doc-number>
<date>20091210</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>23</main-group>
<subgroup>34</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257724</main-classification>
<further-classification>257774</further-classification>
<further-classification>257777</further-classification>
<further-classification>257E23065</further-classification>
<further-classification>257E21499</further-classification>
<further-classification>438107</further-classification>
<further-classification>438109</further-classification>
<further-classification>361749</further-classification>
<further-classification>361810</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e61">Packaging an electronic device</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6208521</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Nakatsuka</name>
<date>20010300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2001/0006252</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kim et al.</name>
<date>20010700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0167817</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Damberg</name>
<date>20050800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257698</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0230154</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Nakayama</name>
<date>20071000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1 119 049</doc-number>
<kind>A2</kind>
<date>20010700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00006">
<othercit>International Search Report issued in corresponding International application No. PCT/EP2010/069214, mailed Feb. 7, 2011.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00007">
<othercit>Written Opinion of the International Searching Authority issued in corresponding International application No. PCT/ EP2010/069214, mailed Feb. 7, 2011.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00008">
<othercit>Scheifers, Steven M. et al., &#x201c;A Novel Method of Minimizing Printed Wire Board Warpage&#x201d;, Motorola Technical Developments, Motorola Inc., Schaumberg, IL, US, vol. 28, Aug. 1, 1996, pp. 50-55, XP000638420, ISSN: 0887-5286.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>2</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257724</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257774</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257777</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E23065</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E21499</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438107</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438109</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>361749</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>361810</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>11</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>14</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120261814</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121018</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Slavov</last-name>
<first-name>Nedialko</first-name>
<address>
<city>Zurich</city>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CH</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Slavov</last-name>
<first-name>Nedialko</first-name>
<address>
<city>Zurich</city>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Patent Portfolio Builders, PLLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>ST-Ericsson SA</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Plan-les-Ouates</city>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Ho</last-name>
<first-name>Tu-Tu</first-name>
<department>2818</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/EP2010/069214</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20101208</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20120608</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2011/070087</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20110616</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An electronic device comprises a plurality of integrated circuit dies mounted on different areas of a carrier. The carrier is folded into a plurality of layers, each layer comprising one of the different areas of the carrier and one of the integrated circuit dies, such that the plurality of integrated circuit dies form a stack. Adjacent surfaces of neighboring layers are fixed together, for example by an adhesive layer, and the folded carrier and the integrated circuit dies are embedded in a molded material.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="99.14mm" wi="158.67mm" file="US08624390-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="102.79mm" wi="180.34mm" file="US08624390-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="106.93mm" wi="150.54mm" file="US08624390-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="108.29mm" wi="149.18mm" file="US08624390-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="108.29mm" wi="156.63mm" file="US08624390-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="243.16mm" wi="133.52mm" file="US08624390-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="241.05mm" wi="145.71mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624390-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="249.26mm" wi="154.60mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624390-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="194.06mm" wi="92.63mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624390-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="135.55mm" wi="173.65mm" file="US08624390-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="229.53mm" wi="139.62mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624390-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="157.31mm" wi="153.25mm" file="US08624390-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present disclosure relates to an electronic device and a method of manufacturing an electronic device. In particular, but not exclusively, the disclosure relates to packaging a plurality of integrated circuit dies in a single electronic device.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND TO THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">There are various ways of packaging a plurality of integrated circuit dies in a single electronic device. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, in a first example according to the prior art, an electronic device <b>10</b> comprises first and second integrated circuit dies <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> mounted side by side on a substrate <b>13</b>. The first and second integrated circuit dies <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> are provided on the substrate <b>13</b> in a housing <b>14</b> and the substrate <b>13</b> is mounted on a printed circuit board (PCB) <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Electrically conductive elements <b>16</b> extend through the substrate <b>13</b> from a surface of the substrate <b>13</b> facing the first and second integrated circuit dies <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> to a surface of the substrate <b>13</b> facing the PCB <b>15</b>. Electrically conductive bumps <b>17</b> are provided on surfaces of the first and second integrated circuit dies <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> facing the substrate <b>13</b> and the first and second integrated circuit dies <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> are positioned such that the electrically conductive bumps <b>17</b> are each in contact with a respective one of the electrically conductive elements <b>16</b>. The substrate <b>13</b> has solder balls <b>18</b>, forming a so-called ball grid array, on the surface of the substrate <b>13</b> facing the PCB <b>15</b>, the solder balls <b>18</b> each being in contact with a respective one of the electrically conductive elements <b>16</b>. The PCB <b>15</b> has electrically conductive tracks <b>19</b> and the substrate <b>13</b> and the PCB <b>15</b> are positioned such that the solder balls <b>18</b> are each in contact with a respective one of the electrically conductive tracks <b>19</b>. Some of the electrically conductive tracks <b>19</b> of the PCB <b>15</b> are arranged to couple the first and second integrated circuit dies <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> to other electronic devices (not shown) and others are arranged to couple the first and second integrated circuit dies <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> to one another. Only a subset of the electrically conductive elements <b>16</b> and electrically conductive tracks <b>19</b> typically required are shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> for clarity.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A problem with the electronic device <b>10</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is that placing the first and second integrated circuit dies <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> side by side increases the width of the electronic device <b>10</b>. In particular, increases in the size of the substrate <b>13</b> and the PCB <b>14</b> increase the size and cost of the electronic device <b>10</b> such that the electronic device <b>10</b> is not suitable for many applications.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, in a second example according to the prior art, an electronic device <b>20</b> similar to the electronic device <b>10</b> of the first example has the second integrated circuit die <b>12</b> mounted on top of the first integrated circuit die <b>11</b>. In other words, the first integrated circuit die <b>11</b> is mounted on the substrate <b>13</b> and the second integrated circuit die <b>12</b> is mounted on a surface of the first integrated circuit die <b>11</b> facing away from the substrate <b>13</b>. For the second integrated circuit die <b>12</b>, instead of the electrically conductive bumps <b>17</b> being provided on the surface facing the substrate <b>13</b>, wires <b>21</b> are provided that extend from the surface facing away from the substrate <b>13</b> to the electrically conductive elements <b>16</b> of the substrate <b>13</b>. This allows the first and second integrated circuit dies <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> to be packaged in the electronic device <b>20</b> without any a significant increase in the width of the electronic device <b>20</b>. However, the coupling of the second integrated circuit <b>12</b> to the conductive elements <b>16</b> of the substrate <b>13</b> by the wires <b>21</b> is not ideal. Provision of the wires <b>21</b> typically involves slower and more expensive manufacturing processes than providing the electrically conductive bumps <b>17</b>. The length of the electrical path provided by the wires <b>21</b> is typically much longer than the length of the electrical path provided by the electrically conductive bumps <b>17</b>, which means that the electrical performance of components coupled by the wires <b>21</b> is reduced. Also, the electrically conductive bumps <b>17</b> tend to provide improved thermal conductivity in comparison to the wires <b>21</b>, with the result that the first and second integrated circuit dies <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> can be cooled more effectively when the electrically conductive bumps <b>17</b> are used for electrical coupling rather than the wires <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, in a third example according to the prior art, an electronic device <b>30</b> similar to the electronic device <b>20</b> of the second example has the second integrated circuit die <b>12</b> mounted on an additional substrate <b>31</b> between the first and second integrated circuit dies <b>11</b>, <b>12</b>. In other words, the second integrated circuit die <b>12</b> is mounted on the additional substrate <b>31</b> and the additional substrate <b>31</b> is mounted on the surface of the first integrated circuit die <b>11</b> facing away from the substrate <b>13</b>. This allows the second integrated circuit die <b>12</b> to retain its electrically conductive bumps <b>17</b>, as in the first example. The additional substrate <b>31</b> has electrically conductive elements <b>32</b> extending through it from a surface of the additional substrate <b>31</b> facing the second integrated circuit die <b>12</b> to a surface of the additional substrate <b>31</b> facing the substrate <b>13</b> of the electronic device <b>30</b> that is also present in the first and second examples, now referred to as the main substrate <b>13</b>. Additional solder balls <b>33</b> are provided on the surface of the additional substrate <b>31</b> facing the main substrate <b>13</b>. The additional solder balls <b>33</b> are each in contact with a respective one of the electrically conductive elements <b>32</b> of the additional substrate <b>31</b>, and the additional substrate <b>31</b> and the main substrate <b>13</b> are positioned such that the additional solder balls <b>33</b> are also in contact with the electrically conductive elements <b>16</b> of the main substrate <b>13</b>. A problem with the electronic device <b>30</b> of the third example is that the provision of the additional substrate <b>31</b> adds to the expense of the electronic device <b>30</b>. The size of the electronic device <b>30</b> is also increased by the provision of the additional solder balls <b>33</b> and the additional substrate <b>31</b> and, in particular, the height of the electronic device <b>30</b> may not therefore be acceptable in some applications.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">According to a first aspect, there is provided an electronic device comprising a plurality of integrated circuit dies mounted to different areas of a carrier, wherein the carrier is folded into a plurality of layers such that the plurality of integrated circuit dies form a stack.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to a second aspect, there is provided a method of manufacturing an electronic device, comprising: mounting a plurality of integrated circuit dies on different areas of a carrier; and folding the carrier into a plurality of layers such that the plurality of integrated circuit dies form a stack.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">By mounting a plurality of integrated circuit dies on a single carrier and folding the carrier to form an electronic device, the electronic device can be formed that has a minimal size. The use of a single carrier also minimises costs.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The plurality of integrated circuits dies may be mounted on the carrier in a variety of ways. However, it is preferable that the all of the integrated circuit dies are mounted on the same surface of the carrier. This feature enables straightforward manufacture, for example by allowing the integrated circuit dies to be mounted on the carrier straightforwardly prior to folding. Electrical contact between the integrated circuit dies and the carrier can also be made more straightforwardly than if the integrated circuit dies are provided on different sides of the carrier, as by mounting the integrated circuit dies on only one side of the carrier, the carrier can have electrical contacts for the integrated circuit dies on only that side.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">One or more layers of the stack may include more than one integrated circuit die. However, preferably, each layer comprises only one of the different areas of the carrier and one of the plurality of integrated circuit dies. Each layer therefore has only a single integrated circuit die. This minimises the size and complexity of the electronic device by eliminating any spaces between different integrated circuit dies within a given layer.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Typically, the different areas of the carrier comprise a first portion and one or more further portions extending from the first portion, each of the further portions being folded over the first portion. The method can comprise folding the one or more further portions extending from the first portion over the first portion. In other words, all but one of the different areas of the carrier to which one of the plurality of integrated circuit dies are mounted may be folded over the one of the areas. Typically, the folding over comprises folding at least partially over or on top of, although it may comprise simply folding so as to overlap or completely overlap. The folding over may not be such that the portions are immediately over one another; there may be intervening layers.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In one example, the further portions extend from the first portion in different directions. The first portion may be central in relation to the further portions prior to the folding. In particular, each of the further portions may extend from the first portion in a different direction. This may mean that the folds extend in different directions or that each of the folds extends in a different direction. This allows convenient layout of the integrated circuit dies on the carrier.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In particular, the dies may be arranged on the carrier on either side or around the first portion. For example, the first portion and further portions may be arranged in a line. Alternatively, they may be arranged in a two dimensional configuration. In a particular example, the further portions may be angularly spaced from one another by the same angle. In this or other examples, the further portions may be angularly spaced from one another by an angle that is 180&#xb0;, 90&#xb0;, 60&#xb0; or 45&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The carrier may be folded in a variety of different ways. For example, one of the further portions may first be folded over another of the further portions and then both of these portions may be folded over the first portion. So, there may be two or more folds between the first portion and the one of the further portions. However, it is preferred that the carrier only has one fold between the first portion and each of the further portions. This is helpful for minimising the length of the carrier between pairs of the plurality of integrated circuit dies. If the pairs of integrated circuit dies are electrically coupled via the carrier, the length of the electrical coupling provided by the carrier can also be minimised in this way.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Indeed, it is preferred that the carrier comprises an electrical coupling means, and one or more of the integrated circuit dies is mounted on the carrier such that it is electrically coupled to the electrical coupling means. It is particularly preferred that at least one of the integrated circuit dies is mounted on the carrier with an electrically conductive protrusion for electrically coupling the integrated circuit die externally to the integrated circuit die facing the carrier. The electrically conductive protrusion may be coupled, or in contact with, the electrical coupling means of the carrier.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The carrier may be mounted on a substrate, and the method may comprise mounting the carrier on the substrate. It is preferred that the substrate is stiffer than the carrier. Thus, whilst the carrier may be flexible, at least prior to folding, the electronic device, as a whole, may be relatively rigid.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">It is preferred that the substrate has a balancing layer. More specifically, in one example, the carrier may comprise a first material of a first thickness and may be mounted on a first surface of the substrate, and a balancing layer comprising a second material of a second thickness may be mounted on a second surface of the substrate opposite to the first surface, wherein the first and second materials and the first and second thicknesses are respectively substantially the same as one another. A part of the carrier mounted to the substrate, the substrate itself and the balancing layer may therefore have a plane of symmetry at a plane mid-way between the two surfaces of the substrate, or at least a point of symmetry. Any strain exerted on the substrate by the carrier and the balancing layer may therefore be substantially the same.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Typically, the electronic device is mounted on a printed circuit board or such like. The electronic device may be electrically coupled to the printed circuit board or such like via the substrate. So, the substrate may comprise an electrical coupling means and the carrier may be mounted on the surface of the substrate such that the electrical coupling means of the substrate is electrically coupled to the electrical coupling means of the carrier.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The electronic device may be provided as an integral device. In one example, a surface of one of the plurality of layers and a surface of another of the plurality of layers are fixed together, the two surfaces being adjacent to and facing one another. Optionally, the carrier and the plurality of integrated circuit dies can be embedded in a moulded housing. Likewise, the method can comprise moulding a material around the carrier and the plurality of integrated circuit dies such that the carrier and the plurality of integrated circuit dies are embedded in a moulded housing. The moulded housing and the substrate may together enclose the carrier and plurality of integrated circuit dies. This feature enables the electronic device to be robust.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The method of manufacturing an electronic device preferably comprises: providing a sheet of substrate material; forming a gap in the sheet of substrate material; applying a sheet of carrier material to the sheet of substrate material extending over and beyond the gap; and dividing the sheet of substrate material and the sheet of carrier material along a plane passing through the gap, thereby forming the carrier and the substrate, one of the different areas of the carrier being in a region where the sheet of carrier material extends beyond the gap, and one of the different areas of the carrier being in a region where the sheet of carrier material extends over the gap. Preferably, the method is carried out in this order, but this is not essential. This feature facilitates manufacture of the electronic device, and in particular enables a plurality of the electronic devices to be manufactured simultaneously from the same sheet of carrier material and the same sheet of substrate material.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Preferred embodiments will now be described, by way of example only, with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic sectional view of a first example of an electronic device according to the prior art;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic sectional view of a second example of an electronic device according to the prior art;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic sectional view of a third example of an electronic device according to the prior art;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic sectional view of an electronic device according to an embodiment of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a flow chart illustrating the steps of manufacturing the electronic device shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6A-G</figref> are schematic sectional views of the electronic device shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> at successive stages of manufacture the electronic device;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a plan view of the electronic device shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> at the stage of manufacture shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6F</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a plan view of an electronic device according to another embodiment of the present disclosure at an intermediate stage of manufacture.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, an electronic device <b>100</b> comprises first, second and third integrated circuit dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> mounted on a carrier <b>150</b>. The first integrated circuit die <b>110</b> has first electrically conductive bumps <b>111</b>, the second integrated circuit die <b>120</b> has second electrically conductive bumps <b>121</b> and the third integrated circuit die <b>130</b> has third electrically conductive bumps <b>131</b>. For conciseness, the first, second and third integrated circuit dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> are referred to as, respectively, the first, second and third dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b>. Likewise, the first, second and third electrically conductive bumps <b>111</b>, <b>121</b>, <b>131</b> are referred to as, respectively, first, second and third bumps <b>111</b>, <b>121</b>, <b>131</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In this embodiment, the first, second and third dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b> <b>130</b> are flip chip devices. This means that they are connectable to the carrier <b>150</b> &#x201c;face-down&#x201d;. More specifically, the conductive bumps <b>111</b>, <b>121</b>, <b>131</b> are provided on bond pads (not shown) on the surfaces of the dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> on which the electrical components of the dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> are provided and the dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> are mounted on the carrier <b>150</b> with this surface facing the carrier <b>150</b>. In this embodiment, the first, second and third dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> are mounted on the carrier <b>150</b> by the first, second and third bumps <b>111</b>, <b>121</b>, <b>131</b> respectively. In other embodiments, different mounting means may be employed. The bumps <b>111</b>, <b>121</b>, <b>131</b> have any form that is electrically conductive and raised from the surface of the dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> on which they are provided. In one embodiment, the bumps <b>111</b>, <b>121</b>, <b>131</b> are pillars of electrically conductive material. In another embodiment, the bumps <b>111</b>, <b>121</b>, <b>131</b> comprise solder.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The first, second and third dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b> <b>130</b> are mounted on different areas of the carrier <b>150</b>, and the carrier <b>150</b> is folded into a plurality of layers A, B, C such that the first, second and third dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> form a stack. The first, second and third dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> can be of a similar size, and can be aligned in the stack, or at least to partially overlap each other in the stack. To facilitate folding, the carrier <b>150</b> comprises a carrier material <b>152</b> that is flexible, at least prior to folding. A first layer A of the plurality of layers A, B, C comprises the first die <b>110</b>, the first bumps <b>111</b>, and a region of the carrier <b>150</b> to which the first die <b>110</b> is mounted. A second layer B of the plurality of layers A, B, C comprises the second die <b>120</b>, the second bumps <b>121</b>, and a region of the carrier <b>150</b> to which the second die <b>120</b> is mounted. A third layer C of the plurality of layers A, B, C comprises the third die <b>130</b>, the third bumps <b>131</b>, and a region of the carrier <b>150</b> to which the third die <b>130</b> is mounted. The second layer B is folded over the first layer A, and the third layer C is folded over the second layer B and the first layer A. Adjacent ones of the plurality of layers A, B, C are fixed together by adhesive. More specifically, the first layer A is fixed to the second layer B by a first adhesive layer <b>122</b>, and the second layer B is fixed to the third layer C by a second adhesive layer <b>132</b>. In particular, a surface of the first die <b>110</b> opposite that on which the first bumps <b>111</b> are located is fixed by the first adhesive layer <b>122</b> to a surface of the second die <b>120</b> opposite that on which the second bumps <b>121</b> are located. Similarly, a surface of the third die <b>130</b> opposite that on which the third bumps <b>131</b> are located is fixed by the second adhesive layer <b>132</b> to the surface of the carrier <b>150</b> to which the third die <b>130</b> is mounted.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The carrier <b>150</b> comprises an electrically non-conductive material, carrier tracks <b>154</b> on one or more surfaces of the carrier <b>150</b>, and carrier vias <b>156</b> through the carrier <b>150</b>. The dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> are positioned on the carrier such that the electrically conductive bumps <b>111</b>, <b>121</b>, <b>131</b> are in contact with the carrier tracks <b>154</b> and carrier vias <b>156</b>. For conciseness, wherever tracks are referred to, these are electrically conductive tracks made from, for example, a metal. In addition, wherever vias are referred to, these are electrically conductive vias.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The folded carrier <b>150</b> with the attached first, second and third dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> is mounted on a substrate <b>160</b>. In this embodiment, the substrate <b>160</b> is substantially flat and the carrier <b>150</b> is folded and mounted on the substrate <b>160</b> such that the first, second and third dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> are parallel to the major plane of the substrate <b>160</b>. The substrate <b>160</b> is rigid and provides support for the folded carrier <b>150</b> and the attached first, second and third dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b>. On a surface of the substrate <b>160</b> opposite that on which the folded carrier <b>150</b> is mounted, the substrate <b>160</b> is provided with solder balls <b>113</b>, such as a ball grid array, for coupling the substrate <b>160</b> externally to the electronic device <b>100</b>, e.g. to a printed circuit board (PCB) (not illustrated).</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The substrate <b>160</b> comprises a core layer <b>162</b> of an electrically non-conductive core layer material and, on a surface of the core layer <b>162</b> opposite to that on which the carrier <b>150</b> is mounted, a balancing layer <b>168</b> of balancing layer material, which is the same material as the carrier material of the carrier <b>150</b>. The balancing layer <b>168</b> balances the mechanical properties of the substrate <b>160</b> and the carrier <b>150</b>, although in some embodiments the balancing layer <b>168</b> may be omitted. The core layer <b>162</b> has core layer vias <b>166</b> and the balancing layer <b>168</b> has balancing layer vias <b>169</b> coupled to the core layer vias <b>166</b> to provide substrate vias extending through the substrate <b>160</b>. The solder balls <b>113</b> are provided on the bottom surface of the substrate <b>160</b> in contact with the balancing layer vias <b>169</b> and the carrier <b>150</b> is positioned on the substrate <b>160</b> such that appropriate ones of the carrier tracks <b>154</b> and carrier vias <b>156</b> are in contact with the core layer vias <b>166</b>. So, the first, second and third dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b> <b>130</b> can be coupled to each other and to devices external to the electronic device <b>100</b> by means of the first, second and third bumps <b>111</b>, <b>121</b>, <b>131</b> of the respective first, second and third dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b>, the carrier tracks <b>154</b> on one or more surfaces of the carrier material, the carrier vias <b>156</b> through the carrier <b>150</b>, core layer vias <b>166</b> through the core layer <b>162</b>, balancing layer vias <b>169</b> through the balancing layer <b>168</b>, the solder balls <b>113</b> of the bottom surface of the substrate <b>160</b> and a PCB (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The carrier <b>150</b> and the first, second and third dies, <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> with their respective first, second and third bumps <b>111</b>, <b>121</b>, <b>131</b> are embedded in a moulded material <b>180</b>. The moulded material <b>180</b> and the carrier <b>160</b> therefore enclose the carrier <b>150</b> and the first, second and third dies, <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> with their respective first, second and third bumps <b>111</b>, <b>121</b>, <b>131</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5</figref>, <b>6</b>A to <b>6</b>G and <b>7</b>, manufacture of the electronic device <b>100</b> described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> commences at step <b>502</b> by forming a sheet <b>262</b>, or panel, of the electrically non-conductive core layer material. Also at step <b>502</b>, the core layer vias <b>166</b> are formed, for example from a metal, through the sheet <b>262</b> of core layer material, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">At step <b>504</b>, a sheet <b>268</b> of the balancing layer material <b>268</b> is formed on a first surface of the sheet <b>262</b> of the core layer material, which is the bottom surface in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref>, and the balancing layer vias <b>169</b> are formed through the sheet <b>268</b> of balancing layer material, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref>. The balancing layer vias <b>169</b> and the core layer vias <b>166</b> coincide with one another so as to form the substrate vias. The substrate <b>160</b>, when the manufacturing process is complete, comprises a portion of the sheet <b>262</b> of the core layer material, the core layer vias <b>166</b>, a portion of the sheet <b>268</b> of the balancing layer material and the balancing layer vias <b>169</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">At step <b>506</b>, a first gap <b>170</b><i>a </i>and a second gap <b>170</b><i>b </i>are formed in the sheet <b>262</b> of the core layer material and the sheet <b>268</b> of the balancing layer material <b>268</b> by cutting out portions of the sheet <b>262</b> of the core layer material and the sheet <b>268</b> of the balancing layer material, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6C</figref>. The gaps <b>170</b><i>a</i>, <b>170</b><i>b </i>extend completely through the sheet <b>262</b> of the core layer material and the sheet <b>268</b> of the balancing layer material, but the sheets <b>262</b>, <b>268</b> remain intact as single sheets. In some embodiments, the first and second gaps <b>170</b><i>a</i>, <b>170</b><i>b </i>are holes, each having a complete peripheries in the sheets <b>262</b>, <b>268</b> of the core layer material and balancing layer material.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">At step <b>508</b>, a sheet <b>250</b>, or panel, of carrier material is formed on a second surface of the sheet <b>262</b> of the core layer material. The second surface of the sheet <b>262</b> of the core layer material is opposite the first surface of the sheet <b>262</b> of core layer material and is the top surface in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6C</figref>. The sheet <b>250</b> of carrier material covers the first and second gaps <b>170</b><i>a</i>, <b>170</b><i>b</i>. Also at step <b>508</b>, the carrier conductive tracks <b>154</b> are formed on the upper and lower planar surfaces of the sheet <b>250</b> of the carrier material and the carrier conductive vias <b>156</b> are formed through the sheet <b>250</b> of the carrier material, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6D</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">At step <b>510</b>, the first, second and third dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> are mounted on the sheet <b>250</b> of the carrier material, on the opposite side of the sheet <b>250</b> of the carrier material to that facing the sheet <b>262</b> of the core layer material, by means of their respective first, second and third bumps <b>111</b>, <b>121</b>, <b>131</b>. The first die <b>110</b> is mounted above a portion of the sheet <b>262</b> of the core layer material where no gap <b>170</b><i>a</i>, <b>170</b><i>b </i>was cut, the second die <b>120</b> is mounted over the first gap <b>170</b><i>a </i>to the right of the first die <b>110</b>, and the third die <b>130</b> is mounted over the second gap <b>170</b><i>b </i>to the left of the first die <b>110</b>, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6E</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">At step <b>512</b>, the sheet <b>250</b> of the carrier material, the sheet <b>262</b> of the core layer material and the sheet <b>268</b> of the balancing layer material <b>268</b> are cut to the right of the second die <b>120</b> along a first plane X-X&#x2032; passing vertically through the first gap <b>170</b><i>a</i>, and are also cut to the left of the third die <b>130</b> along a second plane Y-Y&#x2032; passing vertically through the second gap <b>170</b><i>b</i>, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6E</figref>. Further cuts are made in vertical planes perpendicular to the first and second planes X-X&#x2032;, Y-Y&#x2032; in order to release the elements required for the electronic device <b>100</b> from the sheets <b>250</b>, <b>262</b>, <b>268</b> of the carrier material, core layer material and balancing layer material.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">At this stage, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6F</figref>, the substrate <b>160</b> comprises a portion of the sheet <b>262</b> of the core layer material and a portion of the sheet <b>268</b> of the balancing layer material. In particular, the carrier <b>150</b> comprises a first portion <b>151</b> of the sheet <b>250</b> of the carrier material over the substrate <b>160</b>, a second portion <b>153</b> of the sheet <b>250</b> of the carrier material extending to the right from the first portion <b>151</b> and which was over the first gap <b>170</b><i>a </i>prior to the cutting, and a third portion <b>155</b> of the sheet <b>250</b> of the carrier material <b>250</b> extending to the left from the first portion <b>151</b> and which was over the second gap <b>170</b><i>b </i>prior to the cutting. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates a plan view from above of the electronic device <b>100</b> at this stage, and shows the first second and third dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> mounted on the carrier <b>150</b>, which comprises the first, second and third portions <b>151</b>, <b>153</b>, <b>155</b> and the carrier tracks <b>154</b>, and which is mounted on the substrate <b>160</b>. Additional electronic devices may be cut from the laminated structure comprising the sheets <b>250</b>, <b>262</b>, <b>268</b> of the carrier material, core layer material and balancing layer material.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">At step <b>514</b>, the second portion <b>153</b> of the carrier <b>150</b> is folded over the first portion <b>151</b>, thereby inverting the second die <b>120</b> and bringing the first die <b>110</b> and the second die <b>120</b> together. The facing surfaces of the first die <b>110</b> and the second die <b>120</b> are fixed together by means of the first adhesive layer <b>122</b>. Then the third portion <b>155</b> of the carrier <b>150</b> is folded over the second portion <b>153</b> of the carrier <b>150</b>, thereby inverting the third die <b>130</b> and bringing the third die <b>130</b> and the second portion <b>153</b> of the carrier <b>150</b> together. The facing surfaces of the third die <b>130</b> and the second portion <b>153</b> of the carrier <b>150</b> are fixed together by means of the second adhesive layer <b>132</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6G</figref> illustrates the unfinished assembly at this stage after the folding and application of the first and second adhesive layers <b>122</b>, <b>132</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">At step <b>516</b>, the carrier <b>150</b> and the first, second and third dies, <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> with their respective first, second and third bumps <b>111</b>, <b>121</b>, <b>131</b> have a mouldable material moulded around them, thereby embedding the carrier <b>150</b> and the first, second and third dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> in the moulded material <b>180</b>. The solder balls <b>113</b> are also provided on a surface of the substrate <b>160</b> facing away from the carrier <b>150</b>. The resulting electronic device <b>100</b> is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Although embodiments have been described in which the first, second and third dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> are mounted on the same surface of the carrier <b>150</b>, this is not essential. In other embodiments, either or both of the second and third dies <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> are mounted on the opposite surface of the carrier <b>150</b> to that on which the first die <b>110</b> is mounted. In other embodiments, additional dies may be mounted on the carrier <b>150</b> on either or both of the surfaces.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Although embodiments have been described in which the carrier <b>150</b> comprises a first portion <b>151</b> and two further portions <b>153</b>, <b>155</b> and involves two folds, resulting in the carrier <b>150</b> providing, after folding, the three layers A, B, C each with one of the dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b>, this is not essential. In other embodiments, other numbers of folds may be used. In one embodiment, an electronic device having two layers with a single fold between them is provided, one layer comprising the first portion <b>151</b> of the carrier <b>150</b> and the first die <b>110</b> and the other layer comprising one of the further portions <b>153</b>, <b>155</b> and just one of the second or third ides <b>120</b>, <b>130</b>. In other embodiments, more than two folds are used.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> illustrates a carrier <b>350</b> comprising a first portion <b>351</b> having the first die <b>110</b> mounted on it, and second, third, fourth and fifth further portions <b>353</b>, <b>355</b>, <b>357</b> and <b>359</b> extending from the first portion <b>351</b>. The second portion <b>353</b> of the carrier <b>350</b> has the second die <b>120</b> mounted on it, the third portion <b>355</b> of the carrier <b>350</b> has the third die <b>130</b> mounted on it, the fourth portion <b>357</b> of the carrier <b>350</b> has a fourth die <b>310</b> mounted on it, and the fifth portion <b>359</b> of the carrier <b>350</b> has a fifth die <b>320</b> mounted on it. The second, third, fourth and fifth portions <b>353</b>, <b>355</b>, <b>357</b>, <b>359</b> of the carrier <b>350</b> are of different lengths to facilitate folding, with the second portion <b>353</b> being folded over the first portion <b>351</b>, the third portion <b>355</b> being folded over the second portion <b>353</b>, the fourth portion <b>357</b> being folded over the third portion <b>355</b>, and the fifth portion <b>359</b> being folded over the fourth portion <b>357</b>. After folding, the first, second, third, fourth and fifth dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b>, <b>310</b>, <b>320</b> form a stack, and the base of the stack has a generally rectangular or square shape. In other embodiments, the carrier comprises: a first portion and three further portions, involving three folds and resulting, after folding, in a stack having a generally triangular base; a first portion and five further portions, involving five folds and resulting, after folding, in a stack having a generally pentagonal base; a first portion and six further portions, involving six folds and resulting, after folding, in a stack having a generally hexagonal base; a first portion and seven further portions, involving seven folds and resulting, after folding, in a stack having a generally heptagonal base; and a first portion and eight further portions, involving eight folds and resulting, after folding, in a stack having a generally octagonal base. To facilitate the folding, the further portions can be of different lengths.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Although embodiments of the method have been described comprising folding the carrier <b>150</b>, <b>350</b>, this is not essential. In other embodiments, the carrier <b>150</b>, <b>350</b> is formed having a pre-folded shape.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Although embodiments have been described in which adjacent layers, comprising the carrier <b>150</b> and one of the first, second and third dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> mounted on the carrier <b>150</b>, are fixed together by means of adhesive, this is not essential. In other embodiments, alternative means of fixing are employed. For example, the fixing is provided by the moulded material <b>180</b> without the use of the first or second adhesive layers <b>122</b>, <b>132</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Suitable materials for the carrier <b>150</b>, <b>350</b> are: FR4, polyimide, polytetrafluoroethylene, also known as PTFE, and polyester. In the illustrated embodiments, the carrier <b>150</b>, <b>350</b> comprises a laminated material. Electronic components, particularly resistors, can be integrated in the laminated material. By way of example, if the carrier <b>150</b>, <b>350</b> is made from a polyimide, the following properties are provided: a laminate structure having four layers of carrier tracks <b>154</b>; a total thickness of 50 micrometers; carrier tracks <b>154</b> having line widths of 15 micometers and a line spacing of 10 micrometers; carrier vias <b>156</b> of 30 micrometers in width; and a bend radius when folded of 0.5 millimeters.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Although embodiments have been described in which the first, second and third bumps <b>111</b>, <b>121</b>, <b>131</b> can be made of solder, this is not essential and other materials can be used. For example, an electrically conductive adhesive can be used to mount the first, second and third dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> on the carrier <b>150</b>. Such an electrically conductive adhesive is particular suitable if the carrier <b>150</b> comprises a polyester material.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Although embodiments have been described in which, after the carrier <b>150</b> has been folded to form a stack, the first, second and third dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> are disposed parallel to the surface of the substrate <b>160</b> on which the carrier <b>150</b> is mounted, this is not essential. In other embodiments, the first second and third dies <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> are disposed perpendicular to the surface of the substrate <b>160</b> on which the carrier <b>150</b> is mounted.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Other variations and modifications will be apparent to the skilled person. Such variations and modifications may involve equivalent and other features which are already known and which may be used instead of, or in addition to, features described herein. Features that are described in the context of separate embodiments may be provided in combination in a single embodiment. Conversely, features which are described in the context of a single embodiment may also be provided separately or in any suitable sub-combination.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">It should be noted that the term &#x201c;comprising&#x201d; does not exclude other elements or steps, the term &#x201c;a&#x201d; or &#x201c;an&#x201d; does not exclude a plurality, a single feature may fulfil the functions of several features recited in the claims and reference signs in the claims shall not be construed as limiting the scope of the claims. It should also be noted that the Figures are not necessarily to scale; emphasis instead generally being placed upon illustrating the principles of the present invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method of manufacturing an electronic device, comprising:
<claim-text>mounting a plurality of integrated circuit dies on different areas of a carrier; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>folding the carrier into a plurality of layers such that the plurality of integrated circuit dies form a stack;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the method further comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a sheet of substrate material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first gap and a second gap in the sheet of substrate material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a sheet of carrier material to the sheet of substrate material extending over and beyond the first and second gaps; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>dividing the sheet of substrate material and the sheet of carrier material along a plane passing through the first and second gaps, thereby forming the carrier and a substrate, one of the different areas of the carrier being in a region where the sheet of carrier material extends beyond the first and second gaps, and one of the different areas of the carrier being in a region where the sheet of carrier material extends over the first and second gaps.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A method of manufacturing an electronic device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, the different areas of the carrier comprising a first portion and one or more further portions extending from the first portion, wherein the first portion is central in relation to the further portions prior to the folding. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
