<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622347-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622347</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13165066</doc-number>
<date>20110621</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>189</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>64</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>244131</main-classification>
<further-classification>244119</further-classification>
<further-classification>138107</further-classification>
<further-classification>2482287</further-classification>
<further-classification>248506</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Clip attachment system connecting aircraft structures to each other</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2211728</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>MacFadden</name>
<date>19400800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>248500</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5680680</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>LaConte</name>
<date>19971000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7059565</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Scown et al.</name>
<date>20060600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7210657</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Plate et al.</name>
<date>20070500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7735780</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Coles</name>
<date>20100600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0082431</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Scown et al.</name>
<date>20050400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>244119</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>FR</country>
<doc-number>2952418</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00008">
<othercit>EP search report dated Sep. 12, 2012 regarding application 12170252.6-2422, applicant The Boeing Company, reference NAM/P122370EP00, 7 Pages.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>14</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2441185</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>244119</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2441231</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2441234</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>244131</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>244135 R</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>138106</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>138107</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2482286</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2482287</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2482284</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>248500</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>248506</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>10</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>14</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120325968</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121227</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Oyzerskiy</last-name>
<first-name>Eduard</first-name>
<address>
<city>Sandy</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Oyzerskiy</last-name>
<first-name>Eduard</first-name>
<address>
<city>Sandy</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Yee &#x26; Associates, P.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>The Boeing Company</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Chicago</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Collins</last-name>
<first-name>Timothy D</first-name>
<department>3644</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>McFall</last-name>
<first-name>Nicholas</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">In one advantageous embodiment of the present disclosure, an apparatus and method for supporting a load is provided. The apparatus comprises a structure having an inner surface with a shape configured to substantially conform to an outer surface of a stringer. A number of pins extends from the inner surface of the structure such that the number of pins are configured to engage holes in the outer surface of the stringer when the structure is placed over the outer surface of the stringer. The pins support the structure with respect to the stringer when a load is applied to the structure. A number of members extends from the outer surface of the structure such that the number of members is configured to connect to a part.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="119.21mm" wi="343.07mm" file="US08622347-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="245.96mm" wi="162.81mm" file="US08622347-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="260.94mm" wi="192.79mm" file="US08622347-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="217.34mm" wi="195.50mm" file="US08622347-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="243.84mm" wi="179.83mm" file="US08622347-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="253.41mm" wi="162.14mm" file="US08622347-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="256.12mm" wi="188.04mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622347-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="145.12mm" wi="136.91mm" file="US08622347-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="196.17mm" wi="186.69mm" file="US08622347-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="254.76mm" wi="178.48mm" file="US08622347-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="165.52mm" wi="111.00mm" file="US08622347-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND INFORMATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to attaching structures to each other and, more particularly, to attaching aircraft structures to each other. Still more particularly, the present disclosure relates to a method and apparatus for connecting parts to an aircraft stringer.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Background</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Manufacturing and assembly of structures, such as those for aircraft, involves the assembly of different parts to form the structures. Different parts and/or structures are connected to each other in manufacturing the aircraft. Structures, such as reinforcing ribs, stringers, and/or other suitable structures may be used to support other parts and/or structures in the aircraft. For example, wiring bundles, hoses, cables, and other lines are examples of parts that may run through parts of an aircraft. These lines may be connected to structures, such as ribs and/or stringers in the aircraft. These structures may be used to provide support for system components, such as those described.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In connecting a line to a stringer, a fixture may be used to make the connection. For example, a fixture may be attached to a stringer for use in supporting system components. A fixture is attached to a stringer using blind fasteners. A blind fastener does not allow an operator to inspect the quality of the connection to the stringer.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Regulations may require that fasteners be sealed. The sealing may be performed to isolate the interior of the structure from other sections in the aircraft. This sealing may prevent liquids and/or vapors from exiting the structure from the location of the fasteners. These regulations may apply to different locations in the aircraft, such as a fuel tank or an electrical system in the aircraft.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">A blind fastener is difficult to remove in these structures. As a result, repositioning of the fixture may be more difficult and time consuming than desired.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">As a result, the manufacturing and assembly of the aircraft may take more time and expense than desired to obtain a desired positioning of parts near the stringer. Accordingly, it would be advantageous to have a method and apparatus that takes into account one or more of the issues discussed above, as well as possibly other issues.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The present disclosure provides a method and apparatus for supporting a load from attached system components to a stringer of an aircraft. In one advantageous embodiment of the present disclosure, an apparatus for supporting a load is provided. The apparatus comprises a structure having an inner surface with a shape configured to substantially conform to an outer surface of a stringer. A number of pins extend from the inner surface of the structure such that the number of pins are configured to engage holes in the outer surface of the stringer when the structure is placed over the outer surface of the stringer. The number of pins supports the structure with respect to the stringer when a load is applied to the structure. A number of members extend from the outer surface of the structure such that the number of members is configured to connect to a part.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In another advantageous embodiment, an apparatus for connecting a load to a stringer in an aircraft includes a body having a first arm and a second arm, at least one pin affixed to the first arm and at least one pin affixed to the second arm, and a flange. The body also includes a center portion, with the first arm and the second arm being flexibly connected at the center portion. The first arm is configured to contact a first surface of the stringer, and the second arm is adapted to contact a second surface of the stringer. The body transitions between a flexed position and a locked position. The at least one pin of the first arm is configured to engage a hole positioned in the first surface of the stringer in the locked position and to disengage the hole in the flexed position. The at least one pin of the second arm is configured to engage a hole positioned in the second surface of the stringer in the locked position and to disengage the hole in the flexed position. The flange is configured to secure the first arm and the second arm in a locked position. The body receives the load when the first arm and the second arm are in the locked position.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In still a further advantageous embodiment, a method for supporting a part includes maintaining engagement of a clip with a stringer and supporting the part with a number of members. The clip comprises a structure having an inner surface with a shape configured to substantially conform to an outer surface of the stringer. The clip also comprises pins extending from the inner surface of the structure, wherein the pins are configured to engage holes in the outer surface of the stringer when the structure is placed over the outer surface of the stringer and supports the structure with respect to the stringer when a load is applied to the structure. The clip also includes the number of members, wherein the number of members is configured to be connected to the part.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The features, functions, and advantages can be achieved independently in various embodiments of the present disclosure or may be combined in yet other embodiments in which further details can be seen with reference to the following description and drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The novel features believed characteristic of the advantageous embodiments are set forth in the appended claims. The advantageous embodiments, however, as well as a preferred mode of use, further objectives and advantages thereof, will best be understood by reference to the following detailed description of an advantageous embodiment of the present disclosure when read in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an illustration of a diagram illustrating an aircraft manufacturing and service method in which an advantageous embodiment may be implemented;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an illustration of a diagram of an aircraft in accordance with an advantageous embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an illustration of a block diagram of a load support environment in accordance with an advantageous embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is an illustration of a diagram of a clip in accordance with an advantageous embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an illustration of a diagram of a clip in accordance with an advantageous embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is an illustration of a diagram of a clip in accordance with an advantageous embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is an illustration of an exploded view of a clip and stringer in accordance with an advantageous embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is an illustration of a clip having a standoff from a stringer in accordance with an advantageous embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is an illustration of a diagram of a support system in accordance with an advantageous embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is an illustration of a diagram of a clip in accordance with an advantageous embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is an illustration of a diagram of a jig in accordance with an advantageous embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is an illustration of a flowchart of a process for forming holes in a stringer in accordance with an advantageous embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is an illustration of a flowchart of a process for using a clip to connect a load to a stringer in accordance with an advantageous embodiment; and</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is an illustration of a flowchart of a process for using a clip in accordance with an advantageous embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Referring more particularly to the drawings, embodiments of the disclosure may be described in the context of aircraft manufacturing and service method <b>100</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and aircraft <b>200</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. Turning first to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, an illustration of an aircraft manufacturing and service method is depicted in accordance with an advantageous embodiment. During pre-production, aircraft manufacturing and service method <b>100</b> may include specification and design <b>102</b> of aircraft <b>200</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> and material procurement <b>104</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">During production, component and subassembly manufacturing <b>106</b> and system integration <b>108</b> of aircraft <b>200</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> takes place. Thereafter, aircraft <b>200</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> may go through certification and delivery <b>110</b> in order to be placed in service <b>112</b>. While in service <b>112</b> by a customer, aircraft <b>200</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is scheduled for routine maintenance and service <b>114</b>, which may include modification, reconfiguration, refurbishment, and other maintenance or service.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Each of the processes of aircraft manufacturing and service method <b>100</b> may be performed or carried out by a system integrator, a third party, and/or an operator. In these examples, the operator may be a customer. For the purposes of this description, a system integrator may include, without limitation, any number of aircraft manufacturers and major-system subcontractors; a third party may include, without limitation, any number of vendors, subcontractors, and suppliers; and an operator may be an airline, a leasing company, a military entity, a service organization, and so on.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, an illustration of an aircraft is depicted in which an advantageous embodiment may be implemented. In this example, aircraft <b>200</b> is produced by aircraft manufacturing and service method <b>100</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and may include airframe <b>202</b> with plurality of systems <b>204</b> and interior <b>206</b>. Examples of systems <b>204</b> include one or more of propulsion system <b>208</b>, electrical system <b>210</b>, hydraulic system <b>212</b>, and environmental system <b>214</b>. Any number of other systems may also be included. Although an aerospace example is shown, different advantageous embodiments may be applied to other industries, such as the automotive industry.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Apparatuses and methods embodied herein may be employed during at least one of the stages of aircraft manufacturing and service method <b>100</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. As used herein, the phrase &#x201c;at least one of&#x201d;, when used with a list of items, means that different combinations of one or more of the listed items may be used and only one of each item in the list may be needed. For example, &#x201c;at least one of item A, item B, and item C&#x201d; may include, for example, without limitation, item A, or item A and item B. This example also may include item A, item B, and item C, or item B and item C.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In one illustrative example, components or subassemblies produced in component and subassembly manufacturing <b>106</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> may be fabricated or manufactured in a manner similar to components or subassemblies produced while aircraft <b>200</b> is in service <b>112</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. As yet another example, a number of apparatus embodiments, method embodiments, or a combination thereof may be utilized during production stages, such as component and subassembly manufacturing <b>106</b> and system integration <b>108</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. A number, when referring to items, means one or more items. For example, a number of apparatus embodiments are one or more apparatus embodiments. A number of apparatus embodiments, method embodiments, or a combination thereof may be utilized while aircraft <b>200</b> is in service <b>112</b> and/or during maintenance and service <b>114</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The use of a number of the different advantageous embodiments may substantially expedite the assembly of and/or reduce the cost of aircraft <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">For example, one or more of the different advantageous embodiments may be used to connect a load or part to a structure during, for example, without limitation, component and subassembly manufacturing <b>106</b> and system integration <b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The different advantageous embodiments recognize and take into account a number of different considerations. For example, the different advantageous embodiments recognize and take into account that blind fasteners, such as those used in suspending a part from an aircraft stringer, present undesirable features. Use of a blind fastener makes it difficult or impossible to visually inspect the fastener connection in an aircraft stringer.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The different advantageous embodiments recognize and take into account that lightning strike regulations may require that certain aircraft fasteners be sealed. For example, fasteners, such as those used in a fuel-related application may require sealing and/or isolation. In certain applications, it may be difficult or impossible to inspect and confirm that a fastener remains sealed and/or isolated after fastening.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The different advantageous embodiments also recognize and take into account that the use of blind fasteners in supporting a load from a structure presents difficulties in repositioning the fastener. After positioning a device, such as a part hanger with respect to a structure, it may later be desired to move the hanger. As further described herein, a hanger is a structure adapted for receiving a load or part. In an illustrative embodiment, a hanger may have features that allow for attachment of different kinds and sizes of parts. These features may include, for example, without limitation, holes and brackets. However, the use of a fastener can increase the time and labor needed to move the hanger.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Thus, the different advantageous embodiments provide a method and apparatus for supporting a load on an aircraft stringer. In an advantageous embodiment, an apparatus comprises a flexible polymer clip that is connected to the stringer in a manner that does not use metal fasteners or blind fasteners. Pins positioned on members of the clip secure the clip to the stringer by engaging holes formed in the stringer. The clip may be secured in the connected position. Flexing the clip allows it to be repositioned. A hanger positioned on the clip allows various parts to be connected to the clip and to the stringer.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">As used herein, a first component &#x201c;connected to&#x201d; a second component means that the first component can be connected directly or indirectly to the second component. In other words, additional components may be present between the first component and the second component. The first component is considered to be indirectly connected to the second component when one or more additional components are present between the two components. When the first component is directly connected to the second component, no additional components are present between the two components.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">For example, the first component may be the clip and the second component may be the part to be connected to the clip. The hanger may be used in connecting the part to the clip.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, an illustration of a block diagram illustrating a load support environment is depicted in accordance with an advantageous embodiment. In this example, load support environment <b>301</b> includes structure <b>302</b> and jig <b>303</b> that may be used with aircraft structure <b>308</b>. Aircraft structure <b>308</b> may be an aircraft part, assembly, or component, such as, for example, stringer <b>304</b> or rib <b>309</b>. Jig <b>303</b>, and as further described herein, provides a guide structure with guide holes <b>365</b> being useful in forming holes in aircraft structure <b>308</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In an advantageous embodiment, structure <b>302</b> is connected to stringer <b>304</b> so as to support load <b>305</b>. Structure <b>302</b> may take the form of body <b>306</b>. Additionally, structure <b>302</b> may take the form of clip <b>307</b>. In an advantageous embodiment, structure <b>302</b> includes first member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b>. First member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b> may take the form of first arm <b>312</b> and second arm <b>314</b>. Additionally, first member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b> may be connected to each other by center portion <b>316</b>. Optionally, first member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b> are separate pieces, and center portion <b>316</b> is not present.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Center portion <b>316</b> may comprise a flexible connection such that structure <b>302</b> flexes. The flexing may allow first member <b>311</b> to move with respect to second member <b>313</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Structure <b>302</b> may flex to move between flexed position <b>318</b> and locked position <b>319</b>. Structure <b>302</b> also has inner surface <b>370</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">First member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b> may each comprise contact section <b>327</b> and projection <b>328</b>. Contact section <b>327</b> is shaped and configured to contact aircraft structure <b>308</b> when structure <b>302</b> is engaged with aircraft structure <b>308</b> as described herein. Contact section <b>327</b> may include curves so that contact section <b>327</b> makes substantial contact with a curved surface on aircraft structure <b>308</b>. Projection <b>328</b> may be configured to extend from contact section <b>327</b> in a substantially normal orientation. Projection <b>328</b> may be provided with holes <b>329</b> for attaching to flange <b>330</b> as further described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Structure <b>302</b> may further include number of pins <b>320</b>. In one illustrative example, number of pins <b>320</b> are unitary and formed with structure <b>302</b>. Alternatively, number of pins <b>320</b> may be separate pieces attached to structure <b>302</b>. Pin <b>321</b> in number of pins <b>320</b> may be disposed on first member <b>311</b>. Further, pin <b>321</b> in number of pins <b>320</b> may be disposed on second member <b>313</b>. In one advantageous embodiment, pin <b>321</b> comprises a protrusion that extends from first member <b>311</b> or second member <b>313</b>. Number of pins <b>320</b> may extend from contact section <b>327</b> of structure <b>302</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Structure <b>302</b> may further include flange <b>330</b>. In one advantageous embodiment, flange <b>330</b> is disposed so as to connect to first member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b>. Flange <b>330</b> may connect first member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b> in a spatial relationship that comprises a locked position <b>319</b>. Flange <b>330</b> may be a generally rigid piece which prevents movement of first member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">When flange <b>330</b> is not connected to both first member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b>, structure <b>302</b> may flex. However, when flange <b>330</b> is connected to both first member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b>, structure <b>302</b> cannot flex. As used herein, &#x201c;flex&#x201d;, &#x201c;flexing&#x201d;, and the like, means that structure <b>302</b> can bend or move. Flexing may comprise movement of center portion <b>316</b> such that the positions of first member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b>, relative to each other, can change. In other words, first member <b>311</b> may be moved closer to second member <b>313</b> by the flexing of structure <b>302</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In these illustrative examples, flange <b>330</b> may be connected to first member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b> using fastener <b>333</b>. A number of different fasteners in fastener <b>333</b> may be used, such as, for example, rivets, screws, and bolts. Fastener <b>333</b> may engage with holes <b>329</b> of projection <b>328</b> on first member <b>311</b> and projection <b>328</b> on second member <b>313</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In one illustrative example, hanger <b>340</b> is connected to flange <b>330</b>. In another advantageous embodiment, hanger <b>340</b> is a unitary piece with flange <b>330</b>. Also, hanger <b>340</b> may be connected to structure <b>302</b>. In one advantageous embodiment, hanger <b>340</b> is configured to connect part <b>382</b> to hanger <b>340</b>. Part <b>382</b> includes load <b>305</b>. In this manner, structure <b>302</b> may provide support for load <b>305</b>. Hanger <b>340</b> may comprise a generally rigid piece adapted for receiving other components or parts. For example, other aircraft parts, such as tubes, conduits, wiring, and wire assemblies may be attached to hanger <b>340</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Structure <b>302</b> may comprise a unitary piece or, alternatively, may comprise separate pieces. Structure <b>302</b> may be comprised of one or more different materials. These materials may be selected from one of a plastic, a metal, a metal alloy, a thermoplastic, and any combinations thereof. In one advantageous embodiment, structure <b>302</b> comprises a polymer material formed by injection molding.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In an illustrative example, structure <b>302</b> is configured to attach to aircraft structure <b>308</b>. In one illustrative example, aircraft structure <b>308</b> comprises stringer <b>304</b>. Stringer <b>304</b> may comprise part of aircraft <b>200</b> as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, including a part of airframe <b>202</b>. Stringer <b>304</b> may include outer surface <b>352</b> including first surface <b>353</b>, second surface <b>354</b>, and third surface <b>355</b>. Holes <b>357</b> may be formed in first surface <b>353</b> and second surface <b>354</b>. Structure <b>302</b> may attach to aircraft structure <b>308</b> and, as further described herein, structure <b>302</b> may be removed from aircraft structure <b>308</b> and/or repositioned on aircraft structure <b>308</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Structure <b>302</b> and stringer <b>304</b> are mutually configured so that they may engage. As used herein, the term &#x201c;engaged&#x201d;, &#x201c;engage&#x201d;, &#x201c;engaging&#x201d;, and the like means that when engaged, inner surface <b>370</b> of structure <b>302</b> substantially conforms to outer surface <b>352</b> of stringer <b>304</b>. Inner surface <b>370</b> may be in full or partial contact with outer surface <b>352</b>. Further, when engaged, structure <b>302</b> and stringer <b>304</b> are configured such that forces from load <b>305</b> are transferred through structure <b>302</b> to stringer <b>304</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Additionally, pin <b>321</b> disposed on first member <b>311</b> is configured to engage holes <b>357</b> in first surface <b>353</b>, and pin <b>321</b> in second member <b>313</b> is configured to engage holes <b>357</b> in second surface <b>354</b>. As used herein, when a pin engages with a hole, the term &#x201c;engages&#x201d; also means that the pin enters the hole. The engagement of pin <b>321</b> in holes <b>357</b> further acts to transfer load <b>305</b> through structure <b>302</b> to stringer <b>304</b>. Stringer <b>304</b> may also include third surface <b>355</b>. Third surface <b>355</b> may substantially engage with inner surface <b>370</b> of structure <b>302</b>, but in other embodiments, third surface <b>355</b> does not engage with inner surface <b>370</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Load support environment <b>301</b> may also include jig <b>303</b>. Jig <b>303</b> may comprise first arm <b>361</b> and second arm <b>363</b>. Guide holes <b>365</b> may be formed in first arm <b>361</b> and second arm <b>363</b>. Jig <b>303</b> is configured such that a jig inner surface <b>367</b> closely engages with outer surface <b>352</b> of stringer <b>304</b>. When jig <b>303</b> is closely engaged with stringer <b>304</b>, guide holes <b>365</b> are positioned relative to first surface <b>353</b> and second surface <b>354</b> of stringer <b>304</b> such that guide holes <b>365</b> are aligned where it is desired to form holes <b>357</b> in first surface <b>353</b> and second surface <b>354</b>. Holes <b>357</b> may thus be formed in first surface <b>353</b> and second surface <b>354</b> by a forming operation, such as, for example drilling, using guide holes <b>365</b> as a guide or template for the forming operation. Jig <b>303</b> may also include grip <b>381</b> which an operator may grasp for manually manipulating jig <b>303</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Part <b>382</b>, which may be suspended from hanger <b>340</b>, may comprise any number of articles in aircraft <b>200</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. For example, without limitation, part <b>382</b> may be a conduit, a pipe, a tube, a panel, a wiring bundle, or some other suitable part.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The illustration of load support environment <b>301</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is not meant to imply physical or architectural limitations to the manner in which an advantageous embodiment may be implemented. Other components in addition to, and/or in place of, the ones illustrated may be used. Some components may be unnecessary. Also, the blocks are presented to illustrate some functional components. One or more of these blocks may be combined and/or divided into different blocks when implemented in an advantageous embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">In an advantageous embodiment, structure <b>302</b> may be used with another structure <b>302</b> to support load <b>305</b>. In such an example, a first structure may be attached to a first stringer and a second structure may be attached to a second stringer. In such case, structure <b>302</b> includes first member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b> which are flexibly connected at center portion <b>316</b>. Center portion <b>316</b> is configured to flex so as to transition between flexed position <b>318</b> and locked position <b>319</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">In flexed position <b>318</b>, structure <b>302</b> is configured such that first member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b> may pass over a corresponding surface, such as first surface <b>353</b> and second surface <b>354</b> of aircraft stringer <b>304</b>. First member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b> may pass over stringer <b>304</b> without number of pins <b>320</b> disposed on each of first member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b>, impeding the movement of structure <b>302</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Structure <b>302</b> may engage with stringer <b>304</b> until inner surface <b>370</b> of structure <b>302</b> contacts outer surface <b>352</b> of stringer <b>304</b>. Contact may be made when center portion <b>316</b> contacts third surface <b>355</b> of stringer <b>304</b>. Structure <b>302</b> may be transitioned to locked position <b>319</b> in which number of pins <b>320</b> engages with holes <b>357</b>. Flange <b>330</b> may then be affixed to first member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b> so as to secure structure <b>302</b> in locked position <b>319</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, an illustration of a diagram of clip <b>407</b> is depicted in accordance with an advantageous embodiment. In this example, clip <b>407</b> is an example of a physical implementation of structure <b>302</b> shown in block form in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In this illustrative example, clip <b>407</b> is used in conjunction with stringer <b>404</b> of aircraft <b>401</b>. Aircraft <b>401</b> is an example of one physical implementation of aircraft <b>200</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. Stringer <b>404</b> includes outer surface <b>452</b>, as well as first surface <b>453</b>, second surface <b>454</b>, and third surface <b>455</b>. Clip <b>407</b> includes inner surface <b>470</b>. Inner surface <b>470</b> substantially engages with outer surface <b>452</b> of stringer <b>404</b>. Flange <b>430</b> is connected to clip <b>407</b>, and hanger <b>440</b> is connected to flange <b>430</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">First member <b>411</b> of clip <b>407</b> is shown engaged with first surface <b>453</b> of stringer <b>404</b>. Likewise, second member <b>413</b> of clip <b>407</b> is engaged with second surface <b>454</b>. Number of pins <b>420</b> is engaged with holes <b>457</b>. Clip <b>407</b> is depicted in locked position <b>422</b>. First member <b>411</b> is held in relationship with respect to second member <b>413</b> by flange <b>430</b>. Additionally, flange <b>430</b> is connected to each of first member <b>411</b> and second member <b>413</b> by fastener <b>433</b>. Flange <b>430</b> prevents center portion <b>416</b> of clip <b>407</b> from flexing. When in locked position <b>422</b>, clip <b>407</b> is positioned so that number of pins <b>420</b> is in place with respect to holes <b>457</b>, and inner surface <b>470</b> of clip <b>407</b> is engaged with outer surface <b>452</b>. Locked position <b>422</b> is an example of a physical implementation of locked position <b>319</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the physical dimensions of clip <b>407</b> may vary. In an advantageous embodiment, the dimensions of clip <b>407</b> are set so as to allow for the function of close engagement with stringer <b>404</b>, as well as positioning within the space of aircraft <b>200</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">A typical length is denoted by reference number <b>491</b> and may vary between about 1 inch to about 3 inches. A typical height is denoted by reference number <b>493</b> and may vary between about 2 inches to about 4 inches. A typical width is also denoted by reference number <b>495</b> and may vary between about 1.5 to about 4 inches.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5-8</figref>, various illustrations of diagrams of a clip as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> are depicted in accordance with an advantageous embodiment. Therefore, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5-8</figref> share the same reference numerals as <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> and may correspond to the same components and have similar structures and functions.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Turning now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, an illustration of a clip in a flexed position is depicted in accordance with an advantageous embodiment. In this view, clip <b>407</b> is depicted in flexed position <b>421</b>. Clip <b>407</b> has been flexed along center portion <b>416</b>. In flexed position <b>421</b>, the position of first member <b>411</b> relative to second member <b>413</b> has been changed. There is sufficient clearance so as to allow placement of clip <b>407</b> relative to stringer <b>404</b>. Number of pins <b>420</b> is held with sufficient standoff from outer surface <b>452</b> so as to allow movement of clip <b>407</b> relative to stringer <b>404</b>. Thus, in flexed position <b>421</b>, clip <b>407</b> may be moved both laterally along the length of stringer <b>404</b>, as well as toward or away from full engagement with stringer <b>404</b>. In flexed position <b>421</b>, clip <b>407</b> may be moved so as to allow an alignment of number of pins <b>420</b> with holes <b>457</b>. Clip <b>407</b> may be moved into flexed position <b>421</b> by manual manipulation of an operator. One form of manual manipulation is the squeezing by hand of first member <b>411</b> together with second member <b>413</b>. It is noted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> that flange <b>430</b> is not yet present on clip <b>407</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, an illustration of a diagram of a clip in a locked position is depicted in accordance with an advantageous embodiment. In this view, clip <b>407</b> is depicted in locked position <b>422</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">As compared to the flexed position <b>421</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, an operator has manipulated clip <b>407</b> so as to transition clip <b>407</b> to locked position <b>422</b>. In one advantageous embodiment, the operator releases hand squeezing of clip <b>407</b> which thereby allows clip <b>407</b> to flex back to locked position <b>422</b>. In another embodiment, the operator manually moves first member <b>411</b> and second member <b>413</b> to locked position <b>422</b>. Because number of pins <b>420</b> had been aligned with holes <b>457</b>, when clip <b>407</b> is transitioned to locked position <b>422</b>, number of pins <b>420</b> enter holes <b>457</b> and engages with holes <b>457</b>. It is noted that inner surface <b>470</b> of clip <b>407</b> is in engagement with outer surface <b>452</b> of stringer <b>404</b>. The contact of these surfaces provides load support through the transfer of mechanical forces there between.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> also depicts flange <b>430</b> affixed to first member <b>411</b> and second member <b>413</b> with fasteners <b>433</b>. The placement of flange <b>430</b> serves to maintain clip <b>407</b> in locked position <b>422</b>. First member <b>411</b> cannot move relative to second member <b>413</b> so as to flex clip <b>407</b> at center portion <b>416</b>. Consequently, number of pins <b>420</b> remains positioned in holes <b>457</b>. Thus, until flange <b>430</b> is removed, clip <b>407</b> remains connected to stringer <b>404</b>. Hanger <b>440</b> has been affixed to flange <b>430</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, an illustration of an exploded view of a clip and stringer is depicted in accordance with an advantageous embodiment. In this view, clip <b>407</b> is depicted in an exploded view relative to stringer <b>404</b>. Clip <b>407</b> is in locked position <b>422</b> and has not been transitioned to flexed position <b>421</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates that outer surface <b>452</b> of stringer <b>404</b> closely matches inner surface <b>470</b> of clip <b>407</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> also illustrates features of stringer <b>404</b> including first surface <b>453</b>, second surface <b>454</b>, and third surface <b>455</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, an illustration of a clip having a standoff from a stringer is depicted in accordance with an advantageous embodiment. In this view, clip <b>407</b> is depicted in locked position <b>422</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">Clip <b>407</b> has been positioned so as to provide standoff <b>805</b> between inner surface <b>470</b> of clip <b>407</b> and third surface <b>455</b> of stringer <b>404</b>. Standoff <b>805</b> is spacing between inner surface <b>470</b> and third surface <b>455</b>. Standoff <b>805</b> may be desired so as to compensate the tolerance zone of the stringer web thickness. It is noted that inner surface <b>470</b> in first member <b>411</b> and second member <b>413</b> remains engaged with outer surface <b>452</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, an illustration of a support system is depicted in accordance with an advantageous embodiment. In this view, first clip <b>903</b> is connected to first stringer <b>904</b> and second clip <b>907</b> is affixed to second stringer <b>908</b>. First clip <b>903</b> and second clip <b>907</b> are examples of clip <b>407</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">First clip <b>903</b> includes first flange <b>911</b> and first hanger <b>913</b>. Support <b>915</b> is affixed to first hanger <b>913</b>. Second clip <b>907</b> includes second flange <b>921</b> and second hanger <b>923</b>. Support <b>915</b> is also affixed to second hanger <b>923</b>. Support <b>915</b> is generally positioned so as to span the space between first stringer <b>904</b> and second stringer <b>908</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">Further, support <b>915</b> provides a positioning means for part <b>917</b>. In the illustrative example, part <b>917</b> is a conduit that includes collar <b>919</b>. Support <b>915</b> connects to collar <b>919</b> so as to maintain part <b>917</b> in a desired position relative to first stringer <b>904</b> and second stringer <b>908</b>. First clip <b>903</b> and second clip <b>907</b> are each in locked position <b>319</b> as referenced in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> with respect to first stringer <b>904</b> and second stringer <b>908</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">Should an operator desire to remove or reposition part <b>917</b>, the operator can easily do so. In order to remove part <b>917</b> it would be necessary to remove part <b>917</b> from support <b>915</b> and/or remove support <b>915</b> from first clip <b>903</b> and second clip <b>907</b>. In order to move part <b>917</b>, it may or may not be necessary to move first clip <b>903</b> and second clip <b>907</b>. If it is necessary to move first clip <b>903</b> and second clip <b>907</b>, it can be easily accomplished. An operator removes first flange <b>911</b> from first clip <b>903</b>. First clip <b>903</b> is flexed and transitioned to flexed position <b>318</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, thereby removing number of pins <b>933</b> from holes <b>935</b>. First clip <b>903</b> may then be moved to a desired position. A similar operation would take place for second clip <b>907</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, an illustration of a diagram of a clip is depicted in accordance with an advantageous embodiment. In this example, structure <b>1002</b> is an example of a physical implementation of structure <b>302</b> shown in block form in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. In this illustrative example, structure <b>1002</b> may be used in conjunction with a stringer, such as stringer <b>304</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">Structure <b>1002</b> includes first member <b>1011</b> and second member <b>1013</b>. First member <b>1011</b> and second member <b>1013</b> are separate structures. A flexible center portion <b>316</b> is not present. First member <b>1011</b> and second member <b>1013</b> may be independently moved and positioned with respect to one another. Flange <b>1030</b> is connected to first member <b>1011</b> and second member <b>1013</b> although fastener <b>333</b> has been removed for clarity. Holes <b>1029</b> of first member <b>1011</b> and second member <b>1013</b> are shown in alignment with corresponding holes on flange <b>1030</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">First member <b>1011</b> also includes contact section <b>1027</b> and projection <b>1028</b>. Second member <b>1013</b> also includes contact section <b>1027</b> and projection <b>1028</b>. Contact section <b>1027</b> and projection <b>1028</b> on each of first member <b>1011</b> and second member <b>1013</b> are oriented in a substantially normal configuration. Projection <b>1028</b> on each of first member <b>1011</b> and second member <b>1013</b> are sufficiently aligned to allow flange <b>1030</b> to connect first member <b>1011</b> and second member <b>1013</b>. Flange <b>1030</b> may comprise a substantially linear portion that connects first member <b>1011</b> and second member <b>1013</b>. Projection <b>1028</b> may also be oriented substantially along a center of contact section <b>1027</b>. Number of pins <b>1020</b> extends from contact section <b>1027</b> on each of first member <b>1011</b> and second member <b>1013</b>. Number of pins <b>1020</b> may comprise two pins with a first pin positioned on one side of a center of contact section <b>1027</b> and a second pin positioned on the other side of the center of contact section <b>1027</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, an illustration of a diagram of a jig is depicted in accordance with an advantageous embodiment. In this example, jig <b>1103</b> is an example of a physical implementation of jig <b>303</b> shown in block form in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. In this illustrative example, jig <b>1103</b> is used in conjunction with stringer <b>1104</b> of aircraft <b>1101</b>. Aircraft <b>1101</b> is one example of a physical implementation of aircraft <b>200</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">Jig <b>1103</b> includes first arm <b>1161</b> and second arm <b>1163</b>. Guide holes <b>1165</b> are present in each of first arm <b>1161</b> and second arm <b>1163</b>. Jig <b>1103</b> also includes jig inner surface <b>1167</b> that closely corresponds to stringer outer surface <b>352</b> as referenced in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. Jig <b>1103</b> is configured so as to closely engage with stringer <b>1104</b>. When jig <b>1103</b> is closely engaged with stringer <b>1104</b>, guide holes <b>1165</b> are positioned relative to first surface <b>1153</b> and second surface <b>1154</b> of stringer <b>1104</b> such that guide holes <b>1165</b> are aligned where it is desired to form holes <b>357</b>, as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, in first surface <b>1153</b> and second surface <b>1154</b>. Holes <b>357</b> may thus be formed in first surface <b>1153</b> and second surface <b>1154</b> by a forming operation, such as, for example, drilling, or using guide holes <b>1165</b> as a guide or template for the forming operation. Jig <b>1103</b> may also include grip <b>1181</b> for manually grasping jig <b>1103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">The different components shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4-9</figref> may be combined with components in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, used with components in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, or a combination of the two. Additionally, some of the components in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4-9</figref> may be illustrative examples of how components shown in block form in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> can be implemented as physical structures.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, an illustration of a flowchart of a process for forming holes in a stringer is depicted in accordance with an advantageous embodiment. The process is generally designated by reference number <b>1200</b> and may be a process for forming holes in a stringer using a jig. One example of this process may include forming holes with a jig as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>. The method may be implemented, for example, using jig <b>303</b> interacting with stringer <b>304</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">Process <b>1200</b> begins by positioning jig <b>303</b> on stringer <b>304</b> (operation <b>1201</b>). Jig <b>303</b> may be positioned such that jig inner surfaces <b>367</b> closely engages with outer surface <b>352</b> of stringer <b>304</b>. As desired, an operator may slide jig <b>303</b> along outer surface <b>352</b> until a desired location is obtained. Guide holes <b>365</b> in first arm <b>361</b> and second arm <b>363</b> of jig <b>303</b> is positioned so as to align with a desired location for the placement of holes <b>357</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">In a further step, holes <b>357</b> are formed in first surface <b>353</b> and second surface <b>354</b> of stringer <b>304</b> (operation <b>1202</b>). Forming holes <b>357</b> may take place by a drilling operation. The drilling may include positioning a tool or drill bit through guide holes <b>365</b> so as to form holes <b>357</b>. A plurality of holes <b>357</b> may be formed. In one advantageous embodiment, two holes <b>357</b> are formed in each of first surface <b>353</b> and second surface <b>355</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">In a further step, jig <b>303</b> is removed from stringer <b>304</b>. An operator may grasp grip <b>1081</b> to manually remove jig <b>303</b> (operation <b>1203</b>), with the process terminating thereafter.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, an illustration of a flowchart of a process for using a clip to support a part on a stringer is depicted in accordance with an advantageous embodiment. The process is generally designated by reference number <b>1300</b> and may be a process for supporting a load on a stringer using a clip. One example of this process may include supporting a part as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>. The method may be implemented, for example, using clip <b>307</b> interacting with stringer <b>304</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">Process <b>1300</b> begins by flexing clip <b>307</b> (operation <b>1301</b>). Flexing clip <b>307</b> transitions clip <b>307</b> from locked position <b>319</b> to flexed position <b>318</b>. Flexing clip <b>307</b> may take place by manually squeezing first member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b> so as to induce a flexing at central portion <b>316</b>. In flexed position <b>318</b>, clip <b>307</b> provides clearance for inner surface <b>370</b> of clip <b>307</b> to be moved along outer surface <b>352</b> of stringer <b>304</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">In a further step, clip <b>307</b> is positioned on stringer <b>304</b> (operation <b>1302</b>). In flexed position <b>318</b>, clip <b>307</b> can be easily moved to a desired position. Clip <b>307</b> is positioned such that number of pins <b>320</b> on both first member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b> align with holes <b>357</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">In a further step, clip <b>307</b> is transitioned from flexed position <b>318</b> to locked position <b>319</b> (operation <b>1303</b>). When the transition occurs, number of pins <b>320</b> enters holes <b>357</b>. The transition from flexed position <b>318</b> to locked position <b>319</b> may occur by an operator releasing a manual squeezing force on first member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b> so as to allow center portion <b>316</b> of clip <b>307</b> to spring back to locked position <b>319</b>. This kind of spring back transition may occur when clip <b>307</b> comprises a flexible polymer material. Alternatively, the transition to locked position <b>319</b> may occur by an operator manually moving clip <b>307</b> to that position. Inner surface <b>370</b> of clip <b>307</b> closely engages with outer surface <b>352</b> of stringer <b>304</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">In a further step, flange <b>330</b> is secured to clip <b>307</b> (operation <b>1304</b>). Flange <b>330</b> may be secured by connecting flange <b>330</b> with fastener <b>333</b> to first member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b>. Securing flange <b>330</b> to first member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b> prevents first member <b>311</b> and second member <b>313</b> from moving and, therefore, secures clip <b>307</b> in locked position <b>319</b>. Number of pins <b>320</b> remains in holes <b>357</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">In a further step, hanger <b>340</b> is attached to flange <b>330</b> (operation <b>1305</b>). Hanger <b>340</b> may be fastened to flange <b>330</b>. Alternatively, hanger <b>340</b> may be connected to clip <b>307</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">In a further step, load <b>305</b> is attached to hanger <b>340</b> (operation <b>1306</b>) with the process terminating thereafter. Load <b>305</b> may include part <b>382</b>. The close engagement of inner surface <b>370</b> and outer surface <b>352</b> allows for the efficient transfer of mechanical forces from clip <b>307</b> to stringer <b>304</b>. Thus, forces developed by load <b>305</b> are transferred through clip <b>307</b> to stringer <b>304</b> and thereby to other structures connected to stringer <b>304</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref>, an illustration of a flowchart of a process for using a clip is depicted in accordance with an advantageous embodiment. The process is generally designated by reference number <b>1400</b> and may be a process for supporting a part, such as, for example, supporting a part on a stringer using a clip. The method may be implemented, for example, using clip <b>307</b> interacting with stringer <b>304</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">Process <b>1400</b> begins by maintaining engagement of clip <b>307</b> with stringer <b>304</b> (operation <b>1401</b>). In one advantageous embodiment, clip <b>307</b> may comprise a structure having inner surface <b>370</b> with a shape configured to substantially conform to outer surface <b>352</b> of stringer <b>304</b>. Clip <b>307</b> may also comprise number of pins <b>320</b> which extends from inner surface <b>370</b>. Number of pins <b>320</b> are configured to engage holes <b>357</b> in outer surface <b>352</b> of stringer <b>304</b> when the structure is placed over outer surface <b>352</b> of stringer <b>304</b>, in addition to supporting the structure with respect to the stringer when a load is applied to the structure. Clip <b>307</b> may also comprise a number of members extending from the structure.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">In a further step, part <b>382</b> is supported with the number of members, wherein the number of members is configured to be connected to the part (operation <b>1402</b>). Part <b>382</b> may comprise a number of different parts used in aircraft assembly and manufacturing, such as, for example, a tube, a conduit, a wiring bundle, and the like. Other ancillary equipment, such as collars, fittings, and fasteners, may be used to support part <b>382</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">In a further step, flange <b>330</b> is secured to first arm <b>312</b> and to second arm <b>314</b> (operation <b>1403</b>). Flange <b>330</b> may be secured by attaching fasteners <b>333</b> to each of first arm <b>312</b> and second arm <b>314</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">In a further step, hanger <b>340</b> may be attached to flange <b>330</b> (operation <b>1404</b>). Hanger <b>340</b> may assist in connecting or supporting part <b>382</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">In a further step, part <b>382</b> is attached to hanger <b>340</b> (operation <b>1405</b>) with the process terminating thereafter. Part <b>382</b> may be attached using ancillary equipment, such as collars and supports. Additionally, part <b>382</b> may be supported by using multiple clips <b>307</b> positioned on more than one stringer <b>304</b>. An example of part <b>382</b> supported by more than one clip <b>307</b> and hanger <b>340</b> is illustrated in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>. Additionally, clip <b>307</b> may support part <b>382</b> at different locations on stringer <b>304</b>. In the example of a tube or conduit, part <b>382</b> may have a length that runs along a portion of stringer <b>304</b>. It may be necessary to support part <b>382</b> at a stringer <b>304</b> or between stringers at more than one lateral position. Thus, multiple clips <b>307</b> may be used at more than one lateral position in order to provide support for part <b>382</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">The placement of clip <b>307</b> may also be adjusted once part <b>382</b> is in place. For example, it may be necessary to temporarily move part <b>382</b> in order to gain temporary access to a portion of aircraft <b>200</b> that is blocked by part <b>382</b>. This may be accomplished by removing part <b>382</b> from hanger <b>340</b>, flange <b>330</b>, and/or clip <b>307</b>. It may not be necessary to remove clip <b>307</b>. Optionally, clip <b>307</b> may be removed. Part <b>382</b> may be replaced as needed. Additionally, the support for part <b>382</b> can be adjusted by movement of clip <b>307</b> after part <b>382</b> has been installed. Part <b>382</b> may be disconnected from clip <b>307</b>, and clip <b>307</b> may be moved to a different position on stringer <b>304</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">The flowcharts and block diagrams in the different depicted embodiments illustrate the architecture, functionality, and operation of some possible implementations of apparatus, methods, and computer program products. In this regard, each block in the flowcharts or block diagrams may represent a module, segment, an operation, or a portion of computer usable or readable program code, which comprises one or more executable instructions for implementing the specified function or functions. Some of the blocks may be performed by human operators, machines, or other types of operators.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">In some alternative implementations, the function or functions noted in the block may occur out of the order noted in the figures. For example, in some cases, two blocks shown in succession may be executed substantially concurrently, or the blocks may sometimes be executed in the reverse order, depending upon the functionality involved.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">In an advantageous embodiment of the disclosure described herein, a structure is provided that may interact with an aircraft stringer so as to support a load connected to the structure. The structure may take the form of a body or clip that has an inner surface configured to closely engage with an outer surface of the stringer. The structure may be flexed at a center portion so as to transition between a flexed position and a locked position. The structure may be positioned in the flexed position, and may be secured to the stringer in the locked position. An operator may squeeze the structure so as to transition the structure to the flexed position, and the operator may manually position the structure.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">In an advantageous embodiment of the disclosure described herein, a clip includes a first member and a second member. A number of pins are disposed on the first member and the second member. The pins are configured to engage with holes positioned on a first surface and a second surface of the stringer. A flange, such as a rigid bracket, may be secured between the first member and the second member so as to secure the position of the first member and the second member. Thus, securing the flange to the clip also prevents the number of pins from being removed from the holes in the stringer, and thereby the clip is locked into position with respect to the stringer.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">In another advantageous embodiment of the disclosure described herein, a jig may be used to form holes in a stringer. The jig may include a first arm and second arm that are generally formed so as to conform to the outer surface of the stringer. The jig may be placed over the stringer. Guide holes in each of the first arm and the second arm are positioned where it is desired to form the holes. The guide holes provide a means by which a tool, such as a drill, may be inserted so as to form the holes.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">The description of the different advantageous embodiments has been presented for purposes of illustration and description, and is not intended to be exhaustive or limited to the embodiments in the form disclosed. Many modifications and variations will be apparent to those of ordinary skill in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">Although an advantageous embodiment has been described with respect to aircraft, the advantageous embodiment may be applied to supporting structures in other types of platforms. For example, without limitation, other advantageous embodiments may be applied to a mobile platform, a stationary platform, a land-based structure, an aquatic-based structure, a space-based structure and/or some other suitable object. More specifically, the different advantageous embodiments may be applied to, for example, without limitation, a submarine, a bus, a personnel carrier, tank, a train, an automobile, a spacecraft, a space station, a satellite, a surface ship, a power plant, a dam, a manufacturing facility, a building and/or some other suitable object.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">Further, different advantageous embodiments may provide different advantages as compared to other advantageous embodiments. The embodiment or embodiments selected are chosen and described in order to best explain the principles of the embodiments, the practical application, and to enable others of ordinary skill in the art to understand the disclosure for various embodiments with various modifications as are suited to the particular use contemplated.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a structure having an inner surface with a shape configured to substantially conform to an outer surface of a stringer, the structure having a first arm and a second arm, the first arm contacting a first surface of the stringer and the second arm contacting a second, different surface of the stringer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first number of pins extending from the first arm of the structure and a second number of pins extending from the second arm of the structure, wherein the first number of pins are configured to engage a first number holes in the first surface of the stringer and the second number of pins are configured to engage a second number of holes in the second surface of the stringer when the structure is placed over the outer surface of the stringer and to support the structure with respect to the stringer when a load is applied to the structure;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a number of members extending from the outer surface of the structure, wherein the number of members is configured to be connected to a part; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a flange connected to the structure securing the structure in a locked position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the structure is configured to conform to the outer surface of the stringer when the number of pins are engaged with the holes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a structure is configured to transfer the load to the stringer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the structure is configured to flex such that at least one pin affixed to a first member and at the least one pin affixed to a second member may engage with the holes in the stringer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the structure comprises a thermoplastic.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the structure comprises a unitary piece.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the first member and the second member comprise separate pieces connected by a flange.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the apparatus is formed by injection molding.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A clip for connecting to an aircraft stringer comprising:
<claim-text>a first arm having a first number of pins;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second arm having a second number of pins;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a center portion, the first arm flexibly connected to the second arm at the center portion such that the clip has a flexed position and a locked position,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first arm configured to contact a first wall surface of the stringer in the locked position and the second arm configured to contact a second wall surface of the stringer in the locked position, the first number of pins configured to engage a first number of holes in the first wall surface and the second number of pins configured to engage a second number of holes in the second wall surface; and a flange connected to the first arm and the second arm and securing the clip in the locked position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The clip of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the first arm contacts a center wall surface of the stringer in the locked position and the second arm contacts the center wall surface of the stringer in the locked position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The clip of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref> further comprising a number of members extending from the outer surface of the structure, wherein the number of members is configured to be connected to a part.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The clip of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the center portion of the body does not contact the stringer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A clip for use with a stringer, comprising:
<claim-text>a body having a first arm, a second arm, and a center portion, the first arm and the second arm flexibly connected at the center portion, the first arm configured to contact a first surface of a stringer, and the second arm configured to contact a second surface of the stringer, the body configured to transition between a flexed position and a locked position by flexing the center portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one pin affixed to the first arm, the at least one pin of the first arm configured to engage a hole positioned in the first surface of the stringer in the locked position and to disengage the hole in the flexed position; at least one pin affixed to the second arm, the at least one pin of the second arm configured to engage the hole positioned in the second surface of the stringer in the locked position and to disengage the hole in the flexed position; and a flange securing the first arm and the second arm in the locked position, the body configured to receive the load when the first arm and the second arm are in the locked position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The clip of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> further comprising a hanger attached to the flange. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
