<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08621846-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08621846</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12715946</doc-number>
<date>20100302</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>346</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60286</main-classification>
<further-classification> 60297</further-classification>
<further-classification> 60303</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Gas/liquid mixing device for diesel exhaust aftertreatment</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5839828</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Glanville</name>
<date>19981100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8033099</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Ohshima et al.</name>
<date>20111000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 60286</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0237511</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ripper et al.</name>
<date>20041200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 60286</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0153761</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Bandl-Konrad et al.</name>
<date>20060700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4232391</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0035832</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hirata et al.</name>
<date>20070200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>359484</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0011777</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Cooke</name>
<date>20080100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>222 20</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0022670</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ichikawa</name>
<date>20080100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 60299</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0302088</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Koehler et al.</name>
<date>20081200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 60286</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0004082</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Takahashi et al.</name>
<date>20090100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4232391</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0005790</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Zhang</name>
<date>20100100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 60301</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0107614</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Levin et al.</name>
<date>20100500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 60303</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00012">
<othercit>German Office Action dated Oct. 22, 2012, 5 pgs.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>14</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60286</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110214415</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110908</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Thomas</last-name>
<first-name>Eric D.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Canton</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Thomas</last-name>
<first-name>Eric D.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Canton</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Cantor Colburn LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>GM Global Technology Operations LLC</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Detroit</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Denion</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas</first-name>
<department>3748</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Shanske</last-name>
<first-name>Jason</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An exhaust gas treatment system for an internal combustion engine comprises an exhaust gas conduit configured to receive and to deliver exhaust gas to a downstream exhaust treatment device. An injector bay extends outwardly from the exhaust gas conduit upstream of the exhaust treatment device and an exhaust fluid injector mounts through an opening in the injector bay and is in fluid communication with the exhaust gas conduit and oriented in an upstream direction to deliver an exhaust fluid to the exhaust gas in the upstream direction. An exhaust flow baffle extends outwardly from the injector bay and into the exhaust gas in an upstream direction. The exhaust flow baffle is located upstream of the exhaust fluid injector and is configured to define a turbulent, low pressure velocity field downstream thereof and proximate to the exhaust fluid injector.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="154.52mm" wi="264.84mm" file="US08621846-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="265.01mm" wi="161.46mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621846-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="253.41mm" wi="138.26mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621846-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="241.13mm" wi="142.41mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621846-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="238.42mm" wi="153.92mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621846-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="241.13mm" wi="152.57mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621846-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">Exemplary embodiments of the present invention are related to exhaust gas treatment systems, and, more specifically, to an exhaust gas treatment system for internal combustion engines and vehicles incorporating the same.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Manufacturers of internal combustion engines must satisfy customer demands and meet various regulations for reduced emissions and improved fuel economy. One example of a way to improve fuel economy is to operate an engine at an air/fuel ratio that is lean (excess oxygen) of stoichiometry. Examples of lean-burn engines include compression-ignition (diesel) and lean-burn spark-ignition engines. However, while lean-burn engines may have improved fuel economy, the exhaust gas emitted from such an engine, particularly a diesel engine, is a heterogeneous mixture that contains gaseous emissions such as carbon monoxide (&#x201c;CO&#x201d;), unburned hydrocarbons (&#x201c;HC&#x201d;) and oxides of nitrogen (&#x201c;NO<sub>x</sub>&#x201d;) as well as condensed phase materials (liquids and solids) that constitute particulate matter (&#x201c;PM&#x201d;). The commercial application of lean-burn engines has been limited due to a lack of effective methods to remove sufficient NO<sub>X </sub>from the lean exhaust gas stream before it exits the tail pipe to meet regulations. Thus, efficient reduction of NO<sub>X </sub>from lean-burn gasoline and diesel exhaust before it exits the tail pipe is important to meet future emission standards and improve vehicle fuel economy.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Several potential exhaust treatment systems have been proposed for vehicle applications. These systems employ various exhaust treatment devices. One such exhaust treatment system employs a urea selective catalyst reduction (SCR) catalyst and a NO<sub>X </sub>reductant (e.g., urea) that is injected upstream of the catalyst using a generally downstream facing fluid injector. The NO<sub>x </sub>reductant is converted to ammonia that is used to reduce NO<sub>X </sub>to N<sub>2</sub>. Use of urea as a reductant necessitates a urea distribution infrastructure and an on-vehicle monitoring system for this secondary fluid. Such systems require periodic catalyst regeneration involving fuel injection or injection of reductant to regenerate the storage material of the catalyst.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">An exhaust treatment technology, in use for high levels of particulate matter reduction, is the diesel particulate filter device (&#x201c;DPF&#x201d;). There are several known filter structures used in DPF's that have displayed effectiveness in removing the particulate matter from the exhaust gas such as ceramic honeycomb wall-flow filters, wound or packed fiber filters, open cell foams, sintered metal fibers, etc. Ceramic wall flow filters have experienced significant acceptance in automotive applications. The filter is a physical structure for removing particulates from exhaust gas and, as a result, the accumulation of filtered particulates will have the effect of increasing the exhaust system backpressure experienced by the engine. To address backpressure increases caused by the accumulation of exhaust gas particulates, the DPF is periodically cleaned, or regenerated. Regeneration of a DPF in vehicle applications is typically automatic and is controlled by an engine or other controller based on signals generated by engine and exhaust system sensors. The regeneration event involves increasing the temperature of the DPF to levels that are often above 600&#xb0; C. in order to burn the accumulated particulates.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">One method of generating the temperatures required in the exhaust system for regeneration of the DPF is to deliver unburned HC to an oxidation catalyst device disposed upstream of the DPF. The HC may be delivered by injecting fuel directly into the exhaust gas system typically using a downstream facing exhaust fluid injector. The HC is oxidized in the oxidation catalyst device resulting in an exothermic reaction that raises the temperature of the exhaust gas. The heated exhaust gas travels downstream to the DPF and burns the particulate accumulation.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">While systems that employ SCR catalysts and DPFs have been used for NO<sub>X </sub>and particulate reduction in exhaust gas flow streams, the packaging of the various devices has been problematic, particularly in relatively smaller vehicles having relatively shorter wheelbases, due to the reduced space available to package the desired combinations of devices and the associated injection systems required for the introduction of various exhaust treatment fluids. In some cases there is not enough room to package the catalyst and filter devices while also providing the needed mixing length for conversion of the injected urea into ammonia and vaporization of HC, particularly if the system also employs multiple exhaust treatment devices for the reduction of, or oxidation of, other exhaust constituents, including carbon monoxide (CO), various hydrocarbons (HC), particulate matter (PM) and the like.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In an exemplary embodiment, an exhaust gas treatment system for an internal combustion engine comprises an exhaust gas conduit configured to receive exhaust gas from an exhaust port of an internal combustion engine and to deliver the exhaust gas downstream to an exhaust treatment device. An injector bay extends outwardly from the exhaust gas conduit upstream of the exhaust treatment device and an exhaust fluid injector mounts through an opening in the injector bay and is in fluid communication with the exhaust gas conduit and oriented in an upstream direction to deliver an exhaust fluid to the downstream flowing exhaust gas in the upstream direction. An exhaust flow baffle extends outwardly from the injector bay and into the exhaust gas in an upstream direction. The exhaust flow baffle is located upstream of the exhaust fluid injector and is configured to define a turbulent low pressure velocity field downstream thereof and proximate to the exhaust fluid injector.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In another exemplary embodiment, an exhaust gas treatment system for an internal combustion engine comprises an exhaust gas conduit configured to receive exhaust gas from an exhaust port of an internal combustion engine and to deliver the exhaust gas downstream to a plurality of exhaust treatment devices. A selective catalytic reduction device is configured to reduce oxides of nitrogen in the exhaust gas. An injector bay extending outwardly from the exhaust gas conduit is located upstream of the selective catalytic reduction device and exhaust fluid injector is mounted through an opening in the injector bay in fluid communication with the exhaust gas conduit and oriented in an upstream direction to deliver an ammonia reductant to the exhaust gas in the upstream direction. An exhaust flow baffle extends outwardly from the injector bay into the exhaust gas in an upstream direction. The exhaust flow baffle is located upstream of the exhaust fluid injector and is configured to define a turbulent low pressure velocity field downstream thereof and proximate to the ammonia reductant delivery.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The above features and advantages, and other features and advantages of the present invention are readily apparent from the following detailed description of the best modes for carrying out the invention when taken in connection with the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Other features, advantages and details appear, by way of example only, in the following description of embodiments, the description referring to the drawings in which:</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic partial cross-sectional illustration of an exemplary embodiment of an internal combustion engine and exhaust gas treatment system as disclosed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an enlarged, partial cross-sectional perspective view of the exhaust gas treatment system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, taken at circle <b>2</b>, with certain features shown in phantom for purposes of description;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an enlarged, partial cross-sectional side view of the exhaust gas treatment system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> taken at circle <b>2</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is an enlarged, partial cross-sectional side view of the exhaust gas treatment system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> taken at circle <b>2</b>, illustrating exhaust flow characteristics therein; and</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an enlarged, partial cross-sectional plan view of the exhaust gas treatment system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> taken at circle <b>2</b>, illustrating exhaust flow characteristics therein.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The following description is merely exemplary in nature and is not intended to limit the present disclosure, application or uses. It should be understood that throughout the drawings, corresponding reference numerals indicate like or corresponding parts and features.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, an exemplary embodiment of the invention is directed to an exhaust gas treatment system, referred to generally as <b>10</b>, for the reduction of regulated exhaust gas constituents of an internal combustion engine, such as diesel engine <b>12</b>. It is appreciated that the diesel engine <b>12</b> is merely exemplary in nature and that the invention described herein can be implemented in various engine systems implementing an exhaust particulate filter. Such engine systems may include, but are not limited to, gasoline direct injection systems and homogeneous charge compression ignition engine systems. For ease of description and discussion, the disclosure will be discussed in the context of diesel engine <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The exhaust gas treatment system includes an exhaust gas conduit <b>14</b>, which may comprise several segments that function to transport exhaust gas <b>16</b> from the diesel engine <b>12</b> to the various exhaust treatment devices of the exhaust gas treatment system <b>10</b>. The exhaust treatment devices may include a first diesel oxidation catalyst device (&#x201c;DOC<b>1</b>&#x201d;) <b>18</b>. The DOC<b>1</b> may include a flow-through metal or ceramic monolith substrate <b>20</b> that is wrapped in an intumescent mat (not shown) that expands when heated, securing and insulating the substrate which is packaged in a stainless steel shell or canister <b>21</b> having an inlet and an outlet in fluid communication with exhaust gas conduit <b>14</b>. The substrate <b>20</b> has an oxidation catalyst compound (not shown) disposed thereon. The oxidation catalyst compound may be applied as a washcoat and may contain platinum group metals such as platinum (Pt), palladium (Pd), rhodium (Rh) or other suitable oxidizing catalysts, or combination thereof. The DOC<b>1</b> <b>18</b> is useful in treating unburned gaseous and non-volatile HC and CO, which are oxidized to form carbon dioxide and water.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">A selective catalytic reduction device (&#x201c;SCR&#x201d;) <b>22</b> may be disposed downstream of the DOC<b>1</b> <b>18</b>. In a manner similar to the DOC<b>1</b>, the SCR <b>22</b> may also include a flow-through ceramic or metal monolith substrate <b>24</b> that is wrapped in an intumescent mat (not shown) that expands when heated, securing and insulating the substrate which is packaged in a stainless steel shell or canister <b>25</b> having an inlet and an outlet in fluid communication with exhaust gas conduit <b>14</b>. The substrate <b>24</b> has an SCR catalyst composition (not shown) applied thereto. The SCR catalyst composition preferably contains a zeolite and one or more base metal components such as iron (&#x201c;Fe&#x201d;), cobalt (&#x201c;Co&#x201d;), copper (&#x201c;Cu&#x201d;) or vanadium which can operate efficiently to convert NO<sub>x </sub>constituents in the exhaust gas <b>16</b> in the presence of an injected exhaust fluid such as an ammonia (&#x201c;NH<sub>3</sub>&#x201d;) reductant. The NH<sub>3 </sub>reductant <b>23</b>, supplied from reductant supply tank <b>19</b> through conduit <b>17</b>, may be injected into the exhaust gas conduit <b>14</b> at a location upstream of the SCR <b>22</b> using an upstream oriented or facing injector <b>26</b>. The reductant may be in the form of a liquid or an aqueous urea solution when it is delivered to the exhaust gas <b>16</b> by the upstream oriented or facing injector <b>26</b>. A mixer or turbulator <b>27</b> may also be disposed within the exhaust conduit <b>14</b> in close downstream proximity to the upstream facing injector <b>26</b> to further assist in thorough mixing of the reductant <b>23</b> with the exhaust gas <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In one exemplary embodiment, an exhaust gas filter assembly, in this case a diesel particulate filter device (&#x201c;DPF&#x201d;) <b>28</b> is located within the exhaust gas treatment system <b>10</b>, downstream of the SCR <b>22</b> and operates to filter the exhaust gas <b>16</b> of carbon and other particulates. The DPF <b>28</b> may be constructed using a ceramic wall-flow monolith filter <b>30</b> that is wrapped in an intumescent mat that expands when heated, securing and insulating the filter which is packaged in a stainless steel shell or canister <b>31</b> having an inlet and an outlet in fluid communication with exhaust gas conduit <b>14</b>. Exhaust gas <b>16</b> entering the filter <b>30</b> is forced to migrate through adjacent longitudinally extending walls (not shown) and, it is through this wall-flow mechanism that the exhaust gas <b>16</b> is filtered of carbon and other particulates. The filtered particulates are deposited in the filter <b>30</b> and, over time, will have the effect of increasing the exhaust gas backpressure experienced by the diesel engine <b>12</b>. It is appreciated that a ceramic wall-flow monolith filter <b>30</b> is merely exemplary in nature and that the DPF <b>28</b> may include other filter devices such as wound or packed fiber filters, open cell foams, sintered metal fibers, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In an exemplary embodiment, the increase in exhaust backpressure caused by the accumulation of particulate matter requires that the DPF <b>28</b> is periodically cleaned, or regenerated. Regeneration involves the oxidation or burning of the accumulated carbon and other particulates in what is typically a high temperature (&#x3e;600&#xb0; C.) environment. For regeneration purposes a second diesel oxidation catalyst device (&#x201c;DOC<b>2</b>&#x201d;) <b>58</b> may be located upstream of the filter <b>30</b>, proximate to its upstream end. In the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the DOC<b>2</b> <b>58</b> is a flow-through metal or ceramic monolith substrate <b>60</b> that is wrapped in an intumescent mat (not shown) that expands when heated, securing and insulating the substrate which is packaged in the canister <b>31</b> of the DPF <b>28</b>. The substrate <b>20</b> has an oxidation catalyst compound (not shown) disposed thereon. The oxidation catalyst compound may be applied as a wash coat and may contain platinum group metals such as platinum (Pt), palladium (Pd), rhodium (Rh) or other suitable oxidizing catalysts, or combination thereof. While the embodiment described includes the DOC<b>2</b> <b>58</b> disposed in the canister <b>31</b> of the DPF <b>28</b>, it is contemplated that, depending on packaging and other system constraints, the DOC<b>2</b> <b>58</b> may also be disposed within a separate canister (not shown) that is located upstream of the DPF <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Disposed upstream of the DPF <b>28</b>, in fluid communication with the exhaust gas <b>16</b> in the exhaust gas conduit <b>14</b>, is an upstream oriented or facing HC or fuel injector <b>62</b>. The fuel injector <b>62</b>, in fluid communication with HC <b>65</b> in fuel supply tank <b>63</b> through fuel conduit <b>61</b>, is configured to introduce unburned HC <b>65</b> into the exhaust gas stream for delivery to the DOC<b>2</b> <b>58</b> associated with the DPF <b>28</b>. A mixer or turbulator <b>64</b> may also be disposed within the exhaust conduit <b>14</b>, in close, downstream proximity to the HC injector <b>62</b>, to further assist in thorough mixing of the HC with the exhaust gas <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">A controller such as vehicle controller <b>66</b> is operably connected to, and monitors, the exhaust gas treatment system <b>10</b> through signal communication with a number of sensors. As used herein the term controller may include an application specific integrated circuit (ASIC), an electronic circuit, a processor (shared, dedicated or group) and memory that executes one or more software or firmware programs, a combinational logic circuit, and/or other suitable components that provide the described functionality.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In an exemplary embodiment, a backpressure sensor <b>68</b>, located upstream of DPF <b>28</b>, generates a signal indicative of the carbon and particulate loading in the ceramic wall flow monolith filter <b>30</b>. Upon a determination that the backpressure has reached a predetermined level indicative of the need to regenerate the DPF <b>28</b>, the controller <b>66</b> activates the HC injector <b>62</b> to deliver HC <b>65</b> into the exhaust gas conduit <b>14</b> for mixing with the exhaust gas <b>16</b>. The fuel/exhaust gas mixture enters the DOC<b>2</b> <b>58</b> inducing oxidation of the HC in the exhaust gas <b>16</b> and raising the exhaust gas temperature to a level (e.g. &#x3e;600&#xb0; C.) suitable for regeneration of the carbon and particulate matter in the filter <b>30</b>. The controller <b>66</b> may monitor the temperature of the exothermic oxidation reaction in the DOC<b>2</b> <b>58</b> and the ceramic wall-flow monolith filter <b>30</b> through temperature sensor <b>70</b> and adjust the HC delivery rate of injector <b>62</b> to maintain a predetermined temperature.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Similarly, a NO<sub>x </sub>sensor <b>72</b> located downstream of the SCR <b>22</b> generates a signal indicative of the NO<sub>x </sub>levels in the exhaust gas <b>16</b> exiting the SCR <b>22</b>. Upon a determination that the NO<sub>x </sub>levels have reached a predetermined level the controller <b>66</b> activates the injector <b>26</b> to deliver reductant <b>23</b> into the exhaust gas conduit <b>14</b> for mixing with the exhaust gas <b>16</b>. The ammonia/exhaust gas mixture enters the SCR <b>22</b> where the ammonia reduces the NO<sub>x </sub>to N<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In an exemplary embodiment, and referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, enlarged views are shown of a portion of the exhaust gas conduit <b>14</b> of the exhaust gas treatment system <b>10</b> in which the ammonia reductant injector <b>26</b> is located in an upstream facing configuration. The views have been chosen to illustrate features of the ammonia reductant injector <b>26</b>; however, similar features and descriptions may also apply to the mounting, orientation and operation of the HC injector <b>62</b>. The exhaust gas conduit <b>14</b> includes an injector bay <b>40</b> that may be formed in the conduit or attached thereto as by welding or the like. The injector bay <b>40</b> includes an injector mounting flange <b>42</b> having an opening <b>44</b> formed therein for receiving the injection portion or tip <b>46</b> of injector <b>26</b> therein. A sealing collar <b>48</b> encircles the injector <b>26</b> to define a seal between the injector and the exhaust gas conduit <b>14</b> to thereby prevent leakage of exhaust gas <b>16</b> therebetween while fixing the injector <b>26</b> in place. The configuration of the injector bay <b>40</b> and orientation of the mounting flange <b>42</b> cooperate to orient the injector <b>26</b> in an upstream facing manner such that the axis <b>52</b> of the injector <b>26</b> is at an angle &#x3b1;, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, with respect to the axis <b>54</b> of the exhaust gas conduit <b>14</b>. The angle &#x3b1; (alpha) is preferably in a range from about 40&#xb0; to about 70&#xb0;, depending on exhaust characteristics such as flow volume and speed.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Extending outwardly from the injector bay <b>40</b> into the exhaust gas <b>16</b> flow upstream of the injection portion or tip <b>46</b> of the injector <b>26</b> is an exhaust flow baffle <b>65</b>. The baffle <b>65</b> extends in an upstream direction at an angle &#x3b3; (gamma) that configures the baffle in the exhaust gas <b>16</b> flow generally parallel to the axis <b>52</b> of the injector <b>26</b>. The upstream facing surface <b>72</b> of the exhaust flow baffle <b>65</b> has an outwardly facing (in the upstream direction) convex arcuate configuration that in some respects resembles the back side of a shoehorn. The arcuate upstream face <b>72</b> is configured to separate the downstream flow of exhaust gas <b>16</b> about the exhaust flow baffle <b>65</b>. The separation of the exhaust gas <b>16</b> flow around the exhaust flow baffle <b>65</b> will have the effect of increasing both the speed and the pressure of the exhaust gas <b>16</b> into higher pressure, higher velocity zones <b>78</b>, relative to the exhaust gas pressure upstream of the baffle <b>65</b>. A downstream facing surface <b>74</b> of the exhaust flow baffle <b>65</b> is convex or C-shaped and defines a turbulent low pressure, low velocity field <b>76</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, downstream of the exhaust flow baffle into which the ammonia reductant <b>23</b> is sprayed with an upstream orientation. The turbulent low pressure, low velocity field <b>76</b> is a relatively stagnant zone, downstream of the exhaust flow baffle <b>65</b> into which the higher speed exhaust gas velocity field <b>78</b> collapses towards the center of the exhaust gas conduit <b>14</b> thereby entraining the droplets of the ammonia reductant <b>23</b> into the exhaust gas <b>16</b> flow in a uniform distribution without impingement of the spray onto surfaces of the exhaust gas treatment system <b>10</b>. The collapse of the high speed exhaust gas velocity field <b>78</b> downstream of the exhaust flow baffle <b>65</b> gives the turbulent low pressure, low velocity field <b>76</b> a pressure characteristic that borders on suction allowing the entrained ammonia reductant <b>23</b>, or other exhaust fluid droplets (ex. HC in the case of HC injector <b>62</b>), to become spatially distributed therein and subsequently entrained by the high velocity field <b>78</b>, at the boundary layer <b>77</b>, and carried downstream to the SCR <b>22</b>, or other catalyst device of the exhaust treatment system <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The use of an upstream facing injector <b>26</b>, <b>62</b> with the baffle <b>65</b> allows injection of exhaust fluids such as ammonia reductant <b>23</b> or HC <b>65</b> in a shorter axial length and with less flow resistance to the flow of exhaust gas <b>16</b> than with more conventional mixer devices <b>27</b>, <b>64</b> which must otherwise be oriented downstream or perpendicular to the flow of exhaust gas <b>16</b>. In some cases the conventional mixer devices <b>27</b>, <b>64</b> may be eliminated. In addition, the entrainment of the ammonia <b>23</b> spray provides adequate transport time in the exhaust gas for required reactions (ex. conversion to NH<sub>3</sub>) to occur prior to entry of the exhaust gas into the SCR <b>22</b>, for instance. Additionally, the use of the baffle <b>65</b> facilitates the use of an upstream facing or oriented injector <b>26</b> or <b>62</b> which would not otherwise be possible due to deposit formation and excessive temperatures at the injection tip <b>46</b> caused by unshielded impingement of the exhaust gas <b>16</b> thereon.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">While the invention has been described with reference to exemplary embodiments, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes may be made and equivalents may be substituted for elements thereof without departing from the scope of the invention. In addition, many modifications may be made to adapt a particular situation or material to the teachings of the invention without departing from the essential scope thereof. Therefore, it is intended that the invention not be limited to the particular embodiments disclosed as the best mode contemplated for carrying out this invention, but that the invention will include all embodiments falling within the scope of the present application.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An exhaust gas treatment system for an internal combustion engine comprising:
<claim-text>an exhaust gas conduit having a central longitudinal axis and configured to receive exhaust gas from an exhaust port of an internal combustion engine and to deliver the exhaust gas downstream to an exhaust treatment device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an injector bay extending outwardly from the exhaust gas conduit upstream of the exhaust treatment device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an exhaust fluid injector mounted through an opening in the injector bay, in fluid communication with the exhaust gas in the exhaust gas conduit, and oriented in an upstream direction to deliver an exhaust fluid to the downstream flowing exhaust gas in the upstream direction; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an exhaust flow baffle extending outwardly from the injector bay into the exhaust gas and extending past the central longitudinal axis in an upstream direction, the exhaust flow baffle having an arcuate upstream face that is outwardly facing in the upstream direction and configured to separate the flow of exhaust gas thereabout, the exhaust flow baffle located upstream of the exhaust fluid injector and extending into the exhaust gas conduit from within the injector bay to define a turbulent, low pressure, low velocity field downstream thereof and proximate to the exhaust fluid injector and operable to entrain the delivered exhaust fluid, wherein the exhaust fluid is sprayed into the turbulent, low pressure, low velocity field, and wherein the exhaust flow baffle is coupled to a wall of the injector bay.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The exhaust treatment system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, the exhaust flow baffle further comprising:
<claim-text>a convex downstream face configured to define the turbulent, low pressure, low velocity field downstream of the exhaust flow baffle.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The exhaust treatment system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the exhaust fluid injector is oriented in the upstream direction at an angle &#x3b1; to an axis of the exhaust gas conduit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The exhaust treatment system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the angle &#x3b1; is in a range from about 40&#xb0; to about 70&#xb0;.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The exhaust treatment system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the exhaust flow baffle is oriented in the upstream direction at an angle &#x3b3; to an axis of the exhaust gas conduit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The exhaust treatment system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the angle &#x3b3; is in a range from about 40&#xb0; to about 70&#xb0;.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The exhaust treatment system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the exhaust fluid injector is oriented in the upstream direction at an angle &#x3b1; to an axis of the exhaust gas conduit and wherein the exhaust flow baffle is oriented in the upstream direction at an angle &#x3b3; to an axis of the exhaust gas conduit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The exhaust treatment system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the angle &#x3b1; and the angle &#x3b3; are about equal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The exhaust treatment system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the downstream exhaust treatment device comprises a selective catalytic reduction device and the exhaust fluid comprises an ammonia reductant.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The exhaust treatment system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the downstream exhaust treatment device comprises an oxidation catalyst device and the exhaust fluid comprises hydrocarbon.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. An exhaust gas treatment system for an internal combustion engine comprising:
<claim-text>an exhaust gas conduit configured to receive exhaust gas from an exhaust port of an internal combustion engine and to deliver the exhaust gas downstream to a plurality of exhaust treatment devices;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a selective catalytic reduction device configured to reduce oxides of nitrogen in the exhaust gas;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an injector bay extending outwardly from the exhaust gas conduit upstream of the selective catalytic reduction device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an exhaust fluid injector mounted through an opening in the injector bay, in fluid communication with the exhaust gas in the exhaust gas conduit, and oriented in an upstream direction to deliver an ammonia reductant to the downstream flowing exhaust gas in the upstream direction; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an exhaust flow baffle extending outwardly from the injector bay into the exhaust gas in an upstream direction and oriented in a direction substantially parallel with the exhaust fluid injector and the injector bay, the exhaust flow baffle located upstream of the exhaust fluid injector and extending into the exhaust gas conduit from within the injector bay to define a turbulent, low pressure, low velocity field downstream thereof proximate to the exhaust fluid injector, wherein the exhaust fluid is sprayed into the turbulent, low pressure, low velocity field, and wherein the exhaust flow baffle is oriented in a direction substantially parallel with the exhaust fluid injector such that an axis of the injector does not intersect the exhaust flow baffle within the exhaust gas conduit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The exhaust gas treatment system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>an oxidation catalyst device configured to oxidize hydrocarbon in the exhaust gas and to increase the temperature thereof;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an injector bay extending outwardly from the exhaust gas conduit upstream of the oxidation catalyst device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an exhaust fluid injector mounted through an opening in the injector bay, in fluid communication with the exhaust gas in the exhaust gas conduit, and oriented in an upstream direction to deliver hydrocarbon to the downstream flowing exhaust gas in the upstream direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an exhaust flow baffle extending outwardly from the injector bay into the exhaust gas in an upstream direction, the exhaust flow baffle located upstream of the exhaust fluid injector and configured to define a turbulent, low pressure, low velocity field downstream thereof proximate to the exhaust fluid injector; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an exhaust particulate filter downstream of the oxidation catalyst device and configured to receive the increased temperature exhaust gas for combustion of particulates therein.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The exhaust gas treatment system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, each of the exhaust flow baffles further comprising:
<claim-text>an arcuate upstream face configured to separate the flow of exhaust gas thereabout; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a concave downstream face configured to define the turbulent low pressure, low velocity fields downstream of the exhaust flow baffles.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The exhaust gas treatment system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein axes of the baffles are parallel to axes of the ammonia reductant and the hydrocarbon exhaust fluid injectors. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
