<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622755-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622755</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13067924</doc-number>
<date>20110707</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-155425</doc-number>
<date>20100708</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>155</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>03</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439 762</main-classification>
<further-classification>439 761</further-classification>
<further-classification>439535</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Connector cover and junction box unit provided with the same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5980297</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Sugie</name>
<date>19991100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439354</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6579113</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kodama</name>
<date>20030600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439358</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6696640</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Castellani et al.</name>
<date>20040200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>174483</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6786740</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Ito</name>
<date>20040900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439 762</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7699623</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Yoshida et al.</name>
<date>20100400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439 762</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7785116</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Akahori et al.</name>
<date>20100800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439 762</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0112831</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Asada</name>
<date>20100500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439 762</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2001-339824</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20011200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2005-051912</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20050200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>8</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>174 50</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>174520</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439 761</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439 762</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439535</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>12</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120006594</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120112</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Takeuchi</last-name>
<first-name>Kunihiko</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kakegawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ohashi</last-name>
<first-name>Fumiyoshi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kakegawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Takeuchi</last-name>
<first-name>Kunihiko</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kakegawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ohashi</last-name>
<first-name>Fumiyoshi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kakegawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Edwards Wildman Palmer LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Yazaki Corporation</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Thompson</last-name>
<first-name>Timothy J</first-name>
<department>2835</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Lee</last-name>
<first-name>Pete</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">There is provided a junction box unit that comprises a body to which a power integration unit is attached and a connector cover that positions a connector of a wiring harness with respect to the body. The connector cover comprises a holding portion holding the connector, a mounting portion attached to the body, and a main body to be accommodated therein. The mounting portion comprises an engagement projection and an engagement arm. The engagement projection protrudes from one end of the main body for locking engagement with a locking portion of the junction box body. The engagement arm includes an arm main body having one end continuing to an outer surface of the other end of the main body and a free end. A protrusion is provided at the central portion of the arm main body for locking engagement with the locking portion. When the protrusion is in locking engagement with the locking portion, the other end of the arm main body is positioned more outwardly of the body than the locking portion.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="122.77mm" wi="171.03mm" file="US08622755-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="263.91mm" wi="184.23mm" file="US08622755-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="261.62mm" wi="193.89mm" file="US08622755-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="264.33mm" wi="188.38mm" file="US08622755-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="251.71mm" wi="170.52mm" file="US08622755-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="268.39mm" wi="180.42mm" file="US08622755-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="257.98mm" wi="172.97mm" file="US08622755-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The Japan Patent Application No. 2010-155425 upon which this patent application is based is incorporated by reference herein.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to a connector cover adapted to be attached to an electrical junction box mounted in automobile or other vehicles, and to a junction box unit provided with the same connector cover.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Automobiles or other vehicles generally incorporate various electrical and electronic components including lamps such as a headlight and a taillight, electrical motors such as a starter motor and a motor for an air conditioning unit.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In order to power or provide electricity to these electrical or electronic components, junction blocks are provided at predetermined locations in the automobiles. The junction block integrates a set of electrical circuit units including a number of fuses and relays.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Since the junction block may comprise fuses, relays, and busbars, it may be referred to as a fuse block, a relay box, or more generically an electrical junction box. Also, in this document, the fuse blocks, relay boxes, and junction blocks are generically referred to as the electrical junction box.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The electrical junction box comprises a body defining its outer shape and a busbar provided inside of the body. The electric or electronic components such as relays, fuses, and a power integration unit incorporating the relays and fuses are mounted to the body.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">A connector of a wiring harness is connected to a lower surface of the body, the connectors being connected to various electronic components mounted in the automobile. A power cable that is connected to a battery or a generator is also connected to the body.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The body includes a space defined such that the power integration unit is accommodated therein. Provided in this space is a securing element adapted to secure the power integration unit. Also, other connectors of the wiring harness are connected to a lower surface of the power integration unit.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The busbar is adapted to electrically connect the power cable, electric components such as the fuses, relays, and power integration unit, and terminals of the connectors of the wiring harness, and the various electronic components to each other in accordance with predetermined patterns.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Electricity from a power source is fed to the electrical junction box via the power cable, and the electrical junction box distributes the electricity among the various electronic components via the fuses, relays, and power integration unit and via the electrical wires of the wiring harness or harnesses.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">A power integration unit serving as one of the electric components may be attached to the above sate of the art electrical junction box on an automotive assembly line. In such a case, the junction box unit, which is in a state where electric components other than the power integration unit and the connectors of the wiring harness are attached to the body, is conveyed to the automotive assembly line, the connectors of a desired wiring harness or harnesses are connected to the power integration unit on the automotive assembly line, and then the power integration unit is attached to the body, and thus the electrical junction box is assembled into a finished product.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The connector that has to be attached to the power integration unit may reside deep inside of or at the bottom of the electrical junction box, causing difficulty in pulling it out of the junction box. Further, the connectors of the wiring harness are connected to a large number of the terminals of the electrical wires. As a result, the electrical wires may get tangled with each other while the connectors that are to be attached to the power integration unit are accommodated in the body, and in the automotive assembly line, which hinders smooth mounting of the power integration unit to the electrical junction box.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In order to address this problem, the inventor of the present invention advocates a connector cover configured to hold the connectors, provisionally secured to the section of the body where the power integration unit is mounted, and previously position the connectors to be attached to the power integration unit, the positioning being defined with respect to the body. The connectors cover of this type need to be readily detachable from the body in order to facilitate mounting of the power integration unit on the automotive assembly line.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In view of the above, it is an object of the present invention to provide a connector cover that is readily detachable from the body and to provide a junction box unit that includes the same connector cover.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In order to attain the above objective, a first aspect of the present invention provides a connector cover that comprises (A) a main body sized and dimensioned to be accommodated in a body of an electrical junction box; (B) a holding portion configured to hold a connector of a wiring harness; and (C) a mounting portion configured to be attached to the body of the electrical junction box for mounting of the main body thereto. The connector cover is used to provide positioning of the connector of the wiring harness with respect to the body of the electrical junction box.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The mounting portion comprises (a) an engagement projection protruding from an outer surface of one end of the main body and configured to be brought into locking engagement with a locking portion provided on the body of the electrical junction box, the locking portion being configured to secure an electric component intended to be accommodated in the body of the electrical junction box, and (b) an engagement arm.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The engagement arm comprises (i) an arm main body having one end and an other end, the one end continuing to an outer surface of an other end of the main body and the other end being a free end, and (ii) a protrusion provided at a central portion of the arm main body and configured to be brought into locking engagement with the locking portion of the body of the electrical junction box.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In a state where the protrusion is in locking engagement with the locking portion, the other end of the arm main body is positioned more outwardly of the body than the locking portion.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Preferably, the connector cover further comprises a positioning rib protruding from the outer surface of the one end of the main body, extending lengthwise of the engagement arm, the positioning rib including a reduced portion whose degree of protrusion decreases as the reduced portion becomes more spaced from the holding portion.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Preferably, the connector cover comprises a pair of the positioning ribs such that the engagement projection is provided therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">An other aspect of the present invention provides a junction box unit that comprises (a) a body of an electrical junction box to which an electric component is attached; and (b) the connector cover having the above-described configuration and configured to be attached to the body and provide positioning of a connector of a wiring harness with respect to the body.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The connector cover of the present invention includes, but not limited to, the following advantageous effects.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Since the mounting portion includes the engagement projection and the engagement arm whose other end is positioned more outwardly of the body than the locking portion, the other end of the engagement arm can be readily moved such that the engagement arm can is taken out of locking engagement with the locking portion, allowing the connector cover to be readily detached from the body.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Also, by virtue of the positioning of the connector cover can be achieved with respect to the body. Also, since the positioning rib includes the reduced portion, the positioning rib is protected against being caught by the body as the locking engagement with the by the engagement arm is exited and the connector cover is detached from the body. It is appreciated that the connector cover is allowed to be readily and reliably detached from the body.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In addition, by virtue of the pair of the positioning ribs and the engagement projection provided therebetween, accurate positioning of the connector cover is achieved with respect to the body.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Other objects, features, and advantages of the present invention will be apparent in view of this disclosure to those skilled in the art.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The present invention is described in a preferred embodiment in the following description with reference to the drawings, in which like numbers represent the same or similar elements, as follows:</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a junction box unit according to one embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a plan view of the junction box unit illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a cross-sectional view taken along the line III-III in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a plan view of a body of the junction box unit illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective view of a connector cover of the junction box unit illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a perspective view of the connector cover illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is another perspective view of the connector cover illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a plan view of the first mounting portion of the connector cover illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a perspective view of the junction box unit illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a perspective view of the junction box unit illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> in which the connector cover is detached therefrom;</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a perspective view of illustrated of the connector cover illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> in which the connector of a wiring harness detached from the connector cover is attached to the power integration unit; and</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a perspective view of the power integration unit illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> that is attached to the body.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EXEMPLARY EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The connector cover and junction box unit according to one exemplary embodiment of the present invention is described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 12</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 3</figref>, there is shown a junction box unit <b>1</b> that comprises an electrical junction box <b>2</b> having a body <b>3</b> and a connector cover <b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The electrical junction box <b>2</b> is adapted to be mounted in automobile or other vehicles. The electrical junction box <b>2</b> comprises the body <b>3</b> (illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), a power integration unit <b>5</b> serving as an electric component (illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>), a not-shown upper cover, and a lower cover <b>6</b> (illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 4</figref>, the body <b>3</b> has a rectangular shape in plan view. Various electric components such as a relay <b>7</b> (illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) and a fuse <b>36</b> (illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) are attached to the body <b>3</b> at an upper surface thereof. The upper surface of the body <b>3</b> is illustrated in an upper portion of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. Also, a connector <b>9</b> (as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>) of an automotive wiring harness <b>8</b> (shown partly in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>) is connected to the body <b>3</b> at a lower surface thereof. The lower surface is illustrated in a lower portion of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The wiring harness <b>8</b> includes a plurality of electrical wires <b>10</b> (shown partly in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>) and a plurality of the connectors <b>9</b> (shown partly in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>) each attached to a group of ends of the electrical wires <b>10</b>. Some of the connectors <b>9</b> are adapted to be connected to the various electronic components incorporated in the automobile, while the other thereof are connected to the lower surface of the body <b>3</b>, and remaining two connectors are connected to a lower surface of the power integration unit <b>5</b>. The lower surface of the power integration unit <b>5</b> is illustrated in a lower portion of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the body <b>3</b> includes a component accommodation portion <b>11</b>. The component accommodation portion <b>11</b> is provided near an edge of the body <b>3</b> such that the component accommodation portion <b>11</b> defines a space extending through the body <b>3</b> in a direction in which the upper and lower surfaces are opposed to each other.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The component accommodation portion <b>11</b> has a rectangular shape in plan view. A length direction in a planar dimension of the accommodation portion <b>11</b> is parallel to a length direction in a planar dimension of the body <b>3</b>. The component accommodation portion <b>11</b> has two inner surfaces <b>11</b><i>a </i>opposed to each other in the length direction, and the inner surfaces <b>11</b><i>a </i>each include a locking arm <b>12</b> (serving as a locking portion in the context of the scope of protection of the present invention) and a pair of positioning grooves <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The locking arm <b>12</b> in its literal sense takes a shape of an arm and includes one end continuing to the edge of the inner surface <b>11</b><i>a </i>at the lower side and the other end residing at the upper side and provided as a free end. A throughhole <b>14</b> is provided at the centre of the locking arm <b>12</b> over a substantially full length of the locking arm <b>12</b>. A later-described engagement projection <b>15</b> of the power integration unit <b>5</b> enters the throughhole <b>14</b> such that the engagement projection <b>15</b> is caught by the above-described other end, so that the engagement projection <b>15</b> of the power integration unit <b>5</b> is brought into locking engagement with the locking arm <b>12</b>. By virtue of the locking engagement with the engagement projection <b>15</b>, the locking arm <b>12</b> secures the power integration unit <b>5</b> to the body <b>3</b> in a state where the power integration unit <b>5</b> is accommodated in the component accommodation portion <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The positioning grooves <b>13</b> are provided in a shape of a recess on the inner surface <b>11</b><i>a </i>such that the locking arm <b>12</b> is positioned therebetween. Also, a length direction of the positioning groove <b>13</b> is parallel to a length direction of the locking arm <b>12</b>. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the pair of positioning grooves <b>13</b> each include parallel portions <b>27</b> provided in a shape of a recess on the inner surface <b>11</b><i>a </i>and parallel to each other, and spaced-apart portions <b>28</b> continuing to the parallel portions <b>27</b> and extending in a direction away from each other.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Also, a terminal fitting attached to an end of the power cable connected to a power source such as a battery and a generator is attached to the body <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">A not-shown busbar is provided inside of the body <b>3</b>. The busbar is obtained by punching and bending of a conductive metal plate. The busbar is adapted to electrically connect the relay <b>7</b> and fuse <b>36</b> attached to the upper surface of the body <b>3</b>, the terminals of the connectors <b>9</b> of the wiring harness <b>8</b> attached to the lower surface thereof, the terminal fitting attached to the end of the power cable, and the power integration unit <b>5</b> to each other in accordance with a predetermined pattern.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, the power integration unit <b>5</b> has an external appearance of a flat box sized and dimensioned to be accommodated in the component accommodation portion <b>11</b>. The power integration unit <b>5</b> accommodates therein a circuit board incorporating thereupon the relays and fuses.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The connector <b>9</b> of the wiring harness <b>8</b> is connected to the lower surface of the power integration unit <b>5</b>, the lower surface being illustrated in the lower portion of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>. The terminal of the connector <b>9</b> is connected to the circuit board residing in the power integration unit <b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Electrical power from the power source is fed to the circuit board via the busbar disposed within the body <b>3</b>. Also, the power integration unit <b>5</b> includes engagement projections <b>15</b> on the both ends thereof in its length direction, the engagement projections <b>15</b> taking a shape of a projection and sized and dimensioned to be brought into locking engagement with the locking arm <b>12</b>; and a rib <b>16</b> sized and dimensioned to enter the positioning groove <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The power integration unit <b>5</b> is inserted into the component accommodation portion <b>11</b> in a state where the connector <b>9</b> of the wiring harness <b>8</b> is connected to the lower surface of the power integration unit <b>5</b>. In this manner, the power integration unit <b>5</b> is accommodated in the body <b>3</b> with the engagement projection <b>15</b> brought into locking engagement with the locking arm <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The upper cover is made of insulating synthetic resin and configured to be attached to the body <b>3</b> such that the top surface of the body <b>3</b> is covered by the upper cover. The lower cover is made of insulating synthetic resin and configured to be attached to the body <b>3</b> such that the lower surface of the body <b>3</b> is covered by the lower cover.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The electrical junction box <b>2</b> having the above-described configuration supplies part of the electricity from the power cable via the relay <b>7</b>, fuse <b>36</b>, and the fuses and relays in the power integration unit <b>5</b>, and by way of the wiring harness <b>8</b>, to the electronic components incorporated in the automobile.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The connector cover <b>4</b> is adapted and configured to provide positioning of the connector <b>9</b> of the wiring harness <b>8</b> attached to the power integration unit <b>5</b>, the positioning being provided relative to the body <b>3</b> to which the power integration unit <b>5</b> is yet to be attached.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The connector cover <b>4</b> is made of insulating synthetic resin and in a shape of a flat box with size and dimensions that allow the connector over <b>11</b> to be accommodated in the component accommodation portion <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 to 7</figref>, the connector cover <b>4</b> includes a box-shaped main body <b>17</b>, a holding portion <b>18</b>, and a mounting portion <b>19</b>. When the connector cover <b>4</b> is attached to the body <b>3</b>, the main body <b>17</b> is accommodated in the component accommodation portion <b>11</b> and thus in the body <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The holding portion <b>18</b> continues to the main body <b>17</b> adapted to be accommodated in the component accommodation portion <b>11</b> at a lower side of the body <b>3</b>. The holding portion <b>18</b> includes a plurality of extended walls <b>20</b> extending downward from the main body <b>17</b> in parallel with each other (four walls shown in the illustrated example); and hooking walls <b>21</b> each continuing to an end of the extended walls <b>20</b>, the end being a distal end with respect to the main body <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The extended walls <b>20</b> each include in one piece therewith an engagement arm <b>22</b> adapted to be brought into locking engagement with an outer surface of the connector <b>9</b>. The hooking walls <b>21</b> each extend in a direction in which the mutually adjacent pair of the extended walls <b>20</b> become close to each other.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The holding portion <b>18</b> having the above-described configuration positions the connector <b>9</b> between the mutually adjacent two extended walls <b>20</b> and between the main body <b>17</b> and the hooking wall <b>21</b> so that the connector <b>9</b> is held thereby. At this point, the engagement arm <b>22</b> and the outer surface of the connector <b>9</b> are placed in locking engagement with each other, so that the connector <b>9</b> is not inadvertently detached from the main body <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The mounting portion <b>19</b> includes a first mounting portion <b>23</b> and a second mounting portion <b>24</b>. In a state where the main body <b>17</b> of the connector cover <b>4</b> is accommodated in the component accommodation portion <b>11</b> of the body <b>3</b>, the first mounting portion <b>23</b> resides on an outer surface of one end <b>17</b><i>a </i>of the main body <b>17</b> in its length direction, the one end <b>17</b><i>a </i>facing the one locking arm <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the first mounting portion <b>23</b> includes an engagement projection <b>25</b> and a pair of positioning ribs <b>26</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The engagement projection <b>25</b> protrudes from the outer surface of the one end <b>17</b><i>a </i>of the main body <b>17</b> in its length direction. The engagement projection <b>25</b> is adapted, in a state where the main body <b>17</b> is accommodated in the component accommodation portion <b>11</b>, enters the throughhole <b>14</b> of the locking arm <b>12</b> to be brought into locking engagement with the locking arm <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The pair of positioning ribs <b>26</b> are provided such that the engagement projection <b>25</b> is positioned therebetween, and each have a shape of a protrusion formed on the outer surface of the one end <b>17</b><i>a </i>of the main body <b>17</b> in its length direction and in a direction orthogonal to the outer surface. The positioning ribs <b>26</b> each extend in a straight manner and in parallel with the length direction of the later-described engagement arm <b>30</b> of the second mounting portion <b>24</b>. When the main body <b>17</b> is accommodated in the component accommodation portion <b>11</b>, the positioning ribs <b>26</b> only enter the parallel portion <b>27</b> of the positioning groove <b>13</b> to position the main body <b>17</b> (and accordingly the connector cover <b>4</b>) with respect to the component accommodation portion <b>11</b> (and accordingly to the body <b>3</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">Also, a reduced portion <b>29</b> in the context of the scope of protection of the present invention is provided at an end of the pair of positioning ribs <b>26</b> close to the upper surface of the body <b>3</b> and away from the holding portion <b>18</b>. The amount of protrusion of the reduced portion <b>29</b> with reference to the outer surface of the main body <b>17</b> decreases as the reduced portion <b>29</b> becomes close to the end of the positioning rib <b>26</b> on the side of the upper surface and becomes away from the holding portion <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">When the main body <b>17</b> is accommodated in the component accommodation portion <b>11</b>, the second mounting portion <b>24</b> will be found on the outer surface of the other end <b>17</b><i>b </i>of the main body <b>17</b> facing the other locking arm <b>12</b> in the length direction. The second mounting portion <b>24</b> includes one engagement arm <b>30</b> and a pair of positioning ribs <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">The engagement arm <b>30</b> includes, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, an arm main body <b>32</b> and a protrusion <b>33</b>. The arm main body <b>32</b> has a shape of a strip, whose one end continues to a lower portion of the outer surface of the other end <b>17</b><i>b </i>of the main body <b>17</b>, and the other end being a free end extending from the one end toward the upper surface. The protrusion <b>33</b> is provided at a central portion of the arm main body <b>32</b> in a protruding manner. The protrusion <b>33</b>, when the main body <b>17</b> is accommodated in the component accommodation portion <b>11</b>, enters the throughhole <b>14</b> of the locking arm <b>12</b> to be brought into locking engagement with the locking arm <b>12</b>. When the protrusion <b>33</b> is brought into locking engagement with the locking arm <b>12</b>, the other end opposite the free end of the arm main body <b>32</b> will protrude closer to the upper surface and accordingly the out of the body <b>3</b> than the tip on the side of the upper surface of the locking arm <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">The pair of positioning ribs <b>31</b> are provided such that the engagement arm <b>30</b> is positioned therebetween, and each extend in a straight manner and in parallel with the length direction of the engagement arm <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The positioning ribs <b>31</b> each include in one piece therewith an orthogonal protruding portion <b>34</b> and a parallel protruding portion <b>35</b>. The orthogonal protruding portion <b>34</b> protrudes from the outer surface of the other end <b>17</b><i>b </i>of the main body <b>17</b> in its length direction and extending in a direction orthogonal to the outer surface, and is configured to enter the parallel portion <b>27</b>. The parallel protruding portion <b>35</b> continues to the tip of the orthogonal protruding portion <b>34</b> and extends in a direction in which the pair of positioning ribs <b>31</b> becomes away from each other, and in parallel with the outer surface, and is configured to enter the spaced-apart portion <b>28</b>. When the main body <b>17</b> is accommodated in the component accommodation portion <b>11</b>, the positioning rib <b>31</b> enters the positioning groove <b>13</b> and positions the main body <b>17</b>, and positions, by virtue of positioning of the main body <b>17</b>, the connector cover <b>4</b> with respect to the component accommodation portion <b>11</b> and thus with respect to the body <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The connector cover <b>4</b> having the above-described configuration is used in the following manner as the electrical junction box <b>2</b> is assembled into a finished product.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">First, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, in a state where the connector <b>9</b> to be attached to the power integration unit <b>5</b> is held by the holding portion <b>18</b>, the connector cover <b>4</b> is accommodated in the component accommodation portion <b>11</b> to be attached to the body <b>3</b>, and in this state conveyed as the junction box unit <b>1</b> to the automotive assembly line. At this point, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the engagement projection <b>25</b> is in locking engagement with one of the locking arms <b>12</b>, the protrusion <b>33</b> of the engagement arm <b>30</b> is in locking engagement with the other of the locking arms <b>12</b>, and thus the connector cover <b>4</b> is secured to the body <b>3</b>. Here, it is appreciated that the positioning ribs <b>26</b> and <b>31</b> reside in the positioning groove <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">Also, on the automotive assembly line, the other end of the engagement arm <b>30</b> protruding closer to the protrusion <b>33</b> of the arm main body <b>32</b> is moved close to the main body <b>17</b>, so that the locking engagement with the other locking arm <b>12</b> of the engagement arm <b>30</b> is exited. Further, the connector cover <b>4</b> is rotated about one end <b>17</b><i>a </i>of the main body <b>17</b>, taken out of the component accommodation portion <b>11</b>, and detached from the body <b>3</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>. Here, it is appreciated that the connector <b>9</b> held by the holding portion <b>18</b> is taken out of the body <b>3</b> in conjunction with the connector cover <b>4</b>. Also, the connector <b>9</b> is detached from the connector cover <b>4</b>, and these connectors <b>9</b> are attached to the power integration unit <b>5</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">Further, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, the power integration unit <b>5</b> is accommodated in the component accommodation portion <b>11</b> to be attached to the body <b>3</b>. After that, the upper cover is attached to the electrical junction box <b>2</b>, the electrical junction box <b>2</b> is assembled into the finished product, and then mounted in the automobile.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">In this manner, the electrical junction box <b>2</b> that has been assembled and mounted in the automobile distributes the electrical power from the automobile's power source via the relay <b>7</b>, fuse <b>36</b>, and power integration unit <b>5</b>, to the electronic components of the automobile.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">According to this embodiment, the mounting portion <b>19</b> includes the engagement projection <b>25</b> protruding from the one end of the main body <b>17</b> and the engagement arm <b>30</b> provided at the other end of the main body <b>17</b>, and the other end of the engagement arm <b>30</b> is more outwardly positioned than the locking arm <b>12</b> provided on the body <b>3</b>. By virtue of this configuration, the other end of the engagement arm <b>30</b> can be moved in the direction toward the outer surface of the main body <b>17</b> to exit the state of locking engagement with the locking arm <b>12</b>, and the state of locking engagement with the engagement arm <b>30</b> is readily exited. Thus, the connector cover <b>4</b> can be readily detached from the body <b>3</b>. Accordingly, the connector cover <b>4</b> can be readily detached from the body <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">Since the one end <b>17</b><i>a </i>of the main body <b>17</b> where the engagement projection <b>25</b> is provided includes the positioning ribs <b>26</b>, positioning of the connector cover <b>4</b> attached to the body <b>3</b> can be realized by the positioning ribs <b>26</b>. Also, since the positioning ribs <b>26</b> each include the reduced portion <b>29</b> whose degree of protrusion decreases as the reduced portion <b>29</b> becomes away from the holding portion <b>18</b>, it is made possible to prevent the positioning ribs <b>26</b> from getting caught by the body <b>3</b> as locking engagement of the engagement arm <b>30</b> is exited and the connector cover <b>4</b> is detached from the body. Thus, the connector cover <b>4</b> can be reliably detached from the body <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">Since the pair of the positioning ribs <b>26</b> are provided and the engagement projection <b>25</b> is positioned between the pair of the positioning ribs <b>26</b>, positioning of the connector cover <b>4</b> attached to the body <b>3</b> can be reliably achieved.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">Also, since the junction box unit <b>1</b> includes the connector cover <b>4</b>, the other end of the engagement arm <b>30</b> can be readily moved in the direction in which it is taken out of locking engagement with the locking arm <b>12</b>, the state of locking engagement with the engagement arm <b>30</b> can be readily exited, and the connector cover <b>4</b> can be readily detached from the body <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">It should be noted that, in the above-described embodiment, the connector cover <b>4</b> is detached from the body <b>3</b> and the power integration unit <b>5</b> is attached to the body <b>3</b> and thus the electrical junction box <b>2</b> is assembled. However, the present invention may be configured such that the connector cover <b>4</b> remains attached to the body <b>3</b> and the power integration unit <b>5</b> is not attached to the body <b>3</b>, and thus the electrical junction box <b>2</b> is assembled.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">It should be noted that, in the above-described embodiment, the connector cover <b>4</b> is configured to hold the connector <b>9</b> that is attached to the power integration unit <b>5</b> serving as the electric component. However, the present invention may be configured such that the connector cover <b>4</b> is configured to hold the connector <b>9</b> that is attached to the relay <b>7</b> or any other electric component other than the power integration unit <b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">While the exemplary embodiments of the present invention have been described by way of example, it will be appreciated by those skilled in the art may make various modifications in the light of the above teaching and within the scope and spirit of the present invention, and the scope of the invention is to be defined by the claims appended hereto.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>That which is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A connector cover comprising:
<claim-text>a main body sized and dimensioned to be accommodated in a body of an electrical junction box; a holding portion configured to hold a connector of a wiring harness; and a mounting portion configured to be attached to the body of the electrical junction box for mounting of the main body thereto such that positioning of the connector of the wiring harness with respect to the body of the electrical junction box is provided, wherein the mounting portion including comprising: a first mounting portion; and a second mounting portion; and wherein the first mounting portion comprising an engagement projection protruding from an outer surface of one end of the main body and configured to be brought into locking engagement with a locking portion provided on the body of the electrical junction box, the locking portion being configured to secure an electric component intended to be accommodated in the body of the electrical junction box, and a positioning rib protruding from the outer surface of the one end of the main body, extending lengthwise of the engagement arm, the positioning rib including a reduced portion whose degree of protrusion decreases as the reduced portion becomes more spaced from the holding portion, and the second mounting portion comprising an engagement arm including an arm main body having one end and an other end, the one end continuing to an outer surface of an other end of the main body and the other end being a free end, and a protrusion provided at a central portion of the arm main body and configured to be brought into locking engagement with the locking portion of the body of the electrical junction box, wherein, in a state where the protrusion is in locking engagement with the locking portion, the other end of the arm main body is positioned more outwardly of the body than the locking portion, and wherein the connector cover is capable of being detachably attached to the body of the electrical junction box.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The connector cover recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising a pair of the positioning ribs such that the engagement projection is provided therebetween.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A junction box unit comprising:
<claim-text>(a) a body of an electrical junction box to which an electric component is attached; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) the connector cover of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> the connector cover being configured to be attached to the body and provide positioning of a connector of a wiring harness with respect to the body.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A junction box unit comprising:
<claim-text>(a) a body of an electrical junction box to which an electric component is attached; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) the connector cover of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, the connector cover being configured to be attached to the body and provide positioning of a connector of a wiring harness with respect to the body.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The connector cover recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein during assembly of an article to be assembled, the connector cover in a state where the connector cover is attached to the body of the electrical junction box while holding the connector therewith is configured to be detached from the body of the electrical junction box, and then to be detached from the connector, thereby allowing the connector to attach to a desired electric component being received in the electrical junction box.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The connector cover recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, when the connector cover is detached from the body of the electrical junction box, the protrusion exits the locking engagement with the locking portion and the other end of the arm main body is moved close to the main body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The connector cover recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the connector cover is detached from the body of the electrical junction box by a rotation of the connector cover about the one end of the main body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A connector cover comprising:
<claim-text>a main body sized and dimensioned to be accommodated in a body of an electrical junction box; a holding portion configured to hold a connector of a wiring harness; and a mounting portion configured to be attached to the body of the electrical junction box for mounting of the main body thereto such that positioning of the connector of the wiring harness with respect to the body of the electrical junction box is provided, wherein the mounting portion comprising: a first mounting portion; and a second mounting portion; and wherein the first mounting portion comprising an engagement projection protruding from an outer surface of one end of the main body and configured to be brought into locking engagement with a locking portion provided on the body of the electrical junction box, the locking portion being configured to secure an electric component intended to be accommodated in the body of the electrical junction box, and the second mounting portion comprising an engagement arm including an arm main body having one end and an other end, the one end continuing to an outer surface of an other end of the main body and the other end being a free end, and a protrusion provided at a central portion of the arm main body and configured to be brought into locking engagement with the locking portion of the body of the electrical junction box, wherein, in a state where the protrusion is in locking engagement with the locking portion, the other end of the arm main body is positioned more outwardly of the body than the locking portion, wherein the connector cover is capable of being detachably attached to the body of the electrical junction box, and wherein during assembly of an article to be assembled, the connector cover in a state where the connector cover is attached to the body of the electrical junction box while holding the connector therewith is configured to be detached from the body of the electrical junction box, and then to be detached from the connector, thereby allowing the connector to attach to a desired electric component being received in the electrical junction box. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
