<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622600-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622600</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13293202</doc-number>
<date>20111110</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>100127785 A</doc-number>
<date>20110804</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>245</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>21</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362608</main-classification>
<further-classification>362612</further-classification>
<further-classification>362622</further-classification>
<further-classification>362627</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Backlight module and display device using the same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7481562</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Chua et al.</name>
<date>20090100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0044835</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Oami</name>
<date>20060300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362624</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0170317</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Wang et al.</name>
<date>20110700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362622</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0187942</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Cho</name>
<date>20110800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>348739</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2012/0063171</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lee et al.</name>
<date>20120300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362622</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2375978</doc-number>
<date>20000400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>101725868</doc-number>
<date>20100600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>201680234</doc-number>
<date>20101200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>580550</doc-number>
<date>20040300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>M341857</doc-number>
<date>20081000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362608</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362612</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362622</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362627</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>2</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130033891</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130207</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cheng</last-name>
<first-name>Ching-Hung</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsin-Chu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Huang</last-name>
<first-name>Ta-Jen</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsin-Chu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cheng</last-name>
<first-name>Ching-Hung</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsin-Chu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Huang</last-name>
<first-name>Ta-Jen</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsin-Chu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>WPAT, PC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>King</last-name>
<first-name>Justin</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>AU Optronics Corp.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Hsinchu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Mai</last-name>
<first-name>Anh</first-name>
<department>2889</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Santonocito</last-name>
<first-name>Michael</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An exemplary backlight module includes a frame, a light guide plate, a light source module and an optical film. The light guide plate is arranged on the frame and includes a light-incident surface and a light-emitting surface adjacent to the light-incident surface. The light source module includes a circuit board arranged between the frame and the light guide plate board, and a light emitting element arranged on the circuit board and facing the light-incident surface. The optical film includes a wavelength shifting portion arranged between the light emitting element and the light guide plate, a second extending portion arranged between the light guide plate and the frame, and a first extending portion connected between the wavelength shifting portion and the second extending portion and arranged between the light guide plate and the circuit board. A display device equipped with the backlight module is also provided.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="143.09mm" wi="256.79mm" file="US08622600-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="261.96mm" wi="167.81mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622600-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="268.31mm" wi="166.71mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622600-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The disclosure generally relates to a backlight module, and more particularly to a backlight module capable of providing a light source with high color saturation and a display device equipped with the backlight module.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">A liquid crystal display (LCD) device is primarily structured by an LCD panel and a backlight module. Because the injected liquid crystal molecules in the LCD panel are not able to emit lights by themselves, so it is necessary to use a surface light source provided by the backlight module for illuminating the LCD panel so as to achieve desired display effect. Therefore, the backlight module accordingly plays an important role in the LCD device.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">At present, most of the backlight modules use cold cathode fluorescent lamps (CCFLs) as their light sources. However, in response to an increasing demand in market of lighter and slimmer LCD devices, the backlight modules also need to be designed to be lighter and slimmer. Compared with the CCFLs, light emitting diodes (LEDs) have several advantages such as having a smaller size and a higher power-saving efficiency, so gradually LEDs have been replacing the CCFLs as a light source in the backlight modules.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">There are several conventional designs for configuring (i.e., structuring and arranging) LEDs in a backlight module as a light source. One of them, for example, is using blue-light LEDs as a light source in a backlight module. The blue-light LEDs are used for emitting a blue light to excite phosphorus powders to produce a yellow light and thereby mixing into a white light. However, based on this designing manner, an LCD panel may have a poor color gamut thereby resulting in poor color saturation. To make an LCD panel be able to present higher color saturation, it is highly desirable to improve technologies for enhancing the color saturation of the backlight.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Therefore, a backlight module in accordance with an exemplary embodiment comprises a frame, a light guide plate, a light source module and an optical film. The light guide plate is arranged on the frame and comprises a light-incident surface and a light-emitting surface adjacent to the light-incident surface. The light source module comprises a circuit board and a light emitting element. The circuit board is arranged between the frame and the light guide plate. The light emitting element is arranged on the circuit board and facing the light-incident surface. The optical film comprises a wavelength shifting portion, a first extending portion and a second extending portion. The wavelength shifting portion is arranged between the light emitting element and the light guide plate. The second extending portion is arranged between the light guide plate and the frame. The first extending portion is connected between the wavelength shifting portion and the second extending portion and arranged between the light guide plate and the circuit board.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Moreover, a display device in accordance with another exemplary embodiment comprises a backlight module and a display panel. The backlight module comprises a frame, a light guide plate, a light source module and an optical film. The light guide plate is arranged on the frame and comprises a light-incident surface and a light-emitting surface adjacent to the light-incident surface. The light source module comprises a circuit board and a light emitting element. The circuit board is arranged between the frame and the light guide plate. The light emitting element is arranged on the circuit board and facing the light-incident surface. The optical film comprises a wavelength shifting portion, a first extending portion and a second extending portion. The wavelength shifting portion is arranged between the light emitting element and the light guide plate. The second extending portion is arranged between the light guide plate and the frame. The first extending portion is connected between the wavelength shifting portion and the second extending portion and arranged between the light guide plate and the circuit board. The display panel is arranged on the light-emitting surface of the light guide plate.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The above embodiments will become more readily apparent to those ordinarily skilled in the art after reviewing the following detailed description and accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic cross-sectional side view of a display device in accordance with an exemplary embodiment; and</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic cross-sectional side view of a display device in accordance with another exemplary embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The disclosure will now be described more specifically with reference to the following embodiments. It is to be noted that the following descriptions of preferred embodiments are presented herein for purpose of illustration and description only. It is not intended to be exhaustive or to be limited to the precise form disclosed.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic cross-sectional side view of a display device in accordance with an exemplary embodiment. As depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the display device <b>100</b> comprises a backlight module <b>101</b> and a display panel <b>102</b>. Herein, the display panel <b>102</b> for example is a liquid crystal display (LCD) panel or any non-self-luminous display panel and is arranged on the backlight module <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The backlight module <b>101</b> comprises a frame <b>110</b>, a light guide plate <b>120</b>, a light source module <b>130</b> and an optical film <b>140</b>. Herein, the light guide plate <b>120</b> is arranged on the frame <b>110</b> and comprises a light-incident surface <b>122</b> and a light-emitting surface <b>124</b> adjacent to the light-incident surface <b>122</b>. The light source module <b>130</b> comprises a circuit board <b>132</b> and a light emitting element <b>134</b>. Herein, the circuit board <b>132</b> is arranged between the frame <b>110</b> and the light guide plate <b>120</b>; and the light emitting element <b>134</b> is arranged on the circuit board <b>132</b> and facing the light-incident surface <b>122</b>. In particular, the light emitting element <b>134</b> for example is a light emitting diodes (LED) for emitting white lights, and the circuit board <b>132</b> for example is equipped with one or more light emitting elements <b>134</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> exemplarily shows one light emitting element <b>134</b>). Therefore, the light source module <b>130</b> in the present embodiment for example is an LED light strip.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Please still refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the optical film <b>140</b> comprises a wavelength shifting portion <b>142</b>, a first extending portion <b>144</b> and a second extending portion <b>146</b>. Herein, the wavelength shifting portion <b>142</b> is arranged between the light emitting element <b>134</b> and the light guide plate <b>120</b>; the second extending portion <b>146</b> is arranged between the light guide plate <b>120</b> and the frame <b>110</b>; and the first extending portion <b>144</b> is connected between the wavelength shifting portion <b>142</b> and the second extending portion <b>146</b> and arranged between the light guide plate <b>120</b> and the circuit board <b>132</b>. In particular, the optical film <b>140</b> can be a diffusion film, a brightness enhancement film, a prism sheet or a polarizer. Additionally, the wavelength shifting portion <b>142</b> comprises a surface <b>141</b> facing the light emitting element <b>134</b>, and the surface <b>141</b> for example is covered with a wavelength shifting film which comprises a material selected from a group consisting of a phosphorus powder, a fluorescent material, an organic complex material, a luminous pigment and a quantum dot (QD) material. Besides, the wavelength shifting film can also cover on the entire optical film <b>140</b>; in other words, both the first and second extending portions <b>144</b>, <b>146</b> of the optical film <b>140</b> can be also covered with the wavelength shifting film if necessary.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In the backlight module <b>101</b>, when the light emitting element <b>134</b> emits a light, the light firstly emits to the wavelength shifting portion <b>142</b> of the optical film <b>140</b>, and thereby exciting the wavelength shifting film to produce a light with specific wavelengths according to physical characteristics thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">For example, if the wavelength shifting film covered on the wavelength shifting portion <b>142</b> is a QD film, firstly the wavelength shifting portion <b>142</b> will excite and emit a light with corresponding wavelengths according to particles' size or other related physical structures of the QD film when is being emitted by the light emitting elements <b>134</b>. Afterwards, the light produced by the QD film emits into the light guide plate <b>120</b> through the light-incident surface <b>122</b> thereof, and emits from the light-emitting surface <b>124</b> after being performed optical fractions and/or reflections by the light guide plate <b>120</b>, and then emits into the display panel <b>102</b>. In other words, based on the photochromics needed to be enhanced, the display device <b>100</b> of the present embodiment can correspondingly modulate the particles' size or other related physical structures of the wavelength shifting film, so that desired color saturation is obtained and presented consequently.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Moreover, the first and second extending portions <b>144</b>, <b>146</b> of the optical film <b>140</b> respectively comprise a first and a second attaching surfaces <b>143</b>, <b>145</b>. Herein, the first attaching surface <b>143</b> is used for attaching the circuit board <b>132</b> and the second attaching surface <b>145</b> is used for attaching the frame <b>110</b>. In other words, through the first and second attaching surfaces <b>143</b>, <b>145</b>, the optical film <b>140</b> can respectively attach to the circuit board <b>132</b> and the frame <b>110</b>. Therefore, in the embodiment, the optical film <b>140</b> not only provides a function of shifting a light emitted from the light emitting element <b>140</b> to a specific wavelength thereby enhancing the color saturation to be displayed on the display panel <b>100</b>, but also provides a function of fixedly attaching the circuit board <b>132</b> to the frame <b>110</b> without any extra tapes.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In addition, the backlight module <b>101</b> in the present embodiment further comprises a light shading cover <b>150</b> connected to the frame <b>110</b> and cooperatively forming an accommodation space <b>512</b> with the frame <b>110</b>. Herein, the light source module <b>130</b> is arranged inside the accommodation space <b>152</b>. The light shading cover <b>150</b> for example overlaps a portion of the light-emitting surface <b>124</b> of the light guide plate <b>120</b>, thereby avoiding the leaking light problem which may be occurred in the backlight module <b>101</b> near the light emitting element <b>134</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic cross-sectional side view of a display device in accordance with another exemplary embodiment. It is noted that the display device <b>200</b> is similar to the display device <b>100</b> depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, so that only the different components, compared to the display device <b>100</b>, in the display device <b>200</b> will be described below in detail.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">As depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the optical film <b>140</b> further comprises a third extending portion <b>148</b> extending from the wavelength shifting portion <b>142</b> to a portion of the light-emitting surface <b>124</b> of the light guide plate <b>120</b> and arranged between the light shading cover <b>150</b> and the light guide plate <b>120</b>. In particular, if the optical film <b>140</b> is a diffusion film, the third extending portion <b>148</b> can be used for fogging the leakage light which is produced in an area between the light shading cover <b>150</b> and the light guide plate <b>120</b>, and thereby avoiding an over-high brightness of the leakage light to disturb users to watch the displayed images. Or, the third extending portion <b>148</b> can be used for blocking the leakage light if is covered with a light-shading film.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">It is noted that the third extending portion <b>148</b> can be also covered with the wavelength shifting film. In other words, the wavelength shifting film can cover the entire optical film <b>140</b> if necessary, or, just cover the wavelength shifting portion <b>142</b> only, there is no any restriction given here in the embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">To sum up, because the backlight module of the present embodiment arranges an optical film with a wavelength shifting function between a light emitting element and a light guide plate, a wavelength shifting portion of the optical film can excite and emit a light with desired wavelengths according to its physical characteristics when is being emitted by the light emitting element. In other words, through modulating particulars' sizes or physical structures of the wavelength shifting portion, the light guide plate can emit a color with desired wavelengths so as enhancing the color saturation of the light provided by the backlight module. Therefore, a display device equipped with the backlight module accordingly can present images with higher color saturation.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Additionally, in the backlight module of the present embodiment, a circuit board which is electrically coupled to the light emitting element is fixedly attached to a frame through the optical film without any extra tapes, accordingly the backlight module of the present embodiment consumes less materials, so as successfully responding to the demands of LCDs with a lighter weight and a smaller size.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">While the disclosure has been described in terms of what is presently considered to be the most practical and preferred embodiments, it is to be understood that the disclosure needs not be limited to the disclosed embodiment. On the contrary, it is intended to cover various modifications and similar arrangements included within the spirit and scope of the appended claims which are to be accorded with the broadest interpretation so as to encompass all such modifications and similar structures.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A backlight module comprising:
<claim-text>a frame;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light guide plate, arranged on the frame, comprising a light-incident surface and a light-emitting surface adjacent to the light-incident surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light source module, comprising:
<claim-text>a circuit board, arranged between the frame and the light guide plate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light emitting element, arranged on the circuit board and facing the light-incident surface; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical film, comprising a wavelength shifting portion, a first extending portion and a second extending portion, wherein the wavelength shifting portion is arranged between the light emitting element and the light guide plate, the second extending portion is arranged between the light guide plate and the frame, the first extending portion is connected between the wavelength shifting portion and the second extending portion and arranged between the light guide plate and the circuit board.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The backlight module according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the wavelength shifting portion of the optical film comprises a surface facing the light emitting element, and the surface is covered with a wavelength shifting film.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The backlight module according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the wavelength shifting film comprises a material selected from a group consisting of a phosphorus powder, a fluorescent material, an organic complex material, a luminous pigment and a quantum dot material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The backlight module according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a light shading cover connected to the frame and cooperatively forming an accommodation space with the frame, wherein the light source module is arranged inside the accommodation space, and the light shading cover overlaps with a portion of the light-emitting surface of the light guide plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The backlight module according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the optical film further comprises a third extending portion extending from the wavelength shifting portion to above a portion of the light-emitting surface of the light guide plate and arranged between the light shading cover and the light guide plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The backlight module according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the third extending portion of the optical film is covered with a wavelength shifting film.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The backlight module according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the wavelength shifting film comprises a material selected from a group consisting of a phosphorus powder, a fluorescent material, an organic complex material, a luminous pigment and a quantum dot material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The backlight module according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of the first and second extending portions of the optical film is covered with a wavelength shifting film.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The backlight module according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the optical film comprises a diffusion film, a brightness enhancement film, a prism sheet or a polarizer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The backlight module according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second extending portions of the optical film respectively have a first and a second attaching surfaces, and the first and second attaching surfaces are respectively attached to the circuit board and the frame.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A display device comprising:
<claim-text>a backlight module, comprising:
<claim-text>a frame;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light guide plate, arranged on the frame, comprising a light-incident surface and a light-emitting surface adjacent to the light-incident surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light source module, comprising:
<claim-text>a circuit board, arranged between the frame and the light guide plate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light emitting element, arranged on the circuit board and facing the light-incident surface; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical film, comprising a wavelength shifting portion, a first extending portion and a second extending portion, wherein the wavelength shifting portion is arranged between the light emitting element and the light guide plate, the second extending portion is arranged between the light guide plate and the frame, the first extending portion is connected between the wavelength shifting portion and the second extending portion and arranged between the light guide plate and the circuit board; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a display panel, arranged on the light-emitting surface of the light guide plate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the wavelength shifting portion of the optical film comprises a surface facing the light emitting element, and the surface is covered with a wavelength shifting film.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the wavelength shifting film comprises a material selected from a group consisting of a phosphorus powder, a fluorescent material, an organic complex material, a luminous pigment and a quantum dot material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further comprising a light shading cover connected to the frame and cooperatively forming an accommodation space with the frame, wherein the light source module is arranged inside the accommodation space, and the light shading cover overlaps a portion of the light-emitting surface of the light guide plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the optical film further comprises a third extending portion extending from the wavelength shifting portion to above a portion of the light-emitting surface of the light guide plate and arranged between the light shading cover and the light guide plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the third extending portion of the optical film is covered with a wavelength shifting film.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the wavelength shifting film comprises a material selected from a group consisting of a phosphorus powder, a fluorescent material, an organic complex material, a luminous pigment and a quantum dot material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein each of the first and second extending portions is covered with a wavelength shifting film.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the optical film comprises a diffusion film, a brightness enhancement film, a prism sheet or a polarizer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second extending portions of the optical film respectively comprise a first and a second attaching surfaces, and the first and second attaching surfaces are respectively attached to the circuit board and the frame. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
