<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624918-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624918</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13172829</doc-number>
<date>20110630</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2010 1 0611403</doc-number>
<date>20101229</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>127</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>09</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>345619</main-classification>
<further-classification>345589</further-classification>
<further-classification>345581</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Electronic reader and control method thereof</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2012/0218282</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Choboter et al.</name>
<date>20120800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>345589</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2012/0265126</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Estes</name>
<date>20121000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>604 66</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2012/0311590</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Park</name>
<date>20121200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>718102</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2012/0315963</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Pratt et al.</name>
<date>20121200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>455574</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2012/0316695</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Chen et al.</name>
<date>20121200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>700296</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2383091</doc-number>
<kind>Y</kind>
<date>20000600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>101794228</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20100800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>101815126</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20100800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>101858783</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20101000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1158485</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20060700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>6</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>345619</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>345581</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>345589</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>715864</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120169764</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120705</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Huang</last-name>
<first-name>Hui-Ling</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Li</last-name>
<first-name>Xiao-Guang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Huang</last-name>
<first-name>Hui-Ling</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Li</last-name>
<first-name>Xiao-Guang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hong Fu Jin Precision Industry (ShenZhen) Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Harrison</last-name>
<first-name>Chante</first-name>
<department>2679</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An electronic reader which includes a storage unit, and an input unit generating signals in response to user input. In addition, a processing unit detects the signals corresponding to the user input; controls the electronic reader to enter a reading mode, and displays a file according to the user input, records a length of duration time for which the electronic reader operates in the reading mode; determines the duration time and executes a variety of protective instructions and steps depending on the length of duration time for which the electronic reader operates in the reading mode. A control method is also provided.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="129.03mm" wi="129.62mm" file="US08624918-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="180.09mm" wi="130.30mm" file="US08624918-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="184.07mm" wi="163.24mm" file="US08624918-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="174.50mm" wi="135.13mm" file="US08624918-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to electronic readers and control methods thereof and, particularly, to an electronic reader and a control method for preventing an electronic device from damaging a user's health after long-term use.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">When users use an electronic device over a prolonged period without changing their posture, they will experience eye strain, problems with their spine, wrist tendonitis. Long-term static use of an electronic reader will do harm to users' health.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The components of the drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of an electronic reader and a control method thereof. Moreover, in the drawings, like reference numerals designate corresponding parts throughout multiple views.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view of an electronic reader in accordance with an exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram of the electronic reader of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a flowchart of a control method applied in the electronic reader of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in accordance with an exemplary embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, an electronic reader <b>100</b> includes a display unit <b>10</b>, a storage unit <b>20</b>, a processing unit <b>30</b>, an input unit <b>40</b>, and a detection unit <b>50</b>. The storage unit <b>20</b> stores electronic files. The input unit <b>40</b> receives and translates touch signals from the user. The processing unit <b>30</b> controls the electronic reader <b>100</b> to enter a reading mode, reads a file and displays a page of the file in a document window of the display unit <b>10</b> according to in the reading mode. The processing unit <b>30</b> executes protective instructions depending on a length of duration time for which the electronic reader <b>100</b> operates in the reading mode.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In detail, the processing unit <b>30</b> executes a first protective instruction if the duration time reaches a first preset time; the processing unit <b>30</b> executes a second protective instruction if the duration time reaches a second preset time; the processing unit <b>30</b> executes a third protective instruction if the duration time of the electronic reader <b>100</b> reaches a third preset time.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In the embodiment, the processing unit <b>30</b> includes a detection module <b>31</b>, a mode control module <b>32</b>, a timing module <b>33</b>, an analysis module <b>34</b> and a display module <b>35</b>. The detection module <b>31</b> is configured to detect mode signals from the input unit <b>40</b> and transmits the mode signals to the mode control module <b>32</b>. The mode control module <b>32</b> causes the electronic reader <b>100</b> to enter a reading mode, and reads and opens a file according to a selection signal from the user. The timing module <b>33</b> commences to record a length of duration time for which the electronic reader <b>100</b> operates in the reading mode, which is in fact the time that the user spends in reading the file. The analysis module <b>34</b> determines the duration time of the electronic reader <b>100</b> operates in the reading mode and executes corresponding protective instructions.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In the embodiment, If the analysis module <b>34</b> determines the duration time has reached a first preset time, such as 20 mins, the display module <b>35</b> executes a first protective instruction. The first protective instruction is a command to the display module <b>35</b> to change the display properties of the characters on the display unit <b>10</b>. For example, according to the first protective instruction, the display module <b>35</b> may change the front size, increase the spacing between words for reducing eye fatigue and change the angle of display of the page of the file to encourage users to change their posture.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">If the analysis module <b>34</b> determines the duration time has reached a second preset time, such as 45 mins, the display module <b>35</b> executes a second protective instruction. The second protective instruction commands the display module <b>35</b> to display or play a reminder on the display unit <b>10</b>, to remind the user to take measures to reduce fatigue. For example, the display module <b>35</b> may display a prompt such as &#x201c;please do eye exercises&#x201d; or &#x201c;please change your posture&#x201d; or &#x201c;please take a rest&#x201d; to users. In an alternative embodiment, a speaker and an audio processing unit are included in the electronic reader <b>100</b>, the analysis module may command the audio processing unit to broadcast a prompt via the speaker.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">If the analysis module <b>34</b> determines that the duration time has reached a third preset time, such as 60 mins, the display module <b>35</b> executes a third protective instruction. The third protective instruction commands the display module <b>35</b> to suspend the display unit <b>10</b> for a preset time period, such as 5 mins, to strongly encourage the user to take a rest. When the suspension time has reached the end of the preset time period, the display module <b>35</b> re-activates the display unit <b>10</b> and again displays the file. The electronic reader <b>100</b> may be programmed to be unresponsive to user input except the shutdown command while the display unit <b>10</b> is in suspension. The display module <b>35</b> resets the timing module <b>33</b> to record the suspension time of the display unit <b>10</b> once the display unit <b>10</b> has been suspended. After the display unit <b>10</b> is re-activated, the cycle begins again in that the display module <b>35</b> resets the timing module <b>33</b> to commence to record the length of time for which the electronic reader <b>100</b> operates in the reading mode, and the analysis module <b>34</b> and the protective instructions repeat as before.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In alternatively embodiments, the processing unit <b>30</b> executes only any two of the three protective instructions, and the order of executing the protective instructions may be different in various embodiments. The protective instructions may also include a command to change the background color of a file to render greater clarity to the content in the file.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The detection unit <b>50</b> is configured for detecting the level of the ambient light and the distance between a user and the electronic reader <b>100</b>. In the embodiment, the detection unit <b>50</b> includes a distance sensor <b>51</b> and an optical sensor <b>52</b>. The distance sensor <b>51</b> detects the distance between the head of a user and the display unit <b>10</b> after the electronic reader <b>100</b> has entered the reading mode, and transmits the distance to the processing unit <b>30</b>. The optical sensor <b>52</b> detects the level of the ambient light, and transmits the data to the processing unit <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In the embodiment, the processing unit <b>30</b> may adjust the brightness of the display unit <b>10</b> and the size of a displayed page. For example, the distance sensor <b>51</b> detects the distance between the display unit <b>10</b> and the user's eyes; the display module <b>35</b> may determine whether the distance exceeds a preset distance. The display module <b>35</b> may warn the user that he or she is too near if the distance is less than a preset distance. Furthermore, the optical sensor <b>52</b> may detect the level of the ambient light. The display module <b>35</b> may increase the brightness of the display unit <b>10</b> if the level of the ambient light intensity is lower than a preset light intensity.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a control method applied in the electronic reader <b>100</b> in accordance with an exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In step S<b>301</b>, a detection module <b>31</b> detects mode signals from an input unit <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In step S<b>302</b>, a mode control module <b>32</b> controls the electronic reader <b>100</b> to enter a reading mode, and reads and opens a file according to a selection signal from the input unit <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In step S<b>303</b>, a timing module <b>33</b> is triggered by the selection signal to record a length of time for which the electronic reader <b>100</b> operates in the reading mode.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In step S<b>304</b>, an analysis module <b>34</b> determines a duration time of the electronic reader <b>100</b> operates in the reading mode, and executes corresponding protective instructions.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In the embodiment, if the analysis module <b>34</b> determines that the duration time has reached a first preset time, such as 20 mins, the display module <b>35</b> executes a first protective instruction. The first protective instruction commands the display module <b>35</b> to change the display properties of the characters on the display unit <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">If the analysis module <b>34</b> determines that the duration time has reached a second preset time, such as 45 mins, the display module <b>35</b> executes a second protective instruction. The second protective instruction commands the display module <b>35</b> to display or play a reminder on the display unit <b>10</b>, to remind the user to take measures to avoid or reduce fatigue.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">If the analysis module <b>34</b> determines that the duration time has reached a third preset time, such as 60 mins, the display module <b>35</b> executes a third protective instruction. The third protective instruction commands the display module <b>35</b> to suspend the operation of the display unit <b>10</b> for a preset time period, such as 5 mins, to require the user to take a rest. When the suspension time has reached the end of the preset time period, the display module <b>35</b> re-activates the display unit <b>10</b> and again displays the file. Whilst the display is suspended, the electronic reader <b>100</b> does not respond to any user input except the command to shut down. The display module <b>35</b> resets the timing module <b>33</b> to record the suspension time of the display unit <b>10</b> once the display unit <b>10</b> has been suspended. When the display unit <b>10</b> is re-activated, the display module <b>35</b> resets the timing module <b>33</b> to record the length of time for which the electronic reader <b>100</b> operates in the reading mode. The analysis module <b>34</b> cyclically determines the duration time of the electronic reader <b>100</b> operates in the reading mode, and executes protective instructions again as necessary.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Although the present disclosure has been specifically described on the basis of the exemplary embodiment thereof, the disclosure is not to be construed as being limited thereto. Various changes or modifications may be made to the embodiment without departing from the scope and spirit of the disclosure.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An electronic reader, comprising:
<claim-text>a storage unit configured for storing electronic files;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an input unit configured for generating input signals in response to user input operations;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a display unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a processing unit configured for:
<claim-text>controlling the electronic reader to enter a reading mode where the display unit is configured for displaying the electronic files in response to the input signals;</claim-text>
<claim-text>recording a length of duration time for which the electronic reader operates in the reading mode;</claim-text>
<claim-text>executing a first protective instruction if the duration time reaches a first preset time, wherein the first protective instruction is selected from the group consisting of changing display property of characters displayed on the display unit and playing a reminding file to remind user to take measures to reduce fatigue;</claim-text>
<claim-text>and</claim-text>
<claim-text>executing a second protective instruction if the duration time reaches a second preset time, the second preset time being greater than the first preset time;</claim-text>
<claim-text>further controlling the input unit to be unresponsive to input operations excepting a shutdown command when the display unit is suspended, and activating the display unit after a preset suspension time period is lapsed.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The electronic reader as described in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the processing unit is further configured for restarting recording of the duration time after the display unit is activated.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A control method applied in an electronic reader, comprising:
<claim-text>detecting the input signals:</claim-text>
<claim-text>controlling the electronic reader to enter a reading mode wherein a display unit displays an electronic file in response to the input signals;</claim-text>
<claim-text>recording a length of duration time for which the electronic reader operates in the reading mode;</claim-text>
<claim-text>executing a first protective instruction if the duration time reaches a first preset time;</claim-text>
<claim-text>executing a second protective instruction if the duration time reaches a second preset time, the second preset time being greater than the first preset time;</claim-text>
<claim-text>executing a third protective instruction if the duration time reaches a third preset time, wherein the third preset time is greater than the second preset time, the third protective instruction is selected from the group consisting of changing display property of characters displayed on the display unit, playing a reminding file to remind user to take measures to reduce fatigue, and suspending the display unit for a preset time period;</claim-text>
<claim-text>activating the display unit after a preset suspension time period is lapsed; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>restarting recording of the duration time after the display unit is activated.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method as described in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, further comprising steps of:
<claim-text>activating the display unit after a preset suspension time period is lapsed; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>restarting recording of the duration time after the display unit is activated.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. An electronic reader, comprising:
<claim-text>a storage unit configured for storing electronic files;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an input unit configured for generating input signals in response to user input operations;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a display unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a processing unit configured for:
<claim-text>controlling the electronic reader to enter a reading mode where the display unit is configured for displaying the electronic files in response to the input signals;</claim-text>
<claim-text>recording a length of duration time for which the electronic reader operates in the reading mode;</claim-text>
<claim-text>executing a first protective instruction if the duration time reaches a first preset time, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>executing a second protective instruction if the duration time reaches a second preset time, the second preset time being greater than the first preset time;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light detection unit configured for detecting ambient light intensity and a distance detection unit configured for detecting a distance between a user and the electronic reader.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The electronic reader as described in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the processing unit is further configured for reminding the user if the distance between the user and the electronic reader exceeds a preset distance, and increasing the brightness of the display unit if the detected light intensity is lower than a preset light intensity. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
