<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623731-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623731</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13732196</doc-number>
<date>20121231</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>21</main-group>
<subgroup>331</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438361</main-classification>
<further-classification>257520</further-classification>
<further-classification>257E2903</further-classification>
<further-classification>257E21572</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Methods of forming electrostatic discharge devices</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6266222</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Colombo et al.</name>
<date>20010700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6396107</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Brennan et al.</name>
<date>20020500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6399990</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Brennan et al.</name>
<date>20020600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6406948</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Jun et al.</name>
<date>20020600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2002/0173098</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Tang et al.</name>
<date>20021100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0135141</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Pequignot et al.</name>
<date>20040700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0244796</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Tang et al.</name>
<date>20091000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>34</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>9</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>12</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12714985</doc-number>
<date>20100301</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8350355</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13732196</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130122677</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130516</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Esmark</last-name>
<first-name>Kai</first-name>
<address>
<city>Neuried</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Esmark</last-name>
<first-name>Kai</first-name>
<address>
<city>Neuried</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Slater &#x26; Matsil, L.L.P.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Infineon Technologies AG</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Neubiberg</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Maldonado</last-name>
<first-name>Julio J</first-name>
<department>2898</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>McCall Shepard</last-name>
<first-name>Sonya D</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Electrostatic discharge devices and methods of forming thereof are disclosed. In one embodiment, a semiconductor device includes an electrostatic discharge (ESD) device region disposed within a semiconductor body. A first ESD device is disposed in a first region of the ESD device region, and a second ESD device disposed in a second region of the ESD device region. The second region is separated from the first region by a first trench.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="122.94mm" wi="216.92mm" file="US08623731-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="243.08mm" wi="174.16mm" file="US08623731-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="214.80mm" wi="129.12mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623731-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="238.68mm" wi="169.84mm" file="US08623731-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="205.06mm" wi="127.51mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623731-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="214.29mm" wi="104.73mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623731-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="223.01mm" wi="132.33mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623731-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="218.61mm" wi="113.96mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623731-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="220.81mm" wi="129.12mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623731-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="220.30mm" wi="128.02mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623731-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This is a divisional application of U.S. application Ser. No. 12/714,985, which was filed on Mar. 1, 2010, and is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates generally to semiconductor devices, and in particular embodiments to electrostatic discharge devices.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">As electronic components are getting smaller and smaller along with the internal structures in integrated circuits, it is getting easier to either completely destroy or otherwise impair electronic components. In particular, many integrated circuits are highly susceptible to damage from the discharge of static electricity. Generally, electrostatic discharge (ESD) is the transfer of an electrostatic charge between bodies at different electrostatic potentials (voltages), caused by direct contact or induced by an electrostatic field. The discharge of static electricity, or ESD, has become a critical problem for the electronics industry.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">When an ESD pulse occurs on a transistor, the extremely high voltage of the ESD pulse can break down the transistor and can potentially cause permanent damage. Consequently, the circuits associated with the input/output pads of an integrated circuit need to be protected from ESD pulses so that they are not damaged.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Device failures that result from ESD events are not always immediately catastrophic or apparent. Often, the device is only slightly weakened but is less able to withstand normal operating stresses and, hence, may result in a reliability problem. Therefore, various ESD protection circuits should be included in the device to protect the various components.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">ESD protection devices are designed based on the type of component that is being protected. However, designing ESD protection devices for high voltage components requires overcoming a number of limitations imposed by the need to reduce the device area without reducing the required high voltage protection.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In one embodiment, a semiconductor device comprises an electrostatic discharge (ESD) device region disposed within a semiconductor body. A first ESD device is disposed in a first region of the ESD device region. A second ESD device is disposed in a second region of the ESD device region, the second region being separated from the first region by a first trench.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In another embodiment, a semiconductor device comprises a first bipolar transistor having an emitter, a collector and a base region disposed in a first region of an ESD device region of a semiconductor substrate. A second bipolar transistor having an emitter, a collector and a base region is disposed in a second region of the ESD device region. The semiconductor device further comprises a first trench disposed between the first and the second regions, the first trench isolating the first bipolar transistor from the second bipolar transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The foregoing has outlined rather broadly the features of an embodiment of the present invention in order that the detailed description of the invention that follows may be better understood. Additional features and advantages of embodiments of the invention will be described hereinafter, which form the subject of the claims of the invention. It should be appreciated by those skilled in the art that the conception and specific embodiments disclosed may be readily utilized as a basis for modifying or designing other structures or processes for carrying out the same purposes of the present invention. It should also be realized by those skilled in the art that such equivalent constructions do not depart from the spirit and scope of the invention as set forth in the appended claims.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">For a more complete understanding of the present invention, and the advantages thereof, reference is now made to the following descriptions taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawing, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic illustration of an ESD device used to protect a circuitry in accordance with embodiments of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, which includes <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</figref><i>a </i>and <b>2</b><i>b</i>, illustrates an embodiment of the invention of a stack of low voltage ESD devices forming a high voltage ESD protection device;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates the operation of the ESD device formed from a stack of low voltage ESD devices in accordance with embodiments of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, which includes <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref><i>a </i>and <b>4</b><i>b</i>, illustrates a stack of low voltage thyristors forming an ESD device in accordance with an embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates an embodiment of the invention wherein a stack of diodes form an ESD device; and</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, which includes <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6</figref><i>a</i>-<b>6</b><i>e</i>, illustrates cross-sectional views of an ESD device in various stages of manufacturing in accordance with an embodiment of the invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Corresponding numerals and symbols in the different figures generally refer to corresponding parts unless otherwise indicated. The figures are drawn to clearly illustrate the relevant aspects of the embodiments and are not necessarily drawn to scale.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF ILLUSTRATIVE EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The making and using of various embodiments are discussed in detail below. It should be appreciated, however, that the present invention provides many applicable inventive concepts that can be embodied in a wide variety of specific contexts. The specific embodiments discussed are merely illustrative of specific ways to make and use the invention, and do not limit the scope of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Integrated circuits and the geometry of the transistors that make up the core of the integrated circuits continue to be reduced in size and the transistors arranged closer together. Core transistors are typically aggressively scaled and operate at low voltages (e.g., less than about 5V). A transistor's physical size limits the voltage that the transistor can withstand without being damaged. Thus, breakdown voltages of core transistors are lowered and currents capable of overheating components are more frequently reached by the voltages and currents induced by an ESD event.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In contrast, power devices that may be directly coupled to input voltage typically comprise high voltage transistors. Unlike the low voltage transistors, the high voltage transistors may operate up to about 20V and can withstand larger voltages before breakdown.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">As a consequence, the ESD protection circuit used for protecting components having core transistors is different from the ESD protection circuit used for protecting power components having larger transistors. However, ESD protection circuits used for protecting power components have to operate at high voltages and tend to consume a large area. High voltage ESD protection devices are difficult to tune with respect to ESD targets. For example, changing the breakdown voltage is difficult and requires complicated changes in the process.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In various embodiments, the present invention overcomes these limitations of designing high voltage devices by using a stack of low voltage devices.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic illustration of an ESD device used to protect a circuit in accordance with embodiments of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the ESD device <b>10</b> is coupled in parallel to the circuitry <b>20</b> to be protected. The circuitry <b>20</b> to be protected could be any type of circuit. Examples include logic, analog, mixed signal, memory, power circuits including internal buffers, drivers, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, an ESD device <b>10</b> is triggered when an ESD pulse occurs on the pad <b>5</b>. In the absence of an ESD pulse, the ESD device <b>10</b> is in the &#x201c;off&#x201d; position and does not conduct any current. When the pad <b>5</b> is zapped with an ESD pulse, the ESD device <b>10</b> is triggered &#x201c;on&#x201d; by the ESD stress voltage to conduct an ESD current from the pad to ground (substrate voltage VSS). Thus the charge from the ESD event is dissipated through a parallel ESD circuit protecting the circuitry <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">For effective ESD protection, the ESD device must be triggered at a voltage less than the breakdown voltage of the circuitry <b>20</b> being protected. For example, in case of a MOS transistor this breakdown voltage is typically the gate oxide breakdown voltage. Hence, the ESD device must turn on at a voltage less than the breakdown voltage to avoid destroying the circuitry <b>20</b>. In addition, the holding voltage and &#x201c;on&#x201d; resistance of ESD device <b>10</b> will impact the robustness of the protection. A lower holding voltage and smaller resistance provide a more robust protection. However, the holding voltage must be higher than the operating voltage (VDD) of the circuitry <b>20</b> to avoid hindering its operation under normal operating conditions.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">As a consequence, the ESD circuitry must be matched with the requirements of the circuit to be protected. For example, an ESD device that is to protect a high voltage device requires higher triggering and holding voltages than an ESD device that is to protect a low voltage device.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">However, high voltage ESD protection devices that are required to protect high voltage circuitry typically have many disadvantages. Due to the large triggering voltages, they are large devices requiring a large amount of real estate on the chip. Further, the device behavior of these large devices cannot be easily tuned to meet different individual requirements of different power components.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In contrast, low voltage ESD devices have a number of advantageous characteristics. For example, the trigger speed of the low voltage ESD devices is much higher than that of the high voltage ESD devices. A faster trigger speed is advantageous as it avoids harm to the circuitry <b>20</b> during the rise of the ESD pulse before the ESD device <b>10</b> is turned on. Low voltage ESD devices also allow better control of ESD robustness with respect to ESD targets. Low voltage ESD devices have much better performance with temperature because the breakdown voltage drift with temperature is smaller than high voltage devices.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">However, as described low voltage devices do not have device characteristics suitable for protecting high voltage components. In various embodiments of the present invention, low voltage devices are adapted to high voltage components to produce a circuit having the requisite device characteristics to protect high voltage components.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">An embodiment of the invention illustrating a stack of bipolar transistors forming a high voltage ESD protection device will be described using <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. Further embodiments illustrating a stack of thyristors and diodes will be described using <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>. An embodiment of a method of manufacturing the ESD protection device will be described using <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, which includes <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</figref><i>a </i>and <b>2</b><i>b</i>, illustrates an embodiment of the invention of a stack of low voltage ESD devices (bipolar transistors) forming a high voltage ESD protection device.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>a </i>illustrates a circuit diagram of an ESD device in accordance with an embodiment of the invention. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>a</i>, a first, a second, a third, and a fourth bipolar transistor <b>51</b>-<b>54</b> are stacked to form the ESD device <b>10</b>. Each of the bipolar transistor <b>51</b>-<b>54</b> may be used individually for ESD protection of a low voltage circuitry. As will be described below, although the bipolar transistors <b>51</b>-<b>54</b> are drawn tightly on silicon, parasitic devices do not exist between the bipolar transistors <b>51</b>-<b>54</b>. Hence, advantageously the area occupied by the stack of bipolar transistors <b>51</b>-<b>54</b> is much smaller than the equivalent single high voltage transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>b </i>illustrates a cross-sectional view of the ESD device in accordance with an embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>b</i>, trenches <b>110</b> are embedded in the substrate <b>100</b>, and electrically isolate the doped regions. The trenches <b>110</b> are lined with an insulating liner <b>105</b>. The insulating liner <b>105</b> may comprise an oxide or a nitride, or a combination. The insulating liner <b>105</b> may comprise a single layer or plurality of layers in various embodiments. The trenches <b>110</b> are filled with polysilicon and doped to a high conductive state. In various embodiments, the trenches <b>110</b> are doped higher than about 1&#xd7;10<sup>19 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3</sup>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In some embodiments, all the trenches <b>110</b> may be filled with an insulator such as an oxide. In such embodiments, the trenches <b>110</b> only help to isolate and do not have the added function of being a contact to the substrate <b>100</b>. Similarly, in some embodiments, the trenches <b>110</b> may be filled with undoped or low doped polysilicon without lining the sidewalls with an insulating liner <b>105</b> as described above. The low doped p-n junction thus forms the isolation structure as long as the breakdown voltage of the p-n junction is higher than the maximum operating voltage of the ESD device. The lower breakdown is achieved by lowering the doping of the polysilicon at the p-n junction. Alternatively, in some embodiments, low doped semiconductors having a wider band gap than silicon may be used instead of polysilicon. Examples of materials that may be used to fill the trench include SiC, GaN, GaP, InP, ZnO, ZnS.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">A first well region <b>120</b> is disposed in the substrate <b>100</b> and comprises a low doped n-type region. In various embodiments, the first well region <b>120</b> is doped to a concentration of about 5&#xd7;10<sup>16 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3 </sup>to about 5&#xd7;10<sup>18 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3</sup>, and about 5&#xd7;10<sup>17 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3 </sup>in one embodiment. In one or more embodiments, the depth of the trenches <b>110</b> is selected to ensure that the trenches <b>110</b> are deeper than the lower surface of the first well region <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">A second well region <b>130</b> is disposed within the first well region <b>120</b>. The second well region <b>130</b> comprises a low doped p-type region. In various embodiments, the second well region <b>130</b> is doped to a concentration of about 5&#xd7;10<sup>16 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3 </sup>to about 5&#xd7;10<sup>18 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3</sup>, and about 5&#xd7;10<sup>17 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3 </sup>in one embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">A first doped region <b>140</b> and a second doped region <b>150</b> form the emitter region and collector region of the bipolar transistors <b>51</b>-<b>54</b>. The first and the second doped regions <b>140</b> and <b>150</b> are thus doped to be a heavily doped n<sup>+</sup> region. The first and the second doped regions <b>140</b> and <b>150</b> may be doped with arsenic wherein the doping is greater than about 1&#xd7;10<sup>19 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3</sup>, and higher than about 1&#xd7;10<sup>20 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3 </sup>in one embodiment. In various embodiments, the first and the second doped regions <b>140</b> and <b>150</b> comprise a doping such that the Fermi level is within about 0.1 eV from the valence band of the substrate <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">As illustrated, for each transistor, the emitter and base of the bipolar transistors are tied together. The collector region of the first bipolar transistor <b>51</b> is coupled to the emitter region of the adjacent second bipolar transistor <b>52</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In one or more embodiments, the trenches <b>110</b> may be deep trenches. Alternatively, in one or more embodiments, the trenches <b>110</b> may be shallow trenches. In various embodiments, the trenches <b>110</b> extend past the first and the second well regions <b>120</b> and <b>130</b> and into the substrate <b>100</b>. In various embodiments, the trenches <b>110</b> are at least 5 &#x3bc;m deep and about 10 &#x3bc;m to about 20 &#x3bc;m deep. In various embodiments, a depth of the trenches <b>110</b> into the substrate <b>100</b> is at least 10 times the width of the trenches <b>110</b> along the top surface of the substrate <b>100</b>. In various embodiments, a depth of the trenches <b>110</b> into the substrate <b>100</b> is between about 10 times to about 30 times the width of the trenches <b>110</b> along the top surface of the substrate <b>100</b>. The trenches <b>110</b> are doped to a same conductivity type as the substrate <b>100</b> thus forming contacts to the substrate <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The use of trenches <b>110</b> advantageously increases the packaging density of the low voltage transistors <b>51</b>-<b>54</b> by packing these transistors closer without adding any parasitic devices. The improved isolation achieves high breakdown voltages that would otherwise not be possible due to the earlier breakdown of parasitic devices. For example, in the absence of the trenches <b>110</b>, a parasitic device is formed between adjacent second well regions <b>130</b> separated by the first well region <b>120</b>. In various embodiments, with the inclusion of the trenches <b>110</b>, any parasitic device still present is not activated before the ESD device is activated. Hence, the ESD device behaves as though no parasitic devices are present. Hence, in one or more embodiments, the depth of the trenches <b>110</b> is selected to ensure that the parasitic device is not activated before the ESD device. Alternately, in various embodiments, the depth of the trenches <b>110</b> is selected such that the threshold voltage for the parasitic device is greater than the threshold voltage for the ESD device.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">If the first well region <b>120</b> comprises an n-type doping, the second well region <b>130</b> comprises a p-type doping thereby forming a parasitic pnp transistor. This parasitic transistor may have a lower breakdown/trigger voltage than required for the ESD device. Hence, as the ESD pulse voltage exceeds the breakdown/trigger voltage of the parasitic pnp transistor, the ESD device is triggered earlier. For example, if the parasitic breakdown voltage is lower than the operating voltage of the device, the ESD device is always triggered, severely impacting the operation of the circuitry. Consequently, such an ESD device formed by stacking low voltage devices without trenches <b>110</b> cannot be used to protect higher voltage components. Thus, the trenches <b>110</b> enable effective ESD protection using a stack of low voltage devices in a bulk substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In various embodiments, the use of the trenches <b>110</b> eliminates this parasitic transistor (and other parasitic devices) thereby allowing the operation of the ESD device. In contrast, because the trenches <b>110</b> extend up to the substrate <b>100</b>, any parasitic device must be established between the first well region <b>120</b> and the substrate <b>100</b>. Because of the low doping of the substrate <b>100</b>, the breakdown voltage of this device is much higher. For example, the breakdown voltage of diode between the first well region <b>120</b> and the substrate <b>100</b> can be as high as 100V, and about 80V in one case.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates the operation of the ESD device formed from a stack of low voltage ESD devices in accordance with embodiments of the invention. Because each device is triggered at its breakdown voltage, the effective breakdown voltage of the stack of the transistors <b>51</b>-<b>54</b> is the summation of the breakdown voltage of each transistor. Similarly, the effective hold voltage is also a summation as each transistor drops the hold voltage during its conduction state.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the effective hold voltage and the effective trigger voltage of a plurality of three transistors (curve <b>2</b>) is three times the hold voltage and the trigger voltage of a single low voltage transistor (curve <b>1</b>). Similarly, the effective hold voltage and trigger voltage of a plurality of four transistors (curve <b>3</b>) is four times the hold voltage and the trigger voltage of a single low voltage transistor (curve <b>1</b>). Any number of low voltage devices can be stacked accordingly to form high voltage devices. Hence, for example, if the ESD snap down voltage requirement is 15V, a stack of three bipolar transistors can be used. Alternatively, if the ESD snap down voltage requirement is 20V, a stack of four bipolar transistors can be used.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">While <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrated the use of a bipolar transistor as the low voltage transistor, any other device may be used. For example, in other embodiments, the ESD device may be formed by stacking diodes, thyristors, field effect transistors including field oxide (FOX) transistors, double diffused metal oxide semiconductor (DMOS) transistors, insulated-gate field effect transistors (IGFET), and the like. However, low voltage MOS devices are not preferred as the gate dielectric will likely breakdown at a low voltage. In alternative embodiments, the ESD device may be other types of devices including amorphous materials such as chalcogenide materials. An example of such an ESD device is a ovonic threshold device.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref> illustrate embodiments of the ESD device using thyristors and diodes.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, which includes <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref><i>a </i>and <b>4</b><i>b</i>, illustrates a stack of low voltage thyristors forming an ESD device in accordance with an embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref><i>a</i>, a first and a second silicon controlled rectifier (SCR) <b>201</b> and <b>202</b> are stacked to form an ESD device. Each SCR <b>201</b> and <b>202</b> includes a p-type anode <b>230</b><i>a</i>/<b>230</b><i>b</i>, an n-type cathode <b>240</b><i>a</i>/<b>240</b><i>b</i>, an n-type n-base SCR region <b>210</b><i>a</i>/<b>210</b><i>b</i>, and a p-type p-base SCR region <b>220</b><i>a</i>/<b>220</b><i>b</i>. The anode <b>230</b><i>a </i>and a trigger element <b>215</b><i>a </i>are coupled to a node to be protected <b>205</b> and an intermediate node <b>206</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The trigger element <b>215</b><i>a </i>causes a trigger current I<sub>t </sub>to flow whenever the voltage at node to be protected <b>205</b> exceeds a certain threshold. Typical required trigger thresholds are between about 2V and about 20V. The presence of a trigger current I<sub>t </sub>causes the SCR to conduct a large current, I<sub>ESD</sub>. When the voltage at node <b>205</b> is less than the threshold of the trigger device, the first SCR <b>201</b> does not conduct a large current I<sub>ESD</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In the non-conducting state, the SCR behaves as a bipolar latch, which includes a BJT PNP device, and a BJT NPN device. The representative PNP device is made up of the p-type anode <b>230</b><i>a </i>as the emitter, the n-base region <b>210</b><i>a </i>as the base, and p-base region <b>220</b><i>a </i>as the collector. The representative NPN device is made up of n-base region <b>210</b><i>a </i>as the collector, the p-base region <b>220</b><i>a </i>as the base, and the n-type cathode <b>240</b><i>a </i>as the emitter. When trigger current I<sub>t </sub>flows into the base of representative NPN in response to a voltage transient at node <b>205</b>, the collector of the representative NPN is pulled low, which turns on the representative PNP, which pulls the base of NPN up toward the potential at node <b>205</b>, thereby latching the bipolar latch and causing a large current I<sub>ESD </sub>to flow. An optional resistance can be added to the circuit to adjust the trigger level by bleeding away base current from the representative PNP, thereby requiring a higher trigger current to activate the bipolar latch.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">After the first SCR <b>201</b> is triggered the second SCR <b>202</b> is triggered depending on the voltage at the intermediate node <b>206</b>. As a consequence, the ESD device <b>10</b> is triggered only if both the first and the second SCRs <b>201</b> and <b>202</b> are triggered.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Once the SCRs <b>201</b> and <b>202</b> are latched, it behaves as a forward biased PIN diode where the intrinsic region includes the n-base region <b>210</b><i>a</i>/<b>210</b><i>b </i>and the p-base region <b>220</b><i>a</i>/<b>220</b><i>b </i>in avalanche breakdown. When the SCRs are turned on, I<sub>ESD </sub>will continue to flow even if I<sub>t </sub>is no longer applied. An SCR fabricated in a submicron process will typically conduct about 10 mA to about 100 mA per &#x3bc;m width. The SCR will stop conduction once I<sub>ESD </sub>falls below a holding current, typically about 1 &#x3bc;A to about 1 mA of per &#x3bc;m width.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">In various embodiments, the trigger element can be coupled differently than is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref><i>a</i>. Further, the trigger element may include any suitable device including active and passive devices.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref><i>b </i>illustrates an ESD device comprising a stack of two SCR devices. Only two SCRs are shown for simplicity, whereas in practice more number of SCRs may be similarly stacked to satisfy the ESD target requirements. Although a PNPN SCR is described below, embodiments of the invention also include NPNP SCRs.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">A first well region comprising n-type n-base SCR regions <b>210</b><i>a </i>and <b>210</b><i>b </i>is disposed in the substrate <b>100</b>. In various embodiments, the n-base SCR regions <b>210</b><i>a </i>and <b>210</b><i>b </i>are doped to a concentration of about 5&#xd7;10<sup>16 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3 </sup>to about 5&#xd7;10<sup>18 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3</sup>, and about 5&#xd7;10<sup>17 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3 </sup>in one embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">A second well region comprising p-type p-base SCR regions <b>220</b><i>a </i>and <b>220</b><i>b </i>is disposed adjacent the n-base SCR regions <b>210</b><i>a </i>and <b>210</b><i>b</i>. In various embodiments, the second well region is doped to a concentration of about 5&#xd7;10<sup>16 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3 </sup>to about 5&#xd7;10<sup>18 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3</sup>, and about 5&#xd7;10<sup>17 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3 </sup>in one embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">P-type anodes <b>230</b><i>a </i>and <b>230</b><i>b </i>are disposed within the n-base SCR regions <b>210</b><i>a </i>and <b>210</b><i>b</i>. N-type cathode <b>240</b><i>a </i>and <b>240</b><i>b </i>are disposed within the p-base SCR regions <b>220</b><i>a </i>and <b>220</b><i>b</i>. The p-type anodes <b>230</b><i>a </i>and <b>230</b><i>b </i>and the n-type cathodes <b>240</b><i>a </i>and <b>240</b><i>b </i>are heavily doped regions. The p-type anodes <b>230</b><i>a </i>and <b>230</b><i>b </i>may be doped with boron wherein the doping is greater than about 1&#xd7;10<sup>19 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3</sup>, and higher than about 1&#xd7;10<sup>20 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3 </sup>in one embodiment. The n-type cathodes <b>240</b><i>a </i>and <b>240</b><i>b </i>may be doped with arsenic wherein the doping is greater than about 1&#xd7;10<sup>19 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3</sup>, and higher than about 1&#xd7;10<sup>20 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3 </sup>in one embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The p-type anodes <b>230</b><i>a </i>and <b>230</b><i>b </i>are isolated from the n-type cathodes <b>240</b><i>a </i>and <b>240</b><i>b </i>by isolation regions <b>225</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The p-type anode <b>230</b><i>a </i>of the first SCR <b>201</b> is coupled to the pad to be protected. The n-type cathode <b>240</b><i>a </i>of the first SCR <b>201</b> is coupled to the p-type anode <b>230</b><i>b </i>of the second SCR <b>202</b>, whereas the n-type cathode <b>240</b><i>b </i>of the second SCR <b>202</b> is coupled to the substrate voltage (VSS). Contacts <b>250</b><i>a</i>/<b>250</b><i>b </i>help contact the n-type n-base SCR regions <b>210</b><i>a </i>and <b>210</b><i>b</i>, whereas contacts <b>260</b><i>a</i>/<b>260</b><i>b </i>help contact the p-base SCR regions <b>220</b><i>a </i>and <b>220</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">As in prior embodiments, trenches <b>110</b> are embedded in the substrate <b>100</b>, and electrically isolate the doped regions of the first and the second SCRs <b>201</b> and <b>202</b>. The trenches <b>110</b> are lined with an insulating liner <b>105</b> and filled with undoped or low doped polysilicon, the doping being the same as the substrate <b>100</b>. In some embodiments, the trench may be filled with an undoped or low doped large band gap semiconductor such as SiC, GaP, GaN, InP, ZnO, ZnS. Alternatively, the trenches <b>110</b> may be filled only with an insulator.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">In various embodiments, the trenches <b>110</b> extend past the n-base SCR regions <b>210</b><i>a</i>/<b>210</b><i>b </i>and the p-base SCR regions <b>220</b><i>a</i>/<b>220</b><i>b </i>and into the substrate <b>100</b>. The trenches <b>110</b> are doped to a same conductivity type as the substrate <b>100</b> thus forming contacts to the substrate <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">As in prior embodiments, the use of trenches <b>110</b> advantageously isolates the first SCR <b>201</b> from the second SCR <b>202</b>. For example, in the absence of the trenches <b>110</b>, a parasitic device is formed between the p-base SCR region <b>220</b><i>a </i>and the n-base SCR region <b>210</b><i>b</i>. Due to the heavier doping of the p-base SCR region <b>220</b><i>a </i>and/or the n-base SCR region <b>210</b><i>b</i>, this diode has a low breakdown voltage and prohibits the use of this device (stack of these SCRs) as a high voltage ESD device.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates an embodiment of the invention wherein a stack of diodes form an ESD device.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, well regions <b>330</b><i>a </i>and <b>330</b><i>b </i>are formed having a low doped region of a first conductivity type. In one embodiment, the first conductivity type is an n-type region. The well regions <b>330</b><i>a </i>and <b>330</b><i>b </i>are doped to a concentration of about 5&#xd7;10<sup>16 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3 </sup>to about 5&#xd7;10<sup>18 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3</sup>, and about 5&#xd7;10<sup>17 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3 </sup>in one embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">First doped regions <b>320</b><i>a</i>/<b>320</b><i>b </i>are disposed within the well regions <b>330</b><i>a</i>/<b>330</b><i>b</i>. The first doped regions are separated from oppositely doped second doped regions <b>310</b><i>a </i>and <b>310</b><i>b</i>. The junction between the first doped region <b>320</b><i>a </i>and the well region <b>330</b><i>a </i>forms a first diode <b>301</b>, while the junction between the first doped region <b>320</b><i>b </i>and the well region <b>330</b><i>b </i>forms a second diode <b>302</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">As in prior embodiments, a trench <b>110</b> separates the first diode <b>301</b> from the second diode <b>302</b> avoiding the formation of parasitic diodes.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, which includes <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6</figref><i>a</i>-<b>6</b><i>e</i>, illustrates cross-sectional views of an ESD device in various stages of manufacturing in accordance with an embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref><i>a</i>, a first well region <b>120</b> is formed over the substrate <b>100</b>. The first well region <b>120</b> is formed using an epitaxial process in one embodiment. In various embodiments, the first well region <b>120</b> is doped to a concentration of about 5&#xd7;10<sup>16 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3 </sup>to about 5&#xd7;10<sup>18 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3</sup>, and about 5&#xd7;10<sup>17 </sup>cm<sup>&#x2212;3 </sup>in one embodiment. The first well region <b>120</b> is doped during the epitaxy in one embodiment. Alternatively, the first well region <b>120</b> is doped using an implant or a diffusion process.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">The trench openings <b>111</b> may be formed using a lithography process. For example, a hard mask (not shown) is deposited over the substrate <b>100</b> and patterned using a lithography process. Using the patterned hard mask as a etch mask, the trench openings <b>111</b> are formed by etching the first well region <b>120</b> and the substrate <b>100</b>. Thus, the trench openings <b>111</b> separate the first well region <b>120</b> into first, second, third, and fourth regions <b>151</b>, <b>152</b>, <b>153</b>, and <b>154</b>. Any remaining hard mask is removed.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">An insulating liner <b>105</b> is deposited and removed anisotropically leaving spacers on the sidewalls of the trench openings <b>111</b>, resulting in the structure shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref><i>b</i>. The trench openings <b>111</b> are filled with a conductive material forming the trenches <b>110</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref><i>c</i>. In various embodiments, the trench openings <b>111</b> are filled with polysilicon doped with a same conductivity type as the substrate <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">A second well region <b>130</b> is formed within the first well region <b>120</b>. The second well region <b>130</b> is formed by implanting into a portion of the first well region <b>120</b>. For example, a first portion of the first well region <b>120</b> is masked and the exposed portion is implanted into. The second well region <b>130</b> is doped to be opposite in doping to the first well region <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">A first doped region <b>140</b> and a second doped region <b>150</b> are subsequently formed by implantation and annealing forming the transistors <b>51</b>-<b>54</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref><i>d</i>). The transistors <b>51</b>-<b>54</b> are coupled together using the metallization layers, which are formed over the substrate <b>100</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref><i>e</i>).</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">In various embodiments, a semiconductor device comprises a first ESD device having a p/n junction disposed in a first region. A second ESD device having a p/n junction is disposed in a second region. The second region is adjacent the first region but is separated (electrically isolated) from the first region by a first trench. A third ESD device having a p/n junction is disposed in a third region. Similarly, the third region is disposed adjacent the second region but separated thereby electrically isolated from the second region by a second trench. A fourth ESD device having a p/n junction is disposed in a fourth region. The fourth region is adjacent the third region but electrically isolated from the third region by a third trench. The first, second, third, and fourth ESD devices are diodes, bipolar transistors, field effect transistors, or thyristors in various embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">Advantageously, embodiments of the invention reduce fabrication costs as high voltage ESD devices use a process common to the low voltage ESD devices. The cost savings is realized by the reduction in mask steps and reduction in number of implant steps, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">Although the present invention and its advantages have been described in detail, it should be understood that various changes, substitutions and alterations can be made herein without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention as defined by the appended claims. For example, it will be readily understood by those skilled in the art that many of the features, functions, processes, and materials described herein may be varied while remaining within the scope of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">Moreover, the scope of the present application is not intended to be limited to the particular embodiments of the process, machine, manufacture, composition of matter, means, methods and steps described in the specification. As one of ordinary skill in the art will readily appreciate from the disclosure of the present invention, processes, machines, manufacture, compositions of matter, means, methods, or steps, presently existing or later to be developed, that perform substantially the same function or achieve substantially the same result as the corresponding embodiments described herein may be utilized according to the present invention. Accordingly, the appended claims are intended to include within their scope such processes, machines, manufacture, compositions of matter, means, methods, or steps.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method of forming a semiconductor device, the method comprising:
<claim-text>forming an electrostatic discharge (ESD) device region within a semiconductor body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first ESD device in a first region of the ESD device region; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second ESD device in a second region of the ESD device region;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first trench in the semiconductor body, the second region being separated from the first region by the first trench;</claim-text>
<claim-text>lining sidewalls of the first trench with an insulator liner; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>filling the first trench at least partially with a conductive material.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising coupling a cathode region of the first ESD device to an anode region of the second ESD device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first and the second ESD devices comprise bipolar transistors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the bipolar transistors comprise npn transistors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein a collector region of the first ESD device is coupled to an emitter region of the second ESD device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein an emitter region and a base region of the first ESD device are coupled together.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the conductive material comprises a polysilicon material having a same conductivity type as the semiconductor body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the conductive material comprises a semiconductor material having a same conductivity type as the semiconductor body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the conductive material comprises a wide band-gap semiconductor material having a same conductivity type as the semiconductor body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the semiconductor body comprises a bulk silicon substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>forming a third ESD device in a third region of the ESD device region; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second trench in the semiconductor body, the third region being separated from the second region by the second trench.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first trench is at least 5 &#x3bc;m deep.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first ESD device is coupled to a reference voltage node, and wherein the second ESD device is coupled to a node to be protected.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein an operating voltage of the first ESD device and an operating voltage of the second ESD device is less than about 5V, and wherein an operating voltage of the semiconductor device is greater than about 10V.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein forming the first ESD device and forming the second ESD device comprises:
<claim-text>forming a first well region of a first conductivity type over and/or within the semiconductor body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second well region of a second conductivity type within the first well region, the second conductivity type being opposite to the first conductivity type; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first and a second doped region of the first conductivity type within the second well region, the first and the second doped regions being separated by a portion of the second well region, wherein the first well region of the first ESD device is separated from the first well region of the second ESD device by the first trench.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first and the second ESD devices comprise diodes, and wherein the first and the second ESD devices are a same type of device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first and the second ESD devices comprise thyristors, and wherein the first and the second ESD devices are a same type of device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first and the second ESD devices comprise field effect transistors, and wherein the first and the second ESD devices are a same type of device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A method of fabricating a semiconductor device, the method comprising:
<claim-text>forming an electrostatic discharge (ESD) device region within a semiconductor body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first ESD device in a first region of the ESD device region; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second ESD device in a second region of the ESD device region, the second region being separated from the first region by a first trench; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a wide band gap semiconductor material having the same conductivity type as the semiconductor body within the first trench, the first trench contacting the semiconductor body along sidewalls of the first trench.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the first and the second ESD devices comprise bipolar transistors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, wherein the bipolar transistors comprise npn transistors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, further comprising coupling a collector region of the first ESD device to an emitter region of the second ESD device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, further comprising coupling an emitter region and a base region of the first ESD device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein forming the first ESD device and forming the second ESD device comprises:
<claim-text>forming a first well region of a first conductivity type over and/or within the semiconductor body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second well region of a second conductivity type within the first well region, the second conductivity type being opposite to the first conductivity type; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first and a second doped region of the first conductivity type within the second well region, the first and the second doped regions being separated by a portion of the second well region, wherein the first well region of the first ESD device is separated from the first well region of the second ESD device by the first trench.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text>25. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>forming a third ESD device in a third region of the ESD device region; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second trench in the semiconductor body, the third region being separated from the second region by the second trench.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text>26. A method of forming a semiconductor device, the method comprising:
<claim-text>forming a first bipolar transistor having an emitter, a collector and a base region in a first region of an electrostatic discharge (ESD) device region of a semiconductor substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second bipolar transistor having an emitter, a collector and a base region in a second region of the ESD device region; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first trench between the first and the second regions, the first trench isolating the first bipolar transistor from the second bipolar transistor, wherein forming the first trench comprises:
<claim-text>etching a trench opening between the first and the second regions, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least partially filling the trench opening with a conductive semiconductor material.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text>27. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00026">claim 26</claim-ref>, further comprising forming metallization layers over the semiconductor substrate, wherein the metallization layers electrically couple the emitter of the second bipolar transistor with the collector of the first bipolar transistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text>28. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00026">claim 26</claim-ref>, further comprising coupling the first bipolar transistor to a reference voltage node; and
<claim-text>coupling the second bipolar transistor to a node to be protected.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029" num="00029">
<claim-text>29. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00026">claim 26</claim-ref>, wherein forming the first bipolar transistor and forming the second bipolar transistor comprises:
<claim-text>forming an epitaxial region of a first conductivity type on the substrate, wherein the first trench extends through the epitaxial region, wherein the epitaxial region of the first bipolar transistor is separated from the epitaxial region of the second bipolar transistor by the first trench.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030" num="00030">
<claim-text>30. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00029">claim 29</claim-ref>, wherein forming the first bipolar transistor and forming the second bipolar transistor further comprises:
<claim-text>forming base regions of a second conductivity type within the epitaxial regions, the second conductivity type being opposite to the first conductivity type; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming the emitters and the collectors of the first conductivity type within the base regions, the emitters and the collectors being separated by a portion of the base regions.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031" num="00031">
<claim-text>31. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00029">claim 29</claim-ref>, wherein forming the first trench further comprises:
<claim-text>etching the trench opening through the epitaxial layer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>lining sidewalls of the trench opening with a insulating material.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032" num="00032">
<claim-text>32. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00026">claim 26</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>forming a third bipolar transistor having an emitter, a collector and a base region in a third region of the ESD device region; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second trench between the second and the third regions, the second trench isolating the second bipolar transistor from the third bipolar transistor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033" num="00033">
<claim-text>33. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00032">claim 32</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>forming a fourth bipolar transistor having an emitter, a collector and a base region in a fourth region of the ESD device region; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a third trench between the third and the fourth regions, the third trench isolating the third bipolar transistor from the fourth bipolar transistor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034" num="00034">
<claim-text>34. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00026">claim 26</claim-ref>, wherein an operating voltage of the first bipolar transistor and an operating voltage of the second bipolar transistor is less than about 5V, and wherein an operating voltage of the semiconductor device is greater than about 10V.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
