<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08627191-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08627191</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11647868</doc-number>
<date>20061229</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>1607</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>715203</main-classification>
<further-classification>707102</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Producing an edited visual information sequence</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7424701</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kendall et al.</name>
<date>20080900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>717105</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7660416</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Kline</name>
<date>20100200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>380216</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2002/0175917</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Chakravarty et al.</name>
<date>20021100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>345473</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0220838</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ishii et al.</name>
<date>20031100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>705 14</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0057696</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Peters et al.</name>
<date>20040300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>386 52</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0055636</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Graves</name>
<date>20050300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>715526</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0188319</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Shinkai</name>
<date>20050800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>715751</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0118801</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Harshbarger et al.</name>
<date>20070500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>715730</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0239839</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Buday et al.</name>
<date>20071000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>709208</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0277220</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Shikuma et al.</name>
<date>20071100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>725139</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00011">
<othercit>Marshall, Dave, Open Media Framework Interchange (OMFI) Format:, http://www.cs.cf.ac.uk/Dave/Multimedia/node296.html, p. 1; Oct. 4, 2001.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00012">
<othercit>Ferster, Bill &#x201c;It's a Mob Mentality Out There: OMF Gains Followers&#x201d;, AV Video Magazine, pp. 1-3, http://www.stagetools.com/bill/Omf.htm, Jun. 1997.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00013">
<othercit>Apple Computer, &#x201c;Final Cut Pro&#x201d;, Wikipedia, http://wikipedia.org/wiki/Final<sub>&#x2014;</sub>Cut<sub>&#x2014;</sub>Pro, pp. 1-7, Feb. 22, 2007.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00014">
<othercit>Apple Computer, &#x201c;Cinema Tools&#x201d;, Wikipedia, http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cinema<sub>&#x2014;</sub>Tools, pp. 1-2, Sep. 26, 2006.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>25</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>715203</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080162538</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20080703</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kary</last-name>
<first-name>Michael Loran</first-name>
<address>
<city>Woodside</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kary</last-name>
<first-name>Michael Loran</first-name>
<address>
<city>Woodside</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Kenyon &#x26; Kenyon, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Apple Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Cupertino</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Ries</last-name>
<first-name>Laurie</first-name>
<department>2176</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Marrero</last-name>
<first-name>Zaida I</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A second sequence of visual information is produced, based on a first sequence of visual information. An XML document is generated, which identifies edits to be made to the first sequence of visual information for producing the second sequence of visual information. The XML document includes an element that corresponds to a cut list. The cut list element includes multiple item elements, which are subordinate to the cut list element within the XML document. The multiple item elements include at least one item element that represents an effect; at least one that represents a cut and/or at least one that represents a gap. The XML document is used to determine how to edit the first sequence of visual information, to produce the second sequence of visual information.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="127.51mm" wi="267.38mm" file="US08627191-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="192.19mm" wi="279.40mm" file="US08627191-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="241.64mm" wi="180.51mm" file="US08627191-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="235.71mm" wi="185.25mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627191-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="240.11mm" wi="164.00mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627191-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="127.08mm" wi="175.18mm" file="US08627191-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates generally to visual information, and more specifically, to producing an edited visual information sequence.</p>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Modem visual media include video and film formats. Editing film and video typically involves off-line and on-line processes. The highest quality representations of visual images include, for video media, original camera tape and, for film media, camera original film negative. Editing is typically not performed with these highest quality representations, which are preserved for production activities that follow editing.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Film editing with original negatives is avoided in order to preserve inviolate as much of the highest quality reproduction as possible. For video editing, the expense of procuring and operating the high end recording and playback equipment needed to function with the highest quality videotapes and digital files deters its use in editing. Thus, copies of the source material that are typically of somewhat lower quality than the source media are typically used for editing.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Editing decisions are made with the editing copies. For instance, with film, editing is performed with work prints, which are copies of the source negatives. This allows editing functions with equipment that is relatively inexpensive to procure and operate. Upon completion of editing, when all the editing decisions have been made using the copies, the original high quality source media are conformed to match the results of the editing process. In film editing, upon editing the work prints, a negative cutter matches the camera original negative with the edited reels of work print. Video editing is typically performed off-line to produce an edit decision list (EDL).</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">An EDL is typically exported from an off-line system and imported by an on-line system, which conforms the original videotape to the edit decisions listed in the EDL. The EDL technique was developed long before the existence of digital non-linear editing systems. Although very well established in fields related to video editing and production, EDLs are quite simple and somewhat narrowly focused in the information provided therein. Efforts have thus been made to replace EDLs with techniques capable of transferring from the off-line system to the on-line system more of the information that the more sophisticated digital non-linear editing (DNLE) systems now make available.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">One well known effort is the Open Media Framework (OMF), which is described in the OMF&#x2122; Interchange Specification available from Avid Technology, Inc., a corporation in Tewksbury, MA. This specification states that the OMF interchange format provides a standard for the interchanging of digital media data among heterogeneous platforms. Another effort is the Advanced Authoring Format (AAF), which is described at the website (www.aafassociation.org). More particularly, as described therein at: (www.aafassociation.org/html/techinfo/index.html), the AAF is a multi-media file format, which allows the exchange of digital media and meta-data across platforms and between systems and applications. However, export products of the OMF and AAF formats tend to be somewhat complex and not readily human readable.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Further, editing applications have developed, such as Final Cut Pro&#x2122; and Cinema Tools,&#x2122; which are commercially available from Apple Computers, Inc., a corporation in Sunnyvale, Calif. Final Cut Pro&#x2122; (FCP) and other such editing applications allow the transfer of editing data and meta-data from an off-line editing system to an on-line system or another application. FCP exports information about an edited sequence and the source material of that sequence, including meta-data. FCP exports this information in an Extensible Markup Language (XML) format.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Digital systems are also used with film based editing. The information captured in the film based medium is typically first transferred to a video medium, which is then digitized into the DNLE system. The DNLE system then performs the editing operations on the film based video, just as if the original source material was videotape. However, with this technique it becomes necessary to export a film cut list that contains information relating to the editing decisions, instead of an EDL. The film cut list contains information about film edge numbers, which is needed by the negative cutter to conform the original camera negative to the editing decisions.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Where applications such as FCP are used for editing video based source material, the application exports a video EDL, which identifies (e.g., names) a video by reel. The video EDL includes time code information for use by the on-line system. Where these applications edit film based source material, the applications export a film cut list, which contains film edge numbers for conforming the original camera negative. Conceptually therefore, a video EDL and a film cut list have essentially analogous purposes and contrast with each other in their actual content: the EDL having information specifically relevant for video media and the film cut list having information specifically relevant for film based media.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Newer techniques, such as &#x201c;digital intermediate,&#x201d; for finishing film do not involve cutting and splicing the original camera negative to conform the off-line edited sequence. Instead, the negative is scanned a first time at a relatively low or intermediate resolution, which is used for the off-line editing. Upon reaching the editing decisions, the original camera negative is scanned a second time at high resolution. This second scan, sometimes called a &#x201c;2K&#x201d; scan, is typically used for performing color correction and implementing high resolution effects. A digital printer then outputs the result to film, which can be used for theatrical release.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Some high end post-production facilities perform film finishing using these digital intermediate processes. Digital intermediate facilities typically use their own internal software for importing lists from the off-line editing systems and transforming that information into their own, essentially internal formats. Interestingly, the lists that these facilities rely on for the most part do not readily incorporate any of the alternatives developed to the EDL. Thus, OMF or AAF are not generally applied, nor are applications such as FCP widely used. Instead and despite their limitations, EDL lists are widely still used.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">It would appear that the reasons for the continued, modern use of EDLs for transferring editing data from off-line to on-line systems include its simplicity. Other reasons include the fact that EDLs are well known, popular and established in the field, and that they are time tested, reliable and widely supported. While newer formats such as OMF, AAF and FCP and similar formats make more information exportable than EDLs, complexity associated therewith may be deterring their widespread acceptance. Further, the newer formats are not yet well understood and little effort has been made to develop software to interface with them. Further, with the digital intermediate process, video reel and time code information from the EDL do not necessarily correlate with film edge numbers needed by the negative cutter. Where they are correlated (such as some efforts by Avid Technology, Inc.), exported information, like EDLs, is in plain text. However, plain text has limitations in transferring data from one computer platform to another. Where other formats are used however, they are less human readable than plain text.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Based on the foregoing, it would be useful to simplify the export of editing information from an off-line system.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The approaches described in this section are approaches that could be pursued, but not necessarily approaches that have been previously conceived or pursued. Therefore, unless otherwise indicated, it should not be assumed that any of the approaches described in this section qualify as prior art merely by virtue of their inclusion in this section.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The present invention is illustrated by way of example, and not by way of limitation, in the figures of the accompanying drawings and in which like reference numerals refer to similar elements and in which:</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> depicts an example process, according to an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> depicts an example XML document, according to an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> depicts an example production flow, according to an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> depicts an example computer platform upon which an embodiment of the present invention may be practiced; and</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> depicts an example process, according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF EXAMPLE EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Example embodiments of producing an edited visual information sequence are described herein. In the following description, for the purposes of explanation, numerous specific details are set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding of the present invention. It will be apparent, however, that the present invention may be practiced without these specific details. In other instances, well-known structures and devices are referred to without exhaustive treatment, in order to avoid unnecessarily obscuring the present invention.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">Overview</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Embodiments relate to producing an edited visual information sequence. In an embodiment, an XML document is generated. The XML document identifies edits to be made to the first sequence of visual information (e.g., unedited film or video), to produce the second sequence of visual information (e.g., edited film or video). The XML document includes an element that corresponds to a cut list. The cut list element includes multiple item elements, which are subordinate to the cut list element within the XML document.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The multiple item elements include at least one item element that represents an effect, at least one that represents a cut and/or at least one that represents a gap. The XML document is used to determine how to edit the first sequence of visual information, to produce the second sequence of visual information.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Thus, embodiments described herein allow the exportation of editing information from an off-line system in a format that is readily both human readable and machine readable.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Example Process</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> depicts an example process <b>100</b>, according to an embodiment of the present invention. To produce a second sequence of visual information based on a first sequence of visual information, an XML document is generated <b>101</b>, which identifies edits to be made to the first sequence of visual information.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The XML document includes a cut list element that corresponds to a cut list. A cut list is a list of editing decisions, such as an EDL, which can conform the first sequence of visual information to editing decisions for producing the second sequence of visual information. The cut list element includes multiple item elements, which are subordinate to the cut list element within the XML document.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The item elements include one or more elements that are representative of an effect (e.g., a visual effect such as a fade-in, fade-out, optical, etc.), a cut (e.g., of visual information from the first sequence of visual information) and/or a gap (e.g., between portions of visual information in the first sequence of visual information).</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The XML document is used <b>102</b> to determine how to edit the first sequence of visual information, to produce the second sequence of visual information. For instance, the editing decisions described, e.g., in both machine readable and human readable form, are used to edit the first sequence of visual information, in order to generate the second, e.g., edited sequence of visual information.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Example XML Document</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> depicts an example XML document <b>200</b>, according to an embodiment of the present invention. An sample of an XML document, represented with example XML document <b>200</b>, is appended hereto in Appendix &#x2018;A&#x2019; to the instant application and is incorporated herein. XML document <b>200</b> is generated to identify edits to be made to the first sequence of visual information, such as a film based source negative or a source videotape. Features of the sample XML document in Appendix &#x2018;A&#x2019; that are depicted with elements shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> are shown in the Tables, below. XML document <b>200</b> has a header <b>299</b> that identifies the source, title, sequence, time rates, background and related information about the visual sequences to which it pertains. The sample XML shown below in Table 1 corresponds to header <b>299</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00001" num="00001">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="21pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="196pt" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" rowsep="1">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;?xml version=&#x201c;1.0&#x201d; encoding=&#x201c;UTF-8&#x201d;?&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;ctlists version=&#x201c;0.1&#x201d;&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="28pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="189pt" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;title&#x3e;Sequence 1&#x3c;/title&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;projectname&#x3e;Sequence 1&#x3c;/projectname&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;cinematoolsversion&#x3e;3.1.2&#x3c;/cinematoolsversion&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;date&#x3e;Thu, Oct 12, 2006&#x3c;/date&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;time&#x3e;10:42:23 AM&#x3c;/time&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;database&#x3e;Gladiator CT db&#x3c;/database&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;filmstandard&#x3e;35mm4p&#x3c;/filmstandard&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningfootagestart&#x3e;0000+00&#x3c;/runningfootagestart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningcountstart&#x3e;000000&#x3c;/runningcountstart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimestart&#x3e;01:00:00:00&#x3c;/runningtimestart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimerate&#x3e;24&#x3c;/runningtimerate&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;originaltimebase&#x3e;24&#x3c;/originaltimebase&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;startwithleader&#x3e;false&#x3c;/startwithleader&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;includecutlist&#x3e;true&#x3c;/includecutlist&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;includedupelist&#x3e;true&#x3c;/includedupelist&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;includeopticallist&#x3e;true&#x3c;/includeopticallist&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;includepulllist&#x3e;true&#x3c;/includepulllist&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;includescenelist&#x3e;true&#x3c;/includescenelist&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;includemissinglist&#x3e;true&#x3c;/includemissinglist&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;transitions&#x3e;Standard transitions are cuts&#x3c;/transitions&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;duplicates&#x3e;Warn of duplicates&#x3c;/duplicates&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;transitionhandles&#x3e;0&#x3c;/transitionhandles&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;cuthandles&#x3e;one-half frame&#x3c;/cuthandles&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">XML document <b>200</b> has a cut list element <b>201</b> that corresponds to an editing cut list with a list of editing decisions. The editing decisions, like an EDL, specify how an original source of the first sequence of visual information is to be conformed to editing decisions to produce a second sequence of visual information. Cut list element <b>201</b> thus includes multiple item elements <b>210</b>, which are subordinate to the cut list element <b>201</b> within XML document <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">A cut item element <b>211</b> represents a cut, e.g., visual information that is to be cut (removed) from the first sequence of visual information to produce a final product (e.g., the second sequence of visual information). The sample XML shown in Table 2 below corresponds to cut item element <b>211</b> and shows the running film/video footage start, length and end, the running frame count start, length and end, and the running time start, length, end and rate, which correspond to the cut.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00002" num="00002">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="21pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="196pt" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" rowsep="1">TABLE 2</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;cut&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="28pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="189pt" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;eventnumber&#x3e;0001&#x3c;/eventnumber&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningfootagestart&#x3e;0000+00&#x3c;/runningfootagestart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningfootagelength&#x3e;0015+08&#x3c;/runningfootagelength&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningfootageend&#x3e;0015+07&#x3c;/runningfootageend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningcountstart&#x3e;000000&#x3c;/runningcountstart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningcountlength&#x3e;000248&#x3c;/runningcountlength&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningcountend&#x3e;000247&#x3c;/runningcountend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimestart&#x3e;01:00:00:00&#x3c;/runningtimestart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimelength&#x3e;00:00:10:08&#x3c;/runningtimelength&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimeend&#x3e;01:00:10:07&#x3c;/runningtimeend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimerate&#x3e;24&#x3c;/runningtimerate&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;keycodereversed&#x3e;false&#x3c;/keycodereversed&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;keyprefix&#x3e;KK 23 1166&#x3c;/keyprefix&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;keynumstart&#x3e;8010+06&#x3c;/keynumstart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;keynumend&#x3e;8025+13&#x3c;/keynumend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;inkprefix&#x3e;054&#x3c;/inkprefix&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;inknumstart&#x3e;1040+15&#x3c;/inknumstart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;inknumend&#x3e;1056+06&#x3c;/inknumend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;sourcetimestart&#x3e;08:00:27:07&#x3c;/sourcetimestart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;sourcetimeend&#x3e;08:00:37:14&#x3c;/sourcetimeend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;sourcetimerate&#x3e;24&#x3c;/sourcetimerate&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;filmstandard&#x3e;35mm4p&#x3c;/filmstandard&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;note&#x3e;Here is a note to go with A54-2(A)&#x3c;/note&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;videoreel&#x3e;068&#x3c;/videoreel&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;cameraroll&#x3e;054&#x3c;/cameraroll&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;labroll/&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;dailyroll/&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;scene&#x3e;A54&#x3c;/scene&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;take&#x3e;2(A)&#x3c;/take&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;clipname&#x3e;A54-2(A)&#x3c;/clipname&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;hasduplicateusage&#x3e;false&#x3c;/hasduplicateusage&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;hassuper&#x3e;false&#x3c;/hassuper&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="21pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="196pt" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;/cut&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">A gap item <b>212</b> represents a gap, e.g., a space to be removed between portions of the first sequence of visual information that are to be retained in the second sequence. The sample XML shown in Table 3 below corresponds to gap item element <b>212</b> and shows the running film/video footage start, length and end, the running frame count start, length and end, and the running time start, length, end and rate, which correspond to the gap.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00003" num="00003">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="14pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="203pt" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" rowsep="1">TABLE 3</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;gap&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="21pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="196pt" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;eventnumber&#x3e;0004&#x3c;/eventnumber&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningfootagestart&#x3e;0076+00&#x3c;/runningfootagestart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningfootagelength&#x3e;0015+06&#x3c;/runningfootagelength&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningfootageend&#x3e;0091+05&#x3c;/runningfootageend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningcountstart&#x3e;001216&#x3c;/runningcountstart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningcountlength&#x3e;000246&#x3c;/runningcountlength&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningcountend&#x3e;001461&#x3c;/runningcountend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimestart&#x3e;01:00:50:16&#x3c;/runningtimestart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimelength&#x3e;00:00:10:06&#x3c;/runningtimelength&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimeend&#x3e;01:01:00:21&#x3c;/runningtimeend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimerate&#x3e;24&#x3c;/runningtimerate&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="14pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="203pt" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x2002;&#x3c;/gap&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">An effect item <b>213</b> represents a visual effect to be used with the first sequence of visual information in producing the second sequence of visual information.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Various effects may be used in producing the second sequence of visual information. Some of these effects include the following. A fade in describes visual information relating to an incoming scene. A fade out describes visual information relating to an outgoing scene. A transition describes visual information relating to an outgoing scene, as well as to an incoming scene. A motion describes movement to be shown within a scene. An optical describes visual information relating to a scene that includes an optical effect described in a separate table, list or the like, and described perhaps with its own syntax. The sample XML shown in Table 4 corresponds to effect items <b>213</b>. The effect begins with a fade-in and includes a cross-dissolve, for which the running film/video footage start, length and end, the running frame count start, length and end, and the running time start, length, end and rate, which correspond thereto are given, as well as data relating to the incoming visual information of the cross-dissolve effect.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00004" num="00004">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="14pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="203pt" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" rowsep="1">TABLE 4</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;fadein&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="21pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="196pt" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;effectname&#x3e;Cross Dissolve&#x3c;/effectname&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningfootagestart&#x3e;0000+00&#x3c;/runningfootagestart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningfootagelength&#x3e;0001+08&#x3c;/runningfootagelength&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningfootageend&#x3e;0001+07&#x3c;/runningfootageend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningcountstart&#x3e;000000&#x3c;/runningcountstart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningcountlength&#x3e;000024&#x3c;/runningcountlength&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningcountend&#x3e;000023&#x3c;/runningcountend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimestart&#x3e;01:00:00:00&#x3c;/runningtimestart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimelength&#x3e;00:00:01:00&#x3c;/runningtimelength&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimeend&#x3e;01:00:00:23&#x3c;/runningtimeend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimerate&#x3e;24&#x3c;/runningtimerate&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;incoming&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="28pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="189pt" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;eventnumber&#x3e;0001&#x3c;/eventnumber&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;keycodereversed&#x3e;false&#x3c;/keycodereversed&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;keyprefix&#x3e;KK 23 1166&#x3c;/keyprefix&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;keynumstart&#x3e;8010+06&#x3c;/keynumstart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;keynumend&#x3e;8011+13&#x3c;/keynumend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;inkprefix&#x3e;054&#x3c;/inkprefix&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;inknumstart&#x3e;1040+15&#x3c;/inknumstart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;inknumend&#x3e;1042+06&#x3c;/inknumend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;sourcetimestart&#x3e;08:00:27:07&#x3c;/sourcetimestart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;sourcetimeend&#x3e;08:00:28:06&#x3c;/sourcetimeend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;sourcetimerate&#x3e;24&#x3c;/sourcetimerate&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;filmstandard&#x3e;35mm4p&#x3c;/filmstandard&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;note&#x3e;Here is a note to go with A54-2(A)&#x3c;/note&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;videoreel&#x3e;068&#x3c;/videoreel&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;cameraroll&#x3e;054&#x3c;/cameraroll&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;labroll/&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;dailyroll/&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;scene&#x3e;A54&#x3c;/scene&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;take&#x3e;2(A)&#x3c;/take&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;clipname&#x3e;A54-2(A)&#x3c;/clipname&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="21pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="196pt" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;/incoming&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="14pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="203pt" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;/fadein&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">XML document <b>200</b> may also include a pull list <b>222</b>, which relates information related to film reel and/or videotape identifiers to allow original source material to be conformed to the information in the cut list element <b>201</b>. XML document <b>200</b> may also include an optical list <b>233</b>, which relates information related to film reel and/or videotape identifiers to allow original source material to be conformed to the information in the cut list element <b>201</b>. One or more separate motion effects and/or filter effects elements <b>244</b> may also be included in XML document <b>200</b>. The sample XML shown in Table 5 corresponds to portions of a multiple segment pull list element <b>222</b> and shows the running film/video footage start, length and end, the running frame count start, length and end, and the running time start, length, end and rate, which correspond to the pull list items shown.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00005" num="00005">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217pt" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" rowsep="1">TABLE 5</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;pulllist&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="14pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="203pt" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;items&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="21pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="196pt" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;pull&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="28pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="189pt" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;eventnumber&#x3e;0002&#x3c;/eventnumber&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningfootagestart&#x3e;0014+12&#x3c;/runningfootagestart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningfootagelength&#x3e;0017+12&#x3c;/runningfootagelength&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningfootageend&#x3e;0032+07&#x3c;/runningfootageend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningcountstart&#x3e;000236&#x3c;/runningcountstart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningcountlength&#x3e;000284&#x3c;/runningcountlength&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningcountend&#x3e;000519&#x3c;/runningcountend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimestart&#x3e;01:00:09:20&#x3c;/runningtimestart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimelength&#x3e;00:00:11:20&#x3c;/runningtimelength&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimeend&#x3e;01:00:21:15&#x3c;/runningtimeend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimerate&#x3e;24&#x3c;/runningtimerate&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;keycodereversed&#x3e;false&#x3c;/keycodereversed&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;keyprefix&#x3e;KK 05 1354&#x3c;/keyprefix&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;keynumstart&#x3e;4359+04&#x3c;/keynumstart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;keynumend&#x3e;4376+15&#x3c;/keynumend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;inkprefix&#x3e;054&#x3c;/inkprefix&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;inknumstart&#x3e;1366+10&#x3c;/inknumstart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;inknumend&#x3e;1384+05&#x3c;/inknumend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;sourcetimestart&#x3e;08:04:04:10&#x3c;/sourcetimestart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;sourcetimeend&#x3e;08:04:16:05&#x3c;/sourcetimeend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;sourcetimerate&#x3e;24&#x3c;/sourcetimerate&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;filmstandard&#x3e;35mm4p&#x3c;/filmstandard&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;note/&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;videoreel&#x3e;068&#x3c;/videoreel&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;cameraroll&#x3e;054&#x3c;/cameraroll&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;labroll/&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;dailyroll/&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;scene&#x3e;A54A&#x3c;/scene&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;take&#x3e;1(B)&#x3c;/take&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;clipname&#x3e;A54A-1(B)&#x3c;/clipname&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="21pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="196pt" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;/pull&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The sample XML shown in Table 6 below corresponds to an example of optical list <b>233</b> and shows the running film/video footage start, length and end, the running frame count start, length and end, and the running time start, length, end and rate, which correspond to the respective items shown. Filter effects element <b>244</b> and various other features, functions, effects and items may similarly be shown.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00006" num="00006">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="14pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="203pt" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" rowsep="1">TABLE 6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;optical&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="21pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="196pt" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;eventnumber&#x3e;0003&#x3c;/eventnumber&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;opticalnumber&#x3e;0001&#x3c;/opticalnumber&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningfootagestart&#x3e;0032+08&#x3c;/runningfootagestart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningfootagelength&#x3e;0043+08&#x3c;/runningfootagelength&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningfootageend&#x3e;0075+15&#x3c;/runningfootageend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningcountstart&#x3e;000520&#x3c;/runningcountstart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningcountlength&#x3e;000696&#x3c;/runningcountlength&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningcountend&#x3e;001215&#x3c;/runningcountend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimestart&#x3e;01:00:21:16&#x3c;/runningtimestart&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimelength&#x3e;00:00:29:00&#x3c;/runningtimelength&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimeend&#x3e;01:00:50:15&#x3c;/runningtimeend&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x3c;runningtimerate&#x3e;24&#x3c;/runningtimerate&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="14pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="203pt" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x2002;&#x3c;/optical&#x3e;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Example Production Flow</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> depicts an example production flow <b>300</b>, according to an embodiment of the present invention. An original source stream <b>301</b> of visual information is made with a camera (e.g., an original negative) or videotape recorder (e.g., for high quality video recordings). A copy <b>302</b> is prepared from the source stream <b>301</b> and supplied to an editing application <b>311</b>, which accepts editing inputs. In response to the editing inputs, a document generating function <b>312</b> of editing application <b>311</b> produces an XML document such as XML document <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The XML document is exported to a post-production application <b>313</b>. A conforming function <b>314</b> of application <b>313</b> conforms the original source stream <b>301</b> of visual information to editing decisions specified with the XML document. Upon conforming the original source stream to the editing decisions, a final sequence <b>320</b> (e.g., a second sequence) of visual information is made available.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Example Hardware Implementation</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> depicts an example computer system <b>400</b> upon which an embodiment of the invention may be implemented. Computer system <b>400</b> includes a bus <b>402</b> or other communication mechanism for communicating information, and a processor <b>404</b> coupled with bus <b>402</b> for processing information. Computer system <b>400</b> also includes a main memory <b>406</b>, such as a random access memory (RAM) or other dynamic storage device, coupled to bus <b>402</b> for storing information and instructions to be executed by processor <b>404</b>. Main memory <b>406</b> also may be used for storing temporary variables or other intermediate information during execution of instructions to be executed by processor <b>404</b>. Computer system <b>400</b> further includes a read only memory (ROM) <b>408</b> or other static storage device coupled to bus <b>402</b> for storing static information and instructions for processor <b>404</b>. A storage device <b>410</b>, such as a magnetic disk or optical disk, is provided and coupled to bus <b>402</b> for storing information and instructions.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Computer system <b>400</b> may be coupled via bus <b>402</b> to a display <b>412</b>, such as a liquid crystal display (LCD), a cathode ray tube (CRT) or the like, for displaying information to a computer user. An input device <b>414</b>, including alphanumeric and other keys, is coupled to bus <b>402</b> for communicating information and command selections to processor <b>404</b>. Another type of user input device is cursor control <b>416</b>, such as a mouse, a trackball, or cursor direction keys for communicating direction information and command selections to processor <b>404</b> and for controlling cursor movement on display <b>412</b>. This input device typically has two degrees of freedom in two axes, a first axis (e.g., x) and a second axis (e.g., y), that allows the device to specify positions in a plane. Example embodiments of the invention relate to the use of computer system <b>400</b> for replicating changes, made to data blocks at a source database system, to replicas of the data blocks at the standby database system. According to one embodiment of the invention, replicating changes, made to data blocks at a source database system, to replicas of the data blocks at the standby database system is provided by one or more instances of computer system <b>400</b> in response to processor <b>404</b> executing one or more sequences of one or more instructions contained in main memory <b>406</b>. Such instructions may be read into main memory <b>406</b> from another computer-readable medium, such as storage device <b>410</b>. Execution of the sequences of instructions contained in main memory <b>406</b> causes processor <b>404</b> to perform the process steps described herein. One or more processors in a multi-processing arrangement may also be employed to execute the sequences of instructions contained in main memory <b>406</b>. In alternative embodiments, hard-wired circuitry may be used in place of or in combination with software instructions to implement the invention. Thus, embodiments of the invention are not limited to any specific combination of hardware circuitry and software.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The term &#x201c;computer-readable medium&#x201d; as used herein refers to any medium that participates in providing instructions to processor <b>404</b> for execution. Such a medium may take many forms, including but not limited to, non-volatile media, volatile media, and transmission media. Non-volatile media includes, for example, optical or magnetic disks, such as storage device <b>410</b>. Volatile media includes dynamic memory, such as main memory <b>406</b>. Transmission media includes coaxial cables, copper wire and fiber optics, including the wires that comprise bus <b>402</b>. Transmission media can also take the form of acoustic or light waves, such as those generated during radio wave and infrared data communications.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Common forms of computer-readable media include, for example, a floppy disk, a flexible disk, hard disk, magnetic tape, or any other magnetic medium, a CD-ROM, any other optical medium, punch cards, paper tape, any other legacy or other physical medium with patterns of holes and other computer-readable media, a RAM, a PROM, and EPROM, a FLASH-EPROM, any other memory chip or cartridge, a carrier wave as described hereinafter, or any other medium from which a computer can read.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Various forms of computer readable media may be involved in carrying one or more sequences of one or more instructions to processor <b>404</b> for execution. For example, the instructions may initially be carried on a magnetic disk of a remote computer. The remote computer can load the instructions into its dynamic memory and send the instructions over a telephone line using a modem. A modem local to computer system <b>400</b> can receive the data on the telephone line and use an infrared transmitter to convert the data to an infrared signal. An infrared detector coupled to bus <b>402</b> can receive the data carried in the infrared signal and place the data on bus <b>402</b>. Bus <b>402</b> carries the data to main memory <b>406</b>, from which processor <b>404</b> retrieves and executes the instructions. The instructions received by main memory <b>406</b> may optionally be stored on storage device <b>410</b> either before or after execution by processor <b>404</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Computer system <b>400</b> also includes a communication interface <b>418</b> coupled to bus <b>402</b>. Communication interface <b>418</b> provides a two-way data communication coupling to a network link <b>420</b> that is connected to a local network <b>422</b>. For example, communication interface <b>418</b> may be an integrated services digital network (ISDN) card a cable or digital subscriber line (DSL) modem or another modem to provide a data communication connection to a corresponding type of telephone line. As another example, communication interface <b>418</b> may be a local area network (LAN) card to provide a data communication connection to a compatible LAN. Wireless links may also be implemented. In any such implementation, communication interface <b>418</b> sends and receives electrical, electromagnetic or optical signals that carry digital data streams representing various types of information.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Network link <b>420</b> typically provides data communication through one or more networks to other data devices. For example, network link <b>420</b> may provide a connection through local network <b>422</b> to a host computer <b>424</b> or to data equipment operated by an Internet Service Provider (ISP) <b>426</b>. ISP <b>426</b> in turn provides data communication services through the worldwide packet data communication network now commonly referred to as the &#x201c;Internet&#x201d; <b>428</b>. Local network <b>422</b> and Internet <b>428</b> both use electrical, electromagnetic or optical signals that carry digital data streams. The signals through the various networks and the signals on network link <b>420</b> and through communication interface <b>418</b>, which carry the digital data to and from computer system <b>400</b>, are exemplary forms of carrier waves transporting the information.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Computer system <b>400</b> can send messages and receive data, including program code, through the network(s), network link <b>420</b> and communication interface <b>418</b>. In the Internet example, a server <b>430</b> might transmit a requested code for an application program through Internet <b>428</b>, ISP <b>426</b>, local network <b>422</b> and communication interface <b>418</b>. In accordance with the invention, one such downloaded application provides for replicating changes, made to data blocks at a source database system, to replicas of the data blocks at the standby database system, as described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The received code may be executed by processor <b>404</b> as it is received, and/or stored in storage device <b>410</b>, or other non-volatile storage for later execution. In this manner, computer system <b>400</b> may obtain application code in the form of a carrier wave.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Computer system <b>400</b> can be configured to perform the example processes described herein. In an embodiment, multiple computer systems <b>400</b> are combined to configure a system for generating and parsing XML documents to perform an example process described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Example Process</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> depicts an example process <b>500</b>, according to an embodiment of the present invention. To produce a second sequence of visual information based. on a first sequence of visual information, an XML document is received <b>101</b>, which was generated to identify edits to be made to the first sequence of visual information. The XML document is used <b>102</b> to determine how to edit the first sequence of visual information, to produce the second sequence of visual information.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">Equivalents, Extensions, Alternatives &#x26; Miscellaneous</heading>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Thus, example embodiments relating to producing an edited visual information sequence are described. In the foregoing specification, embodiments of the invention have been described with reference to numerous specific details that may vary from implementation to implementation. Thus, the sole and exclusive indicator of what is the invention, and is intended by the applicants to be the invention, is the set of claims that issue from this application, in the specific form in which such claims issue, including any subsequent correction. Any definitions expressly set forth herein for terms contained in such claims shall govern the meaning of such terms as used in the claims. Hence, no limitation, element, property, feature, advantage or attribute that is not expressly recited in a claim should limit the scope of such claim in any way. The specification and drawings are, accordingly, to be regarded in an illustrative rather than a restrictive sense.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method of producing a second sequence of visual information based on a first sequence of visual information, the method comprising:
<claim-text>receiving input specifying one or more editing decisions that identify one or more edits to be made to the first sequence of visual information to produce the second sequence of visual information;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a single Extensible Markup Language (XML) document that specifies how a source of the first sequence of visual information is to be conformed to the one or more editing decisions to produce the second sequence of visual information;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein at least one editing decision of the one or more editing decisions relates to either:
<claim-text>(a) visual information that is to be cut from the first sequence of visual information to produce a final product,</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a space to be removed between portions of the first sequence of visual information that are to be retained in the second sequence of visual information, or</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) a visual effect to be used with the first sequence of visual information in producing the second sequence of visual information;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the XML document comprises at least one element corresponding to the at least one editing decision;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the at least one element contains information subordinate to the at least one element within the XML document;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the subordinate information pertains to the at least one editing decision and includes running film footage information, running frame count information, and running time information pertaining to the at least one editing decision;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the running film footage information comprises an element, subordinate in the XML document to the at least one element, that specifies a running film footage count pertaining to the at least one editing decision;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the running frame count information comprises an element, subordinate in the XML document to the at least one element, that specifies a running frame count pertaining to the at least one editing decision but does not specify a running footage count pertaining to the at least one editing decision;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the running time information comprises an element, subordinate in the XML document to the at least one element, that specifies a running time pertaining the at least one editing decision;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the method is performed by one or more computing devices.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one element corresponds to a particular cut; and wherein the at least one element that corresponds to the particular cut includes subordinate elements that indicate:
<claim-text>a running footage start for the particular cut;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running footage length for the particular cut;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running footage end for the particular cut;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running count start for the particular cut;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running count length for the particular cut;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running count end for the particular cut;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running time start for the particular cut;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running time length for the particular cut; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running time end for the particular cut.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the at least one element corresponds to a particular gap; and wherein the at least one element that corresponds to the particular gap includes subordinate elements that indicate:
<claim-text>a running footage start for the particular gap;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running footage length for the particular gap;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running footage end for the particular gap;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running count start for the particular gap;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running count length for the particular gap;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running count end for the particular gap;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running time start for the particular gap;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running time length for the particular gap; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running time end for the particular gap.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the at least one element corresponds to a particular effect; and wherein the at least one element that corresponds to the particular effect includes subordinate elements that indicate:
<claim-text>a running footage start for the particular effect;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running footage length for the particular effect;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running footage end for the particular effect;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running count start for the particular effect;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running count length for the particular effect;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running count end for the particular effect;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running time start for the particular effect;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running time length for the particular effect; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a running time end for the particular effect.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref> wherein the particular effect comprises a visual transition effect.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> wherein the visual transition effect comprises one or more of a fade-in and a fade-out.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> wherein, upon said visual transition effect comprising a fade-in, a transitional content associated with the fade-in comprises an essentially gradual development of an incoming scene.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> wherein, upon said visual transition effect comprising a fade-out, a transitional content associated with the fade-out comprises an essentially gradual extinguishing of an outgoing scene.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref> wherein the particular effect comprises an optical effect.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the XML document includes a cut list element that corresponds to a cut list, wherein the cut list element includes a plurality of item elements that are subordinate to the cut list element within the XML document;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the plurality of item elements include one or more items from the set of an item element that represents an effect, an item element that represents a cut, and an item element that represents a gap.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>using said XML document to determine how to edit the source of said first sequence of visual information to produce said second sequence of visual information.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. A method for producing a second sequence of visual information based on a first sequence of visual information, the method comprising:
<claim-text>receiving a single Extensible Markup Language (XML) document that specifies how a source of the first sequence of visual information is to be conformed to one or more editing decisions to produce the second sequence of visual information;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein at least one editing decision of the one or more editing decisions relates to either:
<claim-text>(a) visual information that is to be cut from the first sequence of visual information to produce a final product,</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a space to be removed between portions of the first sequence of visual information that are to be retained in the second sequence of visual information, or</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) a visual effect to be used with the first sequence of visual information in producing the second sequence of visual information;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the XML document comprises at least one element corresponding to the at least one editing decision;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the at least one element contains information subordinate to the at least one element within the XML document;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the subordinate information pertains to the at least one editing decision and includes running film footage information, running frame count information, and running time information pertaining to the at least one editing decision;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the running film footage information comprises an element, subordinate in the XML document to the at least one element, that specifies a running film footage count pertaining to the at least one editing decision;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the running frame count information comprises an element, subordinate in the XML document to the at least one element, that specifies a running frame count pertaining to the at least one editing decision but does not specify a running footage count pertaining to the at least one editing decision;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the running time information comprises an element, subordinate in the XML document to the at least one element, that specifies a running time pertaining to the at least one editing decision;</claim-text>
<claim-text>using said XML document to determine how to edit the source of said first sequence of visual information to produce said second sequence of visual information;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the method is performed by one or more computing devices.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A system for producing a second sequence of visual information based on a first sequence of visual information, the system comprising:
<claim-text>a bus;</claim-text>
<claim-text>one or more processors coupled to said bus;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a storage coupled to said bus;</claim-text>
<claim-text>code stored with said storage, which when executed by said one or more processors causes said one or more processors to generate a single Extensible Markup Language (XML) document that specifies how a source of a first sequence of visual information is to be conformed to one or more editing decisions to produce a second sequence of visual information;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein at least one editing decision of the one or more editing decisions relates to either:
<claim-text>(a) visual information that is to be cut from the first sequence of visual information to produce a final product,</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a space to be removed between portions of the first sequence of visual information that are to be retained in the second sequence of visual information, or</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) a visual effect to be used with the first sequence of visual information in producing the second sequence of visual information;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the XML document comprises at least one element corresponding to the at least one editing decision;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the at least one element contains information subordinate to the at least one element within the XML document;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the subordinate information pertains to the at least one editing decision and includes running film footage information, running frame count information, and running time information pertaining to the at least one editing decision;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the running film footage information comprises an element, subordinate in the XML document to the at least one element, that specifies a running film footage count pertaining to the at least one editing decision;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the running frame count information comprises an element, subordinate in the XML document to the at least one element, that specifies a running frame count pertaining to the at least one editing decision but does not specify a running footage count pertaining to the at least one editing decision;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the running time information comprises an element, subordinate in the XML document to the at least one element, that specifies a running time pertaining to the at least one editing decision.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A computer-readable non-transitory storage medium storing one or more sequences of instructions which, when executed by one or more processors, causes the one or more processors to perform the method recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A computer-readable non-transitory storage medium storing one or more sequences of instructions which, when executed by one or more processors, causes the one or more processors to perform the method recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A computer-readable non-transitory storage medium storing one or more sequences of instructions which, when executed by one or more processors, causes the one or more processors to perform the method recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. A computer-readable non-transitory storage medium storing one or more sequences of instructions which, when executed by one or more processors, causes the one or more processors to perform the method recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. A computer-readable non-transitory storage medium storing one or more sequences of instructions which, when executed by one or more processors, causes the one or more processors to perform the method recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A computer-readable non-transitory storage medium storing one or more sequences of instructions which, when executed by one or more processors, causes the one or more processors to perform the method recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. A computer-readable non-transitory storage medium storing one or more sequences of instructions which, when executed by one or more processors, causes the one or more processors to perform the method recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. A computer-readable non-transitory storage medium storing one or more sequences of instructions which, when executed by one or more processors, causes the one or more processors to perform the method recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. A computer-readable non-transitory storage medium storing one or more sequences of instructions which, when executed by one or more processors, causes the one or more processors to perform the method recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. A computer-readable non-transitory storage medium storing one or more sequences of instructions which, when executed by one or more processors, causes the one or more processors to perform the method recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. A computer-readable non-transitory storage medium storing one or more sequences of instructions which, when executed by one or more processors, causes the one or more processors to perform the method recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text>25. A computer-readable non-transitory storage medium storing one or more sequences of instructions which, when executed by one or more processors, causes the one or more processors to perform the method recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
