<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623564-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623564</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12262889</doc-number>
<date>20081031</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>1083</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>M</subclass>
<main-group>8</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>429428</main-classification>
<further-classification>429429</further-classification>
<further-classification>429430</further-classification>
<further-classification>429408</further-classification>
<further-classification>429413</further-classification>
<further-classification>429432</further-classification>
<further-classification>429444</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Method for remedial action in the event of the failure of the primary air flow measurement device in a fuel cell system</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6504717</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Heard</name>
<date>20030100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>361695</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2002/0022161</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kurosaki et al.</name>
<date>20020200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>429 13</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0159147</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ueda et al.</name>
<date>20040800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 731181</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0164057</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Pospichal et al.</name>
<date>20050700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>429 25</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0160361</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ohara et al.</name>
<date>20080700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>429 17</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0239928</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Tsuchiya</name>
<date>20100900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>429430</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO/2007/117018</doc-number>
<date>20071000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>19</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>429430</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>429408</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>429434</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>429429</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>429413</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>429444</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>429428</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>429432</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>2</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20100112386</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20100506</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kirklin</last-name>
<first-name>Matthew C</first-name>
<address>
<city>Pittsford</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kirklin</last-name>
<first-name>Matthew C</first-name>
<address>
<city>Pittsford</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Miller</last-name>
<first-name>John A.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Miller IP Group, PLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>GM Global Technology Operations LLC</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Detroit</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Ryan</last-name>
<first-name>Patrick</first-name>
<department>1726</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Usyatinsky</last-name>
<first-name>Alex</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A system and method for controlling the speed of a compressor in the event that an airflow meter that measures the airflow from the compressor to the cathode input of the stack fails. When a failure of the airflow meter is detected, an algorithm first deactivates the primary feedback control algorithms used to control cathode pressure and flow, and sets the cathode exhaust valve to a fully open position. The speed of the compressor is controlled by an open loop set-point and the airflow from the compressor is estimated by a model using compressor discharge pressure and the compressor speed. The cathode by-pass valve position is determined by calculating the difference between the requested cathode airflow and the modeled compressor output flow. The position of the by-pass valve is then adjusted using the valve characteristics and the compressor discharge pressure. The estimated airflow to the stack is used to control the maximum stack current.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="185.00mm" wi="237.24mm" file="US08623564-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="241.30mm" wi="187.37mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623564-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="229.70mm" wi="119.72mm" file="US08623564-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This invention relates generally to a system and method for controlling airflow to a fuel cell stack in the event of a cathode input flow meter failure and, more particularly, to a system and method for controlling the flow of cathode input air to a fuel cell stack in a fuel cell system in the event that a flow meter for measuring the airflow fails by providing open-loop control of a compressor.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Discussion of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Hydrogen is a very attractive fuel because it is clean and can be used to efficiently produce electricity in a fuel cell. A hydrogen fuel cell is an electrochemical device that includes an anode and a cathode with an electrolyte therebetween. The anode receives hydrogen gas and the cathode receives oxygen or air. The hydrogen gas is dissociated in the anode to generate free hydrogen protons and electrons. The hydrogen protons pass through the electrolyte to the cathode. The hydrogen protons react with the oxygen and the electrons in the cathode to generate water. The electrons from the anode cannot pass through the electrolyte, and thus are directed through a load to perform work before being sent to the cathode.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFC) are a popular fuel cell for vehicles. The PEMFC generally includes a solid polymer electrolyte proton conducting membrane, such as a perfluorosulfonic acid membrane. The anode and cathode typically include finely divided catalytic particles, usually platinum (Pt), supported on carbon particles and mixed with an ionomer. The catalytic mixture is deposited on opposing sides of the membrane. The combination of the anode catalytic mixture, the cathode catalytic mixture and the membrane define a membrane electrode assembly (MEA). MEAs are relatively expensive to manufacture and require certain conditions for effective operation.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Several fuel cells are typically combined in a fuel cell stack to generate the desired power. For example, a typical fuel cell stack for a vehicle may have two hundred or more stacked fuel cells. The fuel cell stack receives a cathode input gas, typically a flow of air forced through the stack by a compressor. Not all of the oxygen is consumed by the stack and some of the air is output as a cathode exhaust gas that may include water as a stack by-product. The fuel cell stack also receives an anode hydrogen input gas that flows into the anode side of the stack.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The fuel cell stack includes a series of bipolar plates positioned between the several MEAs in the stack, where the bipolar plates and the MEAs are positioned between two end plates. The bipolar plates include an anode side and a cathode side for adjacent fuel cells in the stack. Anode gas flow channels are provided on the anode side of the bipolar plates that allow the anode reactant gas to flow to the respective MEA. Cathode gas flow channels are provided on the cathode side of the bipolar plates that allow the cathode reactant gas to flow to the respective MEA. One end plate includes anode gas flow channels, and the other end plate includes cathode gas flow channels. The bipolar plates and end plates are made of a conductive material, such as stainless steel or a conductive composite. The end plates conduct the electricity generated by the fuel cells out of the stack.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Proper airflow measurement and control to the cathode side of a fuel cell stack is critical for the operation of a fuel cell system. If too much air is delivered to the stack, energy is wasted and the fuel cells in the stack may become too dry, affecting their durability. Too little air delivered to the stack can result in fuel cell instability due to oxygen starvation. Therefore, fuel cell systems typically employ an airflow meter in the cathode input line to provide an accurate measurement of the flow of air to the fuel cell stack. If the airflow meter fails, it has typically been necessary to shut the fuel cell system down because by not knowing the amount of air being delivered to the fuel cell stack with enough accuracy could have a detrimental effect on system components.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In order to increase the reliability of a fuel cell system, it is desirable to continue to operate the system in the event that the primary cathode airflow measuring device fails and to maintain an acceptable level of performance without causing long term damage to the system or stack components.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In accordance with the teachings of the present invention, a system and method are disclosed for controlling the speed of a compressor in a fuel cell system in the event that an airflow meter that measures the airflow from the compressor to the cathode input of the stack fails. When a failure of the airflow meter is detected, an algorithm first deactivates the primary feedback control algorithms used to control cathode pressure and flow, and sets the cathode exhaust valve to a fully open position. Next, the speed of the compressor is controlled by an open loop set-point and the airflow from the compressor is estimated by a model using compressor discharge pressure and the compressor speed. The cathode by-pass valve position is determined by calculating the difference between the requested cathode airflow and the modeled compressor output flow. The position of the by-pass valve is then adjusted using the valve characteristics and the compressor discharge pressure. The estimated airflow to the stack is used to control the maximum stack current.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Additional features of the present invention will become apparent from the following description and appended claims, taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic block diagram of a fuel cell system employing a process for controlling the speed of a cathode input compressor in the event of a failure of an airflow meter, according to an embodiment of the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a flow chart diagram showing the process for controlling the speed of the compressor in response to failure of the airflow meter.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The following discussion of the embodiments of the invention directed to a system and method for controlling a cathode air compressor in response to a failure of an airflow meter is merely exemplary in nature, and is in no way intended to limit the invention or its applications or uses.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic block diagram of a fuel cell system <b>10</b> including a fuel cell stack <b>12</b>. The fuel cell system <b>10</b> also includes a compressor <b>14</b> driven by a motor <b>16</b> that provides an airflow to a cathode side of the fuel cell stack <b>12</b> on a cathode input line <b>18</b>. A temperature sensor <b>20</b> measures the temperature of the cathode input air into the stack <b>12</b> and an RH sensor <b>22</b> measures the relative humidity of the cathode input air into the stack <b>12</b>. The humidity of the cathode input air is provided by a water vapor transfer (WVT) unit <b>24</b> that receives a cathode exhaust gas on cathode exhaust line <b>26</b> that typically has a humidity of 100% or more. Water and water vapor from the cathode exhaust gas is used in the WVT unit <b>24</b> to humidify the cathode input air that is provided on the input line <b>18</b>. A pressure sensor <b>48</b> in the cathode exhaust line <b>26</b> measures the pressure of the cathode side of the stack <b>12</b>. The cathode exhaust gas is output from the WVT unit <b>24</b> on system output line <b>28</b> and is controlled by a cathode exhaust gas valve <b>30</b>. For those times when it may not be desirable to humidify the cathode input air, the cathode input air can be directed around the WVT unit <b>24</b> on by-pass line <b>32</b> through a by-pass valve <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The cathode input air from the compressor <b>14</b> is sent to a heat exchanger <b>36</b> that reduces the temperature of the cathode input air as a result of it being compressed by the compressor <b>14</b>. Additionally, the heat exchanger <b>36</b> can provide heat to the cathode input air during certain times, such as cold start up, to heat the fuel cell stack <b>12</b> more quickly. A pressure sensor <b>50</b> at the output of the compressor <b>14</b> measures the discharge pressure of the compressor <b>14</b>. The cathode input air from the heat exchanger <b>36</b> is sent through an airflow measuring device <b>38</b>, such as a mass flow meter, that measures the flow of the cathode input air to the stack <b>12</b>. As is well understood to those skilled in the art, the flow of the cathode input air to the stack <b>12</b> needs to be tightly controlled to provide the proper cathode stoichiometry so that too much air is not provided to the stack <b>12</b>, which could have an adverse drying effect on the membranes within the fuel cells in the stack <b>12</b>, or too little of air that can cause fuel cell instability as a result of oxygen starvation. A temperature sensor <b>40</b> measures the temperature of the cathode input airflow to control the heat exchanger <b>36</b> and a valve <b>42</b> controls the amount of cathode air that flows into the WVT unit <b>24</b> or by-passes the WVT unit <b>24</b> on the by-pass line <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The flow of air from the compressor <b>14</b> to the cathode side of the stack <b>12</b> is controlled by a controller <b>52</b> based on the stack current demand and the stack pressure. Being able to tune the compressor <b>14</b> to provide the exact amount of air for the desired cathode stoichiometry is typically not possible. Therefore, a cathode by-pass valve <b>44</b> is provided that proportionally controls the amount of cathode input air that by-passes the stack <b>12</b> or flows to the stack <b>12</b> through the heat exchanger <b>26</b>. The cathode air that by-passes the stack <b>12</b> flows through a by-pass line <b>46</b> and directly to the system output line <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">As discussed above, it is necessary to know the amount of cathode airflow to the fuel cell stack <b>12</b> for proper stack operation. Therefore, if the airflow measuring device <b>38</b> fails, it is desirable to have a fallback position where the airflow to the fuel cell stack <b>12</b> can be determined. According to an embodiment of the present invention, in the event of a failure of the airflow measuring device <b>38</b>, an algorithm of the controller <b>52</b> first deactivates the primary feedback control algorithms used to control pressure and flow to the fuel cell stack <b>12</b>, and sets the cathode exhaust gas valve <b>30</b> to a fully open position. Also, the speed of the compressor <b>14</b> is set by an open-loop set-point of the controller <b>52</b> for a particular stack power request from a look-up table, and the airflow from the compressor <b>14</b> is estimated by a model using the compressor discharge pressure and the compressor speed. The position of the by-pass valve <b>44</b> is determined by the controller <b>52</b> by calculating the difference between the requested compressor flow from the open-loop set-point and the modeled compressor output flow. The position of the valve <b>44</b> is adjusted using the valve characteristics and the compressor discharge pressure. The resulting estimated stack airflow to the stack is used to control the maximum stack current.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a flow chart diagram showing a process for controlling the airflow to the cathode side of the fuel cell stack <b>12</b> in the event of a failure of the airflow measuring device <b>38</b>, as discussed above. The airflow control algorithm detects an airflow measuring device failure at box <b>62</b>, and then disengages the primary airflow control algorithms at box <b>64</b>. The algorithm then sets the cathode exhaust valve <b>30</b> to its fully opened position at box <b>66</b>. The algorithm then determines a power demand from the stack <b>12</b> at box <b>68</b>. Based on that power demand, the algorithm controls the speed of the compressor <b>14</b> using an open-loop control set-point and a look-up table at box <b>70</b>. Because the airflow to the stack <b>12</b> will depend on the cathode pressure, the open-loop control of the compressor <b>14</b> is a combination of the speed of the compressor <b>14</b> and the discharge pressure of the compressor <b>14</b>. Therefore, the open-loop control algorithm will estimate or model the compressor flow based on the speed of the compressor <b>14</b> and the discharge pressure at box <b>72</b> to give a more accurate reading of the airflow. If the flow is more than what is necessary for the power demand, the airflow can be tuned using the cathode by-pass valve <b>44</b> by opening the valve <b>44</b> at box <b>74</b> based on the valve characteristics to reduce the flow to the stack <b>12</b>. Reducing the flow to the stack <b>12</b> may have application for idle speeds.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The foregoing discussion discloses and describes merely exemplary embodiments of the present invention. One skilled in the art will readily recognize from such discussion and from the accompanying drawings and claims that various changes, modifications and variations can be made therein without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention as defined in the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method for controlling an airflow to a fuel cell stack, said method comprising:
<claim-text>a controller programmed to:</claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting that an airflow measuring device that measures the airflow to the fuel cell stack has failed;</claim-text>
<claim-text>disengaging primary airflow control algorithms in response to the detected failure;</claim-text>
<claim-text>setting a cathode exhaust valve to an open position;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a power request from the fuel cell stack; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>controlling the speed of a compressor that provides the cathode airflow to the stack using an open-loop control, wherein controlling the speed of the compressor includes determining a predetermined speed of the compressor for the power request, estimating the airflow to the fuel cell stack based on the speed of the compressor and a discharge pressure of the compressor and controlling a cathode by-pass valve to reduce the cathode airflow if the estimated flow is too high for the power request.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein determining a predetermined speed of the compressor for the power request includes using a look-up table to determine the speed of the compressor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein controlling the cathode by-pass valve includes calculating the difference between the compressor airflow from the predetermined speed and the estimated airflow.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref> wherein controlling the cathode by-pass valve includes determining valve characteristics to determine how much to open or close the by-pass valve.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the discharge pressure of the compressor is measured by a pressure sensor at the output of the compressor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the airflow measuring device is a mass airflow meter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A method for controlling an airflow to a fuel cell stack, said method comprising:
<claim-text>a controller programmed to:</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining that an airflow measuring device that measures the airflow to a cathode side of the fuel cell stack has failed;</claim-text>
<claim-text>disengaging primary airflow control algorithms in response to the detected failure;</claim-text>
<claim-text>setting a cathode exhaust valve to an open position; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>controlling the speed of a compressor that provides the cathode airflow to the stack using an open-loop control.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref> wherein controlling the speed of the compressor includes determining a predetermined speed of the compressor for the power request, estimating the airflow to the fuel cell stack based on the speed of the compressor and a discharge pressure of the compressor and controlling a cathode by-pass valve to reduce the cathode airflow if the estimated flow is too high for the power request.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> wherein controlling the cathode by-pass valve includes calculating the difference between the compressor airflow from the predetermined speed and the estimated airflow.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref> wherein controlling the cathode by-pass valve includes determining valve characteristics to determine how much to open or close the by-pass valve.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref> wherein determining a predetermined speed of the compressor for the power request includes using a look-up table to determine the speed of the compressor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref> wherein the discharge pressure of the compressor is measured by a pressure sensor at the output of the compressor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref> wherein the airflow measuring device is a mass airflow meter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A system for controlling an airflow to a fuel cell stack, said system comprising:
<claim-text>a controller programmed to provide</claim-text>
<claim-text>means for detecting that an airflow measuring device that measures the airflow to the fuel cell stack has failed;</claim-text>
<claim-text>means for disengaging primary airflow control algorithms in response to the detected failure;</claim-text>
<claim-text>means for setting a cathode exhaust valve to an open position;</claim-text>
<claim-text>means for determining a power request from the fuel cell stack; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>means for controlling the speed of a compressor that provides the cathode air to the stack using an open-loop control, said means for controlling the compressor including means for determining a predetermined speed of the compressor for the power request, means for estimating the airflow to the fuel cell stack based on the speed of the compressor and a discharge pressure of the compressor and means for controlling a cathode by-pass valve to reduce the cathode airflow if the estimated flow is too high for the power request.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref> wherein the means for determining a predetermined speed of the compressor for the power request includes that the controller is further programmed to use a look-up table to determine the speed of the compressor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref> wherein the means for controlling the cathode by-pass valve includes that the controller is further programmed to include means for calculating the difference between the compressor airflow from the predetermined speed and the estimated airflow.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref> wherein the means for controlling the cathode by-pass valve includes that the controller is further programmed to include means for determining valve characteristics to determine how much to open or close the by-pass valve.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref> wherein the discharge pressure of the compressor is measured by a pressure sensor at the output of the compressor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref> wherein the airflow measuring device is a mass airflow meter.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
