<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626010-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626010</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13718383</doc-number>
<date>20121218</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2009-0096810</doc-number>
<date>20091012</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<disclaimer>
<text>This patent is subject to a terminal disclaimer.</text>
</disclaimer>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>399 37</main-classification>
<further-classification>363 74</further-classification>
<further-classification>363 78</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e69">Electric power relaying unit and image forming apparatus having the same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4926862</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Miyajima et al.</name>
<date>19900500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>607142</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8259422</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Naito et al.</name>
<date>20120900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>361 18</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8358943</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kim</name>
<date>20130100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>399 37</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0238383</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Watanabe et al.</name>
<date>20081000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>323271</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>10-125423</doc-number>
<date>19980500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>2003-0060343</doc-number>
<date>20030700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00007">
<othercit>Tsuchida, Eiji, English Abstract, JP 2008172962 A, Jul. 2008.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00008">
<othercit>Tsuchida, Eiji, English Translation, JP 2008172962 A, Jul. 2008.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00009">
<othercit>U.S. Office Action mailed May 29, 2012 in copending U.S. Appl. No. 12/801,549.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00010">
<othercit>U.S. Notice of Allowance mailed Sep. 28, 2012 in copending U.S. Appl. No. 12/801,549.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00011">
<othercit>U.S. Appl. No. 12/801,549, filed Jun. 14, 2010, Jin Ha Kim, Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>11</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>399 37</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>399 74</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>399 78</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>10</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>10</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12801549</doc-number>
<date>20100614</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8358943</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13718383</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130108305</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130502</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Jin-ha</first-name>
<address>
<city>Seongnam-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Staas &#x26; Halsey LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Suwon-Si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Walsh</last-name>
<first-name>Ryan</first-name>
<department>2852</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An electric power relaying unit of an image forming apparatus which includes an electric power blocking unit which selectively blocks the alternating current electric power output from the electric power input unit to be input to the electric power output unit, the electric power blocking unit including: a switching unit which switches an input of the alternating current electric power with respect to the electric power output unit; an electric power detecting unit which detects an electric power property; a memory unit in which a predetermined electric power property information is stored; and a control unit which controls a switching operation of the switching unit if determining that the detected electric power property corresponds to a predetermined electric power property in a failure of the image forming apparatus main body from a comparison result.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="216.32mm" wi="179.32mm" file="US08626010-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="206.59mm" wi="179.07mm" file="US08626010-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="222.17mm" wi="173.91mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626010-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="240.03mm" wi="179.07mm" file="US08626010-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="230.38mm" wi="180.59mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626010-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="229.62mm" wi="180.59mm" file="US08626010-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="241.47mm" wi="183.56mm" file="US08626010-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="254.17mm" wi="172.38mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626010-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="221.40mm" wi="189.48mm" file="US08626010-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="185.76mm" wi="194.65mm" file="US08626010-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="198.37mm" wi="172.38mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626010-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation of U.S. application Ser. No. 12/801,549, filed on Jun. 14, 2010, which claims priority from Korean Patent Application No. 10-2009-0096810, filed on Oct. 12, 2009 in the Korean Intellectual Property Office, the disclosures of which are incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Apparatuses consistent with the present embodiments relate to an electric power relaying unit connected to an external power supply and an image forming apparatus having the same, and more particularly, to an electric power relaying unit corresponding to the case that an alternating current power supplied from an external power supply shows a failure electric power property and an image forming apparatus having the same.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">An image forming apparatus applies a developer, an ink, etc. to form an image on a printing medium based on an image data input from a host. To perform this function, the image forming apparatus receives an electric power from an external power supply.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The image forming apparatus is designed with a consideration of various using environments in manufacturing thereof, and is applied with a configuration design capable of protecting various elements in the apparatus to prepare the case that an electric power supplied from an external power supply shows an abnormal state such as an overcurrent.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">However, since the image forming apparatus has been released to be used under various environments, a failure may happen due to a factor which fails to be expected in a designing operation. For example, an electric power supplied from an external power supply may have an abnormal property which was not considered in a designing operation. In this case, if a protecting configuration disposed in the image forming apparatus fails to block the electric power showing this property, this may be the cause of a failure or a fire of the image forming apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">If this problem happens, conventionally, the image forming apparatus is collected from a user, and a configuration of the image forming apparatus is replaced or corrected to correspond to a failure electric power property of the problem to be then delivered to the user. That is, a recall preventing a failure or a fire of the image forming apparatus is performed.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">However, in this method, it is difficult for a general user rather than a manufacturer to repair the image forming apparatus. Accordingly, since the image forming apparatus should be collected to a manufacturer, it is inconvenient for the user not to use the image forming apparatus during a recall period. Also, it is difficult for the manufacturer to collect and repair all image forming apparatus of the same model as the recall target.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Accordingly, it is an aspect to provide an electric power relaying unit protecting an image forming apparatus from a failure electric power without the necessity that a manufacturer collects image forming apparatus when it is necessary to recall the image forming apparatus, and an image forming apparatus having the same.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The foregoing and/or other aspects can be achieved by providing an electric power relaying unit of an image forming apparatus which transmits an alternating current electric power output from an external power supply to an image forming apparatus main body, the electric power relaying unit of the image forming apparatus including: an electric power input unit which is connected to the external power supply, and receives an alternating current electric power from the external power supply; an electric power output unit which is connected to an electric power input terminal of the image forming apparatus main body, and outputs the input alternating current electric power to the image forming apparatus main body; and an electric power blocking unit which selectively blocks the alternating current electric power output from the electric power input unit to be input to the electric power output unit, the electric power blocking unit including: a switching unit which switches an input of the alternating current electric power with respect to the electric power output unit; an electric power detecting unit which detects an electric power property of the alternating current electric power; a memory unit in which a predetermined electric power property information is stored; and a control unit which compares an electric power property detected by the electric power detecting unit with an electric power property information stored in the memory unit, and controls a switching operation of the switching unit if determining that the detected electric power property corresponds to a predetermined electric power property in a failure of the image forming apparatus main body from a comparison result.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">If the alternating current electric power corresponds to an abnormal electric power predetermined to correspond to an operating environment of the image forming apparatus main body, the control unit may determine that the alternating current electric power corresponds to an electric power property in a failure of the image forming apparatus main body.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The memory unit may store a profile of a predetermined abnormal electric power pattern, and if an electric power pattern detected by the electric power detecting unit corresponds to the profile of the abnormal electric power stored in the memory unit, the control unit may determine that the alternating current electric power corresponds to an electric power property in a failure of the image forming apparatus main body.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The electric power blocking unit may include an interface unit which is provided to be accessible to the memory unit from an outside so that the profile of the electric power pattern stored in the memory unit can be updated.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The interface unit may include at least one of a memory port to which an external memory is mounted, and a communication port allowing a local communication or a network communication.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The electric power blocking unit may include a display unit which displays that an output of the alternating current electric power is blocked by the switching unit.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The electric power output unit may be provided to allow a plurality of image forming apparatus main bodies to be connected thereto so that the plurality of image forming apparatus main bodies can respectively receive the alternating current electric power.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The alternating current electric power output from the switching unit may diverge to respectively corresponds to the plurality of image forming apparatus main bodies.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The electric power blocking unit may be disposed in plural to correspond to each alternating current electric power diverging to respectively corresponding to the plurality of image forming apparatus main bodies from the electric power input unit.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The electric power relaying unit may include a user input unit, wherein the switching unit may switch the alternating current electric power to correspond to an input command of the user input unit.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The electric power relaying unit may include a user input unit, wherein if a predetermined time is input through the user input unit, the control unit may control a switching operation of the switching unit to correspond to an elapse of the input time.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Another aspect may be achieved by providing an image forming apparatus, including: an image forming apparatus main body; and an electric power relaying unit which transmits an alternating current electric power output from an external power supply to the image forming apparatus main body.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Another aspect may be achieved by providing an electric power relaying unit which transmits an alternating current electric power output from an external power supply to an electronic device, the electric power relaying unit including: an electric power input unit which is connected to the external power supply, and receives an alternating current electric power from the external power supply; an electric power output unit which is connected to an electric power input terminal of the electronic device, and outputs the input alternating current electric power to the electronic device; and an electric power blocking unit which selectively blocks the alternating current electric power output from the electric power input unit to be input to the electric power output unit, the electric power blocking unit including: a switching unit which switches an input of the alternating current electric power with respect to the electric power output unit; an electric power detecting unit which detects an electric power property of the alternating current electric power; a memory unit in which a predetermined electric power property information is stored; and a control unit which compares an electric power property detected by the electric power detecting unit with an electric power property information stored in the memory unit, and controls a switching operation of the switching unit if determining that the detected electric power property corresponds to a predetermined electric power property in a failure of the electronic device from a comparison result.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Additional aspects and/or advantages will be set forth in part in the description which follows and, in part, will be apparent from the description, or may be learned by practice of the embodiments.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The above and/or other aspects and advantages will become apparent and more readily appreciated from the following description of the embodiments, taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings of which:</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> exemplarily illustrates an image forming apparatus according to an exemplary embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a side sectional view illustrating a configuration of an image forming apparatus main body of the image forming apparatus in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an electric power transmitting and controlling configuration of an electric power relaying unit in the image forming apparatus in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a block diagram illustrating a disposition of the electric power relaying unit when the electric power relaying unit is applied to the image forming apparatus in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> exemplarily illustrates an image forming apparatus according to an exemplary embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an electric power transmitting and controlling configuration of an electric power relaying unit in the image forming apparatus in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an electric power transmitting and controlling configuration of an electric power relaying unit according to an exemplary embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an electric power transmitting and controlling configuration of an electric power relaying unit according to an exemplary embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an electric power transmitting and controlling configuration of an electric power relaying unit according to an exemplary embodiment; and</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an electric power transmitting and controlling configuration of an electric power relaying unit according to an exemplary embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Reference will now be made in detail to the embodiments, examples of which are illustrated in the accompanying drawings, wherein like reference numerals refer to like elements throughout. The exemplary embodiments are described below so as to explain the embodiments by referring to the figures. Repetitive description with respect to like elements of different embodiments may be omitted for the convenience of clarity. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> exemplarily illustrates an image forming apparatus <b>1</b> according to an exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, an image forming apparatus <b>1</b> includes an image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> receiving an electric power from an external power supply <b>3</b> to operate, and an electric power cable <b>20</b> connecting the external power supply <b>3</b> and the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> and transmitting an alternating current electric power supplied from the external power supply <b>3</b> to the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> includes a cable connecting unit <b>19</b>, an outer side of which is connected to an end part of the electric power cable <b>20</b> to receive an alternating current electric power.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Hereinafter, an operation of the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> will be described by referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a side sectional view illustrating a configuration of the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> includes a medium supplying unit <b>400</b> supplying a loaded printing medium, an image forming cartridge <b>500</b>K, <b>500</b>C, <b>500</b>M and <b>500</b>Y having an image carrying body <b>510</b>K, <b>510</b>C, <b>510</b>M and <b>510</b>Y forming a visible image by a developer of each color, an exposing unit <b>600</b> corresponding to an image data to expose the image carrying body <b>510</b>K, <b>510</b>C, <b>510</b>M and <b>510</b>Y, a transferring unit <b>700</b> transferring a visible image formed on the image carrying body <b>510</b>K, <b>510</b>C, <b>510</b>M and <b>510</b>Y to a printing medium depending on a middle transferring method, a fusing unit <b>800</b> fusing an image on a printing medium, and an electric power supplying unit <b>900</b> supplying an electric power to these elements.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The medium supplying unit <b>400</b> includes a loading cassette <b>410</b> on which a printing medium is loaded, and a pickup roller <b>420</b> picking up a printing medium loaded on the loading cassette <b>410</b> to supply one by one. The picked up printing medium is transported to a registration roller <b>430</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The registration roller <b>430</b> aligns a front end of a transported printing medium, and transports the printing medium to the transferring unit <b>700</b> at a predetermined timing. The printing medium passes through the transferring unit <b>700</b> and the fusing unit <b>800</b>, and an image is formed on a surface thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">A duplex roller <b>440</b> reversely transports a printing medium, a surface of which is formed with an image to the registration roller <b>430</b>. The printing medium reversely transported by the duplex roller <b>440</b> is transported to the transferring unit <b>700</b> at an appropriate timing by the registration roller <b>430</b> again so that an image can be formed on the other surface thereof on which an image is not formed.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The image forming cartridge <b>500</b>K, <b>500</b>C, <b>500</b>M and <b>500</b>Y is configured to correspond to a plurality of colors. For example, the image forming cartridge <b>500</b>K, <b>500</b>C, <b>500</b>M and <b>500</b>Y is provided to correspond to a developer of black, cyan, magenta and yellow, and supplies the developer of each color to the image carrying body <b>510</b>K, <b>510</b>C, <b>510</b>M and <b>510</b>Y.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The image carrying body <b>510</b>K, <b>510</b>C, <b>510</b>M and <b>510</b>Y is exposed by the exposing unit <b>600</b> so that an electrostatic latent image is formed on a surface thereof, and the image forming cartridge <b>500</b>K, <b>500</b>C, <b>500</b>M and <b>500</b>Y supplies a developer to the electrostatic latent image so that a visible image can be formed on the image carrying body <b>510</b>K, <b>510</b>C, <b>510</b>M and <b>510</b>Y.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The transferring unit <b>700</b> transfers a visible image of the image carrying body <b>510</b>K, <b>510</b>C, <b>510</b>M and <b>510</b>Y on a printing medium with a middle transferring type. For this, the transferring unit <b>700</b> includes a middle transferring belt <b>710</b> moving by a caterpillar type with contacting to the image carrying body <b>510</b>K, <b>510</b>C, <b>510</b>M and <b>510</b>Y so that a visible image can be transferred and overlapped thereon, a driving roller <b>720</b> rotating the middle transferring belt <b>710</b>, a final transferring roller <b>730</b> transferring a visible image on the middle transferring belt <b>710</b> to a printing medium, and a transferring backup roller <b>740</b> backing up the final transferring roller <b>730</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Also, the transferring unit <b>700</b> includes a transferring roller <b>750</b>K, <b>750</b>C, <b>750</b>M and <b>750</b>Y disposed to correspond to the image carrying body <b>510</b>K, <b>510</b>C, <b>510</b>M and <b>510</b>Y to interpose the middle transferring belt <b>710</b> therebetween. The transferring roller <b>750</b>K, <b>750</b>C, <b>750</b>M and <b>750</b>Y faces each image carrying body <b>510</b>K, <b>510</b>C, <b>510</b>M and <b>510</b>Y, and transfers a visible image on the image carrying body <b>510</b>K, <b>510</b>C, <b>510</b>M and <b>510</b>Y to the middle transferring belt <b>710</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The fusing unit <b>800</b> includes a heating roller <b>810</b> generating and emitting a heat, and a pressing roller <b>820</b> pressing the heating roller <b>810</b> to form a nip. A printing medium to which a visible image is transferred by the transferring unit <b>700</b> passes through the nip between the heating roller <b>810</b> and the pressing roller <b>820</b>, and the visible image on the printing medium is fused by the heat and the pressure.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The electric power supplying unit <b>900</b> converts an alternating current electric power supplied from the external power supply <b>3</b> into a direct current electric power, and adjusts to an appropriate voltage level corresponding to each element to output to each element.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Here, since the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> directly receives an alternating current electric power through the electric power cable <b>20</b>, an alternating current electric power of an abnormal electric power pattern which fails to be considered in a design manufacturing process of the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> may be transmitted to the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>. In this case, the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> is apt to be out of order or a fire is apt to be caused.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">For example, the heating roller <b>810</b> of the fusing unit <b>800</b> generates a high heat for fusing. If an abnormal electric power is supplied to the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>, the amount of a heat generated in the heating roller <b>810</b> is apt to increase up as to damage the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>. To prevent this, a fuse (not shown) is disposed in the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>. However, if an electric power having a failure electric power property failing to be considered in a manufacturing process is input to the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>, the fuse fails to be short-circuited and the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> may be ignited due to an overheat of the heating roller <b>810</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Accordingly, the image forming apparatus <b>1</b> includes an electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> selectively transmitting an alternating current electric power from the external power supply <b>3</b> to the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>. If an alternating current electric power corresponds to an abnormal electric power pattern determined to correspond to an operating environment of the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>, the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> blocks the alternating current electric power to be transmitted to the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Accordingly, although the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> is not recalled and repaired, the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> can be protected to correspond to an abnormal electric power pattern considered after the manufacturing process.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Here, the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> has a configuration corresponding to existing plug and outlet to contact and electrically connect to the existing electric power cable <b>20</b> and the cable connecting unit <b>19</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Hereinafter, a configuration of the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> according to the present exemplary embodiment will be described by referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an electric power transmitting and controlling configuration of the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> includes an electric power input unit <b>100</b> to which an alternating current electric power is input from the external power supply <b>3</b>, an electric power output unit <b>200</b> outputting an alternating current electric power input to the electric power input unit <b>100</b> to the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>, and an electric power blocking unit <b>300</b> blocking an alternating current electric power to be transmitted to the electric power output unit <b>200</b> if an alternating current electric power pattern input to the electric power input unit <b>100</b> is determined to be an abnormal electric power pattern.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The electric power input unit <b>100</b> is connected to the electric power cable <b>20</b> connected to the external power supply <b>3</b>, or is directly connected to the external power supply <b>3</b> to receive an alternating current electric power to output to the electric power output unit <b>200</b>. The electric power input unit <b>100</b> may include at least one of an outlet configuration for enabling an end part of the electric power cable <b>20</b> to be connected thereto, and a plug configuration for being connected to the external power supply <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The electric power output unit <b>200</b> outputs an alternating current electric power output from the electric power input unit <b>100</b> to the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>. Like the case of the electric power input unit <b>100</b>, the electric power output unit <b>200</b> may have a configuration to which the electric power cable <b>20</b> connected to the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> is connected, or a configuration allowing to be directly connected to the cable connecting unit <b>19</b> of the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The electric power blocking unit <b>300</b> includes a switching unit <b>310</b> switching an alternating current electric power output from the electric power input unit <b>100</b> to be input to the electric power output unit <b>200</b>, an electric power detecting unit <b>320</b> detecting an electric power pattern of an alternating current electric power output from the electric power input unit <b>100</b>, a memory unit <b>350</b> in which a profile of a predetermined electric power pattern is stored, and a control unit <b>370</b> comparing an electric power pattern detected in the electric power detecting unit <b>320</b> with an electric power pattern profile of the memory unit <b>350</b> to determine whether to be an abnormal electric power or not and controlling the switching unit <b>310</b> depending on this determining result.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Also, the electric power blocking unit <b>300</b> may further include a display unit <b>330</b> displaying a control operation of the control unit <b>370</b>, a user input unit <b>340</b> manipulated by a user and transmitting a predetermined command to the control unit <b>370</b>, and an interface unit <b>360</b> provided to be accessible to the memory unit <b>350</b> or the control unit <b>370</b> from an outside.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The switching unit <b>310</b> is disposed on an electric power path between the electric power input unit <b>100</b> and the electric power output unit <b>200</b>, and selectively allows or blocks an output of an alternating current electric power. The configuration of the switching unit <b>310</b> for this is not defined, and may be embodied by a relay or a switching semiconductor such as a triode for alternating current (TRIAC). The TRIAC means a kind of a two direction and three terminal thyrister capable of controlling an average current.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The electric power detecting unit <b>320</b> is disposed on an electric power path between the electric power input unit <b>100</b> and the switching unit <b>310</b>. The electric power detecting unit <b>320</b> detects various electric power information, such as a current or a voltage of an alternating current electric power, to transmit to the control unit <b>370</b>. In general, since an alternating current electric power output from the external power supply <b>3</b> is a high voltage of 110V or 220V, the electric power detecting unit <b>320</b> decreases the voltage of the alternating current electric power so that the control unit <b>370</b> can be prevented from being damaged. Also, the electric power detecting unit <b>320</b> may convert the alternating current electric power into a direct current electric power having a voltage decreased to a predetermined level to transmit to the control unit <b>370</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The electric power detecting unit <b>320</b> may be embodied by various types depending on a design type, and may employ a potential transformer (PT), a current transformer (CT), a shunt, etc. The potential transformer converts a high voltage to a low voltage which is proportional thereto, and is connected in parallel with a circuit to be used. The current transformer lowers a high current to a low current which is proportional thereto, and is connected in series with a circuited to be used. The shunt is a stationary resistor connected in series with a circuit, and has a high precision in comparison to the current transformer.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The display unit <b>330</b> displays a current operating state of the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b>, for example, the case that an alternating current electric power output is blocked by an abnormal electric power detecting, to inform a user. The display unit <b>330</b> may be embodied by a liquid crystal display, a light emitting diode (LED), a speaker, a buzzer, etc. Also, the display unit <b>330</b> may display a manipulating state of the user input unit <b>340</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The user input unit <b>340</b> is manipulated by a user to transmit a command controlling the switching unit <b>310</b> to the control unit <b>370</b>. For example, the user input unit <b>340</b> may transmit a command blocking or allowing an output of an alternating current electric power through the switching unit <b>310</b> to the control unit <b>370</b>. Also, when updating an electric power pattern profile of the memory unit <b>350</b> through the interface unit <b>360</b>, a user may control this updating process through the user input unit <b>340</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The memory unit <b>350</b> is embodied by a non volatile memory such as a flash memory to prevent a stored data from disappearing although an electric power is blocked. The memory unit <b>350</b> stores a profile of an abnormal electric power pattern corresponding to an operating environment of the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>. That is, various profiles of abnormal electric power patterns which fail to be taken into account at a time manufacturing the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> are stored in the memory unit <b>350</b>, and these profiles are differently designated depending on the kind, a manufacturer, a model name, etc. of the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">A profile of an electric power pattern stored in the memory unit <b>350</b> may be embodied by various information such as a current value, a voltage value, a current wave pattern, etc., and may be not defined thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The interface unit <b>360</b> is disposed so that the control unit <b>370</b> can communicate with an outside, or so that a data stored in the memory unit <b>350</b> can be accessible. That is, the interface unit <b>360</b> allows updating such as deleting, correcting, adding, etc. of an electric power pattern profile already stored in the memory unit <b>350</b> to be performed.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">The interface unit <b>360</b> is connected with an external computer (not shown) by a local or a network to allow this updating to be performed. Also, the interface unit <b>360</b> allows a universal serial bus (USB) memory in which an electric power pattern profile for updating is stored to be connected, and allows an updating code determined in the control unit <b>370</b> to be executed so that an updating can be automatically performed.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The control unit <b>370</b> compares an electric power pattern detected from the electric power detecting unit <b>320</b> with an electric power pattern profile stored in the memory unit <b>350</b>, and determines whether an alternating current electric power transmitted to the electric power output unit <b>200</b> from the electric power input unit <b>100</b> corresponds to an abnormal electric power pattern or not from this comparing result.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">If the control unit <b>370</b> determines that the alternating current electric power does not correspond to an abnormal electric power pattern and is normal, the control unit <b>370</b> allows an electric power output through the switching unit <b>310</b>. Accordingly, the alternating current electric power output from the external electric power <b>3</b> can be supplied to the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> through the electric power output unit <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">On the other hand, if the control unit <b>370</b> determines that the alternating current electric power corresponds to an abnormal electric power pattern, the control unit <b>370</b> controls a switching operation of the switching unit <b>310</b> to block an electric power output through the switching unit <b>310</b>. Accordingly, supplying of the alternating current electric power through the electric power output unit <b>200</b> is blocked, and the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> is prevented from being supplied with an electric power. That is, if an alternating current electric power shows an abnormal electric power pattern which becomes the cause of failure of the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>, the corresponding alternating current electric power can be prevented from being transmitted to the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>, thereby preventing a failure or a fire of the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The control unit <b>370</b> displays this control result of the switching unit <b>310</b> through the display unit <b>330</b> to inform a user.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The control unit <b>370</b> may be embodied by a complex programmable logic device (CPLD), a field programmable gate array (FPGA), a group of integrated circuits (IC), etc., or may be embodied by a mixture thereof. Depending on a designing type, an integrated configuration of the control unit <b>370</b> and the memory unit <b>350</b> can be possible.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">Hereinafter, a using exemplary embodiment of the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> according to the present exemplary embodiment will be described. Here, that the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> directly receives an alternating current electric power from the external power supply <b>3</b> through the electric power cable <b>20</b> is assumed as an initial state.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">If an abnormal electric power pattern which is the cause of a failure of the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> is reported from a user, a laboratory, etc. after manufacturing and releasing of the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>, a manufacture confirms through an experiment whether the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> of the same model as the image forming apparatus currently released is capable of being protected to correspond to the reported abnormal electric power pattern.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">If the configuration of the present image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> is confirmed to fail to correspond to the abnormal electric power pattern, the manufacturer sends to a user the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> having the memory unit <b>350</b> in which a profile of the corresponding abnormal electric power pattern is reported.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">The user disposes the sent electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> to a supplying terminal of an alternating current electric power with respect to the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">An alternating current electric power output from the external power supply <b>3</b> is transmitted to the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> through the electric power input unit <b>100</b>, the electric power detecting unit <b>320</b>, the switching unit <b>310</b> and the electric power output unit <b>200</b>. The electric power detecting unit <b>320</b> transmits an electric power information of the alternating current electric power to the control unit <b>370</b>, and the control unit <b>370</b> compares the transmitted electric power information with an electric power pattern profile of the memory unit <b>350</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">If the control unit <b>370</b> determines that there is no abnormality in the comparison result, the control unit <b>370</b> maintains the switching unit <b>310</b> to allow an electric power output. If the control unit <b>370</b> determines that the alternating current electric power shows an abnormal electric power pattern in the comparison result, the control unit <b>370</b> controls the switching unit <b>310</b> to block an electric power output to prevent an abnormal electric power from being supplied to the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>. Accordingly, the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> can be protected from an abnormal electric power. Also, the control unit <b>370</b> displays the electric power blocking result in the display unit <b>330</b> so that a user can respond thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">Under the state that the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> is disposed to the image forming apparatus <b>1</b>, a new abnormal electric power pattern may be reported again. Then, a user connects the interface unit <b>360</b> to a server (not shown) operated by a manufacturer by a network so that a profile of a new abnormal electric power pattern can be updated in the memory unit <b>350</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">Also, the user downloads an updating application or an electric power profile for updating through a computer (not shown) connected to the server by a network. Then, the user may connect the computer to the interface unit <b>360</b> by a local, and then may perform an updating of the memory unit <b>350</b> through the computer.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">Like this, according to the present exemplary embodiment, whether an alternating current electric power is an abnormal electric power or not is determined based on an electric power pattern profile predetermined in the memory unit <b>350</b>, and an output of the alternating current electric power is blocked depending on the determining result, thereby protecting the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>. Also, without collecting the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> from a user, the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> can be protected to correspond to an abnormal electric power pattern which is considered after releasing of the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">Hereinafter, a position of disposing the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> will be described by referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a block diagram illustrating a disposing type of the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> when the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> is applied to the image forming apparatus <b>1</b>, and an arrow in the drawing refers to a transmission of an alternating current electric power.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">(1) of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates the state that the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> is not applied, and the electric power cable <b>20</b> is connected between the external power supply <b>3</b> and the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> to transmit an alternating current electric power of the external power supply <b>3</b> to the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>. In this case, it is difficult to correspond to an abnormal electric power failing to be considered in manufacturing of the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> to protect the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>. Accordingly, the present exemplary embodiment may employ the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> as follows.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">(2) of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates the state that the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> is connected between the electric power cable <b>20</b> and the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>. In this case, the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> may have an outlet of the same standard as the cable connecting unit <b>19</b> of the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">(3) of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates the state that the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> is connected between the external power supply <b>3</b> and the electric power cable <b>20</b>. In this case, the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> may include a plug for directly connecting to the external power supply <b>3</b>, and an outlet to which the electric power cable <b>20</b> is connected.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">(4) of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates the state that the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> is directly connected between the external power supply <b>3</b> and the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> without the electric power cable <b>20</b>. That is, the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> is connected to the external power supply <b>3</b> and the cable connecting unit <b>19</b> instead of the electric power cable <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">Like this, the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> may be disposed to any position as long as to block an alternating current electric power supplied to the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> from the external power supply <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">In the above exemplary embodiment, the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> is exemplarily illustrated to be disposed to correspond to the single image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>, but the present embodiments are not defined thereto. For example, the configuration of an electric power relaying unit <b>31</b> corresponding to at least two image forming apparatus main bodies <b>11</b> and <b>12</b> is possible, and this configuration will be described as a second exemplary embodiment by referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> exemplarily illustrates an image forming apparatus <b>1</b> according to an exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, according to the exemplary embodiment, the two image forming apparatus main bodies <b>11</b> and <b>12</b> are provided unlike the first exemplary embodiment. The electric power relaying unit <b>31</b> is connected to the external power supply <b>3</b> to receive an alternating current electric power, and a first electric power cable <b>21</b> and a second electric power cable <b>22</b> respectively connected to the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b> are connected to the electric power relaying unit <b>31</b>. That is, in the exemplary embodiment, an alternating current electric power output from the external power supply <b>3</b> diverges to be respectively supplied to the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">Hereinafter, the electric power relaying unit <b>31</b> according to the present exemplary embodiment will be described by referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a block diagram illustrating the electric power relaying unit <b>31</b> according to the present exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, to protect the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b> to correspond to the same abnormal electric power pattern, the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> may be separately disposed to each of the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b>. However, in this case, it is convenient to protect all of the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b> by the single electric power relaying unit <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">For this, the electric power relaying unit <b>31</b> includes an electric power input unit <b>100</b>, an electric power output unit <b>201</b> and an electric power blocking unit <b>301</b>. Also, the electric power blocking unit <b>301</b> includes a switching unit <b>311</b>, an electric power detecting unit <b>330</b>, a display unit <b>330</b>, a user input unit <b>340</b>, a memory unit <b>350</b>, an interface unit <b>360</b> and a control unit <b>370</b>. In the present exemplary embodiment, the configuration performing the same function as the first exemplary embodiment may apply the same configuration as the first exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">The power output unit <b>201</b> includes a first main body connecting unit <b>210</b> to which the first electric power cable <b>21</b> is connected, and a second main body connecting unit <b>220</b> to which the second electric power cable <b>22</b> is connected. Accordingly, the electric power output unit <b>201</b> can respectively output an alternating current electric power with respect to the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">The switching unit <b>311</b> respectively outputs an alternating current electric power output from the electric power input unit <b>100</b> to the first main body connecting unit <b>210</b> and the second main body connecting unit <b>220</b>. If the switching unit <b>311</b> is controlled by the control unit <b>370</b> to block an electric power output, all alternating current electric power output to the first main body connecting unit <b>210</b> and the second main body connecting unit <b>220</b> can be blocked.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">With this configuration, a user connects the electric power relaying unit <b>31</b> to the external power supply <b>3</b>, and respectively connects the electric power relaying unit <b>31</b> to the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b>. In the memory unit <b>350</b> of the electric power relaying unit <b>31</b>, a profile of an abnormal electric power pattern corresponding to all of the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b> is stored.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">The exemplary embodiment may be applied to the configuration of the control unit <b>370</b> determining whether an alternating current electric power is an abnormal electric power or not.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">If an alternating current electric power pattern corresponds to an abnormal electric power pattern, this alternating current electric power may be the cause of a failure of the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b>. Accordingly, the control unit <b>370</b> controls the switching unit <b>311</b> to block an output of the alternating current electric power with respect to the first main body connecting unit <b>210</b> and the second main body connecting unit <b>220</b>. Accordingly, all of the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b> can be protected from the abnormal electric power.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">In the exemplary embodiment, the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b> are illustrated to be protected together to correspond to the same abnormal electric power pattern. However, abnormal electric power patterns respectively corresponding to the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b> may be different from each other.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">The configuration with respect to this case is an exemplary embodiment, which will be described by referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an electric power relaying unit <b>32</b> according to the exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the electric power relaying unit <b>32</b> according to the exemplary embodiment includes an electric power input unit <b>101</b> receiving an alternating current electric power from an external power supply <b>3</b>, an electric power output unit <b>201</b> respectively outputting an alternating current electric power diverging and output from the electric power input unit <b>101</b> to a first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and a second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b>, and a first electric power blocking unit <b>303</b> and a second electric power blocking unit <b>304</b> disposed to block each alternating current electric power diverging and output from the electric power input unit <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">The electric power input unit <b>101</b> diverges and outputs an alternating current electric power from the external power supply <b>3</b> in a plurality of lines, in the present exemplary embodiment, in two lines. Each alternating current electric power diverging and output is output to a first main body connecting unit <b>210</b> and a second main body connecting unit <b>220</b> of the electric power output unit <b>201</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">The first main body connecting unit <b>210</b> and the second main body connecting unit <b>220</b> are respectively connected to the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b> to respectively supply an alternating current electric power output from the electric power input unit <b>101</b> to the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">The first electric power blocking unit <b>303</b> and the second electric power blocking unit <b>304</b> respectively block an alternating current electric power output to the first main body connecting unit <b>210</b> from the electric power input unit <b>101</b>, and an alternating current electric power output to the second main body connecting unit <b>220</b> from the electric power input unit <b>101</b>. The detailed configurations of the first electric power blocking unit <b>303</b> and the second electric power blocking unit <b>304</b> may apply the electric power blocking unit <b>300</b> according to the first exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">The first electric power blocking unit <b>303</b> stores a profile related to an abnormal electric power pattern corresponding to an operating environment of the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b>. On the other hand, the second electric power blocking unit <b>304</b> stores a profile related to an abnormal electric power pattern corresponding to an operating environment of the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b>. Since the operating environments of the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b> are different, each profile has a different pattern property.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">That is, an electric power pattern which an alternating current electric power shows corresponds to one of the case that it is no abnormal electric power in all of the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b>, the case that it is an abnormal electric power in all of the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b>, and the case that that it is an abnormal electric power in only one of the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">The present exemplary embodiment is capable of corresponding to all three cases, and especially, to the third case by respectively regulating an alternating current electric power diverging and output from the electric power input unit <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">Hereinafter, a method by which the electric power relaying unit <b>32</b> according to the present exemplary embodiment separately protects the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b> against an abnormal electric power will be described.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111">A method of a user disposing the electric power relaying unit <b>32</b> may apply the exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">An alternating current electric power having a predetermined electric power pattern is output from the electric power input unit <b>101</b> to be respectively input to the first electric power blocking unit <b>303</b> and the second electric power blocking unit <b>304</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">The first electric power blocking unit <b>303</b> determines whether the alternating current electric power is an abnormal electric power or not based on a predetermined electric power pattern profile, and blocks an output of the alternating current electric power with respect to the first main body connecting unit <b>210</b> if determining to be an abnormal electric power.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">Also, the second electric power blocking unit <b>304</b> determines whether the alternating current electric power is an abnormal electric power or not based on an electric power pattern profile predetermined to be different from the first electric power blocking unit <b>303</b>. Here, the electric power pattern profiles which the first electric power blocking unit <b>303</b> and the second electric power blocking unit <b>304</b> refer to are different. Accordingly, the second electric power blocking unit <b>304</b> may determine the alternating current electric power determined to be an abnormal electric power by the first electric power blocking unit <b>303</b> not to be an abnormal electric power.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">In this case, the second electric power blocking unit <b>304</b> allows an output of the alternating current electric power with respect to the second main body connecting unit <b>220</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116">Like this, if an electric power pattern of an alternating current electric power operates as an abnormal electric power with respect to only a part of a plurality of image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and <b>12</b>, an alternating current electric power supplying with respect to the image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> determining to be an abnormal electric power may be blocked, and an alternating current electric power supplying may be allowed with respect to the remaining image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0117">The electric power blocking unit <b>305</b> may be embodied by a different configuration from the exemplary embodiments described above, and this is an exemplary embodiment, which will be described by referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an electric power relaying unit <b>33</b> according to the exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0118">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the electric power relaying unit <b>33</b> according to the present exemplary embodiment includes an electric power input unit <b>100</b> to which an alternating current electric power is input from an external power supply <b>3</b>, an electric power output unit <b>200</b> outputting an alternating current electric power from the electric power input unit <b>100</b> to an image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>, and an electric power blocking unit <b>305</b> selectively blocking an output of an alternating current electric power with respect to the electric power output unit <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0119">The electric power blocking unit <b>305</b> includes an electric power blocking element <b>380</b> disposed on an electric power path between the electric power input unit <b>100</b> and the electric power output unit <b>200</b> and blocking an electric power flow of the electric power path to correspond to an electric power property in a predetermined failure of the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>, and a control unit <b>361</b> displaying in a display unit <b>330</b> that an electric power is blocked by the electric power blocking element <b>380</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0120">If an alternating current electric power of an abnormal electric power pattern predetermined to correspond to the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> flows, the electric power blocking element <b>380</b> is short-circuited on its own to block the corresponding alternating current electric power to be transmitted to the electric power output unit <b>200</b>. The electric power blocking element <b>380</b> employs a short-circuit property selected by a manufacturer to correspond to an operating environment of the image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0121">The configuration of the electric power blocking element <b>380</b> is not defined, and may be embodied by a fuse, a bimetal, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0122">With this configuration, if an alternating current electric power flowing in the electric power blocking element <b>380</b> is an abnormal electric power to correspond to a short-circuit property of the electric power blocking element <b>380</b>, the electric power blocking element <b>380</b> is short-circuited to block the flow of the alternating current electric power. Accordingly, an abnormal electric power can be prevented from being supplied to the device main body <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0123">In the above exemplary embodiment, the single image forming apparatus main body <b>10</b> is illustrated to be connected to the electric power output unit <b>200</b>, but a plurality of image forming apparatus main bodies <b>11</b> and <b>12</b> may be connected thereto. This case is an exemplary embodiment, which will be described by referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0124"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an electric power relaying unit <b>35</b> according to the exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0125">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, in the electric power relaying unit <b>35</b> according to the exemplary embodiment, a first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and a second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b> are respectively connected to an electric power output unit <b>201</b> so that an alternating current electric power can be respectively received. This configuration of the electric power output unit <b>201</b> may apply the case of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> according to the exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0126">An electric power blocking element <b>380</b> has a short-circuit property corresponding to all of a first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and a second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b>. If an abnormal electric power flows, the electric power blocking element <b>380</b> is short-circuited to block an electric power output with respect to the electric power output unit <b>201</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0127">Accordingly, the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b> can be prevented from being supplied with an abnormal electric power.</p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0128">Also, to be different from the fifth exemplary embodiment, a configuration separately performing an alternating current electric power blocking with respect to the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b> is possible. This configuration is an exemplary embodiment, which will be described by referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0129"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an electric power relaying unit <b>36</b> according to the exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0130">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, the electric power relaying unit <b>36</b> includes an electric power input unit <b>101</b> to which an alternating current electric power is input from an external power supply <b>3</b>, an electric power output unit <b>201</b> respectively outputting an alternating current electric power diverging and output from the electric power input unit <b>101</b> to a first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and a second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b>, and a first electric power blocking element <b>381</b> and a second electric power blocking element <b>382</b> disposed to separately block an alternating current electric power diverging and output from the electric power input unit <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0132" num="0131">The first electric power blocking element <b>381</b> and the second electric power blocking element <b>382</b> have short-circuit properties separately corresponding to abnormal electric power patterns of the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b> and the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0133" num="0132">For example, an alternating current electric power output from the electric power input unit <b>101</b> may not be an abnormal electric power with respect to the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b>, but may be an abnormal electric power with respect to the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b>. In this case, the first electric power blocking element <b>381</b> is not short-circuited and allows a flow of an alternating current electric power, but the second electric power blocking element <b>382</b> is short-circuited to block a flow of an alternating current electric power. Accordingly, the alternating current electric power is supplied to the first image forming apparatus main body <b>11</b>, and the alternating current electric power is not supplied to the second image forming apparatus main body <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0134" num="0133">Like this, the single electric power relaying unit <b>35</b> and <b>36</b> can be applied and correspond to a plurality of image forming apparatus main bodies <b>11</b> and <b>12</b> having different abnormal electric power patterns.</p>
<p id="p-0135" num="0134">In the present exemplary embodiment, the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> is illustrated to be applied to the image forming apparatus <b>1</b>, but the electric power relaying unit <b>30</b> may be applied to various apparatuses receiving an electric power from an outside to perform various functions, for example, a scanner, a multifunction device, an electronic copier, a television, a computer main body, home appliances such as a refrigerator, a washing machine, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0136" num="0135">According to the embodiments, by applying an electric power relaying unit blocking an electric power output to an image forming apparatus to correspond to an abnormal electric power pattern failing to be anticipated in a manufacturing process of the image forming apparatus, the image forming apparatus can be safely protected from a failure electric power.</p>
<p id="p-0137" num="0136">Also, since it is sufficient to just add an electric power relaying unit without repairing an image forming apparatus, it is unnecessary for a manufacturer to collect the image forming apparatus, and a user is capable of easily responding thereto if a problem happens. Accordingly, enormous human and material costs caused in the conventional recall can be drastically reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0138" num="0137">Also, since an electric power pattern profile corresponding to an operating environment of an image forming apparatus is stored in a memory unit, an abnormal electric power pattern corresponding to the image forming apparatus can be easily discerned.</p>
<p id="p-0139" num="0138">Also, by applying an interface unit accessible to a memory unit from an outside, an electric power pattern profile stored in the memory unit can be updated. Accordingly, the present invention can correspond to a new abnormal electric power pattern which may happen later, and can flexibly correspond to and be applied to an image forming apparatus embodied by various types.</p>
<p id="p-0140" num="0139">Also, by applying a display unit displaying an electric power blocking when an electric power is blocked by a switching unit, the electric power blocking can be informed to a user so that the user can deal therewith appropriately.</p>
<p id="p-0141" num="0140">Although a few exemplary embodiments have been shown and described, it will be appreciated by those skilled in the art that changes may be made in these exemplary embodiments without departing from the principles and spirit of the invention, the scope of which is defined in the appended claims and their equivalents.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An electric power relaying unit of an electronic device comprising:
<claim-text>an input unit which is connected to an external power supply so as to receive electric power from the external power supply;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an output unit which is connected to the electronic device so as to output the electric power to the electronic device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a switch which selectively prevents flow of the electric power to the output unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a detector which detects an electric power property of the electric power;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a memory which stores a profile of a predetermined electric power pattern;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a controller which controls the switch to prevent the flow of the electric power to the output unit when the detector detects a profile which is different from the profile to be stored in the memory; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a notice unit which notifies that the flow of the electric power to the output unit is prevented.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The electric power relaying unit of the electronic device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein, if the profile of the electric power detected by the detector does not correspond to the profile stored in the memory, the controller determines that the electric power corresponds to an electric power property in a failure of the electronic device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The electric power relaying unit of the electronic device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising an interface configured to communicate with an outside.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The electric power relaying unit of the electronic device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the interface comprises at least one of a memory port to which an external memory is mounted, a first communication port for a local communication, and a second communication port for a network communication.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The electric power relaying unit of the electronic device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, the notice unit comprises a display which displays that the electric power to the output unit is blocked by the switch.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The electric power relaying unit of the electronic device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the output unit is provided to allow a plurality of the electronic devices to be connected thereto so that the plurality of the electronic devices can respectively receive the electric power.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The electric power relaying unit of the electronic device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the electric power output from the switch diverges to respectively correspond to the plurality of the electronic devices.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The electric power relaying unit of the electronic device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein a plurality of the switches are disposed correspondingly to each electric power diverging to respectively corresponding to the plurality of the electronic devices from the input unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The electric power relaying unit of the electronic device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a user input unit,
<claim-text>wherein the switch switches the electric power to correspond to an input command of the user input unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The electric power relaying unit of the electronic device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a user input unit,
<claim-text>wherein if a time is input by the user input unit, the controller controls a switching operation of the switch to correspond to an elapse of the time input by the user input unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A system, comprising:
<claim-text>an electronic device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an electric power relaying unit which transmits electric power from an external power supply to the electronic device,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the electric power relaying unit comprising
<claim-text>an input unit which is connected to the external power supply so as to receive the electric power from the external power supply;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an output unit which is connected to the electronic device so as to output the electric power to the electronic device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a switch which selectively prevents flow of the electric power to the output unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a detector which detects an electric power property of the electric power;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a memory which stores a profile of a predetermined electric power pattern;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a controller which controls the switch to prevent the flow of the electric power to the output unit when the detector detects a profile which is different from the profile to be stored in the memory; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a notice unit which notifies that the flow of the electric power to the output unit is prevented. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
