<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622576-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622576</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13190168</doc-number>
<date>20110725</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>310</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>21</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>21</main-group>
<subgroup>008</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>21</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36224902</main-classification>
<further-classification>36224906</further-classification>
<further-classification>362363</further-classification>
<further-classification>362391</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Icicle-shaped bulb and string light having multiple of the same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6224239</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Adler</name>
<date>20010500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36224916</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6394624</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Hsu</name>
<date>20020500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36224901</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6971768</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Pepito et al.</name>
<date>20051200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362238</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0164831</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lai</name>
<date>20060700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362231</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0175033</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Chien</name>
<date>20090700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362183</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>6</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36224902</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36224906</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362249</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362 14</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36224914</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362391</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362235</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362363</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362806</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362223</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36221702</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130027940</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130131</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Zhang</last-name>
<first-name>Cheng-Chun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Zhang</last-name>
<first-name>Cheng-Chun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chow</last-name>
<first-name>Ming</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Sinorica, LLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Gemmy Industries Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Coppell</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Sember</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas</first-name>
<department>2885</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A string light has multiple icicle-shaped bulbs, a controller and a connector assembly. The icicle-shaped bulbs are serially connected by a set of wires. Each icicle-shaped bulb has an icicle-shaped lamp holder shell, an elongated lamp strip and a cap assembly. The lamp holder shell has an irregular and rough surface and an opening. The lamp strip is mounted inside the lamp holder shell. The cap assembly is mounted on the opening of the lamp holder shell and has a set of through holes for the set of wires to penetrate into the lamp holder shell. Accordingly, light emitted from each icicle-shaped bulb is scattered irregularly to generate different illuminating effects when the icicle-shaped bulb is powered on and make the lighting variations of the entire string light more versatile and interesting.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="262.04mm" wi="420.03mm" file="US08622576-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="266.70mm" wi="144.61mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622576-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="262.81mm" wi="114.05mm" file="US08622576-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="264.50mm" wi="163.24mm" file="US08622576-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="270.09mm" wi="180.85mm" file="US08622576-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="266.78mm" wi="135.13mm" file="US08622576-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to an ornamental string light, and more particularly to a string light having multiple icicle-shaped bulbs.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Ornamental string lights are widely used for occasions such as balls, parties, exhibitions, festivals and holidays to serve for the purpose of decoration and create resplendent and glamorous atmosphere. To attract participants' attention and raise people's interest in participating in such occasions, the ornamental string lights are preferred to have rich color and brightness variations, which have become a crucial criterion for which the ornamental light industry is eager to pursue.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Each ornamental string light has multiple bulbs serially connected by a set of wires and the set of wires is electrically connected to a controller so that the controller can control the bulbs to blink or switch on or off so as to generate lighting variations of the bulbs. For sake of mass production and standardization, the bulbs, the shapes of the string lights look similarly and the richness in terms of color and brightness variations of the bulbs and the string lights is mitigated. As a consequence, the resulting light and brightness variations of the bulbs and the string light are insipid and dull and fail to capture people's attention.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">An objective of the present invention is to provide a string light having multiple icicle-shaped bulbs for enhancing light-scattering effect.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">To achieve the foregoing objective, the string light having multiple icicle-shaped bulbs has multiple icicle-shaped bulbs, a controller and a connector assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The icicle-shaped bulbs are serially connected by a set of wires. Each icicle-shaped bulb has an icicle-shaped lamp holder shell, an elongated lamp strip and a cap assembly. The icicle-shaped lamp holder shell has an irregular and rough surface and an opening formed through a top of the lamp holder shell. The elongated lamp strip is mounted inside the lamp holder shell for the set of wires to be electrically connected thereto and has multiple light-emitting diode lamps mounted thereon. The cap assembly is mounted on the opening of the lamp holder shell and has a set of through holes for the set of wires to penetrate into the lamp holder shell through the set of through holes.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The controller is electrically connected to the icicle-shaped bulbs through the set of wires.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The connector assembly is electrically connected to the controller.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The irregular and rough surface on the icicle-shaped lamp holder shell of the icicle-shaped bulb gives rise to an irregularly-scattering effect on light emitted from each LED lamp on the lamp strip when the icicle-shaped bulb is powered on. Furthermore, the controller can control the icicle-shaped bulbs to blink or switch on or off to make the lighting variations of the entire string light more versatile and interesting.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Other objectives, advantages and novel features of the invention will become more apparent from the following detailed description when taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a string light having multiple icicle-shaped bulbs in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view of an icicle-shaped bulb in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an exploded perspective view of the icicle-shaped bulb in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is another exploded perspective view of the icicle-shaped bulb in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a front view in partial division of the icicle-shaped bulb in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a string light having multiple icicle-shaped bulbs in accordance with the present invention has multiple icicle-shaped bulbs <b>1</b>, a controller <b>4</b> and a connector assembly <b>5</b>. The icicle-shaped bulbs <b>1</b> are serially connected by a set of wires <b>6</b>. The controller <b>4</b> is electrically connected to the icicle-shaped bulbs <b>1</b> through the set of wires <b>6</b>. The connector assembly <b>5</b> is electrically connected to the controller <b>4</b>. In the present embodiment, the connector assembly <b>5</b> has a plug <b>51</b> and a socket <b>52</b>. The plug <b>51</b> serves to be inserted in an AC power socket or the socket <b>52</b> of another string light so that multiple string lights can be serially connected.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 to 5</figref>, each icicle-shaped bulb <b>1</b> has an icicle-shaped lamp holder shell <b>11</b>, an elongated lamp strip <b>20</b> and a cap assembly <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The icicle-shaped lamp holder shell <b>11</b> has an irregular and rough surface and an opening <b>12</b> formed through a top of the lamp holder shell <b>11</b>. In the present embodiment, the lamp holder shell <b>11</b> further has a ring <b>14</b> and a cavity <b>13</b>. The ring <b>14</b> is mounted on a rim of the opening <b>12</b>. The cavity <b>13</b> has a reduced chamber <b>15</b> and an expanded chamber <b>16</b>. The reduced chamber <b>15</b> and the expanded chamber <b>16</b> are cylindrical. The reduced chamber <b>15</b> is smaller than the expanded chamber <b>16</b> in diameter, and adjoins and communicates with the expanded chamber <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The elongated lamp strip <b>20</b> is mounted inside the lamp holder shell <b>11</b> for the set of wires <b>6</b> to be electrically connected thereto and has multiple LED lamps <b>21</b> mounted thereon. In the present embodiment, the elongated lamp strip <b>20</b> has a wide portion <b>22</b> and a slender portion <b>23</b>. The wide portion <b>22</b> and the slender portion <b>23</b> are rectangular. The wide portion <b>22</b> has a width being larger than the diameter of the reduced chamber <b>15</b> of the cavity <b>13</b> and is mounted inside the expanded chamber <b>16</b> of the cavity <b>13</b>. The slender portion <b>23</b> has a width being smaller than the diameter of the reduced chamber <b>15</b> of the cavity <b>13</b>, is formed on and protrudes downwardly from a bottom of the wide portion <b>22</b>, is mounted inside the reduced chamber <b>15</b> of the cavity <b>13</b>, and has the LED lamps <b>21</b> mounted thereon.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The cap assembly <b>30</b> is mounted on the opening <b>12</b> of the lamp holder shell <b>11</b> and has a set of through holes <b>301</b> formed through a top of the cap assembly <b>30</b> for the set of wires <b>6</b> to penetrate into the lamp holder shell <b>11</b> through the set of through holes <b>301</b>. In the present embodiment, the cap assembly <b>30</b> has a lamp strip seat <b>31</b>, a soft plug <b>32</b> and a cap <b>33</b>. The lamp strip seat <b>31</b> has a base <b>311</b>, two strip holders <b>312</b> and two positioning pins <b>313</b>. The base <b>311</b> has a set of through holes <b>314</b> formed through the base <b>311</b> for the set of wires <b>6</b> to penetrate through. The strip holders <b>312</b> are inverted U-shaped, are formed on and protrude downwardly from a bottom of the base <b>311</b> with the open ends of the strip holders <b>312</b> facing down so as to hold the wide portion <b>22</b> of the lamp strip <b>20</b>. The positioning pins <b>313</b> are formed on and protrude upwardly from a top of the base <b>311</b>. The soft plug <b>32</b> is cylindrical and made from a waterproof material, has a diameter corresponding to a diameter of the opening <b>12</b> of the lamp holder shell <b>11</b>, is plugged in the opening <b>12</b> of the lamp holder shell <b>11</b>, and has a set of through holes <b>321</b> and two pits <b>322</b>. The set of through holes <b>321</b> serves for the set of wires <b>6</b> to penetrate through. Each pit <b>322</b> is formed in a bottom of the soft plug <b>32</b> and has a depth commensurate with a length of a corresponding positioning pin <b>313</b> for the positioning pin <b>313</b> to be inserted therein so that the soft plug <b>32</b> can be positioned on the top of the base <b>311</b>. The cap <b>33</b> is disc-shaped, and has two halves <b>331</b> joined together. Each half has an annular slot <b>332</b> annularly and outwardly formed in a bottom of the half for the ring <b>14</b> of the lamp holder shell <b>11</b> to be slidably mounted in the annular slot <b>332</b>. A bolt <b>34</b> is mounted through the two halves <b>331</b> to fasten the two halves <b>331</b> together.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">When the icicle-shaped bulb <b>1</b> is assembled, the set of wires <b>6</b> sequentially penetrates through the set of through holes <b>321</b> of the soft plug <b>32</b> and the set of through holes <b>314</b> of the lamp strip seat <b>31</b> and then is electrically connected to the elongated lamp strip <b>20</b>. The lamp strip <b>20</b> is mounted in the cavity <b>13</b> of the icicle-shaped lamp holder shell <b>11</b> through the opening <b>12</b> of the lamp holder shell <b>11</b>. The slender portion <b>23</b> of the lamp strip <b>20</b> is mounted in the reduced chamber <b>15</b> of the cavity <b>13</b>. The lamp strip seat <b>31</b> is mounted on a top edge of the lamp strip <b>20</b> to hold the wide portion <b>22</b> of the lamp strip <b>20</b>. The soft plug <b>32</b> is plugged in the opening <b>12</b> of the icicle-shaped lamp holder shell <b>11</b> to seal the lamp strip <b>20</b> inside the icicle-shaped lamp holder shell <b>11</b> and prevent the lamp strip <b>20</b> from being damaged by water or moisture permeating into the icicle-shaped lamp holder shell <b>11</b>. The annular slots <b>332</b> of the two halves <b>331</b> of the cap <b>33</b> align with the ring <b>14</b> of the icicle-shaped lamp holder shell <b>11</b> so that the ring <b>14</b> can be slidably mounted inside the annular slots <b>332</b> of the two halves <b>331</b> of the cap <b>33</b>. The bolt <b>34</b> is mounted through the two halves <b>331</b> of the cap <b>33</b> to fasten the two halves <b>331</b> in completion of the assembly of the icicle-shaped bulb <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Due to the irregular and rough surface on the icicle-shaped lamp holder shell <b>11</b> of the icicle-shaped bulb <b>1</b>, light emitted from each LED lamp <b>21</b> on the lamp strip <b>20</b> is scattered irregularly to generate different illuminating effects when the icicle-shaped bulb is powered on. Additionally, the controller <b>4</b> can control the icicle-shaped bulbs <b>1</b> to blink or switch on or off to make the lighting variations of the entire string light more versatile and interesting.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Even though numerous characteristics and advantages of the present invention have been set forth in the foregoing description, together with details of the structure and function of the invention, the disclosure is illustrative only. Changes may be made in detail, especially in matters of shape, size, and arrangement of parts within the principles of the invention to the full extent indicated by the broad general meaning of the terms in which the appended claims are expressed.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A string light having multiple icicle-shaped bulbs comprising:
<claim-text>multiple icicle-shaped bulbs serially connected by a set of wires, each icicle-shaped bulb having:
<claim-text>an icicle-shaped lamp holder shell having:
<claim-text>an irregular and rough surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an opening formed through a top of the lamp holder shell; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cavity having:
<claim-text>a reduced chamber being cylindrical; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an expanded chamber being cylindrical, adjoining and communicating with the reduced chamber, wherein a diameter of the expander chamber is larger than a diameter of the reduced chamber;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>an elongated lamp strip mounted inside the lamp holder shell for the set of wires to be electrically connected thereto and having:
<claim-text>multiple light-emitting diode (LED) lamps mounted thereon;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a wide portion having a width being larger than the diameter of the reduced chamber of the cavity and mounted inside the expanded chamber of the cavity; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a slender portion having a width being smaller than the diameter of the reduced chamber of the cavity, formed on and protruding downwardly from a bottom of the wide portion, mounted inside the reduced chamber of the cavity, and having the LED lamps mounted thereon; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cap assembly mounted on the opening of the lamp holder shell and having a set of through holes for the set of wires to penetrate into the lamp holder shell through the set of through holes;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a controller electrically connected to the icicle-shaped bulbs through the set of wires; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a connector assembly electrically connected to the controller.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The string light as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the lamp holder shell further has a ring mounted on a rim of the opening; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the cap assembly further has:
<claim-text>a lamp strip seat having:
<claim-text>a base having a set of through holes formed through the base for the set of wires to penetrate through;</claim-text>
<claim-text>two strip holders being inverted U-shaped, formed on and protruding downwardly from a bottom of the base with open ends of the strip holders facing down so as to hold the wide portion of the lamp strip; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>two positioning pins formed on and protruding upwardly from a top of the base;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a soft plug being cylindrical and made from a waterproof material, having a diameter corresponding to a diameter of the opening of the lamp holder shell, plugged in the opening of the lamp holder shell, and having:
<claim-text>a set of through holes serving for the set of wires to penetrate through; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>two pits, each pit formed in a bottom of the soft plug and having a depth commensurate with a length of a corresponding positioning pin for the positioning pin to be inserted therein so that the soft plug is positioned on the top of the base; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cap being disc-shaped and having two halves joined and fastened together by a bolt, each half having an annular slot annularly and outwardly formed in a bottom of the half for the ring of the lamp holder shell to be slidably mounted in the annular slot.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The string light as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the connector assembly has a plug and a socket.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The string light as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the connector assembly has a plug and a socket.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. An icicle-shaped bulb comprising:
<claim-text>an icicle-shaped lamp holder shell having:
<claim-text>an irregular and rough surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an opening formed through a top of the lamp holder shell; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cavity having:
<claim-text>a reduced chamber being cylindrical; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an expanded chamber being cylindrical, adjoining and communicating with the reduced chamber, wherein a diameter of the expanded chamber is larger than a diameter of the reduced chamber; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>an elongated lamp strip mounted inside the lamp holder shell for a set of wires to be electrically connected thereto and having:
<claim-text>multiple light-emitting diode (LED) lamps mounted thereon;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a wide portion having a width being larger than the diameter of the reduced chamber of the cavity and mounted inside the expanded chamber of the cavity; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a slender portion having a width being smaller than the diameter of the reduced chamber of the cavity, formed on and protruding downwardly from a bottom of the wide portion, mounted inside the reduced chamber of the cavity, and having the LED lamps mounted thereon; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cap assembly mounted on the opening of the lamp holder shell and having a set of through holes for the set of wires to penetrate into the lamp holder shell through the set of through holes.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The icicle-shaped bulb as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the lamp holder shell further has a ring mounted on a rim of the opening; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the cap assembly further has:
<claim-text>a lamp strip seat having:
<claim-text>a base having a set of through holes formed through the base for the set of wires to penetrate through;</claim-text>
<claim-text>two strip holders being inverted U-shaped, formed on and protruding downwardly from a bottom of the base with open ends of the strip holders facing down so as to hold the wide portion of the lamp strip; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>two positioning pins formed on and protruding upwardly from a top of the base;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a soft plug being cylindrical, made from a waterproof material, having a diameter corresponding to a diameter of the opening of the lamp holder shell, plugged in the opening of the lamp holder shell, and having:
<claim-text>a set of through holes serving for the set of wires to penetrate through; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>two pits, each pit formed in a bottom of the soft plug and having a depth commensurate with a length of a corresponding positioning pin for the positioning pin to be inserted therein so that the soft plug is positioned on the top of the base; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cap being disc-shaped and having two halves joined and fastened together by a bolt, each half having an annular slot annularly and outwardly formed in a bottom of the half for the ring of the lamp holder shell to be slidably mounted in the annular slot. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
