<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625297-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625297</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13206532</doc-number>
<date>20110810</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2011 1 0203900</doc-number>
<date>20110720</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>159</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>361760</main-classification>
<further-classification>361778</further-classification>
<further-classification>361818</further-classification>
<further-classification>361779</further-classification>
<further-classification>257E25005</further-classification>
<further-classification>257E25013</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Package structure with electronic component and method for manufacturing same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5297006</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Mizukoshi</name>
<date>19940300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0285114</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Pedersen et al.</name>
<date>20071200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>324755</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0085138</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kim et al.</name>
<date>20090400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0250707</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Zhou et al.</name>
<date>20091000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257 81</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0117212</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Corisis et al.</name>
<date>20100500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257686</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0151747</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lu</name>
<date>20100600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439816</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>11</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>361760</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>361778</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>361779</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>361818</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>361719</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257686</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E25005</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E25013</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130021772</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130124</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Xiao</last-name>
<first-name>Jun-Yi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Zhongshan</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Xiao</last-name>
<first-name>Jun-Yi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Zhongshan</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Ambit Microsystems (Zhongshan) Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Zhongshan</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Thompson</last-name>
<first-name>Timothy</first-name>
<department>2847</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Aychillhum</last-name>
<first-name>Andargie M</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A package structure comprises a substrate, a plurality of electronic components configured and structured on the substrate, a plurality of metal resilient units electrically connected to the substrate, and an encapsulation body encapsulating the plurality of electronic components and the plurality of resilient units together with the substrate. Part of each of the plurality of metal resilient units away from the substrate is exposed out of an exterior surface of the encapsulation body.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="93.05mm" wi="172.97mm" file="US08625297-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="160.70mm" wi="166.20mm" file="US08625297-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="136.14mm" wi="157.23mm" file="US08625297-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="129.71mm" wi="154.86mm" file="US08625297-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="151.13mm" wi="166.88mm" file="US08625297-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="136.31mm" wi="164.51mm" file="US08625297-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure generally relates to package structures with embedded electronic components and methods for manufacturing the same, more particularly to a package structure with metal resilient units encapsulated in an encapsulation body.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Generally, a package structure with embedded electronic components (e.g. capacitors,) includes a substrate having a cavity. An electronic component is mounted in the cavity and encapsulated within the substrate. However, it is difficult to reduce cost of the package structure due to complicated fabricating process involved in fabrication of the opening in the substrate. Furthermore, size of the electronic component is required to be smaller than the opening of the substrate to be received in the cavity, therefore, the package structure cannot employ multifarious electronic components.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Therefore, a need exists in the industry to overcome the described problem.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Many aspects of the present embodiments can be better understood with reference to the following drawings. The components in the drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the present embodiments. Moreover, in the drawings, all the views are schematic, and like reference numerals designate corresponding parts throughout the several views.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view of a package structure with a plurality of electronic components and a plurality of metal resilient units encapsulated on a substrate of an exemplary embodiment of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is another view of the package structure of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, in which the package structure has a structure for protecting the electronic components from electromagnetic interference (EMI).</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic view of the package structure capable of cooling the electronic components of an exemplary embodiment of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic view of the package structure of an exemplary embodiment of the disclosure, in which the package structure is a stacked package.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a schematic view of fixing the electronic components and the metal resilient units on the substrate.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The disclosure is illustrated by way of example and not by way of limitation in the figures of the accompanying drawings in which like references indicate similar elements. It should be noted that references to &#x201c;an&#x201d; or &#x201c;one&#x201d; embodiment in this disclosure are not necessarily to the same embodiment, and such references mean at least one.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a package structure <b>100</b> comprises a substrate <b>10</b>, a plurality of electronic components <b>20</b> configured and structured on the substrate <b>10</b>, a plurality of metal resilient units <b>30</b> electrically connected to the substrate <b>10</b>, and an encapsulation body <b>50</b> encapsulating the plurality of electronic components <b>20</b> and the plurality of resilient units <b>30</b> together with the substrate <b>10</b>. Part of each of the plurality of metal resilient units <b>30</b> away from the substrate <b>10</b> is exposed out of an exterior surface <b>51</b> of the encapsulation body <b>50</b>. By this way, input/output interfaces of the substrate <b>10</b> are transmitted to the exterior surface <b>51</b> of the first encapsulation body <b>50</b> by way of the metal resilient units <b>30</b>. In the embodiment, the electronic component <b>20</b> can be a capacitor, a integrated circuit, for example, and the first encapsulation body <b>50</b> is an epoxy resin.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The substrate <b>10</b> comprises a first surface <b>11</b>, a second surface <b>12</b> opposite to the first surface <b>11</b>, a first conductive layer <b>13</b> located on the first surface <b>11</b>, a second conductive layer <b>14</b> on the second surface <b>12</b>, and a plurality of conductive holes <b>15</b> running through the first surface <b>11</b> and the second surface <b>12</b> to electrically connect the first conductive layer <b>13</b> with the second conductive layer <b>14</b>. In the embodiment, the input/output interfaces of the substrate <b>10</b> are configured on the second conductive layer <b>14</b> of the substrate <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The first electronic components <b>20</b> are electrically connected to the first conductive layer <b>13</b> of the substrate <b>10</b> and encapsulated on the first surface <b>11</b> of the substrate <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In the embodiment, each of the metal resilient units <b>30</b> comprises a metal resilient element <b>31</b>, a first metal sheet <b>32</b> and a second metal sheet <b>33</b>. The first metal sheet <b>32</b> and the second metal sheet <b>33</b> are located on two ends of the metal resilient element <b>31</b>, respectively. The first metal sheet <b>32</b> is fixed on the first surface <b>11</b> of the substrate <b>10</b> and electrically connected to the first conductive layer <b>13</b> of the substrate <b>10</b>. The second metal sheet <b>33</b> is exposed out of the exterior surface <b>51</b> of the first encapsulation body <b>50</b>. By this structure, the input/output interfaces of the substrate <b>10</b> on the second conductive layer <b>14</b> are transmitted to the first conductive layer <b>13</b> via the conductive holes <b>15</b>, and subsequently transmitted to the exterior surface <b>51</b> of the first encapsulation body <b>50</b> via the metal resilient units <b>30</b>. That is, the substrate <b>10</b> communicates with exterior circuits via the second metal sheets <b>33</b> of the metal resilient units <b>30</b> exposed out of the exterior surface <b>51</b> of the first encapsulation body <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">During a molding process, the metal resilient units <b>30</b> are protected from damaged by a compressive stress of a module, due to the resilient capability of the metal resilient elements <b>31</b>. In addition, the second metal sheets <b>33</b> of the metal resilient units <b>30</b> always keep contacted with an upper portion of the module during the molding process because of the resilient capability of the metal resilient elements <b>31</b>, which not only prevents the epoxy resin covering the second metal sheets <b>33</b> to ensure the second metal sheets <b>33</b> exposed on the exterior surface <b>51</b> of the first encapsulation body <b>50</b>, but also avoids height differences between the metal resilient units <b>30</b> to ensure a good planeness of the exterior surface <b>51</b> of the first encapsulation body <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In the embodiment, the resilient element <b>31</b> is a spring, the first metal sheets <b>32</b> and the second metal sheets <b>33</b> are made of copper, and surfaces of the first metal sheets <b>32</b> and the second metal sheets <b>33</b> are coated with tin. In other embodiments, the resilient element <b>31</b> can be a metal spring sheet, and surfaces of the first metal sheets <b>32</b> and the second metal sheets <b>33</b> can be coated with gold or silver according to practical requirements</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In the embodiment, edges of the first metal sheet <b>32</b> and the second metal sheet <b>33</b> of each of the metal resilient units <b>30</b> are substantially in shape of frustum of a cone, which leads to the epoxy resin securely integrated with the metal resilient units <b>30</b> to prevent the metal resilient units <b>30</b> from loosening.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, in the embodiment, the second metal sheets <b>33</b> of the metal resilient units <b>30</b> are connected together to collectively form a metal shield <b>90</b>. The metal shield <b>90</b> covers the first electronic components <b>20</b>, and is electrically connected to the conductive layers <b>13</b>, <b>14</b> of the substrate <b>10</b>, which protects the package structure <b>100</b> from electromagnetic interference (EMI).</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the first electronic components <b>20</b> is adhered to the metal shield <b>90</b> by thermal grease <b>80</b> configured as a thermal conduction layer to transmit heat from the first electronic components <b>20</b> to the metal shield <b>90</b>. As a result, the metal shield <b>90</b> is configured to be a heat sink to cool the first electronic components <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, in this embodiment, the package structure <b>100</b> can be a stacked package, because a plurality of second electronic component <b>40</b> can be packed on the second surface <b>12</b> of the substrate <b>10</b> by a second encapsulation body <b>60</b>, due to the input/output interfaces on the second surface <b>12</b> of the substrate <b>10</b> being transmitted to the exterior surface <b>51</b> of the first encapsulation body <b>50</b>, which leads to small size of the package structure <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In summary, the first electronic components <b>20</b> are encapsulated in the first encapsulation body <b>50</b>, and the input/output interfaces of the substrate <b>10</b> are transmitted to the exterior surface <b>51</b> of the encapsulation body <b>50</b> by the metal resilient units <b>30</b>. By this way, the package structure <b>100</b> can employ multifarious first electronic components <b>20</b> with different sizes, due to the resilient capability of the metal resilient units <b>30</b>, which leads to price reduction of the package structure <b>100</b> because of simplified fabricating process of the package structure <b>100</b>. In addition, the package structure <b>100</b> can be a stack package, because the second surface <b>12</b> of the substrate <b>10</b> can pack the second electronic components <b>40</b>, which leads to small size of the package structure <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The fabrication method used to package the first electronic components <b>20</b> with different sizes in the first encapsulation body <b>50</b> comprises steps as follow.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the first electronic components <b>20</b> and the metal resilient units <b>30</b> are mounted on the substrate <b>10</b>. In this embodiment, the first electronic components <b>20</b> and the metal resilient units <b>30</b> are mounted on the substrate <b>10</b> by surface mounting technology (SMT). Each of the metal resilient units <b>30</b> comprises a metal resilient element <b>31</b>, a first metal sheet <b>32</b> and a second metal sheet <b>33</b>. The first metal sheet <b>32</b> and the second metal sheet <b>33</b> are located on two ends of the metal resilient element <b>31</b>, respectively. The first metal sheet <b>31</b> is fixed on the first surface <b>11</b> of the substrate <b>10</b> and electrically connected to the first conductive layer <b>13</b> of the substrate <b>10</b> by tins <b>70</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The first electronic components <b>20</b> and the metal resilient units <b>30</b> are encapsulated on the substrate <b>10</b> to form an encapsulation body <b>50</b> with the second metal sheets <b>33</b> of the resilient units <b>30</b> exposed on the exterior surface <b>51</b> of the encapsulation body <b>50</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. In the embodiment, the encapsulation body <b>50</b> is an epoxy resin.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The remaining epoxy resin on the second metal sheets <b>33</b> of the resilient units <b>30</b> is etched to ensure the second metal sheets <b>33</b> the resilient units <b>30</b> completely exposed on the exterior surface <b>51</b> of the encapsulation body <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The second metal sheets <b>33</b> of the resilient units <b>30</b> are coated with tin by electroplate process. The step can be omitted according to practical requirement.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Although the features and elements of the present disclosure are described as embodiments in particular combinations, each feature or element can be used alone or in other various combinations within the principles of the present disclosure to the full extent indicated by the broad general meaning of the terms in which the appended claims are expressed.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A package structure comprising a substrate, a plurality of electronic components configured and structured on the substrate, a plurality of metal resilient units electrically connected to the substrate, and an encapsulation body encapsulating the plurality of electronic components and the plurality of resilient units together with the substrate;
<claim-text>wherein each of the plurality of metal resilient units comprises a metal resilient element, and a first metal sheet and a second metal sheet respectively located at two ends of the metal resilient element, the first metal sheet is electrically connected to the substrate, and the second metal sheet is exposed out of an exterior surface of the encapsulation body; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the resilient capability of the metal resilient element prevents epoxy resin from covering the second metal sheet to keep the second metal sheet in a stationary position of being exposed out of the exterior surface of the encapsulation body.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The package structure as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first metal sheet and the second metal sheet are both substantially in a shape of a frustum of a cone.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The package structure as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the metal resilient element is a spring.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The package structure as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second metal sheets of the plurality of resilient units are connected together to collectively form a metal shield to protect the electronic components from electromagnetic interference (EMI).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The package structure as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the electronic components are adhered to the metal shield by thermal grease.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The package structure as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a surface of the second metal sheet is coplanar with the exterior surface of the encapsulation body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A package structure comprising a substrate, a plurality of electronic components configured and structured on the substrate, a plurality of metal resilient units electrically connected to the substrate, and an encapsulation body encapsulating the plurality of electronic components and the plurality of metal resilient units together with the substrate;
<claim-text>wherein each of the plurality of metal resilient units comprises a metal resilient element, and a first metal sheet and a second metal sheet respectively located at two ends of the metal resilient element;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first metal sheet is electrically connected to the substrate, and the second metal sheet is exposed out of an exterior surface of the encapsulation body; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a surface of the second metal sheet is coplanar with the exterior surface of the encapsulation body.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The package structure as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the first metal sheet and the second metal sheet are both substantially in a shape of a frustum of a cone.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The package structure as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the metal resilient element is a spring.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The package structure as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the second metal sheets of the plurality of metal resilient units are connected together to collectively form a metal shield to protect the electronic components from electromagnetic interference (EMI).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The package structure as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the electronic components are adhered to the metal shield by thermal grease. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
