<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625048-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625048</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13380076</doc-number>
<date>20110707</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2011 2 0206275 U</doc-number>
<date>20110617</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>118</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>1333</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>349 60</main-classification>
<further-classification>349 58</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Plastic frame, liquid crystal module and liquid crystal display</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0115401</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Tsubokura et al.</name>
<date>20070500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>349 58</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>1725075</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20060100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>101206338</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20080600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00004">
<othercit>International Search Report of the PCT Application No. PCT/CN2011/076966.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>13</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>349 60</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>349 58</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120320303</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121220</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Shi</last-name>
<first-name>Qinjun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Shi</last-name>
<first-name>Qinjun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Shenzhen China Star Optoelectronics Technology Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Chen</last-name>
<first-name>Wen-Ying P</first-name>
<department>2871</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/CN2011/076966</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20110707</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20111222</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2012/171236</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20121220</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The disclosure provides a plastic frame, a liquid crystal module and a liquid crystal display. The plastic frame is provided with a plurality of blocking walls for locating liquid crystal glass, wherein said plastic frame and said blocking walls are arranged in split type. Said blocking walls are detachably connected with said plastic frame, comprising block locating sections with the front ends contacted with liquid crystal glass. Said plastic frame is provided with a plurality of clamping grooves whose positions are different and used for adjusting the positions of the locating sections. Said blocking walls are detachably connected with said clamping grooves. The disclosure further provides a liquid crystal module and a liquid crystal display, on which said plastic frames are arranged. The plastic frame, the liquid crystal module or the liquid crystal display provided by the disclosure can reduce the cost for producing the liquid crystal display effectively.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="99.06mm" wi="164.51mm" file="US08625048-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="136.91mm" wi="104.06mm" file="US08625048-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="203.12mm" wi="170.94mm" file="US08625048-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="224.87mm" wi="182.46mm" file="US08625048-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="112.78mm" wi="145.37mm" file="US08625048-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The disclosure relates to a plastic frame, in particular to a plastic frame used in the liquid crystal module of liquid crystal display.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">As is known, existing liquid crystal display comprises liquid crystal glass. Liquid crystal glass is placed on a plastic frame, and each edge of the plastic frame is provided with blocking walls for locating liquid crystal glass. At present, the plastic frame and the blocking walls are integrally molded of plastic by mould. If there is slight discrepancy for the length and the width of liquid crystal glass of the liquid crystal module, then the plastic frame cannot be matched with the liquid crystal glass. It needs to develop a new mould for molding the plastic frame to match with liquid crystal glass. However, the cost of the mould for the plastic frame will affect the final cost of the liquid crystal module, which is not beneficial for reducing the production cost.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The main purpose of the disclosure is to provide a plastic frame as well as a liquid crystal module with such plastic frame and a liquid crystal display with such liquid crystal module, which aims at reducing the production cost for the liquid crystal module of the liquid crystal display.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In order to realize above mentioned purposes, the disclosure provides a plastic frame which includes a plurality of blocking walls for locating the liquid crystal glass. Said blocking walls and said plastic frame are provided respectively, and said blocking wall includes a block locating section with a front end contacting with the liquid crystal glass; said plastic frame is provided with a plurality of clamping grooves whose positions are different and used for adjusting the positions of the locating sections. Said blocking walls are detachably connected with said clamping grooves.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Preferably, said blocking wall further includes a fixing section which is extended along the back end of the locating section and formed an external field angle with a side of the locating section; said plastic frame is provided with a receiving frame, which is protruded on the surface of the plastic frame and includes an opening with a width thereof equal to that of the locating section; said clamping grooves are arranged on the inner side wall of the receiving frame by layers, the shape and the size of each layer are same.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Preferably, said fixing sections are arranged in a triangle shape, an arc shape or a square shape.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Preferably, said blocking walls are T-shaped; the vertical section of the T shape is the locating section, and the horizontal section is the fixing section.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Preferably, said blocking walls include fixing sections with same shapes and same sizes.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Preferably, said clamping grooves are extended towards the opposite side of the liquid crystal glass on the plastic frame and are arranged at intervals; said clamping groove includes a buckling table; said blocking walls are provided with buckling bodies matched with said buckling tables; said buckling bodies are fitted with said buckling tables, which connect the blocking walls with the plastic frame.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Preferably, said blocking walls are square cavities, said clamping grooves are arranged on inner side walls of the cavities of the blocking walls; and said plastic frame is provided with projections that are matched with said clamping grooves.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Preferably, a thread adjustable structure is arranged between said locating section and said fixing section for adjusting the relative positions of them.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Preferably, said clamping grooves are linearly arrayed with multiple rows. Preferably, the inner side wall of the cavity of said blocking wall is provided with a plurality of linearly-arrayed clamping grooves.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The disclosure further provides a liquid crystal module, comprising a liquid crystal glass and a plastic frame. Said plastic frame is provided with blocking walls for locating liquid crystal glass. Said blocking walls and said plastic frame are provided respectively, and said blocking walls include a block locating section with a front end contacting with liquid crystal glass. Said plastic frame is provided with clamping grooves whose positions are different and used for adjusting the positions of the locating sections; and said blocking walls are detachably connected with said clamping grooves.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The disclosure further provides a liquid crystal display, including a liquid crystal module. Said liquid crystal module includes a liquid crystal glass and a plastic frame. Said plastic frame is provided with a plurality of blocking walls for locating the liquid crystal glass, wherein said blocking walls and said plastic frame are provided respectively, and said blocking wall includes a block locating section with a front end contacting with the liquid crystal glass; said plastic frame is provided with clamping grooves whose positions are different and used for adjusting the positions of the locating sections; and said blocking walls are detachably connected with said clamping grooves.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In the liquid crystal module of the liquid crystal display, the disclosure adjusts the relative positions of the blocking walls on the plastic frame by detachably connecting the blocking walls that are used for locating liquid crystal glass with the plastic frame; as a result, there is no need to develop new moulds to molding plastic frames for fitting with liquid crystal glass of different sizes, so that the production cost for the liquid crystal module of the liquid crystal display is reduced.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is the schematic diagram showing the three-dimensional structure of a first exemplary embodiment of a plastic frame according to the disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is the schematic diagram showing the front-side structure of a second exemplary embodiment of the plastic frame according to the disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is the schematic diagram showing the structure of a blocking wall of the second exemplary embodiment of the plastic frame according to the disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is the schematic diagram showing the structure of a third exemplary embodiment of the plastic frame according to the disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is the schematic diagram showing the structure of a fourth exemplary embodiment of the plastic frame according to the disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is the schematic diagram showing the structure of a first exemplary embodiment of the liquid crystal module according to the disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The purpose implementation, the function features and advantages of the disclosure will be further illustrated by integrating the exemplary embodiments and taking the attached drawings as references.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">It should be understood that the described exemplary embodiment is only used for illustrating this disclosure rather than limiting.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Take <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> as a reference, which is the schematic diagram showing the three-dimensional structures of a plastic frame <b>1</b> and a blocking wall <b>10</b> in the first exemplary embodiment according to the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In this exemplary embodiment, the plastic frame <b>1</b> is made of plastic and is in a shape of square frame. Each edge of the plastic frame is provided with a plurality of blocking walls <b>10</b> for locating a liquid crystal glass <b>100</b>. Said blocking wall <b>10</b> comprises a block locating section <b>101</b>, and a front end of the block locating section <b>101</b> contacts with the liquid crystal glass <b>100</b>. A back end of the locating section <b>101</b> is provided with a fixing section <b>102</b>, which is extended along the back end of the locating section <b>101</b> and is formed with an external field angle (the angle is <b>90</b> degrees in this exemplary) with the side of the locating section <b>101</b>. More specifically, the blocking wall <b>10</b> in this exemplary embodiment is T-shaped; the vertical section of T-shaped is the locating section <b>101</b>, which contacts with the liquid crystal glass <b>100</b>. Multiple locating sections <b>101</b> are integrally enclosed into a receiving frame (not shown in FIGS) for locating the liquid crystal glass <b>100</b>. The horizontal section of the T-shaped horizontal section is the fixing section <b>102</b>, which is used for connecting with the plastic frame <b>1</b>. In this exemplary embodiment, a length of the locating section <b>101</b> is adjustable; for example, the locating section <b>101</b> is arranged into series of different sizes or is arranged into a thread adjustable structure so as to match the liquid crystal glasses <b>100</b> of different sizes. The plastic frame <b>1</b> includes a receiving frame <b>11</b> for locating the blocking wall <b>10</b>. Said receiving frame <b>11</b> is protruded on the surface of the plastic frame <b>1</b>, including an opening end <b>111</b> and a clamping groove <b>112</b>. The blocking wall <b>10</b> can be horizontally placed into said receiving frame <b>11</b>, a front side of the locating section <b>101</b> is protruded on an end plane of the opening end <b>111</b> so as to locate the liquid crystal glass <b>100</b>. An opening width W of the opening end <b>111</b> is approximate equal to a width w of the locating section <b>101</b> for locating the blocking wall <b>10</b> in left side and right side. A height H of the clamping groove <b>112</b> is approximate equal to a height h of the fixing section <b>102</b> for locating the blocking wall <b>10</b> in front side and back side. While connecting, nothing needs but to clamp each part relatively. The plastic material used by the blocking wall <b>10</b> in this exemplary is same as that of the plastic frame <b>1</b>, which is integrally molded with the plastic frame <b>1</b> in one mould. In other embodiments, the blocking wall <b>10</b> can also use the plastic material with the hardness weaker than that of the plastic frame <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Since the blocking walls <b>10</b> are detachably connected with the plastic frame <b>1</b>, so that the relative positions of the blocking walls <b>10</b> on the plastic frame <b>1</b> can be adjusted and said receiving frame can be fitted with various sizes of the liquid crystal glass <b>100</b>. For example, when meeting various sizes of the liquid crystal glass <b>100</b>, it only needs to adjust the size of the locating section <b>101</b> and make it fitted with the liquid crystal glass <b>100</b>, and then assemble the blocking walls <b>10</b> with the receiving frame <b>11</b>; therefore, different sizes of the liquid crystals glass <b>100</b> can be located without developing new moulds. Compared with the integral molding method for the plastic frame <b>1</b> and the blocking walls <b>10</b> in existing technology, the disclosure can reduce the cost for developing moulds. It should be illustrated that the shape of the fixing section <b>102</b> in this exemplary embodiment can not only be a square, but also be a triangle or an arc (such as semicircle, etc.); correspondingly, the clamping groove <b>112</b> on the plastic frame <b>1</b> is fitted therewith.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Take <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> as a reference, which is the schematic diagram showing the structure of the plastic frame <b>2</b> in a second exemplary embodiment according to the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In this exemplary embodiment, the blocking walls can be the ones in the first exemplary embodiments. The plastic frame <b>2</b> is provided with clamping grooves <b>21</b> which are arranged in layers with each layer capable of clamping the fixing section <b>102</b>; the clamping grooves <b>21</b> can either be concaved from the surface of the plastic frame <b>2</b> according to the shape shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> or be provided with a frame body that is protruded on the surface of the plastic frame <b>2</b>. The clamping grooves <b>21</b> are arranged on the inner side wall of the frame body. Front ends of the clamping grooves <b>21</b> are provided with openings <b>211</b>. The clamping groove <b>21</b> of the previous layer and the clamping groove <b>21</b> of the next layer are same in shapes and sizes, a space and a the layer quantity between the two grooves are determined according to width of edges of the plastic frame <b>2</b> so that the size of the receiving frame can be finely adjusted. The layer quantity of the clamping grooves <b>21</b> in this exemplary embodiment is preferably selected as three.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Take <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> as a reference, which is the schematic diagram showing the structure of the blocking wall of a second exemplary embodiment of the plastic frame according to the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Further, the other preferable scheme of the blocking walls <b>10</b> lies as follows. The fixing section <b>102</b> is triangle-shaped (as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) and is also arranged in layers with equal shapes and sizes, as a result, it can be relatively connected with multiple layers of the clamping grooves <b>21</b> when connected with the clamping groove <b>11</b>, so that the blocking walls <b>10</b> are more stably connected with the plastic frame <b>2</b>. It should be illustrated that, in this exemplary embodiment, the shape of the fixing section <b>102</b> can not only be a triangle in this exemplary embodiment, but also be a square shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> or the semicircle in other exemplary embodiments, so as to guarantee the blocking walls <b>10</b> can be located forward and backward.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Since the clamping grooves <b>21</b> are arranged in layers, thus the fixing section <b>102</b> of the blocking walls <b>10</b> can be selectively located on a clamping groove <b>21</b> of a certain layer according to the size of the liquid crystal glass <b>100</b> in the process of assembling. The locating position of the locating section <b>101</b> of the blocking walls <b>10</b> is changed so that the size of the receiving frame is adjusted, which can be fitted with different sizes of the liquid crystal glass <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Take <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> as a reference, which is the schematic diagram showing the structure of a plastic frame <b>3</b> of a third exemplary embodiment according to the disclosure. In this exemplary embodiment, each edge of the plastic frame <b>3</b> is provided with a clamping groove <b>31</b>. The clamping groove <b>31</b> is extended towards the opposite side of the liquid crystal glass <b>100</b> on the plastic frame <b>3</b> and is arranged into multiple rows, each row is provided with a plurality of clamping grooves <b>31</b>. Distances among the rows are designed according to the width of the edge of the plastic frame <b>3</b>. If the edge is wider, the clamping grooves <b>31</b> can be arranged for more than two rows; it the edge is narrower, the clamping grooves <b>31</b> can be arranged for two rows, however, only the adjusting range is relatively smaller. In this exemplary embodiment, the clamping groove <b>31</b> is a buckling groove actually, the bottom of which is provided with a buckle table (not shown in FIGS).The blocking wall <b>10</b> is a strip-shaped plastic block or a plastic box and is only provided with a locating section <b>101</b> rather than a fixing section <b>102</b>. A bottom part of the fixing section <b>101</b> is provided with a buckling body (not shown in FIGS) which is fitted with the clamping groove <b>31</b>. Such buckle body is buckled with the clamping groove <b>31</b> and is used for connecting the blocking wall <b>10</b> with the plastic frame <b>3</b>. When there is a need of adjusting the size of the receiving frame, it only needs to buckle the blocking wall <b>10</b> with the clamping groove <b>31</b> in an appropriate position; therefore it is convenient and energy-saving to adjust.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Take <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> as a reference, which the schematic diagram showing the structure of a plastic frame <b>4</b> in a fourth exemplary embodiment according to the disclosure. The blocking wall <b>10</b> is hollow arranged, specifically, the blocking wall <b>10</b> is a square frame; side walls of the cavity of the square frame is provided with a plurality of clamping groves <b>103</b>. Said clamping grooves <b>103</b> are arranged in layers according to the form of the clamping groove <b>21</b> in the second exemplary embodiment. The plastic frame <b>4</b> is provided with a projection <b>41</b> fitted with an inner cavity of the blocking wall <b>10</b> for locating the blocking wall <b>10</b>. In this exemplary embodiment, the projection <b>41</b> can be one or multiples ones, and each projection <b>41</b> is equal in distance and shape, therefore a larger adjusting range can be obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Since the clamping groove <b>103</b> is arranged, thus the blocking wall <b>10</b> can adjust and locate the size of the receiving cavity of the liquid crystal glass <b>100</b> by moving position of the blocking wall <b>10</b> on the plastic frame <b>4</b> at back, left and right, so as to fit with the liquid crystal glass <b>100</b> of different sizes. In this exemplary embodiment, the blocking wall <b>10</b> can also be molded the plastic frame <b>4</b> by one mould and of the same plastic material.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In addition, the projection <b>41</b> can be arranged on the blocking wall <b>10</b> and the clamping groove <b>103</b> can be arranged on the plastic frame <b>4</b>, thereby the adjusting can be still realized.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The plastic frames <b>1</b>, <b>2</b>, <b>3</b> or <b>4</b> of the disclosure can be applied to the liquid crystal module. Liquid crystal module is an important constituent part of liquid crystal display. Taking <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> as reference, which is the schematic diagram showing the structure of a first exemplary embodiment of the liquid crystal module according to the disclosure. In this exemplary embodiment, the liquid crystal module includes a plastic frame <b>5</b>; such plastic frame <b>5</b> can be said plastic frame <b>1</b>, <b>2</b>, <b>3</b> or <b>4</b>. Since the plastic frame <b>5</b> of the liquid crystal module according to the disclosure provides with the structures of said plastic frame <b>1</b>, <b>2</b>, <b>3</b> or <b>4</b>, so that the liquid crystal module of the disclosure can assembly liquid crystal glass of different sizes without remolding; as a result, the production cost for the liquid crystal module is reduced. Please take the first, the second, the third and the fourth exemplary embodiment of said plastic frame as references to further understand the structures of the plastic frame <b>1</b>, <b>2</b>, <b>3</b> and <b>4</b>, so it will not illustrate more details here.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The disclosure further provides a liquid crystal display, which can be applied to LCD TV (Liquid Crystal Display Television). Except said liquid crystal modules, the liquid crystal display further includes a light source unit, a casing, etc. Since the plastic frame of the liquid crystal module provides with the structures of said plastic frame <b>1</b>, <b>2</b>, <b>3</b> or <b>4</b>, so that the cost of the liquid crystal display is reduced to a large extent. The liquid crystal display and relative products are provided with stronger market competition advantages.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">What is illustrated above is just a preferable exemplary embodiment, which will not limit the patent scope of the disclosure. Any equivalent replacements made by the specifications and drawings of the disclosure, which are directly or indirectly applied to other technical fields, should be included into the protection scope of the disclosure.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A plastic frame, comprising blocking walls for locating a liquid crystal glass, characterized in that, said blocking walls and said plastic frame are provided respectively; said blocking wall comprises a block locating section with a front end contacting with the liquid crystal glass; said plastic frame is provided with a plurality of clamping grooves for adjusting the positions of the locating sections; said blocking walls are detachably connected with said clamping grooves; blocking wall further comprises a fixing section which is extended along the back end of the locating section and formed an external field angle with a side of the locating section; said plastic frame is provided with a receiving frame, which is protruded on the surface of the plastic frame and comprises an opening with a width thereof equal to that of the locating section; said clamping grooves are arranged on inner side walls of the receiving frame by layers, the shape and the size of each layer are same.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The plastic frame according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, characterized in that, said fixing sections are arranged in a triangle shape, an arc shape or a square shape.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The plastic frame according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, characterized in that, a thread adjustable structure is arranged between said locating section and said fixing section for adjusting the relative positions of them.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The plastic frame according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, characterized in that, said blocking walls are T-shaped; the vertical section of the T shape is the locating section, and the horizontal section is the fixing section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The plastic frame according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, characterized in that, said blocking walls comprise at least two layers of fixing sections of same shapes and same sizes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The plastic frame according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, characterized in that, a thread adjustable structure is arranged between said locating sections and said fixing sections for adjusting the relative positions of them.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A liquid crystal module, characterized in that, the liquid crystal module comprises a plastic frame; said plastic frame is provided with blocking walls for locating a liquid crystal glass, wherein said blocking walls and said plastic frame are provided respectively, and said blocking wall comprises a block locating section with a front end contacting with the liquid crystal glass; said plastic frame is provided with clamping grooves for adjusting the positions of the locating sections; and said blocking walls are detachably connected with said clamping grooves; said blocking wall further comprises a fixing section which is extended along the back end of the locating section and formed an external field angle with a side of the locating section; said plastic frame is provided with a receiving frame, which is protruded on the surface of the plastic frame and comprises an opening with a width equal to that of the locating section; said clamping grooves are arranged on the inner side wall of the receiving frame by layers, a shape and a size of each layer are same.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The liquid crystal module according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, characterized in that, said fixing sections are in a triangle shape, an arc shape or a square shape.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The liquid crystal module according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, characterized in that, said blocking walls are T-shaped; the vertical section of the T shape is the locating section, and the horizontal section is the fixing section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The liquid crystal module according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, characterized in that, said blocking walls comprise at least two layers of fixing sections with same shapes and same sizes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A plastic frame, comprising blocking walls for locating a liquid crystal glass, characterized in that, said blocking walls and said plastic frame are provided respectively; said blocking wall comprises a block locating section with a front end contacting with the liquid crystal glass; said plastic frame is provided with a plurality of clamping grooves for adjusting the positions of the locating sections; said blocking walls are detachably connected with said clamping grooves; said clamping grooves are extended towards the opposite side of the liquid crystal glass on the plastic frame and are arranged at intervals; said clamping groove comprises a buckling table; said blocking walls are provided with buckling bodies matched with said buckling tables; said buckling bodies are fitted with said buckling tables, which connect the blocking walls with the plastic frame.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The plastic frame according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, characterized in that, said clamping grooves are linearly arrayed with multiple rows.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A plastic frame, comprising blocking walls for locating a liquid crystal glass, characterized in that, said blocking walls and said plastic frame are provided respectively; said blocking wall comprises a block locating section with a front end contacting with the liquid crystal glass; said plastic frame is provided with a plurality of clamping grooves for adjusting the positions of the locating sections; said blocking walls are detachably connected with said clamping grooves; said blocking walls are square cavities, said clamping grooves are arranged on inner side walls of the cavities of the blocking walls; and said plastic frame is provided with projections matched with said clamping grooves, and the inner side walls of the cavity of said blocking wall is provided with a plurality of linearly-arrayed clamping grooves. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
