<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08621940-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08621940</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13051442</doc-number>
<date>20110318</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>248</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 73862326</main-classification>
<further-classification> 73862328</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Method for detecting torque in a transmission, measuring device and control program</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4136559</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Brown</name>
<date>19790100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4872337</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Watts et al.</name>
<date>19891000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4931949</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hernandez et al.</name>
<date>19900600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5719461</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Peclat et al.</name>
<date>19980200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>31032302</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6578437</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Moerbe</name>
<date>20030600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7617727</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Watson</name>
<date>20091100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 7350413</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0274181</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kutsuna et al.</name>
<date>20051200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 7350412</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0256495</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Watson</name>
<date>20071100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 7350412</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>2815463</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19781100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>19732124</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19990200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>19745823</doc-number>
<date>19990400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO 0008434</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20000200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO 2005012763</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20050200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>12</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7386208</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7386231</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 73862326</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 73862328</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120067138</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120322</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Klein-Hitpass</last-name>
<first-name>Arno</first-name>
<address>
<city>Aachen</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Reimers</last-name>
<first-name>Jan-Dirk</first-name>
<address>
<city>Aachen</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Klein-Hitpass</last-name>
<first-name>Arno</first-name>
<address>
<city>Aachen</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Reimers</last-name>
<first-name>Jan-Dirk</first-name>
<address>
<city>Aachen</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Henry M. Feiereisen LLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Siemens Aktiengesellschaft</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>M&#xfc;nchen</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Noori</last-name>
<first-name>Max</first-name>
<department>2856</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Torque can be detected in a transmission by using at least one vibration sensor to detect at least one vibration signal which is associated with a tooth engagement frequency of intermeshing transmission toothings, and the phase shift of which is dependent on at least one tooth engagement duration of the intermeshing transmission toothings. The tooth engagement duration is torque-dependent as a result of toothing deformations. A torque acting on the transmission is determined from the phase shift of the detected vibration signal and/or of the at least one tooth engagement duration.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="165.27mm" wi="172.80mm" file="US08621940-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="172.97mm" wi="172.30mm" file="US08621940-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="235.71mm" wi="143.17mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621940-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="252.98mm" wi="144.27mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621940-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCES TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the priority of European Patent Application, Serial No. EP 10002921, filed Mar. 19, 2010, pursuant to 35 U.S.C. 119(a)-(d), the content of which is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety as if fully set forth herein.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to the field of detecting torque in a transmission.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The following discussion of related art is provided to assist the reader in understanding the advantages of the invention, and is not to be construed as an admission that this related art is prior art to this invention.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In industrial processing and manufacturing processes, a wide range of complex demands is imposed on drive systems comprising transmissions, for example reliable operation for a prolonged period of use with minimal outlay on maintenance. Drive system failures which impair industrial processing and manufacturing processes may result in high financial damage, for example due to plant downtimes.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In particular in wind power plants, transmissions are subject during the period of use thereof to a dynamic load sequence of torques and bending moments and also axial and radial forces. In order to configure transmissions, use is made of load collectives defined by plant operators or manufacturers. Problems may arise if said load collectives do not correspond to the actual loads occurring during operation. In order to identify and to avoid overload situations, torque sensors can be provided in a transmission.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">A torque measurement at a shaft is frequently based on the fact that a shaft has torsion spring properties and experiences rotation because of the effect of torque. Said rotation can be determined, for example, by means of strain gauges, optical sensors or magneto-elastic sensors. If the torsional rigidity of the shaft is known, the rotation determined can be used to derive the torque acting on the shaft.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">It would be desirable and advantageous to provide an improved method for torque detection to obviate prior art shortcomings and to allow implementation in a simple manner in a transmission while permitting contact-free measurement which is reliable over the long term and is insensitive to malfunctions.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to one aspect of the present invention, a method for determining a torque in a transmission, with the steps of detecting with at least one vibration sensor at least one vibration signal associated with a tooth engagement frequency of intermeshing transmission toothings, determining a phase shift of the at least one vibration signal, said phase shift depending on at least one tooth engagement duration, and determining a torque value acting on the transmission from the phase shift or the at least one tooth engagement duration, or both.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In accordance with the invention, torque is detected in a transmission, using at least one vibration sensor to detect at least one vibration signal which is associated with a tooth engagement frequency of intermeshing transmission toothings, and the phase shift of which is dependent on at least one tooth engagement duration of the intermeshing transmission toothings. In this case, the tooth engagement duration is torque-dependent as a result of toothing deformations. A torque acting on the transmission is determined from the phase shift of the detected vibration signal and/or of the at least one tooth engagement duration.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The present invention permits, for example, use of vibration sensors, which were hitherto used for transmission state monitoring systems or condition monitoring systems, additionally for detecting torque. In contrast to previous contact-free torque measurement systems which are arranged about a transmission shaft and take up space there, a measuring device according to the invention can be integrated more easily into transmissions.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In order to detect torque, a torque-dependent difference between phase shifts of tooth engagement frequencies of at least two different tooth engagements can also be determined. The torque acting on the transmission is then determined from the difference between the phase shifts. As an alternative thereto, a plurality of vibration signals or vibration signal components which are associated with a plurality of different tooth engagements can be detected. In this case, the torque acting on the transmission is determined with reference to an average value calculated for a plurality of different tooth engagements. In this case, the tooth engagements of the transmission can be monitored for deviations between the average value and measured torque values individual to the tooth engagement. If a deviation exceeds a specifiable threshold value, an alarm signal comprising an indication of an affected tooth engagement can be generated, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to another aspect of the present invention, a measuring device for determining a torque acting on a transmission includes at least one vibration sensor for measuring at least one vibration signal associated with a tooth engagement frequency of intermeshing transmission toothings, wherein the intermeshing transmission toothings define a phase shift of the at least one vibration signal which depends on at least one torque-dependent tooth engagement duration, and a signal processing unit operatively connected to the at least one vibration sensor for determining the torque acting on the transmission from the phase shift of the at least one vibration signal or the at least one torque-dependent tooth engagement duration.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to yet another aspect of the present invention, a control program for detecting torque in a transmission is stored on a non-transitory computer-readable medium and has at least one code section which, when loaded into a memory of a data processing device and executed in the data processing device, causes the data processing device to detect with at least one vibration sensor at least one vibration signal associated with a tooth engagement frequency of intermeshing transmission toothings, determine a phase shift of the at least one vibration signal, wherein the phase shift depends on at least one tooth engagement duration, and determine a torque value acting on the transmission from the phase shift or the at least one tooth engagement duration, or both.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWING</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Other features and advantages of the present invention will be more readily apparent upon reading the following description of currently preferred exemplified embodiments of the invention with reference to the accompanying drawing, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows an illustration by way of example of a tooth engagement of a cylindrical gear pair having involute toothing,</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a diagram produced for a plurality of different torque loads with tooth profile pressing gradients along a tooth engagement section,</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a schematic illustration of an arrangement with a transmission and a torque measuring device.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Throughout all the figures, same or corresponding elements may generally be indicated by same reference numerals. These depicted embodiments are to be understood as illustrative of the invention and not as limiting in any way. It should also be understood that the figures are not necessarily to scale and that the embodiments are sometimes illustrated by graphic symbols, phantom lines, diagrammatic representations and fragmentary views. In certain instances, details which are not necessary for an understanding of the present invention or which render other details difficult to perceive may have been omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Turning now to the drawing, and in particular to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, there is shown, by way of example, a tooth engagement of a cylindrical gear pair having involute toothing. Two gearwheels <b>101</b>, <b>102</b> of the cylindrical gear pair are illustrated there in a first position (continuous line) at a time T<b>1</b> at which a tooth <b>111</b> of a first gearwheel <b>101</b> intermeshes at an engagement point A with a tooth <b>121</b> of a second gearwheel <b>102</b>. In addition, the two gearwheels <b>101</b>, <b>102</b> are illustrated in a second position (dashed line) at a second time T<b>2</b> at which the engagement between the tooth <b>111</b> of the first gearwheel <b>101</b> and the tooth <b>121</b> of the second gearwheel <b>102</b> ends at an engagement point E when both gearwheels <b>101</b>, <b>102</b> are rotated in the sketched direction. Only the two teeth <b>111</b>, <b>121</b> of the gearwheels <b>101</b>, <b>102</b> intermesh in an individual engagement area between an engagement point B and an engagement point D. By contrast, further teeth of the gearwheels <b>101</b>, <b>102</b> are also connected to one another in double engagement areas between the engagement points A and B and between the engagement points D and E. At an engagement point C, which is also referred to as a rolling contact point, the gearwheels <b>101</b>, <b>102</b> roll along each other in a manner free from sliding friction. The engagement points A-E lie on a straight line <b>103</b> in the case of an involute toothing.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Intermeshing teeth of a pair of gearwheels deform under the load, and therefore teeth which follow in the direction of rotation intermesh earlier, considered relatively. This gives rise to varying tooth engagement durations and tooth force fluctuations which in turn result in noises and vibrations. Said noises and vibrations can be detected as a vibration signal by means of a vibration sensor. In this case, the vibration signal is representative of a tooth engagement frequency of the pair of gearwheels, the gearwheels of which intermesh. The vibration signal has a phase shift which is dependent on at least one tooth engagement duration of the intermeshing gearwheels.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In the case of spur-toothed gearwheels, deformations substantially determined by the tooth rigidity and acting torque arise under load. These result in a tooth engagement phase shift which increases as the torque increases. This is basically also applicable to gearwheels having helical toothing. Corresponding to the diagram produced in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> for a plurality of different torque loads and having tooth profile pressing gradients <b>201</b>-<b>206</b>, the tooth engagement duration increases continuously along a tooth engagement section between the engagement points A and E as the torque increases. The gradient <b>201</b> is associated with the lowest torque load while the gradient <b>206</b> is associated with the highest torque load. The torque load increases continuously from the gradient <b>201</b> to the gradient <b>206</b>. In addition, it is apparent with reference to the tooth profile pressing that the tooth engagement duration along a tooth engagement section between the engagement points B and D decreases as the torque load increases. This load-dependent behavior can be detected, for example, by airborne sound vibration pickups or structure borne sound vibration pickups.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The arrangement which is illustrated schematically in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> comprises a torque measuring device with two vibration sensors <b>301</b>, <b>302</b> mounted on a housing of a transmission <b>307</b> and with a computer-based signal processing unit <b>306</b>. In principle, even a single vibration sensor is sufficient. In this case, a signal processing unit having greater computational power and being able to be executed, for example, even purely on a hardware basis, should be selected.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The two vibration sensors <b>301</b>, <b>302</b> are used to detect vibration signals which each represent a tooth engagement frequency of intermeshing transmission toothings of a first transmission stage <b>371</b> and a second transmission stage <b>372</b>. As explained above, the phase shifts of the tooth engagement frequencies are dependent on the tooth engagement durations of the intermeshing transmission toothings. The tooth engagement durations in turn are torque-dependent as a result of toothing deformations. The two vibration sensors <b>301</b>, <b>302</b> are sensors of a condition monitoring system <b>309</b> for the transmission <b>307</b>, which sensors are used for determining a vibration signature, and therefore, if a condition monitoring system is present, basically no new sensors are required in order to detect torque.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">With two vibration sensors, use can additionally be made of the fact that a drive train between the intermeshing transmission toothings of the first transmission stage <b>371</b> and those of the second transmission stage <b>372</b> experiences torque-dependent rotations. Said rotations of the drive train lead to phase shifts between the vibration signals detected by the two vibration sensors <b>301</b>, <b>302</b>. The drive train between the transmission toothings under consideration frequently has a torsional spring rigidity which is substantially identical for all of the transmissions of a series and can be determined within the scope of a calibration operation, for example on a transmission test rig.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The signal processing unit <b>306</b> of the torque measuring device comprises a processor <b>361</b>, a working memory <b>362</b>, a nonvolatile memory <b>363</b>&#x2014;for example a hard disk drive or a flash memory&#x2014;and an input/output unit <b>364</b>. The signal processing unit <b>305</b> is coupled to the vibration sensors <b>301</b>, <b>302</b> via a bandpass filter <b>305</b> assigned to said signal processing unit.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">A control program <b>308</b> is stored in the memory <b>363</b> of the signal processing unit <b>306</b>, which control program can be loaded into the working memory <b>362</b> and has code sections which can be processed by the processor <b>361</b> and upon the execution of which vibration signals are detected via the vibration sensors <b>301</b>, <b>302</b>. A torque acting on the transmission <b>307</b> is determined from the phase shifts of the detected vibration signals or from the detected tooth engagement durations by the control program <b>308</b> when the latter is running in the signal processing unit <b>306</b>. For example, play caused by bearing slackness or tooth backlash in the drive train can be derived from a hysteresis-like gradient of the determined torque by the method implemented by the control program.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">By means of the signal processing unit <b>306</b>, the detected vibration signals can also be transformed from a frequency domain into a time domain, for example by means of inverse Laplace or Fourier transformation or by means of inverse Z transformation in the case of discrete signals. The tooth engagement durations between the engagement points B and D and between the engagement points A and E can then be determined from the vibration signals transformed into the time domain.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The vibration signals detected by means of the vibration sensors <b>301</b>, <b>302</b> are pre-processed for the signal processing unit <b>306</b> by the bandpass filter <b>305</b> with respect to specifiable frequency ranges by basic tooth engagement frequencies of the transmission toothings under consideration. In the present exemplary embodiment, basic tooth engagement frequencies are determined by means of revolution counters <b>303</b>, <b>304</b> assigned to the two transmission stages <b>371</b>, <b>372</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The above-described method for detecting torque in a transmission can be expanded by forming an average value via a plurality of torque measuring signals. This enables individual geometry deviations in the transmission toothings to be placed against one another and toothing deviations or increased play to be detected. For this purpose, a plurality of vibration signals or vibration signal components associated with a plurality of different tooth engagements are detected. The torque acting on the transmission is then determined with reference to an average value calculated for a plurality of different tooth engagements. Tooth engagements of the transmission can then be monitored for deviations between the average value and measured torque values individual to the tooth engagement. If there is a deviation above a specifiable threshold value, an alarm signal comprising an indication of an affected tooth engagement is generated, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The use of the present invention is not restricted to the exemplary embodiment described here.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">While the invention has been illustrated and described in connection with currently preferred embodiments shown and described in detail, it is not intended to be limited to the details shown since various modifications and structural changes may be made without departing in any way from the spirit and scope of the present invention. The embodiments were chosen and described in order to explain the principles of the invention and practical application to thereby enable a person skilled in the art to best utilize the invention and various embodiments with various modifications as are suited to the particular use contemplated.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">What is claimed as new and desired to be protected by Letters Patent is set forth in the appended claims and includes equivalents of the elements recited therein:</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method for determining a torque in a transmission having a pair of gearwheels with intermeshing teeth that deform under load, comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>detecting with at least one vibration sensor at least one vibration signal associated with a tooth engagement frequency of the intermeshing teeth of the gearwheels;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a phase shift of the at least one vibration signal, said phase shift depending on the tooth engagement duration, wherein the at least one tooth engagement duration depends on a torque value in the transmission caused by deformation of the intermeshing teeth under the load; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining the torque value acting on the transmission from the phase shift or the at least one tooth engagement duration, or both.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising the steps of determining a torque-dependent difference between phase shifts of tooth engagement frequencies of at least two different tooth engagements, and determining the torque value acting on the transmission from the difference between the phase shifts.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising the steps of detecting a plurality of vibration signals or vibration signal components which are associated with a plurality of different tooth engagements, and determining an average torque value acting on the transmission by averaging the plurality of vibration signals or vibration signal components.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, further comprising the steps of monitoring differences between the average torque value and individual measured torque values, and generating an alarm signal when a deviation lies above a predetermined threshold value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the alarm signal comprises an indication of an affected tooth engagement.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising the steps of
<claim-text>transforming the at least one vibration signal from a frequency domain into a time domain, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining from the vibration signal transformed into the time domain a tooth engagement duration between a time when a tooth of a first gearwheel first makes contact with a meshing tooth of a second gearwheel of the transmission and a time when the tooth of the first gearwheel last makes contact with the meshing tooth of the second gearwheel, or</claim-text>
<claim-text>a tooth engagement duration between a time when in absence of contact between other teeth of the first and second gearwheel, the tooth of the first gearwheel makes exclusive contact with the meshing tooth of the second gearwheel of the transmission and a time when the tooth of the first gearwheel last makes exclusive contact with the meshing tooth of the second gearwheel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>or both.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising the step of band-pass-filtering the at least one vibration signal in a predetermined frequency range about a basic tooth engagement frequency.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the basic tooth engagement frequency is determined by a revolution counter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one vibration sensor is constructed as an airborne sound vibration pickup or a structure borne sound vibration pickup.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one vibration sensor constructed as sensor of a condition monitoring system employed for determining a vibration signature.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A measuring device for determining a torque acting on a transmission having a pair of gearwheels with intermeshing teeth that deform under load, said measuring device comprising:
<claim-text>at least one vibration sensor for measuring at least one vibration signal associated with a tooth engagement frequency of the intermeshing teeth of the gearwheels, said at least one vibration signal defining a phase shift which depends on at least one torque-dependent tooth engagement duration; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a signal processing unit operatively connected to the at least one vibration sensor for determining the torque acting on the transmission from the phase shift of the at least one vibration signal or the at least one torque-dependent tooth engagement duration.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. A control program for detecting torque in a transmission having a pair of gearwheels with intermeshing teeth that deform under load, said control program stored on a non-transitory computer-readable medium and having at least one code section which, when loaded into a memory of a data processing device and executed in the data processing device, causes the data processing device to:
<claim-text>detect with at least one vibration sensor at least one vibration signal associated with a tooth engagement frequency of the intermeshing teeth of the gearwheels;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determine a phase shift of the at least one vibration signal, said phase shift depending on at least one tooth engagement duration of the intermeshing teeth of the gearwheels, wherein the at least one tooth engagement duration depends on a torque in the transmission caused by deformation of the intermeshing teeth under the load; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determine a torque value acting on the transmission from the phase shift or the at least one tooth engagement duration, or both.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
