<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624963-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624963</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13151697</doc-number>
<date>20110602</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2010-0054009</doc-number>
<date>20100608</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>251</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20110101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>T</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>348 51</main-classification>
<further-classification>345419</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Stereoscopic image display device and method for manufacturing the same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6799859</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Ida et al.</name>
<date>20041000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0296877</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kang</name>
<date>20071200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>349 15</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0007835</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lim et al.</name>
<date>20080100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0233102</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Toyama et al.</name>
<date>20090900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4284231</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0310216</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Roh et al.</name>
<date>20091200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0289884</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kang</name>
<date>20101100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>348 58</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0096568</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Schattinger et al.</name>
<date>20110400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362613</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>101065693</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20071000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>101097271</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20080100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>101101844</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20080100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>101604071</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20091200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2007-0122267</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20071200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00013">
<othercit>Office Action issued in related Korean Patent Application No. 10-2010-0054009 dated Oct. 22, 2012.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00014">
<othercit>Office Action dated Jul. 26, 2013 from The State Intellectual Property Office of the People's Republic of China in Chinese Application No. 201110160248.0.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>14</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>345419</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>348 51</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>11</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110298792</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20111208</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lim</last-name>
<first-name>Kyong Ho</first-name>
<address>
<city>Gyeonggi-do</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lim</last-name>
<first-name>Kyong Ho</first-name>
<address>
<city>Gyeonggi-do</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Morgan, Lewis &#x26; Bockius LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>LG Display Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Czekaj</last-name>
<first-name>Dave</first-name>
<department>2487</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Owens</last-name>
<first-name>Tsion B</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Disclosed is a stereoscopic image display device and a method for manufacturing the same, which facilitates to improve picture quality and to realize wide viewing angle and high luminance of stereoscopic images by improving crosstalk of left-eye image and right-eye image, wherein the stereoscopic image display device comprises a display panel including lower and upper substrates which are bonded to each other, and are provided with a left-eye displaying area (LDA) for displaying a left-eye image of stereoscopic image, and a right-eye displaying area (RDA) for displaying a right-eye image of stereoscopic image; a light-guiding member formed in the upper substrate and overlapped with an interface between the left-eye displaying area (LDA) and the right-eye displaying area (RDA); and an optical-axis changing member formed on the upper substrate, wherein the optical-axis changing member includes a left-eye retarder corresponding to the left-eye displaying area, and a right-eye retarder corresponding to the right-eye displaying area.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="86.44mm" wi="162.39mm" file="US08624963-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="189.65mm" wi="162.73mm" file="US08624963-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="230.72mm" wi="169.16mm" file="US08624963-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="226.23mm" wi="168.57mm" file="US08624963-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="242.91mm" wi="171.70mm" file="US08624963-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="244.18mm" wi="175.60mm" file="US08624963-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of the Korean Patent Application No. 10-2010-0054009 filed on Jun. 8, 2010, which is hereby incorporated by reference as if fully set forth herein.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to a stereoscopic image display device, and more particularly, to a stereoscopic image display device which facilitates to realize good picture quality, wide viewing angle, and good luminance by preventing crosstalk of left-eye image and right-eye image.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Discussion of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">With development of information society, a display device is faced with requirement for a large size and a thin profile. In order to satisfy these requirements, there is the explosive increase for various kinds of flat type display devices having advantages of thin profile, lightness in weight, and low power consumption.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The flat type display device may include a liquid crystal display device (LCD), a plasma display panel (PDP), a field emission display device (FED), a light-emitting diode display device (LED), and etc. Among the various flat panel display devices, the LCD device is widely used owing to various advantages, for example, technical development for the mass production, easiness of driving means, low power consumption, and high-quality resolution.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Recently, a user's demand for a stereoscopic image is rapidly increased so that a stereoscopic image display device capable of displaying 3D (3-dimensional) image as well as 2D (2-dimensional) image is actively developed.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The stereoscopic image display device makes left-eye image and right-eye image with a binocular parallax separately seen in both eyes of a user. That is, the stereoscopic image display device makes the left-eye image recognized only in the user's left eye, and also makes the right-eye image recognized only in the user's right eye, whereby the user can watch the stereoscopic 3D image.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">However, in case of the related art stereoscopic image display device, the left-eye image expected to be seen in the user's left eye might be recognized in the user's right eye, or the right-eye image expected to be seen in the user's right eye might be recognized in the user's left eye. Thus, the related art stereoscopic image display device may have a problem of low picture quality due to crosstalk of the left-eye image and right-eye image.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Accordingly, the present invention is directed to a stereoscopic image display device and a method for manufacturing the same that substantially obviates one or more problems due to limitations and disadvantages of the related art.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">An advantage of the present invention is to provide a stereoscopic image display device which facilitates to improve picture quality and to realize wide viewing angle and high luminance of stereoscopic images by improving crosstalk of left-eye image and right-eye image.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Additional advantages and features of the invention will be set forth in part in the description which follows and in part will become apparent to those having ordinary skill in the art upon examination of the following or may be learned from practice of the invention. The objectives and other advantages of the invention may be realized and attained by the structure particularly pointed out in the written description and claims hereof as well as the appended drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">To achieve these and other advantages and in accordance with the purpose of the invention, as embodied and broadly described herein, there is provided a stereoscopic image display device comprising: a display panel including lower and upper substrates which are bonded to each other, and are provided with a left-eye displaying area (LDA) for displaying a left-eye image of stereoscopic image, and a right-eye displaying area (RDA) for displaying a right-eye image of stereoscopic image; a light-guiding member formed in the upper substrate and overlapped with an interface between the left-eye displaying area (LDA) and the right-eye displaying area (RDA); and an optical-axis changing member formed on the upper substrate, wherein the optical-axis changing member includes a left-eye retarder corresponding to the left-eye displaying area, and a right-eye retarder corresponding to the right-eye displaying area.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">At this time, the light-guiding member reflects the right-eye image, which is transmitted through the right-eye displaying area and is advanced to the left-eye retarder, toward the right-eye retarder; and also reflects the left-eye image, which is transmitted through the left-eye displaying area and is advanced to the right-eye retarder, toward the left-eye retarder.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Also, the light-guiding member is hollowly formed from the upper surface of the upper substrate in such a manner that a thickness of the light-guiding member is more than a half of an entire thickness of the upper substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In another aspect of the present invention, there is provided a method for manufacturing a stereoscopic image display device comprising: preparing a display panel including lower and upper substrates which are bonded to each other, and are provided with a left-eye displaying area (LDA) for displaying a left-eye image of stereoscopic image, and a right-eye displaying area (RDA) for displaying a right-eye image of stereoscopic image; forming a light-guiding member overlapped with an interface between the left-eye displaying area (LDA) and the right-eye displaying area (RDA) in the upper substrate; adhering an upper polarizing plate to a front surface of the upper substrate including the light-guiding member; and forming an optical-axis changing member on the upper substrate, wherein the optical-axis changing member includes a left-eye retarder corresponding to the left-eye displaying area, and a right-eye retarder corresponding to the right-eye displaying area.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">At this time, the light-guiding member is hollowly formed from the upper surface of the upper substrate in such a manner that a thickness of the light-guiding member is more than a half of an entire thickness of the upper substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The process for forming the light-guiding member in the upper substrate comprises forming a light reflecting layer of aluminum or silicon in the light-guiding member.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">It is to be understood that both the foregoing general description and the following detailed description of the present invention are exemplary and explanatory and are intended to provide further explanation of the invention as claimed.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The accompanying drawings, which are included to provide a further understanding of the invention and are incorporated in and constitute a part of this application, illustrate embodiment(s) of the invention and together with the description serve to explain the principle of the invention. In the drawings:</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a stereoscopic image display device according to the first embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross section view along A-A&#x2032; of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a light-guiding member shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates a processing path in both left-eye image and right-eye image depending on light reflection of a light-guiding member according to the embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross section view illustrating a stereoscopic image display device according to the second embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6A to 6D</figref> illustrate a method for manufacturing the stereoscopic image display device according to the embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates a light reflecting layer in a light-guiding member after forming the light-guiding member shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> illustrates an upper polarizing plate adhered to an upper substrate after forming the light reflecting layer shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Reference will now be made in detail to the exemplary embodiments of the present invention, examples of which are illustrated in the accompanying drawings. Wherever possible, the same reference numbers will be used throughout the drawings to refer to the same or like parts.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Hereinafter, a stereoscopic image display device according to the present invention and a method for manufacturing the same will be described with reference to the accompanying drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a stereoscopic image display device according to the first embodiment of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross section view along A-A&#x2032; of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, the stereoscopic image display device according to the first embodiment of the present invention comprises a display panel <b>100</b>, a light-guiding member <b>200</b>, and an optical-axis changing member <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The display panel <b>100</b> comprises a lower substrate <b>110</b> and an upper substrate <b>120</b> which are bonded to each other, and are provided with a left-eye displaying area (LDA) for displaying a left-eye image of stereoscopic image, and a right-eye displaying area (RDA) for displaying a right-eye image of stereoscopic image. At this time, the lower substrate <b>110</b> and the upper substrate <b>120</b> are bonded to each other with a liquid crystal layer <b>130</b> interposed therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">On the lower substrate <b>110</b>, there is a thin film transistor array <b>112</b> which includes a plurality of gate lines (GL), a plurality of data lines (DL), and a plurality of pixels (P).</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The plurality of gate lines (GL) are arranged at fixed intervals in a first direction of the lower substrate <b>110</b>, wherein the plurality of gate lines (GL) are supplied with a gate signal from the external.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The plurality of data lines (DL) are arranged at fixed intervals in a second direction of the lower substrate <b>110</b>, wherein the second direction is perpendicular to the first direction. The plurality of data lines (DL) are supplied with a data signal from the external. At this time, the data signal may correspond to a two-dimensional image (2D image) in a 2D image mode; or may correspond to the left-eye image and right-eye image in a stereoscopic image mode.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Each of the plurality of pixels (P) is formed every pixel region defined by crossing the gate lines (GL) and data lines (DL) to each other. Each pixel (P) comprises a thin film transistor (T) which is connected with the data line (DL) adjacent to the neighboring gate line (GL); a pixel electrode (PE) which is connected with the thin film transistor (T); and a common electrode (not shown) which faces with the pixel electrode (PE).</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">As the thin film transistor (T) is switched-on in accordance with the gate signal supplied from the gate line (GL), the data signal supplied from the data line (DL) is supplied to the pixel electrode (PE).</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The pixel electrode (PE) forms an electric field depending on the data signal supplied through the thin film transistor (T), to thereby control transmittance of light passing through the liquid crystal layer <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The common electrode is formed between each of the pixel electrodes (PE) while being provided at a predetermined interval from the pixel electrode (PE). The common electrode is supplied with a reference voltage from the external. At this time, the common electrode may be formed on the upper substrate <b>120</b> being faced with the pixel electrode (PE) instead of the lower substrate <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">For the stereoscopic image mode, each horizontal line corresponding to a longitudinal direction of the gate line (GL) is divided into the left-eye displaying area (LDA) for displaying the left-eye image of the stereoscopic image, and the right-eye displaying area (RDA) for displaying the right-eye image of the stereoscopic image. For example, among the horizontal lines for the stereoscopic image mode, the odd-numbered horizontal line is set as the left-eye displaying area (LDA) to display the left-eye image, and the even-numbered horizontal line is set as the right-eye displaying area (RDA) to display the right-eye image.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The lower substrate <b>110</b> drives the respective pixels (P) in accordance with the gate signal supplied to the gate line (GL), and the data signal corresponding to the 2D image data or 3D (left-eye and right-eye) image data supplied to the data line (DL), to thereby control the transmittance of light through the liquid crystal layer <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">On the upper substrate <b>120</b>, there are a plurality of color filters (CF), a black matrix (BM), and an overcoat layer <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The plurality of color filters (CF) include red (R), green (G), and blue (B) color filters which correspond to the plurality of pixels (P). The red (R), green (G), and blue (B) color filters and the corresponding red, green, and blue pixels (P) constitute a unit pixel for displaying a color image. The plurality of color filters (CF) may be arranged in such a manner that the different kinds of the color filters (CF) may be repetitively provided along a longitudinal direction of the gate line (GL), and the same kind of the color filters (CF) may be repetitively provided along a longitudinal direction of the data line (DL).</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The black matrix (BM) is formed along the interfaces of the color filters (CF), thereby defining the plurality of color filters (CF), and optically separating the adjacent color filters (CF) from one another.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The overcoat layer <b>122</b> with a predetermined thickness is formed on an entire rear surface of the upper substrate <b>120</b> including the plurality of color filters (CF) and black matrix (BM), to thereby planarize the rear surface of the upper substrate <b>120</b> facing toward the lower substrate <b>120</b>. An alignment film (not shown) for aligning the liquid crystal layer <b>130</b> may be formed on the overcoat layer <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The display panel <b>100</b> may further comprise a lower polarizing plate <b>114</b> and an upper polarizing plate <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The lower polarizing plate <b>114</b> is adhered to the rear surface of the lower substrate <b>110</b>, that is, the surface facing toward a backlight unit (not shown), whereby the light emitted from the backlight unit and being incident on the lower substrate <b>110</b> is polarized by the lower polarizing plate <b>114</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The upper polarizing plate <b>124</b> is formed on a front surface of the upper substrate <b>120</b>, that is, the surface which is not in contact with the liquid crystal layer <b>130</b>, thereby polarizing the light transmitting through the upper substrate <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">For the stereoscopic image mode, the left-eye image of the stereoscopic image is displayed on the left-eye displaying area (LDA) of the display panel <b>100</b>, and the right-eye image of the stereoscopic image is displayed on the right-eye displaying area (RDA) of the display panel <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The light-guiding member <b>200</b> is formed on the upper substrate <b>120</b> while being overlapped with the interface between the left-eye displaying area (LDA) and the right-eye displaying area (RDA), whereby the light-guiding member <b>200</b> reflects the light incident at a predetermined angle. The light-guiding member <b>200</b> reflects the light which is transmitted at a predetermined angle via the left-eye displaying area (LDA) and is advanced toward the upper side of the right-eye displaying area (RDA), whereby the reflected light is advanced toward the upper side of the left-eye displaying area (LDA). Also, the light-guiding member <b>200</b> reflects the light which is transmitted at a predetermined angle via the right-eye displaying area (RDA) and is advanced toward the upper side of the left-eye displaying area (LDA), whereby the reflected light is advanced toward the upper side of the right-eye displaying area (RDA).</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Also, the light-guiding member <b>200</b> collects the light passing through the left-eye displaying area (LDA) and the right-eye displaying area (RDA), to thereby improve the luminance of the stereoscopic image.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">As shown in (a) of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the light-guiding member <b>200</b> according to the first embodiment of the present invention is hollowly formed from the upper surface of the upper substrate <b>120</b>, wherein the light-guiding member <b>200</b> has a triangular-shaped or V-shaped cross section. Preferably, a depth (d) of the light-guiding member <b>200</b> is more than a half of an entire thickness of the upper substrate <b>120</b>. Preferably, a width (W) of the light-guiding member <b>200</b> may be the same as or larger than a width of the black matrix (BM), but not necessarily. For optimizing efficiency of the device, the depth and width of the light-guiding member <b>200</b> may be appropriately changed based on the size and structure of the display panel <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">As shown in (b) of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the light-guiding member <b>200</b> according to the second embodiment of the present invention is hollowly formed from the upper surface of the upper substrate <b>120</b>, wherein the light-guiding member <b>200</b> has a square-shaped cross section. Preferably, a depth (d) of the light-guiding member <b>200</b> is more than a half of an entire thickness of the upper substrate <b>120</b>. Preferably, a width (W) of the light-guiding member <b>200</b> may be the same as or larger than a width of the black matrix (BM), but not necessarily. For optimizing efficiency of the device, the depth and width of the light-guiding member <b>200</b> may be appropriately changed based on the size and structure of the display panel <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">As shown in (c) of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the light-guiding member <b>200</b> according to the third embodiment of the present invention is hollowly formed from the upper surface of the upper substrate <b>120</b>, wherein the light-guiding member <b>200</b> has a rectangle-shaped cross section. Preferably, a depth (d) of the light-guiding member <b>200</b> is more than a half of an entire thickness of the upper substrate <b>120</b>. Preferably, a width (W) of the light-guiding member <b>200</b> may be smaller than a width of the black matrix (BM).</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The light-guiding member <b>200</b> may be hollowly formed from the surface of the upper substrate <b>120</b> by a physical etching process or chemical etching process using a mask (not shown). At this time, the physical etching process may be a sand-blasting process; and the chemical etching process may be a dry-etching process or wet-etching process. A process for forming the light-guiding member <b>200</b> is carried out before a process for adhering the upper polarizing plate <b>124</b> after a process for bonding the lower substrate <b>110</b> and the upper substrate <b>120</b> to each other.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, the optical-axis changing member <b>300</b> divides the light incident via the left-eye displaying area (LDA) and right-eye displaying area (RDA) defined in the display panel <b>100</b> into the left-eye image and right-eye image having the different optical axes. For this, the optical-axis changing member <b>300</b> may comprise a base member <b>310</b>, a left-eye retarder <b>320</b>L, a right-eye retarder <b>320</b>R, and a reflection preventing film <b>330</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The base member <b>310</b> may be formed of glass or film with a predetermined thickness.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The left-eye retarder <b>320</b>L is formed on a rear surface of the base member <b>310</b> while being corresponding to the left-eye displaying area (LDA) defined in the display panel <b>100</b>. The left-eye retarder <b>320</b>L is positioned on the upper polarizing plate <b>124</b>. The left-eye retarder <b>320</b>L changes the optical axis of the light which is incident via the left-eye displaying area (LDA), whereby the left-eye image of the stereoscopic image is provided to the viewer's left eye for the stereoscopic image mode. At this time, the left-eye retarder <b>320</b>L may change the light incident via the left-eye displaying area (LDA) to the left-handed polarized light.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The right-eye retarder <b>320</b>R is formed on the rear surface of the base member <b>310</b> while being corresponding to the right-eye displaying area (RDA) defined in the display panel <b>100</b> and being in parallel to the left-eye retarder <b>320</b>L. At this time, the right-eye retarder <b>320</b>R is formed between each of the left-eye retarders <b>320</b>L, and is positioned on the upper polarizing plate <b>124</b>. The right-eye retarder <b>320</b>R changes the optical axis of the light which is incident via the right-eye displaying area (RDA), whereby the right-eye image of the stereoscopic image is provided to the viewer's right eye for the stereoscopic image mode. At this time, the right-eye retarder <b>320</b>R may change the light incident via the right-eye displaying area (RDA) to the right-handed polarized light.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The reflection preventing film <b>330</b> may be adhered to or coated onto the front surface of the base member <b>310</b>, thereby decreasing the surface reflection, and removing the light interference or scattering by the reflected light.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The aforementioned optical-axis changing member <b>300</b> may be adhered to the front surface of the upper polarizing plate <b>124</b> by an adhesive material (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, in case of the stereoscopic image display device according to the first embodiment of the present invention, the light-guiding member <b>200</b> reflects the right-eye image (RI), which is transmitted via the right-eye displaying area (RDA) and is then advanced toward the adjacent left-eye retarder <b>320</b>L, toward the right-eye retarder <b>320</b>R; and simultaneously reflects the left-eye image (LI), which is transmitted via the left-eye displaying area (LDA) and is then advanced toward the adjacent right-eye retarder <b>320</b>R, toward the left-eye retarder <b>320</b>L.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">In the stereoscopic image display device according to the first embodiment of the present invention, the light-guiding member <b>200</b> is formed on the upper substrate <b>120</b> while being overlapped with the interface between the left-eye displaying area (LDA) and the right-eye displaying area (RDA), thereby improving picture quality by preventing crosstalk in the left-eye image and right-eye image of the stereoscopic image, and realizing the wide vertical (up-and-down) viewing angle of the stereoscopic image. Generally, the vertical viewing angle of the stereoscopic image is generally determined by an interval between the rear surface of the upper substrate <b>120</b> and the retarders <b>320</b>L and <b>320</b>R, and the width of the black matrix (BM), which is typically about 30&#xb0;. Meanwhile, the vertical viewing angle of the stereoscopic image according to the present invention is determined by the width of the black matrix (BM), and an interval (D) between the rear surface of the upper substrate <b>120</b> and the light-guiding member <b>200</b> by the light collection of the light-guiding member <b>200</b>. Accordingly, the vertical viewing angle of the stereoscopic image according to the present invention may be increased depending on the depth (d) of the light-guiding member <b>200</b>, which might be above 60&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross section view illustrating a stereoscopic image display device according to the second embodiment of the present invention, which is a cross section view along A-A&#x2032; of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the stereoscopic image display device according to the second embodiment of the present invention comprises a display panel <b>100</b>, a light-guiding member <b>200</b>, an optical-axis changing member <b>300</b>, and a light reflecting layer <b>400</b>. Except a structure of the light reflecting layer <b>400</b>, the stereoscopic image display device according to the second embodiment of the present invention is identical in structure to the stereoscopic image display device according to the first embodiment of the present invention, whereby a detailed explanation for the same parts <b>100</b>, <b>200</b>, and <b>300</b> will be omitted, and a same reference numbers will be used throughout the drawings to refer to the same or like parts.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The light reflecting layer <b>400</b> is formed inside the light-guiding member <b>200</b> which is hollowly formed from an upper surface of an upper substrate <b>120</b>, wherein the light-guiding member <b>200</b> has a triangular-shaped or quadrangle-shaped cross section. Preferably, the light reflecting layer <b>400</b> is formed of a material with high reflectance, for example, aluminum or silicon. The light reflecting layer <b>400</b> reflects the light transmitting through the light-guiding member <b>200</b> toward the targeted retarder <b>320</b>L or <b>320</b>R, whereby the picture quality and luminance of the stereoscopic image can be improved owing to the high reflection efficiency in the light-guiding member <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6A to 6D</figref> illustrate a method for manufacturing the stereoscopic image display device according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">A method for manufacturing the stereoscopic image display device according to the embodiment of the present invention will be described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6A to 6D</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">First, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref>, the display panel <b>100</b> is prepared, wherein the display panel <b>100</b> comprises the lower substrate <b>110</b> and the upper substrate <b>120</b> which are bonded to each other, and are provided with the left-eye displaying area (LDA) for displaying the left-eye image of stereoscopic image, and the right-eye displaying area (RDA) for displaying the right-eye image of stereoscopic image. On the lower substrate <b>110</b>, there is the thin film transistor array <b>112</b> which includes the plurality of gate lines (not shown), the plurality of data lines (not shown), and the plurality of pixels (not shown). On the rear surface of the upper substrate <b>120</b>, there is a color filter array which includes the plurality of color filters (CF) corresponding to the respective pixels of pixel regions defined by the black matrix (BM); and the overcoat layer formed flat at a predetermined thickness to cover the black matrix (BM) and the plurality of color filters (CF). The lower substrate <b>110</b> and the upper substrate <b>120</b> are bonded to each other with the liquid crystal layer <b>130</b> interposed therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">Then, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref>, the light-guiding member <b>200</b> is formed in the upper substrate <b>120</b>, and more particularly, along the interface between the left-eye displaying area (LDA) and the right-eye displaying area (RDA). At this time, as shown in (a) to (c) of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the light-guiding member <b>200</b> is hollowly formed from the upper surface of the upper substrate <b>120</b>, wherein the light-guiding member <b>200</b> has the triangular-shaped or quadrangle-shaped cross section. At this time, the light-guiding member <b>200</b> is hollowly formed in such a manner that the depth (d) of the light-guiding member <b>200</b> is more than a half of an entire thickness of the upper substrate <b>120</b>. The light-guiding member <b>200</b> may be hollowly formed from the surface of the upper substrate <b>120</b> by the physical etching process or chemical etching process using the mask (not shown). At this time, the physical etching process may be the sand-blasting process; and the chemical etching process may be the dry-etching process or wet-etching process.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6C</figref>, the lower polarizing plate <b>114</b> is adhered to the rear surface of the lower substrate <b>110</b>; and the upper polarizing plate <b>124</b> is adhered to the front surface of the upper substrate <b>120</b> with the light-guiding member <b>200</b> formed therein.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6D</figref>, the optical-axis changing member <b>300</b> is provided on the upper substrate <b>120</b>. At this time, the optical-axis changing member <b>300</b> may comprise the base member <b>310</b>, the left-eye retarder <b>320</b>L, the right-eye retarder <b>320</b>R, and the reflection preventing film <b>330</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The base member <b>310</b> may be formed of glass or film with the predetermined thickness.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">The left-eye retarder <b>320</b>L is formed on the rear surface of the base member <b>310</b> while being corresponding to the left-eye displaying area (LDA). The left-eye retarder <b>320</b>L changes the optical axis of the light which is incident via the left-eye displaying area (LDA), that is, makes the leftward polarization, whereby the left-eye image of the stereoscopic image is provided to the viewer's left eye for the stereoscopic image mode.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The right-eye retarder <b>320</b>R is formed between each of the left-eye retarders <b>320</b>L to be corresponding to the right-eye displaying area (RDA) while being in parallel with the left-eye retarder <b>320</b>L. The right-eye retarder <b>320</b>R changes the optical axis of the light which is incident via the right-eye displaying area (RDA), that is, makes the rightward polarization, whereby the right-eye image of the stereoscopic image is provided to the viewer's right eye for the stereoscopic image mode.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">The reflection preventing film <b>330</b> may be adhered to or coated onto the front surface of the base member <b>310</b>, thereby decreasing the surface reflection, and removing the light interference or scattering by the reflected light.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">The aforementioned optical-axis changing member <b>300</b> may be adhered to the front surface of the upper polarizing plate <b>124</b> by the adhesive material (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">For the manufacturing method of the stereoscopic image display device according to the embodiment of the present invention, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the process for forming the light-guiding member <b>200</b> in the upper substrate <b>120</b> may further comprise forming the light reflecting layer <b>400</b> inside the light-guiding member <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">The light reflecting layer <b>400</b> is formed inside the light-guiding member <b>200</b> which is hollowly formed from the upper surface of the upper substrate <b>120</b>, wherein the light-guiding member <b>200</b> has the triangular-shaped or quadrangle-shaped cross section. Preferably, the light reflecting layer <b>400</b> is formed of the material with high reflectance, for example, aluminum or silicon. The light reflecting layer <b>400</b> reflects the light transmitting through the light-guiding member <b>200</b> toward the targeted retarder <b>320</b>L or <b>320</b>R, whereby the picture quality and luminance of the stereoscopic image can be improved owing to the high reflection efficiency in the light-guiding member <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">For the manufacturing method of the stereoscopic image display device according to the embodiment of the present invention, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the aforementioned upper polarizing plate <b>124</b> is adhered to the front surface of the upper substrate <b>120</b> with the light-guiding member <b>200</b> and the light reflecting layer <b>400</b> formed therein.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">For the above explanation of the stereoscopic image display device according to the embodiment of the present invention and the method for manufacturing the same, the light-guiding member <b>200</b> is formed in the upper substrate <b>120</b> of the liquid crystal display panel <b>100</b>, but not necessarily. However, the light-guiding member <b>200</b> may be formed in an upper substrate of another flat-type display panel instead of the liquid crystal display panel <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">The stereoscopic image display device according to the embodiment of the present invention may be used for a mobile communication terminal, a notebook computer, a monitor, a television, a public display, and etc.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">In the above stereoscopic image display device according to the present invention, the light-guiding member <b>200</b> is formed in the upper substrate <b>120</b> while being overlapped with the interface between the left-eye displaying area (LDA) and the right-eye displaying area (RDA).</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">This enables to improve the picture quality by preventing the crosstalk of the left-eye image and right-eye image of the stereoscopic image through the light reflection of the light-guiding member <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">Also, it is possible to realize the wide vertical (up-and-down) viewing angle and good luminance of the stereoscopic image through the light collection of the light-guiding member <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">It will be apparent to those skilled in the art that various modifications and variations can be made in the present invention without departing from the spirit or scope of the inventions. Thus, it is intended that the present invention covers the modifications and variations of this invention provided they come within the scope of the appended claims and their equivalents.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A stereoscopic image display device comprising:
<claim-text>a display panel including lower and upper substrates which are bonded to each other, and are provided with a left-eye displaying area (LDA) for displaying a left-eye image of stereoscopic image, and a right-eye displaying area (RDA) for displaying a right-eye image of stereoscopic image; a light-guiding member formed in the upper substrate and overlapped with an interface between the left-eye displaying area (LDA) and the right-eye displaying area (RDA) for preventing crosstalk of left-eye image and right-eye image; and an optical-axis changing member formed on the upper substrate, wherein the optical axis changing member includes a left-eye retarder corresponding to the left-eye displaying area, and a right-eye retarder corresponding to the right-eye displaying area, wherein, the upper substrate of the display panel comprises a black matrix defining pixel regions for displaying the left-eye image and the right-eye image, and the light-guiding member is hollowly formed from the upper surface of the upper substrate to be overlapped with the black matrix in such a manner that a thickness of the light-guiding member is more than a half of an entire thickness of the upper substrate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The stereoscopic image display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the light-guiding member reflects the right-eye image, which is transmitted through the right-eye displaying area and is advanced to the left-eye retarder, toward the right-eye retarder; and also reflects the left-eye image, which is transmitted through the left-eye displaying area and is advanced to the right-eye retarder, toward the left-eye retarder.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The stereoscopic image display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein,
<claim-text>the upper substrate of the display panel comprises a black matrix defining pixel regions for displaying the left-eye image and the right-eye image, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the light-guiding member having a triangular-shaped or quadrangle-shaped cross section is hollowly formed from the upper surface of the upper substrate to be overlapped with the black matrix.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The stereoscopic image display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a light reflecting layer formed in the light-guiding member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The stereoscopic image display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the light reflecting layer is formed of aluminum or silicon.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The stereoscopic image display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the display panel further comprises:
<claim-text>an upper polarizing plate adhered to a front surface of the upper substrate to cover the light-guiding member; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lower polarizing plate adhered to a rear surface of the lower substrate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The stereoscopic image display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the optical-axis changing member comprises:
<claim-text>a base member of glass or film with a predetermined thickness; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the left-eye retarder and right-eye retarder which are alternately formed on the rear surface of the base member facing the upper polarizing plate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The stereoscopic image display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the optical-axis changing member further comprises a reflection preventing film on the front surface of the base member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A method for manufacturing a stereoscopic image display device comprising:
<claim-text>preparing a display panel including lower and upper substrates which are bonded to each other, and are provided with a left-eye displaying area (LDA) for displaying a left-eye image of stereoscopic image, and a right-eye displaying area (RDA) for displaying a right eye image of stereoscopic image; forming a light-guiding member overlapped with an interface between the left-eye displaying area (LDA) and the right-eye displaying area (RDA) in the upper substrate of the display panel for preventing crosstalk of left-eye image and right-eye image; adhering an upper polarizing plate to a front surface of the upper substrate of the display panel including the light-guiding member; and forming an optical-axis changing member on the upper substrate of the display panel, wherein the optical-axis changing member includes a left-eye retarder corresponding to the left-eye displaying area, and a right-eye retarder corresponding to the right-eye displaying area, wherein, the upper substrate of the display panel comprises a black matrix defining pixel regions for displaying the left-eye image and the right-eye image, and the light-guiding member is hollowly formed from the upper surface of the upper substrate to be overlapped with the black matrix in such a manner that a thickness of the light-guiding member is more than a half of an entire thickness of the upper substrate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein,
<claim-text>the upper substrate of the display panel comprises a black matrix defining pixel regions for displaying the left-eye image and the right-eye image, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the light-guiding member having a triangular-shaped or quadrangle-shaped cross section is hollowly formed from the upper surface of the upper substrate to be overlapped with the black matrix.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the light-guiding member is formed by a physical etching process or chemical etching process using a mask.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the process for forming the light-guiding member in the upper substrate comprises forming a light reflecting layer of aluminum or silicon in the light-guiding member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A stereoscopic image display device comprising:
<claim-text>a display panel including lower and upper substrates which are bonded to each other, and are provided with a left-eye displaying area (LDA) for displaying a left-eye image of stereoscopic image, and a right-eye displaying area (RDA) for displaying a right-eye image of stereoscopic image; a light-guiding member formed in the upper substrate and overlapped with an interface between the left-eye displaying area (LDA) and the right-eye displaying area (RDA) for preventing crosstalk of left-eye image and right-eye image; and an optical-axis changing member formed on the upper substrate, wherein the optical axis changing member includes a left-eye retarder corresponding to the left-eye displaying area, and a right-eye retarder corresponding to the right-eye displaying area, wherein, the upper substrate of the display panel comprises a black matrix defining pixel regions for displaying the left-eye image and the right-eye image, and the light-guiding member having a triangular-shaped or quadrangle-shaped cross section is hollowly formed from the upper surface of the upper substrate to be overlapped with the black matrix.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A method for manufacturing a stereoscopic image display device comprising:
<claim-text>preparing a display panel including lower and upper substrates which are bonded to each other, and are provided with a left-eye displaying area (LDA) for displaying a left-eye image of stereoscopic image, and a right-eye displaying area (RDA) for displaying a right eye image of stereoscopic image; forming a light-guiding member overlapped with an interface between the left-eye displaying area (LDA) and the right-eye displaying area (RDA) in the upper substrate of the display panel for preventing crosstalk of left-eye image and right-eye image; adhering an upper polarizing plate to a front surface of the upper substrate of the display panel including the light-guiding member; and forming an optical-axis changing member on the upper substrate of the display panel, wherein the optical-axis changing member includes a left-eye retarder corresponding to the left-eye displaying area, and a right-eye retarder corresponding to the right-eye displaying area, wherein, the upper substrate of the display panel comprises a black matrix defining pixel regions for displaying the left-eye image and the right-eye image, and the light-guiding member having a triangular-shaped or quadrangle-shaped cross section is hollowly formed from the upper surface of the upper substrate to be overlapped with the black matrix.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
