<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626402-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626402</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12896204</doc-number>
<date>20101001</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10 2009 047 343</doc-number>
<date>20091201</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>361</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>70</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>701 50</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Drive arrangement and method for a work machine with two internal combustion engines</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4161991</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>van der Lely</name>
<date>19790700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>180 537</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0177345</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Severinsky et al.</name>
<date>20090700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>701 22</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0242301</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>McClanahan et al.</name>
<date>20091000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0082192</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hofbauer</name>
<date>20100400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>701 22</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>AU</country>
<doc-number>6163380</doc-number>
<date>19820200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>6949295</doc-number>
<date>19691200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>3741891</doc-number>
<date>19890600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>102008009447</doc-number>
<date>20090800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1640201</doc-number>
<date>20060300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1731345</doc-number>
<date>20061200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1818524</doc-number>
<date>20070800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00012">
<othercit>European Search Report, Mar. 1, 2011, 4 Pages.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>3</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110246030</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20111006</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Jueptner</last-name>
<first-name>Detlef</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kleinblittersdorf</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Jueptner</last-name>
<first-name>Detlef</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kleinblittersdorf</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Deere &#x26; Company</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Moline</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Tarcza</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas</first-name>
<department>3663</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Alharbi</last-name>
<first-name>Adam</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A drive arrangement for a work machine is provided, having a first internal combustion engine and a second internal combustion engine. A controller is allocated to the internal combustion engines, and a drive train is selectively connected to both internal combustion engines for driving elements of the work machine. In the case of a double-engine mode, the controller specifies a maximum single power (P<b>1</b>) of the internal combustion engines that is less than the maximum power (P<b>2</b>) that can be specified by the controller for an internal combustion engine operating in the single-engine mode.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="133.27mm" wi="238.25mm" file="US08626402-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="237.24mm" wi="132.42mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626402-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="239.01mm" wi="164.93mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626402-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="214.55mm" wi="173.48mm" file="US08626402-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The invention relates to a drive arrangement for a work machine having a first internal combustion engine and a second internal combustion engine. A controller is allocated to the internal combustion engines. A drive train can be connected to the two internal combustion engines for driving elements of the work machine. An associated method is also described.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">In recent years, self-propelled agricultural harvesting machines have been equipped with more and more powerful internal combustion engines that can currently output, in the case of forage harvesters, up to 800 kW. Due to the relatively small number of such powerful engines produced, these engines are relatively expensive and usually more expensive than two internal combustion engines that each have half the power. Furthermore, the entire power of the engine is not always needed&#x2014;for example, it is usually not needed during transport on a street or while mowing. This leads to poorer efficiency of the engine than during full-load operation, which is why it was proposed, e.g., in European Patent Application EP 1 640 201 A1 to equip a self-propelled harvesting machine with two internal combustion engines of which one can be added to the other internal combustion engine for handling greater power requirements. Consequently, the first internal combustion engine is always in operation, while the second internal combustion engine is turned on only when needed. In the single-engine mode, the power of an individual internal combustion engine is available, and in the double-engine mode, the power of both internal combustion engines is available, i.e., twice the power. The maximum available power from the individual internal combustion engines is the same in both operating modes. Similar arrangements are also used in airplanes and buses, e.g. German Patent Documents DE 69 49 295 U1 and DE 37 41 891 A1, respectively. The mentioned harvesting machines are also available on the market with internal combustion engines of different powers, wherein the first internal combustion engine has the greater power.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">There are certain operating conditions in which the power of a single internal combustion engine is not sufficient, for example, while harvesting a relatively thin crop or while in transport with a towed harvesting attachment when a steep incline is to be climbed. One could indeed equip the work machine with one or two internal combustion engines of greater power, but in the case of the double-engine mode, this would again have the result that the other components of the work machine, in the case of a harvesting machine, for example, the drive train for driving crop-processing devices and the devices themselves would have to be designed larger. In many cases, however, this measure is undesirable for reasons of cost and/or weight. The known solution with a larger primary engine and a smaller secondary engine that can be connected is disadvantageous in so far as the primary engine experiences significantly greater wear.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The problem forming the basis of the invention is seen in improving a drive arrangement comprising two internal combustion engines for a work machine to the extent that, in the single-engine mode, power sufficient for many applications is provided, but upper power limits are observed in the double-engine mode.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">A drive arrangement for a work machine comprises a first internal combustion engine, a second internal combustion engine, a controller allocated to the internal combustion engines, and a drive train that can be connected to both internal combustion engines for driving elements of the work machine. In the double-engine mode, the controller specifies a maximum single power of the internal combustion engines that is less than the maximum power specified by the controller for an internal combustion engine operated in the single-engine mode. In one embodiment, the maximum power of an internal combustion engine in the single-engine mode could be, for example, 500 kW, while it equals only 400 kW in the double-engine mode. Consequently, in the double-engine mode, there is an overall maximum of 800 kW available.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In this way the power in the double-engine mode is limited at the top to a value that lies below the sum of the maximum individual powers of the internal combustion engines in the single-engine mode. Therefore, the drive train of the work machine and its driven elements are designed for only this reduced power. In the case of the single-engine mode, however, a power is available that is sufficient for many (and more than in the prior art) applications.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Advantageously, both internal combustion engines could be used alternately in the single-engine mode, in order to be able to distribute the wear on them as uniformly as possible. For this purpose, they are each connected to the drive train by way of a detachable coupling. However, an arrangement with a continuously running first internal combustion engine and a second internal combustion engine that can be connected to the drive train is also possible.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The invention can be used on any work machine, for example, construction machines, such as diggers or wheel loaders, agricultural tractors or harvesting machines, in particular, combine harvesters, forage harvesters, or cotton harvesters.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">A detailed description of an embodiment of the invention is set forth below with reference to the accompanying drawings wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic side view of a work machine in the form of a forage harvester;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic top view of the drive arrangement of the work machine of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>; and,</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a flow chart according to which the controller controls the internal combustion engine.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a work machine <b>10</b> is shown as a kind of self-propelled forage harvester in a schematic side view. The work machine <b>10</b> is mounted on a frame <b>12</b> that is carried by front, driven wheels <b>14</b> and steerable, rear wheels <b>16</b>. The work machine <b>10</b> is operated from a driver's cab <b>18</b> from which a harvesting attachment <b>20</b> in the form of a pick-up can be seen. The crop, e.g., grass or the like, picked up from the ground by means of the harvesting attachment <b>20</b> is fed by means of an in-take auger <b>22</b> with prepress rollers that are arranged within an in-take housing <b>24</b> on the front side of the work machine <b>10</b> to a chopping drum <b>26</b> that is arranged underneath the driver's cab <b>18</b> and chops the crop into small pieces and discharges it to a conveying device <b>28</b>. The material exits the work machine <b>10</b>, via a discharge chute <b>30</b> that can rotate about an approximately vertical axis and can be adjusted in its slope, to a transport vehicle traveling alongside. It should be noted here that in the description below directional information, such as side, bottom, and top, refer to the direction of forward motion V of the work machine <b>10</b> that moves to the right in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a top view of the drive arrangement of the work machine <b>10</b>. In the rear region of the work machine <b>10</b>, there are two (first and second) internal combustion engines <b>36</b>, <b>38</b> respectively, arranged behind the rear axle, in particular, in the form of diesel engines arranged laterally one next to the other. The maximum powers of the internal combustion engines <b>36</b>, <b>38</b> are advantageously identical, although internal combustion engines <b>36</b>, <b>38</b> of different powers could also be used. The internal combustion engines <b>36</b>, <b>38</b> extend in the forward direction of the work machine <b>10</b> up to approximately the rear end of the frame <b>12</b> and comprise first and second crankshafts <b>40</b>, <b>42</b> respectively, that extend forward from the housings of the internal combustion engines <b>36</b>, <b>38</b>. The crankshafts <b>40</b>, <b>42</b> each drive a (first and second) longitudinal shaft <b>44</b>, <b>46</b> extending horizontally and forward.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">While operating, the first internal combustion engine <b>36</b> drives, with its crankshaft <b>40</b>, a first longitudinal shaft <b>44</b> that is connected to the input side of a first coupling <b>56</b>. The output side of the first coupling <b>56</b> is connected by means of a fourth longitudinal shaft <b>104</b> to a first conical gear wheel <b>48</b> of a first angular gear <b>52</b>. The fourth longitudinal shaft <b>104</b> also drives, by means of gear wheels <b>70</b>, <b>72</b> and a fifth longitudinal shaft <b>76</b>, a pump assembly <b>74</b> that comprises a hydraulic pump for driving hydraulic motors for the propulsion of the harvesting machine, a steering pump, a hydraulic pump for driving hydraulic motors for the harvesting attachment <b>22</b>, and a hydraulic pump for feeding oil to the controller of the hydrostatic drive for the propulsion of the work machine <b>10</b>. It is also conceivable to drive other continuously driven elements, such as an electrical generator and/or a blower drive for feeding cooling air to the internal combustion engines <b>36</b>, <b>38</b> by means of one of the gear wheels <b>70</b>, <b>72</b> or an intermediate gear wheel (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The second conical gear wheel <b>50</b> of the first angular gear <b>52</b> is connected to a first section <b>58</b> of a transverse shaft <b>58</b>, <b>80</b>, <b>90</b> that is connected, in turn, via a universal-joint drive shaft <b>92</b> to a second section <b>90</b> of the transverse shaft <b>58</b>, <b>80</b>, <b>90</b> that extends up to a second conical gear wheel <b>68</b> of the second angular gear <b>64</b>. During operation, the second internal combustion engine <b>38</b> drives, with its crankshaft <b>42</b>, a second longitudinal shaft <b>46</b> that is connected to the input side of a second coupling <b>60</b>. The output side of the second coupling <b>60</b> is connected via a third longitudinal shaft <b>62</b> to the first conical gear wheel <b>66</b> of the second angular gear <b>64</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The internal combustion engines <b>36</b>, <b>38</b> are mounted separately from each other on the frame <b>12</b> or a secondary frame, usually by means of damping elements. The associated couplings <b>56</b> or <b>60</b> and angular gears <b>52</b>, <b>64</b> are also mounted on their housings. The universal-joint drive shaft <b>92</b> allows for the compensation of possible tolerances of the positions of the internal combustion engines <b>36</b>, <b>38</b> and the angular gears <b>52</b>, <b>64</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The second section <b>90</b> of the transverse shaft <b>58</b>, <b>80</b>, <b>90</b> and the second conical gear wheel <b>68</b> of the second angular gear <b>64</b> are connected to an outer section <b>80</b> of the transverse shaft <b>58</b>, <b>80</b>, <b>90</b> that extends through a hollow shaft <b>106</b> connected to the belt pulley <b>82</b> on the side of the belt pulley <b>82</b> away from the angular gears <b>52</b>, <b>64</b>, and is connected there to a third coupling <b>78</b>. The belt pulley <b>82</b> is wrapped around a drive belt <b>84</b> that also wraps around a belt pulley <b>86</b> for driving the auger device <b>28</b> and a belt pulley <b>88</b> for driving the chopping drum <b>26</b>. Instead of or in addition to the third coupling <b>78</b>, the drive train of the chopping drum <b>26</b> and the auger device <b>28</b> can also be set in motion or stopped by a mechanism for tensioning and loosening the drive belt <b>84</b>. The third coupling <b>78</b> is connected on the output side to the hollow shaft <b>106</b> that also drives, on the side of the belt pulley <b>82</b> facing the angular gears <b>52</b>, <b>64</b>, via gear wheels <b>96</b>, <b>108</b>, and <b>100</b>, a hydraulic pump <b>102</b> that is used for driving a hydraulic motor (not shown) for driving the take-in auger <b>22</b>. The third coupling <b>78</b> allows the drive belt <b>84</b> and with it the chopping drum <b>26</b> and the auger device <b>28</b> to be turned on and off. The gear wheels <b>96</b>, <b>108</b>, and <b>100</b> could be mounted within a housing that is mounted on the housing of the second angular gear <b>64</b>. In contrast, the gear wheels <b>70</b> and <b>72</b> are advantageously integrated within the housing of the first angular gear <b>52</b> and the first coupling <b>56</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">A suitable controller <b>94</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) is used in the case of both embodiments for connecting and separating the internal combustion engines <b>36</b>, <b>38</b> from the drive train. The controller <b>94</b> is connected to the couplings <b>56</b>, <b>60</b>, and <b>78</b> and to engine controllers <b>110</b>, <b>112</b> of the internal combustion engines <b>36</b> and <b>38</b>. In addition to the stoppage of the internal combustion engines <b>36</b>, <b>38</b>, three operating modes are possible, as shown below with reference to the flow chart of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. After the start in Step <b>200</b>, in Step <b>202</b> it is queried whether a double-engine mode is required or desired. This is selected in the case of greater power requirements, for example, while harvesting corn with a mowing attachment (not shown) mounted instead of the pick-up <b>20</b>, and Step <b>204</b> follows, according to which both internal combustion engines <b>36</b>, <b>38</b> are running and the couplings <b>56</b> and <b>60</b> are closed. The third coupling <b>78</b> is used in a known way to turn on and off the auger device <b>28</b> and the chopping drum <b>26</b> when needed, wherein a suitable interface <b>98</b> (e.g., switch) is connected to the controller <b>94</b>. In addition, the controller <b>94</b> instructs the engine controllers <b>110</b>, <b>112</b> to let the internal combustion engines <b>36</b> and <b>38</b> each run at a maximum power P<b>1</b>. If the two internal combustion engines <b>36</b>, <b>38</b> are of the same type and the same maximum power, the maximum power P<b>1</b> commanded to each of them is the same magnitude. If they are different, different maximum powers P<b>1</b> can be commanded to them.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In the case of lower power requirements, e.g., for harvesting a swath by means of the pick-up <b>20</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> or when driving on a street or when, while harvesting corn, only individual rows at the edge of the field are to be harvested, in Step <b>206</b> that follows Step <b>202</b>, if no double-engine mode is provided, then only one of the internal combustion engines <b>36</b> or <b>38</b> is needed, while the other internal combustion engine <b>38</b> or <b>36</b> is stopped. The coupling <b>60</b> or <b>56</b> allocated to the unneeded internal combustion engine <b>38</b> or <b>36</b> is then opened, while the other coupling <b>56</b> or <b>60</b> is closed and also drives the pump assembly <b>74</b>. In addition, the controller <b>94</b> instructs the engine controller <b>110</b> or <b>112</b> of the running internal combustion engine <b>36</b> or <b>38</b> to let the running internal combustion engine <b>36</b> or <b>38</b> to run at a maximum power P<b>2</b>. The maximum power P<b>2</b> in Step <b>206</b> is greater than the maximum power P<b>1</b> in Step <b>204</b>. If the two internal combustion engines <b>36</b>, <b>38</b> are of the same type and the same maximum power, then the maximum power P<b>2</b> commanded to each of them is the same magnitude. If they are different, different maximum powers P<b>2</b> can be commanded to them.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Then Step <b>202</b> follows again. Consequently, if both internal combustion engines <b>36</b> and <b>38</b> are needed later, the stationary internal combustion engine <b>38</b> or <b>36</b> is started up, brought to the rotational speed of the running internal combustion engine <b>36</b> or <b>38</b>, and the associated coupling <b>60</b> or <b>56</b> is closed. It would also be possible to close the associated coupling <b>60</b> or <b>56</b> for starting up the stationary internal combustion engine <b>38</b> or <b>36</b> and to start it in this way.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">An internal combustion engine <b>36</b> or <b>38</b> can be connected to or disconnected from the drive train by an operator input by means of the interface <b>98</b> or automatically by the controller <b>94</b>, e.g., based on load-sensing equipment of the internal combustion engines <b>36</b> and/or <b>38</b> (for example, with reference to its rotational speed) or on a torque sensor in the drive train. It is also conceivable to automatically turn off one of the internal combustion engines <b>36</b>, <b>38</b> by the controller <b>94</b> when a street/field mode switch of the interface <b>98</b> is located in the street mode position and to automatically turn it on when the street/field mode switch is located in the field-mode position and an automatic harvesting attachment detector (see European Patent Application EP 0 377 163 A or German Patent Document DE 199 49 994 A) signals that a corn-harvesting attachment is mounted, while one of the internal combustion engines <b>36</b>, <b>38</b> always remains turned off when a harvesting attachment <b>20</b> in the form of a pick up (as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) is detected. In the single-engine mode, the controller <b>94</b> uses both internal combustion engines <b>36</b>, <b>38</b> alternately (in particular, with reference to their operating hours or the consumed fuel or the delivered kWh), in order to keep their wear approximately equal.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In the double-engine mode, the maximum power to be output by the internal combustion engines <b>36</b>, <b>38</b> is less than in the single-engine mode. Therefore, in the single-engine mode, in the case of internal combustion engines <b>36</b>, <b>38</b> of the same type, more than half of the maximum total power is available, which increases the number of actions that can be served in the single-engine mode, but makes it unnecessary to adapt the drive train to a greater maximum power in the double-engine mode.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Having described the preferred embodiment, it will become apparent that various modifications can be made without departing from the scope of the invention as defined in the accompanying claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A drive arrangement for a self-propelled agricultural harvesting machine, the work machine having a first internal combustion engine, a second internal combustion engine, a controller allocated to both the first and second internal combustion engines, and a drive train that can be connected to both internal combustion engines for driving elements of the work machine:
<claim-text>wherein in a double-engine mode the controller specifies a maximum single power (P<b>1</b>) of the internal combustion engines that is less than a maximum power (P<b>2</b>) that can be specified by the controller for an internal combustion engine operating in a single-engine mode; and,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein components of the drive train are sized and adapted only for up to the maximum power (P<b>2</b>) that can be specified by the controller for an internal combustion engine operating in the single-engine mode.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A drive arrangement according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein both internal combustion engines are selectively connected to the drive train by corresponding couplings allocated to the engines.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A method for operating a drive arrangement for a self-propelled agricultural harvesting machine, wherein the drive arrangement comprises a first internal combustion engine, a second internal combustion engine, a controller allocated to the internal combustion engines, and a drive train that is selectively connected to two internal combustion engines for driving elements of the work machine, the method comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>specifying a maximum single power (P<b>1</b>) for the internal combustion engines in the case of the double-engine mode; and,</claim-text>
<claim-text>specifying, in the case of a single-engine mode, a maximum single power (P<b>2</b>) for the running internal combustion engine in the double-engine mode wherein the maximum single power (P<b>1</b>) is less than the maximum power (P<b>2</b>) in the single-engine mode. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
