<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622704-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622704</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13508875</doc-number>
<date>20101112</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10 2009 052 881</doc-number>
<date>20091113</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>18</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>416146R</main-classification>
<further-classification>416232</further-classification>
<further-classification>416231 R</further-classification>
<further-classification>416195</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e61">Gas turbine blade for a turbomachine</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3328867</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Guengant</name>
<date>19670700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3572968</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Musick et al.</name>
<date>19710300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3626568</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Silverstein et al.</name>
<date>19711200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 2988972</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4136516</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Corsmeier</name>
<date>19790100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 60 39091</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5393200</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Dinh et al.</name>
<date>19950200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6158104</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Roberts et al.</name>
<date>20001200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6883700</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kottilingam et al.</name>
<date>20050400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>228119</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7077622</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Ehrhard et al.</name>
<date>20060700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>415  9</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0116964</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Brock</name>
<date>20090500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0313822</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lee et al.</name>
<date>20091200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 298891</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>1426778</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>19691100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>2016283</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19701000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>102005030516</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20070100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1939401</doc-number>
<kind>A2</kind>
<date>20080700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00015">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2004108290</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20040400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>7</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>416146 R</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>416232</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>416231 R</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>416 96 R</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>416 97 R</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>416189</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>416195</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120230825</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120913</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Stiehler</last-name>
<first-name>Frank</first-name>
<address>
<city>Bad Liebenwerda</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Borufka</last-name>
<first-name>Hans Peter</first-name>
<address>
<city>Starnberg</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Prokopczuk</last-name>
<first-name>Patrick</first-name>
<address>
<city>Munich</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Stiehler</last-name>
<first-name>Frank</first-name>
<address>
<city>Bad Liebenwerda</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Borufka</last-name>
<first-name>Hans Peter</first-name>
<address>
<city>Starnberg</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Prokopczuk</last-name>
<first-name>Patrick</first-name>
<address>
<city>Munich</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Barlow, Josephs &#x26; Holmes, Ltd.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>MTU Aero Engines GmbH</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Munich</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Nguyen</last-name>
<first-name>Ninh H</first-name>
<department>3745</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/DE2010/001334</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20101112</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20120509</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2011/057622</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20110519</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The invention relates to a gas turbine blade (<b>10</b>), in particular a compressor blade and/or turbine blade for a turbomachine, wherein the gas turbine blade (<b>10</b>) comprises at least one receptacle (<b>18</b>) for the form-fitting arrangement of a connecting element, by means of which a mechanical load can be introduced into gas turbine blade (<b>10</b>). The invention further relates to a shrouding band segment (<b>16</b>) for arrangement on a gas turbine blade (<b>10</b>), a connection system having a gas turbine blade (<b>10</b>) and having a connecting element, a method for connecting a gas turbine blade (<b>10</b>) to a connecting element, and a rotor for a turbomachine having a rotor disk (<b>12</b>) joined to a blade ring or having a rotor ring joined to a blade ring.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="123.27mm" wi="127.76mm" file="US08622704-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="211.16mm" wi="163.07mm" file="US08622704-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="217.42mm" wi="152.57mm" file="US08622704-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The invention relates to a gas turbine blade, in particular a compressor blade and/or turbine blade, for a turbomachine. The invention further relates to a shrouding band segment for arrangement on a gas turbine blade, a connection system of the type named in the preamble of patent claim <b>10</b>, a method of the type named in the preamble of patent claim <b>12</b> for connecting a gas turbine blade to a connecting element, and a rotor of the type indicated in the preamble of patent claim <b>13</b> for a turbomachine.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">When gas turbine blades and rotor disks or rings are joined during assembly, repair or maintenance, each gas turbine blade must be positioned, moved or twisted opposite adjacent gas turbine blades and in this way can be provided with a pre-stress (so-called pre-twist). Different connecting elements or special tools exist for this purpose, by means of which an appropriate mechanical load can be introduced into the respective gas turbine blade.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Viewed as disadvantages of the known connecting elements are the following points: they are relatively expensive, they do not make possible introducing an optimal load into the gas turbine blade and, in fact, the gas turbine blade can be damaged when the load is introduced.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The problem of the present invention is to make possible an improved possibility for introducing a load into a gas turbine blade.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The problem is solved according to the invention by a gas turbine blade with the features of patent claim <b>1</b>, a shrouding band segment with the features of patent claim <b>8</b> for the arrangement on a gas turbine blade, a connection system with the features of patent claim <b>10</b>, a method with the features of patent claim <b>12</b> for connecting a gas turbine blade to a connecting element, and by a rotor with the features of patent claim <b>13</b> for a turbomachine. Advantageous embodiments of the invention are given in the respective subclaims.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">An improved possibility for introducing the load into a gas turbine blade is made possible according to the invention in that the gas turbine blade comprises at least one receptacle for the form-fitting arrangement of a connecting element, by means of which a mechanical load can be introduced into the gas turbine blade. In other words, the geometry of the gas turbine blade according to the invention is designed in such a way that the gas turbine blade has a receptacle that forms an integral interface for the form-fitting arrangement of a corresponding connecting element. Due to the integrated receptacle, the gas turbine blade and the connecting element can be engaged with one another in form-fitting manner, so that mechanical loads can be transmitted normally, i.e., at a right angle to the surfaces of the two connection partners. The connecting element, which can be designed, for example, as a tool, pin, mandrel or the like, can be introduced or plugged in very simply in a form-fitting way into the receptacle and without adversely affecting the remaining regions of the gas turbine blade, and if needed, can be detached again from the gas turbine blade in a corresponding simple way. Mechanical loads can be introduced into the gas turbine blade in a simple and flexible manner in this way without damaging the gas turbine blade. Also, the gas turbine blade can be designed in a weight-neutral or even in a weight-reduced manner and this makes possible a short tolerance chain with correspondingly high repeat precision due to the simple construction. The respective geometry of the receptacle, for example, its arrangement, depth of form-fit or edging can be selected as a function of the geometry or of the application purpose of the respective gas turbine blade.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In an advantageous embodiment of the invention, it is provided that a radially inner end region of the gas turbine blade for connecting the gas turbine blade to a rotor disk or to a rotor ring of the turbomachine and/or a radially outer end region of the gas turbine blade is (are) designed as a shrouding band segment. A simple joining of gas turbine blade and rotor disk or rotor ring is made possible by means of this type of radially inner end region. The gas turbine blade can thus be designed as a compressor blade and/or turbine blade. A radially outer end region designed as a shrouding band segment serves to attenuate blade vibrations and is particularly suitable for use of gas turbine blades in a rear turbine stage. In addition, the shrouding band segment reduces the flow around the tip of the gas turbine blade and in this way increases the efficiency of the assigned turbomachine. The shrouding band segment therefore can be basically designed in one part or in multiple parts with the gas turbine blade.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In another advantageous embodiment of the invention, it is provided that the receptacle is formed on the radially outer end region of the gas turbine blade. By forming the receptacle at the radially outer end region of the gas turbine blade, the receptacle is particularly well accessible. In this way, a corresponding connecting element, for example a tool, can be introduced into the receptacle in a correspondingly simple way, in order to load the gas turbine blade with a mechanical load.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">A weight optimization of the gas turbine blade is made possible in another embodiment such that it is formed as a hollow blade and comprises at least one hollow space.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In addition, it has been shown as advantageous that the receptacle is formed as a core outlet region of the hollow space. This makes possible a particularly space-saving arrangement of the receptacle without adversely affecting the remaining regions of the gas turbine blade.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Additional advantages result by forming the gas turbine blade in one piece with the receptacle and/or as a cast part. In this way, the gas turbine blade can be produced cost-favorably, simply and in an especially stable way mechanically.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">By precision machining or processing at least one surface region of the gas turbine blade, the actual geometry of the gas turbine blade can be completely or at least largely approximated to a theoretical geometry. For example, electrochemical drilling methods (PECM drilling) can be used for the precision processing. Alternatively or additionally, however, further mechanical and/or electrochemical erosion and/or coating methods can be provided for precision processing.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Another aspect of the invention relates to a shrouding band segment for arrangement on a gas turbine blade, in particular a gas turbine blade according to one of the preceding examples of embodiment, whereby an improved possibility for introducing a load into a gas turbine blade is made possible according to the invention in that the shrouding band segment comprises a receptacle for the form-fitting arrangement of a connecting element, by means of which a mechanical load can be introduced into the shrouding band segment. The advantages resulting therefrom can be taken from the preceding descriptions, in which advantageous embodiments of the gas turbine blade are to be viewed as advantageous embodiments of the shrouding band segment and vice versa. The shrouding band segment can be basically designed in one piece with the gas turbine blade or can be produced first as an individual part and subsequently connected to the gas turbine blade.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In an advantageous embodiment of the invention, it is provided that the shrouding band segment has two contact surfaces that are essentially Z-shaped in longitudinal section and disposed opposite one another for the attachment of corresponding contact surfaces of two other shrouding band segments. In this way, adjacent gas turbine blades, which are each provided with a shrouding band segment of this type, can support each other in pairs during the operation of an assigned turbomachine or of a rotor provided with these gas turbine blades, whereby mechanically a particularly stable shroud is created. An undesired bending or twisting of the gas turbine blade during operation is also minimized in this way.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Another aspect of the invention relates to a connection system having a gas turbine blade, in particular a compressor blade and/or turbine blade for a turbomachine, and having a connecting element, by means of which a mechanical load can be introduced into the gas turbine blade, whereby an improved possibility for introducing a load into the gas turbine blade is made possible according to the invention in that the gas turbine blade comprises a receptacle formed to correspond to the connecting element for the form-fitting arrangement of the connecting element. Due to the integrated receptacle, the gas turbine blade and the corresponding connecting element can engage with one another in a form-fitting manner, so that mechanical loads can be transmitted normally, i.e., at a right angle to the surfaces of the two connection partners. Thus a simple, detachable and damage-free loading into and/or unloading out of the gas turbine blade is possible. In this way, for example, prior to connecting it to a shaft of the turbomachine, the gas turbine blade can be provided with a so-called pre-twist very simply and without damage. The gas turbine blade can be provided with a so-called re-twist in a correspondingly simple and damage-free manner within the scope of a repair or overhaul, so that the gas turbine blade can be readjusted. Further advantages can be taken from the preceding descriptions, whereby advantageous embodiments of the gas turbine blade or of the shrouding band segment can be viewed as advantageous embodiments of the connection system and vice versa.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In an advantageous embodiment of the invention, it is provided that the receptacle is formed as a polygonal socket receptacle, especially as a hexagon socket receptacle, and the connecting element is designed as a multi-edge socket wrench, in particular, as an Allen wrench, for loading the gas turbine blade with torque. In this way, a load can be introduced into the gas turbine blade in a particularly simple and cost-favorable way, without requiring a special expensive tool. This also increases the ease of maintenance of the gas turbine blade or a turbomachine provided with it. Thus, the receptacle and the connecting element can be formed alternatively or additionally into an Inbus-like configuration, and basically also as a slotted, Pozidriv, Torx, Tri-Wing, Torq-Set or screwdriver-like bit and socket set.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Another aspect of the invention relates to a method for connecting a gas turbine blade, in particular a compressor blade and/or turbine blade for a turbomachine, to a connecting element, by means of which a mechanical load can be introduced into the gas turbine blade, whereby an improved possibility for introducing a load into the gas turbine blade is made possible according to the invention in that the connecting element is disposed in a form-fitting way in a receptacle of the gas turbine blade designed corresponding to the connecting element. Due to the integrated receptacle, the gas turbine blade and the corresponding connecting element can be arranged relative to one another in a form-fitting manner, so that mechanical loads can be transmitted normally, i.e., at a right angle to the surfaces of the two connection partners. Thus a simple, detachable and damage-free loading into and/or unloading out of the gas turbine blade is possible. Further advantages can be taken from the preceding descriptions, whereby advantageous embodiments of the gas turbine blade, of the shrouding band segment and/or of the connection system can be seen as advantageous embodiments of the method and vice versa.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Another aspect of the invention relates to a rotor for a turbomachine having a rotor disk joined to a blade ring, or having a rotor ring joined to a blade ring, whereby it is provided according to the invention that the blade ring has at least one gas turbine blade that comprises at least one receptacle for the form-fitting arrangement of a connecting element, whereby a mechanical load can be introduced into the gas turbine blade by means of the connecting element. The advantages resulting therefrom can be taken from the preceding descriptions, whereby advantageous embodiments of the gas turbine blade, of the shrouding band segment, of the connection system and/or of the method for connecting a gas turbine blade to a connecting element can be viewed as advantageous embodiments of the rotor and vice versa.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">It has thus been shown as advantageous if the rotor is designed as a blisk (&#x201c;bladed disk&#x201d;) or as a bling (&#x201c;bladed ring&#x201d;) for a compressor and/or for a turbine of a turbomachine, in particular a thermal gas turbine. A particularly high structural freedom is obtained hereby.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Further features of the invention result from the claims, the embodiment examples as well as on the basis of the drawings. The features and combinations of features named above in the description as well as the features and combinations of features named in the embodiment examples given below are applicable not only in the combination indicated in each case, but also in other combinations or in isolation without departing from the scope of the invention. Here:</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a schematic perspective view of three gas turbine blades according to the invention that are disposed on a rotor disk;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows an enlarged view of the detail II shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a schematic lateral view of a gas turbine blade shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a schematic bottom view of the gas turbine blade shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows a schematic lateral sectional view of the gas turbine blade along the cutting line V-V shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a schematic perspective view of three gas turbine blades <b>10</b> according to the invention that are disposed on a rotor disk <b>12</b>. By completely equipping rotor disk <b>12</b> with gas turbine blades <b>10</b> and connecting it to these blades, an integrally bladed rotor (so-called blisk or &#x201c;bladed disk&#x201d;) can be produced for a compressor and/or for a turbine of a turbomachine, in particular a thermal gas turbine. Instead of a rotor disk <b>12</b>, a rotor ring (not shown) can also be basically used, whereby a so-called bling (&#x201c;bladed ring&#x201d;) can be produced. A radially outer end region <b>14</b><i>a </i>is formed as a shrouding band segment <b>16</b> for each gas turbine blade <b>10</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). Shrouding band segments <b>16</b> and their respective gas turbine blades <b>10</b> in the present example of embodiment are thus formed in one piece as cast parts. In order to improve the surface geometry, it can be provided that one or more gas turbine blades <b>10</b> are precision processed by appropriate post-processing methods, such as PECM drilling. For introducing mechanical loads, each gas turbine blade <b>10</b> also comprises an integral receptacle <b>18</b>, in which a connecting element (not shown) can be arranged in a form-fitting manner. Each receptacle <b>18</b> is formed as a hexagon socket receptacle at the radially outer end region <b>14</b><i>a </i>of gas turbine blades <b>10</b> in shrouding band segments <b>16</b>. At least one Allen-wrench-shaped connecting element can be detachably inserted simply into the respective receptacle <b>18</b> in the connecting region in this way in order to load the respective gas turbine blade <b>10</b> with torque. In this way, each gas turbine blade <b>10</b> can be provided with a so-called pre-twist in a simple manner without causing damage and without the requirement of a special tool.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows an enlarged view of the detail II shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. In addition to shrouding band segments <b>16</b> and integral receptacles <b>18</b> it can be recognized in particular that each shrouding band segment <b>16</b> has two contact surfaces that are disposed opposite to one another and that are essentially Z-shaped in longitudinal section (so-called Z shroud) for attachment to corresponding contact surfaces <b>20</b> of adjacent shrouding band segments <b>16</b>. In addition, it can be recognized that each shrouding band segment <b>16</b> comprises two opposite-lying sealing fins <b>22</b>, which brush against a sealing structure of an assigned turbomachine in a grazing region, in particular during a rotation of rotor <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a schematic lateral view of one of the gas turbine blades <b>10</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> for further clarification. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> will be explained in the following together with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a schematic bottom view of the gas turbine blade <b>10</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, while <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows a schematic lateral sectional view of gas turbine blade <b>10</b> along cutting line V-V shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. It can be recognized particularly in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> that gas turbine blade <b>10</b> is presently formed as a hollow blade and comprises at least one hollow space <b>24</b>. In turn, receptacle <b>18</b> is formed as a core outlet region of hollow space <b>24</b>. In addition, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a fir-tree structure <b>26</b> formed on a radially inner end region <b>14</b><i>b </i>of the gas turbine blade for joining gas turbine blade <b>10</b> to rotor disk <b>12</b> can be recognized. The geometry and depth of form-fitting of receptacle <b>18</b> can be designed as a function of the shrouding band segment geometry, wherein, for example, the core outlet region of hollow space <b>24</b>, the arrangement of contact surfaces <b>20</b> and/or a geometry of sealing fins <b>22</b> can be taken into consideration.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A gas turbine blade (<b>10</b>), comprising:
<claim-text>at least one receiver (<b>18</b>) for the form-closing arrangement of a connecting element, by means of which a mechanical load can be introduced into the gas turbine blade (<b>10</b>), wherein the gas turbine blade (<b>10</b>) is formed as a hollow blade and comprises at least one hollow space (<b>24</b>), and wherein the receiver (<b>18</b>) is formed as a core outlet region of the hollow space (<b>24</b>), wherein the receiver (<b>18</b>) is configured in order to receive the connecting element, configured as a tool, pin or mandrel, for form-closing insertion and/or plugging-in into the receiver (<b>18</b>) and loading the gas turbine blade with torque.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The gas turbine blade (<b>10</b>) according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a radially inner end region (<b>14</b><i>b</i>) of the gas turbine blade (<b>10</b>) is formed for the connection of the gas turbine blade (<b>10</b>) to a rotor disk (<b>12</b>) or a rotor ring of the turbomachine, and/or a radially outer end region (<b>14</b><i>a</i>) of the gas turbine blade (<b>10</b>) is formed as a shroud-band segment (<b>16</b>).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The gas turbine blade (<b>10</b>) according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the receiver (<b>18</b>) is formed on the radially outer end region (<b>14</b><i>a</i>) of the gas turbine blade (<b>10</b>).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The gas turbine blade (<b>10</b>) according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the blade is formed in one piece with the receiver (<b>18</b>) and/or as a cast portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The gas turbine blade (<b>10</b>) according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein at least one surface region of the gas turbine blade (<b>10</b>) is finely machined.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The gas turbine blade (<b>10</b>) according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the receiver is formed as a polygonal receiver, and the connecting element is configured as a multi-edge socket wrench.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The gas turbine blade (<b>10</b>) according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the receiver is formed as a hexagon receiver. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
