<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624454-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624454</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12888902</doc-number>
<date>20100923</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2009-219511</doc-number>
<date>20090924</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>575</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>50</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>46</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>37</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>310 71</main-classification>
<further-classification>336192</further-classification>
<further-classification>310 4913</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Coil wound body and motor</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5412367</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Shibui et al.</name>
<date>19950500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>336192</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6046519</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hanazumi et al.</name>
<date>20000400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>310 4913</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7017851</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Matsuura et al.</name>
<date>20060300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>242437</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7071593</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Matsushita et al.</name>
<date>20060700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>310257</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7348696</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Sonohara et al.</name>
<date>20080300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>310 4908</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7911094</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Yajima</name>
<date>20110300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>310 71</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7990000</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Suzuki et al.</name>
<date>20110800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>310 71</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2007-259543</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20071000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>24</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>310 4901</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>310 4913</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>310 71</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>310179</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>336192</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>10</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110068653</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110324</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Agematsu</last-name>
<first-name>Ikuo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Nagano</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Agematsu</last-name>
<first-name>Ikuo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Nagano</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Cantor Colburn LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Nidec Sankyo Corporation</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Mullins</last-name>
<first-name>Burton</first-name>
<department>2834</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A coil wound body may include a coil bobbin around which a coil wire is wound. The coil bobbin may include a wound part around which the coil wire is wound, a terminal block part, a circuit board receiving face which is provided on the terminal block part and on which a wiring circuit board is disposed, and pin-shaped terminals. The coil bobbin is provided with a coil wire leading-out path reaching to root portions of the pin-shaped terminals from the wound part through an inner side of the circuit board receiving face. The coil wire are led out to the pin-shaped terminals by passing through the coil wire leading-out path without passing through a position overlapping with the outer side of the circuit board receiving face. The coil wound body is preferably applied to a motor.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="206.25mm" wi="154.01mm" file="US08624454-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="151.55mm" wi="175.26mm" file="US08624454-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="226.06mm" wi="174.33mm" file="US08624454-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="193.72mm" wi="183.22mm" file="US08624454-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="233.26mm" wi="188.47mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624454-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="175.26mm" wi="169.33mm" file="US08624454-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="173.31mm" wi="157.82mm" file="US08624454-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="206.93mm" wi="175.60mm" file="US08624454-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention claims priority under 35 U.S.C. &#xa7;119 to Japanese Application No. 2009-219511 filed Sep. 24, 2009, the entire content of which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">At least an embodiment may relate to a coil wound body in which a coil wire is wound around a coil bobbin and a motor.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, a stator of a stepping motor commonly includes a coil wound body <b>1011</b> which is provided with a coil wire <b>1110</b> and a coil bobbin <b>1120</b>. The coil bobbin <b>1120</b> includes a wound part <b>1121</b> where the coil wire <b>1110</b> is wound around, a terminal block part <b>1122</b> provided on an outer side in the radial direction of the wound part <b>1121</b>, and pin-shaped terminals <b>1123</b> and <b>1124</b> which are stood up from the terminal block part <b>1122</b> to the outer side in the radial direction. End parts of the coil wire <b>1110</b> are bound around the pin terminals <b>1123</b> and <b>1124</b>. An entire face directing to an outer side in the radial direction of the terminal block part <b>1122</b> is formed as a circuit board receiving face <b>1122</b><i>a </i>on which a wiring circuit board <b>1010</b> is disposed in an overlapped manner. The pin-shaped terminals <b>1123</b> and <b>1124</b> are stood up on the circuit board receiving face <b>1122</b><i>a </i>at inner positions of the edge. In the coil bobbin <b>1120</b> structured as described above, after the wiring circuit board <b>1010</b> is overlapped on the circuit board receiving face <b>1122</b><i>a </i>while the pin-shaped terminals <b>1123</b> and <b>1124</b> are inserted into through holes <b>1102</b> formed in the wiring circuit board <b>1010</b>, the coil wire <b>1110</b> and the land parts of the wiring circuit board <b>1010</b> are soldered with each other in a state that the wiring circuit board <b>1010</b> is held in a stable attitude.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">According to this structure, in lead-out parts <b>1110</b><i>b </i>and <b>1110</b><i>d </i>of the coil wire <b>1110</b> in the coil wound body <b>1011</b> which are led out from the winding part <b>1121</b> to the pin-shaped terminals <b>1123</b> and <b>1124</b>, floated portions <b>1110</b><i>x </i>which are floated from the circuit board receiving face <b>1122</b><i>a </i>are formed between a corner portion <b>1122</b><i>r </i>located on the winding part <b>1121</b> side and the pin-shaped terminals <b>1123</b> and <b>1124</b> on the terminal block part <b>1122</b>. Therefore, when the wiring circuit board <b>1010</b> is placed on the circuit board receiving face <b>1122</b><i>a</i>, the floated portions <b>1110</b><i>x </i>of the lead-out parts <b>1110</b><i>b </i>and <b>1110</b><i>d </i>are held between the wiring circuit board <b>1010</b> and the circuit board receiving face <b>1122</b><i>a </i>and thus the floated portions <b>1110</b><i>x </i>are pressed by the wiring circuit board <b>1010</b>. As a result, the coil wire <b>1110</b> may be pulled and disconnected. In Japanese Patent Laid-Open No. 2007-259543, in order to prevent disconnection of a coil wire when the coil wire is wound around a coil bobbin, a structure has been proposed in which a cut-out groove for passing the coil wire is formed at a corner part of a terminal block part.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">However, in the technique described in the above-mentioned Patent Literature, even when the cut-out groove is formed, floated portions of the coil wire from the circuit board receiving face are newly formed between another corner portion formed by the cut-out groove and the pin-shaped terminals and thus the problem described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is not eliminated.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In view of the problems described above, at least an embodiment of the present invention may advantageously provide a coil wound body in which disconnection and damage of a coil wire are not easily occurred even when a wiring circuit board is disposed on a circuit board receiving face in an overlapped manner after the coil wire has been led out to the pin-shaped terminals which are stood up in a terminal block part having the circuit board receiving face, and a motor utilizing the coil wound body.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">According to at least an embodiment of the present invention, there may be provided a coil wound body including a coil bobbin around which a coil wire is wound. The coil bobbin includes a wound part around which the coil wire is wound, a terminal block part which is protruded toward an outer side in a radial direction from the wound part, a circuit board receiving face which is located on the outer side in the radial direction of the terminal block part and on which a wiring circuit board is disposed in an overlapped manner, and pin-shaped terminals which are located on the outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and protruded toward the outer side in the radial direction. The coil wire includes a winding part which is wound around the wound part, lead-out parts which are led out from the winding part to contacted positions with the pin-shaped terminals, and binding parts which are located on tip end sides with respect to the lead-out parts and bound around the pin-shaped terminals. The coil bobbin is provided with a coil wire leading-out path which reaches to root portions of the pin-shaped terminals from the wound part through an inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face. Further, the lead-out parts of the coil wire are led out to the contacted positions with the pin-shaped terminals by passing through the coil wire leading-out path without passing through a position overlapping with the outer side in the radial direction of the circuit board receiving face.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In at least an embodiment of the present invention, the &#x201c;lead-out part&#x201d; means a portion where the coil wire is not bound around the pin-shaped terminal, in other words, a portion from the winding part to a contacted position with the pin-shaped terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In accordance with an embodiment of the present invention, the lead-out parts of the coil wire are led out to the contacted positions with the pin-shaped terminals by passing through the coil wire leading-out path without passing through a position overlapping with the outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face. In other words, the coil wire is not located on the outer side in the radial direction of the circuit board receiving face between the wing part and the binding parts around the pin-shaped terminals and the lead-out parts of the coil wire are not passed over the circuit board receiving face. As a result, the coil wire is not floated from the circuit board receiving face and thus, even when the wiring circuit board is placed on the terminal block part, the coil wire is not pressed by the wiring circuit board. Therefore, disconnection or damage of the coil wire due to contacting of the coil wire with the wiring circuit board or due to that the coil wire is pulled by depression of the wiring circuit board can be prevented. Further, since the coil wire is not present on the circuit board receiving face, an inclination of the wiring circuit board due to the coil wire does not occur and the wiring circuit board is received by the circuit board receiving face in a face-contacted state. Therefore, the wiring circuit board is disposed in a stable state.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In accordance with an embodiment of the present invention, the pin-shaped terminals are provided on inner sides with respect to both end parts in a circumferential direction of the terminal block part, and the coil wire leading-out path is structured on an inner side in the circumferential direction with respect to the both end parts in the circumferential direction of the terminal block part. According to this structure, the lead-out parts of the coil wire are led out to the pin-shaped terminals without passing through the side faces in the circumferential direction of the terminal block part. Therefore, after the coil wire has been bound around the pin-shaped terminals, even when something is contacted with the side faces of the terminal block part, disconnection or damage of the coil wire can be prevented. Further, since the lead-out parts of the coil wire are not passed through the side faces in the circumferential direction of the terminal block part, even when both side end parts of the terminal block part are held by a hand for handling the coil wound body, the hand does not touch the coil wire and thus the coil wire is not disconnected. Therefore, the coil wound body is easily handled.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In accordance with an embodiment of the present invention, the lead-out part of the coil wire is led out from the winding part to the contacted position with the pin-shaped terminal in a not-slacked state. According to this structure, the lead-out part is passed through only a predetermined position of the coil bobbin and thus the lead-out position or the like is not displaced. Further, when the lead-out part of the coil wire is not slacked, the lead-out part is prevented from being sandwiched between the wiring circuit board and the circuit board receiving face and so on. In addition, the coil wire of the winding part is not loosened.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In accordance with an embodiment of the present invention, the coil wire leading-out path of the coil bobbin is structured so as to pass through a front side where the wound part is located with respect to the pin-shaped terminals, the front side of the terminal block part with respect to the pin-shaped terminals is formed to be a first inner side region which is located on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and structures the coil wire leading-out path, and a region which is adjacent in a circumferential direction to the pin-shaped terminal in an extending direction of the lead-out part from the wound part is formed to be a second inner side region which is located on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and structures the coil wire leading-out path. Specifically, it may be structured so that a front face of the pin-shaped terminal on a side where the wound part is located is formed with a wall face in the terminal block part so as to extend toward the wound part side from the circuit board receiving face and so as to continuously form the same face on the inner side in the radial direction as the front face of the root portion of the pin-shaped terminal and, in the terminal block part, a front space of the wall face is formed to be the first inner side region which is located on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and structures the coil wire leading-out path. Further, it may be structured so that a wall face is formed so as to continuously form the same face on the inner side in the radial direction as a side face of the root portion of the pin-shaped terminal in at least one of both sides of the terminal block part which are adjacent in the circumferential direction to the pin-shaped terminal, and the wall face forms the second inner side region which is located on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and structures the coil wire leading-out path. According to this structure, the lead-out part of the coil wire is led out without passing through the position overlapping with the outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and connected with the contacted position on the front side or one of both sides of the pin-shaped terminal. Also in this case, since the lead-out parts of the coil wire are not passed over the circuit board receiving face, the lead-out parts are not floated from the circuit board receiving face. Therefore, when the wiring circuit board is placed on the terminal block part, disconnection and damage due to depressing of the wiring circuit board can be prevented.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In accordance with an embodiment of the present invention, a front face of the pin-shaped terminal where the wound part is located is extended toward a wound part side with respect to the circuit board receiving face so that a wall face is formed so as to be continuously connected with a front face of a root portion of the pin-shaped terminal, and a front space of the wall face is formed to be the first inner side region, the terminal block is formed with a wall face which is continuously connected with a side face of the root portion of the pin-shaped terminal in a region adjacent to the pin-shaped terminal in the extending direction of the lead-out part from the wound part, and the wall face is formed to be the second inner side region, and the lead-out part is contacted with a corner portion between the wall face in the first inner side region and the wall face in the second inner side region, and a tip end part of the lead-out part is contacted with an edge on a rear face side of the root portion of a side face of the pin-shaped terminal and bound around the pin-shaped terminal. According to this structure, the tip end part of the lead-out part is bound around the pin-shaped terminal from the same height as the circuit board receiving face and thus, the coil wire is bound around from the root portion of the pin-shaped terminal while preventing disconnection and damage due to depressing of the wiring circuit board when the wiring circuit board is placed on the terminal block part.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In accordance with an embodiment of the present invention, the coil bobbin is provided with a flange part whose diameter is enlarged at an end part of a body part of the wound part, and the lead-out part is contacted with a corner portion between an upper end part of a front face wall part which is continuously formed from the flange part toward the outer side in the radial direction and the wall face of the first inner side region.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In accordance with an embodiment of the present invention, the region which is adjacent in the circumferential direction to the pin-shaped terminal in the extending direction of the lead-out part from the wound part is formed to be an inclined face part which is inclined toward the wound part to structure the second inner side region. In this case, it is preferable that the inclined face part is inclined toward the winding part from a position adjacent in the circumferential direction to a rear face of the pin-shaped terminal which is located on an opposite side to the winding part side. According to this structure, the lead-out part is easily passed through the second inner side region.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In accordance with an embodiment of the present invention, the coil wire leading-out path of the coil bobbin is structured so as to pass through a front side where the wound part is located with respect to the pin-shaped terminal, and the front side where the wound part is located with respect to the pin-shaped terminal is formed to be an inner side region which is located on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and structures the coil wire leading-out path. According to this structure, the lead-out part of the coil wire is led out without passing through the position overlapping with the outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and is connected with the front side of the pin-shaped terminal. Further, also in this structure, since the lead-out parts of the coil wire are not passed over the circuit board receiving face, the lead-out parts are not floated from the circuit board receiving face. Therefore, when the wiring circuit board is placed on the terminal block part, disconnection and damage due to depressing of the wiring circuit board is prevented. In addition, since the coil wire leading-out path can be structured only on the front side of the pin-shaped terminal, an area of the circuit board receiving face in the terminal block part can be widely secured. Therefore, the wiring circuit board is received in a stable state.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In accordance with an embodiment of the present invention, the coil wire leading-out path of the coil bobbin is structured so as to pass through a region which is adjacent in a circumferential direction to the pin-shaped terminal on an opposite side to an extending direction of the lead-out part from the wound part and, in the terminal block part, the region and a front side region on the wound part side with respect to the region are formed to be an inner side region which is located on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and structures the coil wire leading-out path. According to this structure, the lead-out part of the coil wire is led out without passing through the position overlapping with the outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and is connected with the pin-shaped terminal. Also in this structure, since the lead-out parts of the coil wire are not passed over the circuit board receiving face, the lead-out parts are not floated from the circuit board receiving face. Therefore, when the wiring circuit board is placed on the terminal block part, disconnection and damage due to depressing of the wiring circuit board can be prevented.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In this case, it is preferable that the region which is adjacent to the pin-shaped terminal on the opposite side to the extending direction of the lead-out part from the wound part is formed to be an inclined face part which is inclined toward the wound part to structure the inner side region. According to this structure, the lead-out part is easily passed through the second inner side region.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In this case, it is preferable that the inclined face part is inclined toward the winding part from a position adjacent in the circumferential direction to a rear face of the pin-shaped terminal which is located on an opposite side to the winding part side. According to this structure, the lead-out part can be led out along the inclined face part and thus the lead-out part is guided to the pin-shaped terminal in a stable state. Further, since the lead-out part can be led out along the inclined face part, an unnecessary floating is hard to occur in the lead-out part. Therefore, a problem can be prevented in which the lead-out part is caught by something to cause the coil wire to be disconnected.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In accordance with an embodiment of the present invention, the pin-shaped terminals and the terminal block part are integrally formed of resin. According to this structure, different from a case that pin-shaped terminals formed of separated members from the terminal block part are used, even when the terminal block part is designed in any shape in order to prevent disconnection of the coil wire, a problem that the pin-shaped terminals are detached from the terminal block part does not occur.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The coil wound body to which at least an embodiment of the present invention is applied is applied to a motor which includes a stator provided with the coil wound body and a rotor provided with a rotor magnet.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Other features and advantages will be apparent from the following detailed description, taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings that illustrate, by way of example, various features of embodiments of the invention.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Embodiments will now be described, by way of example only, with reference to the accompanying drawings which are meant to be exemplary, not limiting, and wherein like elements are numbered alike in several Figures, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a side view showing a motor in accordance with a first embodiment of the present invention, a part of which is cut off.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view showing a coil wound body which is used in a motor in accordance with the first embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an enlarged perspective view showing a terminal block part of a coil wound body which is used in a motor in accordance with the first embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>a</i>) is a rear view showing a coil wound body used in a motor in accordance with the first embodiment of the present invention which is viewed from an opposite-to-output side of the motor, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>b</i>) is its side view, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>c</i>) is its front view which is viewed from an output side of the motor, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>d</i>) is a plan view showing a terminal block part.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an enlarged perspective view showing a terminal block part of a coil wound body which is used in a motor in accordance with a second embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is an enlarged perspective view showing a terminal block part of a coil wound body which is used in a motor in accordance with a third embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is an explanatory perspective view showing a conventional coil wound body.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">A coil wound body and a stepping motor will be described below with reference to the accompanying drawings. In the following description, an output side of a rotation shaft is a front side and its opposite-to-output side is a rear side. Further, in the description of a terminal block part, a direction where pin-shaped terminals are protruded is a higher direction and a side of the coil bobbin where the winding part is located is described as a lower side.</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">First Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a side view showing a motor in accordance with a first embodiment of the present invention, a part of which is cut off. A motor <b>1</b> in the first embodiment is a stepping motor, which includes a stator <b>2</b> formed in a cylindrical shape and a rotor <b>3</b> which is disposed on an inner peripheral side of the stator <b>2</b>. The rotor <b>3</b> includes a rotation shaft <b>31</b> and a rotor magnet <b>32</b> which is formed in a cylindrical shape and coaxially attached to an outer peripheral face of the rotation shaft <b>31</b>. A first end plate <b>4</b> is fixed to an end face <b>2</b><i>a </i>on the output side of the stator <b>2</b> and the first end plate <b>4</b> holds a first bearing <b>5</b> which rotatably supports the rotation shaft <b>31</b> around the axial line &#x201c;L<b>1</b>&#x201d;. An end face <b>2</b><i>b </i>on the opposite-to-output side of the stator <b>2</b> is fixed with a second end plate <b>6</b>, which holds a second bearing <b>7</b> rotatably supporting the rotation shaft <b>31</b> around the axial line &#x201c;L<b>1</b>&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The stator <b>2</b> includes a first stator assembly <b>21</b> and a second stator assembly <b>22</b> which are disposed in a front and rear direction along the axial line &#x201c;L<b>1</b>&#x201d; of the rotation shaft <b>31</b>. The first stator assembly <b>21</b> includes a first coil wound body <b>11</b> where a coil wire <b>110</b> is wound around a coil bobbin <b>120</b>, and a ring-shaped outer stator core <b>211</b> and a ring-shaped inner stator core <b>212</b> on both sides in the axial line &#x201c;L<b>1</b>&#x201d; direction with respect to the first coil wound body <b>11</b>. Each of the outer stator core <b>211</b> and the inner stator core <b>212</b> is formed of a magnetic metal member, which forms a magnetic path. Each of the outer stator core <b>211</b> and the inner stator core <b>212</b> is provided with pole teeth <b>213</b> which are stood up from its inner circumferential edge. The pole teeth <b>213</b> of the outer stator core <b>211</b> and the pole teeth <b>213</b> of the inner stator core <b>212</b> are alternately juxtaposed on the inner peripheral side of the first coil wound body <b>11</b> in the circumferential direction so as to face the outer peripheral face of the rotor magnet <b>32</b>. The second stator assembly <b>22</b> also includes, similarly to the first stator assembly <b>21</b>, a second coil wound body <b>12</b> where a coil wire <b>140</b> is wound around a coil bobbin <b>150</b>, and a ring-shaped outer stator core <b>221</b> and a ring-shaped inner stator core <b>222</b> on both sides in the axial line &#x201c;L<b>1</b>&#x201d; direction with respect to the second coil wound body <b>12</b>. Each of the outer stator core <b>221</b> and the inner stator core <b>222</b> is formed of a magnetic metal member, which forms a magnetic path. Each of the outer stator core <b>221</b> and the inner stator core <b>222</b> is provided with pole teeth <b>223</b> which are stood up from its inner circumferential edge. The pole teeth <b>223</b> of the outer stator core <b>221</b> and the pole teeth <b>223</b> of the inner stator core <b>222</b> are alternately juxtaposed on the inner peripheral side of the second coil wound body <b>12</b> in the circumferential direction so as to face the outer peripheral face of the rotor magnet <b>32</b>. In this embodiment, outer circumferential edges of the outer stator cores <b>211</b> and <b>221</b> are respectively bent toward the axial line &#x201c;L<b>1</b>&#x201d; direction and the bent portions are formed as cases <b>8</b> and <b>9</b> which cover the coil wires <b>110</b> and <b>140</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The first coil wound body <b>11</b> includes a coil bobbin <b>120</b> and a coil wire <b>110</b> which is wound around the coil bobbin <b>120</b>. The coil bobbin <b>120</b> is provided with a wound part <b>121</b> around which the coil wire <b>110</b> is wound, a terminal block part <b>122</b> which is protruded from the wound part <b>121</b> to an outer side in a radial direction (upward), and two pin-shaped terminals (a first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and a second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>) which are stood up from the terminal block part <b>122</b> to an outer side in the radial direction (upward). A face of the terminal block part <b>122</b> facing the outer side in the radial direction is a circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>on which a wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is disposed in an overlapped manner. The terminal block part <b>122</b>, the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are protruded from an opening of the case <b>8</b> to the outer side in the radial direction.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The second coil wound body <b>12</b> includes, similarly to the first coil wound body <b>11</b>, a coil bobbin <b>150</b> and a coil wire <b>140</b> which is wound around the coil bobbin <b>150</b>. The coil bobbin <b>150</b> is provided with a wound part <b>151</b> around which the coil wire <b>140</b> is wound, a terminal block part <b>152</b> which is protruded from the wound part <b>151</b> to an outer side in a radial direction (upward), and two pin-shaped terminals (a first pin-shaped terminal <b>153</b> and a second pin-shaped terminal <b>154</b>) which are stood up from the terminal block part <b>152</b> to an outer side in the radial direction (upward). A face of the terminal block part <b>152</b> facing the outer side in the radial direction is a circuit board receiving face <b>152</b><i>a </i>on which the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is disposed in an overlapped manner. The terminal block part <b>152</b>, the first pin-shaped terminal <b>153</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>154</b> are protruded from an opening of the case <b>9</b> to the outer side in the radial direction.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In the motor <b>1</b> structured as described above, an electrical power is supplied to the coil wires <b>110</b> and <b>140</b> through the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> to drive and control rotation of the rotor <b>3</b> by controlling the electric current. A rigid circuit board or a flexible circuit board may be used as the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> but, in this embodiment, a flexible circuit board is used as the wiring circuit board <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view showing the coil wound body which is used in a motor in accordance with the first embodiment of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an enlarged perspective view showing the terminal block part of the coil wound body which is used in the motor in accordance with the first embodiment of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>a</i>) is a rear view showing the coil wound body used in the motor in accordance with the first embodiment of the present invention which is viewed from the opposite-to-output side of the motor, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>b</i>) is its side view, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>c</i>) is its front view which is viewed from the output side of the motor, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>d</i>) is a plan view showing the terminal block part. In this embodiment, the first coil wound body <b>11</b> and the second coil wound body <b>12</b> are provided with the same structure as each other and thus only the first coil wound body <b>11</b> will be described below and description of the second coil wound body <b>12</b> is omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4(</figref><i>a</i>) through <b>4</b>(<i>d</i>), the coil bobbin <b>120</b> of the first coil wound body <b>11</b> is provided with the wound part <b>121</b> around which the coil wire <b>110</b> is wound. The wound part <b>121</b> is provided with a body part <b>121</b><i>a </i>in a cylindrical shape, a ring-shaped front side flange part <b>121</b><i>b </i>whose diameter is enlarged at an end part on the output side of the body part <b>121</b><i>a </i>(front end part), and a ring-shaped rear side flange part <b>121</b><i>c </i>whose diameter is enlarged at an end part on the opposite-to-output side of the body part <b>121</b><i>a </i>(rear end part). In the wound part <b>121</b> described above, the coil wire <b>110</b> is wound around the body part <b>121</b><i>a </i>in a region sandwiched by the front side flange part <b>121</b><i>b </i>and the rear side flange part <b>121</b><i>c</i>. At an outer circumferential edge of the rear side flange part <b>121</b><i>c </i>of the coil bobbin <b>120</b>, the terminal block part <b>122</b> having a large thickness is formed so as to protrude toward the outer side in the radial direction from a part in the circumferential direction of the rear side flange part <b>121</b><i>c </i>to form the terminal block part <b>122</b>. The terminal block part <b>122</b> is formed in a shape protruded to the outer side in the radial direction from the wound part <b>121</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">A face directing to the outer side of the most outer portion in the radial direction of the terminal block part <b>122</b> is formed as the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>on which the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is disposed in an overlapped manner. The wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is formed with a pair of land parts <b>101</b> and a through hole <b>102</b> is formed at the center of the land part <b>101</b>. The terminal block part <b>122</b> is formed with the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> which are located on the outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>and protruded to the outer side in the radial direction. The first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are made of resin and integrally formed with the terminal block part <b>122</b> when the coil bobbin <b>120</b> is molded by using resin. In other words, the coil bobbin <b>120</b> is a resin molded product in which the wound part <b>121</b>, the terminal block part <b>122</b>, the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are integrally molded by using resin.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The coil wire <b>110</b> is provided with a winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>which is wound around the wound part <b>121</b>, a first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>which is led to the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c</i>, and a first binding part <b>110</b><i>a </i>which is bound around the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> on a tip end side with respect to the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b</i>. The first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>is led out in a no-slackened state from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>which is wound around the wound part <b>121</b> and bound around the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>. Further, the coil wire <b>110</b> is provided with a second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>which is led to the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>and a second binding part <b>110</b><i>e </i>which is bound around the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> on a tip end side with respect to the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>. The second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>is led out in a no-slackened state from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>which is wound around the wound part <b>121</b> and bound around the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In this embodiment, the binding part (the first binding part <b>110</b><i>a </i>and the second binding part <b>110</b><i>e</i>) is a portion where the coil wire <b>110</b> is wound around a side face of the pin-shaped terminal (the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>). Further, the lead-out part (the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>) is a portion ranging from the wound part <b>121</b> to a contacted position where the coil wire <b>110</b> is contacted with the side face of the pin-shaped terminal (the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>). Further, in the coil wire <b>110</b>, a side of the second binding part <b>110</b><i>e </i>and the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>is a winding start side when the coil wire <b>110</b> is wound around the coil bobbin <b>120</b>, and a side of the first binding part <b>110</b><i>a </i>and the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>is a winding end side when the coil wire <b>110</b> is wound around the coil bobbin <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, in the first coil wound body <b>11</b> in this embodiment, when viewed from a side in an axial line &#x201c;L<b>1</b>&#x201d;, the terminal block part <b>122</b> of the coil bobbin <b>120</b> is formed in a rectangular block shape whose length in a circumferential direction of the coil bobbin <b>120</b> (right and left direction &#x201c;L<b>2</b>&#x201d;) is longer, and both of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are stood up at inner side positions from side end parts <b>122</b><i>c </i>and <b>122</b><i>d </i>in the circumferential direction of the terminal block part <b>122</b>. Further, the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are stood up at separated positions in the circumferential direction. Further, the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are provided at substantially center positions in the axial line &#x201c;L<b>1</b>&#x201d; direction on the outer side end part in the radial direction of the terminal block part <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In the terminal block part <b>122</b>, an upper end part of a front face wall part <b>128</b> which is continuously stood up from the rear side flange part <b>121</b><i>c </i>to the outer side in the radial direction (upper side) is formed with an inclined face part <b>125</b><i>a </i>which is inclined obliquely downward toward the wound part <b>121</b> side. The inclined face part <b>125</b><i>a </i>is formed so as to cut off the front side of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> of the terminal block part <b>122</b>. Further, the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>a </i>is extended toward the wound part <b>121</b> with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>from under positions of front faces <b>123</b><i>a </i>and <b>124</b><i>a </i>of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> on the side where the wound part <b>121</b> is located. A wall face <b>127</b> is formed upward from a rear end edge of the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>a </i>so as to be continuously connected to root portions of the front faces <b>123</b><i>a </i>and <b>124</b><i>a </i>of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. The wall face <b>127</b> is formed in the terminal block part <b>122</b> on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>so as to continuously form the same flat face as the front faces <b>123</b><i>a </i>and <b>124</b><i>a </i>of the root portions of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. Therefore, a front side of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> is formed as a first inner side region <b>129</b><i>a </i>which is comprised of a front space to the wall face <b>127</b>, a front space to the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>a</i>, and a front space to the front face wall part <b>128</b>. The first inner side region <b>129</b><i>a </i>is located on the inner side in the radial direction (lower side) with respect to the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>, the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> and the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. In other words, in a state that the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is disposed on the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>formed on the terminal block part <b>122</b> and the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are penetrated through the through holes <b>102</b> of the land parts <b>101</b> formed in the wiring circuit board <b>10</b>, the first inner side region <b>129</b><i>a </i>is formed at the inner side position in the radial direction with respect to the root portions of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> and with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>on which the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is disposed.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Further, one of both side regions adjacent to the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> in the circumferential direction in the terminal block part <b>122</b>, which is the region located in an extending direction of the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>(counter-clockwise direction; CCW) is formed to be an inclined face part <b>125</b><i>b </i>which is inclined toward the wound part <b>121</b>. The inclined face part <b>125</b><i>b </i>is formed so as to cut off one side of the terminal block part <b>122</b> with respect to the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>b </i>structures a second inner side region <b>129</b><i>b </i>which is located on the inner side in the radial direction (lower side) with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. In other words, in a state that the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is disposed on the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>formed on the terminal block part <b>122</b> and the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> is penetrated through the through hole <b>102</b> of the land part <b>101</b> formed in the wiring circuit board <b>10</b>, the second inner side region <b>129</b><i>b </i>is formed at the inner side position in the radial direction with respect to the root portion of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. In this embodiment, the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>b </i>is inclined toward the wound part <b>121</b> from a position which is adjacent in the circumferential direction to a rear face <b>123</b><i>b </i>of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> located on an opposite side to the wound part <b>121</b>. Further, a wall face <b>130</b> is formed on an upper portion from an edge on the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> side of the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>b </i>so as to be continuously connected to the side face <b>123</b><i>c </i>of the root portions of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>. The wall face <b>130</b> is formed in the terminal block part <b>122</b> on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>so as to continuously form the same flat face as the side face <b>123</b><i>c </i>of the root portion of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Further, one of both side regions adjacent to the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> in the circumferential direction in the terminal block part <b>122</b>, which is the region located in an extending direction of the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>(clockwise direction; CW) is formed to be an inclined face part <b>125</b><i>c </i>which is inclined toward the wound part <b>121</b>. The inclined face part <b>125</b><i>c </i>is formed so as to cut off the other side of the terminal block part <b>122</b> with respect to the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> and the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>c </i>structures a second inner side region <b>129</b><i>c </i>which is located on the inner side in the radial direction (lower side) with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. In other words, in a state that the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is disposed on the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> is penetrated through the through hole <b>102</b> of the wiring circuit board <b>10</b>, the second inner side region <b>129</b><i>c </i>is formed at the inner side position in the radial direction with respect to the root portion of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> and with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>on which the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is disposed. In this embodiment, the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>c </i>is inclined toward the wound part <b>121</b> from a position which is adjacent in the circumferential direction to a rear face <b>124</b><i>b </i>of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> located on an opposite side to the wound part <b>121</b>. Further, a wall face <b>131</b> is formed on an upper portion from an edge on the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> side of the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>c </i>so as to be continuously connected to the side face <b>124</b><i>c </i>of the root portions of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. The wall face <b>131</b> is formed in the terminal block part <b>122</b> on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>so as to continuously form the same flat face as the side face <b>124</b><i>c </i>of the root portion of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. In addition, lower sides of the inclined face parts <b>125</b><i>b </i>and <b>125</b><i>c </i>are connected with the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>a </i>and the inclined face parts <b>125</b><i>a</i>, <b>125</b><i>b </i>and <b>125</b><i>c </i>structure a continuous inclined face part.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In the terminal block part <b>122</b> of the coil bobbin <b>120</b> structured as described above, a flat face is formed only in a region which is sandwiched by the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>, regions on opposite sides to the sides where the wound part <b>121</b> is located with respect to the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>, and regions on opposite sides to the sides where the wound part <b>121</b> is located with respect to the inclined face parts <b>125</b><i>b </i>and <b>125</b><i>c</i>. The flat face is the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In this embodiment, the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>of the coil wire <b>110</b> is extended in a counter-clockwise CCW direction from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>and the coil wire <b>110</b> is bound around the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> by passing through the counter-clockwise CCW side of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>. Further, the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>is extended in a clockwise CW direction from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>and the coil wire <b>110</b> is bound around the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> by passing through the clockwise CW side of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. The first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>are crossed in a front space of the front face wall part <b>128</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>is led out to the root portion of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>through a coil wire leading-out path <b>180</b><i>a </i>comprised of the first inner side region <b>129</b><i>a </i>and the second inner side region <b>129</b><i>b </i>and bound around the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>. The second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>is led out to the root portion of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>through a coil wire leading-out path <b>180</b><i>b </i>comprised of the first inner side region <b>129</b><i>a </i>and the second inner side region <b>129</b><i>c </i>and bound around the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">More specifically, the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>is extended in the counter-clockwise CCW direction from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>and then, extended obliquely above along the front face wall part <b>128</b> in the first inner side region <b>129</b><i>a </i>and next, the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>is contacted with a corner portion <b>128</b><i>a </i>formed by the front face wall part <b>128</b> and the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>a</i>. After that, the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>is contacted with a corner portion <b>127</b><i>a </i>formed between the wall face <b>127</b> in the first inner side region <b>129</b><i>a </i>and the wall face <b>130</b> in the second inner side region <b>129</b><i>b</i>. After that, the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>is extended along the wall face <b>130</b> formed to be the same flat face as the side face <b>123</b><i>c </i>of the root portion of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> in the second inner side region <b>129</b><i>b </i>and a tip end part <b>110</b><i>s </i>of the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>(position located between the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the first binding part <b>110</b><i>a</i>) is contacted with an edge on the rear face <b>123</b><i>b </i>side of the root part of the side face <b>123</b><i>c </i>of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>. In this embodiment, the contact part <b>110</b><i>t </i>of the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>with the corner portion <b>127</b><i>a </i>is located on the inner side in the radial direction (lower side) with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. Further, the tip end part <b>110</b><i>s </i>of the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>is located at the same height as the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. After that, the tip end side (first binding part <b>110</b><i>a</i>) of the coil wire <b>110</b> with respect to the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>is extended in the circumferential direction while contacting with the rear face <b>123</b><i>b </i>and then the tip end side of the coil wire <b>110</b> is wound around the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Further, the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>is extended in the clockwise CW direction from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>and then, extended obliquely above along the front face wall part <b>128</b> in the first inner side region <b>129</b><i>a </i>and next, the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>is contacted with a corner portion <b>128</b><i>a </i>formed between the front face wall part <b>128</b> and the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>a</i>. After that, the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>is contacted with a corner portion <b>127</b><i>b </i>formed between the wall face <b>127</b> in the first inner side region <b>129</b><i>a </i>and the wall face <b>131</b> in the second inner side region <b>129</b><i>c</i>. After that, the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>is extended along the wall face <b>131</b> formed to be the same flat face as the side face <b>124</b><i>c </i>of the root portion of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> in the second inner side region <b>129</b><i>c </i>and a tip end part <b>110</b><i>u </i>of the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>(position located between the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>and the second binding part <b>110</b><i>e</i>) is contacted with an edge on the rear face <b>124</b><i>b </i>side of the root part of the side face <b>124</b><i>c </i>of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4(</figref><i>a</i>) and <b>4</b>(<i>d</i>)). In this embodiment, the contact part <b>110</b><i>v </i>of the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>with the corner portion <b>127</b><i>b </i>is located on the inner side in the radial direction (lower side) with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. Further, the tip end part <b>110</b><i>u </i>of the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>is located at the same height as the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. After that, the tip end side (second binding part <b>110</b><i>e</i>) of the coil wire <b>110</b> with respect to the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>is extended in the circumferential direction while contacting with the rear face <b>124</b><i>b </i>and then the tip end side of the coil wire <b>110</b> is wound around the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In the first coil wound body <b>11</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, in order to wind the coil wire <b>110</b>, for example, one end part of the coil wire <b>110</b> is bound from the root side of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> to its tip end side (or from the tip end side to the root side) so that the one end part of the coil wire <b>110</b> is held by the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. As a result, the second binding part <b>110</b><i>e </i>is formed. Next, after the coil wire <b>110</b> has been wound around the wound part <b>121</b> of the coil bobbin <b>120</b>, the coil wire <b>110</b> is led out to the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and, after that, the coil wire <b>110</b> is bound around the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In this embodiment, the second coil wound body <b>12</b> is also manufactured by a similar method to the first coil wound body <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The wiring circuit board <b>10</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref> is mounted on the coil bobbin <b>120</b>. The mounting step is, for example, performed after the stepping motor <b>1</b> has been assembled by using the first coil wound body <b>11</b> and the second coil wound body <b>12</b>. In this case, the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are respectively penetrated through two through holes <b>102</b> of the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> and the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is placed on the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>of the first coil wound body <b>11</b> and the circuit board receiving face <b>152</b><i>a </i>of the second coil wound body <b>12</b>. After that, the first binding part <b>110</b><i>a </i>and the second binding part <b>110</b><i>e </i>of the coil wire <b>110</b> are soldered to the land parts <b>101</b>. Similarly, after the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> has been placed on the circuit board receiving face <b>152</b><i>a </i>of the second coil wound body <b>12</b>, the binding parts of the coil wire <b>140</b> are soldered to the land parts <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In this embodiment, since the lead-out parts (the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>) are passed through the coil wire leading-out paths <b>180</b><i>a </i>and <b>180</b><i>b</i>, the lead-out parts are respectively connected with the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b> without passing through positions overlapping with the outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. In other words, the lead-out parts are respectively connected with the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b> by passing through the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. Therefore, the coil wire <b>110</b> is not located at a position on the outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>between the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>and the binding parts of the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b>, and the lead-out parts (the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>) do not pass over the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. As a result, a floated portion of the coil wire <b>110</b> which is floated from the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>is not formed, in other words, a gap space between the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>and the coil wire <b>110</b> is not formed and thus, even when the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is placed on the terminal block part <b>122</b>, the coil wire <b>110</b> is not pressed by the wiring circuit board <b>10</b>. Therefore, disconnection or damage of the coil wire <b>110</b> due to contact of the coil wire <b>110</b> with the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> or due to that the coil wire <b>110</b> is pulled by depression of the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> can be prevented. Further, since the coil wire <b>110</b> is not located over the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>, an inclination of the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> due to the coil wire <b>110</b> does not occur and the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> can be received by the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>in a face-contacted state. Therefore, the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is placed in a stable state.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Further, the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are provided on inner sides with respect to both side end parts <b>122</b><i>c </i>and <b>122</b><i>d </i>in the circumferential direction of the terminal block part <b>122</b>, and the coil wire leading-out path <b>180</b> is structured on the inner sides in the circumferential direction with respect to the both side end parts <b>122</b><i>c </i>and <b>122</b><i>d </i>in the circumferential direction of the terminal block part <b>122</b>. Therefore, the lead-out parts of the coil wire <b>110</b> (the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>) are led out to the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> without passing through the side end faces in the circumferential direction of the terminal block part <b>122</b>. Accordingly, after the coil wire <b>110</b> has been wound around the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>, even when something is contacted with the side end faces of the terminal block part <b>122</b> (side end parts <b>122</b><i>c </i>and <b>122</b><i>d</i>), the coil wire <b>110</b> is not disconnected. Further, the lead-out parts of the coil wire <b>110</b> (the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>) are not passed through the side end faces in the circumferential direction of the terminal block part <b>122</b>. Therefore, in a case that the first coil wound body <b>11</b> is handled, even when both side end parts <b>122</b><i>c </i>and <b>122</b><i>d </i>of the terminal block part <b>122</b> are held by a hand, the hand does not contact with the coil wire <b>110</b> and thus the coil <b>110</b> is not disconnected. Therefore, the first coil wound body <b>11</b> is easily handled.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Further, the lead-out parts (the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>) are led out in a no-slackened state and the contacted parts (<b>110</b><i>t </i>and <b>110</b><i>v</i>) contacted with the corner portions (<b>127</b><i>a </i>and <b>127</b><i>b</i>) are provided between the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>and the pin-shaped terminals (<b>123</b> and <b>124</b>) where the lead-out parts are bound. As a result, since movements in the radial direction of the contacted parts (<b>110</b><i>t </i>and <b>110</b><i>v</i>) are prevented or reduced, the lead-out parts (the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>) are led out through only predetermined positions of the coil bobbin <b>120</b> and are not floated.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Further, in the coil bobbin <b>120</b>, the upper end part of the front face wall part <b>128</b> which is continuously stood up from the rear side flange part <b>121</b><i>c </i>of the wound part <b>121</b> is formed with the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>a</i>, which is formed so as to cut off the front side of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> of the terminal block part <b>122</b>, and the wall face <b>127</b> which is extended upward from the rear end edge of the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>a </i>and continuously connected to the front faces <b>123</b><i>a </i>and <b>124</b><i>a </i>of the root parts of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. In addition, the wall face <b>127</b> is formed so as to be the same flat face as the front faces <b>123</b><i>a </i>and <b>124</b><i>a </i>of the root portions of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. Therefore, the wall face <b>127</b> is receded by one step from the front face wall part <b>128</b> when the coil bobbin <b>120</b> is viewed from the side of the wound part <b>121</b>. As a result, when the coil wire <b>110</b> is to be wound around the wound part <b>121</b>, the coil wire <b>110</b> is hard to be caught by the terminal block part <b>122</b>, the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. Further, since the upper end part of the front face wall part <b>128</b> is formed to be the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>a</i>, in a case that the coil wire <b>110</b> is to be wound around the wound part <b>121</b>, even when the coil wire <b>110</b> is displaced to a side of the terminal block part <b>122</b>, the displaced portion of the coil wire <b>110</b> is returned to the wound part <b>121</b> side without being caught by the terminal block part <b>122</b>. Therefore, disconnection of the coil wire <b>110</b> is prevented when the coil wire <b>110</b> is to be wound around the winding part <b>121</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Further, the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>, the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> and the terminal block part <b>122</b> are integrally formed of resin. Therefore, different from a case that pin-shaped terminals formed of separated members from the terminal block part <b>122</b> are used, even when the terminal block part <b>122</b> is designed in any shape in order to prevent disconnection of the coil wire <b>110</b>, a problem does not occur that the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are detached from the terminal block part <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">In the first embodiment, the tip end part <b>110</b><i>s </i>of the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the tip end part <b>110</b><i>u </i>of the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>are contacted with the root portions of the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b>. However, according to an embodiment of the present invention, the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>are only required to be contacted with the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b> without passing through the positions overlapping with the outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>and thus the contacted positions of the tip end parts <b>110</b><i>s </i>and <b>110</b><i>u </i>are not limited to the root portions of the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Therefore, for example, as shown by the dotted lines in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, it may be structured so that the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b</i>&#x2032; is contacted with the corner portion <b>128</b><i>a </i>between the front face wall part <b>128</b> and the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>b </i>after having been extended obliquely above along the front face wall part <b>128</b> and, after that, the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b</i>&#x2032; is contacted with the corner portion <b>127</b><i>a </i>between the wall face <b>127</b> of the first inner side region <b>129</b><i>a </i>and the wall face <b>130</b> of the second inner side region <b>129</b><i>b </i>and then the tip end part <b>110</b><i>s</i>&#x2032; of the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b</i>&#x2032; is contacted with the outer side in the radial direction (upper side) with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>at an edge position of the rear face <b>123</b><i>b </i>side of the side face <b>123</b><i>c </i>of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>. Similarly, it may be structured so that the tip end part <b>110</b><i>u</i>&#x2032; of the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>&#x2032; is contacted with the outer side in the radial direction (upper side) with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>at an edge position of the rear face <b>124</b><i>b </i>side of the side face <b>124</b><i>c </i>of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Further, as shown by the alternate long and short dash line in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, it may be structured so that the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b</i>&#x2033; is contacted with the corner portion <b>128</b><i>a </i>between the front face wall part <b>128</b> and the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>b </i>after having been extended obliquely above along the front face wall part <b>128</b> and, after that, the tip end part <b>110</b><i>s</i>&#x2033; of the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b</i>&#x2033; is contacted with the outer side in the radial direction (upper side) with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>at an edge position of the front face <b>123</b><i>a </i>side of the side face <b>123</b><i>c </i>of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>. Similarly, it may be structured so that the tip end part <b>110</b><i>u</i>&#x2033; of the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>&#x2033; is contacted with the outer side in the radial direction (upper side) with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>at an edge position of the front face <b>124</b><i>a </i>side of the side face <b>124</b><i>c </i>of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. In these states, the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are respectively penetrated through the through holes <b>102</b> of the wiring circuit board <b>10</b>. Therefore, when the tip end part <b>110</b><i>s</i>&#x2033; and the tip end part <b>110</b><i>u</i>&#x2033; are led out from the through holes <b>102</b> without being pressed by the wiring circuit board <b>10</b>, the similar state can be obtained that the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b</i>&#x2033; and the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>&#x2033; are passed through the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>and then contacted with the respective pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In addition, although not shown, it may be structured so that the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>is contacted with the corner portion <b>128</b><i>a </i>between the front face wall part <b>128</b> and the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>b </i>after having been extended obliquely above along the front face wall part <b>128</b> and, after that, the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>is contacted with a lower end of the corner portion <b>127</b><i>a </i>between the wall face <b>127</b> of the first inner side region <b>129</b><i>a </i>and the wall face <b>130</b> of the second inner side region <b>129</b><i>b </i>and then led out along the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>b </i>and, after that, the tip end part <b>110</b><i>s </i>of the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>is contacted with the edge portion of the rear face <b>123</b><i>b </i>side of the side face <b>123</b><i>c </i>of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>. Similarly, it may be structured so that the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>&#x2032; is led out along the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>b </i>and then the tip end part <b>110</b><i>u </i>of the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>&#x2032; is contacted with an edge portion of the rear face <b>124</b><i>b </i>side of the side face <b>124</b><i>c </i>of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">In any modified example, the coil wire <b>110</b> is not located on the outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>between the portion led out from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>and the binding parts of the respective pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b> and, in addition, the lead-out parts (the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>) do not pass over the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. As a result, the coil wire <b>110</b> is not floated from the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>and thus, even when the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is placed on the terminal block part <b>122</b>, the coil wire <b>110</b> is not pressed by the wiring circuit board <b>10</b>. Therefore, disconnection or damage of the coil wire <b>110</b> due to contact of the coil wire <b>110</b> with the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> or due to that the coil wire <b>110</b> is pulled by depression of the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> can be prevented. Further, since the coil wire <b>110</b> is not located on the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>, an inclination of the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> due to the coil wire <b>110</b> does not occur and the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> can be received by the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>in a face-contacted state. Therefore, the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is received in a stable state.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">In the first embodiment, the inclined face parts <b>125</b><i>b </i>and <b>125</b><i>c </i>are inclined toward the winding part <b>121</b> from the positions adjacent in the circumferential direction to the rear face <b>123</b><i>b </i>of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the rear face <b>124</b><i>b </i>of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. However, it may be structured so that the inclined face parts <b>125</b><i>b </i>and <b>125</b><i>c </i>are inclined toward the wound part <b>121</b> from the front side or the rear side with respect to the positions adjacent in the circumferential direction to the rear face <b>123</b><i>b </i>of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the rear face <b>124</b><i>b </i>of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. In other words, the second inner side regions <b>129</b><i>b </i>and <b>129</b><i>c </i>may be respectively formed from the front side or the rear side with respect to the positions adjacent in the circumferential direction to the rear face <b>123</b><i>b </i>of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the rear face <b>124</b><i>b </i>of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Further, in the first embodiment, the second inner side regions <b>129</b><i>b </i>and <b>129</b><i>c </i>may be structured so that perpendicularly recessed parts are formed instead of the inclined face parts <b>125</b><i>b </i>and <b>125</b><i>c. </i></p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In addition, in the first embodiment, the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b> are made of resin and integrally formed with the wound part <b>121</b> and the terminal block part <b>122</b>. However, a metal pin may be used as the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b>. In this case, for example, the metal pins may be integrally formed with the terminal block part <b>122</b> by insert molding. When the pin-shaped terminal is structured of a metal pin, a portion located on the outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>is regarded as the pin-shaped terminal. An exposed portion of the pin-shaped terminal on an inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>is regarded as a part of the terminal block part <b>122</b>.</p>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">Second Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an enlarged perspective view showing a terminal block part of a coil wound body used in a motor in accordance with a second embodiment of the present invention. A basic structure of the second embodiment is similar to the first embodiment and thus the same reference signs are used in common portions and their detailed descriptions are omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, in the second embodiment, similarly to the first embodiment, a coil bobbin <b>120</b> of a first coil wound body <b>11</b> is formed with a terminal block part <b>122</b> having a large thickness so as to protrude to an outer side in a radial direction from a wound part <b>121</b>. A face directing to the outer side of the most outer portion in the radial direction of the terminal block part <b>122</b> is formed as a circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>on which a wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is disposed in an overlapped manner. Two pieces of a first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and a second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> which are formed in a square bar-shape are stood up to an outer side in the radial direction from the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>of the terminal block part <b>122</b>. The first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are made of resin and, when the coil bobbin <b>120</b> is to be molded by using resin, they are integrally formed with the coil bobbin <b>120</b>. Both of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are stood up at inner side positions in the circumferential direction with respect to side end parts <b>122</b><i>c </i>and <b>122</b><i>d </i>of the terminal block part <b>122</b> and protruded to an outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. Further, the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are stood up at separated positions in the circumferential direction.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">In this embodiment, the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are stood up from a front edge <b>122</b><i>e </i>on an end part on an outer side in the radial direction of the terminal block part <b>122</b>, and a front face wall part <b>128</b> is continuously connected with front faces <b>123</b><i>a </i>and <b>124</b><i>a </i>of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. Therefore, in this embodiment, the front face wall part <b>128</b> is formed so as to be the same flat face as the front faces <b>123</b><i>a </i>and <b>124</b><i>a </i>of the root portions of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. Further, in an end part on an outer side in the radial direction of the terminal block part <b>122</b>, an entire flat face except a region where the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are stood up is formed as a circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. In the coil bobbin <b>120</b> structured as described above, the entire front side of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> is formed to be an inner side region <b>129</b><i>d </i>which is located on an inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. In other words, in a state that the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is disposed on the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>formed on the terminal block part <b>122</b> and the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are penetrated through the through holes <b>102</b> of the land parts <b>101</b> formed in the wiring circuit board <b>10</b>, the inner side region <b>129</b><i>d </i>is formed at the inner side position in the radial direction with respect to the root portions of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> and with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>on which the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is disposed.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">A first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>of the coil wire <b>110</b> is led out from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>to a root portion of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> through a coil wire leading-out path <b>180</b><i>c </i>comprised of the inner side region <b>129</b><i>d </i>and is bound around the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>. Similarly, the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>is also led out from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>to a root portion of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> through the coil wire leading-out path <b>180</b><i>c </i>comprised of the inner side region <b>129</b><i>d </i>and is bound around the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">More specifically, the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>is extended in a counter-clockwise CCW direction from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>and then, extended obliquely above along the front face wall part <b>128</b> in the inner side region <b>129</b><i>d</i>. After that, a tip end part <b>110</b><i>s </i>of the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>(portion which is located at a position between the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and a first binding part <b>110</b><i>a</i>) is contacted with an edge on one side face <b>123</b><i>c </i>side of the root portion of the front face <b>123</b><i>a </i>of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>. The tip end part <b>110</b><i>s </i>of the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>is located at the same height as the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. After that, a tip end side with respect to the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>(first binding part <b>110</b><i>a</i>) in the coil wire <b>110</b> is extended to a rear side while contacting with the side face <b>123</b><i>c </i>and, after that, the tip end side is wound around the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">Further, the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>is extended in a clockwise CW direction from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>and then, extended obliquely above along the front face wall part <b>128</b> in the inner side region <b>129</b><i>d</i>. After that, a tip end part <b>110</b><i>u </i>of the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>(portion which is located at a position between the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>and a second binding part <b>110</b><i>e</i>) is contacted with an edge on one side face <b>124</b><i>c </i>side (which is opposite side to the side face <b>123</b><i>c</i>) of the root portion of the front face <b>124</b><i>a </i>of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. The tip end part <b>110</b><i>u </i>of the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>is located at substantially the same height as the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. After that, a tip end side with respect to the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>(second binding part <b>110</b><i>e</i>) in the coil wire <b>110</b> is extended to a rear side while contacting with the side face <b>124</b><i>c </i>and, after that, the tip end side is wound around the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">Also in this embodiment, since the lead-out parts (the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>) are passed through the coil wire leading-out path <b>180</b><i>c</i>, the lead-out parts are respectively contacted with the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b> without passing through positions overlapping with the outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. In other words, the lead-out parts are respectively passed through the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>and contacted with the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b>. Therefore, the coil wire <b>110</b> is not located at a position on the outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>between the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>and the binding parts of the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b>, and the lead-out parts (the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>) do not pass over the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. As a result, the coil wire <b>110</b> is not floated from the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>and thus, even when the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is placed on the terminal block part <b>122</b>, the coil wire <b>110</b> is not pressed by the wiring circuit board <b>10</b>. Therefore, disconnection or damage of the coil wire <b>110</b> due to contact of the coil wire <b>110</b> with the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> or due to that the coil wire <b>110</b> is pulled by depression of the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> can be prevented. Further, since the coil wire <b>110</b> is not located over the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>, an inclination of the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> due to the coil wire <b>110</b> does not occur and the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> can be received by the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>in a face-contacted state. Therefore, the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is received in a stable state.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">Further, in this embodiment, the coil wire leading-out path <b>180</b><i>c </i>is structured only on the front side of the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b> and thus an area for the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>can be widely secured on the terminal block part <b>122</b>. Therefore, the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> can be received in a stable state.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">Also in this embodiment, the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>are only required to be contacted with the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b> without passing through the positions overlapping with the outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>and thus the contacted positions of the tip end parts <b>110</b><i>s </i>and <b>110</b><i>u </i>are not limited to the root portions of the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">For example, as shown by the dotted line in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the tip end part <b>110</b><i>s</i>&#x2032; of the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b</i>&#x2032; may be led out so as to contact with an outer side in the radial direction (upper side) with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>at an edge portion on the side face <b>123</b><i>c </i>side of the front face <b>123</b><i>a </i>of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>. Similarly, the tip end part <b>110</b><i>u</i>&#x2032; of the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>&#x2032; may be led out so as to contact with an outer side in the radial direction (upper side) with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>at an edge portion on the side face <b>124</b><i>c </i>side of the front face <b>124</b><i>a </i>of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. Also in this case, since the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are respectively penetrated through the through holes <b>102</b> of the wiring circuit board <b>10</b>, when the tip end part <b>110</b><i>s</i>&#x2032; and the tip end part <b>110</b><i>u</i>&#x2032; are led out through the through holes <b>102</b>, similar operations and effects to the second embodiment can be attained.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">Also in the second embodiment, the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b> are made of resin and integrally formed with the winding part <b>121</b> and the terminal block part <b>122</b>. However, a metal pin may be used as the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b>. In this case, for example, the metal pins may be integrally formed with the terminal block part <b>122</b> by insert molding.</p>
<heading id="h-0009" level="1">Third Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is an enlarged perspective view showing a terminal block part of a coil wound body used in a motor in accordance with a third embodiment of the present invention. A basic structure of the third embodiment is similar to the first embodiment and thus the same reference signs are used in common portions and their detailed descriptions are omitted. In the first and second embodiments, the coil wire is bound around from the outer side of the pin-shaped terminal. However, in the third embodiment, the coil wire is bound around from the inner side of the pin-shaped terminal as described below.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, also in the third embodiment, similarly to the first embodiment, a coil bobbin <b>120</b> of a first coil wound body <b>11</b> is formed with a terminal block part <b>122</b> having a large thickness so as to protrude to an outer side in a radial direction from a wound part <b>121</b>. A face directing to the outer side of the most outer portion in the radial direction of the terminal block part <b>122</b> is formed as a circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>on which a wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is disposed in an overlapped manner. Two pieces of a first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and a second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> which are formed in a square bar-shape are stood up to an outer side in the radial direction from the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>of the terminal block part <b>122</b>. The first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are made of resin and, when the coil bobbin <b>120</b> is to be molded by using resin, they are integrally formed with the coil bobbin <b>120</b>. Both of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are stood up at inner side positions in the circumferential direction with respect to side end parts <b>122</b><i>c </i>and <b>122</b><i>d </i>of the terminal block part <b>122</b> and protruded to an outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. Further, the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are stood up at separated positions in the circumferential direction. Further, the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are provided at a substantially center position in the axial line &#x201c;L<b>1</b>&#x201d; direction on an end part on the outer side in the radial direction of the terminal block part <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">On both sides adjacent in the circumferential direction to the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> in the terminal block part <b>122</b>, a region which is adjacent to an opposite side to an extending direction of the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>(counter-clockwise CCW direction) is formed to be an inclined face part <b>125</b><i>e </i>which is inclined toward the wound part <b>121</b>. Further, on both sides adjacent in the circumferential direction to the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>, a region which is adjacent to an opposite side to an extending direction of the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>(clockwise CW direction) is formed to be the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>e </i>which is inclined toward the wound part <b>121</b>. In other words, a portion between the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> of the terminal block part <b>122</b> is cut off toward the front side and the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>e </i>inclining toward the wound part <b>121</b> is formed. The inclined face part <b>125</b><i>e </i>is inclined toward the wound part <b>121</b> from the position adjacent in the circumferential direction to the rear face <b>123</b><i>b </i>of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the rear face <b>124</b><i>b </i>of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">Further, the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>e </i>is connected with the front face wall part <b>128</b>. Therefore, a region between the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> and its front side region is formed to be an inner side region <b>129</b><i>e </i>which is located on an inner side in the radial direction (lower side) with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. In other words, in a state that the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is disposed on the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>and the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are penetrated through the through holes <b>102</b> of the land parts <b>101</b> formed in the wiring circuit board <b>10</b>, the inner side region <b>129</b><i>e </i>is formed at the inner side position in the radial direction with respect to the root portions of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> and with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. An upper side from an edge on the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> side of the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>e </i>is formed with a wall face <b>132</b> which is continuously connected with the side face <b>123</b><i>d </i>of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>. The wall face <b>132</b> is formed in the terminal block part <b>122</b> on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>so as to continuously form the same flat face as the side face <b>123</b><i>d </i>of the root portion of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>. Further, an upper side from an edge on the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> side of the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>e </i>is formed with a wall face <b>133</b> which is continuously connected with the side face <b>124</b><i>d </i>of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. The wall face <b>133</b> is formed in the terminal block part <b>122</b> on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>so as to continuously form the same flat face as the side face <b>124</b><i>d </i>of the root portion of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">In this embodiment, inclined face parts <b>125</b><i>f </i>and <b>125</b><i>g </i>being inclined toward the wound part <b>121</b> are formed in regions adjacent on outer sides to the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. Lower end sides of the inclined face parts <b>125</b><i>f </i>and <b>125</b><i>g </i>are connected with the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>e</i>. Therefore, front sides of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> are also formed in an inclined face part.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">In the terminal block part <b>122</b> structured as described above, a flat face of the outer side end part except the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>, the second pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the inclined face parts <b>125</b><i>e </i>through <b>125</b><i>g </i>is formed to be the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">In this embodiment, an extending direction of the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>is a counter-clockwise CCW direction and the coil wire <b>110</b> is bound around the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> through a clockwise direction CW side with respect to the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> (opposite side to the extending direction of the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c</i>). Therefore, the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>is passed through between the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. Further, an extending direction of the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>is a clockwise CW direction and the coil wire <b>110</b> is bound around the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> through a counter-clockwise direction CCW side with respect to the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> (opposite side to the extending direction of the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c</i>). Therefore, the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>is passed through between the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. The first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>are crossed in a front space of the front face wall part <b>128</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">More specifically, the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>is led out from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>to the root portion of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> through the coil wire leading-out path <b>180</b><i>d </i>comprised of the inner side region <b>129</b><i>e </i>and bound around the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>. In other words, the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>is extended in the counter-clockwise CCW direction from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>along the front face wall part <b>128</b> and next, the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>is contacted with a corner portion <b>128</b><i>a </i>formed by the front face wall part <b>128</b> and the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>e</i>. After that, the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>is extended along the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>e </i>and then the tip end part <b>110</b><i>s </i>of the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>(position located between the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the first binding part <b>110</b><i>a</i>) is contacted with an edge on the rear face <b>123</b><i>b </i>side of the root part of the side face <b>123</b><i>d </i>of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>. Further, the tip end part <b>110</b><i>s </i>of the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>is located at the same height as the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. After that, the tip end side (first binding part <b>110</b><i>a</i>) of the coil wire <b>110</b> with respect to the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>is extended in the circumferential direction while contacting with the rear face <b>123</b><i>b </i>and then the tip end side of the coil wire <b>110</b> is wound around the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">Further, the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>is led out to the root portion of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> through the coil wire leading-out path <b>180</b><i>d </i>comprised of the inner side region <b>129</b><i>e </i>and bound around the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. In other words, the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>is extended in the clockwise CW direction from the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>and then, contacted with a corner portion <b>128</b><i>a </i>formed between the front face wall part <b>128</b> and the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>a</i>. Next, the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>is extended along the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>e </i>and a tip end part <b>110</b><i>u </i>of the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>(position located between the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>and the second binding part <b>110</b><i>e</i>) is contacted with an edge on the rear face <b>124</b><i>b </i>side of the root part of the side face <b>124</b><i>d </i>of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. The tip end part <b>110</b><i>u </i>of the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>is located at substantially the same height as the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. After that, the tip end side (second binding part <b>110</b><i>e</i>) of the coil wire <b>110</b> with respect to the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>is extended in the circumferential direction while contacting with the rear face <b>124</b><i>b </i>and then the tip end side of the coil wire <b>110</b> is wound around the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">Also in this embodiment, since the lead-out parts (the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>) are passed through the coil wire leading-out path <b>180</b><i>d</i>, the lead-out parts are respectively contacted with the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b> without passing through positions overlapping with the outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. Therefore, the coil wire <b>110</b> is not located at a position on the outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>between the winding part <b>110</b><i>c </i>and the binding parts of the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b>, and the lead-out parts (the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>) are not passed over the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. As a result, the coil wire <b>110</b> is not floated from the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>and thus, even when the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is placed on the terminal block part <b>122</b>, the coil wire <b>110</b> is not pressed by the wiring circuit board <b>10</b>. Therefore, disconnection or damage of the coil wire <b>110</b> due to contact of the coil wire <b>110</b> with the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> or due to that the coil wire <b>110</b> is pulled by depression of the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> can be prevented. Further, since the coil wire <b>110</b> is not located over the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>, an inclination of the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> due to the coil wire <b>110</b> does not occur and the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> can be received by the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>in a face-contacted state. Therefore, the wiring circuit board <b>10</b> is received in a stable state.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">Further, since the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>e </i>is formed between the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>, the lead-out parts (first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>) are led out along the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>e </i>and thus the lead-out parts (first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>) are led out in a stable state. Further, since the lead-out parts (first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>) are led out along the inclined face part, an unnecessary floating is hard to occur in the lead-out parts (first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>). Moreover, the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>e </i>is inclined toward the wound part <b>121</b> from the positions adjacent in the circumferential direction to the rear face <b>123</b><i>b </i>of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the rear face <b>124</b><i>b </i>of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. Therefore, the entire lead-out parts (first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>) can be led out along the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>e </i>on the terminal block part <b>122</b> and thus an unnecessary floating is hard to occur in the lead-out parts. Accordingly, a problem can be prevented in which the lead-out parts are caught by something to cause the coil wire to be disconnected.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">Also in this embodiment, the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d </i>are only required to be contacted with the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b> without passing through the positions overlapping with the outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>and thus the contacted positions of the tip end parts <b>110</b><i>s </i>and <b>110</b><i>u </i>are not limited to the root portions of the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">For example, as shown by the dotted line in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, it may be structured so that the first lead-out part <b>110</b><i>b</i>&#x2032; is extended obliquely above along the front face wall part <b>128</b> and then contacted with the corner portion <b>128</b><i>a </i>formed by the front face wall part <b>128</b> and the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>e </i>and, after that, its tip end part <b>110</b><i>s</i>&#x2032; is contacted with an edge on the rear face <b>123</b><i>b </i>side of the side face <b>123</b><i>d </i>of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> on an outer side in the radial direction (upper side) with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. Similarly, it may be structured so that the second lead-out part <b>110</b><i>d</i>&#x2032; is extended obliquely above along the front face wall part <b>128</b> and then contacted with the corner portion <b>128</b><i>a </i>formed by the front face wall part <b>128</b> and the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>e </i>and, after that, its tip end part <b>110</b><i>u</i>&#x2032; is contacted with an edge on the rear face <b>124</b><i>b </i>side of the side face <b>124</b><i>d </i>of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b> on an outer side in the radial direction (upper side) with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a</i>. Also in this case, similar operations and effects to the third embodiment can be attained.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">In the third embodiment, the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>e </i>is inclined toward the wound part <b>121</b> from the positions adjacent in the circumferential direction to the rear face <b>123</b><i>b </i>of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the rear face <b>124</b><i>b </i>of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. However, it may be structured so that the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>e </i>is inclined toward the wound part <b>121</b> from a rear side with respect to the position adjacent in the circumferential direction to the rear face <b>123</b><i>b </i>of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the rear face <b>124</b><i>b </i>of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. In other words, the inner side region <b>129</b><i>e </i>may be formed from a rear side with respect to the position adjacent in the circumferential direction to the rear face <b>123</b><i>b </i>of the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the rear face <b>124</b><i>b </i>of the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">In the third embodiment, the inclined face part <b>125</b><i>e </i>is formed in order to structure the inner side region <b>129</b><i>e </i>between the first pin-shaped terminal <b>123</b> and the second pin-shaped terminal <b>124</b>. However, the inner side region <b>129</b><i>e </i>may be structured by a recessed part which is perpendicularly recessed.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">In the third embodiment, the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b> are made of resin and integrally formed with the wound part <b>121</b> and the terminal block part <b>122</b>. However, a metal pin may be used as the pin-shaped terminals <b>123</b> and <b>124</b>. In this case, for example, the metal pins may be integrally formed with the terminal block part <b>122</b> by insert molding. In accordance with an embodiment of the present invention, when the pin-shaped terminal is structured of a metal pin or the like, a portion located on the outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>is regarded as the pin-shaped terminal. An exposed portion of the pin-shaped terminal on an inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face <b>122</b><i>a </i>is regarded as a part of the terminal block part <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">While the description above refers to particular embodiments of the present invention, it will be understood that many modifications may be made without departing from the spirit thereof. The accompanying claims are intended to cover such modifications as would fall within the true scope and spirit of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">The presently disclosed embodiments are therefore to be considered in all respects as illustrative and not restrictive, the scope of the invention being indicated by the appended claims, rather than the foregoing description, and all changes which come within the meaning and range of equivalency of the claims are therefore intended to be embraced therein.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A coil wound body comprising:
<claim-text>a coil bobbin around which a coil wire is wound, the coil bobbin comprising:
<claim-text>a wound part around which the coil wire is wound;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a terminal block part which is protruded toward an outer side in a radial direction from the wound part;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a circuit board receiving face which is located on the outer side in the radial direction of the terminal block part and on which a wiring circuit board is disposed in an overlapped manner; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>pin-shaped terminals which are located on the outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and protruded toward the outer side in the radial direction; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the coil wire comprises:
<claim-text>a winding part which is wound around the wound part of the coil bobbin;</claim-text>
<claim-text>lead-out parts which are led out from the winding part to contacted positions with the pin-shaped terminals; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>binding parts which are located on tip end sides with respect to the lead-out parts and bound around the pin-shaped terminals;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the coil bobbin is provided with a coil wire leading-out path which reaches to root portions of the pin-shaped terminals from the wound part through an inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the lead-out parts of the coil wire are led out to the contacted positions with the pin-shaped terminals by passing through the coil wire leading-out path without passing through a position overlapping with the outer side in the radial direction of the circuit board receiving face.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The coil wound body according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the pin-shaped terminals are provided on inner sides with respect to both side end parts in a circumferential direction of the terminal block part, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the coil wire leading-out path is structured on an inner side in the circumferential direction with respect to both the side end parts in the circumferential direction of the terminal block part.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The coil wound body according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the lead-out part of the coil wire is led out from the winding part to the pin-shaped terminal in a taut state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The coil wound body according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the coil wire leading-out path of the coil bobbin is structured so as to pass through a front side where the wound part is located with respect to the pin-shaped terminals,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the front side of the terminal block part with respect to the pin-shaped terminals is formed to be a first inner side region which is located on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and structures the coil wire leading-out path of the coil bobbin, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a region which is adjacent in a circumferential direction to the pin-shaped terminal in an extending direction of the lead-out part of the coil wire from the wound part is formed to be a second inner side region which is located on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and structures the coil wire leading-out path of the coil bobbin.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The coil wound body according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>a front face of the pin-shaped terminal where the wound part is located is extended toward a wound part side with respect to the circuit board receiving face so that a wall face is formed so as to be continuously connected with a front face of a root portion of the pin-shaped terminal, and a front space of the wall face is formed to be the first inner side region,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the terminal block part is formed with a wall face which is continuously connected with a side face of the root portion of the pin-shaped terminal in a region adjacent to the pin-shaped terminal in the extending direction of the lead-out part from the wound part, and the wall face is formed to be the second inner side region, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the lead-out part of the coil wire is contacted with a corner portion between the wall face in the first inner side region and the wall face in the second inner side region, and a tip end part of the lead-out part is contacted with an edge on a rear face side of the root portion of a side face of the pin-shaped terminal and bound around the pin-shaped terminal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The coil wound body according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the coil bobbin is provided with a flange part whose diameter is enlarged at an end part of a body part of the wound part, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the lead-out part of the coil wire is contacted with a corner portion between an upper end part of a front face wall part which is continuously formed from the flange part toward the outer side in the radial direction and the wall face of the first inner side region.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The coil wound body according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the region which is adjacent in the circumferential direction to the pin-shaped terminal in the extending direction of the lead-out part of the coil wire from the wound part is formed to be an inclined face part which is inclined toward the wound part of the coil bobbin to structure the second inner side region.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The coil wound body according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the inclined face part is inclined toward the wound part from a position adjacent in the circumferential direction to a rear face of the pin-shaped terminal which is located on an opposite side to the wound part.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The coil wound body according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the coil wire leading-out path of the coil bobbin is structured so as to pass through a front side where the wound part is located with respect to the pin-shaped terminal, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the front side where the wound part is located with respect to the pin-shaped terminal is formed to be an inner side region which is located on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and structures the coil wire leading-out path.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The coil wound body according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the coil wire leading-out path of the coil bobbin is structured so as to pass through a region which is adjacent in a circumferential direction to the pin-shaped terminal on an opposite side to an extending direction of the lead-out part of the coil wire from the wound part, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>in the terminal block part, the region which is adjacent to the pin-shaped terminal and a front side region on the wound part side with respect to the region are formed to be an inner side region which is located on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and structures the coil wire leading-out path.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The coil wound body according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the region which is adjacent to the pin-shaped terminal on the opposite side to the extending direction of the lead-out part of the coil wire from the wound part is formed to be an inclined face part which is inclined toward the wound part to structure the inner side region.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The coil wound body according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the inclined face part is inclined toward the wound part from a position adjacent in the circumferential direction to a rear face of the pin-shaped terminal which is located on an opposite side to the wound part.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The coil wound body according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the pin-shaped terminals and the terminal block part are integrally formed of resin.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The coil wound body according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>a front face of the pin-shaped terminal on a side where the wound part is located is formed with a wall face in the terminal block part so as to extend toward the wound part side with respect to the circuit board receiving face and so as to continuously form a same face on the inner side in the radial direction as the front face of a root portion of the pin-shaped terminal, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>in the terminal block part, a front space of the wall face is formed to be a first inner side region which is located on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and structures the coil wire leading-out path.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The coil wound body according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the pin-shaped terminals are provided on inner sides with respect to both side end parts in a circumferential direction of the terminal block part, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the coil wire leading-out path is structured on an inner side in the circumferential direction with respect to both the side end parts in the circumferential direction of the terminal block part.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The coil wound body according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>a wall face is formed so as to continuously form a same face on the inner side in the radial direction as a side face of a root portion of the pin-shaped terminal in at least one of both sides of the terminal block part which are adjacent in the circumferential direction to the pin-shaped terminal, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the wall face forms a second inner side region which is located on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and structures the coil wire leading-out path.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The coil wound body according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the lead-out part of the coil wire is contacted with a corner portion between the wall face in the first inner side region and the wall face in the second inner side region, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a tip end part of the lead-out part is contacted with an edge on a rear face side of the root portion of the side face of the pin-shaped terminal and bound around the pin-shaped terminal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The coil wound body according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>a wall face is formed so as to continuously form a same face on the inner side in the radial direction as a side face of a root portion of the pin-shaped terminal in at least one of both sides of the terminal block part which are adjacent in the circumferential direction to the pin-shaped terminal, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the wall face forms a second inner side region which is located on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and structures the coil wire leading-out path.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A motor comprising:
<claim-text>a coil wound body which is provided with a coil bobbin around which a coil wire is wound;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a stator which is provided with the coil wound body; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a rotor which is provided with a rotor magnet and disposed on an inner peripheral side of the stator;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the coil bobbin comprises:
<claim-text>a wound part around which the coil wire is wound;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a terminal block part which is protruded toward an outer side in a radial direction from the wound part;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a circuit board receiving face which is located on the outer side in the radial direction of the terminal block part and on which a wiring circuit board is disposed in an overlapped manner; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>pin-shaped terminals which are located on the outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and protruded toward the outer side in the radial direction;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the coil wire comprises:
<claim-text>a winding part which is wound around the wound part;</claim-text>
<claim-text>lead-out parts which are led out from the winding part to the pin-shaped terminals; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>binding parts which are located on tip end sides with respect to the lead-out parts and bound around the pin-shaped terminals;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the coil bobbin is provided with a coil wire leading-out path which reaches to root portions of the pin-shaped terminals from the wound part through an inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the lead-out parts of the coil wire contact the pin-shaped terminals by passing through the coil wire leading-out path without passing through a position overlapping with the outer side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The motor according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>in the terminal block part of the coil bobbin, a front side of the pin-shaped terminal is formed to be a first inner side region which is located on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and structures the coil wire leading-out path,</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one of both sides of the terminal block part which are adjacent in the circumferential direction to the pin-shaped terminal is formed to be a second inner side region which is located on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and structures the coil wire leading-out path,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the wiring circuit board is formed with land parts having a through hole at a center of the land part,</claim-text>
<claim-text>in a state that the wiring circuit board is disposed on the circuit board receiving face which is formed in the terminal block part and the pin-shaped terminals are penetrated through the through holes, the first inner side region and the second inner side region are formed at positions which are located on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the root portions of the pin-shaped terminals and the circuit board receiving face which is formed in the terminal block part,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the lead-out parts of the coil wire are contacted with the pin-shaped terminals by passing through the coil wire leading-out path which is formed of the first inner side region and the second inner side region.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The motor according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the pin-shaped terminals and the terminal block part are integrally formed of resin,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first inner side region is formed so that a front face of the pin-shaped terminal on a side where the wound part is located is formed with a wall face which is formed in the terminal block part so as to extend toward the wound part side with respect to the circuit board receiving face and so as to continuously form a same face on the inner side in the radial direction as the front face of a root portion of the pin-shaped terminal, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second inner side region is formed so that a wall face is formed so as to continuously form a same face on the inner side in the radial direction as a side face of the root portion of the pin-shaped terminal in at least one of both sides of the terminal block part which are adjacent in the circumferential direction to the pin-shaped terminal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The motor according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>in the terminal block part of the coil bobbin, a front side of the pin-shaped terminal is formed to be a first inner side region which is located on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and structures the coil wire leading-out path,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the wiring circuit board is formed with land parts having a through hole at a center of the land part,</claim-text>
<claim-text>in a state that the wiring circuit board is disposed on the circuit board receiving face which is formed in the terminal block part and the pin-shaped terminals are penetrated through the through holes, the first inner side region is formed at a position which is located on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the root portions of the pin-shaped terminals and the circuit board receiving face which is formed in the terminal block part, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the lead-out parts of the coil wire are contacted with the pin-shaped terminals by passing through the coil wire leading-out path which is formed of the first inner side region.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. The motor according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the pin-shaped terminals and the terminal block part are integrally formed of resin, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first inner side region is formed so that a front face of the pin-shaped terminal on a side where the wound part is located is formed with a wall face which is formed in the terminal block part so as to extend toward the wound part side with respect to the circuit board receiving face and so as to continuously form a same face on the inner side in the radial direction as the front face of the root portion of the pin-shaped terminal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. The motor according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>in the terminal block part of the coil bobbin, a wall face is formed so as to continuously form a same face on the inner side in the radial direction as a side face of a root portion of the pin-shaped terminal in at least one of both sides of the terminal block part which are adjacent in the circumferential direction to the pin-shaped terminal,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the wall face forms a second inner side region which is located on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the circuit board receiving face and structures the coil wire leading-out path,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the wiring circuit board is formed with land parts having a through hole at a center of the land part,</claim-text>
<claim-text>in a state that the wiring circuit board is disposed on the circuit board receiving face which is formed in the terminal block part and the pin-shaped terminals are penetrated through the through holes, the second inner side region is formed at a position which is located on the inner side in the radial direction with respect to the root portions of the pin-shaped terminals and the circuit board receiving face which is formed in the terminal block part, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the lead-out parts of the coil wire are contacted with the pin-shaped terminals by passing through the coil wire leading-out path which is formed of the second inner side region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
