<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624567-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624567</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13341300</doc-number>
<date>20111230</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>162</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>577</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>40</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>323267</main-classification>
<further-classification>323268</further-classification>
<further-classification>323283</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Controllers for DC/DC converters</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6424128</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Hiraki et al.</name>
<date>20020700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>323268</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6667603</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Hiraki et al.</name>
<date>20031200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>323268</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7253596</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Yamamoto et al.</name>
<date>20070800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>323281</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7493504</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Chapuis</name>
<date>20090200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>713300</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8294299</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Huang et al.</name>
<date>20121000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>307 75</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>18</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>323265</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>323267</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>323268</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>323272</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>323282-285</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130169254</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130704</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Popescu</last-name>
<first-name>Serban Mihai</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Carlos</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Popescu</last-name>
<first-name>Serban Mihai</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Carlos</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>O2Micro, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Santa Clara</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Berhane</last-name>
<first-name>Adolf</first-name>
<department>2838</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A controller for a DC/DC converter includes multiple signal generators and a control circuit. The signal generators generate multiple pulse signals, each signal generator generating a corresponding pulse signal of the pulse signals and controlling the corresponding pulse signal to have a predetermined pulse width by counting a same preset number of cycles of a same oscillating signal. The control circuit selectively activates the signal generators according to an output of the DC/DC converter to generate the pulse signals.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="161.29mm" wi="225.04mm" file="US08624567-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="245.45mm" wi="179.41mm" file="US08624567-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="219.79mm" wi="156.38mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624567-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="221.06mm" wi="157.65mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624567-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="247.40mm" wi="180.68mm" file="US08624567-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="187.79mm" wi="142.24mm" file="US08624567-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="224.96mm" wi="173.65mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624567-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="255.02mm" wi="191.60mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624567-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="146.73mm" wi="148.00mm" file="US08624567-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">DC to DC (or DC/DC) converters are used to convert input DC (direct current) voltages to output DC voltages. Such converters may step down (buck) or step up (boost) the input DC voltages. The converter typically has a controller, a driver, a pair of switches, and an LC filter coupled to the pair of switches. The controller provides a control signal to the driver which then drives the pair of switches, e.g., a high-side switch and a low-side switch. The driver alternately turns each switch on and off thereby controlling the inductor current and the output voltage of the DC/DC converter. The controller typically utilizes a pulse-width modulation (PWM) signal to control the state of the high-side and low-side switches.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a schematic diagram of a conventional DC/DC converter using multiple controllers <b>102</b>_<b>1</b>-<b>102</b>_N. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, multiple PWM signals are generated to control the states of several sets of switches (e.g., switches S<sub>11 </sub>and S<sub>12</sub>, switches S<sub>21 </sub>and S<sub>22</sub>, . . . , and switches S<sub>N1 </sub>and S<sub>N2</sub>), and each set of switches includes a high-side switch (e.g., the switch S<sub>11</sub>-S<sub>N1</sub>) and a low-side switch (e.g., the switch S<sub>12</sub>-S<sub>N2</sub>). Taking the controller <b>102</b>_<b>1</b> for example, if the PWM signal generated by the controller <b>102</b>_<b>1</b> is logic high, the high-side switch S<sub>11 </sub>is on and the low-side switch S<sub>12 </sub>is off. Thus, the inductor L<sub>1 </sub>is coupled to the input voltage source V<sub>IN</sub>, and the inductor current begins to ramp up. If the PWM signal is logic low, the high-side switch S<sub>11 </sub>is off and the low-side switch S<sub>12 </sub>is on. Thus, the inductor L<sub>1 </sub>is coupled to ground, and the inductor current begins to ramp down. Hence, the controller <b>102</b>_<b>1</b> can control the inductor current by controlling the duty cycle of the PWM signal.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, currents flowing through the inductors L<sub>1</sub>-L<sub>N </sub>are controlled by controllers <b>102</b>_<b>1</b>-<b>102</b>_N, respectively. More specifically, each controller <b>102</b>_<b>1</b>-<b>102</b>_N receives a sense signal indicative of a corresponding inductor current from a corresponding sense resistor R<sub>1</sub>-R<sub>N</sub>. Each controller <b>102</b>_<b>1</b>-<b>102</b>_N includes a comparator to compare the sense signal with a reference level, and controls the duty cycle of the PWM signal according to the comparison. In order to balance the inductor currents respectively flowing through the inductors L<sub>1</sub>-L<sub>N</sub>, the pulse widths of the PWM signals are required to be identical. However, due to non-ideality of analog circuits, e.g., the sense resistors R<sub>1</sub>-R<sub>N</sub>, comparators in the controllers <b>102</b>_<b>1</b>-<b>102</b>_N, etc., the controllers <b>102</b>_<b>1</b>-<b>102</b>_N may not be able to control the pulse widths of the PWM signals to be identical.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Accordingly, there is a need in the art for DC/DC converters that better control pulse width for each of the generated PWM signals.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In one embodiment, a controller for a DC/DC converter includes multiple signal generators and a control circuit coupled to the signal generators. The signal generators generate multiple pulse signals, each signal generator generating a corresponding pulse signal of the pulse signals and controlling the corresponding pulse signal to have a predetermined pulse width by counting a same preset number of cycles of a same oscillating signal. The control circuit selectively activates the signal generators according to an output of the DC/DC converter to generate the pulse signals.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Features and advantages of embodiments of the claimed subject matter will become apparent as the following detailed description proceeds, and upon reference to the drawings, wherein like numerals depict like parts, and in which:</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a schematic diagram of a conventional DC/DC converter.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates a block diagram of an example of a controller for use with a DC/DC converter in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a schematic diagram of an example of a PWM generator in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates examples of waveforms of PWM signals, trigger signals, an oscillating signal and an index signal PULSE in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates a schematic diagram of an example of a control channel in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates a block diagram of an example of a DC/DC converter in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates a block diagram of an example of a DC/DC converter in accordance with another embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> illustrates a flowchart of examples of operations performed by a controller, in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Reference will now be made in detail to the embodiments of the present invention. While the invention will be described in conjunction with these embodiments, it will be understood that they are not intended to limit the invention to these embodiments. On the contrary, the invention is intended to cover alternatives, modifications and equivalents, which may be included within the spirit and scope of the invention as defined by the appended claims.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Furthermore, in the following detailed description of the present invention, numerous specific details are set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding of the present invention. However, it will be recognized by one of ordinary skill in the art that the present invention may be practiced without these specific details. In other instances, well known methods, procedures, components, and circuits have not been described in detail as not to unnecessarily obscure aspects of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Embodiments according to the present invention provide controllers for controlling DC/DC converters. The controller can provide multiple pulse-width modulation signals to control an output of the DC/DC converter. Advantageously, a controller of the present invention can control the pulse-width modulation signals to have the same pulse width.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates a block diagram of an example of a controller <b>200</b> for use with a DC/DC converter in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. The controller <b>200</b> includes a set of control terminals T<sub>1</sub>, T<sub>2</sub>, . . . , and T<sub>N</sub>, each providing a respective pulse signal, e.g., PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_N (N is a natural number and N&#x2267;1), as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, according to an output, e.g., an output voltage or an output current, of the DC/DC converter. By way of example, a differential signal based on feedback signals RS+ and RS&#x2212; shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is indicative of an output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>of the DC/DC converter. The controller <b>200</b> can control the PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_N according to the feedback signals RS+ and RS&#x2212;, to control the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>of the DC/DC converter.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">More specifically, in one embodiment, the controller <b>200</b> includes a PWM generator <b>204</b>, an oscillator <b>202</b>, and a control channel <b>206</b>, which can be integrated inside the controller <b>200</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. In another embodiment of the present invention, the oscillator <b>202</b> and the control channel <b>206</b> can be placed outside the controller <b>200</b>. The oscillator <b>202</b> generates a first oscillating signal CLK, e.g., a clock signal. The control channel <b>206</b> generates an index signal PULSE according to both a reference voltage V<sub>SET </sub>and a signal which is representative of the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>of the DC/DC converter, e.g., the differential signal based on the feedback signals RS+ and RS&#x2212;. The PWM generator <b>204</b>, which is coupled to the oscillator <b>202</b> and the control channel <b>206</b>, generates multiple PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_N according to both a first oscillating signal CLK provided from the oscillator <b>202</b> and an index signal PULSE provided from the control channel <b>206</b>. The index signal PULSE is representative of the output of the DC/DC converter.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Advantageously, the PWM generator <b>204</b> can control the PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_N based on the first oscillating signal CLK, such that the PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_N have substantially the same pulse width. As used herein, &#x201c;substantially the same pulse width&#x201d; means the pulse widths of the PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_N can have differences caused by, e.g., non-ideality of circuit components, so long as the differences are within a range that can be neglected. The PWM generator <b>204</b> can also control the PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_N based on the index signal PULSE, such that the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>of the DC/DC converter is adjusted to the level of the reference voltage V<sub>SET</sub>. Further details are described below.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a schematic diagram of an example of the PWM generator <b>204</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is described in combination with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The PWM generator <b>204</b> includes multiple signal generators and a control circuit coupled to the signal generators. In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the control circuit includes a counter <b>302</b>, and each signal generator includes a counting unit <b>304</b>_<b>1</b>, <b>304</b>_<b>2</b>, . . . , or <b>304</b>_N. In one embodiment, the counter <b>302</b> can be a ring counter that includes a circular shift register; however, the present invention is not so limited. The signal generators, e.g., the counting units <b>304</b>_<b>1</b>-<b>304</b>_N, are operable for generating pulse signals, e.g., the PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_N, respectively. As described below, the signal generators further control each pulse signal to have a predetermined pulse width by counting a same preset number of cycles of a same oscillating signal, e.g., the first oscillating signal CLK. The control circuit, e.g., the counter <b>302</b>, selectively activates the signal generators according to both the index signal PULSE and a second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032;, e.g., a clock signal, to generate the pulse signals. Moreover, the counter <b>302</b> further controls the number of activated signal generators based on the duration of the index signal PULSE. For example, the signal generators including the counting units <b>304</b>_<b>1</b>-<b>304</b>_N are activated selectively based on a logic AND result of the index signal PULSE and the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032;. To be more specific, in one embodiment of the present invention, one of the counting units <b>304</b>_<b>1</b>, <b>304</b>_<b>2</b>, . . . , and <b>304</b>_N is selected and activated by the counter <b>302</b> when both the index signal PULSE and the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032; are logic high; also, while the index signal PULSE stays logic high, additional counting units from the counting units <b>304</b>_<b>1</b>, <b>304</b>_<b>2</b>, . . . , and <b>304</b>_N are activated successively on the active edges of the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032;. As used herein, &#x201c;activated successively&#x201d; means a counting unit <b>304</b>_<b>1</b>, <b>304</b>_<b>2</b>, . . . , or <b>304</b>_N is activated one by one in sequence. One or more counting units may be activated depending on the duration of the index signal PULSE. Further details are illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> below. Moreover, as detailed in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the index signal PULSE is logic high when the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>of the DC/DC converter is less than a reference voltage V<sub>SET</sub>, and is logic low when the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>of the DC/DC converter reaches or is greater than the reference voltage V<sub>SET</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In one embodiment, when the index signal PULSE is logic high to indicate that the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>is less than the reference voltage V<sub>SET</sub>, the counter <b>302</b> starts the activation of the counting units <b>304</b>_<b>1</b>, <b>304</b>_<b>2</b>, . . . , or <b>304</b>_N. With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, an AND gate <b>306</b> receives the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032; and the index signal PULSE. In this embodiment, when the index signal PULSE is logic high, the waveform of the AND result signal is substantially the same as the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032;. In other words, the counter <b>302</b> starts to count on each active edge of the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032; when the index signal PULSE becomes logic high. A trigger signal TR_<b>1</b>, TR_<b>2</b>, . . . , or TR_N, e.g., a logic-high pulse, is generated from the counter <b>302</b> when the counter <b>302</b> counts according to one clock cycle of the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032;. By way of example, the counter <b>302</b> can increase a count value CT<sub>302 </sub>by one in response to each cycle of the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032;. When the count value CT<sub>302 </sub>reaches K (K is a natural number and 1&#x2266;K&#x2266;N), the counter <b>302</b> generates the trigger signal TR_K to the counting unit <b>304</b>_K. If the index signal PULSE stays logic high long enough to span multiple clock cycles of the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032;, then the count value CT<sub>302 </sub>continues to increment and multiple trigger signals are generated successively. As used herein, &#x201c;multiple trigger signals are generated successively&#x201d; means the trigger signals are generated one by one in sequence, each in response to one corresponding clock pulse of the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032;. For example, on a first clock cycle of the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032; after the index signal PULSE becomes logic high, a trigger signal TR_K is generated; on a second clock cycle next to the first clock cycle if the index signal PULSE stays logic high, a trigger signal TR_(K+1) is generated; and on a third clock cycle next to the second clock cycle if the index signal PULSE stays logic high, a trigger signal TR_(K+2) (here, K&#x2266;(N&#x2212;2)) is generated; and so on.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Furthermore, in one embodiment, the counter <b>302</b> can be set to have a start value N<sub>S </sub>and an end value N<sub>E </sub>(N<sub>S </sub>and N<sub>E </sub>are natural numbers and 1&#x2266;N<sub>S</sub>&#x2266;N<sub>E</sub>&#x2266;N). In one such embodiment, when the count value CT<sub>302 </sub>of the counter <b>302</b> equals the end value N<sub>E</sub>, the counter <b>302</b> generates a loop closure signal from a terminal X of the counter <b>302</b>, and the loop closure signal then resets the counter <b>302</b> to N<sub>S </sub>instead of increasing the count value CT<sub>302 </sub>by one.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Moreover, in one embodiment, the counter <b>302</b> includes a circular shift register (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) controlled by both the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032; and the index signal PULSE as mentioned above. The circular shift register (e.g., an 8-bit register) has parallel outputs (e.g., trigger signals TR_<b>1</b>-TR_<b>8</b>). The circular shift register can be clocked according to the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032; based on the index signal PULSE, and can circularly shift a binary code (e.g., with initial register values of 10000000) accordingly. The circular shift register can cause the counter <b>302</b> to generate the trigger signals TR_<b>1</b>-TR_<b>8</b>, e.g., a number of logic-high pulses successively, in response to multiple clock cycles of the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Additionally, in one embodiment, the counting units <b>304</b>_<b>1</b>-<b>304</b>_N are selectively activated by the trigger signals to successively generate multiple pulse signals. More specifically, in response to a trigger signal (e.g., TR_K) from the counter <b>302</b>, a corresponding counting unit (e.g., <b>304</b>_K) starts to count the first oscillating signal CLK, e.g., by counting the clock cycles of the first oscillating signal CLK, and generates a PWM signal (e.g., PWM_K) at a first level, e.g., logic high. A count value CT<sub>304</sub><sub><sub2>&#x2014;</sub2></sub><sub>K </sub>of the counting unit <b>304</b>_K can increase by one in response to each clock cycle of the first oscillating signal CLK. When the count value CT<sub>304</sub><sub><sub2>&#x2014;</sub2></sub><sub>K </sub>obtained by counting the clock cycles of the first oscillating signal CLK equals a preset end value CT<sub>PRE</sub>, the corresponding counting unit <b>304</b>_K controls the corresponding PWM signal PWM_K to have a second level (e.g., logic low). Consequently, the counting unit <b>304</b>_K controls the PWM signal PWM_K to have a predetermined pulse width that is equal to the preset end value CT<sub>PRE </sub>multiplied by the cycle period of the first oscillating signal CLK.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In other words, based on the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032; and the index signal PULSE, the counter <b>302</b> generates multiple trigger signals. In response to the trigger signals (e.g., from the trigger signals TR_<b>1</b>-TR_N), corresponding counting units (e.g., from the counting units <b>304</b>_<b>1</b>-<b>304</b>_N) respectively start to count the first oscillating signal CLK and successively generate the corresponding PWM signals (e.g., from PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_N) at a first level. As each count value (e.g., from the count values CT<sub>304</sub><sub><sub2>&#x2014;</sub2></sub><sub>1</sub>-CT<sub>304</sub><sub><sub2>&#x2014;</sub2></sub><sub>N</sub>) obtained by counting the clock cycles of the first oscillating signal CLK equals the preset end value CT<sub>PRE</sub>, the respective counting unit controls the corresponding PWM signals to have a second level. More specifically, in response to a first trigger signal, a first counting unit starts to count the first oscillating signal CLK and generates a first PWM signal at the first level, e.g., logic high. In response to a second trigger signal (the next trigger signal following the first trigger signal), a second counting unit also starts to count the first oscillating signal CLK and generates a second PWM signal at the first level, e.g., logic high. A third trigger signal (the next trigger signal following the second trigger signal) activates a third counting unit, and so on. When the count value from the first counting unit increases to a preset end value, e.g. CT<sub>PRE</sub>, the first counting unit controls the first PWM signal to have the second level, e.g., logic low. The second, third, etc., counting units behave similarly when their respective counts reach the preset end value. Because each of the counting units <b>304</b>_<b>1</b>, <b>304</b>_<b>2</b>, . . . , and <b>304</b>_N counts the same oscillating signal, e.g., the first oscillating signal CLK, to the same value, e.g., the preset end value CT<sub>PRE </sub>as mentioned above, the PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_N generated by the counting units <b>304</b>_<b>1</b>-<b>304</b>_N can have substantially the same pulse width.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In an embodiment of the present invention, the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032; and the first oscillating signal CLK are the same signal, both generated from the same oscillator, e.g., the oscillator <b>202</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. However, in another embodiment, the first and second oscillating signals CLK and CLK&#x2032; are different signals. In one such embodiment, the frequency of the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032; can be a submultiple of the frequency of the first oscillating signal CLK, and the active edge of the first oscillating signal CLK will always substantially coincide with the active edge of the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032;. Here, &#x201c;substantially coincide&#x201d; means the active edge of the first oscillating signal CLK and the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032; can have a slight delay with each other caused by, e.g., non-ideality of circuit components, as long as the delay is within a range that can be neglected.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the AND gate <b>306</b> provides the logic AND result of the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032; and the index signal PULSE to the counter <b>302</b>. For example, when the index signal PULSE is logic low, the counter <b>302</b> receives a logic low signal and the activation of the signal generators is halted; thus, the generation of the pulse signals is halted. When the index signal PULSE is logic high, the counter <b>302</b> receives a signal substantially the same as the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032; and starts counting to generate trigger signals accordingly. When the index signal PULSE stays logic high, the counter <b>302</b> receives a number M<sub>CLK </sub>(M<sub>CLK </sub>is a natural number, where in M<sub>CLK</sub>&#x2267;1) of successive pulses, each substantially the same as one clock pulse of the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032;, and the counter <b>302</b> generates the number M<sub>CLK </sub>of trigger signals. Accordingly, corresponding counting units of the counting units <b>304</b>_<b>1</b>-<b>304</b>_N are activated by the generated trigger signals to successively generate multiple pulse signals. The number of generated pulse signals equals the number of the activated counting units, which equals the number of the generated trigger signals, e.g., M<sub>CLK</sub>. The number M<sub>CLK </sub>of the successively generated pulse signals is determined by the index signal PULSE. By way of example, when the index signal PULSE is logic high, the number of successive pulses received by the counter <b>302</b> increases; thus, by counting accordingly, the counter <b>302</b> increases the number of the generated trigger signals and the number of the successively generated pulse signals, e.g., M<sub>CLK</sub>. Moreover, as detailed in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the DC/DC converter can increase the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>by increasing the number M<sub>CLK </sub>of successively generated pulse signals, or decrease the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>by halting the generation of the pulse signals. As a result, the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>of the DC/DC converter can be adjusted to the reference voltage V<sub>SET</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In operation, in one embodiment, if the index signal PULSE is logic low, the counter <b>302</b> receives a logic-low input signal and therefore the count value CT<sub>302 </sub>of the counter <b>302</b> is unchanged. If the index signal PULSE is logic high, the counter <b>302</b> receives one or more pulses, each substantially the same with one clock pulse of the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032;, and the counter <b>302</b> increases the count value CT<sub>302 </sub>accordingly. As the count value CT<sub>302 </sub>of the counter <b>302</b> increases, a corresponding counting unit (e.g., one of the counting units <b>304</b>_<b>1</b>-<b>304</b>_N) is activated to generate a corresponding pulse signal. For instance, on counting to K (1&#x2266;K&#x2266;N), the counter <b>302</b> provides the trigger signal TR_K to activate the counting unit <b>304</b>_K, which in response generates the PWM signal PWM_K at logic high and starts to count the first oscillating signal CLK. The counting unit <b>304</b>_K further controls the PWM signal PWM_K to be logic low when the count value CT<sub>304</sub><sub><sub2>&#x2014;</sub2></sub><sub>K </sub>gained by counting the first oscillating signal CLK reaches the preset end value CT<sub>PRE </sub>mentioned above. Advantageously, all the pulses of the PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_N can be configured with identical pulse widths by having the counting units <b>304</b>_<b>1</b>-<b>304</b>_N count the same preset number (e.g., the preset end value CT<sub>PRE</sub>) of clock cycles of the oscillating signal, e.g., the first oscillating signal CLK. Furthermore, compared with the analog circuits (e.g., sense resistors and comparators) of the controllers in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the digital circuits (e.g., the counting units <b>304</b>_<b>1</b>, <b>304</b>_<b>2</b>, . . . , and <b>304</b>_N in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) in the present invention can control the pulse widths of the PWM signals more accurately.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates examples of waveforms of the PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_<b>6</b> generated from the PWM generator <b>204</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, in combination with the waveforms of the trigger signals TR_<b>1</b>-TR_<b>6</b>, the first oscillating signal CLK, and the index signal PULSE in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is described in combination with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the first and second oscillating signals CLK and CLK&#x2032; are the same signal, the start value of the counter <b>302</b> is set to one, the end value of the counter <b>302</b> is set to six, and the preset end value CT<sub>PRE </sub>for each counting unit <b>304</b>_<b>1</b>-<b>304</b>_<b>6</b> is set to four.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, from time t<b>1</b> to time t<b>6</b>, the index signal PULSE is logic high. As such, five pulses, each substantially the same as the clock pulse of the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032;, are received at the counter <b>302</b>, enabling the counter <b>302</b> to count from, e.g., one to five. Thus, five trigger signals, e.g., TR_<b>1</b>-TR_<b>5</b>, are consecutively generated by the counter <b>302</b> as shown. In response to the trigger signals TR_<b>1</b>-TR_<b>5</b>, the signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_<b>5</b> are set to logic high at, e.g., times t<b>1</b>, t<b>2</b>, t<b>3</b>, t<b>4</b> and t<b>5</b>, respectively. In other words, the counting units <b>304</b>_<b>1</b>-<b>304</b>_<b>5</b> are activated to generate five pulse signals, e.g., the pulses of the signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_<b>5</b>, in a successive way (a pulse signal per counting unit). Because the preset end value CT<sub>PRE </sub>is four in this example, each of the signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_<b>5</b> has a pulse width equal to four cycles of the first oscillating signal CLK. From time t<b>6</b> and to time t<b>11</b>, the index signal PULSE is logic low, and therefore the counter <b>302</b> halts the counting of the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032; and the activation of the counting units. Similarly, from time t<b>11</b> to t<b>12</b>, the index signal PULSE is logic high, and one pulse (e.g., substantially the same with one clock pulse of the second oscillating signal CLK&#x2032;) is received at the counter <b>302</b>. By time t<b>6</b>, the count value CT<sub>302 </sub>of the counter <b>302</b> has reached five, so that the counter <b>302</b> will count to six at time t<b>11</b>. Thus, at time t<b>11</b>, the trigger signal TR_<b>6</b> is provided from the counter <b>302</b> to activate the counting unit <b>304</b>_<b>6</b> to generate a pulse signal, e.g., a pulse of the signal PWM_<b>6</b>. By time t<b>12</b>, the count value CT<sub>302 </sub>has reached six, which is the end value configured for the counter <b>302</b> in this example, and so the counter <b>302</b> is reset by the loop closure signal and the count value CT<sub>302 </sub>is reset to zero. At times t<b>12</b> through t<b>14</b>, the index signal PULSE is logic low, and therefore the counter <b>302</b> halts the counting and the generation of the trigger signals. From time t<b>14</b> to time t<b>16</b>, the index signal PULSE becomes logic high again, and the counter <b>302</b> starts counting from one. Similarly, two trigger signals TR_<b>1</b> and TR_<b>2</b> are generated to set the signals PWM_<b>1</b> and PWM_<b>2</b> to logic high again at times t<b>14</b> and t<b>15</b>, respectively. The process continues on in this manner.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Moreover, when the index signal PULSE is logic high, the number M<sub>CLK </sub>of the successively generated pulse signals increases. When the index signal PULSE is logic low, the generation of the pulse signals is halted and the number M<sub>CLK </sub>is reset to an initial value, e.g., zero. Taking <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> for example, from time t<b>1</b> to time t<b>6</b>, the index signal PULSE is logic high and the number M<sub>CLK </sub>increases from zero to five. From time t<b>6</b> to time t<b>11</b>, the index signal PULSE is logic low and no new pulse signal is generated, resetting the number M<sub>CLK </sub>to zero.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Furthermore, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_<b>6</b> have identical pulse widths. By way of example, upon the counting unit <b>304</b>_<b>1</b> being activated by the trigger signal TR_<b>1</b> at time t<b>1</b>, the counting unit <b>304</b>_<b>1</b> starts to count the first oscillating signal CLK. When the count value CT<sub>304</sub><sub><sub2>&#x2014;</sub2></sub><sub>1 </sub>obtained by counting the first oscillating signal CLK reaches a preset end value CT<sub>PRE</sub>, which in this example is configured to be four as stated above, the counting unit <b>304</b>_<b>1</b> controls the pulse of the PWM signal PWM_<b>1</b> to be logic low at time t<b>5</b>. Thus, the pulse of the PWM signal PWM_<b>1</b> has a width of four clock cycles of the first oscillating signal CLK. Similarly, the pulses of the PWM signals PWM_<b>2</b>-PWM_<b>6</b> are controlled to have the same width, which is also equal to four clock cycles of the first oscillating signal CLK.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Advantageously, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_<b>6</b> are generated and controlled based on the index signal PULSE, such that the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>of the DC/DC converter is adjusted to the level of the reference voltage V<sub>SET</sub>. More details will be described below. Moreover, the PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_<b>6</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> have identical pulse widths.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates a schematic diagram of an example of the control channel <b>206</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is described in combination with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. The control channel <b>206</b> includes a comparator <b>504</b> for comparing the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>of the DC/DC converter with the reference voltage V<sub>SET </sub>to generate the aforementioned index signal PULSE, so as to control the number M<sub>CLK </sub>of successively generated pulse signals. The comparator <b>504</b> can be any type of comparator, such as a clock comparator, etc. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the control channel <b>206</b> can further include a differential amplifier <b>502</b> for generating a signal which is indicative of the output of the DC/DC converter.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the differential amplifier <b>502</b> receives feedback signals RS+ and RS&#x2212; and provides a signal S<sub>IND </sub>to the comparator <b>504</b>. The feedback signals RS+ and RS&#x2212; can be a pair of differential signals whose difference is equal to the level of the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>of the DC/DC converter. The output signal S<sub>IND </sub>of the differential amplifier <b>502</b> can be linearly proportional to (e.g., equal to) the output voltage V<sub>OUT</sub>. Thus, the comparator <b>504</b> can compare the reference voltage V<sub>SET </sub>with the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>by comparing the reference voltage V<sub>SET </sub>with the signal S<sub>IND</sub>. In one embodiment, if the value of the signal S<sub>IND </sub>is greater than the value of the reference voltage V<sub>SET</sub>, e.g., if the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>is greater than the reference voltage V<sub>SET</sub>, then the output signal of the comparator <b>504</b>, which is the index signal PULSE, is set to be logic low. If the value of the signal S<sub>IND </sub>is less than the value of the reference voltage V<sub>SET</sub>, e.g., if the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>is less than the reference voltage V<sub>SET</sub>, then the index signal PULSE is set to be logic high. As illustrated above, the index signal PULSE, when logic high, enables the counter <b>302</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> to start counting, which results in activating a set of counting units, e.g, the counting units <b>304</b>_<b>1</b>-<b>304</b>_N, to generate a set of pulse signals.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In other words, in one embodiment, the control channel <b>206</b> determines whether a condition is satisfied; if the condition is satisfied, then a pulse signal PWM_K can be generated from an activated counting unit <b>304</b>_K. If the reference voltage V<sub>SET </sub>together with the signal S<sub>IND </sub>indicate that the condition is satisfied, then the index signal PULSE is generated by the control channel <b>206</b> with logic high. In one embodiment, the condition is that the signal S<sub>IND </sub>is less than the reference voltage V<sub>SET</sub>. When the index signal PULSE is logic high, the counter <b>302</b> is controlled to start counting and provide trigger signals to activate the corresponding counting units. The activated counting units generate corresponding pulse signals in response to the trigger signals. Consequently, the index signal PULSE that represents the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>of the DC/DC converter can be used to indicate when the number of pulse signals generated is to be increased.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates a block diagram of an example of a DC/DC converter <b>600</b> in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is described in combination with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the DC/DC converter <b>600</b> includes a controller <b>612</b>, multiple sets of switches, e.g., switches S<sub>11 </sub>and S<sub>12</sub>, switches S<sub>21 </sub>and S<sub>22</sub>, . . . , switches S<sub>N1 </sub>and S<sub>N2</sub>, and multiple inductors L<sub>1</sub>-L<sub>N</sub>. In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the controller <b>612</b> includes controller <b>200</b>, which includes the oscillator <b>202</b>, the PWM generator <b>204</b>, and the control channel <b>206</b> as described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In one embodiment, the control channel <b>206</b> generates a index signal PULSE according to both a reference voltage V<sub>SET </sub>and a signal which is representative of an output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>of the DC/DC converter <b>600</b>, e.g., the differential signal based on the feedback signals RS+ and RS&#x2212;, and the PWM generator <b>204</b> generates a set of PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>, PWM_<b>2</b>, . . . , and PWM_N to control the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>of the DC/DC converter <b>600</b>. More specifically, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the PWM generator <b>204</b> provides the set of PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_N to control the switches via a signal bus <b>618</b>. If the signal PWM_<b>1</b> is in a first state, e.g., logic high, the switch S<b>11</b> is on and the switch S<b>12</b> is off. Accordingly, the inductor L<sub>1 </sub>is coupled to the input voltage source V<sub>IN</sub>, and an inductor current I<sub>L1 </sub>flowing through the inductor L<b>1</b> increases. If the PWM signal is in a second state, e.g., logic low, the switch S<sub>11 </sub>is off and the switch S<sub>12 </sub>is on. Thus, the inductor L<sub>1 </sub>is coupled to ground, and the inductor current I<sub>L1 </sub>decreases. The inductor current I<sub>L1 </sub>thus controls the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>of the DC/DC converter <b>600</b> accordingly. In one embodiment, the controller <b>200</b> can turn off the switches S<sub>11 </sub>and S<sub>12 </sub>when the inductor L<sub>1 </sub>ramps down to zero. Thus, when a pulse of the signal PWM_<b>1</b> occurs, the inductor current I<sub>L1 </sub>is generated. The signals PWM_<b>2</b>-PWM_N can control inductor currents respectively flowing through the inductors L<sub>2</sub>-L<sub>N </sub>in like manner.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">As described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the controller <b>200</b> can generate a set of pulses of the signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_N. When the index signal PULSE stays logic high, the PWM generator <b>204</b> generates a number M<sub>CLK </sub>of pulses of the signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_N. Thus, the number M<sub>CLK </sub>of the successively generated pulse signals is determined by the index signal PULSE; in other words, the controller <b>200</b> can control the number M<sub>CLK </sub>of the pulses according to the output voltage V<sub>OUT</sub>. In one embodiment, the controller <b>200</b> increases the number M<sub>CLK </sub>of the pulses according to the output voltage V<sub>OUT</sub>. More specifically, the controller <b>200</b> can increase the number M<sub>CLK </sub>if the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>is less than the reference voltage V<sub>SET</sub>. The controller <b>200</b> can also halt the generation of the pulses if the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>reaches or is greater than the reference voltage V<sub>SET</sub>. Accordingly, if the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>is less than the reference voltage V<sub>SET</sub>, the controller <b>200</b> can increase the summation of the inductor currents of the inductors L<sub>1</sub>-L<sub>N </sub>to increase the output voltage V<sub>OUT</sub>. If the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>reaches or is greater than the reference voltage V<sub>SET</sub>, the controller <b>200</b> can halt the generation of the inductor currents to decrease the output voltage V<sub>OUT</sub>. Consequently, the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>can be adjusted to the reference voltage V<sub>SET</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In one embodiment, the OSC <b>202</b> can control the frequency of the first oscillating signal CLK to be linearly proportional to a difference between the input voltage V<sub>IN </sub>and the reference voltage V<sub>SET</sub>, e.g., the target level of the output voltage V<sub>OUT</sub>. Additionally, according to the above description, the pulse widths of the PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_N can be linearly proportional to the cycle period of the first oscillating signal CLK. Thus, the pulse widths of the PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_N are inversely proportional to the difference between the input voltage V<sub>IN </sub>and the reference voltage V<sub>SET</sub>. In this way, the inductor currents of the inductors L<sub>1</sub>-L<sub>N </sub>are controlled to have constant ripple amplitudes &#x394;I. Furthermore, the pulse widths of the PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_N can be identical, and therefore the inductor currents of the inductors L<sub>1</sub>-L<sub>N </sub>can have substantially the same ripple amplitude &#x394;I. As used herein &#x201c;substantially the same ripple amplitude&#x201d; means the ripple amplitudes for the inductor currents of the inductors L<sub>1</sub>-L<sub>N </sub>can have differences caused by, e.g., non-ideality of circuit components, so long as the differences are within a range that can be neglected. Advantageously, the inductor currents of the inductors L<sub>1</sub>-L<sub>N </sub>can have the same and constant ripple amplitude &#x394;I. As a result, the inductor currents of the inductors L<sub>1</sub>-L<sub>N </sub>are balanced with one another and the stability of the DC/DC converter <b>600</b> is enhanced.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the PWM generator <b>204</b> provides the PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_N to control the output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>of the DC/DC converter <b>600</b> via the signal bus <b>618</b>. A start value of the counter in the PWM generator <b>204</b>, e.g., the counter <b>302</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, is set to be one, and an end value of the counter in the PWM generator <b>204</b> is set to be N.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates a block diagram of an example of a DC/DC converter <b>700</b> in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is described in combination with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the DC/DC converter <b>700</b> includes a controller <b>712</b>, multiple switch pairs SWP_<b>1</b>, SWP_<b>2</b>, . . . , SWP_N, and multiple inductors L<sub>1</sub>-L<sub>N</sub>. Switch pairs SWP_<b>1</b>-SWP_N include similar structures to that of the switch pairs S<sub>11 </sub>and S<sub>12</sub>, S<sub>21 </sub>and S<sub>22</sub>, . . . , and S<sub>N1 and S</sub><sub>N2 </sub>shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the controller <b>712</b> includes two control circuitries <b>200</b>_<b>1</b> and <b>200</b>_<b>2</b>. The control circuitry <b>200</b>_<b>1</b> generates a first PWM signal set [PWM_<b>1</b>, PWM_<b>2</b>, . . . , and PWM_A] to control an output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>of the DC/DC converter <b>600</b> (A&#x2266;N) via the signal bus <b>618</b>. The control circuitry <b>200</b>_<b>2</b> generates a second PWM signal set [PWM_(A+1), PWM_(A+2), . . . , and PWM_N] to control another output voltage V<sub>OUT&#x2032;</sub> of the DC/DC converter <b>600</b> via a signal bus <b>718</b>, in a similar manner. The configurations of the control circuitry <b>200</b>_<b>1</b> and <b>200</b>_<b>2</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> are each similar to the configuration of the controller <b>200</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">According to the above description of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the pulse widths of the PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b> to PWM_A can be inversely proportional to the difference between the input voltage V<sub>IN </sub>and the reference voltage V<sub>SET</sub>, and the pulse widths of the PWM signals PWM_(A+1) to PWM_N can be inversely proportional to the difference between the input voltage V<sub>IN </sub>and the reference voltage V<sub>SET&#x2032;</sub>. The reference voltage V<sub>SET&#x2032;</sub> indicates a reference level of the output voltage V<sub>OUT&#x2032;</sub> of the DC/DC converter <b>600</b> such that the output voltage V<sub>OUT&#x2032;</sub> is adjusted to the level of the reference voltage V<sub>SET&#x2032;</sub>. In this way, the inductor currents of the inductors L<sub>1</sub>-L<sub>A </sub>are controlled to have constant ripple amplitudes &#x394;I, and the inductor currents of the inductors L<sub>(A+1)</sub>-L<sub>N </sub>are controlled to have constant ripple amplitudes &#x394;I&#x2032;. Additionally, as described above, the pulse widths of the PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b> to PWM_A can be identical, and the pulse widths of the PWM signals PWM_(A+1) to PWM_N can be identical. As a result, the inductor currents of the inductors L<sub>1</sub>-L<sub>A </sub>are balanced with one another, the inductor currents of the inductors L<sub>(A+1)</sub>-L<sub>N </sub>are balanced with one another, and the stability of the DC/DC converter <b>700</b> is enhanced.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Furthermore, in the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, a start value of the counter in the control circuitry <b>200</b>_<b>1</b>, e.g., the counter <b>302</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, is set to be one, and an end value of the counter in the control circuitry <b>200</b>_<b>1</b> is set to be A. A start value of the counter in the control circuitry <b>200</b>_<b>2</b>, e.g., also represented by the counter <b>302</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, is set to be (A+1), and an end value of the counter in the control circuitry <b>200</b>_<b>2</b> is set to be N. However, the invention is not so limited. In another embodiment, the start values and the end values for the control circuitry <b>200</b>_<b>1</b> and <b>200</b>_<b>2</b> can have other values as long as the control circuitry <b>200</b>_<b>1</b> and <b>200</b>_<b>2</b> do not simultaneously control the same PWM signal.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Although two control circuitries (e.g., <b>200</b>_<b>1</b> and <b>200</b>_<b>2</b>) are disclosed in the DC/DC converter <b>700</b> in the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, any number of control circuitries can be included in the DC/DC converter.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> illustrates a flowchart <b>800</b> of examples of operations performed by a controller, in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is described in combination with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In block <b>802</b>, the controller (e.g., the controller <b>200</b> or the control circuitry <b>200</b>_<b>1</b> and <b>200</b>_<b>2</b>) selectively activates a set of signal generators (e.g., the counting units <b>304</b>_<b>1</b>-<b>304</b>_N) according to an output, e.g., an output voltage or an output current, of a DC/DC converter (e.g., converter <b>600</b> or <b>700</b>), to generate a set of pulse signals (e.g., pulses of the PWM signals PWM_<b>1</b>-PWM_N).</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In block <b>804</b>, the signal generators (e.g., the counting units <b>304</b>_<b>1</b>-<b>304</b>_N) control each pulse signal of the pulse signals to have a predetermined pulse width by counting a same preset number (e.g., the preset end value CT<sub>PRE</sub>) of a same oscillating signal (e.g., the first oscillating signal CLK). Advantageously, the signal generators (e.g., the counting units <b>304</b>_<b>1</b>-<b>304</b>_N) control the pulse signals to have substantially the same pulse width by multiplying the same preset number with a cycle period of the same oscillating signal.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In summary, embodiments according to the present invention provide controllers for DC/DC converters and methods for controlling the generation of multiple pulse signals. The controller for the DC/DC converter includes multiple signal generators to generate multiple PWM signals. By having the signal generators count the same oscillating signal to the same value, the PWM signals can have the same pulse width. The controller can be used in many applications such as multiphase DC/DC converters in GPUs (graphic processor units), CPUs (central processor units), VRs (voltage regulators), etc.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">While the foregoing description and drawings represent embodiments of the present invention, it will be understood that various additions, modifications and substitutions may be made therein without departing from the spirit and scope of the principles of the present invention as defined in the accompanying claims. One skilled in the art will appreciate that the invention may be used with many modifications of form, structure, arrangement, proportions, materials, elements, and components and otherwise, used in the practice of the invention, which are particularly adapted to specific environments and operative requirements without departing from the principles of the present invention. The presently disclosed embodiments are therefore to be considered in all respects as illustrative and not restrictive, the scope of the invention being indicated by the appended claims and their legal equivalents, and not limited to the foregoing description.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A controller for a DC/DC converter, comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of signal generators that generates a plurality of pulse signals having a predetermined pulse width by counting cycles of a same first oscillating signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control circuit, coupled to said signal generators, that selectively activates said signal generators according to an output of said DC/DC converter to generate said pulse signals,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each signal generator of said signal generators, in response to a trigger signal from said control circuit, starts to count said cycles of said same first oscillating signal and generates a corresponding pulse signal of said pulse signals at a first level, and wherein said each signal generator controls said corresponding pulse signal to have a second level when a count value obtained by counting said cycles of said same first oscillating signal equals a preset end value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The controller as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said predetermined pulse width is determined by multiplying said preset end value with a cycle period of said same first oscillating signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The controller as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said signal generators control said pulse signals to have substantially the same pulse width by counting a same preset number of cycles of said same first oscillating signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The controller as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said DC/DC converter comprises a plurality of switches and a plurality of inductors, and wherein each pulse signal of said pulse signals controls a pair of switches of said plurality of switches to control a current flowing through a corresponding inductor of said plurality of inductors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The controller as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein said current increases if said each pulse signal is in a first state, and wherein said current decreases if said each pulse signal is in a second state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The controller as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein said signal generators generate said pulse signals, by counting a same preset number of cycles of said same first oscillating signal, to control a plurality of currents flowing through said inductors to have substantially the same ripple amplitude.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The controller as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a comparator operable for comparing said output of said DC/DC converter with a reference level.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The controller as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein if said output is less than said reference level, then said control circuit increases said output by activating at least one signal generator of said signal generators one-by-one to generate at least one pulse signal, each of said at least one signal generator activated in response to a clock pulse of a second oscillating signal; and wherein if said output increases to said reference level, then said control circuit halts the activation of said signal generators.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The controller as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said control circuit comprises a shift register that is controlled by a second oscillating signal and that causes said control circuit to generate, in response to a plurality of cycles of said second oscillating signal, a plurality of trigger signals to selectively activate said signal generators.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A method for controlling a DC/DC converter, comprising:
<claim-text>selectively activating a plurality of signal generators according to an output of said DC/DC converter to generate a plurality of pulse signals; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>controlling each pulse signal of said pulse signals to have a predetermined pulse width, said controlling comprising:
<claim-text>controlling said each pulse signal to have a first level in response to a trigger signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>starting to count cycles of a same oscillating signal in response to said trigger signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>controlling said each pulse signal to have a second level when a count value obtained by counting said cycles of said same oscillating signal equals a same preset end value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein said selectively activating comprises:
<claim-text>activating at least one signal generator of said signal generators one by one to generate at least one pulse signal if said output is less than a reference level, wherein each of said at least one signal generator is activated in response to a clock pulse of a clock signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>halting the activation of said signal generators if said output increases to said reference level.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. A controller for a DC/DC converter, comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of terminals that provide a plurality of pulse signals; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>control circuitry that is coupled to said terminals and selectively activates a plurality of signal generators according to an output of said DC/DC converter to generate said pulse signals, and controls each pulse signal of said pulse signals to have a predetermined pulse width by counting cycles of a same oscillating signal, wherein each signal generator of said signal generators, in response to a trigger signal, starts to count said cycles of said same first oscillating signal and generates a corresponding pulse signal of said pulse signals at a first level, and wherein said each signal generator controls said corresponding pulse signal to have a second level when a count value obtained by counting said cycles of said same first oscillating signal equals a preset end value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The controller as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein said predetermined pulse width is determined by multiplying said preset end value with a cycle period of said same oscillating signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The controller as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein said signal generators control said pulse signals to have substantially the same pulse width by counting a same preset number of cycles of said same oscillating signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The controller as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein said DC/DC converter comprises a plurality of switches and a plurality of inductors, and wherein said each pulse signal controls a pair of switches of said plurality of switches to control a current flowing through a corresponding inductor of said plurality of inductors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The controller as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein said current increases if said each pulse signal is in a first state, and wherein said current decreases if said each pulse signal is in a second state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The controller as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein said signal generators generate said pulse signals, by counting a same preset number of cycles of said same oscillating signal, to control a plurality of currents flowing through said inductors to have substantially the same ripple amplitude.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The controller as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein if said output is less than a reference level, then said control circuitry increases said output by activating at least one signal generator of said signal generators one-by-one to generate at least one pulse signal, each of said at least one signal generator activated in response to a clock pulse of a clock signal; and wherein if said output increases to said reference level, then said control circuitry halts the activation of said signal generators. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
