<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624987-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624987</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12834749</doc-number>
<date>20100712</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2009-173437</doc-number>
<date>20090724</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>217</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>232</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>3482111</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Image capturing apparatus, method of controlling the same, and program therefor</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0156706</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Koehler et al.</name>
<date>20030800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>37926505</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0076251</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yasuda</name>
<date>20070400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0236583</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Vuong et al.</name>
<date>20071000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>34823199</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0068675</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Sakuda</name>
<date>20080300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>358474</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2007-97052</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20070400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2008-42552</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20080200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>22</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>725105</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>7</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110019017</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110127</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ohshima</last-name>
<first-name>Hideaki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kawasaki</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ohshima</last-name>
<first-name>Hideaki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kawasaki</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Carter, DeLuca, Farrell &#x26; Schmidt LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Canon Kabushiki Kaisha</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Velez</last-name>
<first-name>Roberto</first-name>
<department>2662</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Kao</last-name>
<first-name>Yih-Sien</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A communication apparatus is provided, which discloses a plurality of control content items to an external apparatus. The control content items are used to cause the communication apparatus to perform processing for generating content, and to generate different content in different formats. If one of the plurality of the control content items is requested from the external apparatus, the communication apparatus performs processing according to the requested control content, and transmits the generated content. The disclosed control content items are each in a format of the content generated in the processing according to the control content.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="115.99mm" wi="124.71mm" file="US08624987-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="260.27mm" wi="181.10mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624987-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="162.48mm" wi="107.19mm" file="US08624987-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="137.33mm" wi="123.61mm" file="US08624987-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="129.96mm" wi="117.35mm" file="US08624987-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="226.65mm" wi="178.99mm" file="US08624987-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="264.75mm" wi="188.47mm" file="US08624987-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="264.41mm" wi="176.53mm" file="US08624987-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to an image capturing apparatus, and a method of controlling the same, and a program therefor.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In recent years, the trade organization Digital Living Network Alliance (DLNA&#xae;) established guidelines for mutually sharing digital content such as still images, moving images, and voice between devices from different manufacturers, and the guidelines now are widespread. DLNA compliant devices can transmit/receive digital content between a digital media server (DMS) that provides the digital content and a digital media player (DMP) that displays the digital content. Thereby, the DMP can display the digital content provided from the DMS.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Japanese Patent Application Laid-Open No. 2007-97052 discusses a technology that enables display of image data in real time on an image display apparatus after a reading apparatus such as a scanner reads the data.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Japanese Patent Application Laid-Open No. 2008-42552 discusses a technology that enables direct transmission and display of image data to and on an image display apparatus via a network when a reading apparatus such as a scanner reads the data.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The former patent literature, however, only referred to the technology to control a start of reading by a display apparatus from a reading apparatus that serves as an image provider. There is no reference to other controls.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In contrast, the latter patent literature discusses a technology to control a change in settings, in addition to the control of reading by a display apparatus as to the content provided from a reading apparatus that serves as an image provider. The technology, however, requires a display apparatus to have a file for determining setting values.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The present invention is directed to a technology that enables various controls on an image capturing apparatus that provides content from an external apparatus, and does not require the external apparatus to have information such as setting files.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to an aspect of the present invention, an image forming apparatus includes a communication apparatus that transmits content recorded in a recording medium to an external apparatus in response to a request for the content from the external apparatus. The communication apparatus includes a disclosure unit to disclose control content items to the external apparatus. The control content items may be used to cause the communication apparatus to perform processing for generating the content, and to generate content in different formats, respectively. The communication apparatus also includes a generation unit to generate content, if one of the control content items is requested from the external apparatus, by performing processing corresponding to the requested control content item. The communication apparatus further includes a transmission unit to transmit the content generated by the generation unit. Each control content item disclosed by the disclosure unit is in a format that is the same as that of content generated in processing according to the requested control content item.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Further features and aspects of the present invention will become apparent from the following detailed description of exemplary embodiments with reference to the attached drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The accompanying drawings, which are incorporated in and constitute a part of the specification, illustrate exemplary embodiments, features, and aspects of the invention and, together with the description, serve to explain the principles of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a hardware configuration of a digital camera.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a flowchart illustrating a process to transmit content information to be disclosed to a display apparatus after a digital camera is turned on.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a folder configuration of control content to be disclosed to a display apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates a configuration of a folder of content that is stored in a recording medium and is disclosed to a display apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a flowchart illustrating a process to reproduce still images on a display apparatus, after content of the still image is requested from the display apparatus to a digital camera.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flowchart illustrating a process to reproduce moving images on a display apparatus, after content of the moving images is requested from the display apparatus to the digital camera, until capturing moving images at a digital camera is stopped.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a flowchart illustrating a process to reproduce voice on a displays device after voice content is requested from a displays device to a digital camera.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Exemplary embodiments, features, and aspects of the present invention will now be described in detail below with reference to the attached drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In the following exemplary embodiments, a digital camera <b>100</b>, which is an image capturing apparatus, serves as a content providing server. A display apparatus <b>200</b> displays content. A network connects the digital camera <b>100</b> and the display apparatus <b>200</b> to communicate with each other.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a hardware configuration of a digital camera according to a first exemplary embodiment according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The digital camera <b>100</b> has a lens unit <b>101</b>. The lens unit <b>101</b> is configured with a plurality of lenses and is interchangeable. The lens unit <b>101</b> includes a lens control circuit <b>101</b><i>a </i>and a diaphragm control circuit <b>101</b><i>b</i>, and can communicate with a microcomputer <b>127</b>. The microcomputer <b>127</b> controls the lens control circuit <b>101</b><i>a </i>to move and focus a focusing lens in the lens unit <b>101</b>. The amount of lens movement is calculated based on an output from a focus control circuit <b>117</b>. The microcomputer <b>127</b> controls the diaphragm control circuit <b>101</b><i>b </i>to change an optical aperture value.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The digital camera <b>100</b> includes a quick-return mirror <b>102</b>, a shutter <b>103</b>, an optical filter <b>104</b>, an image sensor <b>105</b>, an analog-to-digital (A/D) converter <b>106</b>, and a timing generation circuit <b>108</b>. The quick-return mirror <b>102</b> is disposed in a photographing optical path to move between a position where the mirror leads light of an object from the lens unit <b>101</b> to a finder optical system (not illustrated) and a position where the mirror is retracted from the optical path. The optical filter <b>104</b> is covered with a dust-shielding glass plate. The image sensor <b>105</b> converts optical images into electrical signals. The A/D converter <b>106</b> converts analogue signals output from the image sensor <b>105</b> into digital signals. The timing generation circuit <b>108</b> supplies clock signals and control signals to the image sensor <b>105</b> and the A/D converter <b>106</b>. A memory control circuit <b>111</b> and a microcomputer <b>127</b>, which will be described later, control the timing generation circuit <b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The digital camera <b>100</b> further includes an image processing circuit <b>107</b>, an image display circuit <b>109</b>, a memory control circuit <b>111</b>, an image display memory <b>112</b>, a display unit <b>110</b>, and a memory <b>113</b>. The image processing circuit <b>107</b> applies predetermined pixel interpolating processing and development processing to data from the A/D converter <b>106</b> and data from the memory control circuit <b>111</b>, based on processing data added to the image data. The memory control circuit <b>111</b> controls the A/D converter <b>106</b>, the image processing circuit <b>107</b>, the timing generation circuit <b>108</b>, the image display memory <b>112</b>, the memory <b>113</b>, and the compression/expansion circuit <b>114</b>. The signals converted by the A/D converter <b>106</b> are written into the image display memory <b>112</b> or the memory <b>113</b> via the image processing circuit <b>107</b> and the memory control circuit <b>111</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The display unit <b>110</b> is a display such as thin film transistor liquid crystal display (TFT-LCD). The image data written in the image display memory <b>112</b> for display is displayed on the display unit <b>110</b> by the image display circuit <b>109</b>. The memory <b>113</b> is used as an image buffer area that temporarily stores image data that is not compressed after captured. The memory <b>113</b> also is used as a work buffer area that stores processing data for development processing of image data at the image processing circuit <b>107</b>, autofocus (AF)/auto-exposure (AE)/auto white balance (AWB) (AF/AE/AWB) calculation results, and other data that is temporarily used. In addition, the memory <b>113</b> also is used as a file buffer that stores image data compressed at the compression/expansion circuit <b>114</b>. The memory <b>113</b> has a capacity sufficient to store a predetermined number of still images and a predetermined volume of moving images. Accordingly, a large volume of images can be written into the memory <b>113</b> at high speed even in the case of continuous shooting where a plurality of still images is captured sequentially.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The digital camera <b>100</b> further includes a compression/expansion circuit <b>114</b>, a shutter control circuit <b>115</b>, a mirror control circuit <b>116</b>, a focus control circuit <b>117</b>, a light metering circuit <b>118</b>, a microcomputer <b>127</b>, and a non-volatile memory <b>119</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The compression/expansion circuit <b>114</b> compresses/expands image data to Joint Photographic Experts Group (JPEG) data, using an adaptive discrete cosine transform (ADCT) for example. The compression/expansion circuit <b>114</b> reads image data from the memory <b>113</b>, and writes the data into the memory <b>113</b> after compression/expansion processing thereof. The shutter control circuit <b>115</b> controls the shutter <b>103</b>. The mirror control circuit <b>116</b> drives and controls the quick-return mirror <b>102</b> to move into and out of the photographing optical path. The focus control circuit <b>117</b> measures a distance between the focusing lens in the lens unit <b>101</b> and an object, and controls the focusing lens based on the distance. The light metering circuit <b>118</b> measures a luminance of an object, and controls an exposure based on the luminance. The microcomputer <b>127</b> controls the overall digital camera <b>100</b>. The non-volatile memory <b>119</b> stores various programs including an image capturing processing program, an image processing program, and a program for recording image file data on a recording medium as created there. The non-volatile memory <b>119</b> stores other programs such as an operation system (OS) that runs multitasking of the above programs, and adjustment values for various controls.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The digital camera <b>100</b> further includes various operation units. The operation units include button switches, dials, and touch panels that are used by a user to input various operating instructions to the microcomputer <b>127</b>. These operation units will be specifically described here. A release switch <b>120</b> includes a SW<b>1</b> mode when the switch <b>120</b> is half-way pressed and a SW<b>2</b> mode when the switch <b>120</b> is fully pressed. In the SW<b>1</b> mode of the release switch <b>120</b>, the microcomputer <b>127</b> starts shooting preparation such as autofocus (AF) processing and auto-exposure (AE) processing.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In the SW<b>2</b> mode of the release switch <b>120</b>, the microcomputer <b>127</b> starts the following processing. The microcomputer <b>127</b> performs image capturing processing that includes reading signals from the image sensor <b>105</b> and writing the signals into the memory <b>113</b> via the A/D converter <b>106</b> and the memory control circuit <b>111</b>. The microcomputer <b>127</b> also performs: white-balance correction processing according to a white-balance mode set for image data, using the image processing circuit <b>107</b>, and development processing. Furthermore, the microcomputer <b>127</b> performs recording processing that includes reading developed image data from the memory <b>113</b>, compressing the data at the compression/expansion circuit <b>114</b>, and writing the data into a recording medium.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">A menu operation switch <b>121</b> includes menu keys, set keys, and cross keys (not illustrated). A user can use the menu operation switch <b>121</b> to input various instructions such as a change in setting of shooting and developing conditions of the camera and a selection of power-saving mode of an external recording medium, while checking a screen displayed on the display unit <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Next, units and components connected to the digital camera <b>100</b> will be described. The digital camera <b>100</b> includes a power source control circuit <b>122</b>, an interface (I/F) control unit <b>123</b>, and a connector <b>125</b>. The power source control circuit <b>122</b> includes a battery detection circuit, a DC-DC converter, and a switch circuit that switches blocks to be turned on. The power source control circuit <b>122</b> detects presence of battery, type of the battery, and an amount of remaining power of the battery. The power source control circuit <b>122</b> controls the DC-DC converter in response to detected results and instructions from the microcomputer <b>127</b>, and supplies power of an adequate voltage to each unit including a recording medium for an adequate period.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The I/F control unit <b>123</b> controls a recording medium such as a memory card. The connector <b>125</b> connects the digital camera <b>100</b> to a recording medium such as a memory card.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The digital camera <b>100</b> includes a communication unit <b>128</b>. The communication unit <b>128</b> controls transmission/reception of information and content between the digital camera <b>100</b> and the display apparatus <b>200</b>. The communication unit <b>128</b> controls communication between the digital camera <b>100</b> and the display apparatus <b>200</b> via a communication path such as wireless LAN and wired LAN.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The digital camera <b>100</b> is provided with a recording medium <b>130</b> such as a memory card and a hard disk. The recording medium <b>130</b> includes a storage medium unit <b>133</b> composed of a semiconductor memory, and an I/F control unit <b>132</b> that is an interface to the digital camera <b>100</b> and controls the storage medium unit <b>133</b>. The recording medium <b>130</b> also includes a connector <b>131</b> that is connected to the digital camera <b>100</b>. In the exemplary embodiment, the recording medium <b>130</b> is a memory card configured with a semiconductor memory. The digital camera <b>100</b> has a housing provided with an inlet through which the recording medium <b>130</b> is inserted. The inlet of the digital camera <b>100</b> is provided with an openable/closable lid that covers the opening of the inlet.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">When the microcomputer <b>127</b> executes processing according to a predetermined program, processing in a flowchart, which will be described later, is run on the digital camera <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The display apparatus <b>200</b> has hardware such as a central processing unit (CPU), a memory, and a display. When the CPU of the display apparatus <b>200</b> executes processing according to a program stored in the memory of the display apparatus <b>200</b>, processing in a flowchart, which will be described later, is run on the display apparatus <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0005" num="0000">&#x3c;Content Providing Process Flow&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a flowchart illustrating a process flow for transmitting content information to be disclosed to a display apparatus after a digital camera is turned on.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">An instruction from a user activates the digital camera <b>100</b>, and starts the following process. In S<b>202</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> establishes a network via the communication unit <b>128</b>. The establishment of the network requires necessary items such as Internet Protocol (IP) address of the digital camera <b>100</b>. The digital camera <b>100</b>, in addition to the requirements set therein, is supposed to have a network configuration using a protocol such as Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol (TCP/IP).</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In S<b>203</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> is initialized to function as a content providing server. In this exemplary embodiment, the digital camera <b>100</b> functions as a digital media server (DMS). The digital camera <b>100</b> has a still-image capturing function and a moving-image capturing function. The digital camera <b>100</b> further has a function to change camera setting in each image capturing mode.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In S<b>204</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> generates control content that is associated with a start control of still-image capturing, in a format of image content that is generated in the still image capturing (e.g., JPEG file format). The digital camera <b>100</b> also generates control content that is associated with a start control of moving-image capturing, in a format of image content that is generated in the moving image capturing (e.g., MPEG4 file format). In the exemplary embodiment, the digital camera <b>100</b> also generates control content that is associated with a change in camera setting, in a format of voice content (e.g., MP3 file).</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a folder configuration of control content disclosed to a display apparatus. The disclosure here refers to notification of the content managed by its own apparatus, by the digital camera <b>100</b> to the display apparatus <b>200</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the configuration has control content &#x201c;Release.JPG&#x201d; <b>303</b>, under a folder <b>300</b> for still image capturing, which is associated with a start control of still image capturing (control information for starting still image capturing). In response to a request from a display apparatus to obtain the control content Release.JPG <b>303</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> starts to capture still images. The control content indicates an access to content in the digital camera <b>100</b> from an external device, and controls and causes the digital camera <b>100</b> to execute predetermined operations. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the configuration has control content Movie.MOV <b>304</b>, under a folder <b>301</b> for moving image capturing, which is associated with a start control of moving image capturing (control information on start of moving image capturing). In this exemplary embodiment, content for setting change is provided as control content in MP3 format. The format of the content may be any format other than voice files. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the configuration has control content ISO100.MP3 <b>305</b>, under a setting folder <b>302</b>, which is associated with a change control to ISO 100.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> again, in S<b>205</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> generates content information of digital content in the recording medium <b>130</b> for example that is inserted into the digital camera <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates a folder configuration of media content, which is generally called content, such as images and music files that are stored in a recording medium to be disclosed to a display apparatus. In this exemplary embodiment, there are recording media <b>130</b> consisted of a CompactFlash (CF) card and SD card.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the configuration has a file <b>403</b> including content IMG<sub>&#x2014;</sub>0001.JPG and IMG<sub>&#x2014;</sub>0002.JPG of the CF card, under a CF folder <b>400</b>. The configuration also has a file <b>404</b> including content IMG<sub>&#x2014;</sub>0001.JPG and IMG<sub>&#x2014;</sub>0002.JPG of the SD card, under an SD folder <b>402</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> again, in S<b>206</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> transmits the content information generated in S<b>204</b> and S<b>205</b> (e.g., information illustrate in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref>), in response to a request for the information from the display apparatus <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Next, processing in the digital camera <b>100</b> will be described in a case where control content is requested from the displays device <b>200</b> after the content information is provided to the display apparatus <b>200</b>. In this exemplary embodiment, the provided content information includes control content (still image control content) of still images. The following is a description of processing in the digital camera <b>100</b> when the still image control content is requested from the display apparatus <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0006" num="0000">&#x3c;Still Image Capturing Operation Sequence&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a flowchart illustrating operations for reproducing still images on a display apparatus after still image content is requested from the display apparatus to a digital camera.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In S<b>501</b>, the display apparatus <b>200</b> transmits a transmission request for still image content to the digital camera <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In S<b>502</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines whether a request (transmission request) from the display apparatus <b>200</b> is received. When the digital camera <b>100</b> receives a request from the display apparatus <b>200</b> (YES in S<b>502</b>), the process goes to S<b>503</b>. When the digital camera <b>100</b> does not receive a request (NO in S<b>502</b>), the digital camera <b>100</b> waits for a request.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In S<b>503</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines whether the request from the display apparatus <b>200</b> is about a start control of still image capturing. For example, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines whether the request is about a start control of still image capturing depending on whether the request includes &#x201c;Release.JPG&#x201d; <b>303</b>. More specifically, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines that the request is control of a start of still image capturing when the request includes &#x201c;Release.JPG&#x201d; <b>303</b> (YES in S<b>503</b>), and the process goes to S<b>504</b>. When the request does not include &#x201c;Release.JPG&#x201d; <b>303</b> (i.e., the request includes a file name of still image such as xxxx.JPG) (NO in S<b>503</b>), the digital camera <b>100</b> determines that the request is not about a start control of still image capturing, and the process goes to S<b>507</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In S<b>504</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> performs a control to start capturing still images, and the process goes to S<b>505</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In S<b>505</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines whether the control in S<b>504</b> is successfully achieved. When the control in S<b>504</b> is successfully achieved (YES in S<b>505</b>), the process goes to S<b>506</b>. When the control in S<b>504</b> fails (NO in S<b>505</b>), the process goes to S<b>508</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In S<b>506</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> generates still image content as a result of the capturing of still images. After the digital camera <b>100</b> generates still image content, the process goes to S<b>509</b>. In the generation, the digital camera <b>100</b> writes the still image content into both the memory <b>113</b> and the recording medium <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">In S<b>507</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> reads the requested still image content from the recording medium <b>130</b>, and the process goes to S<b>509</b>. In the exemplary embodiment, if the request does not include the description of &#x201c;Release.JPG&#x201d;, the request includes a file name such as xxxx.JPG that identifies still image content. The digital camera <b>100</b> reads the still image content from the recording medium <b>130</b>, based on the file name.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In S<b>508</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> generates error content in the same format as that of the still image content (i.e., .JPG file format), and the process goes to S<b>509</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In S<b>509</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines the content generated in S<b>506</b> or S<b>508</b>, or the content read in S<b>507</b> as transmission content.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">In S<b>510</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> transmits the content (still image content) determined in S<b>509</b> to the display apparatus <b>200</b> that is the source of the request (the transmitter of the request). After the transmission, the process goes back to S<b>502</b>, where the digital camera <b>100</b> waits for a next request for content.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">In S<b>511</b>, the display apparatus <b>200</b>, which requested the still image content in S<b>501</b> and waited for receipt of the content, receives and displays the still image content transmitted in S<b>510</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The display apparatus <b>200</b> requests still image content based on content information that is provided from the digital camera <b>100</b> that serves as a content providing server, and displays (or reproduces) the still image content. In other words, the display apparatus <b>200</b> without any particular configuration can control capturing of still images in the digital camera <b>100</b>, only by transmitting a request that includes control content &#x201c;Release.JPG&#x201d; (<b>303</b>) associated with a start control of still image capturing.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The configuration of the digital camera <b>100</b> and the operation flow for providing content information of this exemplary embodiment are similar to those in the case of still image content. In this exemplary embodiment, the provided content information includes control content of moving images, and the following is a description of operations to control the digital camera <b>100</b> when the moving image control content is requested from the display apparatus <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0007" num="0000">&#x3c;Moving Image Capturing Operation Sequence&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flowchart illustrating operations for reproducing moving images on a display apparatus after the moving image content is requested from the display apparatus to a digital camera until the moving image capturing is stopped in the digital camera.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">In S<b>601</b>, the display apparatus <b>200</b> transmits a request for transmission of moving image to the digital camera <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">In S<b>602</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines whether a request (transmission request) from the display apparatus <b>200</b> is received. When the digital camera <b>100</b> receives a request from the display apparatus <b>200</b> (YES in S<b>602</b>), the process goes to S<b>603</b>. When the digital camera <b>100</b> does not receive a request (NO in S<b>602</b>), the digital camera <b>100</b> waits for a request.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">In S<b>603</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines whether the request from the display apparatus <b>200</b> is about a start control of moving image capturing. For example, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines whether the request is about a start control of moving images capturing, depending on whether the request includes &#x201c;Movie.MOV&#x201d; <b>304</b>. More specifically, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines that the request is a control of a start of moving images when the request includes &#x201c;Movie.MOV&#x201d; <b>304</b> (YES in S<b>603</b>), and the process goes to S<b>604</b>. When the request does not include &#x201c;Movie.MOV&#x201d; <b>304</b> (i.e., the request includes a file name of moving image such as xxxx.MOV) (NO in S<b>603</b>), the digital camera <b>100</b> determines that the request is not about a start control of moving images, and the process goes to S<b>608</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In S<b>604</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> performs a control to start capturing moving images, and the process goes to S<b>605</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">In S<b>605</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines whether the control in S<b>604</b> is successfully achieved. When the control in S<b>604</b> is successfully achieved (YES in S<b>605</b>), the process goes to S<b>606</b>. When the control in S<b>604</b> fails (NO in S<b>605</b>), the process goes to S<b>607</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">In S<b>606</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> generates moving image content as a result of the capturing of moving images. When the request specifies a size (=length) of moving image content, the digital camera <b>100</b> generates moving image content of the size (hereinafter, referred to as requested size), and the process goes to S<b>609</b>. For example, the digital camera <b>100</b> generates a plurality of moving image content items of the requested size with the last item having a size smaller than the requested size. When the request does not specify a size of moving image content, the digital camera <b>100</b> generates moving image content of a predetermined size. The digital camera <b>100</b> writes the generated moving image content into both the memory <b>113</b> and the recording medium <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">In S<b>607</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> generates error content in the same format as that of the moving image content (i.e., .MOV file format), and the process goes to S<b>609</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">In S<b>608</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> reads the requested moving image content from the recording medium <b>130</b>, and the process goes to S<b>609</b>. In the exemplary embodiment, if the request does not include the description of &#x201c;Movie.MOV&#x201d;, the request includes a file name such as xxxx.MOV that identifies moving image content. The digital camera <b>100</b> reads moving image content from the recording medium <b>130</b>, based on the file name. When the request specifies a size (requested size) of moving image content, the digital camera <b>100</b> reads the moving image content in the requested size.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">In S<b>609</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines the content generated in S<b>606</b> or S<b>607</b>, or the content read in S<b>608</b> as transmission content.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">In S<b>610</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> transmits the transmission data determined in S<b>609</b> in streaming to the display apparatus <b>200</b> (content transmission).</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">In S<b>611</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines whether the content transmission is completed. When the entire content is transferred (YES in S<b>611</b>), the process goes to S<b>613</b>, whereas when some content remains to be transferred (NO in S<b>611</b>), the process goes to S<b>612</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">In S<b>612</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines whether there is a request for capturing stop from the display apparatus <b>200</b>, or whether the transmission failed. When there is a request for stop or the transmission failed (YES in S<b>612</b>), the process goes to S<b>613</b>, whereas if there is no request for stop or the transmission was a success (NO in S<b>612</b>), the process goes to S<b>615</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">In S<b>615</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> shifts the process based on the determination result in S<b>603</b>. More specifically, when the digital camera <b>100</b> determines that the request from the display apparatus <b>200</b> is a start control of moving image capturing in S<b>603</b>, the process goes to S<b>606</b>, where the digital camera <b>100</b> determines a next transmission data (transmission content). In contrast, when the digital camera <b>100</b> determines that the request from the display apparatus <b>200</b> is not a start control of moving image capturing in S<b>603</b>, the process goes to S<b>608</b>, where the digital camera <b>100</b> reads next data from the recording medium <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">Similarly, in S<b>613</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> shifts the process based on the determination result in S<b>603</b>. More specifically, when the digital camera <b>100</b> determined that the request from the display apparatus <b>200</b> is a control to start capturing moving images in S<b>603</b>, the process goes to S<b>614</b>. In contrast, when the digital camera <b>100</b> determines that the request from the display apparatus <b>200</b> is not a control to start capturing moving images in S<b>603</b>, the serial operation ends and the process goes back to S<b>602</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">In S<b>614</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> stops capturing moving images: the process goes to S<b>602</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">In S<b>616</b>, the display apparatus <b>200</b>, which requested moving image content in S<b>601</b> and is waiting for the content, receives the moving image content transmitted in S<b>610</b> and simultaneously reproduces the received moving image content.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">In S<b>617</b>, the display apparatus <b>200</b> determines whether there is a stop instruction from a user during the reproducing of content. When there is a stop instruction from a user during the reproducing of content (YES in S<b>617</b>), the display apparatus <b>200</b> transmits a stop request to the digital camera <b>100</b>. When there is not a stop instruction from a user during the reproducing of content (NO in S<b>617</b>), the display apparatus <b>200</b> continues the reproducing.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">The display apparatus <b>200</b> requests moving image content, based on content information provided from the digital camera <b>100</b> that serves as a content providing server, and reproduces the moving image content. In other words, the display apparatus <b>200</b> can control the capturing of moving images without any particular configuration in the digital camera <b>100</b>, only by transmitting a request that includes control content &#x201c;Movie.MOV&#x201d; <b>304</b> associated with control of a start of still image capturing.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">In the present exemplary embodiment, the provided content information includes control content for setting, and control of the digital camera <b>100</b> when the display apparatus <b>200</b> requested the control content for setting is described. Also, in this case, the configuration of the digital camera <b>100</b> and the operation flow for providing content information are similar to those in the case of still image content.</p>
<p id="h-0008" num="0000">&#x3c;Setting Control Sequence&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a flowchart illustrating operations for reproducing still images on a display apparatus after the still image content is requested from the display apparatus to a digital camera.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">In S<b>701</b>, the display apparatus <b>200</b> transmits a transmission request for voice content to the digital camera <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">In S<b>702</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines whether a request (transmission request) from the display apparatus <b>200</b> is received. When the digital camera <b>100</b> receives a request from the display apparatus <b>200</b> (YES in S<b>702</b>), the process goes to S<b>703</b>. When the digital camera <b>100</b> does not receive a request (NO in S<b>602</b>), the digital camera <b>100</b> waits for a request.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">In S<b>703</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines whether the request from the display apparatus <b>200</b> is a change in setting. For example, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines whether the request from the display apparatus <b>200</b> is a change in setting depending on whether the request includes &#x201c;ISO100.MP3&#x201d; <b>305</b>. More specifically, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines that the request is a change in setting when the request includes &#x201c;ISO100.MP3&#x201d; <b>305</b> (YES in S<b>703</b>), and the process goes to S<b>704</b>. In contrast, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines that the request is not a change in setting when the request does not include &#x201c;ISO100.MP3&#x201d; <b>305</b> (i.e., the request includes a voice file name such as xxxx.MP3) (NO in S<b>703</b>). Then, the operation ends and the process goes to S<b>708</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">In S<b>704</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> changes settings, and the process goes to S<b>705</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">In S<b>705</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines whether the control in S<b>704</b> was successfully achieved. When the control in S<b>704</b> was successfully achieved in S<b>704</b> (YES in S<b>705</b>), the process goes to S<b>706</b>. When the control failed in S<b>704</b> (NO in S<b>705</b>), the process goes to S<b>707</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">In S<b>706</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> generates content in a format corresponding to the format of control content that is associated with the change in setting, and the process goes to S<b>709</b>. In the present exemplary embodiment, the control content associated with the change in setting is in an MP3 format, and thereby the digital camera <b>100</b> generates voice content in MP3 format that notifies a change in setting. If the request specifies a size (=length) of voice content, the digital camera <b>100</b> generates voice content of a size equal to or less than the size (hereinafter, referred to as requested size). When the request does not specify a size of voice content, the digital camera <b>100</b> generates voice content of a predetermined size or less.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">In S<b>707</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> generates error content in the same format as that of the voice content (i.e., .MP3 file format), and the process goes to S<b>709</b>. The digital camera <b>100</b> generates the error content in a size equal to or smaller than the requested size.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">In S<b>708</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> reads the requested voice content from the recording medium <b>130</b>, and the progress goes to S<b>709</b>. In the exemplary embodiment, if the request does not include &#x201c;ISO100.MP3&#x201d; <b>305</b>, the request includes a file name such as xxxx.MP3 that identifies voice content. The digital camera <b>100</b> reads voice content from the recording medium <b>130</b>, based on the file name. When the request specifies a size (requested size) of voice content, the digital camera <b>100</b> reads the voice content in the requested size or less than the requested size.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">In S<b>709</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines the content generated in S<b>706</b> or S<b>707</b>, or the content read in S<b>708</b> as transmission content.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">In S<b>710</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> transmits the transmission data determined in S<b>709</b> in streaming to the display apparatus <b>200</b> (content transmission).</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">In S<b>711</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines whether the content transmission is completed. When the entire content is transferred (YES in S<b>711</b>), the process goes to S<b>713</b>, whereas when some content remains to be transferred (NO in S<b>711</b>), the process goes to S<b>712</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">In S<b>712</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> determines whether there is a request for capturing stop from the display apparatus <b>200</b>, or whether the transmission failed. When there is a request for capturing stop or the transmission failed (YES in S<b>712</b>), the operation ends and the process goes to S<b>702</b>. When there is no request for capturing stop or the transmission was a success (NO in S<b>712</b>), the process goes to S<b>713</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">In S<b>713</b>, the digital camera <b>100</b> shifts the process based on the determination result in S<b>703</b>. More specifically, when the digital camera <b>100</b> determines that the request from the display apparatus <b>200</b> is a change in setting in S<b>703</b>, the operation ends and the process goes back to S<b>702</b>. In contrast, when the digital camera <b>100</b> determines that the request from the display apparatus <b>200</b> is not a change in setting in S<b>703</b>, the process goes back to S<b>708</b>, where the digital camera <b>100</b> reads next data from the recording medium <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">In S<b>714</b>, the display apparatus <b>200</b>, which requested voice content in S<b>701</b> and is waiting for the content, receives the voice content transmitted in S<b>710</b> and simultaneously reproduces the received voice content.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">In S<b>715</b>, the display apparatus <b>200</b> determines whether there is a stop instruction from a user during the reproducing of content. When there is a stop instruction from a user during the reproducing of content (YES in S<b>715</b>), the display apparatus <b>200</b> transmits a stop request to the digital camera <b>100</b>. When there is not a stop instruction from a user during the reproducing of content (NO in S<b>715</b>), the display apparatus <b>200</b> continues the reproducing.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">The display apparatus <b>200</b> requests voice content, based on content information provided from the digital camera <b>100</b> that serves as a content providing server, and reproduces the voice content. In other words, the display apparatus <b>200</b> can change setting of the digital camera <b>100</b> without any particular configuration, only by transmitting a request that includes control content (e.g., ISO100.MP3 (<b>305</b>)) associated with change in setting.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">In the present exemplary embodiment, the case of a change in setting associated with voice content is described, but the content may be still image or moving image, instead of voice content.</p>
<heading id="h-0009" level="1">Other Embodiments</heading>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">The present invention can be realized through the following processing: software (i.e., a program) that achieves the functions of the above exemplary embodiment is supplied to a system or apparatus via a network or storage medium, so that a computer in the system or apparatus (or CPU or MPU) reads and executes the program. The invention also can be realized through a non-transitory computer-readable storage medium having stored thereon, a program that causes a communication apparatus to perform a method of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">According to the exemplary embodiments, the digital camera <b>100</b> makes control information associated with control content, generates the control content in a format corresponding to the format of control information, and discloses the control content as content information. This allows the display apparatus <b>200</b> to request any control content without discriminating the control content from ordinary content, and to display or reproduce the content in a format corresponding to the format of the requested content. Furthermore, the display apparatus <b>200</b> can control the digital camera <b>100</b> by requesting control content.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">In other words, according to the above exemplary embodiments, an external apparatus such as the display apparatus <b>200</b> does not have to have information like a setting file, but can perform various controls on an image capturing apparatus such as the digital camera <b>100</b> that provides content.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">While the present invention has been described with reference to exemplary embodiments, it is to be understood that the invention is not limited to the disclosed exemplary embodiments. The scope of the following claims is to be accorded the broadest interpretation so as to encompass all modifications, equivalent structures, and functions.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">This application claims priority from Japanese Patent Application No. 2009-173437 filed Jul. 24, 2009, which is hereby incorporated by reference herein in its entirety.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A communication apparatus to transmit content recorded in a recording medium to an external apparatus in response to a request for the content from the external apparatus, the communication apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a disclosure unit configured to disclose a plurality of control content items to the external apparatus, the plurality of control content items being used to cause the communication apparatus to perform processing for generating different contents in different formats;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a determination unit configured to determine one of the different formats of content to be generated based on one of the plurality of control content items requested from the external apparatus;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a generation unit configured to generate content by performing processing according to the determined format; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transmission unit configured to transmit the content generated by the generation unit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each control content item disclosed by the disclosure unit is in a format that is the same as the format of content generated in processing according to the requested control content item.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The communication apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the disclosure unit further is configured to disclose still-image generating content in a format that is the same as that of still image content generated by the communication apparatus, wherein the disclosed still-image generating content is configured to cause the communication apparatus to generate still image content.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The communication apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, further comprising an image capturing unit, wherein the still-image generating content further is configured to cause the communication apparatus to capture images using the image capturing unit and to generate still image content using the generation unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The communication apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the disclosure unit further is configured to disclose moving-image generating content in a format that is the same as that of moving image content generated by the communication apparatus, wherein the disclosed moving-image generating content is configured to cause the communication apparatus to generate moving image content.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The communication apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, further comprising an image capturing unit, wherein the moving-image generating content further is configured to cause the communication apparatus to capture images using the image capturing unit and to generate moving image content using the generation unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The communication apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the disclosure unit further is configured to disclose setting-changing content in a format of voice content, wherein the setting-changing content is configured to cause the communication apparatus to change settings of the communication apparatus.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The communication apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the disclosure unit further is configured to disclose a control content item by transmitting the control content item to the external apparatus that is the source of the request for the one of the plurality of control content items.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The communication apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a second determination unit configured to determine whether the requested control content item is content for changing the setting of the communication apparatus; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a setting changing unit configured to change a setting corresponding to a requested control content item, when the requested control content item is the content for changing the setting of the communication apparatus,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the content generated by the generation unit is a content including a processing result provided by the setting changing unit, when the requested control content item is the content for changing the setting of the communication apparatus.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The communication apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein if an error occurs when processing is performed according to the requested control content item, the generation unit generates a content informing of occurrences of the error in a same format as that of the control content items.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The communication apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the external apparatus requests any control content items without discriminating the control content items from ordinary content items and reproduces the content in a format corresponding to the format of the requested control content.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The communication apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the requested control content item includes setting information having the same format as the format of content generated in processing according to the requested control content item.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The communication apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the second determination unit is configured to determine whether the requested control content item is content for changing the setting of the communication apparatus by determining whether a file name of the requested control content item is a predetermined file name different from a file name of content generated in processing according to the requested control content item.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The communication apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the disclosure unit discloses a plurality of media content items to the external apparatus, the plurality of media content items being generated before the communication apparatus is connected to the external apparatus.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The communication apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a third determination unit configured to determine whether the requested content item is the media content,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the transmission unit transmits the content generated by the generation unit when the requested content item is the control content item, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the transmission unit transmits the requested content when the requested content item is the media content item.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The communication apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the communication apparatus communicates with the external apparatus according to a Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol (TCP/IP).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The communication apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the disclosure unit discloses a plurality of content items to the external apparatus by operating the communication apparatus as a digital media server (DMS).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The communication apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the format includes a file type, and
<claim-text>wherein the control content item disclosed by the disclosure unit has a file type that is the same as the file type of content generated in processing according to the requested control content item.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The communication apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the format includes a file extension, and
<claim-text>wherein the control content item disclosed by the disclosure unit has a file extension that is the same as the file extension of content generated in processing according to the requested control content item.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A method of controlling a communication apparatus that transmits content recorded in a recording medium to an external apparatus, in response to a request for the content from the external apparatus, the method comprising:
<claim-text>disclosing a plurality of control content items to the external apparatus, the plurality of control content items being used to cause the communication apparatus to perform processing for generating different contents in different formats;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining one of the different formats of content to be generated based on one of the plurality of control content items requested from the external apparatus;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating content by performing processing according to the determined format; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting the generated content, wherein each disclosed control content item is in a format that is the same as the format of content generated in processing according to the requested control content item.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. A non-transitory computer-readable storage medium having stored therein, a program that causes a communication apparatus to perform a method of controlling a communication apparatus that transmits content recorded in a recording medium to an external apparatus, in response to a request for the content from the external apparatus, the method comprising:
<claim-text>disclosing a plurality of control content items to the external apparatus, the plurality of control content items being used to cause the communication apparatus to perform processing for generating different contents in different formats;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining one of the different formats of content to be generated based on one of the plurality of control content items requested from the external apparatus;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating content by performing processing according to the determined format; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting the generated content, wherein each disclosed control content item is in a format that is the same as the format of content generated in processing according to the requested control content item.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. A communication apparatus to transmit content recorded in a recording medium to an external apparatus in response to a request for the content from the external apparatus, the communication apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a disclosure unit configured to disclose a plurality of control content items to the external apparatus, the plurality of control content items being used to cause the communication apparatus to perform processing for generating different contents having different file types;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a determination unit configured to determine one of the different file types of content to be generated based on one of the plurality of control content items requested from the external apparatus;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a generation unit configured to generate content by performing processing according to the determined file type; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transmission unit configured to transmit the content generated by the generation unit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each control content item disclosed by the disclosure unit has a file type that is the same as the file type of content generated in processing according to the requested control content item.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. A communication apparatus to transmit content recorded in a recording medium to an external apparatus in response to a request for the content from the external apparatus, the communication apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a disclosure unit configured to disclose a plurality of control content items to the external apparatus, the plurality of control content items being used to cause the communication apparatus to perform processing for generating different contents having different file extensions;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a determination unit configured to determine one of the different file extensions of content to be generated based on one of the plurality of control content items requested from the external apparatus;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a generation unit configured to generate content by performing processing according to the determined file extension; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transmission unit configured to transmit the content generated by the generation unit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each control content item disclosed by the disclosure unit has a file extension that is the same as the file extension of content generated in processing according to the requested control content item.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
