<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08621924-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08621924</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12958840</doc-number>
<date>20101202</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>98142865 A</doc-number>
<date>20091215</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>376</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>19</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7333504</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4816748</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Tazawa et al.</name>
<date>19890300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>324694</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5531097</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Tsuchida et al.</name>
<date>19960700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5909061</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Sasaki et al.</name>
<date>19990600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>307 44</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7267002</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Itakura et al.</name>
<date>20070900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 7333503</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>M367535</doc-number>
<date>20091000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>18</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7333504</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110138908</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110616</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liu</last-name>
<first-name>Te-Chung</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan Hsien</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lee</last-name>
<first-name>Yi-Hua</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan Hsien</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liu</last-name>
<first-name>Te-Chung</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan Hsien</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lee</last-name>
<first-name>Yi-Hua</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan Hsien</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Muncy, Geissler, Olds &#x26; Lowe, PLLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Delta Electronics, Inc.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan Hsien</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Williams</last-name>
<first-name>Hezron E</first-name>
<department>2856</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Frank</last-name>
<first-name>Rodney T</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation includes a wave producing module, a phase processing module, a sensing module and a detecting module. The wave producing module outputs a wave signal. The phase processing module outputs an oscillatory wave and an invert oscillatory wave according to the wave signal. The sensing module has a temperature sensor and a humidity sensor which are connected in series. The temperature sensor and the humidity sensor respectively receive the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave. The sensing module outputs a parameter signal according to the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave. The detecting module outputs a detection signal according to the parameter signal. Hence, the humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation senses the temperature and humidity by the simple circuit design. Moreover, it is feasible for circuit design and application.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="68.92mm" wi="208.70mm" file="US08621924-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="192.02mm" wi="141.73mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621924-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="211.41mm" wi="141.31mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621924-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="222.42mm" wi="141.39mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621924-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="214.46mm" wi="146.22mm" file="US08621924-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This Non-provisional application claims priority under 35 U.S.C. &#xa7;119(a) on Patent Application No(s). 098142865 filed in Taiwan, Republic of China on Dec. 15, 2009, the entire contents of which are hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to a sensing circuit and, in particular, to a humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic diagram of a conventional temperature-humidity sensing circuit <b>1</b>, which includes a humidity sensing unit <b>11</b>, a temperature sensing unit <b>12</b>, two analog-to-digital converters (A/D converters) <b>13</b> and <b>14</b>, and a detecting unit <b>15</b>. The humidity sensing unit <b>11</b> has an operation amplifier <b>111</b>, a plurality of resisters R, and a plurality of sensors O. In the humidity sensing unit <b>11</b>, the humidity signal detected by the sensor O is processed by the resistors R and operation amplifier <b>111</b> so as to output an analog signal S<b>1</b> with respective to the humidity. Then, the analog-to-digital converter <b>13</b> converts the analog signal S<b>1</b> to a digital signal S<b>2</b>. Meanwhile, the temperature sensing unit <b>12</b> measures the temperature to correspondingly output an analog signal S<b>3</b>, and then the analog-to-digital converter <b>14</b> converts the analog signal S<b>3</b> to a digital signal S<b>4</b>. The detecting unit <b>15</b>, which includes a comparison table and a microprocessor, receives the digital signals S<b>2</b> and S<b>4</b> with respective to the humidity and temperature respectively. The microprocessor outputs a suitable control signal S<b>5</b> based on the comparison table in view of the digital signals S<b>2</b> and S<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The conventional temperature-humidity sensing circuit must detect the current temperature and humidity respectively, and then output the control signal through the detecting unit, so that two analog-to-digital converters are necessary. However, the analog-to-digital converter is a large and complicated circuit for converting the detected analog signal to a digital signal, and the digital signals with respective to the temperature and humidity must be integrated by the microprocessor. Accordingly, the entire temperature-humidity sensing circuit has a very complex circuit and involves large amount of electronic components, so that the manufacturing cost as well as the total volume is increased. Therefore, it is an important aspect of the present invention to provide a humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation that has simple circuit design for detecting both temperature and humidity, thereby being suitable for further circuit design and application.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In view of the foregoing, it is an aspect of the present invention to provide a humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation that has simple circuit design for detecting both temperature and humidity, thereby being suitable for further circuit design and application.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">To achieve the above-mentioned aspect, the present invention discloses a humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation including a wave producing module, a phase processing module, a sensing module and a detecting module. The wave producing module is capable of outputting a wave signal. The phase processing module is capable of outputting an oscillatory wave and an invert oscillatory wave according to the wave signal. The sensing module has a temperature sensor and a humidity sensor, which are connected and respectively receive the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave. The sensing module is capable of outputting a parameter signal according to the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave. The detecting module is capable of outputting a detection signal according to the parameter signal.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In one aspect of the invention, the wave producing module includes an operation amplifier, a first resistor, a second resistor, a third resistor, a fourth resistor, and a capacitor.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In one aspect of the invention, the phase processing module includes two Schmitt trigger circuits.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In one aspect of the invention, the phase processing module includes a first comparator and a second comparator.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In one aspect of the invention, the humidity sensing circuit further includes a reference signal producing module electrically connected with a negative input terminal of the first comparator and a positive input terminal of the second comparator, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In one aspect of the invention, the wave producing module is electrically connected with a positive input terminal of the first comparator and a negative input terminal of the second comparator, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In one aspect of the invention, the phase processing module further includes two amplifiers electrically connected with the first comparator and the second comparator, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In one aspect of the invention, the phase processing module further includes two attenuators electrically connected with the first comparator and the second comparator, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In one aspect of the invention, the amplitudes of the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave are the same.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In one aspect of the invention, the phases of the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave are inverted.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In one aspect of the invention, each of the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave is a square wave.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In one aspect of the invention, the detecting module includes a switch unit and a detecting unit. The switch unit includes a switch element, and one end of the switch element is electrically connected with the detecting unit.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In one aspect of the invention, the detecting unit includes an operation amplifier, a seventh resistor, an eighth resistor, a ninth resistor, a capacitor, and a diode.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">As mentioned above, the humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation of the invention has a phase processing module for outputting an oscillatory wave and an invert oscillatory wave, which have the same amplitudes and inverted phases. The sensing module receives the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave, and then the temperature sensor and the humidity sensor outputs a parameter signal according to the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave. Finally, the detecting module outputs a detection signal according to the parameter signal. Thus, the humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation of the invention can sense the temperature and humidity simultaneously with simple circuit design, so that the feasibility of circuit design and application is achieved.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The present invention will become more fully understood from the subsequent detailed description and accompanying drawings, which are given by way of illustration only, and thus are not limitative of the present invention, and wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic diagram showing a conventional temperature-humidity sensing circuit;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic diagram of a humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation according to an embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a circuit diagram of the humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation according to the embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic diagram of a wave producing module according to the embodiment of the invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a schematic diagram of a detecting unit according to the embodiment of the invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The present invention will be apparent from the following detailed description, which proceeds with reference to the accompanying drawings, wherein the same references relate to the same elements.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic diagram of a humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation according to an embodiment of the invention. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the humidity sensing circuit <b>2</b> includes a wave producing module <b>3</b>, a reference signal producing module <b>4</b>, a phase processing module <b>5</b>, a sensing module <b>6</b>, and a detecting module <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The wave producing module <b>3</b> outputs a wave signal S<b>11</b>, and the reference signal producing module <b>4</b> outputs a reference signal S<b>12</b>. The phase processing module <b>5</b> is electrically connected with the wave producing module <b>3</b> and the reference signal producing module <b>4</b> for receiving the wave signal S<b>11</b> and the reference signal S<b>12</b>, and then outputs an oscillatory wave S<b>13</b> and an invert oscillatory wave S<b>14</b> according to the wave signal S<b>11</b> and the reference signal S<b>12</b>. The sensing module <b>6</b> is electrically connected with the phase processing module <b>5</b> for receiving the oscillatory wave S<b>13</b> and the invert oscillatory wave S<b>14</b>, and then outputs a parameter signal S<b>15</b> according to the oscillatory wave S<b>13</b> and the invert oscillatory wave S<b>14</b>. The detecting module <b>7</b> outputs a detection signal S<b>16</b> according to the parameter signal S<b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a circuit diagram of the humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation according to the embodiment of the invention, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic diagram of a wave producing module according to the embodiment of the invention. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref>, the wave producing module <b>3</b> includes an operation amplifier <b>31</b>, a first resistor R<b>1</b>, a second resistor R<b>2</b>, a third resistor R<b>3</b>, a fourth resistor R<b>4</b>, and a capacitor C<b>1</b>. One end of the first resistor R<b>1</b> receives a power signal Vcc, and the other end thereof is electrically connected with a positive input terminal of the operation amplifier <b>31</b>. One end of the second resistor R<b>2</b> is electrically connected with the positive input terminal of the operation amplifier <b>31</b>, and the other end thereof is electrically connected with a ground G. One end of the third resistor R<b>3</b> is electrically connected with a negative input terminal of the operation amplifier <b>31</b>, and the other end thereof is connected with an output terminal of the operation amplifier <b>31</b>. One end of the fourth resistor R<b>4</b> is electrically connected with the positive input terminal of the operation amplifier <b>31</b>, and the other end thereof is connected with the output terminal of the operation amplifier <b>31</b>. One end of the capacitor C<b>1</b> is electrically connected with a negative input terminal of the operation amplifier <b>31</b>, and the other end thereof is electrically connected with the ground G. The output terminal of the wave producing module <b>3</b> outputs a wave signal S<b>11</b>, which is a square wave for example.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the reference signal producing module <b>4</b> includes a fifth resistor R<b>5</b> and a sixth resistor R<b>6</b>. One end of the fifth resistor R<b>5</b> receives a power signal Vcc, and the other end thereof is electrically connected with one end of the sixth resistor R<b>6</b>. The other end of the sixth resistor R<b>6</b> is electrically connected with the ground G. Thus, the power signal Vcc can be divided by the fifth resistor R<b>5</b> and the sixth resistor R<b>6</b>, and then a reference signal S<b>12</b> can be outputted through the connection of the fifth resistor R<b>5</b> and the sixth resistor R<b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The phase processing module <b>5</b> includes a first comparator <b>51</b> and a second comparator <b>52</b>, which are electrically connected with the wave producing module <b>3</b> and the reference signal producing module <b>4</b>, respectively. The wave producing module <b>3</b> outputs the wave signal S<b>11</b> to the positive input terminal of the first comparator <b>51</b> and the negative input terminal of the second comparator <b>52</b>. The reference signal producing module <b>4</b> outputs the reference signal S<b>12</b> to the negative input terminal of the first comparator <b>51</b> and the positive input terminal of the second comparator <b>52</b>. Consequently, the output signals of the first comparator <b>51</b> and the second comparator <b>52</b> can have the same amplitude and inverted phases.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Alternatively, the phase processing module <b>5</b> may have two Schmitt trigger circuits (not shown) for replacing the above-mentioned first comparator <b>51</b> and the second comparator <b>52</b>. The Schmitt trigger circuits are electrically connected with the wave producing module <b>3</b> and the reference signal producing module <b>4</b>. One of the Schmitt trigger circuits is an inverting Schmitt trigger circuit, and the other one is a non-inverting Schmitt trigger circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In this embodiment, the phase processing module <b>5</b> may further include two amplifiers such as a first amplifier <b>53</b> and a second amplifier <b>54</b>. The first amplifier <b>53</b> is electrically connected with the first comparator <b>51</b>, and the second amplifier <b>54</b> is electrically connected with the second comparator <b>52</b>. Thus, the first amplifier <b>53</b> and the second amplifier <b>54</b> can amplify the signals outputted from the first comparator <b>51</b> and the second comparator <b>52</b>, and then the phase processing module <b>5</b> can output the oscillatory wave S<b>13</b> and the invert oscillatory wave S<b>14</b> according to the amplified signals. Herein, the amplitudes of the oscillatory wave S<b>13</b> and the invert oscillatory wave S<b>14</b> are the same, and the phases thereof are inverted. In other words, when the oscillatory wave S<b>13</b> is in a positive phase, the invert oscillatory wave S<b>14</b> is in a negative phase; otherwise, when the oscillatory wave S<b>13</b> is in a negative phase, the invert oscillatory wave S<b>14</b> is in a positive phase. For example, the oscillatory wave S<b>13</b> and the invert oscillatory wave S<b>14</b> of the embodiment are both a square wave.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Alternatively, the phase processing module <b>5</b> of the embodiment may further include two attenuators (not shown) to replacing the above-mentioned amplifiers. The attenuators are electrically connected with the first comparator <b>51</b> and the second comparator <b>52</b>, respectively, for attenuating the signals outputted from the first comparator <b>51</b> and the second comparator <b>52</b>. To be noted, either the amplifiers or the attenuators can be used depending on the overall design, and may be influenced by the level of the power source and the durability of the electronic components such as the temperature sensor and the humidity sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The sensing module <b>6</b> has a temperature sensor <b>61</b> and a humidity sensor <b>62</b> connected in series. One end of the temperature sensor <b>61</b> is connected to one end of the humidity sensor <b>62</b>, and the other ends of the temperature sensor <b>61</b> and the humidity sensor <b>62</b> respectively receive the oscillatory wave S<b>13</b> and the invert oscillatory wave S<b>14</b>. The impendence of the temperature sensor <b>61</b> and the impendence of the humidity sensor <b>62</b> can be various according to the environment temperature and humidity, respectively. Moreover, the oscillatory wave S<b>13</b> and the invert oscillatory wave S<b>14</b> have the same amplitude and different phases, so that there are certain voltage differences between two ends of the temperature sensor <b>61</b> and the humidity sensor <b>62</b>. Accordingly, the temperature sensor <b>61</b> and the humidity sensor <b>62</b> can generate divided voltages according to the oscillatory wave S<b>13</b> and the invert oscillatory wave S<b>14</b>, and a reference signal S<b>15</b> can be outputted from the connection of the temperature sensor <b>61</b> and the humidity sensor <b>62</b>. To be noted, since the oscillatory wave S<b>13</b> and the invert oscillatory wave S<b>14</b> have symmetrical waves, they may approach the alternate signal, so that the sensing module <b>6</b> can precisely response the sensed values and the temperature sensor <b>61</b> and the humidity sensor <b>62</b> can be protected.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The detecting module <b>7</b> includes a switch unit <b>71</b> and a detecting unit <b>72</b>. The switch unit <b>71</b> has a switch element <b>711</b> having one end electrically connected to the connection of the temperature sensor <b>61</b> and the humidity sensor <b>62</b> and the other end electrically connected with the detecting unit <b>72</b>. In this embodiment, the switch element <b>711</b> is turned ON/OFF according to a signal outputted from the second comparator <b>52</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a schematic diagram of a detecting unit <b>72</b> according to the embodiment of the invention. With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 5</figref>, the detecting unit <b>72</b> includes an operation amplifier <b>721</b>, a seventh resistor R<b>7</b>, an eighth resistor R<b>8</b>, a ninth resistor R<b>9</b>, a diode D, and a capacitor C<b>2</b>. The positive input terminal of the operation amplifier <b>721</b> receives the reference signal S<b>15</b> from the switch element <b>711</b>. One end of the seventh resistor R<b>7</b> is electrically connected with a negative input terminal of the operation amplifier <b>721</b>, and the other end thereof is connected to a ground G. One end of the eighth resistor R<b>8</b> is electrically connected with a negative input terminal of the operation amplifier <b>721</b>, and the other end thereof is electrically connected with an output terminal of the operation amplifier <b>721</b>. One end of the ninth resistor R<b>9</b> is electrically connected with an output terminal of the operation amplifier <b>721</b>, and the other end thereof is connected with the capacitor C<b>2</b>. The diode D is connected with the ninth resistor R<b>9</b> in parallel. That is, the diode D is electrically connected to the output terminal of the operation amplifier <b>721</b> and the capacitor C<b>2</b>. The end of the capacitor C is electrically connected with the ground G. In this embodiment, the capacitor C<b>2</b> and the ninth resistor R<b>9</b> together form an integrator. The operation amplifier <b>721</b> of the detecting unit <b>72</b> receives the reference signal S<b>15</b> and amplifies the reference signal S<b>15</b>. Then, the detecting module <b>7</b> outputs a detection signal S<b>16</b> according to a humidity measuring value with respective to the amplified reference signal S<b>15</b>. Herein, the detection signal S<b>16</b> can be directly used as a driving signal of a load, such as a fan or a motor, or provided to the microprocessor to read the humidity value.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">To sum up, the humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation of the invention has a phase processing module for outputting an oscillatory wave and an invert oscillatory wave, which have the same amplitudes and inverted phases. The sensing module receives the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave, and then the temperature sensor and the humidity sensor outputs a parameter signal according to the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave. In the invention, the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave may approach the alternate signal, so that the temperature sensor and the humidity sensor can precisely response the sensed values. Finally, the detecting module outputs a detection signal according to the parameter signal. In one embodiment of the invention, the detection signal can be directly used as a driving signal of a load or provided to the microprocessor to read the humidity value. For example, the temperature sensor and the humidity sensor are connected in series for achieving the temperature compensation of the outputted humidity signal, so that the reference signal has already involved the humidity signal with temperature compensation. Thus, the complex components for the conventional comparison table and the related determine actions may not be necessary. Thus, the humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation of the invention can sense the temperature and humidity simultaneously with simple circuit design. Moreover, the detection signal outputted from the detecting module may be directly used as a driving signal of a load, and it is feasible for circuit design and application.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Although the present invention has been described with reference to specific embodiments, this description is not meant to be construed in a limiting sense. Various modifications of the disclosed embodiments, as well as alternative embodiments, will be apparent to persons skilled in the art. It is, therefore, contemplated that the appended claims will cover all modifications that fall within the true scope of the present invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation, comprising:
<claim-text>a wave producing module, capable of outputting a wave signal, wherein the wave producing module comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>an operation amplifier;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first resistor having one end for receiving a power signal and the other end electrically connected with a positive input terminal of the operation amplifier;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second resistor having one end electrically connected with the positive input terminal of the operation amplifier and the other end grounded;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third resistor having one end electrically connected with a negative input terminal of the operation amplifier and the other end connected with an output terminal of the operation amplifier;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth resistor having one end electrically connected with the positive input terminal of the operation amplifier and the other end connected with the output terminal of the operation amplifier; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a capacitor having one end electrically connected with a negative input terminal of the operation amplifier and the other end grounded;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a phase processing module, capable of receiving the wave signal and outputting an oscillatory wave and an invert oscillatory wave according to the wave signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensing module having a temperature sensor and a humidity sensor connected in series, wherein the temperature sensor and the humidity sensor respectively receive the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave, and the sensing module is capable of outputting a parameter signal according to the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a detecting module, capable of outputting a detection signal according to the parameter signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the wave signal is a square wave signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation, comprising:
<claim-text>a wave producing module, capable of outputting a wave signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a phase processing module, capable of receiving the wave signal and outputting an oscillatory wave and an invert oscillatory wave according to the wave signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensing module having a temperature sensor and a humidity sensor connected in series, wherein the temperature sensor and the humidity sensor respectively receive the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave, and the sensing module is capable of outputting a parameter signal according to the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a detecting module, capable of outputting a detection signal according to the parameter signal,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the phase processing module comprises two Schmitt trigger circuits.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein one of the Schmitt trigger circuits is an inverting Schmitt trigger circuit, and the other one of the Schmitt trigger circuits is a non-inverting Schmitt trigger circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the phase processing module comprises a first comparator and a second comparator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation, comprising:
<claim-text>a wave producing module, capable of outputting a wave signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a phase processing module, capable of receiving the wave signal and outputting an oscillatory wave and an invert oscillatory wave according to the wave signal, wherein the phase processing module comprises a first comparator and a second comparator;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensing module having a temperature sensor and a humidity sensor connected in series, wherein the temperature sensor and the humidity sensor respectively receive the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave, and the sensing module is capable of outputting a parameter signal according to the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a detecting module, capable of outputting a detection signal according to the parameter signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a reference signal producing module electrically connected with a negative input terminal of the first comparator and a positive input terminal of the second comparator, respectively.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the reference signal producing module comprises a fifth resistor and a sixth resistor, one end of the sixth resistor is electrically connected with the fifth resistor, and the other end of the sixth resistor is grounded.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the wave producing module is electrically connected with a positive input terminal of the first comparator and a negative input terminal of the second comparator, respectively.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation, comprising:
<claim-text>a wave producing module, capable of outputting a wave signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a phase processing module, capable of receiving the wave signal and outputting an oscillatory wave and an invert oscillatory wave according to the wave signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensing module having a temperature sensor and a humidity sensor connected in series, wherein the temperature sensor and the humidity sensor respectively receive the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave, and the sensing module is capable of outputting a parameter signal according to the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a detecting module, capable of outputting a detection signal according to the parameter signal,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the phase processing module comprises a first comparator and a second comparator, and the phase processing module further comprises two amplifiers electrically connected with the first comparator and the second comparator, respectively.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation, comprising:
<claim-text>a wave producing module, capable of outputting a wave signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a phase processing module, capable of receiving the wave signal and outputting an oscillatory wave and an invert oscillatory wave according to the wave signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensing module having a temperature sensor and a humidity sensor connected in series, wherein the temperature sensor and the humidity sensor respectively receive the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave, and the sensing module is capable of outputting a parameter signal according to the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a detecting module, capable of outputting signal according to the parameter signal,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the phase processing module comprises a first comparator and a second comparator, and the phase processing module further comprises two attenuators electrically connected with the first comparator and the second comparator, respectively.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the amplitudes of the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave are the same.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the phases of the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave are inverted.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the oscillatory wave is a square wave.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the invert oscillatory wave is a square wave.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation, comprising:
<claim-text>a wave producing module, capable of outputting a wave signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a phase processing module, capable of receiving the wave signal and outputting an oscillatory wave and an invert oscillatory wave according to the wave signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensing module having a temperature sensor and a humidity sensor connected in series, wherein the temperature sensor and the humidity sensor respectively receive the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave, and the sensing module is capable of outputting a parameter signal according to the oscillatory wave and the invert oscillatory wave; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a detecting module, capable of outputting a detection signal according to the parameter signal,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the phase processing module comprises a first comparator and a second comparator, and the detecting module comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a switch unit comprising a switch element; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a detecting unit electrically connected with one end of the switch element.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the switch element is turned ON/OFF according to a signal outputted from the second comparator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the detecting unit comprises:
<claim-text>an operation amplifier, wherein a positive input terminal of the operation amplifier receives the reference signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a seventh resistor having one end electrically connected with a negative input terminal of the operation amplifier and the other end grounded;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an eighth resistor having one end electrically connected with a negative input terminal of the operation amplifier and the other end electrically connected with an output terminal of the operation amplifier;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a ninth resistor having one end electrically connected with an output terminal of the operation amplifier;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a diode connected with the ninth resistor in parallel; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a capacitor having one end electrically connected with the ninth resistor and the other end grounded.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The humidity sensing circuit with temperature compensation according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the capacitor and the ninth resistor form an integrator.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
