<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622962-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622962</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12501848</doc-number>
<date>20090713</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>590</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>M</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>604111</main-classification>
<further-classification>604110</further-classification>
<further-classification>604218</further-classification>
<further-classification>604228</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Safety syringe and method for using the same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4759750</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>DeVries</name>
<date>19880700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6866648</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Hadzic</name>
<date>20050300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0191785</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Barere et al.</name>
<date>20070800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>604228</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00004">
<othercit>Hadzic, &#x201c;Combination of Intrneural Injection and High Injection Pressure Leads to Fascicular Injury and Neurologic Deficits in Dogs&#x201d;, , pp. 417-723, vol. 29, No. 5, Publisher: Regional Anesthesia and Pain Medicine, Published in: US.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>16</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>11</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>604110</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>604111</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>604118</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>604121</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>604218</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>604220</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>604227</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>604228</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>16</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>61080614</doc-number>
<date>20080714</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wiley</last-name>
<first-name>Christopher W.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hanover</city>
<state>NH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wiley</last-name>
<first-name>Christopher W.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hanover</city>
<state>NH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Loginov &#x26; Sicard</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sicard</last-name>
<first-name>Keri E.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="03" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Loginov</last-name>
<first-name>William A.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Clinic</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Lebanon</city>
<state>NH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Bosworth</last-name>
<first-name>Kami A</first-name>
<department>3767</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A safety syringe that effectively prevents the administration of an injection in excess of a maximum injection pressure, and that provides a clear, immediate tactile feedback to the practitioner each time a maximum injection pressure is exceeded. The practitioner is provided a predetermined number of attempts to inject fluid without exceeding the maximum injection pressure, each time receiving a direct tactile feedback in the form of a ratcheting click within the plunger assembly of the syringe. After a final attempt, the next over-pressure event causes a disconnect between the thumb plate of the syringe and the piston that engages the fluid within the syringe barrel, positively prevent a potentially harmful injection. In an illustrative embodiment, the plunger assembly includes a distal portion connected to the piston and a proximal portion, connected to the thumb plate.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="125.05mm" wi="186.35mm" file="US08622962-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="187.11mm" wi="135.13mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622962-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="201.34mm" wi="146.30mm" file="US08622962-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="188.13mm" wi="130.47mm" file="US08622962-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="190.75mm" wi="129.12mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622962-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="171.03mm" wi="154.18mm" file="US08622962-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="161.46mm" wi="160.10mm" file="US08622962-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="205.23mm" wi="131.49mm" file="US08622962-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="185.17mm" wi="95.59mm" file="US08622962-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Patent Application Ser. No. 61/080,614, filed Jul. 14, 2008, entitled SAFTEY SYRINGE AND METHOD FOR USING THE SAME, the entire disclosure of which is herein incorporated by reference.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This invention relates to hypodermic medical syringes, and more particularly to medical syringes adapted to prevent over-pressurized administration of fluids.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Peripheral nerve blocks are performed by injecting local anesthetic solution very near, but not inside, major nerves or plexuses. When properly performed, these blocks can provide surgical anesthesia and/or postoperative pain relief. General anesthesia and/or narcotics can often be avoided or minimized, thus reducing potential side effects. Unfortunately, if the local anesthetic is mistakenly injected inside the nerve, rather than next to it, the result can be permanent nerve damage.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Various techniques and technologies have evolved over the past century in an effort to improve the success and safety of regional anesthesia. Blind techniques, relying on paresthesias or &#x201c;clicks and pops&#x201d; being sensed by the practitioner as the needle is inserted, were supplanted by the use of peripheral nerve stimulation to elicit a motor response when the block needle approached the nerve. In turn, nerve stimulation is now being replaced in many treatment centers by direct visual guidance using high-frequency ultrasound. While ultrasound guidance has greatly improved the speed and reliability of peripheral blocks, the possibility of intraneuronal injection with permanent catastrophic neuropathy still remains a concern. For example, if the block needle is angled slightly relative to the ultrasound beam, its tip may fall outside the beam, and not be visible as it enters a nerve. Dr. Admir Hadzic and colleagues have shown that it is actually injection pressure that determines whether or not a nerve will be damaged by intraneuronal injection (Reg. Anesth. Pain Med. 2004; 29:417-423). Specifically, it was determined that it is unsafe to exceed 20 psi during the injection. Injection pressures below that threshold failed to damage the nerves, even when the needle had penetrated the wall, and was definitely inside the nerve at the time of injection.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">U.S. Pat. No. 6,866,648, entitled METHOD AND APPARATUS TO DECREASE THE RISK OF INTRANEURONAL INJECTION DURING ADMINISTRATION OF NERVE BLOCK ANESTHESIA, by Dr. Admir Hadzic, et al., the teachings of which are expressly incorporated herein by reference, describes a system for more safely administering injections using a syringe that incorporates a &#x201c;pop-up&#x201d; valve assembly in line with the injection tubing and associated fluid path. The valve pops up to provide a visual cue that a predetermined safe injection pressure has been exceeded. A version of this device is marketed under the name BSMART&#x2122; by Concert Medical LLC, Norwell, Mass. While this device is useful&#x2014;particularly in raising awareness as to the need for a safety-injection system, it possesses at least two significant shortcomings. First, the pop-up valve must be continually observed by the practitioner while the injection is being made. This is not practical in a real-world clinical setting. Rather, distractions are possible in any setting, and with the use of ultrasound guidance all eyes tend to be on the ultrasound screen&#x2014;not the syringe. Second, while the Hadzic device may indicate excessive pressure during the injection, it does not prevent it. The danger of permanent nerve damage, while reduced, still remains completely in the hands of the practitioner.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Another earlier attempt to provide a safety syringe is disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 4,759,750, entitled PRESSURE SENSING SYRINGE, by James H. DeVries, et al., the teachings of which are expressly incorporated herein by reference. This device provides a pop-up projection within the center of the syringe plunger thumb plate. This projection is biased through the thumb plate, and painlessly into the practitioner's thumb, if the injection pressure fed-back though the syringe barrel exceeds a predetermined level. Thus, this device avoids the disadvantageous requirement that the practitioner split his or her attention between the syringe and the ultrasound display as encountered in Hadzic by providing a tactile, rather than a visual, indicator of excess injection pressure. However, this device also fails to prevent an over-pressurized injection. In addition, different practitioners' sensitivity and response time to an over-pressure indication may vary widely. Some practitioners may simply not feel the indicator, or only feel it after significant over-pressure has occurred&#x2014;particularly through thickened surgical gloves.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">It is, therefore, desirable to provide a safety syringe, applicable to the administration of neural blocks and other forms of hypodermic injection, which provides a tactile indication of an injection pressure that exceeds a predetermined level. It is further desirable that the safety syringe allow the practitioner to maintain visual attention of the injection site and/or an imaging display of the site, such as employed in ultrasound device. Moreover, it is desirable to provide a safety syringe system, and method for using such a system, which actively prevents the administration of an injection that exceeds a predetermined fluid pressure. The system should be adapted so that the fluid pressure limit is variable for differing types of injections/syringes, and should be easily manufactured, facilitating its use as a generally disposable item.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">This invention overcomes the disadvantages of the prior art by providing a safety syringe that effectively prevents the administration of an injection in excess of a maximum injection pressure, and that provides clear, immediate tactile feedback to the practitioner each time a maximum injection pressure is exceeded. The practitioner is provided a predetermined number (three in one example) attempts to inject fluid without exceeding the maximum injection pressure, each time receiving a direct tactile feedback in the form of a ratcheting click within the plunger assembly of the syringe if the maximum pressure is exceeded. After a final attempt, the next over-pressure event causes a disconnect between the thumb plate of the syringe and the piston that engages the fluid within the syringe barrel, positively preventing a potentially harmful injection. In an illustrative embodiment, the plunger assembly includes a distal portion connected to the piston and a proximal portion, connected to the thumb plate. The distal portion and the proximal portion are interconnected via a ratcheting mechanism constructed of spring loaded pawls on one section and conforming ramps, arranged as a series of steps on the other section. The ramps can be externally located on the section or internally located. The distal-most ramp leads to a sliding section that elastically deforms the spring structures that carry the pawls (unitarily molded leaf-spring arms for example), and allows the pawls to slide, relatively free of resistance so that the two sections become disconnected from each other. A stop prevents the proximal section from hereafter sliding distally into engagement with the distal section. The stop can be the proximal end of the barrel itself, or can be an internally located abutment within the barrel that engages distal ends of arms after they have been elastically deformed in a radially outward direction by the disconnection mechanism&#x2014;the arms normally sliding past the internal abutment when not deformed.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In various embodiments, the arm assembly can comprise a plurality of circumferentially separated, individual leaf springs and pawls that depend from the proximal portion. Alternatively the arm assembly can comprise a unitary rim that deforms to jump from one ramp to another by a hoop stress generated as a result of the force differential between the proximal and distal sections. In various embodiments, an additional guiding structure, such as a central guide rod can be provided on one of the sections and communicate with a channel on another of the sections to maintain alignment therebetween, and alleviating a bending moment as the proximal section delivers driving force to the distal section.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The invention description below refers to the accompanying drawings, of which:</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an exposed diagram of a safety syringe system administering a neural block according to an illustrative embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a an exposed side view of the safety syringe according to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> with the plunger assembly located in a position prior to administration of an injection;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an exposed side view of the safety syringe as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, with the plunger assembly located in a position subsequent to the successful administration of an injection on the first attempt thereof;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is an exposed side view of the safety syringe as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, with the plunger assembly located in a position prior to administration of an injection following a first unsuccessful attempt in which a predetermined injection pressure is exceeded;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an exposed side view of the safety syringe as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, with the plunger assembly located in a position subsequent to the successful administration of an injection;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is an exposed side view of the safety syringe as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, with the plunger assembly located in a position prior to administration of an injection following a second unsuccessful attempt in which the predetermined injection pressure is exceeded;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is an exposed side view of the safety syringe as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, with the plunger assembly located in a position subsequent to the successful administration of an injection;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is an exposed side view of the safety syringe as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, with the plunger assembly located in a position prior to administration of an injection following a third unsuccessful attempt in which the predetermined injection pressure is exceeded;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is an exposed side view of the safety syringe as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, wherein the plunger assembly becomes configured so as to prevent further attempts at administration of the injection;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a bottom view of the proximal section of the plunger assembly of the safety syringe, including four ratchet arms disposed at 90-degree intervals about the perimeter, according to an illustrative embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a bottom view of a proximal section of the plunger assembly of a safety syringe according to an alternate embodiment, including a multiplicity of, adjacent closely spaced ratchet arms disposed about the perimeter;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a bottom view of a proximal section of the plunger assembly of a safety syringe according to an alternate embodiment, including a central guiding rod for increased rotational stability between the proximal section and a distal section, and at least a pair of opposed ratchet arms;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is an exposed side view of the safety syringe, according to an alternate embodiment, employing the proximal section of the plunger assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is an exposed side view of a plunger assembly for a safety syringe according to another alternate embodiment, including a proximal section having a resilient ratchet lip that flexes in response to induced hoop stress so as to move with respect to an attached distal section;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is a bottom view of the proximal section of the plunger assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> detailing an induced hoop stress along the perimeter of the ratchet lip;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref> is a partial side cross section of a safety syringe, providing an internal ratcheting mechanism according to a further alternate embodiment of this invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> details, by way of example, the administration of a peripheral nerve block with respect to a target nerve <b>110</b> beneath body tissue <b>112</b> according to an illustrative embodiment of this invention. In the depicted embodiment, the nerve is provided with a local anesthetic using a hypodermic needle <b>120</b> sized and arranged for that task. The needle <b>120</b> is mounted on, and in fluid-communication with, the distal end of an elongated tubing <b>122</b>. The opposing proximal end of the tubing <b>122</b> is fitted, using a proximal fitting <b>124</b>, to the distal end <b>126</b> of an illustrative syringe <b>128</b> according to an embodiment of this invention.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In operation, the practitioner fills the transparent/translucent barrel <b>130</b> of the syringe <b>128</b> with an appropriate volume of anesthetic or another solution. The barrel <b>130</b> can include the depicted volumetric gradations 132 that allow for metering of the appropriate amount of solution prior to attachment of the tubing <b>122</b> and/or needle <b>120</b>. The anesthetic is directed pressurably from the distal end <b>124</b> of the needle <b>140</b> by pressing (in a distal direction as shown by arrow <b>142</b>) of a syringe's plunger assembly <b>150</b>. As will be described below, the plunger assembly <b>150</b> can be constructed in a variety of sizes, shapes and geometries. In general, the plunger assembly <b>150</b> consists of a proximal plunger section <b>152</b> that is engaged by a thumb or other portion of the practitioner's hand, and an interconnected distal plunger section <b>154</b> that includes a distal plunger end or piston <b>156</b> that moves slidably within the barrel <b>130</b> in a manner that maintains a seal with respect to the inner wall of the barrel.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">As described generally above, it has been recognized by research that, in most cases, even when the needle's distal end <b>140</b> pierces a nerve <b>110</b>, actual damage is not typically caused by the piercing action, but by excess fluid pressure building rapidly within the interior of the nerve. Nerves are, in fact, bundles of neurons formed into individual vesicles. When the outer sheath of a nerve is pierced, the needle tends to travel into the space between vesicles. The vesicles itself may tend to move aside rather than rupturing as the needle passes, thereby protecting the more delicate neuron structure inside each vesicle. However, when injected fluid pressure exceeds a predetermined level, it tends to fill the region of the nerve around the needle without a rapid means of escape. This excess pressure can, in essence, constrict and deprive the vesicles of needed blood flow. This condition causes actual nerve damage. Below a predetermined pressure, the nerves retain their ability to receive sufficient blood flow until the local pressure is relieved by seepage of the infused fluid into surrounding tissues. Hence, the plunger assembly <b>150</b> according to the various embodiments of this invention, to be described below, is constructed and arranged to ensure the practitioner does not inject fluid beyond a predetermined, maximum allowable injection pressure. In accordance with illustrative embodiments relating to peripheral nerve block syringes, this maximum injection pressure is set to approximately 20 psi or less.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">It should be appreciated that the safety syringe according to the various embodiments of this invention (to be described in further detail below) can be applied to other areas of the body and other forms of treatment in addition to the exemplary nerve blocks, where the maximum pressure may be set at another predetermined level&#x2014;for example, the eye or an internal organ.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In the case of a peripheral nerve block application of the illustrative safety syringe, it is contemplated that any pressure in excess of 20 psi, caused either an overly aggressive attempt at injection into normal tissue by the practitioner, or more likely, an attempt to inject fluid into a region that resists introduction of such fluid. In particular, the interior of a nerve will tend to resist rapid introduction of fluid and thus, even injections at a normal flow rate will be resisted by a resulting backpressure. More particularly, attempts to inject fluid at a normal flow rate into the interior of a nerve will generally require pressures in excess of 20 psi. The functionality of the illustrative safety syringe is such that attempts to inject fluid that meet resistance above a predetermined maximum pressure will cause the novel plunger assembly <b>150</b> of this embodiment to deliver an immediate, and unmistakable tactile response, thereby placing the practitioner on notice that the injection site is improper. Repeated failed injection attempts by the practitioner, which exceed the maximum injection pressure, will eventually lead to complete lock-up of the plunger assembly without the ability to further inject fluid effectively preventing harm to the injection site.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Reference is now made to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-9</figref>, which show the first illustrative embodiment of the safety syringe <b>128</b> in various stages of operation. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the plunger assembly <b>150</b> of the safety syringe <b>128</b> is shown fully withdrawn proximally, ready to inject the fluid contents of the barrel <b>130</b>. The barrel <b>130</b> in this embodiment is transparent or translucent, exposing the fluid contents of the syringe <b>128</b> and the components of the plunger assembly <b>150</b> to the practitioner, as shown. The barrel <b>130</b> includes a flange <b>120</b>, which can be any appropriate size and/or shape to assist the practitioner in supporting the barrel during the injection procedure. The barrel <b>128</b> includes a smooth inner wall <b>212</b> that slidably receives the piston end <b>156</b> of the plunger assembly <b>150</b>. The inner wall has a substantially unchanging inner diameter DB along its length. The piston <b>156</b> has an approximately similar diameter to that of the wall <b>212</b>. The piston <b>156</b> can define a smooth edge that provides a low-friction, substantially fluid-tight seal with the inner wall <b>212</b>. Alternatively, the piston <b>156</b> can include additional sealing members (O-rings for example).</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The plunger assembly includes a proximal-most thumb plate <b>220</b>, which is pressed upon distally (arrow <b>142</b>) by the practitioner to deliver the injection, while gripping the barrel <b>130</b> with at lest two other fingers, braced against the flange <b>210</b>. When the thumb plate is depressed, it generates a force and pressure on the plunger assembly <b>150</b>, which is resisted mainly by the resistance to flow of the fluid within the barrel <b>130</b>. The plunger assembly <b>150</b> comprises a main operative component of the novel safety syringe according various embodiments of this invention. The movably interconnected proximal section <b>152</b> and distal section <b>154</b> of the plunger assembly <b>150</b> collectively provide an immediate tactile indicator of an injection pressure in excess of the maximum injection pressure based upon relative movement between these sections in a longitudinal (parallel to arrow <b>142</b>) direction under sufficient pressure therebetween. More particularly, the proximal end of the piston-containing distal section <b>154</b> includes a plurality of wedge-shaped ramps <b>230</b>, <b>232</b> and <b>234</b> arranged as steps along the longitudinal direction. In this embodiment, each ramp has a similar size and shape, with the ramp face <b>240</b> being disposed at a non-perpendicular angle AR with respect to the longitudinal direction. The bottom of each ramp <b>230</b>, <b>232</b>, <b>234</b> includes a shoulder <b>242</b> that extends at an approximately perpendicular angle. The proximal-most ramp <b>230</b> is capped by a shoulder formed by an overlying plate <b>250</b>. The ramps <b>230</b>, <b>232</b>, <b>234</b> can each extend around the entire circumference of the distal section <b>154</b>, or can be circumferentially segmented, and placed at locations where needed to receive resilient, distally extended ratchet arms on the proximal section <b>152</b> of the plunger assembly <b>150</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The ratchet arms <b>270</b> are so named because they each include a distal pawl or spur <b>272</b> that is shaped to conform to the shape of each ramp <b>230</b>, <b>232</b>, <b>234</b>. The ratchet arms <b>270</b> extend from a proximal base <b>274</b>, and each have a thickness TA in the radial direction that enables elastic deformation/bending within the predetermined range. In a resting state, the arms take the form depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> wherein the pawls <b>272</b> are firmly nested against the corresponding ramp. In this manner each pawl is captured by the corresponding ramp and the overall plunger <b>150</b> assembly is defined by the two engaging sections <b>152</b>, <b>154</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The combination of the proximal section's (<b>152</b>) modulus of elasticity and spring constant, the thickness TA of the arms <b>270</b> and the radial depth and angle AR of the ramps <b>230</b>, <b>232</b>, <b>234</b> and length LA of the arms <b>270</b> combine to define a degree of force applied to the distal section that will overcome the engagement between the pawls <b>272</b> and the corresponding ramp, and jump to the next, more distal ramp. That is, each arm is a leaf spring, unitarily molded as part of the proximal section. The ramps and pawls are inclined planes. When a sufficient longitudinal force is applied to the proximal section against resistance in the distal section <b>154</b>, the longitudinal force is resolved into vectors that allow the arms to be flexed/elastically deformed. Hence the pawls can move distally relative to the adjacent ramps and allow them to jump from the current ramp onto the next ramp in a highly noticeable, ratcheting manner.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In this embodiment, the portion of the distal section <b>154</b> that is proximal of the piston <b>156</b> has a relatively constant diameter DDP along its length. This diameter is less than the inner diameter DB of the barrel <b>130</b>. Within the barrel, near the distal tip resides an internal stop <b>260</b>. This stop projects inwardly a predetermined distance sop as to define smaller inner diameter DS. The stop <b>260</b> can be molded into the syringe or applied subsequent to formation of the barrel <b>130</b>. It can be a circumferential ring or a segmented structure. In particular, the diameter DDP is defined so that the distal section <b>154</b> can clear the inwardly projecting stop <b>260</b> with the stop inner diameter DS equal-to, or slightly greater than, the distal section diameter DDP. Moreover, the diameter DRA of the proximal section <b>152</b> (including the ratchet arms when unflexed and captured in one of the ramps <b>230</b>, <b>232</b>, <b>234</b>) DRA is less than or equal to the stop diameter DS. The inner diameter DPP between the arms <b>270</b>, and within a cavity <b>280</b> (shown in phantom) proximally above the arms is smaller than the distal section diameter DDP. Likewise, the maximum diameter of the first two ramps <b>230</b>, <b>232</b> and the <b>250</b> conform to the smaller diameter DPP so that the arms are unflexed, and can clear the stop <b>260</b>, as the plunger <b>150</b> passes down the barrel <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Accordingly, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, when the plunger assembly is pressed (arrow <b>142</b>), and the resistance of the fluid does not generate back pressure in excess of the maximum pressure (20 psi in one example), the ratchet arms do not flex sufficiently to ride over the first ramp, and the plunger <b>150</b> assembly, as a unit drives the piston <b>156</b> completely to the bottom of the barrel <b>130</b>. Thus, the syringe of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> represents an acceptable completed injection procedure in which no potentially dangerous levels of injection pressure were encountered. Note that the thumb plate <b>220</b> is spaced apart from the flange <b>210</b> when the injection is completed. This is because the overall length LDP (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) of the proximal section <b>152</b> between the plate <b>250</b> and the piston <b>156</b> is sufficient to leave an exposed length LS of the section. This length is needed to complete the injection if the plunger assembly is forced to ratchet once or twice during the injection procedure.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Such a ratcheting action is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, in which the practitioner has encountered an excess back pressure in the fluid (arrows <b>410</b>) bearing upon the piston <b>156</b> as the plunger assembly <b>150</b> is driven distally (arrow <b>420</b>). The excess pressure has caused the spring force of the arms <b>270</b> to be overcome, making then slip off the proximal-most ramp <b>230</b>, and onto the next ramp <b>232</b> (curved arrows <b>430</b>). It is assumed that this slippage and the clearly felt click as the pawls <b>272</b> seat within the next ramp <b>232</b> will be sufficient to alert the practitioner of the use of excess pressure, and possibly the need to manipulate the location of the needle further to avoid a nerve interior or other problematic location. Assuming the needle is properly manipulated subsequent to the ratcheting event, or injection pressure is otherwise reduced, then the remainder of the injection procedure can be completed as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. In this case, the distance LS<b>1</b> between the flange <b>210</b> and the thumb plate <b>220</b> has been reduced by the movement onto ramp <b>232</b>. The distance LS<b>1</b> is less than the distance LS of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, but still provided sufficient clearance to complete the injection and allow for further ratcheting if needed.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Such additional ratcheting is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, in which the practitioner has yet again encountered excess backpressure (arrows <b>610</b>) as the plunger assembly <b>150</b> (already ratcheted to ramps <b>232</b>) is driven distally (arrow <b>620</b>). The excess pressure has again caused the spring force of the arms <b>270</b> to be overcome, making then slip off the central/second ramp <b>232</b>, and onto the next, distal-most ramp <b>234</b> (curved arrows <b>630</b>). It is again assumed that this slippage and the clearly felt click as the pawls <b>272</b> seat within the next ramp <b>232</b> will be sufficient to alert the practitioner of the use of excess pressure, and possibly the need to even further manipulate the location of the needle to avoid a nerve interior or other problematic location. Note that, while the ratcheting action is shown occurring at the initiation of the injection procedure, it may also occur during the course of plunger movement. So long as the stop <b>260</b> and the arms <b>270</b> are arranged to prevent interference too early in the process, the arms are free to ratchet even as the plunger piston <b>165</b> has moved some distance into the barrel <b>130</b>. Once the arms move over the stop, they may be restricted from flexing. However, it is assumed that the injection has mostly succeeded before the arms become restricted from flexing. As will be described below, it is expressly contemplated that alternate ratcheting or slippage mechanisms can be employed that are not limited by a stop.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Assuming the second injection attempt is eventually completed successfully, then the syringe assumes the orientation depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>. In this embodiment, minimal clearance remains between the thumb plate <b>220</b> and the barrel flange <b>210</b>. This is because the practitioner has been provided his or her last chance to perform the injection properly.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the practitioner has again exceeded excess backpressure (arrows <b>810</b>) during his or her attempt to drive (arrow <b>820</b> the plunger assembly distally. The pawls <b>272</b> have, thus, jumped over the last ramp <b>234</b> (curved arrows <b>830</b>), and are no longer captured by a more distal ramp. Rather the arms <b>270</b> become spread and elastically flexed radially outwardly as shown. The radial thickness of the pawls <b>272</b>, combined with the diameter DDP of the distal section <b>154</b> locate the ends of the arms at a radial spacing that practically matches the inner diameter DB and ensures the arm ends will not pass the stop. In addition the proximal section's upper cavity <b>280</b> has a diameter and longitudinal length sufficient to receive the distal section <b>154</b> thereinto as shown in phantom in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>. Hence, with relatively little resistance, the pawls slide along the distal section as shown, without driving the distal section against the backpressure <b>810</b>. Eventually, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the proximal end of the distal section <b>154</b> is completely enveloped by the cavity <b>280</b>, and the proximal section <b>152</b> can move no further due to interference between the arm ends and the stop <b>260</b>. At this point the syringe is locked against further injection.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Of course in the illustrative embodiment, the practitioner can withdraw the proximal section <b>152</b> proximally to place the pawls <b>272</b> back onto (at least) the distal-most ramp <b>234</b> and try again, but in any event a potentially crippling injection procedure has been effectively avoided, and cannot be completed, regardless of the number of attempts, until the backpressure is reduced. In alternate embodiments, an additional locking structure can prevent withdrawal of the proximal section at all, once it has finally failed as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>. For example, such a locking structure can include one or more notches located adjacent to the distal end of the straight section of the distal portion that capture corresponding arm pawls after they slide distally over the straight section to the stop.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In the illustrative embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-9</figref>, the proximal section <b>152</b> includes four circumferentially spaced arms <b>270</b>. The layout of the arms <b>270</b>, as well as other components, is further detailed in the bottom view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>. The individual arms can have a width WA that is highly variable. This width dimension, as well as the length LA of the arms and the thickness TA collectively define the spring constant. One or more dimension can be altered to adjust the resistance pressure. Likewise the number of arms employed and their placement can affect the resistance force.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">An alternate embodiment of a proximal section <b>1110</b> of a plunger assembly that can be employed with the above-described distal section <b>154</b> and barrel <b>130</b> shown in bottom view in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>. One concern with the use of a minimal number of arms is that the proximal section of the plunger assembly may not be stably supported on the distal section as it is depressed. That is, one of the arms may experience greater driving pressure than the others during depression due to uneven application of force on the thumb plate&#x2014;thereby causing that leg to jump to the next ramp while the others only flex. The result would be a bent plunger assembly that would make administering the injection difficult or impossible. To provide a more stable interconnection between the proximal and distal sections, the number of arms <b>1120</b> is increased to a virtually continuous circumferential array as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>. The arms <b>1120</b> are thereby divided by a relatively narrow gap.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">A plunger assembly <b>1310</b> with a more-positive mechanism for ensuring an aligned transition between ratchet positions is detailed in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12 and 13</figref>. The embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12 and 13</figref> includes a central guide rod <b>1210</b> attached to the interior of the thumb plate <b>1312</b> and extends through an upper/proximal cavity <b>1314</b> (shown in phantom) distally over a predetermined distance. The guide rod <b>1210</b> is surrounded at least two flexible spring arms <b>1320</b> with associated pawls <b>1322</b> mounted on a proximal section <b>1230</b>. The pawls <b>1322</b> move in a ratcheting manner distally as the maximum pressure is exceeded over ramps <b>1330</b>, <b>1332</b> and <b>1334</b> in the distal section <b>1340</b>. The distal section <b>1340</b> includes a cylindrical distal portion that terminates in an appropriately sized piston <b>1350</b>, which conforms to the inner diameter of the associated syringe barrel (not shown). The distal section <b>1340</b> also includes a conforming central channel <b>1360</b> (shown in phantom) that receives the central guide rod <b>1210</b> as the proximal section <b>1230</b> is ratcheted and/or disconnects to lock-up the syringe (dashed arrow <b>1370</b>). The central guide rod <b>1210</b> and channel <b>1360</b> collectively resist misalignment or bending of the proximal section <b>1230</b> with respect to the distal section <b>1340</b> as it ratchets between ramps. Other functions are in accordance with the description of the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-10</figref> above. Note that the guide rod <b>1210</b> and channel <b>1360</b> can be formed in a polygonal, or more-complex geometrical shape (for, example cruciform) so that relative rotation of the distal and proximal sections is resisted. Likewise, the number of arms is highly variable, as is their placement. More generally, this embodiment contemplates that a slidable member interengages the two plunger assembly sections so as to resist bending therebetween, while a ratcheting component that interacts between the sections provides for a tactile signal between multiple attempts to inject, along with a final lock-up of the syringe.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Another alternate embodiment of ratcheting plunger assembly <b>1410</b> for use in a safety syringe (having a syringe barrel (<b>130</b>) as generally described herein) is detailed in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 14 and 15</figref>. This plunger assembly <b>1410</b> includes a proximal section <b>1420</b> and an interengaging distal section <b>1430</b> that operate to ratchet and lock-up the syringe generally in conformance with the principles described herein. The distal section <b>1420</b> includes a circumferential pawl structure <b>1440</b> that extends into the distal end of a cavity <b>1450</b> (and terminates at the inner side of the thumb plate <b>1460</b>). When the backpressure (arrows <b>1470</b>) provides resistance to downward injection pressure (arrow <b>1472</b>) in excess of the maximum injection pressure, the ramps <b>1480</b>, <b>1482</b>, <b>1484</b> induce a radial hoop stress (arrows <b>1490</b>) on the pawl rim that is sufficient to elastically deform the rim sufficiently so that it can jump between ramps to thereby ratchet the plunger assembly <b>1410</b>. The material and/or dimensions of the proximal section <b>1420</b> afford sufficient elasticity so that the continuous rim of the pawl rim structure <b>1440</b> can jump to the next ramp and/or the continuous-diameter, cylindrical-portion <b>1492</b> of the plunger's distal section <b>1420</b> in response to pressure in excess of the maximum injection pressure. After three attempts (in this embodiment) toward a successful injection, the pawl rim structure <b>1440</b> rides onto the continuous portion <b>1492</b>, thereby providing a disconnect between the proximal section <b>1420</b> and the distal section <b>1430</b>, which provides the requisite lock-up of the syringe so as to prevent overpressure in the injection procedure. The materials of the plunger assembly's sections should be sufficiently non-frictional in engagement so that the practitioner's distal driving action (arrow <b>1472</b>) of the hoop-stressed rim <b>1440</b> still overcomes the backpressure (arrows <b>1470</b>) of the fluid. Hence, the pawl rim structure <b>1440</b> can effectively override the distal, cylindrical portion <b>1492</b>, thereby causing the radially outwardly deformed distal end <b>1494</b> of the rim <b>1440</b> to engage the barrel's stop (not shown, but equivalent to the stop <b>260</b> above) if three attempts are failed&#x2014;thereby locking-up the syringe in a manner described above.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">It is expressly contemplated that the ratcheting mechanism that provides both a direct, immediate tactile feedback to the practitioner and the ability to lock-up the injection procedure in the event of one or more over-pressure events can be constructed in a variety of manners. In general, the plunger assembly provides the ratcheting and lock-up functionalities herein. In various embodiments, as described above, the syringe barrel is modified from a relatively conventional design to include a stop structure (<b>260</b>) that can be omitted where the safety syringe is directed mainly toward a tactile indicator of overpressure, or provides an alternate lock-up mechanism. Of course, in alternate embodiments, the barrel can be further modified to include other aspects of thee ratcheting and/or lock-up mechanisms.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref> depicts a partial view of a safety syringe <b>1610</b> according to a further embodiment of the invention in which the barrel <b>1620</b> (shown in phantom) is free of an internal stop or other modifications with respect to convention syringe barrel designs. This allows the barrel to remain substantially unmodified, thereby reducing complexity and production costs. This arrangement also potentially eases assembly concerns since the plunger assembly <b>1622</b> can be slid into the completed safety syringe unit without concern for the obstruction of an internal stop assembly within the barrel.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">As depicted, the plunger assembly <b>1622</b> consists of a proximal section <b>1630</b> and a distal section <b>1640</b>. The proximal section includes a thumb plate <b>1650</b> that is attached to a plurality of circumferentially separated ratchet arms <b>1660</b>. The ratchet arms <b>1660</b> each carry a radially outwardly extended pawl <b>1662</b> at a distal-most end thereof. The pawls <b>1662</b> conform to a set of stepped ramps <b>1670</b>, <b>1672</b>, <b>1674</b> that extend toward a narrowed channel <b>1678</b>, terminating adjacent to a piston <b>1690</b> residing at distal-most end of the distal section <b>1640</b>. The arms <b>1660</b> flex radially inwardly (curved arrows <b>1680</b>) in response to a predetermined pressure differential (between proximally directed fluid backpressure (arrows <b>1694</b>) and distally directed injection driving force (arrow <b>1696</b>) to jump from one ramp to another as the maximum injection pressure is exceeded. The radial gap GA between the arms <b>1660</b> is sufficient to allow such flexure and enable the pawls <b>1662</b> to override the ramps <b>1670</b>, <b>1672</b>, <b>1674</b>. The diameter DC of the channel <b>1668</b> is also defined so that the arms <b>1660</b> can be fully inwardly flexed, and ride distally into the channel <b>1678</b>. By appropriate sizing and arranging of the proximal and distal sections <b>1630</b> and <b>1640</b>, respectively, the thumb plate <b>1650</b> engaged to proximal/top end <b>1694</b> of the barrel <b>1620</b> before the distal ends of the arms <b>1660</b> bottom-out within the channel <b>1678</b>. Thus, the plunger assembly <b>1622</b> provides the requisite lock-up function subsequent to a predetermined number of injection attempts (three attempts in this embodiment). The lock-up is achieved completely within the plunger assembly <b>1622</b>, thereby allowing it to be employed universally within a variety of standard-sized syringe barrels. In this embodiment, the combination of the barrel's proximal end and the thumb plate can be defined as the &#x201c;stop&#x201d; that prevents the injection from occurring after the distal and proximal sections are disconnected by the ratcheting mechanism.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In this embodiment, and others described herein, one or more of the components of the safety syringe and/or plunger assembly can be provided with a discrete indicia, such as color-coding, to identify the relevant application of the safety syringe (e.g. neural block, ocular, etc.) and/or the maximum allowable injection pressure permitted by the assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">It should be clear to those of ordinary skill that a safety syringe according to the various embodiments described herein affords the practitioner a highly discernable and immediate tactile feedback to any condition in which a maximum safe injection pressure is exceeded using a ratcheting mechanism. This mechanism also allows for multiple injection attempts after readjusting the orientation of the needle within the patient. In addition, the mechanism enables to provision of a final attempt, in which further attempts are blocked. More particularly, a lock-up function in which the plunger components become disconnected, positively prevents an over-pressurized injection (following one or more attempts) by disconnection movable components that interface the practitioner's hand with respect to the fluid piston.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The foregoing has been a detailed description of illustrative embodiments of the invention. Various modifications and additions can be made without departing from the spirit and scope of this invention. Each of the various embodiments described above may be combined with other described embodiments in order to provide multiple features. Furthermore, while the foregoing describes a number of separate embodiments of the apparatus and method of the present invention, what has been described herein is merely illustrative of the application of the principles of the present invention. For example, it is expressly contemplated that the lock-up function and/or the tactilely stimulating ratcheting function can be separately provided in a safety syringe according to alternate embodiments of this invention. In alternate embodiments, a single injection attempt can result in lock-up and/or the syringe can afford a plurality of ratcheting attempts without an eventual lock-up of the injection function. The ratcheting mechanism can also be implemented in a variety of manners, some of which may include additional moving parts, such as individually spring-loaded bearings mounted on the arms or another base. The pawls can define an alternate shape, such as a curvilinear outline, which conforms to a conforming curvilinear ramp shape. In addition, while the moving component is provided within the proximal section of the plunger assembly in the various illustrative embodiments shown and described herein, the moving component(s) can be provided within the distal section, within a combination of the distal and proximal sections, or within both sections&#x2014;and also within the barrel where appropriate. Based upon the foregoing description, such implementations should be within the purview of those of ordinary skill in the art. Accordingly, this description is meant to be taken only by way of example, and not to otherwise limit the scope of this invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A safety syringe comprising:
<claim-text>a barrel that contains a predetermined volume of fluid, and having an inner wall, a proximal end, a distal end and a longitudinal axis;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plunger assembly including a proximal plunger section having proximal and distal ends, and an interconnected distal plunger section having proximal and distal ends;
<claim-text>the distal plunger section including a piston at the distal end of the distal plunger section and that provides a substantially fluid-tight slidable seal with respect to the inner wall of the barrel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the proximal plunger section including, at the proximal end thereof, a cavity for matingly receiving the proximal end of the distal plunger section for relative motion therebetween;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a ratcheting mechanism constructed and arranged to provide a tactile feedback in response to direction of the piston against the fluid so as to generate a backpressure in excess of a predetermined maximum pressure, the tactile feedback being provided each of a predetermined number of times;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the ratcheting mechanism including a plurality of wedge-shaped ramps constructed and arranged as steps in a direction of the longitudinal axis and disposed at the proximal end of the distal plunger section;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the ratcheting mechanism further including at least one ratchet arm that is peripherally disposed and extends distally at the distal end of the proximal plunger section;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the ratchet arm including a distal pawl for conforming engagement with a corresponding wedge-shaped ramp;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a thumb plate disposed at the proximal end of the proximal plunger section; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a stop secured to the inner wall of the barrel forming a projection against which a distal pawl end of the ratchet arm engages subsequent to disconnection of the distal plunger section from the proximal plunger section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The safety syringe as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the ratcheting mechanism is constructed and arranged to disconnect the distal plunger section from the proximal plunger section so as to prevent the proximal plunger section from directing force to the piston after the predetermined number of times.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The safety syringe as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> wherein the distal plunger section includes a distal portion disposed between the piston and ramps, a distal-most of the ramps being constructed and arranged to direct the ratchet arm into the distal portion so as to disconnect the distal plunger section from the proximal plunger section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The safety syringe as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref> wherein the projection comprises an annular projection.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The safety syringe as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising a guide rod that maintains a bend-free alignment between the proximal plunger section and the distal plunger section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The safety syringe as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the at least one ratchet arm includes a continuous rim that flexes under hoop stress in response to a predetermined pressure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The safety syringe as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the distal plunger section includes a distal portion disposed between the piston and ramps, and wherein the proximal plunger section includes a plurality of ratchet arms, the ratchet arms engaging with the distal portion when an excess back pressure is reached.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The safety syringe as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref> wherein, when the ratchet arms ride over the distal portion, the ratchet arms are constructed and arranged to engage with the stop to inhibit further motion of the proximal plunger section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The safety syringe as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> wherein the projection comprises an annular stop having an inside diameter that is greater than a diameter of the distal portion so that when the pawl engages a ramp the proximal plunger section passes the annular stop.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The safety syringe as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref> wherein the ratchet arms comprise four disposed in a diametric pattern.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A safety syringe comprising:
<claim-text>a barrel that contains a predetermined volume of fluid, and having an inner wall, a proximal end, a distal end and a longitudinal axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plunger assembly including a proximal plunger section having proximal and distal ends, and an interconnected distal plunger section having proximal and distal ends;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the distal plunger section including a piston at the distal end of the distal plunger section and that provides a substantially fluid-tight slidable seal with respect to the inner wall of the barrel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a ratcheting mechanism constructed and arranged to provide a tactile feedback in response to direction of the piston against the fluid so as to generate a backpressure in excess of a predetermined maximum pressure, the tactile feedback being provided each of a predetermined number of times;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the ratcheting mechanism including a plurality of wedge-shaped ramps constructed and arranged as steps in a direction of the longitudinal axis and disposed along the distal plunger section;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the ratcheting mechanism further including at least one ratchet arm that is peripherally disposed and extends distally at the distal end of the proximal plunger section;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the ratchet arm including a distal pawl for conforming engagement with a corresponding wedge-shaped ramp; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a thumb plate disposed at the proximal end of the proximal plunger section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The safety syringe as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> including a stop secured to the inner wall of the barrel forming a projection against which a distal pawl end of the ratchet arm engages subsequent to disconnection of the distal plunger section from the proximal plunger section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The safety syringe as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref> wherein, when the ratchet arm rides over the distal portion, the ratchet arm is constructed and arranged to engage with the stop to inhibit further motion of the proximal plunger section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The safety syringe as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> wherein the wedge-shaped ramps are disposed on an outer surface of the distal plunger section and the pawl extends inwardly to engage a ramp.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The safety syringe as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref> wherein the distal plunger section includes a distal portion disposed between the piston and ramps, and wherein the proximal plunger section includes a plurality of ratchet arms, the ratchet arms engaging with the distal portion when an excess back pressure is reached.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The safety syringe as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> wherein the wedge-shaped ramps are disposed within a channel of the proximal plunger section and the pawl extends outwardly to engage a ramp.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
