<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624555-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624555</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13033061</doc-number>
<date>20110223</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-045569</doc-number>
<date>20100302</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>338</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>M</subclass>
<main-group>10</main-group>
<subgroup>44</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>M</subclass>
<main-group>10</main-group>
<subgroup>46</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>320116</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Voltage monitoring system, voltage monitoring device, and method of setting information</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8140281</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Ishikawa et al.</name>
<date>20120300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0001593</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Odajima et al.</name>
<date>20080100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>324105</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0319210</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yanagisawa</name>
<date>20091200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>702 64</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2009-017657</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20090100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>24</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>320107</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>320116</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>320118</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>320119</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>320134</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>320136</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>324426</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>324427</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>324433</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>7</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110215810</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110908</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Murakami</last-name>
<first-name>Yoshihiro</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Murakami</last-name>
<first-name>Yoshihiro</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Kubotera &#x26; Associates, LLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Oki Semiconductor Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Tso</last-name>
<first-name>Edward</first-name>
<department>2859</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A voltage monitoring system includes a plurality of voltage monitoring devices connected to each other in series for monitoring a voltage of each of battery units obtained by dividing per specific number a plurality of batteries connected in series. Each of the voltage monitoring devices includes a reception unit for receiving specific information transmitted from a former stage; a storage unit for storing the specific information received with the reception unit as self specific information; and a transmission unit for adding predetermined information to the specific information received with the reception unit, and for transmitting the specific information to a later stage as later stage specific information.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="207.43mm" wi="153.92mm" file="US08624555-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="219.96mm" wi="153.67mm" file="US08624555-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="236.47mm" wi="172.21mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624555-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="228.94mm" wi="153.08mm" file="US08624555-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="187.79mm" wi="167.89mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624555-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="235.88mm" wi="165.52mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624555-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="227.50mm" wi="152.48mm" file="US08624555-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="242.23mm" wi="155.11mm" file="US08624555-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION AND RELATED ART STATEMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to a voltage monitoring system, a voltage monitoring device of the voltage monitoring system, and a method of setting information in the voltage monitoring device of the voltage monitoring system. More specifically, the present invention relates to a voltage monitoring system capable of setting specific information for specifying the voltage monitoring device among a plurality of voltage monitoring devices; a voltage monitoring device of the voltage monitoring system, and a method of setting information in the voltage monitoring device of the voltage monitoring system.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">An assembled battery has been widely installed in a vehicle, an electrical tool, and the likes. In the assembled battery, a plurality of secondary batteries is arranged and connected in series as a power source for driving a vehicle, an electrical tool, and the likes. When the assembled battery is installed in a hybrid motor vehicle or an electric vehicle as a power source for driving the hybrid motor vehicle or the electric vehicle, it is necessary to use the assembled battery having a large capacity. Accordingly, the assembled battery may be formed of secondary batteries in a range from a few tens to a few hundreds.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In the assembled battery, the secondary batteries may include a lithium ion battery, a lithium ion polymer secondary battery, and a nickel-hydrogen battery. In the following description, when it is not necessary to distinguish the secondary battery from other batteries such as a primary battery, the secondary battery is collectively referred to as a battery.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In general, a plurality of voltage monitoring devices is connected to a plurality of batteries of the assembled battery to be used as the drive power source, so that each of the voltage monitoring devices monitors a voltage value of each of the batteries. The voltage monitoring devices are connected in series. Further, a main device is provided for monitoring and controlling an operation of each of the voltage monitoring devices, so that the main device and the voltage monitoring devices constitute a voltage monitoring system.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a block diagram showing a conventional voltage monitoring system <b>100</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the conventional voltage monitoring system <b>100</b> includes a plurality of voltage monitoring devices <b>102</b> connected in series and a main device <b>104</b> for controlling an entire operation of the conventional voltage monitoring system <b>100</b> (refer to Patent Reference).
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0006">Patent Reference: Japanese Patent Publication No. 2009-17657</li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0007">In the conventional voltage monitoring system <b>100</b>, each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>102</b> includes communication terminals <b>106</b> and <b>108</b>. The main device <b>104</b> is connected to the communication terminal <b>106</b>, and the communication terminal <b>106</b> is connected to the communication terminal <b>108</b> of the voltage monitoring device <b>102</b> at a later stage. Accordingly, it is configured such that the main device <b>104</b> is capable of receiving and transmitting information with respect to all of the voltage monitoring devices <b>102</b> through the voltage monitoring device <b>102</b> directly connected to the main device <b>104</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0008">In the conventional voltage monitoring system <b>100</b>, each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>102</b> includes a control circuit <b>110</b>, a voltage measurement circuit <b>112</b>, and a clock generation circuit <b>114</b> connected to each other. The communication terminals <b>106</b> and <b>108</b> are separately connected to the control circuit <b>110</b>. The control circuit <b>110</b> includes a CPU (Central Processing Unit), an ROM (Read Only Memory), an RAM (Random Access Memory), and a non-volatile storage medium such as an NVM (Non-Volatile Memory) for storing various types of information to be stored even after the voltage monitoring device <b>102</b> is turned off. The control circuit <b>110</b> is provided for controlling an entire operation of the voltage monitoring device <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0009">In the conventional voltage monitoring system <b>100</b>, the voltage measurement circuit <b>112</b> is provided for measuring a voltage of a power source according to an instruction of the control circuit <b>110</b>. A plurality of batteries <b>118</b> is connected in series to constitute an assembled battery <b>116</b>, and the voltage measurement circuit <b>112</b> is connected to one of the batteries <b>118</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0010">More specifically, the voltage measurement circuit <b>112</b> is connected to a positive polarity terminal <b>118</b> of one of the batteries <b>118</b> through a positive polarity terminal <b>120</b> thereof. Further, the voltage measurement circuit <b>112</b> is connected to a negative polarity terminal of one of the batteries <b>118</b> through a negative polarity terminal <b>122</b> thereof. With the configuration described above, the voltage measurement circuit <b>112</b> measures a voltage of the corresponding battery <b>118</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0011">In the conventional voltage monitoring system <b>100</b>, the clock generation circuit <b>114</b> is provided for generating a clock signal for defining an operation timing of the control circuit <b>110</b> and the voltage measurement circuit <b>112</b>. The clock generation circuit <b>114</b> is provided also for supplying the clock signal thus generated to the control circuit <b>110</b> and the voltage measurement circuit <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0012">In the conventional voltage monitoring system <b>100</b>, each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>102</b> further includes an ID input terminal <b>124</b> for receiving from an external device an input of specific information (referred to as an ID signal) for specifying the voltage monitoring device <b>102</b> thereof. The ID input terminal <b>124</b> is connected to the control circuit <b>110</b>. When the voltage monitoring device <b>102</b> receives the ID signal from the external device through the ID input terminal <b>124</b>, the ID signal is input to the control circuit <b>110</b>, so that the ID signal is stored in the NVM. Accordingly, the specific ID signal is set in each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0013">In the conventional voltage monitoring system <b>100</b> used for the assembled battery <b>116</b> to be installed in a motor vehicle, when the assembled battery <b>116</b> has a large capacity, it is necessary to increase the number of the batteries <b>118</b>, i.e., the subject of the voltage monitoring. Accordingly, it is necessary to increase the number of the ID input terminals <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0014">For example, when the conventional voltage monitoring system <b>100</b> includes <b>32</b> of the voltage monitoring devices <b>102</b> connected in series in multiple stages, each of the ID input terminals <b>124</b> is formed of cables in the number of five (a bit number). Accordingly, when a semiconductor circuit formed of a package having 30 pins to 56 pins is applied to the voltage monitoring device <b>102</b>, it is difficult to apply the conventional voltage monitoring system <b>100</b> to the assembled battery <b>116</b> having a large capacity due to the restriction of the number of the ID input terminals <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0015">In view of the problems described above, an object of the present invention is to provide a voltage monitoring system capable of setting specific information with respect to each of a plurality of voltage monitoring devices without disposing a special terminal in each of the voltage monitoring devices for setting the specific information. Further object of the present invention is to provide a voltage monitoring device of the voltage monitoring system and a method of setting information in the voltage monitoring device of the voltage monitoring system.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0016">Further objects and advantages of the invention will be apparent from the following description of the invention.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0017">In order to attain the objects described above, according to a first aspect of the present invention, a voltage monitoring system includes a plurality of voltage monitoring devices connected to each other in series for monitoring a voltage of each of a plurality of battery units obtained by dividing per specific number a plurality of batteries connected in series.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0018">According to the first aspect of the present invention, each of the voltage monitoring devices includes a reception unit for receiving specific information transmitted from a former stage; a storage unit for storing the specific information received with the reception unit as self specific information; and a transmission unit for adding predetermined information to the specific information received with the reception unit, and for transmitting the specific information to a later stage as later stage specific information.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0019">As described above, in the voltage monitoring system in the first aspect of the present invention, a plurality of the voltage monitoring devices connected to each other in series is provided for monitoring the voltage of each of the battery units obtained by dividing per specific number a plurality of the batteries connected in series. Each of the voltage monitoring devices includes the reception unit for receiving the specific information transmitted from the former stage.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0020">Further, in the voltage monitoring system in the first aspect of the present invention, each of the voltage monitoring devices includes the storage unit for storing the specific information received with the reception unit as the self specific information; and the transmission unit for adding the predetermined information to the specific information received with the reception unit, and for transmitting the specific information to the later stage as the later stage specific information.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0021">As described above, in the voltage monitoring system in the first aspect of the present invention, the voltage monitoring devices are connected to each other in series for monitoring the voltage of each of the battery units. Further, the reception unit receives the specific information transmitted from the former stage, and the storage unit stores the specific information thus received as the self specific information.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0022">Further, the transmission unit adds the predetermined information to the specific information thus received, and transmits the specific information to the voltage monitoring device at the later stage as the later stage specific information. Accordingly, it is possible to set the specific information with respect to each of the voltage monitoring devices without disposing a special terminal in each of the voltage monitoring devices for setting specific information for specifying each of the voltage monitoring devices.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0023">According to a second aspect of the present invention, a voltage monitoring system includes a plurality of voltage monitoring devices connected to each other in series for monitoring a voltage of each of a plurality of battery units obtained by dividing per specific number a plurality of batteries connected in series.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0024">According to the second aspect of the present invention, each of the voltage monitoring devices includes a reception unit for receiving specific information transmitted from a former stage; a generation unit for adding predetermined information to the specific information received with the reception unit to generate self specific information; a storage unit for storing the self specific information generated with the generation unit; and a transmission unit for transmitting the self specific information generated with the generation unit to a later stage.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0025">As described above, in the voltage monitoring system in the second aspect of the present invention, a plurality of the voltage monitoring devices connected to each other in series is provided for monitoring the voltage of each of the battery units obtained by dividing per specific number a plurality of the batteries connected in series. Each of the voltage monitoring devices includes the reception unit for receiving the specific information transmitted from the former stage; and the generation unit for adding the predetermined information to the specific information received with the reception unit to generate the self specific information.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0026">Further, in the voltage monitoring system in the second aspect of the present invention, each of the voltage monitoring devices includes the storage unit for storing the specific information generated with the generation unit as the self specific information; and the transmission unit for transmitting the specific information generated with the generation unit to the later stage.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0027">As described above, in the voltage monitoring system in the second aspect of the present invention, the voltage monitoring devices are connected to each other in series for monitoring the voltage of each of the battery units. Further, the reception unit receives the specific information transmitted from the former stage, and the generation unit adds the predetermined information to the specific information received with the reception unit to generate the self specific information.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0028">Further, the storage unit stores the self specific information thus generated, and the transmission unit transmits the self specific information thus generated to the later stage. Accordingly, it is possible to set the specific information with respect to each of the voltage monitoring devices without disposing a special terminal in each of the voltage monitoring devices for setting specific information for specifying each of the voltage monitoring devices.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0029">According to a third aspect of the present invention, in the voltage monitoring system in one of the first aspect and the second aspect of the present invention, each of the reception unit and the transmission unit is formed of a communication terminal for communicating with an external device. Accordingly, it is possible to set the specific information with respect to each of the voltage monitoring devices without disposing a special terminal in each of the voltage monitoring devices for setting specific information for specifying each of the voltage monitoring devices.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0030">According to a fourth aspect of the present invention, in the voltage monitoring system in one of the first aspect to the third aspect of the present invention, the transmission unit or the generation unit is arranged to add a predetermined value as the predetermined information to the specific information. Accordingly, it is possible to easily generate the specific information.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0031">According to a fifth aspect of the present invention, in the voltage monitoring system in the fourth aspect of the present invention, the transmission unit or the generation unit is arranged to add one as the predetermined value to the specific information. Accordingly, it is possible to set the specific information with respect to a large number of the voltage monitoring devices.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0032">According to a sixth aspect of the present invention, in one of the first aspect to the fifth aspect of the present invention, the voltage monitoring system further includes a main device connected in series to the voltage monitoring device at the most front stage, so that the main device is situated at a former stage relative to the voltage monitoring device at the most front stage. The main device is provided for receiving and transmitting information from and to each of the voltage monitoring devices through the reception unit and the transmission unit. Accordingly, it is possible to acquire the information obtained with each of the voltage monitoring devices and control each of the voltage monitoring devices with a simple configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0033">According to a seventh aspect of the present invention, in the voltage monitoring system in the sixth aspect of the present invention, the main device is arranged to acquire voltage information indicating a monitored voltage from each of the voltage monitoring devices. Accordingly, it is possible to easily confirm a relative remaining capacity among the batteries.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0034">According to an eighth aspect of the present invention, a voltage monitoring device is arranged to function as each of the voltage monitoring devices in the voltage monitoring system in one of the first aspect to the seventh aspect of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0035">As described above, in the eighth aspect of the present invention, the voltage monitoring device is arranged to function as each of the voltage monitoring devices in the voltage monitoring system in one of the first aspect to the seventh aspect of the present invention. Accordingly, when the voltage monitoring device is applied to the voltage monitoring system in the first aspect to the seventh aspect of the present invention, it is possible to obtain an effect similar to that of the voltage monitoring system in one of the first aspect to the seventh aspect of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0036">According to a ninth aspect of the present invention, a method is provided for setting specific information relative to each of a plurality of voltage monitoring devices of a voltage monitoring system, in which the voltage monitoring devices are connected to each other in series for monitoring a voltage of each of a plurality of battery units obtained by dividing per specific number a plurality of batteries connected in series.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0037">According to the ninth aspect of the present invention, the method of setting the information includes a reception step of receiving specific information transmitted from a former stage with a reception unit disposed in each of the voltage monitoring devices; a storage step of storing the specific information received with the reception unit as self specific information in a storage unit disposed in each of the voltage monitoring devices; and a transmission step of adding predetermined information to the specific information received with the reception unit, and transmitting the specific information to a later stage as later stage specific information with a transmission unit disposed in each of the voltage monitoring devices.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0038">In the ninth aspect of the present invention, the method of setting the information is performed similar to the voltage monitoring devices in the voltage monitoring system in one of the first aspect to the seventh aspect of the present invention. Accordingly, it is possible to obtain an effect similar to that in the voltage monitoring system in one of the first aspect to the seventh aspect of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0039">According to a tenth aspect of the present invention, a method is provided for setting specific information relative to each of a plurality of voltage monitoring devices of a voltage monitoring system, in which the voltage monitoring devices are connected to each other in series for monitoring a voltage of each of a plurality of battery units obtained by dividing per specific number a plurality of batteries connected in series.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0040">According to the tenth aspect of the present invention, the method of setting the information includes a reception step of receiving specific information transmitted from a former stage with a reception unit disposed in each of the voltage monitoring devices; a generation step of adding predetermined information to the specific information received with the reception unit to generate self specific information with a generation unit disposed in each of the voltage monitoring devices; a storage step of storing the self specific information generated with the generation unit in a storage unit disposed in each of the voltage monitoring devices; and a transmission step of transmitting the self specific information generated with the generation unit to a later stage with a transmission unit disposed in each of the voltage monitoring devices.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0041">In the tenth aspect of the present invention, the method of setting the information is performed similar to the voltage monitoring devices in the voltage monitoring system in one of the first aspect to the seventh aspect of the present invention. Accordingly, it is possible to obtain an effect similar to that in the voltage monitoring system in one of the first aspect to the seventh aspect of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0042">As described above, according to the present invention, it is possible to set the specific information with respect to each of the voltage monitoring devices without disposing a special terminal in each of the voltage monitoring devices for setting specific information for specifying each of the voltage monitoring devices.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0043" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram showing a voltage monitoring system according to a first embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram showing an ID setting circuit and a selection circuit of the voltage monitoring system according to the first embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a block diagram showing a main portion of the voltage monitoring system according to the first embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a time chart showing an operation of the voltage monitoring system in an SPI communication according to the first embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a time chart showing an operation of the ID setting circuit of the voltage monitoring device according to the first embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a block diagram showing a main portion of a voltage monitoring system according to a second embodiment of the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a block diagram showing a conventional voltage monitoring system.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0050" num="0050">Hereunder, preferred embodiments of the present invention will be explained with reference to the accompanying drawings. In the following description, components similar to those of the conventional voltage monitoring system <b>100</b> and the assembled battery <b>116</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> are designated with the same reference numerals, and explanations thereof are omitted.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">First Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0051" num="0051">A first embodiment of the present invention will be explained. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram showing a voltage monitoring system <b>10</b> according to the first embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0052">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the voltage monitoring system <b>10</b> includes a plurality of voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> for monitoring a voltage of each of the batteries <b>118</b>. The voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> are connected in series.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0053">In the embodiment, a main device <b>14</b> is connected in series to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> at the most front stage, so that the main device <b>14</b> is situated at a former stage relative to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> at the most front stage. The main device <b>14</b> is provided for receiving voltage information (for example, a voltage value) indicating a voltage from each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>, and for controlling an operation of each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0054">In the embodiment, each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> is connected to each of the batteries <b>118</b> of the assembled battery <b>116</b> for monitoring a voltage value of each of the batteries <b>118</b>. The voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> are connected in series, so that the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> arranged adjacently are capable of communicating with each other. The voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> of the voltage monitoring system <b>10</b> have an identical configuration. In the following description, the configuration of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> directly connected to the main device <b>14</b> will be explained as an example.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0055">In the embodiment, the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> includes communication terminals <b>20</b>H and <b>28</b>D. The communication terminal <b>20</b>H is connected to a communication terminal <b>14</b>A of the main device <b>14</b>, and the communication terminal <b>28</b>D is connected to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> at a later stage. Accordingly, it is configured such that the main device <b>14</b> is capable of receiving and transmitting information with respect to all of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> through the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> directly connected to the main device <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0056">In the embodiment, the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> includes a control circuit <b>20</b>, a voltage measurement circuit <b>22</b>, a clock generation circuit <b>24</b>, an ID setting circuit <b>26</b>, and a selection circuit <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0057">In the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>, the control circuit <b>20</b> includes first to third input terminals <b>20</b>A to <b>20</b>C, first to fourth output terminals <b>20</b>D to <b>20</b>G, and a communication terminal <b>20</b>H. The voltage measurement circuit <b>22</b> includes first and second input terminals <b>22</b>A and <b>22</b>B, an output terminal <b>22</b>C, a positive polarity connection terminal <b>22</b>D, and a negative polarity connection terminal <b>22</b>D. The clock generation circuit <b>24</b> includes an output terminal <b>24</b>A. The ID setting circuit <b>26</b> includes first to third input terminals <b>26</b>A to <b>26</b>C and first to third output terminals <b>26</b>D to <b>26</b>F. The selection circuit <b>28</b> includes first to third input terminals <b>28</b>A to <b>28</b>C and a communication terminal <b>28</b>D.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0058">In the embodiment, the control circuit <b>20</b> includes a CPU (Central Processing Unit), an ROM (Read Only Memory), an RAM (Random Access Memory), and a non-volatile storage medium such as an NVM (Non-Volatile Memory) for storing various types of information to be stored even after the voltage monitoring device <b>102</b> is turned off. The control circuit <b>20</b> is provided for controlling an entire operation of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0059">In the embodiment, the second input terminal <b>20</b>B of the control circuit <b>20</b> is connected to the output terminal <b>22</b>C of the voltage measurement circuit <b>22</b>. The first output terminal <b>20</b>D of the control circuit <b>20</b> is connected to the first input terminal <b>22</b>A of the voltage measurement circuit <b>22</b>. The fourth output terminal <b>20</b>G of the control circuit <b>20</b> is connected to the first input terminal <b>28</b>A of the selection circuit <b>28</b>. The communication terminal <b>20</b>H of the control circuit <b>20</b> is connected to the communication terminal <b>14</b>A of the main device <b>14</b>. Accordingly, the control circuit <b>20</b> is capable of controlling an operation of the voltage measurement circuit <b>22</b>, acquiring information from the voltage measurement circuit <b>22</b>, outputting information to the selection circuit <b>28</b>, and receiving and transmitting with the main device <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0060">In the embodiment, the voltage measurement circuit <b>22</b> is provided for measuring a voltage of a power source according to an instruction of the control circuit <b>20</b>. More specifically, the positive polarity connection terminal <b>22</b>D of the voltage measurement circuit <b>22</b> is connected to a positive polarity terminal of corresponding one of the batteries <b>118</b>, and the negative polarity connection terminal <b>22</b>E of the voltage measurement circuit <b>22</b> is connected to a negative polarity terminal of corresponding one of the batteries <b>118</b>, so that the voltage measurement circuit <b>22</b> is capable of measuring a voltage of corresponding one of the batteries <b>118</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0061">In the embodiment, the clock generation circuit <b>24</b> is provided for generating a clock signal (a CLK signal) for defining an operation timing of the control circuit <b>20</b>, the voltage measurement circuit <b>22</b>, and the ID setting circuit <b>26</b> of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>. The output terminal <b>24</b>A of the clock generation circuit <b>24</b> is connected to the first input terminal <b>20</b>A of the control circuit <b>20</b>, the second input terminal <b>22</b>B of the voltage measurement circuit <b>22</b>, the second input terminal <b>22</b>B of the voltage measurement circuit <b>22</b>, and the first input terminal <b>26</b>A of the ID setting circuit <b>26</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0062">Accordingly, the clock generation circuit <b>24</b> is arranged to generate the clock signal for defining the operation timing of the control circuit <b>20</b>, the voltage measurement circuit <b>22</b>, and the ID setting circuit <b>26</b> of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>, and to supply the clock signal thus generated to the control circuit <b>20</b>, the voltage measurement circuit <b>22</b>, and the ID setting circuit <b>26</b> of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0063">In the embodiment, the second input terminal <b>26</b>B of the ID setting circuit <b>26</b> is connected to the third output terminal <b>20</b>F of the control circuit <b>20</b>. The third input terminal <b>26</b>C of the ID setting circuit <b>26</b> is connected to the second output terminal <b>20</b>E of the control circuit <b>20</b>. The second output terminal <b>26</b>E of the ID setting circuit <b>26</b> is connected to the second input terminal <b>28</b>B of the selection circuit <b>28</b>. The third output terminal <b>26</b>F of the ID setting circuit <b>26</b> is connected to the third input terminal <b>28</b>C of the selection circuit <b>28</b>. Accordingly, the ID setting circuit <b>26</b> is capable of setting an ID signal of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>, and for controlling the selection circuit <b>28</b> according to an instruction of the control circuit <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0064">In the embodiment, the communication terminal <b>28</b>D of the selection circuit <b>28</b> is connected to the communication terminal <b>20</b>H of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> connected to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> of the selection circuit <b>28</b>. Accordingly, the selection circuit <b>28</b> is capable of selecting one of the information input from the control circuit <b>20</b> and the information input from the ID setting circuit <b>26</b> according to an instruction of the control circuit <b>20</b>, and is capable of receiving and transmitting information between the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> and the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> of the selection circuit <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0065"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram showing the ID setting circuit <b>26</b> and the selection circuit <b>28</b> of the voltage monitoring system <b>10</b> according to the first embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0066">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the ID setting circuit <b>26</b> includes a divider circuit <b>40</b>, a first holding circuit <b>42</b>, a second holding circuit <b>44</b>, a third holding circuit <b>46</b>, a fourth holding circuit <b>48</b>, a fifth holding circuit <b>50</b>, a counter circuit <b>52</b>, a comparison circuit <b>54</b>, an AND circuit <b>56</b>, a shift register <b>58</b>, an inversion circuit <b>60</b>, a multiplexer circuit <b>62</b>, an increment circuit <b>64</b>, and a bus connection circuit <b>66</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0067">In the embodiment, the divider circuit <b>40</b> includes a clock signal input terminal, a D terminal representing a signal input terminal for inputting a signal; a Q terminal representing a signal output terminal for outputting a signal; a QB terminal representing an inverse signal outputting terminal for outputting an inverse signal of the signal output from the Q terminal; and an EN terminal representing an enable terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0068">In the embodiment, the first holding circuit <b>42</b> includes a clock signal input terminal, an S terminal representing a set input terminal; an R terminal representing a reset input terminal; and a Q terminal representing a data output terminal. Each of the second holding circuit <b>44</b>, the third holding circuit <b>46</b>, and the fourth holding circuit <b>48</b> includes a clock signal input terminal, the D terminal, and the Q terminal. The fifth holding circuit <b>50</b> includes a clock signal input terminal, the D terminal, the Q terminal, and the EN terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0069">In the embodiment, the counter circuit <b>52</b> includes the clock signal input terminal, the Q terminal, the EN terminal, and the R terminal. The comparison circuit <b>54</b> includes the Q terminal, and an A terminal and a B terminal representing signal input terminals for inputting various signals. The AND circuit <b>56</b> includes a first input terminal, a second input terminal, and an output terminal. The shift register <b>58</b> includes an SEN terminal representing a shift operation enable terminal, the EN terminal, the D terminal, the clock signal input terminal, and the Q terminal. Each of the inversion circuit <b>60</b> and the increment circuit <b>64</b> includes an input terminal and an output terminal. The multiplexer circuit <b>62</b> includes an output terminal and first to third input terminals. The bus connection circuit <b>66</b> includes an output terminal and first to third terminals.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0070">In the embodiment, the clock signal input terminal of the divider circuit <b>40</b> is connected to the first input terminal <b>26</b>A, and the Q terminal of the divider circuit <b>40</b> is connected to the second output terminal <b>26</b>E and the first input terminal of the AND circuit <b>56</b>. Further, the EN terminal of the divider circuit <b>40</b> is connected to the second input terminal of the AND circuit <b>56</b> and the input terminal of the inversion circuit <b>60</b>, and the QB terminal of the divider circuit <b>40</b> is connected to the D terminal of the divider circuit <b>40</b>. Accordingly, when the clock signal is input into the clock signal input terminal of the divider circuit <b>40</b> from the clock generation circuit <b>24</b> through the first input terminal <b>26</b>A, the divider circuit <b>40</b> converts the clock signal to a serial clock signal (an SCLK signal) with a specific frequency, and outputs the serial clock signal from the Q terminal thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0071">In the embodiment, the clock signal input terminal of the first holding circuit <b>42</b> is connected to the first input terminal <b>26</b>A (connection is not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>), and the S terminal of the first holding circuit <b>42</b> is connected to the second input terminal <b>26</b>B. Further, the Q terminal of the first holding circuit <b>42</b> is connected to the D terminal of the second holding circuit <b>44</b> and the EN terminal of the counter circuit <b>52</b>, and the R terminal of the first holding circuit <b>42</b> is connected to the Q terminal of the comparison circuit <b>54</b>. Accordingly, when a high level signal is input into the S terminal of the first holding circuit <b>42</b> from the control circuit <b>20</b> through the second input terminal <b>26</b>B as a start signal for starting the ID setting circuit <b>26</b>, the first holding circuit <b>42</b> outputs the high level signal from the Q terminal thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0072">In the embodiment, the clock signal input terminal of the second holding circuit <b>44</b> is connected to the first input terminal <b>26</b>A (connection is not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>), and the Q terminal of the first holding circuit <b>42</b> is connected to the D terminal of the third holding circuit <b>46</b>. Accordingly, when the high level signal is input from the first holding circuit <b>42</b>, the second holding circuit <b>44</b> outputs the high level signal from the Q terminal thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0073">In the embodiment, the clock signal input terminal of the third holding circuit <b>46</b> is connected to the first input terminal <b>26</b>A (connection is not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>), and the Q terminal of the first holding circuit <b>42</b> is connected to the second input terminal of the AND circuit <b>56</b>, the first input terminal of the multiplexer circuit <b>62</b>, and the third output terminal <b>26</b>F. Accordingly, when the high level signal is input from the second holding circuit <b>44</b>, the third holding circuit <b>46</b> outputs the high level signal as a selection signal from the Q terminal thereof, thereby constituting a delay circuit together with the second holding circuit <b>44</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0074">In the embodiment, the clock signal input terminal of the fourth holding circuit <b>48</b> is connected to the first input terminal <b>26</b>A (connection is not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>), and the D terminal of the fourth holding circuit <b>48</b> is connected to the second input terminal <b>26</b>B. Further, the Q terminal of the fourth holding circuit <b>48</b> is connected to the EN terminal of the shift register <b>58</b>. Accordingly, when the high level signal as the start signal is input into the D terminal of the fourth holding circuit <b>48</b> from the control circuit <b>20</b> through the second input terminal <b>26</b>B, the fourth holding circuit <b>48</b> outputs the high level signal from the Q terminal thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0075">In the embodiment, the clock signal input terminal of the fifth holding circuit <b>50</b> is connected to the first input terminal <b>26</b>A (connection is not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>), and the D terminal of the fifth holding circuit <b>50</b> is connected to the third input terminal <b>26</b>C. Further, the EN terminal of the fifth holding circuit <b>50</b> is connected to the second input terminal <b>26</b>B, and the Q terminal of the fifth holding circuit <b>50</b> is connected to the input terminal of the increment circuit <b>64</b> and the first output terminal <b>26</b>D. Accordingly, when a write data signal with 8 bit representing information (for example, an ID signal) to be set relative to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> is input into the D terminal of the fifth holding circuit <b>50</b> from the control circuit <b>20</b> through the third input terminal <b>26</b>C, the fifth holding circuit <b>50</b> outputs the write data signal from the Q terminal thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0076">In the embodiment, the clock signal input terminal of the counter circuit <b>52</b> is connected to the first input terminal <b>26</b>A (connection is not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>), and the R terminal of the counter circuit <b>52</b> is connected to the EN terminal of the counter circuit <b>52</b>. Further, the Q terminal of the counter circuit <b>52</b> is connected to the A terminal of the comparison circuit <b>54</b>. Accordingly, when the high level signal is output from the Q terminal of the first holding circuit <b>42</b>, the counter circuit <b>52</b> starts a count-up operation.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0077">In the embodiment, it is configured such that a predetermined value with 6 bit (for example, data indicating 47 in the decimal numeration system) is input into the B terminal of the comparison circuit <b>54</b>. When a count value of the counter circuit <b>52</b> reaches a predetermined value, the comparison circuit <b>54</b> outputs from the Q terminal thereof a high level signal as a count end signal indicating the count value of the counter circuit <b>52</b> reaches the predetermined value.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0078">In the embodiment, the output terminal of the AND circuit <b>56</b> is connected to the SEN terminal of the shift register <b>58</b>. When the high level signal is input from the divider circuit <b>40</b>, and the high level signal is input from the third holding circuit <b>46</b>, the AND circuit <b>56</b> outputs the high level signal from the output terminal thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0079">In the embodiment, the clock signal input terminal of the shift register <b>58</b> is connected to the first input terminal <b>26</b>A (connection is not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>), and the D terminal of the shift register <b>58</b> is connected to the output terminal of the bus connection circuit <b>66</b>. Further, the Q terminal of the counter circuit <b>52</b> is connected to the second input terminal of the multiplexer circuit <b>62</b>. Accordingly, when the signal is input from the bus connection circuit <b>66</b>, the shift register <b>58</b> outputs the signal per one bit from the Q terminal thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0080">In the embodiment, the output terminal of the inversion circuit <b>60</b> is connected to the second output terminal <b>26</b>E. Accordingly, when the signal is input from the divider circuit <b>40</b>, the inversion circuit <b>60</b> inverts the signal, and outputs a chip select signal (a CS signal) from the output terminal thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0081">In the embodiment, it is configured such that a predetermined value with one bit (for example, data indicating one in the binary numeration system) is input into the third input terminal of the multiplexer circuit <b>62</b>. The output terminal of the multiplexer circuit <b>62</b> is connected to the second output terminal <b>26</b>E. When a plurality of signals is input, the multiplexer circuit <b>62</b> combines the signals and outputs one single serial data signal (an SDI signal).</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0082">In the embodiment, the output terminal of the increment circuit <b>64</b> is connected to the first input terminal of the bus connection circuit <b>66</b>. Accordingly, when the write data signal is input from the fifth holding circuit <b>50</b>, the increment circuit <b>64</b> adds one to a value indicated with the write data signal, and outputs an updated data signal (a new write data signal) from the output terminal thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0083">In the embodiment, it is configured such that a command signal with 8 bit (for example, a signal indicating write access) for instructing an operation content of the ID setting circuit <b>26</b> is input into the second input terminal of the bus connection circuit <b>66</b>. Further, it is configured such that an address signal (for example, an address assigned to an arbitrary circuit of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>) is input into the third input terminal of the bus connection circuit <b>66</b>. Accordingly, the bus connection circuit <b>66</b> outputs a shift data signal obtained through combining the address signal, the command signal, and the updated data signal.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0084">In the embodiment, according to a signal with three bit input into the second input terminal <b>28</b>B from the ID setting circuit <b>26</b> through the second output terminal <b>26</b>E, a signal with three bit input into the first input terminal <b>28</b>A from the control circuit <b>20</b> through the fourth output terminal <b>20</b>G, and the selection signal input into the third input terminal <b>28</b>C from the third holding circuit <b>46</b> through the third output terminal <b>26</b>F, the selection circuit <b>28</b> is provided for outputting a serial data output signal (an SDO signal) from the communication terminal <b>28</b>D to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> at the later stage.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0085">As described above, in the voltage monitoring system <b>10</b> in the embodiment, an SPI (Serial Peripheral Interface) communication is applied for communicating between the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> and between the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> and the main device <b>14</b>. The SPI communication is performed according to the CS signal, the SCLK signal, the SDI signal, and the SDO signal.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0086"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a block diagram showing a main portion of the voltage monitoring system <b>10</b> according to the first embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0087">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> includes a reception unit <b>62</b>&#x2032;, a storage unit <b>64</b>&#x2032;, a generation unit <b>66</b>&#x2032;, a transmission unit <b>68</b>, a connection terminal <b>70</b>, and communication terminals <b>72</b> and <b>74</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0088">In the embodiment, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the reception unit <b>62</b>&#x2032; corresponds to the control circuit <b>20</b>; storage unit <b>64</b>&#x2032; and generation unit <b>66</b>&#x2032; correspond to the ID setting circuit <b>26</b>; the transmission unit <b>68</b> corresponds to the selection circuit <b>28</b>; the communication terminal <b>72</b> corresponds to the communication terminal <b>20</b>H; the communication terminal <b>74</b> corresponds to the communication terminal <b>28</b>D, and the connection terminal <b>70</b> corresponds to the positive polarity connection terminal <b>22</b>D and the negative polarity connection terminal <b>22</b>E.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0089">In the embodiment, an output terminal of the reception unit <b>62</b>&#x2032; is connected to an input terminal of storage unit <b>64</b>&#x2032; and an input terminal of generation unit <b>66</b>&#x2032;. An output terminal of generation unit <b>66</b>&#x2032; is connected to an input terminal of the transmission unit <b>68</b>. The communication terminal <b>74</b> as an output terminal of the transmission unit <b>68</b> is connected to the communication terminal <b>72</b> of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> at the later stage.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0090">In the embodiment, an output terminal of the main device <b>14</b> is connected to an input terminal of the reception unit <b>62</b>&#x2032; through the communication terminal <b>72</b>. Accordingly, the main device <b>14</b> transmits the ID signal of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> to which the main device <b>14</b> is directly connected.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0091">In the embodiment, each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> is connected to the corresponding battery <b>118</b> through the connection terminal <b>70</b>, so that the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> is capable of measuring a voltage value of the battery <b>118</b>. More specifically, each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> measures a voltage value of the corresponding battery <b>118</b> at a specific interval (for example, 0.1 second), and stores the voltage value in an internal memory (not shown) in an overwriting manner. Each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> outputs the voltage value to the main device <b>14</b> through the communication terminal <b>72</b> according to an instruction from the main device <b>14</b>. Accordingly, the main device <b>14</b> is capable of acquiring information obtained with each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> (for example, the voltage value of the battery <b>118</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0092">In the embodiment, the reception unit <b>62</b>&#x2032; is provided for receiving the ID signal transmitted from the main device <b>14</b>. Then, storage unit <b>64</b>&#x2032; outputs the ID signal thus received to storage unit <b>64</b>&#x2032; as well as generation unit <b>66</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0093">In the embodiment, storage unit <b>64</b>&#x2032; is provided for storing the ID signal input from the reception unit <b>62</b>&#x2032; as specific information (referred to as a self ID signal) for specifying the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> thereof into a predetermined storage area. Accordingly, it is possible to set the ID signal specific to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0094">In the embodiment, generation unit <b>66</b>&#x2032; is provided for adding predetermined information to the ID signal input from the reception unit <b>62</b>&#x2032;. Accordingly, generation unit <b>66</b>&#x2032; is capable of generating an ID signal (referred to as a later stage ID signal) to be set relative to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> arranged at the later stage of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> thereof, and of outputting the later stage ID signal to the transmission unit <b>68</b>. The transmission unit <b>68</b> is provided for transmitting the later stage ID signal input from generation unit <b>66</b>&#x2032; to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> at the later stage through the communication terminal <b>74</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0095">In the embodiment, in the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> connected in series at the later stages, the self ID signal is set similar to the process described above. Further, the later stage ID signal is generated as the ID signal of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> with the ID signal not set yet, so that the later stage ID signal thus generated is output.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0096">An operation of the voltage monitoring system <b>10</b> will be explained. First, the SPI communication applied to the voltage monitoring system <b>10</b> will be explained with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a time chart showing the operation of the voltage monitoring system <b>10</b> in the SPI communication according to the first embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0097">In the following description, as an example, it is supposed that the specific ID signal is set to each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>. Further, the main device <b>14</b> outputs the CS signal, the SCLK signal, and the SDI signal as well as the command signal including the ID signal and the address signal from the communication terminal <b>14</b>A thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0098">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, when the main device <b>14</b> executes a write access for writing information into the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>, first, the control circuit <b>20</b>, the voltage measurement circuit <b>22</b>, and the ID setting circuit <b>26</b> of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> directly connected to the main device <b>14</b> obtain the CS signal, the SCLK signal, and the SDI signal input from the main device <b>14</b>. When the CS signal input from the main device <b>14</b> is at a low level, the control circuit <b>20</b> obtains the SDI signal at a rising edge of the SCLK signal, so that the control circuit <b>20</b> acquires the address signal, the command signal, and the write data signal. In the next step, the control circuit <b>20</b> of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> performs a writing process for writing the information only in the predetermined storage area of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> matching to the ID signal contained in the command signal.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0099">In the embodiment, when the main device <b>14</b> executes a read access for reading information from the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>, and the CS signal input from the main device <b>14</b> is at a low level, the control circuit <b>20</b> obtains the SDI signal at the rising edge of the SCLK signal, so that the control circuit <b>20</b> acquires the address signal and the command signal. Then, according to the address signal and the command signal specified with the main device <b>14</b>, the control circuit <b>20</b> of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> matching to the ID signal contained in the command signal performs a reading process for reading the information from the predetermined storage area to read the read data signal. After the control circuit <b>20</b> of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> performs the reading process, the control circuit <b>20</b> of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> outputs the read data as the SDO signal to the main device <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0100">Next, an operation of the voltage monitoring system <b>10</b> for setting the ID signal relative to the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> will be explained with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a time chart showing an operation of the ID setting circuit <b>26</b> of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> according to the first embodiment of the present invention. In the following description, it is supposed that the ID signal is not set to each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> yet.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0101">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, first, the main device <b>14</b> performs the write access to an address specifying the ID setting circuit <b>26</b> of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>, and outputs the write data signal indicating a value &#x201c;0&#x201d;. It is noted that the write data signal functions as a trigger signal for setting the ID signal to each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0102">In the embodiment, when the control circuit <b>20</b> of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> detects the write access, the control circuit <b>20</b> transits the start signal from the low level signal to the high level signal to start the ID setting circuit <b>26</b>. At the same time, the control circuit <b>20</b> outputs the write data signal indicating the value &#x201c;0&#x201d; and input from the main device <b>14</b> to the ID setting circuit <b>26</b>. Accordingly, at a timing T<b>1</b>, the write data signal at the third input terminal <b>26</b>C of the ID setting circuit <b>26</b> changes to &#x201c;0&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0103">In the embodiment, when the start signal becomes the high level signal, the first holding circuit <b>42</b> outputs the high level signal from the Q terminal thereof, and the fourth holding circuit <b>48</b> and the fifth holding circuit <b>50</b> acquire the high level signal as the start signal. Accordingly, the fourth holding circuit <b>48</b> outputs the high level signal from the Q terminal thereof. Further, the fifth holding circuit <b>50</b> retrieves the write data signal with the value &#x201c;0&#x201d;, so that the write data signal is set as the ID signal of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> thereof. Then, the fifth holding circuit <b>50</b> outputs the write data signal to the storage unit <b>64</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0104">In the embodiment, when the storage unit <b>64</b>&#x2032; receives the write data signal from the fifth holding circuit <b>50</b>, the storage unit <b>64</b>&#x2032; adds one to the value &#x201c;0&#x201d; indicated with the write data signal input from the fifth holding circuit <b>50</b>, and outputs the write data signal to the generation unit <b>66</b>&#x2032;. At a timing T<b>2</b>, the generation unit <b>66</b>&#x2032; combines the address signal, the command signal, and the write data signal with the value &#x201c;1&#x201d; input from the storage unit <b>64</b>&#x2032; to generate the shift data signal with 24 bit, and outputs the shift data signal to the D terminal of the shift register <b>58</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0105">In the embodiment, at a timing T<b>3</b>, when the high level signal is input into the counter circuit <b>52</b> from the Q terminal of the first holding circuit <b>42</b>, the counter circuit <b>52</b> starts a count up operation.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0106">In the embodiment, at a timing T<b>4</b>, when a count up value of the counter circuit <b>52</b> changes from &#x201c;1&#x201d; to &#x201c;2&#x201d;, the third holding circuit <b>46</b> outputs the high level signal as the selection signal from the Q terminal thereof. At the same time, the inversion circuit <b>60</b> changes the high level signal input from the Q terminal of the third holding circuit <b>46</b> to the low level signal, and outputs the low level signal as the CS signal.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0107">In the embodiment, at a timing T<b>5</b>, when the counter circuit <b>52</b> counts up to a predetermined value (for example, 47), the counter circuit <b>52</b> controls the comparison circuit <b>54</b> to output the high level signal from the Q terminal of the comparison circuit <b>54</b>, so that the high level signal output from the Q terminal of the first holding circuit <b>42</b> at that time is transited to the low level signal. Accordingly, at a timing T<b>6</b>, the third holding circuit <b>46</b> transits the high level signal output from the Q terminal thereof at that time to the low level signal, so that the inversion circuit <b>60</b> transits the low level signal output from the output terminal thereof to the high level signal.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0108">In the embodiment, during a period of time from when the selection signal becomes the high level signal to when the selection signal returns to the low level signal, i.e., a period of time from the timing T<b>4</b> to the timing T<b>6</b>, the CS signal, the SCLK signal, the address signal indicating the address of the ID setting circuit <b>26</b> of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> connected thereto, the command signal indicating the write access, and the SDI signal containing the write data signal with the value &#x201c;1&#x201d; are output to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> with the ID signal at the later stage at that time, i.e., the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> connected thereto with the ID signal not set yet.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0109">In the embodiment, when the high level signal is input from the fourth holding circuit <b>48</b> to the EN terminal of the shift register <b>58</b>, the shift register <b>58</b> retrieves the shift data signal from the bus connection circuit <b>66</b> through the D terminal thereof. Accordingly, when the high level signal is input from the AND circuit <b>56</b>, the shift data signal is retrieved, and the SDI signal is generated and output per one bit from the address signal.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0110">As described above, in the first embodiment, after the ID signal indicating the specific value is set to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>, the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> adds one to the specific value to generate the new ID signal, and outputs the new ID signal as the later stage ID signal to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> at the later stage. Accordingly, the specific ID signal is set to each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> in the serial connection order from the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> at the most front stage directly connected to the main device <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0111">Accordingly, in the voltage monitoring system <b>10</b> in the first embodiment, it is not necessary to provide an ID setting special terminal in each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> for setting the ID signal as opposed to the conventional voltage monitoring system. Further, the communication terminals <b>20</b>H and <b>28</b>D are provided for communicating with the external device such as the main device <b>14</b>, and function as the ID setting special terminal as well.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0112">Further, when the conventional voltage monitoring system is used for monitoring an assembled battery with a large capacity, it is difficult to provide an external interface for adding various functions due to the restriction of the number of the terminals. On the other hand, in the voltage monitoring system <b>10</b> in the first embodiment, as described above, it is not necessary to provide an ID setting special terminal in each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>. Accordingly, it is possible to expand freedom of the terminal arrangement, and it is possible to provide an external interface for adding various functions.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0113">For example, when the bit number of input/output signals of the fifth holding circuit <b>50</b> of the ID setting circuit <b>26</b> is 8 bit, it is possible to connect <b>256</b> of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> in series at multiple stages, and it is possible to provide an external interface in each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0114">As described above, in the voltage monitoring system <b>10</b> in the first embodiment, the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> are connected in series for monitoring the voltage of each of the batteries <b>118</b> connected in series. The control unit <b>20</b> of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> receives the ID signal transmitted from the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> at the former stage, and stores and sets the ID signal in the fifth holding circuit <b>50</b> as the self ID signal. Further, the increment circuit <b>64</b> adds &#x201c;1&#x201d; as the predetermined information to the ID signal thus received, so that the ID signal is transmitted to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> at the later stage as the later stage ID signal. Accordingly, it is possible to set the ID signal in each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> without providing a special terminal for setting the ID signal for specifying each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0115">Further, in the voltage monitoring system <b>10</b> in the first embodiment, &#x201c;1&#x201d; as the predetermined information is added to the self ID signal to generate the later stage ID signal. Accordingly, it is possible to assign the specific ID signal to each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> with the minimum bit number. As a result, it is possible to set the ID signal in a large number of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>. Further, it is possible to transmit and receive the ID signal with a minimum number of signal lines.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0116">Further, in the voltage monitoring system <b>10</b> in the first embodiment, the main device <b>14</b> is connected in series to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> at the most front stage, so that the main device <b>14</b> is situated at a former stage relative to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> at the most front stage. The main device <b>14</b> is provided for receiving and transmitting the information with respect to each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>. Accordingly, it is possible to confirm the information collected with the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>, and for controlling the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> with the simple configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0117">Further, in the voltage monitoring system <b>10</b> in the first embodiment, the main device <b>14</b> is provided for collecting the voltage information indicating the voltage to be monitored from each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>. Accordingly, it is possible to easily confirm a relative remaining amount of the batteries <b>118</b>.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">Second Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0118" num="0118">A second embodiment of the present invention will be explained next. In the first embodiment, the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> sets the ID signal input from outside as the self ID signal. Then, the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> generates and outputs the later stage ID signal to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b> at the later stage, so that the specific ID signal is set to each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0119">In the second embodiment, the specific ID signal is set to each of voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>A with a different process. Components in the second embodiment similar to those in the first embodiment are designated with the same reference numerals, and explanations thereof are omitted. In the following description of the second embodiment, only differences from the first embodiment will be explained.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0120"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a block diagram showing a main portion of a voltage monitoring system <b>10</b>A according to the second embodiment of the present invention. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, instead of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> of the voltage monitoring system <b>10</b> in the first embodiment, the voltage monitoring system <b>10</b>A includes the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0121">In the second embodiment, as opposed to the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> in the first embodiment, each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>A includes a reception unit <b>62</b>A instead of the reception unit <b>62</b>&#x2032;, a storage unit <b>64</b>A instead of storage unit <b>64</b>&#x2032;, a generation unit <b>66</b>A instead of generation unit <b>66</b>&#x2032;, and a transmission unit <b>68</b>A instead of the transmission unit <b>68</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0122">In the second embodiment, an output terminal of the reception unit <b>62</b>A is connected to an input terminal of the generation unit <b>66</b>A. An output terminal of the generation unit <b>66</b>A is connected to an input terminal of the transmission unit <b>68</b>A. Another output terminal of the generation unit <b>66</b>A is connected to an input terminal of the storage unit <b>64</b>A. The communication terminal <b>74</b> as an output terminal of the transmission unit <b>68</b>A is connected to the communication terminal <b>72</b> of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>A at the later stage.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0123">In the second embodiment, the output terminal of the main device <b>14</b> is connected to an input terminal of the reception unit <b>62</b>A through the communication terminal <b>72</b>. Accordingly, the main device <b>14</b> transmits a generation signal for generating the ID signal of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>A to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>A to which the main device <b>14</b> is directly connected.</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0124">In the embodiment, the reception unit <b>62</b>A is provided for receiving the ID signal transmitted from the main device <b>14</b>. Then, the storage unit <b>64</b>A outputs the ID signal thus received to the generation unit <b>66</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0125">In the embodiment, the generation unit <b>66</b>A is provided for adding predetermined information (for example, a signal indicating the value &#x201c;1&#x201d;) to the generation signal input from the reception unit <b>62</b>A. Accordingly, the generation unit <b>66</b>A is capable of generating and outputting the self ID signal to the storage unit <b>64</b>A. Further, the generation unit <b>66</b>A is capable of outputting the ID signal to <b>68</b><i>a </i>as the generating signal for generating the later stage ID of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>A arranged at the later stage.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0126">In the embodiment, the storage unit <b>64</b>A is provided for storing the ID signal input from the generation unit <b>66</b>A as the specific information for specifying the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>A thereof into a predetermined storage area. Accordingly, it is possible to set the specific ID signal to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>A. The transmission unit <b>68</b> is provided for transmitting the later stage ID signal input from the generation unit <b>66</b>A to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>A at the later stage through the communication terminal <b>74</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0127">In the second embodiment, in the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>A connected in series at the later stages, the generation signal as the self ID signal is set similar to the process described above. Further, in the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>A at the later stages, the self ID signal is set and the generation signal is generated, so that the generation signal is transmitted.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0128">As described above, in the second embodiment, after the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>A receives the generation signal from the former stage, the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>A adds one to the generation signal thus received to generate the new generation signal, and the new generation signal is stored in the storage unit <b>64</b>A as the self ID signal. Then, the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>A outputs the self ID signal as the generation signal for generating the later stage ID signal to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>A at the later stage. Accordingly, the specific ID signal is set to each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>A in the serial connection order from the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>A at the most front stage directly connected to the main device <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0129">As described above, in the voltage monitoring system <b>10</b>A in the second embodiment, the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>A are connected in series for monitoring the voltage of each of the batteries <b>118</b> connected in series. The control unit <b>20</b> of the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>A receives the ID signal transmitted from the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>A at the former stage, and the predetermined information is added to the ID signal thus received to generate the self ID signal, so that the self ID signal is stored and set in the predetermined storage area. Further, the self ID signal thus generated is transmitted to the voltage monitoring device <b>12</b>A at the later stage. Accordingly, it is possible to set the ID signal in each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>A without providing a special terminal for setting the ID signal for specifying each of the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0130">In the first and second embodiments described above, the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> or the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>A are provided for monitoring the voltage values of the batteries <b>118</b>. Alternatively, the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> or the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>A may be connected to the assembled battery <b>116</b>, in which the batteries <b>118</b> are divided into a specific number such as two and three to form battery units. Accordingly, the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> or the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>A may be provided for monitoring voltage values of the battery units.</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0131">Further, in the first and second embodiments described above, the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> or the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>A are provided for monitoring the voltage values of the batteries <b>118</b> as the secondary batteries. Alternatively, the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b> or the voltage monitoring devices <b>12</b>A may be connected in series to primary batteries functioning as the assembled battery.</p>
<p id="p-0132" num="0132">Further, in the first and second embodiments described above, &#x201c;1&#x201d; is added to the ID signal to generate the new ID signal. Alternatively, a value other than &#x201c;1&#x201d; such as &#x201c;2&#x201d; may be added to the ID signal to generate the new ID signal.</p>
<p id="p-0133" num="0133">The disclosure of Japanese Patent Application No. 2010-045569, filed on Mar. 2, 2010, is incorporated in the application by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0134" num="0134">While the invention has been explained with reference to the specific embodiments of the invention, the explanation is illustrative and the invention is limited only by the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A voltage monitoring system comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of voltage monitoring devices connected to each other in series for monitoring a voltage of each of a plurality of battery units, wherein each of said voltage monitoring devices comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a reception unit for receiving specific information transmitted from a former stage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a storage unit for storing the specific information as self specific information; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transmission unit for adding predetermined information to the specific information, and for transmitting the specific information to a later stage as later stage specific information, or</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said voltage monitoring devices comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a reception unit for receiving specific information transmitted from a former stage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a generation unit for adding predetermined information to the specific information to generate self specific information;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a storage unit for storing the self specific information; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transmission unit for transmitting the self specific information to a later stage.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The voltage monitoring system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said reception unit and said transmission unit are formed of a communication terminal for communicating with an external device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The voltage monitoring system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said transmission unit is arranged to add a predetermined value as the predetermined information to the specific information.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The voltage monitoring system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein said transmission unit is arranged to add one as the predetermined value to the specific information.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The voltage monitoring system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a main device connected in series to the voltage monitoring device at a most front stage for communicating with the voltage monitoring devices.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The voltage monitoring system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein said main device is arranged to acquire voltage information indicating the voltage from each of the voltage monitoring devices.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A voltage monitoring device arranged to function as each of the voltage monitoring devices in the voltage monitoring system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A method for setting specific information relative to each of a plurality of voltage monitoring devices of a voltage monitoring system, in which the voltage monitoring devices are connected to each other in series for monitoring a voltage of each of a plurality of battery units, comprising:
<claim-text>a reception step of receiving the specific information transmitted from a former stage with a reception unit disposed in each of the voltage monitoring devices;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a storage step of storing the specific information as self specific information in a storage unit disposed in each of the voltage monitoring devices; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transmission step of adding predetermined information to the specific information and transmitting the specific information to a later stage as later stage specific information with a transmission unit disposed in each of the voltage monitoring devices, or</claim-text>
<claim-text>a reception step of receiving the specific information transmitted from a former stage with a reception unit disposed in each of the voltage monitoring devices;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a generation step of adding predetermined information to the specific information to generate self specific information with a generation unit disposed in each of the voltage monitoring devices;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a storage step of the self specific information in a storage unit disposed in each of the voltage monitoring devices; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transmission step of transmitting the self specific information to a later stage with a transmission unit disposed in each of the voltage monitoring devices.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A voltage monitoring system comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of voltage monitoring devices connected to each other in series for monitoring a voltage of each of a plurality of battery units connected to each other in series; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a main device connected in series to one of the voltage monitoring devices at a most front stage so that the main device is configured to output address information to the one of the voltage monitoring devices,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of said voltage monitoring devices includes an address generation unit, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said address generation unit is arranged to set the address information as self specific information, and add specific information to the address information to be output to a later stage, or</claim-text>
<claim-text>said address generation unit is arranged to add specific information to the address information to be set as self specific information, and add the specific information to the address information to be output to a later stage.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The voltage monitoring system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein said address generation unit is arranged to add one as the specific information to an address of the address information.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The voltage monitoring system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein each of said voltage monitoring devices includes a control unit for controlling an operation of each of the voltage monitoring devices and a selection unit for selecting one of an output from the control unit and an output from the address generation unit to be output to the later stage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The voltage monitoring system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein, said selection unit is arranged to output the one of the output from the control unit and the output from the address generation unit through a same terminal thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The voltage monitoring system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein said address generation unit is arranged to output a selection signal, and
<claim-text>said selection unit is arranged to select the one of the output from the control unit and the output from the address generation unit according to the selection signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The voltage monitoring system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein said address generation unit includes a selection signal output period setting unit for setting an output period of the selection signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The voltage monitoring system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein said selection signal output period setting unit is arranged to set the output period that starts with a start signal output from the control unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The voltage monitoring system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein said address generation unit includes a delay unit for delaying the selection signal from inputting to the selection unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. A voltage monitoring device connected to each other in series for monitoring a voltage of each of a plurality of battery units connected to each other in series per a predetermined number of the battery units, comprising:
<claim-text>an address generation unit arranged to set the address information as self specific information, and add specific information to the address information to be output to a later stage, or</claim-text>
<claim-text>arranged to add specific information to the address information to be set as self specific information, and add the specific information to the address information to be output to a later stage.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The voltage monitoring device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein said address generation unit is arranged to add one as the specific information to an address of the address information.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The voltage monitoring device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein each of said voltage monitoring devices includes a control unit for controlling an operation of each of the voltage monitoring devices and a selection unit for selecting one of an output from the control unit and an output from the address generation unit to be output to the later stage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The voltage monitoring device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein said selection unit is arranged to output the one of the output from the control unit and the output from the address generation unit through a same terminal thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The voltage monitoring device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein said address generation unit is arranged to output a selection signal, and
<claim-text>said selection unit is arranged to select the one of the output from the control unit and the output from the address generation unit according to the selection signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The voltage monitoring device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein said address generation unit includes a selection signal output period setting unit for setting an output period of the selection signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. The voltage monitoring device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, wherein said selection signal output period setting unit is arranged to set the output period that starts with a start signal output from the control unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. The voltage monitoring device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein said address generation unit includes a delay unit for delaying the selection signal from inputting to the selection unit. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
