<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624255-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624255</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13027073</doc-number>
<date>20110214</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2010-0041005</doc-number>
<date>20100430</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>108</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>29</main-group>
<subgroup>12</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257 71</main-classification>
<further-classification>257 68</further-classification>
<further-classification>257 69</further-classification>
<further-classification>257 70</further-classification>
<further-classification>257296</further-classification>
<further-classification>257516</further-classification>
<further-classification>257E27016</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Array substrate and method of fabricating the same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5923390</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Jung Mok et al.</name>
<date>19990700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0181218</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Jung et al.</name>
<date>20060800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>313631</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0158209</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ozawa</name>
<date>20080700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>345204</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0085037</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Chen et al.</name>
<date>20090400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257 71</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-1999-0003712</doc-number>
<date>19990100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2003-0016536</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20030300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2003-0055502</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20030400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-0754128</doc-number>
<date>20070800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>17</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257 59</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257 68- 71</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257296</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257516</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E27016</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110266545</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20111103</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Won</last-name>
<first-name>Yu-Bong</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yongin-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Jung</last-name>
<first-name>Jin-Goo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yongin-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tae</last-name>
<first-name>Seung-Gyu</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yongin-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Won</last-name>
<first-name>Yu-Bong</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yongin-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Jung</last-name>
<first-name>Jin-Goo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yongin-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tae</last-name>
<first-name>Seung-Gyu</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yongin-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Christie, Parker &#x26; Hale, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Samsung Display Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Yongin-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Yang</last-name>
<first-name>Minchul</first-name>
<department>2891</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An array substrate includes an active layer including a channel region, a gate electrode positioned corresponding to the channel region, and a gate insulating film between the active layer and the gate electrode. The gate electrode includes a transparent conductive film and an opaque conductive film, and the transparent conductive film is between the channel region and the opaque conductive film.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="134.11mm" wi="168.66mm" file="US08624255-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="195.24mm" wi="133.52mm" file="US08624255-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="155.62mm" wi="168.66mm" file="US08624255-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="151.55mm" wi="163.91mm" file="US08624255-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="192.53mm" wi="128.10mm" file="US08624255-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="190.67mm" wi="132.84mm" file="US08624255-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="199.31mm" wi="130.73mm" file="US08624255-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority to and the benefit of Korean Patent Application No. 10-2010-0041005 filed in the Korean Intellectual Property Office on Apr. 30, 2010, the entire contents of which are incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The described technology relates generally to an array substrate, and more particularly, to a thin film transistor array substrate of a liquid crystal display or an organic light emitting diode display, and a method of fabricating the same.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Liquid crystal displays (LCDs) and organic light emitting diode (OLED) displays are widely used for small-sized electronics and other products, such as cell phones, personal digital assistants (PDAs), and portable multimedia players (PMPs), in part because they themselves are relatively small-sized and lightweight.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">As display devices become smaller in size, the demand for higher resolutions increases. In order to realize higher resolution, it is desirable to make the size of each pixel smaller. As the size of pixels becomes smaller, it is necessary to increase the aperture ratio of the pixels, in order to satisfy brightness higher than a predetermined level.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">A display device, such as a liquid crystal display or an organic light emitting diode display, includes an array substrate, where a thin film transistor (TFT) for applying a driving voltage to a pixel electrode and a storage capacitor for storing a voltage signal in each pixel are formed on the array substrate in order to display an image. In general, a gate electrode of a thin film transistor, an electrode of a storage capacitor, etc., are formed of an opaque metal. In this case, reduction in aperture ratio may occur. Moreover, reduced picture quality caused by crosstalk between adjacent thin film transistors due to leakage current formed in the display device may occur.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The above information disclosed in the Background section is only for enhancement of understanding of the background of the described technology, and therefore, may contain information that does not form the prior art that is already known in this country to a person of ordinary skill in the art.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The described technology has been made to provide an array substrate of a display device that enhances picture quality by improving the aperture ratio and reducing leakage current.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Furthermore, embodiments of the present invention provide a method of fabricating an array substrate that improves the aperture ratio without an additional mask process.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to one exemplary embodiment, an array substrate includes an active layer including a channel region, a gate electrode positioned corresponding to the channel region, and a gate insulating film between the active layer and the gate electrode. The gate electrode includes a transparent conductive film and an opaque conductive film, and the transparent conductive film is between the channel region and the opaque conductive film.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The transparent conductive film and the opaque conductive film may be in direct contact with each other.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The transparent conductive film may include indium tin oxide (ITO), and the opaque conductive film may include molybdenum.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The transparent conductive film and the opaque conductive film may have substantially a same width.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The active layer may include polysilicon, the active layer may further include a source region on one side of the channel region and a drain region on an opposite side of the channel region, wherein the channel region may include N-type impurities, and the source region and the drain region may include P-type impurities.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">According to one exemplary embodiment, the array substrate may further include a capacitor including: a transparent lower electrode; a first insulating film on the transparent lower electrode and utilized as a dielectric film; an upper electrode positioned on the first insulating film corresponding to the transparent lower electrode; and an opaque lower electrode between the first insulating film and the transparent lower electrode.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The transparent lower electrode and the opaque lower electrode may include the same materials as the transparent conductive film and the opaque conductive film, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The transparent lower electrode and the opaque lower electrode may be arranged on the same layer as the transparent conductive film and the opaque conductive film, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The upper electrode may include a transparent conductive material.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">A width of the transparent lower electrode may be greater than a width of the upper electrode.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">According to one exemplary embodiment, the array substrate may further include a second insulating layer on the first insulating film, wherein the first insulating film may be on the gate electrode, the active layer, and the gate insulating film, and the upper electrode may be between the first insulating film and the second insulating layer.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">According to one exemplary embodiment, the array substrate may further include a source electrode connected to the source region through a first hole in the first insulating film and the second insulating layer, and a drain electrode connected to the drain region through a second hole in the first insulating film and the second insulating layer, and connected to the upper electrode through a third hole in the second insulating layer.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The third hole may be positioned corresponding to the opaque lower electrode, with the first insulating film and the upper electrode interposed therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">According to one exemplary embodiment, the array substrate may further include an organic film on the second insulating layer, the source electrode, and the drain electrode.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">According to the exemplary embodiment, the array substrate may further include a protective film separating the second insulating layer and source and drain electrodes from the organic film.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">According to the exemplary embodiment, the array substrate may further include a pixel electrode connected to the drain electrode through a fourth hole in the organic film.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The fourth hole may be positioned corresponding to the opaque lower electrode, with the first insulating film, the upper electrode, and the drain electrode interposed therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">According to another the exemplary embodiment, a method of fabricating an array substrate includes: sequentially forming an active layer, an insulating layer, a transparent conductive layer, an opaque conductive layer, and a photoresist layer on a substrate; and forming a first photoresist film positioned corresponding to the active layer and having a smaller width than that of the active layer and a second photoresist film spaced apart from the first photoresist film from the photoresist layer. The method further includes: forming a first opaque conductive film and a second opaque conductive film under the first photoresist film and the second photoresist film, respectively, by etching the opaque conductive layer utilizing a first etching process; forming a first transparent conductive film and a second transparent conductive film under the first opaque conductive film and the second opaque conductive film, respectively, by etching the transparent conductive layer utilizing a second etching process; reducing the width of the second photoresist film utilizing an ashing process, reducing widths of the first opaque conductive film and the second opaque conductive film to be smaller than the widths of the first photoresist film and the second photoresist film, respectively, utilizing a third etching process; and removing the first photoresist film and the second photoresist film.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The method may further include doping side portions of the active layer with a P+ impurity after the second etching process, and doping the active layer with a P&#x2212; impurity after the removal of the first photoresist film and the second photoresist film.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The first opaque conductive film and the first transparent conductive film may form a gate electrode, and the second opaque conductive film and the second transparent conductive film may form a lower electrode of a capacitor.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The first opaque conductive film and the first transparent conductive film may have a substantially same width, and a width of the second transparent conductive film may be greater than the width of the second opaque conductive film.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The first etching process may be a dry etching process or wet etching process.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The second etching process and the third etching process may be wet etching processes.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The opaque conductive layer may have a lower electrical resistance than the transparent conductive layer.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The opaque conductive layer may include molybdenum, and the transparent conductive layer may include ITO.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">According to one exemplary embodiment, a display device having high resolution can be realized by increasing the aperture ratio of a pixel.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Moreover, the picture quality of the display device can be enhanced by preventing crosstalk by a reduction in leakage current.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Furthermore, in the fabrication of an array substrate of the display device having high resolution, the process can be simplified because there is no additional mask process.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a planar layout view of an array substrate according to a first exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the array substrate taken along line II-II of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a cross-sectional view of an array substrate according to a second exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a planar layout view of an array substrate according to a third exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A to 5D</figref> are views sequentially showing a fabrication process of an array substrate according to one exemplary embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF SYMBOLS</heading>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><b>100</b>, <b>101</b>, <b>102</b>: array substrate</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><b>110</b>, <b>210</b>: insulation substrate</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><b>121</b>, <b>121</b>&#x2032; <b>221</b>: active layer</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><b>122</b>, <b>222</b>: source region</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><b>123</b>, <b>223</b>: drain region</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><b>124</b>, <b>224</b>: channel region</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050"><b>125</b>, <b>126</b>, <b>225</b>, <b>226</b>: lightly doped drain region</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><b>131</b>, <b>230</b>: gate insulating film</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><b>133</b>: first interlayer insulating layer</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053"><b>135</b>: second interlayer insulating layer</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><b>137</b>: protective film</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055"><b>139</b>, <b>139</b>&#x2032; organic film</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056"><b>141</b>, <b>141</b>&#x2032; gate line</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057"><b>142</b>, <b>251</b>: opaque conductive film</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058"><b>143</b>, <b>241</b>: transparent conductive film</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059"><b>151</b>: sustain voltage line</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060"><b>152</b>, <b>252</b>: opaque lower electrode</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061"><b>153</b>, <b>153</b>&#x2032; <b>242</b>: transparent lower electrode</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062"><b>161</b>, <b>161</b>&#x2032; upper electrode</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063"><b>162</b>: third contact hole</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064"><b>171</b>: data line</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065"><b>172</b>, <b>172</b>&#x2032; source electrode</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066"><b>173</b>, <b>173</b>&#x2032; drain electrode</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067"><b>174</b>, <b>174</b>&#x2032; first contact hole</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068"><b>175</b>, <b>175</b>&#x2032; second contact hole</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069"><b>181</b>: pixel electrode</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070"><b>182</b>: via hole</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071"><b>220</b>: polysilicon layer</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072"><b>240</b>: transparent conductive film</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073"><b>250</b>: opaque conductive film</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074"><b>261</b>, <b>262</b>: photoresist film</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">The present invention will be described more fully hereinafter with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which exemplary embodiments of the invention are shown.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">As those skilled in the art will recognize, the described embodiments may be modified in various different ways without departing from the spirit or scope of the present invention. In addition, the size and thickness of each component in the drawings are arbitrarily shown for better understanding and ease of description, and thus the present invention is not limited to those shown in the drawings. In the drawings, the thickness of layers, films, panels, regions, etc., are exaggerated for clarity. It will be understood that when an element such as a layer, film, region, or substrate is referred to as being &#x201c;on&#x201d; another element, it can be directly on the other element, or one or more intervening elements may also be present.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a planar layout view of an array substrate according to a first exemplary embodiment, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the array substrate taken along line II-II of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, the array substrate <b>100</b> according to this exemplary embodiment includes a thin film transistor including an active layer <b>121</b>, a gate electrode, a source electrode <b>172</b>, and a drain electrode <b>173</b>, a storage capacitor including an upper electrode <b>161</b> and a lower electrode (<b>152</b> and <b>153</b>), and a pixel electrode <b>181</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">First, a region where the thin film transistor is formed will be described with reference to the left bottom of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and the left side of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The active layer <b>121</b> may be formed of polysilicon on an insulation substrate <b>110</b>, and may include a source region <b>122</b>, a drain region <b>123</b>, and a lightly doped drain (LDD) region (<b>125</b> and <b>126</b>) that are provided around a channel region <b>124</b> formed at a center thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">A gate insulating film <b>131</b> for insulating the active layer <b>121</b>, and a gate line <b>141</b>, are formed on the active layer <b>121</b>, where the gate line <b>141</b> is formed on the gate insulating film <b>131</b>. A portion of the gate line <b>141</b> corresponding to the channel region <b>124</b> of the active layer <b>121</b> acts as a gate electrode of the thin film transistor, and gate signals are transmitted through the gate line <b>141</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">In this exemplary embodiment, the gate line <b>141</b> may be formed in a double-layered structure including an opaque conductive film <b>142</b> and a transparent conductive film <b>143</b>. In this exemplary embodiment, the opaque conductive film <b>142</b> and the transparent conductive film <b>143</b> have approximately the same side etching surface because the widths thereof are approximately the same, and the opaque conductive film <b>142</b> and the transparent conductive film <b>143</b> may respectively include molybdenum and indium tin oxide (hereinafter referred to as &#x201c;ITO&#x201d;). However, the present invention is not limited thereto, and the opaque conductive film <b>142</b> and the transparent conductive film <b>143</b> may respectively include various low-resistance conductive materials and transparent conductive materials.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">A transparent conductive material such as ITO for forming the transparent conductive film <b>143</b> has relatively high electrical resistance. Thus, in the case that the gate line <b>141</b> is formed only of the transparent conductive film <b>143</b> to obtain an aperture ratio, a problem of signal delay may occur. In this exemplary embodiment, however, the problem of signal delay can be alleviated or avoided since the opaque conductive film <b>142</b> including molybdenum having low electrical resistance and the transparent conductive film <b>143</b> together form the gate line <b>141</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">On the other hand, in the case that the gate line <b>141</b> is formed only of the opaque conductive film <b>142</b> including molybdenum, a high off-leakage current of about 10<sup>&#x2212;7 </sup>A to 10<sup>&#x2212;8 </sup>A is generated. In the case of a high leakage current, crosstalk is generated between adjacent thin film transistors, and as a result, the picture quality may be lowered. However, in this exemplary embodiment, the opaque conductive film <b>142</b> including molybdenum and the transparent conductive film <b>143</b> including ITO together form the gate line <b>141</b>, and this leads to a negative shift in threshold voltage, thereby reducing leakage current to about 10<sup>&#x2212;12 </sup>A. Specifically, the transparent conductive film <b>143</b>, along with the gate insulating film <b>131</b>, serves as a dielectric film because the transparent conductive film <b>143</b> including ITO is formed adjacent to the gate insulating film <b>131</b>. Since the ITO has relatively high electrical resistance, a voltage drop occurs in the ITO, thereby shifting the threshold voltage in a negative direction, which can result in the reduction of the leakage current to about 10<sup>&#x2212;12 </sup>A, and therefore can suppress crosstalk and improve picture quality.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">A first interlayer insulating layer <b>133</b> and a second interlayer insulating layer <b>135</b> are formed on the gate line <b>141</b>, and a data line <b>171</b> for transmitting data signals is formed on the second interlayer insulating layer <b>135</b>. Although in this embodiment the data line <b>171</b> is formed in a laminated structure of titanium-aluminum-titanium, this is only an illustration and the data line may be formed of various different metals. The data line <b>171</b> is connected to a source electrode <b>172</b> at a position corresponding to one side of the active layer <b>121</b>, and a drain electrode <b>173</b> is formed at a position corresponding to the other side of the active layer <b>121</b>, spaced apart from the source electrode <b>172</b>. A first contact hole <b>174</b> and a second contact hole <b>175</b> respectively provide access to the source region <b>122</b> and the drain region <b>123</b> of the active layer <b>121</b>, and are formed in the gate insulating film <b>131</b>, the first interlayer insulating layer <b>133</b>, and the second interlayer insulating layer <b>135</b>, and the source electrode <b>172</b> and the drain electrode <b>173</b> formed on the second interlayer insulating layer <b>135</b> are connected to the source region <b>122</b> and the drain region <b>123</b>, respectively, through these contact holes.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">A driving voltage is applied to the pixel electrode <b>181</b> to be described later by the above configuration of the thin film transistor including the active layer <b>121</b>, the gate line <b>141</b>, the source electrode <b>172</b>, and the drain electrode <b>173</b>. The configuration of the thin film transistor in this exemplary embodiment has been disclosed for illustrative purposes, and it will be apparent to those skilled in the art that various modifications can be made to the structure of the thin film transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">Subsequently, referring to the central portion of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and the right side portion of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a region where the storage capacitor is formed will now be described. A sustain voltage line <b>151</b> is formed on the same layer as the gate line <b>141</b> on the gate insulating film <b>131</b>. The sustain voltage line <b>151</b> forms the opaque lower electrode <b>152</b> at the center of a pixel. In this exemplary embodiment, the transparent lower electrode <b>153</b> is further formed between the gate insulating film <b>131</b> and the sustain voltage line <b>151</b>, and forms the lower electrode of the storage capacitor together with the opaque lower electrode <b>152</b>. In this exemplary embodiment, the sustain voltage line <b>151</b> and the opaque lower electrode <b>152</b> may be formed of the same material as the opaque conductive film <b>142</b>, and the transparent lower electrode <b>153</b> may be formed of the same material as the transparent conductive film <b>143</b>. That is, the sustain voltage line <b>151</b> and the opaque lower electrode <b>152</b> may include molybdenum, and the transparent lower electrode <b>153</b> may include ITO. However, it is understood that the materials described herein are only illustrative, and various other materials can be utilized as will be recognized by a person of ordinary skill in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">In this exemplary embodiment, the transparent lower electrode <b>153</b> is formed wider than the opaque lower electrode <b>152</b>. A voltage is applied to the opaque lower electrode <b>152</b> through the sustain voltage line <b>151</b>. The opaque lower electrode <b>152</b> can prevent or reduce signal delay because it is formed of a low resistance material, but the aperture ratio can also be reduced due to the sustain voltage line <b>151</b> and the opaque lower electrode <b>152</b>. Therefore, if the opaque lower electrode <b>152</b> is made small and the transparent lower electrode <b>153</b> is made relatively larger, the storage capacitor can ensure sufficient capacitance and the aperture ratio can be improved.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">An upper electrode <b>161</b> is formed on the opaque lower electrode <b>152</b> and the transparent lower electrode <b>153</b>, with a first interlayer insulating layer <b>133</b> interposed therebetween. The upper electrode <b>161</b> constitutes the storage capacitor together with the lower electrode including the opaque lower electrode <b>152</b> and the transparent lower electrode <b>153</b>. At this time, the first interlayer insulating layer <b>133</b> serves as a dielectric film. In this exemplary embodiment, the upper electrode <b>161</b> may be formed of ITO, which is a transparent conductive material, in order to improve the aperture ratio by the upper electrode <b>161</b>. The upper electrode <b>161</b> is covered with the second interlayer insulating layer <b>135</b>, and is connected to the drain electrode <b>173</b> through a third contact hole <b>176</b> formed in the second interlayer insulating layer <b>135</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">A voltage signal to be applied to the pixel electrode <b>181</b> to be described later can be sustained by the configuration of the storage capacitor including the opaque lower electrode <b>152</b>, the transparent lower electrode <b>153</b>, the upper electrode <b>161</b>, and the first interlayer insulating layer <b>133</b> serving as the dielectric film.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">A protective film <b>137</b> is formed on the thin film transistor and storage capacitor described hereinabove, and an organic film <b>139</b> is further formed on the protective film <b>137</b>. A via hole <b>182</b> providing access to the drain electrode <b>173</b> is formed in the protective film <b>137</b> and the organic film <b>139</b>, and the pixel electrode <b>181</b> formed on the organic film <b>139</b> is connected to the drain electrode <b>173</b> through the via hole <b>182</b>. With this configuration, the pixel electrode <b>181</b> can receive a driving voltage, and an electric field is applied between the pixel electrode <b>181</b> and a common electrode facing the pixel electrode <b>181</b>, whereby, for example, liquid crystal or an organic emission layer interposed between the pixel electrode <b>181</b> and the common electrode can be driven to display an image.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">Meanwhile, in this exemplary embodiment, the via hole <b>182</b> and the third contact hole <b>176</b> are formed at a position corresponding to (e.g., substantially aligned with) the opaque lower electrode <b>152</b>. With this configuration, a reduction in aperture ratio by the via hole <b>182</b> and the third contact hole <b>176</b> can be effectively suppressed. However, the present invention is not limited to this configuration, but the positions of the via hole <b>182</b> and the third contact hole <b>176</b> can be variously changed according to process conditions, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">As such, the array substrate <b>100</b> according to this exemplary embodiment can improve the aperture ratio and suppress or reduce picture quality degradation or inaccuracies caused by signal delay and the generation of leakage current, by utilizing the gate line <b>141</b> having a double layer including the opaque conductive film <b>142</b> and the transparent conductive film <b>143</b> and utilizing a lower electrode of the storage capacitor having a double layer including the opaque lower electrode <b>152</b> and the transparent lower electrode <b>153</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">Other exemplary embodiments will be described below. In the following description, components that are same or similar as, or equivalent to those in the first exemplary embodiment are described only briefly, or a description thereof may be omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a cross-sectional view of an array substrate according to a second exemplary embodiment. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the array substrate <b>101</b> according to this exemplary embodiment includes a thin film transistor, a storage capacitor, and a pixel electrode <b>181</b>, and the thin film transistor and the pixel electrode <b>181</b> are configured in the same or similar manner as in the first exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">The storage capacitor in this exemplary embodiment includes a lower electrode including an opaque lower electrode <b>152</b> and a transparent lower electrode <b>153</b>&#x2032;, an upper electrode <b>161</b>&#x2032;, and a first interlayer insulating layer <b>133</b> interposed therebetween and serving as a dielectric film. In this exemplary embodiment, the size of the transparent lower electrode <b>153</b>&#x2032; may be relatively greater than the size of the upper electrode <b>161</b>&#x2032;. That is, the size of the transparent lower electrode <b>153</b>&#x2032; may be greater compared to the size of the transparent electrode <b>153</b> in first exemplary embodiment. With this configuration, a storage capacitance with the upper electrode <b>161</b>&#x2032; can be further increased. Accordingly, the aperture ratio can be improved, and the performance of the storage capacitor can be improved.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">Moreover, in this exemplary embodiment, only an organic film <b>139</b>&#x2032; is formed on the thin film transistor and the storage capacitor, and no separate protective film is formed. Since the formation of a protective film may cause a reduction in aperture ratio, this exemplary embodiment can contribute to improvement of the aperture ratio by omitting the protective film.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a planar layout view of an array substrate according to a third exemplary embodiment. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the array substrate <b>102</b> according to this exemplary embodiment includes a thin film transistor, a storage capacitor, and a pixel electrode <b>181</b>, and the storage capacitor and the pixel electrode <b>181</b> are configured in the same or similar manner as in the first exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">In this exemplary embodiment, the thin film transistor includes an active layer <b>121</b>&#x2032;, a gate line <b>141</b>&#x2032;, a source electrode <b>172</b>&#x2032; connected to a data line <b>171</b>, and a drain electrode <b>173</b>&#x2032; spaced apart therefrom. Moreover, a gate insulating film is formed between the active layer <b>121</b>&#x2032; and the gate line <b>141</b>&#x2032;, a first interlayer insulating layer and a second interlayer insulating layer are formed between the gate line <b>141</b>&#x2032; and the source electrode <b>172</b>&#x2032; and drain electrode <b>173</b>&#x2032;, and a first contact hole <b>174</b>&#x2032; and a second contact hole <b>175</b>&#x2032; are formed on the gate insulating film, the first interlayer insulating layer, and the second interlayer insulating layer. The source electrode <b>172</b>&#x2032; and the drain electrode <b>173</b>&#x2032; are respectively connected to the source region and drain region of the active layer <b>121</b>&#x2032; through the first and second contact holes <b>174</b>&#x2032; and <b>175</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">The drain electrode <b>173</b>&#x2032; of this exemplary embodiment is formed shorter compared to the drain electrode <b>173</b> of the first exemplary embodiment. Accordingly, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the thin film transistor has such a configuration in which it is shifted towards the center of the pixel. The drain electrode is generally made of a metal, and as such, may cause the aperture ratio to be lowered. In this exemplary embodiment, the overall aperture ratio of the pixel can be improved by minimizing or reducing the reduction in aperture ratio caused by the drain electrode <b>173</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A to 5D</figref> are views sequentially showing a fabrication process of an array substrate according to one exemplary embodiment. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A to 5D</figref>, a method of fabricating an array substrate according to one exemplary embodiment will now be described.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>, a polysilicon layer <b>220</b> is laminated on an insulation substrate <b>210</b>, and then an active layer <b>221</b> is formed by a first mask process. Thereafter, a gate insulating film <b>230</b>, a transparent conductive film <b>240</b>, and an opaque conductive film <b>250</b> are sequentially laminated, a photoresist layer is formed, and then a first photoresist film <b>261</b> and a second photoresist film <b>262</b> are formed from the photoresist layer by a second mask process. In the second mask process for forming the photoresist films <b>261</b> and <b>262</b>, the second photoresist film <b>262</b> is formed to have a wider bottom than top by using a half-tone mask. In this exemplary embodiment, the transparent conductive film <b>240</b> and the opaque conductive film <b>250</b> include ITO and molybdenum, respectively. However, these materials are only illustrative, and the materials of the transparent conductive film <b>240</b> and opaque conductive film <b>250</b> are not limited thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>, a first etching process is performed on the opaque conductive film <b>250</b>, and thereafter a second etching process is performed on the transparent conductive film <b>240</b>. Here, the first etching process is a dry etching process using, for example, a gas plasma reaction, whereby an opaque conductive film <b>251</b> and an opaque lower electrode <b>252</b> respectively having substantially the same widths as the first photoresist film <b>261</b> and the second photoresist film <b>262</b> are formed under the first photoresist film <b>261</b> and the second photoresist film <b>262</b>. The second etching process may be a wet etching process using, for example, an etchant that is able to etch a particular material, whereby a transparent conductive film <b>241</b> and a transparent lower electrode <b>242</b> respectively having smaller widths than those of the opaque conductive film <b>251</b> and the opaque lower electrode <b>252</b> are formed under the opaque conductive film <b>251</b> and the opaque lower electrode <b>252</b>. In the second etching process, cross-sectional etching may also be performed. In the second etching process, fine etching of about 0.2 &#x3bc;m may be performed in a cross-sectional direction.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">Alternatively, the first etching process may be carried out as a wet etching process. In the case where the first etching process is performed as a wet etching process, the opaque conductive film <b>251</b> and the opaque lower electrode <b>252</b> are configured to be finely etched in the cross-sectional direction under the first photoresist film <b>261</b> and the second photoresist film <b>262</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</figref>, a source region <b>222</b> and a drain region <b>223</b> are formed by doping the active layer <b>221</b> with a P+ impurity such as boron on the top of the insulation substrate <b>210</b>. Thereafter, the bottom of the second photoresist film <b>262</b> is removed by an ashing process to expose the opaque lower electrode <b>252</b> under the second photoresist film <b>262</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5D</figref>, a third etching process is performed on the material of the opaque conductive film in order to reduce the width of the opaque lower electrode <b>252</b>. The third etching process may be carried out as a wet etching process, whereby the opaque conductive film <b>251</b> and the opaque lower electrode <b>252</b> may be etched to have smaller widths than the widths of the first photoresist film <b>261</b> and the second photoresist film <b>262</b>, respectively. As a result of this, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5D</figref>, the opaque conductive film <b>251</b> can have approximately the same width as the opaque conductive film <b>241</b>, and the opaque lower electrode <b>252</b> can have a smaller width than the width of the transparent lower electrode <b>242</b>, thereby improving the aperture ratio of the pixel.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">Subsequent to the third etching process, a P&#x2212; impurity is lightly doped on the top of the insulation substrate <b>210</b> to form a lightly doped drain region (<b>225</b> and <b>226</b>), and accordingly a channel region <b>224</b> is formed at the center of the active layer <b>221</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">As such, after forming a gate electrode of a thin film transistor including the opaque conductive film <b>251</b> and transparent conductive film <b>241</b>, the active layer <b>221</b> of the thin film transistor, and a lower electrode of a storage capacitor including the opaque lower electrode <b>252</b> and the transparent lower electrode <b>242</b>, the remaining components may be formed according to a general process. That is, the thin film transistor and the storage capacitor are formed by sequentially forming a first interlayer insulating layer, an upper electrode of the storage capacitor, a second interlayer insulating layer, first to third contact holes, and a source electrode and drain electrode, and a protective film and an organic film are laminated so as to cover the thin film transistor and the storage capacitor. A via hole is formed in the protective film and the organic film, and then a pixel electrode is formed on the top thereof, thereby completing an array substrate. As described above, the protective film may be omitted in order to improve the aperture ratio.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">By the process described hereinabove, a gate line and the gate electrode can be formed to have a double layer including the opaque conductive film <b>251</b> and the transparent conductive film <b>241</b>, and the lower electrode of the storage capacitor can also be formed to have a double layer including the opaque lower electrode <b>252</b> and the transparent lower electrode <b>242</b>. Therefore, signal delay can be suppressed or reduced, the aperture ratio can be improved, and the picture quality can be enhanced by reducing leakage current. Moreover, according to the above process, no additional mask is required to form the opaque conductive film <b>251</b>, the transparent conductive film <b>241</b>, the opaque lower electrode <b>252</b>, and the transparent lower electrode <b>242</b>. Thus, no mask process is added, thus simplifying the process.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">While this disclosure has been described in connection with what is presently considered to be practical exemplary embodiments, it is to be understood that the invention is not limited to the disclosed embodiments. The scope of the present invention is determined by the claims that follow. Those skilled in the art will recognize that various modifications and changes can be made without departing from the spirit and scope of the claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An array substrate comprising:
<claim-text>an active layer comprising a channel region;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a gate electrode positioned corresponding to the channel region; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a gate insulating film between the active layer and the gate electrode,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the gate electrode comprises a transparent conductive film and an opaque conductive film, and the transparent conductive film is between the channel region and the opaque conductive film; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a capacitor comprising:
<claim-text>a transparent lower electrode;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an opaque lower electrode directly contacting the transparent lower electrode;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first insulating film on the transparent lower electrode and utilized as a dielectric film; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an upper electrode on the first insulating film.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The array substrate of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the transparent conductive film and the opaque conductive film are in direct contact with each other.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The array substrate of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the transparent conductive film comprises indium tin oxide (ITO), and the opaque conductive film comprises molybdenum.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The array substrate of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the active layer comprises polysilicon, the active layer further comprising a source region on one side of the channel region and a drain region on an opposite side of the channel region, wherein the channel region comprises N-type impurities, and the source region and the drain region comprise P-type impurities.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The array substrate of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the upper electrode is positioned on the first insulating film corresponding to the transparent lower electrode.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The array substrate of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the transparent lower electrode and the opaque lower electrode are comprised of the same materials as the transparent conductive film and the opaque conductive film, respectively.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The array substrate of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the transparent lower electrode and the opaque lower electrode are arranged on the same layer as the transparent conductive film and the opaque conductive film, respectively.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The array substrate of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the upper electrode comprises a transparent conductive material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The array substrate of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a width of the transparent lower electrode is greater than a width of the upper electrode.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The array substrate of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a second insulating layer on the first insulating film,
<claim-text>wherein the first insulating film is on the gate electrode, the active layer, and the gate insulating film, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the upper electrode is between the first insulating film and the second insulating layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The array substrate of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a source electrode connected to the source region through a first hole in the first insulating film and the second insulating layer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a drain electrode connected to the drain region through a second hole in the first insulating film and the second insulating layer, and connected to the upper electrode through a third hole in the second insulating layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The array substrate of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the third hole is positioned corresponding to the opaque lower electrode, with the first insulating film and the upper electrode interposed therebetween.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The array substrate of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further comprising an organic film on the second insulating layer, the source electrode, and the drain electrode.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The array substrate of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further comprising a protective film separating the second insulating layer and source and drain electrodes from the organic film.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The array substrate of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further comprising a pixel electrode connected to the drain electrode through a fourth hole in the organic film.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The array substrate of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the fourth hole is positioned corresponding to the opaque lower electrode, with the first insulating film, the upper electrode, and the drain electrode interposed therebetween.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The array substrate of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the transparent conductive film and the opaque conductive film have substantially a same width. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
