<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622014-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622014</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13145818</doc-number>
<date>20090122</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>71</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>63</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>8</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>114312</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Cable connection system for underwater vehicle</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3955522</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Gaudiano et al.</name>
<date>19760500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>114259</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5291194</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Ames</name>
<date>19940300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>340850</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5349916</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hillenbrand et al.</name>
<date>19940900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5748102</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Barron</name>
<date>19980500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6600695</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Nugent et al.</name>
<date>20030700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>367131</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6928947</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Clapham</name>
<date>20050800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>114312</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7992682</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Ziaylek</name>
<date>20110800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>182127</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00008">
<othercit>PCT/ISA/210&#x2014;International Search Report&#x2014;December 9, 2009.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00009">
<othercit>PCT/ISA/237&#x2014;Written Opinion of the International Searching Authority&#x2014;December 9, 2009.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00010">
<othercit>PCT/IPEA/409&#x2014;International Preliminary Report on Patentability&#x2014;April 5, 2011.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>19</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>114312</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>12</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>13</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120006245</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120112</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lundberg</last-name>
<first-name>Lars</first-name>
<address>
<city>Motala</city>
<country>SE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>SE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lundberg</last-name>
<first-name>Lars</first-name>
<address>
<city>Motala</city>
<country>SE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Venable LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Franklin</last-name>
<first-name>Eric J.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>SAAB AB</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Link&#xf6;ping</city>
<country>SE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Avila</last-name>
<first-name>Stephen</first-name>
<department>3617</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/EP2009/050721</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20090122</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20110929</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2010/083885</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20100729</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A system for interconnecting a mother ship with a submersible vehicle using a cable towed by the mother ship. The cable has a first cable end connected to the mother ship and a second cable end to be connected to the submersible vehicle. The second cable end is provided with a first connector. A capturing mast is arranged at the submersible vehicle for capturing the cable towed by the mother ship. A connector holder is arranged at the submersible vehicle for holding the first connector when it is to be connected to a second connector. The second connector is connected to the submersible vehicle. A first guide is arranged at the submersible vehicle for guiding the first connector towards the connector holder of the submersible vehicle. A second guide turns the connector to a well defined position into the connector holder.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="128.61mm" wi="245.45mm" file="US08622014-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="246.80mm" wi="153.67mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622014-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="245.45mm" wi="152.99mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622014-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="199.22mm" wi="173.40mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622014-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="218.95mm" wi="141.39mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622014-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="242.65mm" wi="157.65mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622014-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="154.86mm" wi="160.02mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622014-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="147.83mm" wi="148.08mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622014-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="227.75mm" wi="159.77mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622014-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="247.40mm" wi="148.17mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622014-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="244.77mm" wi="113.54mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622014-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="203.96mm" wi="146.13mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622014-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="230.04mm" wi="171.62mm" file="US08622014-20140107-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is the national phase under 35 U.S.C. &#xa7;371 of PCT/EP2009/050721 filed 22 Jan. 2009.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a system for interconnecting a mother ship with a submersible vehicle, using a cable towed by the mother ship, the cable having a first cable end connected to the mother ship, and a second cable end to be connected to the submersible vehicle.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">U.S. Pat. No. 5,748,102 disclose an apparatus for interconnecting an unmanned underwater vehicle and a free floating communications pod.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The inventors have realised that thee is a need within the field of submersible vehicles, in particular autonomous underwater vehicles (AUVs) and unmanned underwater vehicles (UUVs), and even unmanned surface vehicle (USV), to be able to be recharged without having to take them ashore, or aboard or alongside a mother ship to connect manually to a power cable or the like. There is also a need to be able to upload data via high speed data link, e.g. via an optical fibre connection, to said submersible vehicle. In addition, sometimes there is an need to operate an AUV in a more conventional way, that is, operation by having real time communication with, and by having power supplied by, a surface mother ship.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Therefore, it is an object of the present invention to provide a system for enabling an underwater vehicle to capture a cable towed by a mother ship, to find a first connector at an end of said cable, and to connect said connector to a second connector being part of said underwater vehicle. When the cable is connected, this enables for example for the transmission of electrical power to recharge batteries of the unmanned underwater vehicle. In one embodiment the first connector has an oval cross section. In another embodiment the connector has a circular cross section. The UUV is provided with a capturing mast, preferably arranged to be moveable, even more preferred it is arranged to be foldable, and being arranged to capture the cable during a manoeuvre wherein the UUV is travelling largely transversally to the lengthwise direction of the cable. The capturing mast is preferably arranged to fold due to the cable pulling forces and the driving force of the swimming UUV. Alternatively, a force transducer can be arranged to sense a pulling force affecting the capturing mast, and a motor or servo arrangement can be arranged to fold the capturing mast when the sensed pulling force exceeds a certain value. When a foldable capturing mast folds from an upright position to a folded position the cable follows and comes closer to an upper surface of the UUV. The cable also comes closer to a first guiding frame of a particular shape. As the cable runs in the first guiding frame, eventually the cable end together with the connector will be guided down to a connector cradle having guiding structures wherein the connector, due to the oval shape, turns into a predetermined position to enable the second connector to be linearly moved by the help of an actuator, and establish electrical contact by connecting the second connector with the first connector.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Thus, according to a first aspect there is provided a submersible vehicle having means for connecting to a cable in water having a first cable end with a first connector to be connected to the submersible vehicle, the submersible vehicle comprises:</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">a capturing mast;</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">a first guiding means;</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">a connector holder;</p>
<p id="h-0005" num="0000">wherein the capturing mast is adapted to capture the cable and guide the cable towards the first guiding means;</p>
<p id="h-0006" num="0000">the first guiding means is adapted to guide the first connector towards the connector holder;</p>
<p id="h-0007" num="0000">the connector holder is adapted to hold the first connector when it is to be connected to a second connector.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The submersible vehicle may further comprise:</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">second guiding means for turning the connector to a predefined position into the connector holder.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The capturing mast is preferably moveable, and even foldable.</p>
<p id="h-0008" num="0000">The first guiding means is a preferably a guiding frame. The second guiding means is preferably a guiding frame.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The submersible vehicle further comprises an actuator arranged at the submersible vehicle for moving the second connector, towards the first connector to establish connection between the mother ship and the submersible vehicle.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The actuator is preferably a linear actuator arranged at the submersible vehicle for linearly moving the second connector, towards the first connector to establish connection between the mother ship and the submersible vehicle.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The capturing mast is preferably arranged at a distance from the longitudinal midline of the submersible vehicle and at a front half portion of the submersible vehicle.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The first guiding means is arranged near a horizontal midline and at a rear half portion of the submersible vehicle.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The submersible vehicle has an upper side mainly free of protruding objects except for the capturing mast and the guiding means.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The first guiding means comprises a first and a second member, the first member is arranged to guide the cable downwards and sideways towards the second guiding frame, and the second member is arranged to guide the cable mainly in sideways direction towards the second guiding frame.</p>
<p id="h-0009" num="0000">The submersible vehicle may be provided with a hook organ arranged at a top portion of the capturing mast.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The hook organ may be partly ring shaped for surrounding the cable, and has an opening for letting the cable into space defined by the hook organ, as an alternative, the hook organ is a principally a straight member arranged with an angle towards a main portion of the mast.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">According to a second aspect there is provided a system for interconnecting a mother ship with a submersible vehicle, using a cable towed by the mother ship, the cable having a first cable end connected to the mother ship, and a second cable end to be connected to the submersible vehicle, the second cable end being provided with a first connector, the system comprising:</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">a capturing mast arranged at the submersible vehicle for capturing the cable towed by the mother ship;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">a connector holder being arranged at the submersible vehicle for holding the first connector when it is to be connected to a second connector, the second connector being connected to the submersible vehicle;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">first guiding means being arranged at the submersible vehicle for guiding the first connector towards the connector holder of the submersible vehicle;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">second guiding means for turning the connector to a predefined position into the connector holder.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">According to a third aspect there is provided a method for connecting a towed cable to a submersible vehicle, the cable having a second cable end connectable to an entity, and a first cable end to be connected to the submersible vehicle, the first cable end being provided with a first connector, the method comprising the following steps:</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">capturing the cable with the aid of a capturing mast arranged at the submersible vehicle;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">guiding the cable towards first guiding means with the aid of the capturing mast</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">guiding the first connector towards a connector holder of the submersible vehicle with the aid of first guiding means;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">holding the first connector with the aid of the connector holder which holder is adapted to hold the connector firmly in the predefined position where it can be connected to a second connector, the second connector being connected to the submersible vehicle;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">moving the second connector towards the first connector.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The method may further comprise the step of:</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">turning the connector to a predefined position into the connector holder.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Described embodiments discloses features that enable handling of rotationally dependent connectors, i.e., connectors that must be rotated into a particular position to be able to connect, just like many normal domestic connectors. If so rotationally independent connectors, i.e., connectors which do not need to be in a certain rotational position to enable connection, were used, the design of the embodiments could of course be simplified. On the market today there is a wider supply of rotationally dependent connectors having a wide range of specifications concerning maximum current, water resistance etc., and therefore it is desirable to not having to be forced to use rotationally independent connectors.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">It should be emphasized that the term &#x201c;comprises/comprising&#x201d; when used in this specification is taken to specify the presence of stated features, integers, steps or components but does not preclude the presence or addition of one or more other features, elements, integers, steps, components or groups thereof.</p>
<p id="h-0010" num="0000">Features that are described and/or illustrated with respect to one embodiment may be used in the same way or in a similar way in one or more other embodiments and/or in combination with or instead of the features of the other embodiments.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0011" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Preferred embodiments will be explained below with the aid of enclosed drawings, of which</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a side view of an UUV with means of a first embodiment for capturing a towed cable and connecting to a connector at an end of said cable;</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>a </i>shows a view from above of the UUV of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>b </i>shows an aft view of the UUV of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref></p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>c </i>shows an enlarged side view of the aft half portion of the UUV of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref></p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</figref><i>d</i>-<i>f </i>shows detailed views of the UUV at a certain moments of cable docking</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a side view of an UUV with means according to a second embodiment, for capturing a towed cable and connecting to a connector at an end of said cable;</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a view from above of the UUV of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows a detailed view of a second embodiment of a capturing mast having captured a cylindrical connector;</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows an even more detailed view of the cylindrical connector of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref></p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>a </i>shows a detailed view of the linear actuator and a connector of oval cross section;</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref><i>b </i>shows a detailed view of a cam arrangement for turning the connector of the UUV into a position determined by a guiding pin of the connector of the cable.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0012" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a side view of an UUV <b>110</b> with means for capturing a towed cable and connecting to a connector at an end of said cable. A foldable capturing mast <b>105</b> is arranged at a side of the UUV <b>110</b>, and is foldable around a pivoting point <b>107</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The foldable capturing mast <b>105</b> can be raised to an upright position as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, and can be folded by a folding angle <b>115</b> to a folded position as is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The folding angle is arranged to be around 75 to 90 degrees. More preferred is around 90 degrees. The capturing mast comprises a main portion <b>101</b> and a hook portion <b>102</b>, <b>103</b>, <b>104</b>, <b>106</b>. When there is captured a cable, the foldable capturing mast folds and cable pulling forces and a mid section of the hook portion arranged with a hook angle <b>140</b> in relation to the main portion <b>101</b>, forces the cable to travel towards a hook bend <b>102</b> of the foldable capturing mast. The cable <b>211</b>, <b>212</b> now can be said to comprise two sections, a first section <b>211</b> extending from the mother ship to the hook bend <b>102</b> of the foldable capturing mast <b>105</b>, and a second section <b>212</b> extending from the hook bend <b>102</b> of the foldable capturing mast <b>105</b> to the cable end with the connector <b>220</b>. Due to the movement of the UUV <b>110</b> and of the mother ship, and according to hydrodynamics, there are forces pulling the cable section <b>211</b>, <b>210</b> obliquely backwards in relation to UUV travelling direction <b>150</b>. When a cable angle A between the first section <b>211</b>, and the second section <b>212</b> becomes such that the cable <b>211</b> approaches (from the upper regions of the figure) a first guiding frame <b>120</b> and a second guiding frame <b>125</b>. The first guiding frame <b>120</b> is designed as a flat arch <b>120</b> having a first and a second end, the first end being fastened to the UUV upper surface at a first point, and the second end of the first guiding frame is fastened to the UUV upper surface at a second point, farther aft than the first point, and in close proximity to the cradle, in order to let the cable slip towards the cradle. The first point of guiding frame <b>120</b> is preferably identical to a foremost point of same first guiding frame <b>120</b>. The foremost point of guiding frame <b>120</b> should preferably be arranged fore of second guiding frame <b>125</b>, and in height it should preferably be positioned at least half height of least diameter (width) of connector <b>220</b>. In shown case approximately 60 millimeters and increasing as further aft and further away from the upper hull surface one gets. This will prevent the connector <b>220</b> from jumping over the first guiding frame <b>120</b> and escape in the direction of arrow <b>215</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The second guiding frame <b>125</b> is a tall arch with a first leg ascending to an apex, and a second leg descending from the apex to a first bend approximately at half of the height of the second guiding frame, and a third leg extending from the first bend approximately horizontally aftwards to a second bend and a third leg then bending downwards and there meeting and being attached to the cradle.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">With this design, as the UUV moves forward, the first section <b>211</b> of the cable <b>211</b>, <b>212</b>, becomes guided towards the cradle and escapes at an open farther end of the cradle. At a point in time when the second section <b>212</b> of the cable <b>211</b>, <b>212</b> become smaller and smaller it eventually flips around the foldable capturing mast <b>105</b> together with the connector <b>220</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The purpose of the second guiding frame <b>125</b> is to, when mast <b>105</b> is folded; the cable <b>211</b> shall be guided between the first guiding frame <b>120</b> and the second guiding frame <b>125</b>. If h<b>2</b> is made to small or UUV is travelling at a too high speed, the cable may end up above the second guiding frame <b>125</b> and the connector <b>220</b> will continue in the direction of the arrow <b>215</b>. As mentioned above, the dimensioning is a trade-off between permanent hydrodynamic resistance and the probability of successfully catching the cable and its connector at increasing speeds. A foot portion of the second guiding frame <b>125</b> that is joining the hull is preferably arranged as far aft as allowed by structural strength and geometry of UUV. This is to prevent the foot portion from disturbing the cable <b>211</b> and the connector <b>220</b> when it is to be catched by the guiding frames <b>120</b>, <b>125</b>. The angle marked C of the second guiding frame <b>125</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>c </i>is preferably as small as possible to prevent the cable from getting stuck on the second guiding frame and instead is forced in between second guiding frame <b>125</b> and first guiding frame <b>120</b>. However, an uppermost point of the second guiding frame <b>125</b> must not be arranged too much forward since it then is necessary to arrange pivoting point <b>107</b> more forward, or make main portion <b>101</b> shorter.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The second section of the cable is thus guided through the cradle and when the connector is to pass the cradle it gets catched there because the cradle cross section is wider than the cable but smaller than the connector, and therefore lets the cable <b>211</b>, <b>212</b> pass but not the connector <b>220</b>. The connector in the catched position in the cradle is given reference number <b>130</b>, for illustrative purposes. Subsequently, the catching of the connector <b>130</b>, <b>220</b> is detected with suitable means, and the actuator is activated to press connectors together as mentioned above.</p>
<p id="h-0013" num="0000">Considerations on Precise Position of Pivoting Point of Capturing Mast</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The pivoting point <b>107</b> is arranged below an upper hull surface of the UUV. It is arranged lengthwise such that, when mast is folded, depending on the length of a main portion <b>101</b> of mast <b>105</b>, the hook portion <b>102</b>, <b>103</b>, <b>104</b>, <b>106</b>, lands in a position such that the cable guided by the hook has a good chance of becoming captured and guided by the guiding frame <b>125</b>. The longer the main portion of the mast, the longer forward on the UUV the pivoting point <b>107</b> should be arranged. It is also so that it is desired to have as low height of the guiding frame <b>125</b>, i.e., the measure h<b>2</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>b </i>should be low in order to keep hydrodynamic drag low. This is also true for the hook, i.e. the measure h<b>1</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>b</i>. The height is preferably such that the connector <b>130</b>, <b>220</b> is able to pass without getting jammed, and additionally the angle <b>140</b> of a first hook bend <b>102</b> is less than 90 degrees which entails that the mast in a folded position forces the cable towards the upper surface of the UUV hull.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Many parameters influence optimal position of pivoting point <b>107</b>, length of the mast <b>105</b>, and distance sideways between mast <b>105</b>/hook <b>103</b> and guiding frames <b>120</b>, <b>125</b>. Among these parameters are velocity of UUV, and length of cable laid out from mother ship. An arrangement of cable catching elements based on said position of pivoting point, length of mast and sideways distance are restricted by the size of the UUV. It is undesirable to have an arrangement extending outside the length and width of UUV, and it should not extend too much in height in order to reduce hydrodynamic resistance when UUV is not catching cable. Disclosed embodiments have been tested in velocities of 1 to 3 knots with good results using laid out cable lengths of 50 meters and more. It is expected that during regular operation cable lengths of 300 to 800 meters will be used. It is advantageous to have connector <b>130</b> attached at an aft or aftmost position, because this will apply the cable drag force to the UUV straight backwards. Since these forces may be in the order of 300 kilograms, it would be difficult to manoeuvre the UUV if the force were applied at another position.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The guiding frames <b>120</b>, <b>125</b> may preferably be of bent pipes, thereby reducing drag. The material could preferably be stainless steel, or of other sea-water resistant and strong material.</p>
<p id="h-0014" num="0000">Rotating Means of First Embodiment</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The submersible vehicle <b>110</b> may further comprise rotating guiding means <b>711</b>-<b>713</b> at linear actuator <b>750</b> for rotating second connector <b>740</b> into position to be connected to first connector <b>130</b>, see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7</figref><i>a</i>, and <b>7</b><i>b</i>. Suitable detection means <b>770</b> may be arranged to sense or detect that the connector <b>130</b> is safely in place in the cradle <b>440</b> in order to be connected. A pin or other mechanical protruding part <b>713</b> is arranged at the first connector <b>130</b> to cooperate with a first cam edge <b>711</b> or a second cam edge <b>712</b> attached to the second connector <b>740</b>, such that corresponding contacts of the connectors' ends up straight in front of each other.</p>
<heading id="h-0015" level="1">Second Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a side view of an UUV <b>110</b> with means according to a second embodiment for capturing a towed cable and connecting to a connector at an end of said cable. A foldable capturing mast <b>305</b> is arranged to extend from a top surface of the UUV <b>110</b>, and is foldable around a pivoting point <b>307</b> (not shown). The pivoting point <b>307</b> of capturing mast <b>305</b> is preferably arranged at a front third portion of the UUV to allow for portions <b>301</b> and <b>302</b> to show sufficient length. The length of portion <b>302</b> is longer than the connector <b>420</b>, preferably at least 50 millimeters longer. The pivoting point is preferably arranged in a central third portion regarding its position in a port-starboard direction.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The foldable capturing mast <b>305</b> can be raised to an upright position as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, and can be folded by a folding angle <b>315</b> to a folded position as is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. The folding angle is arranged to be around 90 degrees. Folding is arranged to occur when cable forces together with hydrodynamic forces exceeds a certain value, which value could be predetermined or made dependent on UUV speed. The capturing mast comprises a main portion <b>301</b> and a hook portion <b>302</b> including a hook organ <b>303</b>. When there is captured a cable, the foldable capturing mast folds and cable pulling forces, forces the cable to travel towards the hook organ <b>303</b> of the foldable capturing mast <b>305</b>. The cable <b>411</b>, <b>412</b> now can be said to comprise two sections, a first section <b>411</b> extending from the mother ship to the hook organ <b>303</b> of the foldable capturing mast <b>305</b>, and a second section <b>412</b> extending from the hook organ <b>303</b> of the foldable capturing mast <b>305</b> to the cable end with a connector <b>420</b>. Due to the movement of the UUV <b>110</b> and of the mother ship, and according to hydrodynamics, there are forces pulling the cable section <b>411</b>, <b>412</b> obliquely backwards in relation to UUV travelling direction <b>350</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0016" num="0000">Flipping of Connector</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The second cable section <b>412</b> becomes smaller and smaller as the cable slides through the hook organ <b>303</b>, and eventually it comes to the cable end and the connector <b>420</b> flips around and gets catched in the hook organ <b>303</b>. The detailed design of the hook organ <b>303</b> and the connector <b>420</b> and how they cooperate will be explained further with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. The hook organ <b>303</b> is preferably shaped as a non-closed ring <b>303</b>. The ring <b>303</b> has a predetermined inner diameter which is adapted to an outer diameter of a tubular casing <b>510</b> of the connector <b>420</b> in that a tubular casing <b>510</b> of the connector <b>420</b> narrowly passes through the hook organ <b>303</b> but gets hung up by a spring ring <b>515</b>. The tubular casing <b>510</b> is provided with a helical groove <b>505</b>. There is provided, at ring <b>303</b>, an abutment <b>530</b> that prevents the tubular casing <b>510</b> from rotating and also from translational movement. The connector body <b>511</b> is provided with a pin <b>610</b> that fits movably in the helical groove <b>505</b>. The pin <b>610</b> of the connector body and the helical groove <b>505</b> of the tubular casing is arranged to cooperate in that the pin <b>610</b> of the connector body <b>511</b> of connector <b>420</b> is guided by the helical grove of the tubular casing <b>510</b> such that the connector body <b>511</b> begins to turn when the cable section <b>411</b> pulls the connector <b>420</b> and continues to turn until a keel <b>520</b> of the connector body <b>511</b> makes contact with rod portion <b>540</b> of hook portion <b>302</b> of the mast. The connector body <b>511</b>, which encompasses the electrical contacts, in this way becomes in a predefined rotational position, when the keel <b>520</b> faces downwards.</p>
<p id="h-0017" num="0000">Bringing Connector to Connecting Position</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The spring ring <b>515</b> of the tubular casing <b>510</b> is devised to give at a predetermined, higher amount of force, and the connector <b>420</b> can continue further, guided by a rail <b>430</b> for the keel <b>520</b>, down to a connecting position, i.e. to the cradle <b>440</b>, where the UUV connector is to be connected with the aid of a linear actuator. The rail <b>430</b> and the keel <b>520</b> are devised such that when the keel has entered the rail, it will not come into a lock before it has moved into the connecting position, i.e. into the cradle <b>440</b>. The keel <b>520</b> is provided with a derailing guard <b>521</b> for preventing the keel <b>520</b> from undesirably leaving the rail <b>430</b> during the connector's travel to the cradle <b>440</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Thus, when the connector is catched in the hook organ <b>303</b>, this is sensed by first suitable detection means and the hook portion <b>302</b> is extended towards the cradle <b>440</b>. There are arranged rails <b>430</b> for guiding the hook portion with the connector <b>420</b> towards the cradle <b>440</b>. When the connector is safely in place in the cradle this is detected with second suitable detection means, and an actuator is activated to press connectors together in the same way as mentioned above, establishing an electrical connection between the UUV <b>110</b> and the mother ship.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The connector <b>420</b> is preferably provided with a spring ring <b>515</b> for re-turning the tubular casing <b>510</b> to it original position where it will be ready to repeat its task at a new connection operation.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A submersible vehicle, comprising:
<claim-text>a connector configured to connect the submersible vehicle to a cable in water, the connector comprising a first free cable end including a first connector arranged at the free cable end and facing away from the cable;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an upright arm comprising a hook portion arranged at an end of the upright arm distal to the submersible vehicle, wherein the upright arm is foldable from an upright position extending away from a surface of the submersible vehicle to a folded position substantially parallel to the surface of the submersible vehicle;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first guide, wherein the upright arm is adapted to capture the cable and guide the cable towards the first guide; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a connector holder configured to hold the first connector in a position to be connected to a second connector, wherein the first guide is adapted to guide the first connector towards the connector holder.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The submersible vehicle according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a second guide configured to turn the connector to a predefined position into the connector holder.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The submersible vehicle according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the upright arm is moveable.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The submersible vehicle according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first guide comprises a guiding frame comprising a first guiding frame designed as a flat arch, and a second guiding frame designed as a tall arch.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The submersible vehicle according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the second guide comprises a guiding frame comprising a cam edge arranged to cooperate with a protruding part of the first connector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The submersible vehicle according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a linear actuator arranged at an outside of the submersible vehicle for linearly moving the second connector towards the first connector to establish connection between the mother ship and the submersible vehicle.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The submersible vehicle according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a capturing mast arranged at a distance from a longitudinal midline of the submersible vehicle and at a front half portion of the submersible vehicle.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The submersible vehicle according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first guide is arranged near a horizontal midline and at a rear half portion of the submersible vehicle.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The submersible vehicle according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the submersible vehicle has an upper side mainly free of protruding objects except for the capturing mast and the first guide and the second guide.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The submersible vehicle according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the first guide comprises a first member and a second member, the first member being arranged to guide the cable downwards and sideways towards the second guiding frame, and the second member being arranged to guide the cable mainly in sideways direction towards the second guiding frame.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The submersible vehicle according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a hook organ arranged at a top portion of the capturing mast.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The submersible vehicle according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the hook organ is partly ring shaped for surrounding the cable, and has an opening for letting the cable into a space defined by the hook organ.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The submersible vehicle according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the hook organ is a principally a straight member arranged with an angle towards a main portion of the mast.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The submersible vehicle according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the connector holder designed as a cradle.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The submersible vehicle according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the cradle has a cross section that is wider than the cable but narrower than the first connector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A system for interconnecting a mother ship with a submersible vehicle, using a cable towed by the mother ship, the cable having a first cable end connected to the mother ship, and a second free cable end, the second cable end being provided with a first connector facing away from the cable, the system comprising:
<claim-text>an upright arm comprising a hook portion arranged at an end of the upright arm distal to the submersible vehicle, wherein the upright arm is arranged at the submersible vehicle for capturing the cable towed by the mother ship, and wherein the upright arm is foldable from an upright position extending away from a surface of the submersible vehicle to a folded position substantially parallel to the surface of the submersible vehicle;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a connector holder being arranged at the submersible vehicle for holding the first connector in a position to be connected to a second connector, the second connector being connected to the submersible vehicle;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first guide arranged at the submersible vehicle and configured to guide the first connector towards the connector holder of the submersible vehicle; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second guide for turning the connector to a connection position into the connector holder.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. A method for connecting a towed cable to a submersible vehicle, the cable having a first cable end connectable to an entity, and a second cable end, the second cable end being provided with a first connector facing away from the cable, the method comprising:
<claim-text>capturing the cable with aid of an upright arm arranged at the submersible vehicle, wherein the upright arm is foldable from an upright position extending away from a surface of the submersible vehicle to a folded position substantially parallel to a surface of the submersible vehicle, and wherein the upright are comprises a hook portion arranged at an end of the upright arm distal to the submersible vehicle;</claim-text>
<claim-text>guiding the cable towards a first guide with aid of the upright arm;</claim-text>
<claim-text>guiding the first connector towards a connector holder of the submersible vehicle with the aid of first guide;</claim-text>
<claim-text>holding the first connector with aid of the connector holder, wherein the holder is adapted to hold the first connector firmly in a predefined position where the first connector can be connected to a second connector, the second connector being connected to the submersible vehicle; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>moving the second connector towards the first connector.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>turning the connector to a predefined position into the connector holder.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A submersible vehicle, comprising:
<claim-text>a connector configured to connect the submersible vehicle to a cable in water having a first free cable end with a first connector arranged at the free cable end and facing away from the cable;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an upright arm comprising a hook portion arranged at an end of the upright arm distal to the submersible vehicle, wherein the upright arm is foldable from an upright position extending away from a surface of the submersible vehicle to a folded position substantially parallel to the surface of the submersible vehicle;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first guide, wherein the upright arm is adapted to capture the cable and guide the cable towards the first guide;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a connector holder configured to hold the first connector in a position to be connected to a second connector, wherein the first guide is adapted to guide the first connector towards the connector holder; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a linear actuator arranged at the outside of the submersible vehicle for linearly moving the second connector, towards the first connector to establish connection between the mother ship and the submersible vehicle. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
