<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08621927-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08621927</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13850309</doc-number>
<date>20130326</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20120101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>19</main-group>
<subgroup>56</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7350414</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Angular rate sensor with suppressed linear acceleration response</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6946742</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Karpman</name>
<date>20050900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257778</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0272410</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Mao et al.</name>
<date>20061200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 7350402</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>8</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7350414</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>18</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>18</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12692606</doc-number>
<date>20100123</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8453504</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13850309</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130213134</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130822</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Mao</last-name>
<first-name>Minyao</first-name>
<address>
<city>Santa Rosa</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Mao</last-name>
<first-name>Minyao</first-name>
<address>
<city>Santa Rosa</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Williams</last-name>
<first-name>Hezron E</first-name>
<department>2856</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Redmann</last-name>
<first-name>Gregory J</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An angular rate sensor having two generally planar proof masses disposed along a drive axis in the plane of the masses, a sense axis perpendicular to the drive axis, and an input axis perpendicular to the plane of the masses. The masses are suspended from a pair of driving frames, which are mounted and constrained for anti-phase linear movement along the drive axis in drive-mode. Detectors responsive to the anti-phase movement of the masses in directions parallel to the sense axis in response to Coriolis forces produced by rotation of the masses about the input axis for monitoring rate of rotation about the input axis.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="181.78mm" wi="167.22mm" file="US08621927-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="224.11mm" wi="176.45mm" file="US08621927-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="192.11mm" wi="154.60mm" file="US08621927-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="188.04mm" wi="157.40mm" file="US08621927-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="205.06mm" wi="164.85mm" file="US08621927-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="215.22mm" wi="187.37mm" file="US08621927-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="205.06mm" wi="180.51mm" file="US08621927-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="210.48mm" wi="178.48mm" file="US08621927-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="219.37mm" wi="196.85mm" file="US08621927-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="182.54mm" wi="198.20mm" file="US08621927-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="194.82mm" wi="191.43mm" file="US08621927-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="208.45mm" wi="188.04mm" file="US08621927-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="222.08mm" wi="178.48mm" file="US08621927-20140107-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="219.37mm" wi="191.43mm" file="US08621927-20140107-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00014" num="00014">
<img id="EMI-D00014" he="211.16mm" wi="193.46mm" file="US08621927-20140107-D00014.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00015" num="00015">
<img id="EMI-D00015" he="214.55mm" wi="184.57mm" file="US08621927-20140107-D00015.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00016" num="00016">
<img id="EMI-D00016" he="226.14mm" wi="201.00mm" file="US08621927-20140107-D00016.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00017" num="00017">
<img id="EMI-D00017" he="156.04mm" wi="198.88mm" file="US08621927-20140107-D00017.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00018" num="00018">
<img id="EMI-D00018" he="147.83mm" wi="195.50mm" file="US08621927-20140107-D00018.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This is a division of application Ser. No. 12/692,606, filed on Jan. 23, 2010, now pending.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">This invention pertains generally to micromachined angular rate sensors or gyroscopes, and more particularly to vibratory rate sensors utilizing dual-mass anti-phase translational movement in drive or sense modes.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Many applications in automotive and consumer market require rate sensors to be insensitive to linear acceleration in all directions. In general, a rate sensor can be susceptible to linear acceleration in the drive and sense directions of the proof masses of the sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">For rate sensors utilizing translational drive motion, commonly used dual-mass approach with conventional coupling method, such as that disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 5,895,850, has an in-phase linear vibration mode with resonant frequency below that of the anti-phase drive-mode. This parasitic mode allows the centroid of the proof masses to move in response to linear acceleration along the drive axis, so that the velocities of the masses are susceptible to linear acceleration in the drive direction. To reduce this susceptibility, the in-phase mode must be well suppressed such that its resonant frequency is much higher than that of anti-phase drive-mode.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Geen disclosed a mechanical coupling method in U.S. Pat. No. 5,635,638, which allows anti-phase linear movement of the two-coupled masses but resists their in-phase movement. However, the in-phase mode cannot be well suppressed due to the fact that the arcuate coupling member used is prone to bending and buckling under linear acceleration forces in the drive direction. Furthermore, no actual gyroscope device utilizing that coupling method has been disclosed.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Geen disclosed a different mechanical coupling method in U.S. Pat. No. 6,877,374 in a Z-axis gyroscope that leads to a better suppression of in-phase translational movement of the proof masses. However, this coupling structure is complex which includes multiple levers, pivots, and flexures, and each proof mass has to split into two parts that move in arcuate motion, instead of pure linear movement. The unbalanced arcuate motion of the two parts of a proof mass due to the process imperfections results in an undesired net movement of the masse in sense direction, which causes the error of the sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">U.S. Pat. No. 7,036,372 discloses a Z-axis gyroscope that utilizes a mechanical linkage between two masses which resists in-phase movement. Again, that linkage is complicated with requirement of multiple stiff rotation beams with inner anchor points as pivots that occupy a considerable layout area. Furthermore, the linkage must include pivots anchored to the substrate. That makes it impossible to mount the linkage on movable structure, which is often desirable in multi-axes rate sensors.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">For many vibratory dual-mass gyroscopes, the rejection of linear acceleration in sense direction, which is perpendicular to drive axis, is achieved by differential processing of the electrical signals from the sense responses of the two masses. The spurious sense signals caused by linear acceleration noise can only be cancelled when the two masses and their resonant frequencies of sense modes are identical, which are impractical due to the process imperfections. And the un-cancelled residual signal becomes the error and noise in the rate signal.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">OBJECTS AND SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">It is in general an object of the invention to provide a new and improved angular rate sensor or gyroscope.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Another object of the invention is to provide a rate sensor or gyroscope of the above character, which overcomes the limitations, and disadvantages of rate sensors of the prior art.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">These and other objects are achieved in accordance with the invention by providing an angular rate sensor having two generally planar proof masses, a planar supporting frame, means for suspending the masses from the supporting frame for movement along a sense axis in the plane of the masses, an input axis in the plane of the masses perpendicular to the sense axis, means for driving the masses and the supporting frame to oscillate about the input axis in drive-mode, means for constraining the masses for anti-phase sense-mode oscillation along the sense axis in response to Coriolis forces produced by rotation of the masses about the input axis, means responsive to the anti-phase sense-mode movement of the masses for monitoring rate of rotation.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a top plan view of an embodiment of a y-axis rate sensor according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2(</figref><i>a</i>) is an operational view, illustrating the anti-phase drive-mode movement of the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2(</figref><i>b</i>) is an operational view, illustrating the in-phase mode movement of the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a top plan view of another embodiment of a y-axis rate sensor according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a top plan view of an embodiment of a z-axis rate sensor according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a top plan view of another embodiment of a z-axis rate sensor according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a top plan view of another embodiment of a y-axis rate sensor according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a top plan view of an embodiment of a dual-axis rate sensor according to the present invention for detecting rate of rotation about the y-, and z-axes.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a top plan view of another embodiment of a z-axis rate sensor according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a top plan view of another embodiment of a z-axis rate sensor according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a top plan view of another embodiment of a z-axis rate sensor according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a top plan view of another embodiment of a y-axis rate sensor according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a top plan view of an embodiment of a dual-axis rate sensor according to the present invention for detecting rate of rotation about the x-, and y-axes.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a top plan view of another embodiment of a z-axis rate sensor according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is a top plan view of another embodiment of a z-axis rate sensor according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is a top plan view of an embodiment of a dual-axis rate sensor according to the present invention for detecting rate of rotation about the x-, and z-axes.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref> is a top plan view of an embodiment of a tri-axis rate sensor according to the present invention for detecting rate of rotation about the x-, y-, and z-axes.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</figref> is a top plan view of another embodiment of a tri-axis rate sensor according to the present invention for detecting rate of rotation about the x-, y-, and z-axes.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the rate sensor has a pair of generally planar proof masses <b>20</b><i>a</i>, <b>20</b><i>b </i>that lie in an x, y reference plane when the device is at rest. The masses are disposed and spaced apart along the x-axis, which is the drive axis, i.e. the axis along which the masses are driven to oscillate in drive-mode. The input axis, i.e. the axis about which the angular rate of rotation is measured, is the y-axis.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The proof masses are suspended from a supporting frame, or sensing frame, <b>22</b> in the plane of the masses by flexible beams, or flexures, <b>24</b><i>a</i>, <b>24</b><i>b</i>. The flexures, which extend along the y-axis, are relatively flexible in the drive direction, but relatively stiff in other directions. These flexures constrain each one of the masses for linear movement along the x-axis.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The masses can be driven into oscillation along the drive axis by comb drives <b>44</b><i>a</i>, <b>44</b><i>b</i>, which have interdigitated comb fingers with moveable fingers attached to masses <b>20</b><i>a</i>, <b>20</b><i>b </i>and stationary fingers affixed to the anchored electrodes <b>46</b><i>a</i>, <b>46</b><i>b </i>respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The sensing frame is generally planner and disposed in the x, y plane with and surrounding the masses. It is suspended from substrate (not shown) by a pair of torsion springs <b>26</b>, which are spaced apart and extend along the y-axis and connect to anchors <b>28</b> affixed to the substrate. These torsion springs constrain the sensing frame for rotation about the y-axis in response to the Coriolis forces produced by the rotation of the masses about the input axis, i.e. the y-axis, when the masses are driven to oscillate in anti-phase manner along the x-axis, as indicated by the arrows <b>21</b><i>a</i>, <b>21</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The torsion movement of the sensing frame and the masses about the y-axis in sense-mode is detected capacitively by a pair of capacitors formed between masses <b>20</b><i>a</i>, <b>20</b><i>b </i>and corresponding electrode plates <b>42</b><i>a</i>, <b>42</b><i>b</i>, which are mounted under the masses respectively on the substrate. These capacitors work together to serve as a differential sensor, or detector, for monitoring the rate of rotation about the y-axis.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">A pair of mechanical linkages, or anti-phase couplers, <b>30</b>, which are mounted on the sensing frame and connected between the masses, couple the masses together and constrain them for precise anti-phase movement in drive-mode. The two couplers are spaced apart along the y-axis and disposed symmetrically about the x-axis.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Each anti-phase coupler includes a supporting beam <b>34</b> and a pair of link springs <b>32</b><i>a</i>, <b>32</b><i>b</i>. The supporting beam extends along the x-axis and is affixed to the sensing frame at its two ends. The link springs extend from respective masses to the supporting beam. They are tilted slightly from the y-axis and disposed symmetrically about that axis. The two link springs join together at the midpoint of the supporting beam forming a common joint <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Each link spring of the anti-phase couplers consists of a relatively long, stiff stem <b>40</b> and a pair of short flexible beams, or hinges, <b>38</b> connected to the two ends of the stem. The flexible beams are orientated substantially along the longitudinal direction of the stem. Under this arrangement, a link spring can be approximated as a rigid bar with rotation hinges attached to its both ends so that it is stiff in its longitudinal direction while permitting rotation about the z-axis, which is perpendicular to the x, y reference plane.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In operation, the link springs transfer the drive-mode movement of masses along the x-axis to joints <b>36</b>, which are constrained for linear movement along the y-axis by supporting beams <b>34</b>. When the two masses move in an anti-phase manner, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2(</figref><i>a</i>), two link springs in each anti-phase coupler tend to move their joint in same direction along the y-axis and cause the supporting beam to bend. Since the supporting beam is flexible in that direction, the anti-phase movement of the masses experiences minimal resistance from the anti-phase coupler. With symmetric design about the y-axis, the two masses have equal amplitudes in drive-mode oscillation, and the phase difference between the masses is precisely 180 degrees, which is guaranteed by the geometry of the anti-phase coupler and tolerant to fabrication process imperfections.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">When the two masses try to move in in-phase manner, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2(</figref><i>b</i>), two link springs in each anti-phase coupler tend to cause their joint to move in opposite direction along the y-axis and to cancel each other ideally, which actually results in suppression of the in-phase movement. However, in a real device, the constraints of joints from supporting beams are not ideal. As also shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2(</figref><i>b</i>), joints <b>36</b> can still have, to some extent, some undesired translational and rotational freedoms caused by the asymmetric bending of supporting beams <b>34</b> and bending or buckling of hinges <b>38</b>, which leads to overall deformation of the link springs in their longitudinal directions. As a result, the in-phase mode of the two masses is not suppressed completely. However, the resonant frequency of the in-phase mode in a typical design is still significantly higher than that of the anti-phase mode, which is the working mode of the rate sensor in operation.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">With fixed working mode frequency, maximizing the in-phase mode resonant frequency in a dual-mass gyroscope is important to improve its performance of linear vibration noise rejection. In general, the larger the tilt angle of link spring the higher efficiency in transferring the longitudinal movement of the masses along the x-axis into lateral motions along the y-axis at joints <b>36</b>, which result in stronger coupling effect of the anti-phase couplers. However, to accommodate larger motion at the joints, supporting beams <b>34</b> have to be softer in order to keep the anti-phase mode frequency constant. The softer supporting beams result in weaker constraint of joints in undesired freedoms, such as the translation along the x-axis and the rotation about the z-axis, which actually cause weaker in-phase mode. Therefore, there is a tradeoff in maximizing the in-phase mode frequency, which depends on detailed design of the gyroscope.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">To maximize the in-phase mode frequency under fixed tilt angle of link springs, it is important to increase the longitudinal stiffness of the link springs. Lower longitudinal stiffness results in lower efficiency in transferring the movement of the masses in the x-direction to the motion of the joints in the y-direction. In the worst case, a link spring can undergo buckling, which leads to zero transferring efficiency and no coupling effect between the masses at all. Compared to a simple straight beam, a link spring with a stiff stem in the middle can have significantly increased longitudinal stiffness and buckling threshold that leads to much higher efficiency in motion transferring.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">It is also important to increase the overall linear stiffness of the link springs along the drive direction so to reduce their deformation under linear acceleration along the x-axis. In general, the longer and stiffer stems <b>40</b>, and shorter hinge beams <b>38</b> lead to more rigid in-phase mode. However, the shorter hinge beam requires smaller width to keep it flexible enough to serve as a rotation hinge, which increases the process sensitivity of its spring constant.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In a typical design, with a hinge length of &#x2153;-&#xbd; of that of stem and tilt angle of 10-30 degrees from the y-axis, the in-phase mode frequency can be pushed to 3-5 times of that of anti-phase drive-mode, which greatly suppresses the displacement of the masses in response to linear acceleration along the drive axis.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">It should also be noted that the anti-phase coupler structure described above could lead to the best performance in suppressing the in-phase mode. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows another embodiment of a y-axis rate sensor which is very similar to the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, except it uses straight beams <b>48</b> as link springs. This link spring design can be viewed as a special case of that of the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, if the width of stems <b>40</b> in that embodiment is reduced to the same as that of hinge beams <b>38</b>. With proper design optimization of the tilt angle and dimensions of related beams, fairy good in-phase mode suppression may also be achieved.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">One should note that the anti-phase coupling design disclosed in the present invention has a significant improvement over the prior art, such as disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 5,635,638, wherein the coupling member, which is equivalent to link spring of the present invention, is an arcuate member. Due to its curved shape that is prone to buckling and bending in multiple directions, the arcuate member can only be viewed as a poor link spring with significantly lower stiffness in longitudinal direction and overall linear stiffness along the drive axis than that of link springs disclosed in the present invention. Therefore, it results in much lower efficiency in motion transferring and more displacement under linear acceleration, which lead to lower efficiency in anti-phase coupling and in-phase suppression.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows an embodiment of a z-axis rate sensor using similar anti-phase coupled dual-mass drive as that in the embodiment of a y-axis rate sensor shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. Since very similar masses and coupling designs are used, they are assigned same numbers as that in the previous embodiment. Again, masses <b>20</b><i>a</i>, <b>20</b><i>b </i>are suspended from sensing frame <b>22</b>, and linked by anti-phase couplers <b>30</b>, which consist of link springs <b>32</b><i>a</i>, <b>32</b><i>b </i>and supporting beams <b>34</b>, for anti-phase drive-mode oscillation along the x-axis.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">However, the sensing frame in this embodiment is suspended by four flexures <b>50</b> disposed at the corners of the rectangular frame and connected to anchors <b>52</b>. Each flexure is generally stiff in longitudinal direction but compliant in its lateral direction in the plane of the masses. The flexures are preferably oriented along radial directions that permit the sensing frame to rotate about the z-axis but resist other movements.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In operation, the masses are driven electrostatically by combs <b>44</b><i>a</i>, <b>44</b><i>b </i>to oscillate in anti-phase manner along the x-direction. The rotation of masses about the input axis, which is the z-axis, produces Coriolis forces that cause the masses and the sensing frame to rotate about the z-axis. This sense-mode rotation of the sensing frame about the z-axis is monitored by capacitors <b>54</b> which have interleaved parallel plates <b>56</b>, <b>58</b> connected to the sensing frame and to anchors <b>60</b> respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The rate sensor of this embodiment has longitudinal comb drives <b>44</b><i>a</i>, <b>44</b><i>b </i>oriented along the drive axis with movable fingers directly attached to the proof masses for driving the masses to oscillate in drive-mode. One troublesome side effect of this straightforward drive approach is that small imbalances of the gaps between the fingers induce a lateral motion in addition to the longitudinal drive-mode oscillation along the x-axis. The imbalances of the gaps of fingers can be caused by process imperfections, stress, or external acceleration, etc, which are difficult to eliminate completely.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">This lateral motion caused by the gap imbalance has a component that is in-phase with the motion caused by the Coriolis forces. Unlike quadrature signal, it cannot be separated and rejected from the real rate signal by phase sensitive circuitry. Furthermore, any instability of this in-phase signal directly contributes to the noise and error of the output of the rate sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">This problem is solved in the present invention by using a decoupled comb drive system in which the drive motion of the comb fingers is perpendicular to the drive axis of the sensor and decoupled from the sense-mode movement. This drive design is used in another embodiment of a z-axis rate sensor, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">This embodiment is generally similar to the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, except it uses a new drive system to replace the comb drives <b>44</b><i>a</i>, <b>44</b><i>b </i>of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. The drive system is disposed in the center area surrounded by masses <b>20</b><i>a</i>, <b>20</b><i>b </i>and anti-phase couplers <b>30</b>. The drive system consists of two identical sub drive systems that are disposed along the y-axis and are symmetrical about the x-axis.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Each sub drive system is generally symmetric about the y-axis. It includes a T-shape rigid driving frame <b>61</b>, which consists of an arm <b>62</b> extending along the x-direction and arm <b>64</b> extending along the y-axis, and comb drives <b>66</b> with moving fingers affixed to arm <b>62</b> and stationary fingers anchored to the substrate. The driving frame is suspended by suspension flexures <b>68</b> which extend along the x-axis and connect to anchors. These flexures permit the driving frame to move along the y-axis and severely resist movement in all other directions. The comb drives are oriented with fingers parallel to the y-axis for exciting the driving frames to oscillate along the y-axis in drive-mode.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Each driving frame <b>61</b> is connected to respective joint <b>36</b> by a link flexure <b>70</b>, which extends along the y-axis. The link flexure is relatively stiff in its longitudinal direction, but relatively compliant in its lateral direction for bending in the plane of the masses.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In operation, comb drives <b>66</b> electrostatically excite each frame <b>61</b> to move in the y-direction. This motion is linked and transferred by link flexure <b>70</b> to joint <b>36</b>, and further transferred through link springs <b>32</b><i>a</i>, <b>32</b><i>b </i>to move the masses along the x-axis. Since the two sub drive systems are disposed symmetrically about the x-axis, the same drive signal applied on all combs <b>66</b> causes two joints <b>36</b> of the sensor to move in opposite directions along the y-axis. Thus, the two link springs connected to each mass tend to move the mass in same direction. Again, as in the previous embodiments, the anti-phase couplers <b>30</b> connected to the masses ensure the two masses to oscillate in precise anti-phase manner with equal amplitudes.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">When the rate sensor rotates about its input axis, which is the z-axis, Coriolis forces produced by this rotation and the velocities of the masses of drive-mode oscillation cause the masses and the sensing frame to rotate about the z-axis. Such sense-mode movement experiences little resistance from link flexures <b>70</b>, because they are compliant in lateral directions.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">In this embodiment, the erroneous output of the sensor induced by the lateral motion of drive fingers caused by imbalances of the gaps of the fingers is greatly suppressed. First, the lateral movement of drive fingers result from the same gap imbalances is significantly reduced, because driving frames <b>61</b> are now severely resistant to movement in the lateral direction by the suspension flexures <b>68</b> which extend along that direction. Second, link flexures <b>70</b> are compliant in this lateral direction so that the lateral motion transferred to the sensing frame is further reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Another advantage of this drive design is that the amplitude of masses in drive-mode oscillation can be different from that of comb drives <b>66</b>, and can be tuned by adjusting the tilt angle of the link springs. This allows one to design a sensor with large drive amplitude of the masses but relative short fingers of comb drives. This results in more efficient drive and smaller device. Also interesting is the opposite case, where the travel distance of comb is larger than the drive amplitude of the masses in drive-mode. The larger travel distance of the combs can put in more electrostatic energy to the system in each drive cycle, thus the drive voltage can be reduced in order to drive the masses into the same amplitude. This is particularly desirable for gyroscopes operating in atmosphere or poor vacuum environment with low Q (quality factor) that usually require high drive voltages.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the two sub drive systems can be further coupled together by another pair of anti-phase couplers <b>72</b> which are disposed along the x-axis and symmetric about the y-axis. Each coupler is also symmetric about the x-axis. The design of anti-phase coupler <b>72</b> is similar to that of anti-phase coupler <b>30</b>, each includes a pair of link springs <b>74</b> and a supporting beam <b>76</b>. The two link springs in each anti-phase coupler <b>72</b> are tilted slightly from the x-axis and connected respectively to the ends of rigid arms <b>64</b>. And the supporting beams which extend along the y-axis are connected to the anchors affixed to the substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Anti-phase couplers <b>72</b> further suppress the in-phase movement of the two sub drive systems, and ensure precise anti-phase and equal amplitudes of the two sub drive systems in drive-mode. That makes the drive system immune to the external acceleration along the y-axis.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">For simplicity, each link spring <b>74</b> in anti-phase couplers <b>72</b> is drawn as a simple straight beam. Certainly, more complicated shape similar to that of <b>32</b><i>a </i>in anti-phase coupler <b>30</b> can be used for better performance.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">This decoupled drive approach can also be applied to y-axis rate sensors. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates another embodiment of a y-axis gyroscope, which is generally similar to the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> but employs the same decoupled drive system shown in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">In this embodiment, the sense-mode motion in response to Coriolis forces produced by rate of rotation about the y-axis is the rotation of sensing frame <b>22</b> and masses <b>20</b><i>a</i>, <b>20</b><i>b </i>about the y-axis. It should be noted that, link flexures <b>70</b> which extend along the y-axis also permit rotation about the y-axis. Therefore, they impose little resistance to the sense-mode movement, and decouple the sense motion from the drive system.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows an embodiment of a dual-axis rate sensor for detecting rate of rotation about the y-, and z-axes. It has similar drive and coupling structures as that shown in the embodiments of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, but different sense structure. In addition to sensing frame <b>22</b>, it has another sensing frame <b>23</b>, which surrounds <b>22</b>. And frame <b>22</b> is suspended from <b>23</b> by torsion springs <b>78</b> for rotation relative to <b>23</b> about the y-axis. Frame <b>23</b> is suspended from the substrate by a set of flexures <b>80</b> for rotation about the z-axis.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">In operation, masses <b>20</b><i>a</i>, <b>20</b><i>b </i>are driven to oscillate in anti-phase manner along the x-axis, which is similar to that described in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. The rate of rotation about the y-axis produces Coriolis forces that cause the masses and frame <b>22</b> to rotate about the y-axis. This sense mode rotation is sensed capacitively for monitoring rate of rotation by two electrode plates <b>42</b><i>a</i>, <b>42</b><i>b </i>mounted beneath the two masses respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">In the meantime, the rate of rotation about the z-axis produces Coriolis forces that cause the masses and frames <b>22</b>, <b>23</b> to rotate together about the z-axis. And this sense-mode rotation is detected for monitoring rate of rotation by parallel-plate capacitors <b>82</b>, which have interleaved plates with moveable ones mounted on frame <b>23</b> and stationary ones affixed to electrodes anchored on the substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">In a typical gyroscope design with comparable resonant frequencies of the two sense modes, i.e. rotations about the y-, and z-axis, torsion springs <b>78</b> are often much shorter and substantially stiffer for bending in the plane than that of flexures <b>80</b>. Therefore, frames <b>22</b> and <b>23</b> rotate together with little difference in amplitudes in the sense mode of rotation about the z-axis.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">Under this design of sense structure, the two sense-mode rotations are well decoupled from one another, the dual-axis rate sensor monitors two components (y-, and z-) of an angular velocity simultaneously with little interference, or cross-talk from one another. Therefore, with two such dual-axis sensors rotated 90 degrees about the z-axis from one another in same substrate or same package, all three components (x-, y-, and z-) of an angular velocity can be determined simultaneously. This is one way of making a tri-axis rate sensor, which is more efficient and can have smaller size than conventional approach that assembles three single-axis gyroscopes together.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">All embodiments of rate sensors described above have sensing frames disposed outside and surrounding the masses. This approach requires relatively larger frame structures that occupy more layout areas. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> shows another embodiment of a z-axis rate sensor that has a sensing frame surrounded by the masses.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the rate sensor of this embodiment is essentially symmetric about the x-, and y-axes. Two horseshoe shaped masses <b>84</b><i>a</i>, <b>84</b><i>b </i>are disposed side-by-side along the x-axis with the openings of cutout areas facing each other. The masses are suspended from a sensing frame <b>86</b>, which is disposed in the center area enclosed by the two masses, by suspension flexures <b>88</b> extending along the y-axis. The two masses are coupled by a pair of anti-phase couplers <b>90</b>, each of which consists of a pair of link springs <b>92</b> and a supporting beam <b>94</b> which is mounted to the sensing frame. Link springs <b>92</b> are tilted slightly from the y-direction, and supporting beams <b>94</b> extend along the x-axis. The anti-phase couplers ensure the two masses to move in anti-phase manner along the x-axis in drive-mode. Sensing frame <b>86</b> is suspended by a set of sense flexures <b>96</b> disposed along radial directions that permit the frame to rotate about the z-axis and severely resist other movement. These flexures are mounted to the substrate by anchor <b>98</b> located at the center of the sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">In operation, masses <b>84</b><i>a</i>, <b>84</b><i>b </i>are driven electrostatically to oscillate along the x-axis in an anti-phase manner by comb drivers <b>100</b><i>a</i>, <b>100</b><i>b </i>respectively. The input rate of rotation about the z-axis produces Coriolis forces that cause the masses and the sensing frame to rotate about the z-axis. This sense-mode rotation is monitored for measuring rate of rotation by parallel-plate capacitors <b>102</b> that have interleaved plates mounted to the sensing frame and to anchored electrodes.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">This embodiment has generally smaller sensing frame, or smaller moment of inertia of sense mode compared to that in the previous embodiments with sensing frames surrounding the masses. Since the sensing frame is a passive part of the device that serves as a load mass to Coriolis forces, the smaller moment of inertia of the frame leads to greater Coriolis displacement, thus, higher detection efficiency of the sensor. Also, the sensor of this embodiment has minimal sensitivities to temperature and external stresses, because it employs only one anchor for suspending the movable structures.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">The embodiments described above have anti-phase couplers that are all mounted to the sensing frame and move with the frame in sense-mode. However, rate sensors according to the present invention can also have anti-phase couplers mounted directly to the substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> illustrates another embodiment of a z-axis gyroscope that has anti-phase couplers mounted to the substrate. The rate sensor of this embodiment is symmetric about the x-, and y-axes. Two proof masses <b>103</b><i>a</i>, <b>103</b><i>b </i>disposed along the x-axis are suspended from a sensing frame <b>104</b> by flexures <b>105</b>, which extend along the y-axis and constrain the masses for movement along the x-axis. Frame <b>104</b> is suspended by a set of flexures <b>106</b> and constrained for rotation about the z-axis.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">Masses <b>103</b><i>a</i>, <b>103</b><i>b </i>are further connected respectively to driving frames <b>107</b><i>a</i>, <b>107</b><i>b </i>by flexures <b>108</b> which extend along the x-axis. The two driving frames are disposed side-by-side along the x-axis in the region between the two masses. The driving frames are suspended from the substrate by a set of flexures <b>110</b> for movement along the x-axis. Comb drives <b>122</b><i>a</i>, <b>122</b><i>b </i>are attached to the driving frames respectively for exciting the frames to oscillate along the x-axis in drive-mode.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">The two driving frames are further coupled by a pair of anti-phase couplers <b>112</b>, which are disposed spaced apart along the y-axis and symmetric about the x-axis, for anti-phase movement along the x-axis. Similar to anti-phase coupler <b>30</b> of the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, each anti-phase coupler <b>112</b> includes a pair of tilted link springs <b>114</b> and a supporting beam <b>120</b>. Each link spring <b>114</b> consists of a stiff stem <b>116</b> and two hinge flexures <b>118</b>. Each supporting beam <b>120</b> extends along the x-axis and is affixed to the substrate at its two ends.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">In operation, frames <b>107</b><i>a</i>, <b>107</b><i>b </i>are driven by comb drives <b>122</b><i>a</i>, <b>122</b><i>b </i>respectively to oscillate in anti-phase manner along the x-axis in drive-mode. Flexures <b>108</b> transfer the movement of the driving frames to the masses. Since flexures <b>108</b> are stiff in longitudinal direction, masses <b>103</b><i>a</i>, <b>103</b><i>b </i>are rigidly linked to frames <b>107</b><i>a</i>, <b>107</b><i>b </i>respectively for movement along the x-axis, the phase of each mass is the same as that of the driving frame connected to it. Thus, the two masses are also oscillating in precise anti-phase manner along the x-axis. The rate of rotation about the z-axis produces Coriolis forces that cause the masses and the sensing frame to rotate about the z-axis. Since the masses move in lateral directions of flexures <b>108</b>, these flexures impose little resistance to the sense-mode rotation. This rotation movement is sensed capacitively by the parallel-plate capacitors <b>124</b>, which have interleaved plates attached to the sensing frame and to the anchors affixed to the substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">Unlike the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the drive directions of the comb drives in this embodiment are parallel to the drive axis, i.e. the x-axis. And the driving frames serve as both the decoupled driver and part of anti-phase coupling means for the two masses. This is more efficient than that of the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, wherein the masses have additional anti-phase couplers <b>30</b> that directly couple the masses. However, this approach cannot be directly applied in y-axis gyroscope, because link flexures <b>108</b> resist the sense-mode rotation about the y-axis.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">The rate sensors disclosed in the previous embodiments all have a single sensing frame for each sense-mode. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> shows another embodiment of a z-axis rate sensor that has dual sensing frames for the sense-mode. In this embodiment, two masses <b>126</b><i>a</i>, <b>126</b><i>b</i>, which are disposed along the x-axis, are suspended from two driving frames <b>128</b><i>a</i>, <b>128</b><i>b </i>respectively by flexures <b>130</b> that extend along the x-axis. Flexures <b>130</b> link each mass to move together with its corresponding driving frame along the x-axis, while permit it to move relative to the frame along the y-axis, which is the sense axis of the mass.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">Driving frames <b>128</b><i>a</i>, <b>128</b><i>b </i>are disposed side-by-side in a region between the two masses, and suspended by flexures <b>132</b> which extend along the y-axis and constrain the frames for movement along the x-axis. The two driving frames are coupled by a pair of anti-phase coupler <b>134</b>, which are disposed along the y-axis and constrain the driving frames for anti-phase movement along the x-axis. Each anti-phase coupler <b>134</b> consists of a pair of tilted link springs <b>136</b> and a supporting beam <b>138</b> which extend along the x-axis and mounted to the substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">Each mass is connected to a pair of sensing frames <b>142</b> by flexures <b>140</b> which extend along the y-axis. The two sensing frames extending along the x-axis are disposed spaced apart along the y-axis. Each sensing frame is suspended by a flexure <b>144</b> which extends along the y-axis and are anchored to the substrate, and a flexure <b>146</b> that extend along the x-axis with its center affixed to the substrate. These two flexures constrain the sensing frame for rotation about an axis that is parallel to the z-axis and passes through the interception point of the extrapolating of the two flexures.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">Masses <b>126</b><i>a</i>, <b>126</b><i>b </i>are further connected to two additional driving frames <b>150</b><i>a</i>, <b>150</b><i>b </i>respectively by flexures <b>151</b> extending along the x-axis. These frames are suspended from the substrate by flexures <b>152</b> extending along the y-axis. With these two additional frames, the masses can be well constrained for drive-mode movement along the x-axis with the driving frames, and sense-mode movement along the y-axis relative to the driving frames. And comb drives <b>154</b> attached to frames <b>150</b><i>a</i>, <b>150</b><i>b </i>can be used to drive the masses to oscillate in drive-mode or monitoring the velocity of the masses for drive loop control.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">In operation, the masses are driven to oscillate in anti-phase manner along the x-axis. The Coriolis forces produced by the rate of rotation about the z-axis cause the masses to move in their sense directions parallel to the y-axis. This sense movement is transferred to two sensing frames <b>142</b> by flexures <b>140</b> to cause each sensing frame to rotate about its rotation axis parallel to the z-axis. The rotations of the two sensing frames are in-phase to one another. And this sense-mode rotation is monitored by parallel-plate capacitors <b>148</b> attached to the frames for measuring rate of rotation.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">The use of dual rotation sensing frames in this embodiment reduces the inertia moment of inactive parts in the sense mode, in comparison to the single sensing frame used in the previous embodiments. Thus, it improves the detection efficiency of the rate sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> shows another embodiment of a y-axis rate sensor which has similar structure as to the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, but has different operation mode with reversed drive and sense functionalities compared to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. The drive signals are now applied to electrode plates <b>42</b><i>a</i>, <b>42</b><i>b </i>to drive the masses <b>20</b><i>a</i>, <b>20</b><i>b </i>and supporting frame <b>22</b>, which serves as a driving frame now, to move out-of-plane and rotate about the y-axis. In presence of rate of rotation about the y-axis, Coriolis forces produced by this rotation and the velocities of the masses in z-axis cause the masses to move in anti-phase manner along the x-axis, which is now the sense axis of the masses. This movement is transferred to joints <b>36</b> by link springs <b>32</b><i>a</i>, <b>32</b><i>b </i>for movement along the y-axis. The movement of joints <b>36</b> is further transferred by link flexures <b>70</b> to a pair of sensing frames <b>156</b>, which are spaced apart along the y-axis, which is a normal axis perpendicular to the sense axis. The sense frames are constrained for movement primary along the y-axis by a set of flexures <b>158</b> which extend along the x-axis.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">The two sensing frames are coupled by anti-phase couplers <b>72</b> to move in anti-phase manner along the y-axis, and to further suppress their in-phase movement. The anti-phase movement of the sensing frames is monitored for measuring rate of rotation about the y-axis by parallel-plate capacitors <b>160</b> which have interleaved plates attached to the sensing frames and connected to the anchors affixed to the substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">It can be seen, driving frames <b>64</b> of the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> are replaced by sensing frames <b>156</b>, and drive combs <b>66</b> are replaced by parallel-plate capacitors <b>160</b> in this embodiment. The combination of anti-phase couplers <b>30</b> and <b>72</b> ensure the masses, as well as sensing frames to oscillate in anti-phase manners, so that the sense-mode is severely resistant to external linear acceleration along the x- and y-axes. This leads to superior performance of the sensor in vibration noise rejection.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">It should be noted that, in this embodiment, the sense-mode motion of the sensing frames can be larger than that of the masses by adjusting the tilt angle of the link springs, which provides a mechanical amplifier for the sense mode. Amplified sensing frame displacement leads to larger capacitance output for same angular rate input, which results in higher sensitivity of the sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">Similar modifications can also be made to the embodiment of the dual-axis rate sensor illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, so that it becomes a dual-axis gyroscope for measuring rate of rotation about the x-, and y-axes, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>. This embodiment of dual-axis rate sensor can be viewed as a y-axis rate sensor, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, suspended by a pair of torsion springs <b>26</b> from sensing frame <b>23</b>, which is mounted for rotation about the z-axis. Torsion springs <b>26</b> permit driving frame <b>22</b> to rotate about the y-axis relative to sensing frame <b>23</b> while severely resisting other relative movement between the two frames. Sensing frame <b>23</b> adds an additional rotation freedom to the device that enables the masses to rotate about the z-axis, in addition to the x-axis.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">Again, masses <b>20</b><i>a</i>, <b>20</b><i>b </i>are driven electrostatically by the electrodes <b>42</b><i>a</i>, <b>42</b><i>b </i>respectively to rotate with frame <b>22</b> about the y-axis in drive-mode. The Coriolis forces produced by the velocities of the masses in the z-axis and rate of rotation about the y-axis cause the masses to move along the x-axis. The movements of the masses along the x-axis are linked and transferred to sensing frames <b>156</b> for oscillation along the y-axis in anti-phase manner. This sense-mode movement is monitored by capacitors <b>160</b> for measuring the rate of rotation about the y-axis. In the meantime, the Coriolis forces produced by the velocities of the masses in the z-axis and rate of rotation about the x-axis cause the masses and frames <b>22</b>, <b>23</b> to rotate together about the z-axis. The sense-mode rotation of frame <b>23</b> is monitored by parallel-plate capacitors <b>82</b> for measuring rate of rotation about the x-axis.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">Since the movements of the masses in the two sense modes are independent from one another, i.e. the two sense modes are decoupled, this dual-axis rate sensor can measure the two components (x-, and y-) of an angular velocity simultaneously with minimal interference or cross-talk.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">With similar modifications, the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> can also have another operation mode by switching the drive and sense functionalities. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, a driving frame <b>162</b> suspended for rotation about the z-axis replaces sensing frame <b>22</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. Comb drivers <b>164</b><i>a</i>, <b>164</b><i>b</i>, which have movable fingers attached to the driving frame, are disposed along the circumference of the frame for driving the frame to rotate about the z-axis. Since comb drivers <b>164</b><i>a </i>and <b>164</b><i>b </i>in each pair are oriented in opposite directions, they can be used for differential drive, or one for drive and the other for drive amplitude monitoring.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">Since flexures <b>24</b><i>a</i>, <b>24</b><i>b</i>, which suspend the masses from the driving frame, are stiff in longitudinal directions, the masses move together with the driving frame to rotate about the z-axis in drive-mode. In presence of rate of rotation about the z-axis, Coriolis forces produced by this rotation and the velocities of the masses along the y-axis cause the masses to move along their sense axis, i.e. the x-axis, in anti-phase manner. Similar to that in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, the movement of the masses are linked and transferred to a pair of coupled sensing frames <b>156</b> for anti-phase movement along the y-axis. This movement is sensed by capacitors <b>160</b> for measuring the rate of rotation about the z-axis.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> shows another embodiment of a z-axis gyroscope that is modified from the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> with switched drive and sense functionalities. A driving frame <b>166</b> which is mounted for rotation about the z-axis and driven by comb drives <b>167</b><i>a</i>, <b>167</b><i>b </i>replaces sensing frame <b>104</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">Similar to the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, masses <b>103</b><i>a</i>, <b>103</b><i>b </i>move with frame <b>166</b> for rotation about the z-axis in drive-mode. In presence of rate of rotation about the z-axis, Coriolis forces produced by this rotation and the velocities of the masses in the y-direction cause the masses to move along the x-axis in anti-phase manner. The movements of the masses are transferred by flexures <b>108</b> to a pair of sensing frames <b>168</b> which are constrained for anti-phase movement along the x-axis. This sense-mode movement of the sensing frames is monitored by the capacitors <b>170</b> for measuring rate of rotation about the z-axis. The drive approach shown as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> can also be applied to the embodiment of dual-axis gyroscope of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> so that it becomes a dual-axis gyroscope for measuring the rate of rotation about the x-, and z-axes, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref>. A driving frame <b>172</b> in this embodiment replaces sensing frame <b>23</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>. The driving frame is driven by comb drives <b>173</b><i>a</i>, <b>173</b><i>b </i>to rotate with supporting frame <b>22</b> and masses <b>20</b><i>a</i>, <b>20</b><i>b </i>about the z-axis in drive-mode.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">In presence of rate of rotation about the x-axis, Coriolis forces produced by this rotation and the velocities of the masses along the y-axis cause the masses and frame <b>22</b> to rotate about the y-axis. This sense-mode movement is detected capacitively by electrode plates <b>42</b><i>a</i>, <b>42</b><i>b </i>which are placed underneath the masses for measuring rate of rotation about the x-axis.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">In presence of angular rate input about the z-axis, Coriolis forces produced by that rotation and the velocities of the masses along the y-axis cause the masses to move along the x-axis in anti-phase manner. This movement is transferred to sensing frames <b>156</b> for anti-phase movement along the y-axis. This sense-mode movement of the sensing frames is monitored by parallel-plate capacitors <b>160</b> for measuring rate of rotation about the z-axis.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref> shows an embodiment of a tri-axis gyroscope for measuring rate of rotations about the x-, y-, and z-axes. It employs two sub-sensors, each of which is a dual-axis rate sensor as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref>. The two sub-sensors are disposed side-by-side along the x-axis with the right one rotated 90 degrees about the z-axis from the left one. The left sub-sensor measures rate of rotation about the x-, and z-axes, and the right sub-sensor measures rate of rotation about the y-, and z-axes.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">The two sub-sensors can be further coupled together by a coupling spring <b>174</b>, which connect the midpoints of the adjacent edges of driving frames <b>172</b><i>a</i>, <b>172</b><i>b </i>of the two sub-sensors. The coupling spring is in the form of a small rectangular frame, with relative long, flexible flexures extending in the y-direction and relatively short, stiff ones in the x-direction. This spring constrains frames <b>172</b><i>a</i>, <b>172</b><i>b </i>to rotate in anti-phase manner about their drive axes <b>176</b><i>a</i>, <b>176</b><i>b</i>, which locate at the centers of the frames respectively and extend parallel to the z-axis.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">The structures of the two sub-sensors can be identical, so that their oscillations about the drive axes in drive-mode are equal in amplitude and precisely anti-phase to one another. Therefore, the net angular drive momentum is zero and the device does not inject vibration energy into the substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">Since the overall tri-axis rate sensor has a single resonant mode that is excited as drive-mode, a single drive loop is sufficient to achieve amplitude-controlled drive-mode oscillation of all masses in the sensor. It simplifies the circuitry of the device and lowers cost.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">The tri-axis rate sensor of this embodiment includes two rate sensors for measuring rate of rotation about the z-axis. That could be advantageous for some applications, such as stability controlling for automobile, which is desirable to have a redundant YAW rate sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</figref> illustrates another embodiment of a tri-axis rate sensor which employs two subsensors without redundant sensors about the z-axis. The left subsensor is similar to that of the previous embodiment for measuring rate of rotation about the x-, and z-axes. However, the right subsensor is simplified to a single axis rate sensor for measuring rate of rotation about the y-axis only.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">The right subsensor includes a driving frame <b>178</b> mounted for rotation about a rotation axis, or driving axis, <b>177</b>, which is parallel to the z-axis. Mass <b>180</b> is disposed within the driving frame and suspended from it by a pair of torsion springs <b>182</b>, which are spared apart and extend along the x-axis. The torsion springs permit the mass to rotate about the x-axis and severely resist other relative movements between the mass and the driving frame.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">In operation, driving frame <b>178</b> and mass <b>180</b> are excited to rotate about driving axis <b>177</b> in drive-mode by comb drives <b>186</b><i>a</i>, <b>186</b><i>b</i>, which have moving comb fingers attached to driving frame <b>178</b> and stationary fingers connected to anchored electrodes. Coriolis forces produced by rate of rotation about the y-axis cause the mass to rotate about the x-axis. This sense-mode rotation movement is detected capacitively by electrode plates <b>184</b><i>a</i>, <b>184</b><i>b</i>, which are disposed underneath the mass and spaced apart along the y-axis, for monitoring rate of rotation about the y-axis.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">Similar to the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref>, the two subsensors can be further coupled together to have a common drive-mode by a coupling spring <b>188</b>, which is similar to <b>174</b> in the previous embodiment and are connected to the midpoints of adjacent edges of driving frames <b>172</b><i>a </i>and <b>178</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">The rate sensors according the present invention can be made from a material such as single-crystal silicon, polycrystalline silicon, metal, or other conductive materials, or insulate materials coated with conductive films, on a substrate such as silicon, glass, or other materials, by suitable MEMS process such as deep-reactive-ion-etching. And the sensor may be operated in atmosphere ambient or in vacuum housing for better performances.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">It is apparent from the foregoing that a new and improved angular rate sensor has been provided. While only presently preferred embodiments have been described in detail, as will be apparent to those familiar with the art, certain changes and modifications can be made without departing from the scope of the invention as defined by the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An angular rate sensor comprising:
<claim-text>a planar substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second generally planar masses disposed above the substrate and spaced apart along a pre-selected drive axis in the plane of the masses;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an input axis perpendicular to the plane of the masses;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sense axis in the plane of the masses and perpendicular to the drive axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second driving frames disposed along the drive axis in a region between the masses;</claim-text>
<claim-text>coupling means for constraining the driving frames for anti-phase movement along the drive axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>flexures connecting the first and second masses to the first and second driving frames respectively, wherein said flexures substantially constrain the masses to move together with respective driving frames along the drive axis in drive-mode, and permit the masses to move relatively to the driving frames in directions parallel to the sense axis in sense-mode;</claim-text>
<claim-text>actuation means for exciting the driving frames to oscillate along the drive axis in drive-mode;</claim-text>
<claim-text>detection means responsive to the anti-phase movement of the masses in directions parallel to the sense axis for monitoring rate of rotation about the input axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said coupling means includes a pair of anti-phase couplers disposed in a region between the drive frames and spaced apart along the sense axis, each said anti-phase coupler comprising:
<claim-text>a supporting beam which extends in a direction substantially parallel to the drive axis and is mounted to the substrate at its two ends;</claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second link springs which extend from the first and second driving frames respectively to the supporting beam and join one another to form a common joint at substantially the midpoint of the supporting beam.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The rate sensor of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein each said link spring is a straight beam.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The rate sensor of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein each said link spring comprises:
<claim-text>a substantially stiff stem;</claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second hinges connected to the two ends of said stem respectively, wherein said hinges are flexible beams permitting bending in the plane of the masses.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The rate sensor of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said link springs are tilted from a direction parallel to the sense axis at a predetermined angle.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The rate sensor of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said actuation means includes comb drives attached to at least one of the driving frames.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The rate sensor of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said detection means comprising:
<claim-text>a sensing frame disposed in the plane of the masses, wherein said sensing frame surrounds the masses;</claim-text>
<claim-text>flexures mounting the masses on the sensing frame and constraining the masses for movement relative to the sensing frame along the drive axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>flexures suspending the sensing frame from the substrate for rotation about the input axis in response to Coriolis forces produced by rotation of masses about the input axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>capacitors with movable electrodes attached to the sensing frame for detecting the rotation movement of the sensing frame about the input axis for monitoring rate of rotation about the input axis.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The rate sensor of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said detection means comprising:
<claim-text>first and second sensing frames disposed along the sense axis with the masses located between the sensing frames, wherein said sensing frames extend in directions parallel to the drive axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>means for suspending the sensing frames for torsional movement about respective rotation axes which are parallel to the input axis and spaced apart along the sense axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>flexures extending in directions parallel to the sense axis and connecting the masses to the sensing frames for transferring anti-phase movement of the masses in directions parallel to the sense axis to rotation movement of the sensing frames about their rotation axes;</claim-text>
<claim-text>actuation means for exciting the driving frames to oscillate along the drive axis in drive-mode;</claim-text>
<claim-text>capacitors with movable electrodes attached to the sensing frames for detecting the rotation movement of the sensing frames about their rotation axes for monitoring rate of rotation about the input axis.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The rate sensor of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref> wherein means for suspending each sensing frame including:
<claim-text>a first flexible beam extended parallel to the drive axis with its two ends mounted to the sensing frame and midpoint anchored to the substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second flexible beam extended along the sense axis with one end connected to the sensing frame and the other end anchored to the substrate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
