<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08621792-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08621792</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12638864</doc-number>
<date>20091215</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>E</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>18</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 521733</main-classification>
<further-classification> 52599</further-classification>
<further-classification> 525841</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Flexible clamps for clamping panels</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2317428</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Anderson</name>
<date>19430400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 52509</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2490663</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Van Uum et al.</name>
<date>19491200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 52460</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3276800</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Loudon et al.</name>
<date>19661000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>403397</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6672018</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Shingleton</name>
<date>20040100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 521733</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7194844</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Dennis</name>
<date>20070300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 525821</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7434362</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Liebendorfer</name>
<date>20081000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 521733</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>6</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 52543</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 52546</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 52547</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 52548</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 52549</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 52689</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 52699</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 52700</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 52704</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 521733</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 52460</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 52471</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 52 47</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 52  2</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 525821</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 525841</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 525861</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 525862</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 525851</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>411 34</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>411 35</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>403373</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>403374</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>403277</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>18</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20100146899</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20100617</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Zante</last-name>
<first-name>Anthony A.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fremont</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Zante</last-name>
<first-name>Anthony A.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fremont</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>GSS Law Group</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Laux</last-name>
<first-name>Jessica</first-name>
<department>3635</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A flexible height-adjustable clamp for clamping a solar panel to a support structure or base, with flat surfaces on the upper and lower parts of the clamp, the upper section clamping on the panels; and the lower section mounting against the base; with a hole through both flat surfaces for bolting a connector through the surfaces to secure the clamp and panel to the supporting structure; and a flexible section connecting the two surfaces in the form of an arc or folded section; with mechanical stops to allow positioning to against said panel.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="121.50mm" wi="184.66mm" file="US08621792-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="216.58mm" wi="175.60mm" file="US08621792-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="211.92mm" wi="185.08mm" file="US08621792-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="211.50mm" wi="152.57mm" file="US08621792-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="218.52mm" wi="155.70mm" file="US08621792-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="206.16mm" wi="139.02mm" file="US08621792-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of provisional patent application Ser. No. 61/138,052 filed Dec. 16, 2008 by the present inventor.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">This invention relates to a clamping system incorporating flexible clamps or clips for securing photovoltaic modules, panels, and plates against support structures and frames.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Prior Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Generally solar photo voltaic (PV) modules are attached to support frames mounted on rooftops, poles, and other surfaces with various means of clamping techniques. These clamping methods must provide sufficient force to insure that the modules will remain in place against their associated support frames even under very high wind loads. Examples of prior art are shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Typical clamping methods utilize various forms of edge holding clamps that clamp on top of the panel and hold the panel against a base or structural member using a bolt or screw for attachment. The structural member is typically a rail style member such as a commercial strut channel. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates typical clamps for clamping solar panels to strut bases.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Currently there are many forms of clamps that are used for panel or plate clamping applications. For clamping two panels adjacent to each other with a common clamp there are two popular configurations: the T-clamp (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) or flanged U-clamp that grips two adjacent panel edges and clamps them to a common strut channel. U.S. Pat. No. 6,672,018 describes the T-clamp and its clamping method. Typically the clamp is made shorter than the height of the panels in order to insure proper clamping action. The major problem with this type of apparatus is that since it is shorter than the panel that it is clamping, it will not stay in place and will fall off of the edge if only one panel is present. The second adjacent panel must be put in position first so that the T-clamp or U-clamp can be supported by both panel edges. Unfortunately this limits its usefulness since panels are typically installed in sequence. And since they are typically installed on an inclined surface such as a roof, it is difficult for a single installer to temporarily hold the first panel in position and simultaneously bring the second panel into position for clamping.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">T-clamps and U-clamps can be made longer than the part that they must clamp, however they still will not clamp the first panel in place without large forces needed to overcome their stiffness. These clamps are therefore also difficult to use for this application.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Currently there are other types of clamps that are used for clamping a single panel edge into place. One of the most popular types of clamps for this application is the Z-clamp (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>). The Z-clamp grips the top of the module with its upper lip and clamps to the strut channel using a bolt through the lower lip of the clamp. It is typically made intentionally short to insure gripping. Unfortunately this method of clamping with an intentionally short clamp has a tendency to pivot or slip away from the panel module edge causing loss of clamping force and consequent panel disengagement. Also, since the panel height varies, the height of the clamp must also vary in order to meet the appropriate height requirement. This leads to the need for a number of different height clamps because they have no adjustability. It is also difficult to uniformly clamp the panel into place because of the need for intentionally shorter Z-clamps.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">An L-clamp (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) forming an inverted L shape when clamped against the panel can also be used for clamping the panels in place. However, unless it is made exactly the correct height it will create an uneven force on the panels causing stress concentrations and slippage toward or away from the panels.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Although there are many conventional clamps for clamping PV modules and panels to structures they all suffer from the following disadvantages:</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Existing T-clamps and U-clamps that are shorter than the panel height tend to slip or fall off of the initial panel if not held in place before the adjacent panel can be positioned next to it. This increases the assembly labor because the clamp must be temporarily held in place until the next panel is positioned next to it.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Existing T-clamps and U-clamps that are longer than the panels also suffer from their limited usefulness in clamping the first panel.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Because of the solar panel thickness tolerances, existing Z-clamps and other end clamps are constructed intentionally shorter to insure proper gripping. However bolting down the base causes the top edge to slip away from the panel edge while tightening (See <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Existing end clamps do not squarely clamp the panel edge and can create stress concentrations on the outer panel edges when tightened.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In summary there is a need for flexible height clamps that can provide sufficient clamping force without causing slippage or stress concentrations on the devices being clamped.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">3. Objects and Advantages</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The present invention is a flexible clamp that is formed to provide the flexibility needed to clamp variable height panels or flat surfaces. The clamp is tightened against the panel with a bolt through the clamp. The clamp configuration for the required deflection path is in the form of an arch or C, rectangle, or other folded shape. An important feature of the clamp shape is the ability to apply asymmetric deflection and consequent forces against the components to be clamped.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">There are a number of objects and advantages of this invention over existing clamping systems.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The tolerance in the height of the solar panel is no longer critical for proper clamping because the clamp's inherent flexibility allows height variations.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Unlike most solar clamps the pivot point for tightening is located above and outside the clamp tightening bolt. This means that as bolt tightening proceeds the clamp rotates towards the panel instead of away from it insuring positive contact.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">When clamping two panels with this clamp the first panel can be secured by initial tightening and it still allows the second panel to be inserted under the clamp flange to be tightened.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Because of its flexibility the clamp's bearing surface adjusts angularly to the panel surface angle and provides more uniform loading&#x2014;compared with Z-clamps that provide little or no flexibility and instead create corner stress concentrations.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The flexible configuration of the clamp allows it to act as a stiff hinge and provide a relatively constant force to the panel even when temperature changes or stresses cause slight thickness changes in the solar panel.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The flexible clamp when formed into an undulating profile allows it to be used in tight spaces and still retain its flexibility.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The flexible clamp properties allow it to withstand the dynamic loads and vibrations associated with solar panels subject to high wind loads and solar tracking.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Further objects and advantages will become apparent from a consideration of the drawings and ensuing description.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In accordance with the present invention a flexible height adjustable clamp comprises flat horizontal surfaces on the top and bottom with flexible material between the two flat surfaces joining them together. The joining point to each horizontal surface is asymmetrically positioned to effect angular and downward movement of the top flat surface relative to the bottom flat surface. A hole through the top and bottom surfaces allows for a bolt to be installed and provide the force necessary to effect the downward and angular movement clamping the panels in place.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">A flexible height-adjustable clamp for clamping a solar panel to a support structure or base, with flat surfaces on the upper and lower parts of the clamp, the upper section clamping on the panels; and the lower section mounting against the base; with a hole through both flat surfaces for bolting a connector through the surfaces to secure the clamp and panel to the supporting structure; and a flexible section connecting the two surfaces in the form of an arc or folded section; with mechanical stops to allow positioning to against said panel. The flexible section may be asymmetrically positioned to cause the clamp to apply a horizontal force as well as vertical force against the panel. The bolt may be positioned between the flex section and the panel. The flex section may be sufficiently stiff to provide reaction loading of the panel to the required force. The clamping section may have serrations on the clamping surface to prevent slippage. The clamp may be formed by extrusion. The clamp may be forged. The clamp may be manufactured in more than one part. The flex section may be configured in a narrow profile to fit between two panels and clamp said panels using a single bolt connection. The flex section may be asymmetrically positioned to allow initial clamping of the first panel before said clamp secures the second panel. The flex section may be sufficiently flexible to allow for greater height adjustability. The flex section may be in the form of a circle, oval, rectangle, or folded pattern.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> shows a side view of the prior art clamps in their assembled positions</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> shows a perspective view of the prior art clamps in their assembled positions</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a view of the prior art T-clamp detail</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a view of the prior art Z-clamp detail</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a view of the prior art L-clamp detail</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> shows a side view of the flexible clamps in their assembled positions</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref> shows a perspective view of the flexible clamps in their assembled positions</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</figref> shows a side view of the flexible C-clamp assembly detail</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5D</figref> shows a side view of the flexible folding clamp assembly detail</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref> shows a perspective view of the flexible C-clamp</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref> shows a side view of the flexible C-clamp</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6C</figref> shows a detail view of the flexible C-clamp serrated surface</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</figref> shows a perspective view of the flexible folded clamp</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</figref> shows a side view of the flexible folded clamp</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7C</figref> shows a detail view of the flexible folded clamp serrated surface</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</figref> shows a view of the flexible folded clamp prior to tightening</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8B</figref> shows a view of the flexible folded clamp clamping the first panel</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8C</figref> shows a view of the flexible folded clamp clamping both panels</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DRAWINGS</heading>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">Reference Numerals</heading>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00001" num="00001">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="77pt" align="right"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="140pt" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>10</entry>
<entry>T-clamp</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>20</entry>
<entry>Z-clamp</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>30</entry>
<entry>L-clamp</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>70</entry>
<entry>mounting bolt</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>80</entry>
<entry>mounting base</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>90</entry>
<entry>solar panel</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>100</entry>
<entry>flexible C-clamp</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>110</entry>
<entry>C-clamp mounting base</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>120</entry>
<entry>C-clamp arched wall</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>130</entry>
<entry>C-clamp clamping section</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>140</entry>
<entry>C-clamp bolt hole</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>150</entry>
<entry>C-clamp mechanical stop</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>160</entry>
<entry>C-clamp serrated surface</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>200</entry>
<entry>flexible folded clamp</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>210</entry>
<entry>folded clamp mounting base</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>220</entry>
<entry>folded clamp folded wall</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>230</entry>
<entry>folded clamp clamping section</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>240</entry>
<entry>folded clamp bolt hole</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>250</entry>
<entry>folded clamp mechanical stop</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>260</entry>
<entry>folded clamp serrated surface</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The mounting method and use of the flexible clamps is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A</figref>, <b>5</b>B, <b>5</b>C, and <b>5</b>D. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A and 5B</figref> the flexible C-clamp <b>100</b> is shown mounted on the panel <b>90</b> outside edges and the flexible folded clamp <b>200</b> is shown between two said panels. Because of the available space on the outside edges of said panels there is sufficient space for the C-clamps to be used for clamping. Said C-clamps have a relatively stiff arched wall <b>120</b> to provide sufficient clamping force to hold said panels in place. The available space between the panels is smaller and therefore a different configuration of clamp is required. In this case the panels are clamped with said flexible folded clamps since they have a smaller width profile. Said folded clamps have a thinner folded wall <b>220</b> to allow sufficient flexibility for mounting said panels. There is less strength necessary in the folded wall because said panel edges react against the forces exerted by the mounting bolt <b>70</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The details of this flexible C-clamp are illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6A</figref>, <b>6</b>B, and <b>6</b>C. The bottom or base <b>110</b> of the clamp is flat and mounts directly to the strut mounting base <b>80</b> that also supports the panel. The curved wall <b>120</b> provides the flexing portion of the clamp. In the embodiment shown said curve wall is typically a thin metal that is 1 to 3 mm thick. The thicker clamping section <b>130</b> is used to clamp down against the top of said panel. The mounting hole <b>40</b> is used to bolt the clamp with the panel under the clamping section to the strut. The panel stop <b>50</b> is used to prevent the clamp from slipping too far onto one of the panels. Other embodiments may be either thinner or thicker depending on the gripping height required to match the particular solar panel. Thicker walls may be required for taller clamps and thinner walls required for shorter clamps. The wall thickness is further dependent on the material used. Aluminum flexes more easily and allows use of a thicker wall than steel. Plastic and composites may also be used for this particular embodiment dependent on the forces required.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The arched shape allows the C-clamp to lean toward the panel insuring positive engagement. Other asymmetric shapes also provide the same function including rectangular C shapes and other polygonal C shapes. As the clamp leans toward the panel while tightening, the mechanical stop <b>50</b> provides positive positioning of the C-clamp. Serrations <b>60</b> in the gripping portion of the clamp minimize the possibility of slippage between the panel and the clamp.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows the clamp bolted to the mounting base <b>80</b> supported by the arched wall <b>120</b> on the outside and supported by the panel edge on the other side thereby clamping the panel against the mounting support. When the bolt is tightened the clamp pivots from the heel of its base <b>110</b>, through its arched wall and imparts a downward force on the panel and a horizontal force towards the panel causing a compressive horizontal force against the panel thereby preventing slip. The curved wall thickness is designed to impart the force necessary for the item that must be clamped. This particular force is dependent on the weight of the items being clamped in place, wind loads, and other static and dynamic loads that may be applied to the panel.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">A second embodiment of clamp is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>. In this particular embodiment the clamp is constructed in a folded form that allows it to fit between two adjacent panels and still maintain its flexibility. This particular embodiment is shown in the form of an E or S. The folded surfaces that are in the vertical position are the mechanical stops <b>250</b> that position the panels relative to the clamp as well as to each other. Bolt hole <b>240</b> passes directly through the top clamping surface <b>230</b>, folded surfaces <b>220</b>, and base <b>210</b> into the structural support. Other folded or undulating profiles are also possible for said mechanical stops as long as they maintain sufficient flexibility. The combinations are mainly dependent on the wall thickness, flexible section length, and materials used. In this embodiment there are two relatively thicker clamping surfaces <b>230</b> that clamp directly on top of the adjacent panel edge horizontal surfaces. Said clamping surfaces generally create a grip height to the bottom base <b>210</b> that is slightly taller than the panel so that the panel can easily slide under said clamping surfaces. The asymmetric connection from said clamping surfaces to the folded flex section <b>220</b> provides the functionality needed for sequential clamping of two adjacent panels. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows the assembly with the flexible E or S shaped clamp mounted to the support and clamped to the panels. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8A</figref>, <b>8</b>B, and <b>8</b>C illustrate the sequence of assembly for solar panels on an incline. The normal sequence consists of first positioning the clamp so that <b>220</b> to <b>230</b> joint is farthest away from the first panel to be clamped. The bolt <b>70</b> is then tightened which initially draws the open clamping section <b>230</b> against and towards the first panel, temporarily holding the first panel in position. The flanged face is tightened down against this first panel with the second clamping section face still raised to accept the second panel. The second adjacent panel is then slid under the second clamping section. The bolt connecting the flexible clamping section to the panel surface is then tightened causing the clamp to deflect downward onto the second panel surface. The clamp is then tightened to the required torque for securing both panels into position.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">For both of the embodiments described above the clamping mechanism utilizes an anchor nut that is mounted in the support structure or strut. This anchor nut is generally prevented from rotating therefore allowing the bolt to tighten into this restrained nut allowing the clamp to be forced against the support or strut. This anchor nut or strut nut typically slides in a slot within the strut or support where the panel is supported.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Thus the reader will see that the flexible clamp provides a highly reliable, labor saving, yet economical device that has a wide range of usage. While my above description contains many specificities these should not be construed as limitations on the scope of the invention, but rather as an exemplification of one preferred embodiment thereof. Many other variations are possible.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The clamping plate and flex section may be two separate components that are fitted together to function as a flexible clamp. For example the C shaped section can be a formed spring steel component that is fitted to the clamping flange. This allows more flexibility so that the same clamp can be used for clamping a wider variety of panel thicknesses.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">A further embodiment would incorporate the anchor nut that is typically mounted into the support strut as part of the clamp. This anchor nut can either be forged or extruded with the clamp or be subsequently attached after fabrication. In this particular case the clamp is slid into the strut with the nut sliding inside the strut housing.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Accordingly, the scope of the invention should be determined not by the embodiments illustrated, but by the appended claims and their legal equivalents.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>I claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A height-adjustable clamp for clamping a solar panel to a support structure, comprising:
<claim-text>a clamping section comprising:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a clamping surface formed with a through-hole;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first end; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second end opposite said first end along a longest edge of said clamping surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mounting base comprising;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a bottom surface formed with a through-hole;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a longest side perpendicular to said bottom surface and having an edge in common with said bottom surface, wherein said bottom surface and said clamping surface are separated by a distance greater than a thickness dimension of the solar panel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a panel stop extending from said clamping surface toward said mounting base said panel stop having a surface extending from said first end to said second end of said clamping section and said surface on said panel stop coplanar with said longest side of said mounting base; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a flexible arched wall joining said mounting base to said clamping section, said arched wall extending from said first end to said second end of said clamping section with said arched wall disposed outside a gap between said clamping surface and said mounting base, wherein said through-holes in said mounting base and said clamping section are unthreaded and aligned with one another for passage of a bolt through both through-holes.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The height-adjustable clamp of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said clamp is formed by extrusion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The height-adjustable clamp of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said clamp is forged.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The height-adjustable clamp of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said clamp is manufactured in more than one part.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. An apparatus for clamping more than one solar panel to a support structure, comprising:
<claim-text>a first clamp, comprising:
<claim-text>a clamping section comprising:
<claim-text>a clamping surface formed with a through-hole and a first gripping surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first end; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second end opposite said first end along a longest edge of said clamping surface;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mounting base comprising:
<claim-text>a bottom surface formed with a through-hole; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a longest side perpendicular to said bottom surface and having an edge in common with said bottom surface;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a panel stop extending from said clamping surface toward said mounting base, said panel stop having a surface extending from said first end to said second end of said clamping section and said surface on said panel stop coplanar with said longest side of said mounting base; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a flexible arched wall joining said mounting base to said clamping section, said arched wall extending from said first end to said second end of said clamping section with an outer surface of said arched wall disposed entirely outside a gap between said clamping surface and said mounting base,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said through-holes in said clamping section and said mounting base are unthreaded and aligned with one another; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second clamp for clamping two adjacent solar panels, comprising:
<claim-text>a clamping section comprising:
<claim-text>a clamping surface for clamping against the solar panel, said clamping surface formed with a through-hole and a first gripping surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first end; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second end opposite said first end of said clamping surface;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mounting base comprising:
<claim-text>a bottom surface formed with a through-hole; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a longest side having an edge in common with said bottom surface; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a flexible wall joining said mounting base to said clamping section, said flexible wall comprising a plurality of wall segments, each of said plurality of wall segments perpendicular to an adjacent wall segment and at least one of said plurality of wall segments having a surface coplanar with said longest side of said mounting base.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein said clamping section in said second clamp further comprises a second gripping surface, and when a bolt is passed through said through hole in said clamping section and through said through-hole in said mounting base and attached to the support structure, said first gripping surface holds one solar panel to the support structure before said second gripping surface contacts an adjacent solar panel.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
