<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624477-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624477</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13657663</doc-number>
<date>20121022</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2012 1 0087160</doc-number>
<date>20120329</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>313309</main-classification>
<further-classification>313336</further-classification>
<further-classification>313351</further-classification>
<further-classification>313495</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e61">Carbon nanotube field emitter</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0181893</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ousati Ashtiani</name>
<date>20100700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>313243</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>313309</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>313336</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>313351</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>313495</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>13</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>13</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130257262</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20131003</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liu</last-name>
<first-name>Peng</first-name>
<address>
<city>Beijing</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Fan</last-name>
<first-name>Shou-Shan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Beijing</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liu</last-name>
<first-name>Peng</first-name>
<address>
<city>Beijing</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Fan</last-name>
<first-name>Shou-Shan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Beijing</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Tsinghua University</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Beijing</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Patel</last-name>
<first-name>Vip</first-name>
<department>2889</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present application relates to a carbon nanotube field emitter. The carbon nanotube field emitter includes a carbon nanotube structure. The carbon nanotube structure includes a plurality of carbon nanotubes joined end-to-end by van der waals attractive force. The carbon nanotube structure has two joined portions, one portion is a triangle shaped carbon nanotube film, which is an electron emitting portion, the other portion is a carbon nanotube wire, which is a support portion.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="164.00mm" wi="302.26mm" file="US08624477-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="249.34mm" wi="120.57mm" file="US08624477-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="141.14mm" wi="144.36mm" file="US08624477-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="240.11mm" wi="145.20mm" file="US08624477-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="233.93mm" wi="95.59mm" file="US08624477-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="239.01mm" wi="87.46mm" file="US08624477-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="237.74mm" wi="103.21mm" file="US08624477-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="162.14mm" wi="162.81mm" file="US08624477-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="248.41mm" wi="95.50mm" file="US08624477-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="179.24mm" wi="148.84mm" file="US08624477-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="178.31mm" wi="151.81mm" file="US08624477-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="128.35mm" wi="138.01mm" file="US08624477-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="172.38mm" wi="153.67mm" file="US08624477-20140107-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="163.07mm" wi="155.28mm" file="US08624477-20140107-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims all benefits accruing under 35 U.S.C. &#xa7;119 from China Patent Application No. 201210087160.5, filed on Mar. 29, 2012 in the China Intellectual Property Office, the disclosure of which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present application relates to a field emitter, and particularly to a carbon nanotube based field emitter.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Discussion of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Many potential applications have been proposed for carbon nanotubes, including conductive and high-strength composites, energy storage and energy conversion devices, sensors, field emission displays, and nanometer-sized semiconductor devices.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">As the carbon nanotubes are used in field emitters, shielding effect between two adjacent carbon nanotubes makes only a few carbon nanotubes emit electrons. Therefore, an emission current density of the field emitter is very small. Improving an emission voltage of the field emitter is often used to improve the emission current density. But improving the emission voltage will damage an emission tip of the field emitter. The damage to emission tips further damages the entire field emitter. Therefore, how to solve the shielding effect between two adjacent carbon nanotubes is a problem in application of a carbon nanotube field emitter.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Moreover, the carbon nanotube field emitter includes an end that is opposite to the emission tip. A high strength of the end is required, in order to support the carbon nanotube field emitter. But the strength of the end of the carbon nanotube field emitter is not very high, affecting stability of emitting electrons, and limiting the widespread use of the carbon nanotube field emitter.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">What is needed, therefore, is to provide a carbon nanotube field emitter.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Many aspects of the embodiments can be better understood with references to the following drawings. The components in the drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the embodiments. Moreover, in the drawings, like reference numerals designate corresponding parts throughout the several views.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a flowchart of a first embodiment of a method for making a carbon nanotube field emitter.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a scanning electron microscope (SEM) image of a carbon nanotube film.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a flowchart of the first embodiment of another method for making the carbon nanotube field emitter.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a flowchart of a second embodiment of a method for making a carbon nanotube field emitter.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a flowchart of a second embodiment of another method for making a carbon nanotube field emitter.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flowchart of a third embodiment of a method for making a carbon nanotube field emitter.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows a scanning electron microscope (SEM) image of a carbon nanotube film including some carbon nanotube strings.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a flowchart of a fourth embodiment of a method for making a carbon nanotube field emitter.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a schematic view showing a structure of first embodiment of the carbon nanotube field emitter.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a schematic view showing another structure of first embodiment of the carbon nanotube field emitter.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is an optical microscope image of one embodiment of the carbon nanotube field emitter.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a FN curve of one embodiment of the carbon nanotube field emitter.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a current-voltage curve of one embodiment of the carbon nanotube field emitter.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The disclosure is illustrated by way of example and not by way of limitation in the figures of the accompanying drawings in which like references indicate similar elements. It should be noted that references to &#x201c;an&#x201d; or &#x201c;one&#x201d; embodiment in this disclosure are not necessarily to the same embodiment, and such references mean at least one.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a method for making a carbon nanotube field emitter <b>30</b> of the first embodiment includes following steps:</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">S<b>1</b>, providing a carbon nanotube array <b>12</b> located on a surface of a substrate <b>10</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">S<b>2</b>, selecting some carbon nanotube segments of the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b> and pulling out a carbon nanotube film from the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b> by a drawing tool <b>18</b>, wherein the carbon nanotube film includes a triangle region <b>14</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">S<b>3</b>, treating a portion of the carbon nanotube film with an organic solvent <b>24</b> to form a carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b>, wherein the carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b> includes a vertex of the triangle region <b>14</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">S<b>4</b>, cutting off the triangle region <b>14</b> from the carbon nanotube film by a laser beam along a cutting line AB, wherein a distance between the vertex of the triangle region <b>14</b> and the cutting line AB can be in a range from about 10 microns to about 5 millimeters, to obtain a fan-shaped or triangular carbon nanotube field emitter <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In step S<b>1</b>, the substrate <b>10</b> can be a substantially flat and smooth silicon substrate with a diameter of 4 inches, wherein the silicon substrate can be a P-type silicon wafer, an N-type silicon wafer or a silicon wafer formed with an oxidized layer thereon. In the first embodiment, a 4-inch, P-type silicon wafer is used as the substrate <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The carbon nanotube array can be a super-aligned array formed by a chemical vapor deposition method. The chemical vapor deposition method for making the carbon nanotube array generally includes the following steps:</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">S<b>11</b>, forming a catalyst layer on the substrate, wherein the catalyst layer is made of a material selected from the group consisting of iron (Fe), cobalt (Co), nickel (Ni), and an alloy thereof. In the first embodiment, the catalyst layer is Fe;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">S<b>12</b>, annealing the substrate with the catalyst layer in air at a temperature in a range from 700&#xb0; C. to 900&#xb0; C. for about 30 minutes to about 90 minutes;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">S<b>13</b>, providing a carbon source gas at high temperature to a furnace for about 5 minutes to about 30 minutes to grow the carbon nanotube array on the substrate, wherein the substrate has been put in the furnace which has been heated to a temperature of 400&#xb0; C.-740&#xb0; C. and is filled with a protective gas. The carbon source gas can be, e.g., methane, ethylene, propylene, acetylene, methanol, ethanol, or a mixture thereof. The protective gas can, preferably, be made up of at least one of nitrogen (N2), ammonia (NH3), and a noble gas in the present embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The growth rate of the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b> needs to be high, while the deposition rate of amorphous carbon needs to be low. The growth rate of carbon nanotube array <b>12</b> is proportional to a difference between the furnace temperature and the local temperature of the catalyst. Generally, the difference in the temperatures is controlled to be at least 50&#xb0; C., in order to enhance the growth rate of the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b>. The deposition rate of amorphous carbons is proportional to the partial pressure of carbon source gas. In practice, the local temperature of the catalyst can be controlled by adjusting the flow rate of carbon source gas, and the furnace temperature can be directly controlled. The partial pressure of carbon source gas can be controlled by adjusting the ratio of the flow rates of the carbon source gas and the protecting gas. Typically, the partial pressure of the carbon source gas is no more than 0.2, and preferably no more than 0.1.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Moreover, the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b> formed under the above conditions is essentially free of impurities such as carbonaceous or residual catalyst particles.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In step S<b>2</b>, the carbon nanotube film is obtained by extracting a portion of the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b> by the substeps of:</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">S<b>21</b> selecting some carbon nanotube segments of the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b> having a determined width, and then using a drawing tool with the predetermined width to secure the end of the carbon nanotube segments of the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">S<b>22</b> pulling the drawing tool <b>18</b> away from the carbon nanotube at an even/uniform speed to make the carbon nanotube segments of the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b> separate from the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In step S<b>22</b>, the pulling direction can be substantially perpendicular to the growing direction of the carbon nanotube array. The drawing tool <b>18</b> can be a nipper, a clamp, an adhesive tape, and so on.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In step S<b>22</b>, during the extracting process, when the end of the carbon nanotube segments of the carbon nanotubes of the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b> is drawn out, other carbon nanotube segments are also drawn out in a manner that ends of a carbon nanotube is connected with ends of adjacent carbon nanotubes, by the help of the van der Waals attractive force between the ends of carbon nanotube segments. This characteristic of the carbon nanotubes ensures that a continuous carbon nanotube film can be formed.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In step S<b>22</b>, during the extracting process, a width of the carbon nanotube film increases gradually. In detail, the carbon nanotube segments selected by a clip as the drawing tool <b>18</b> is continuously drawn out, to obtain the carbon nanotube film. The width of the carbon nanotube film increases gradually because some carbon nanotube segments adjacent to the carbon nanotube segments are continuously drawn out due to the van der Waals attractive force. Therefore, a triangular part of the carbon nanotube film is first formed, wherein the carbon nanotube segments selected by the drawing tool <b>18</b> form a vertex of the triangular part of the carbon nanotube film. Then, a rectangular part of the carbon nanotube film is obtained, with continuous drawing. The carbon nanotube film includes the triangle region <b>14</b> and a rectangular region <b>13</b>. In one embodiment, the carbon nanotube film only includes the triangle region <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The carbon nanotube film can comprise or consist of a plurality of carbon nanotubes. In the carbon nanotube film, the overall aligned direction of a majority of carbon nanotubes is parallel to a surface of the carbon nanotube film. A majority of the carbon nanotubes in the rectangular region <b>13</b> are substantially aligned along the same direction in the carbon nanotube film. A majority of the carbon nanotubes in the triangle region <b>14</b> are radially arranged. Along the aligned direction of the majority of carbon nanotubes, each carbon nanotube is joined to adjacent carbon nanotubes end to end by van der Waals attractive force therebetween, whereby the carbon nanotube film is capable of being free-standing structure. There may be a minority of carbon nanotubes in the carbon nanotube film that are randomly aligned. However, the number of the randomly aligned carbon nanotubes is very small and does not affect the overall oriented alignment of the majority of carbon nanotubes in the carbon nanotube film. The majority of the carbon nanotubes in the rectangular region <b>13</b>, that are substantially aligned along the same direction may not be exactly straight, can be curved at a certain degree, are not exactly aligned along the overall aligned direction, and can deviate from the overall aligned direction by a certain degree. Therefore, partial contacts can exist between the juxtaposed carbon nanotubes in the majority of the carbon nanotubes aligned along the same direction in the rectangular region <b>13</b> of carbon nanotube film. The carbon nanotube film may include a plurality of successive and oriented carbon nanotube segments. The plurality of carbon nanotube segments are joined end to end by van der Waals attractive force. Each carbon nanotube segment includes a plurality of carbon nanotubes substantially parallel to each other, and the plurality of paralleled carbon nanotubes are in contact with each other and combined by van der Waals attractive force therebetween. Therefore, the carbon nanotube film includes a plurality of carbon nanotubes joined end-to-end by van der Waals attractive force. There can be clearances between adjacent and juxtaposed carbon nanotubes in the carbon nanotube film. A thickness of the carbon nanotube film at the thickest location can be in a range from about 0.5 nanometers to about 100 microns. In some embodiments, the thickness of the carbon nanotube film at the thickest location is in a range from about 0.5 nanometers to about 10 microns.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The term &#x201c;free-standing&#x201d; includes, but not limited to, a carbon nanotube film that does not have to be supported by a substrate. For example, a free-standing carbon nanotube film can sustain the weight of itself when it is hoisted by a portion thereof without any significant damage to its structural integrity. So, if the free-standing carbon nanotube film is placed between two separate supporters, a portion of the free-standing carbon nanotube film, not in contact with the two supporters, would be suspended between the two supporters and yet maintain film structural integrity. The free-standing carbon nanotube film is realized by the successive carbon nanotubes joined end to end by van der Waals attractive force.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The plurality of carbon nanotubes in the triangle region <b>14</b> of the carbon nanotube film define a fan-shaped divergence along directions from a position of the drawing tool <b>18</b> to the surrounding of the drawing tool <b>18</b>. The plurality of carbon nanotubes in the rectangular region <b>13</b> of the carbon nanotube film is oriented along a preferred orientation. The orientation of the plurality of carbon nanotubes in the rectangular region of the carbon nanotube film is parallel to the extracting direction as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In step S<b>3</b>, the portion of the carbon nanotube film closes to the drawing tool <b>18</b>, and the portion of the carbon nanotube film includes the carbon nanotube segments selected by the drawing tool <b>18</b>. A method for treating the portion of the carbon nanotube film with the organic solvent <b>24</b> can be selected according to need. In one embodiment, a first container <b>20</b> is located on upside of the carbon nanotube segments selected by the drawing tool <b>18</b>. The first container <b>20</b> fills with the organic solvent <b>24</b>. The organic solvent <b>24</b> can be ethanol, methanol, acetone, dichloroethane, chloroform, or the combinations thereof. In the first embodiment, the organic solvent <b>24</b> is ethanol. The first container <b>20</b> includes a tunnel <b>22</b> on its sidewall. The organic solvent <b>24</b> is dropped from the tunnel <b>22</b> to wet the vertex of the triangle region <b>14</b> of the carbon nanotube film. A second container <b>26</b> located on downside of the triangle region <b>14</b> of the carbon nanotube film is used to hold the organic solvent <b>24</b> from the tunnel <b>22</b>. The entire vertex of the triangle region <b>14</b> of the carbon nanotube film is soaked by the organic solvent <b>24</b>. After being soaked by the organic solvent <b>24</b>, the entire vertex of the triangle region <b>14</b> of the carbon nanotube film is shrunk into a carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b>, due to the action of the surface tension of the organic solvent <b>24</b>. The carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b> is connected to the triangle region <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The triangle region <b>14</b> of the carbon nanotube film includes a plurality of carbon nanotubes joined end-to-end by van der waals attractive force. The triangle region <b>14</b> includes an aggregated portion and a dispersed portion opposite to the aggregated portion. The carbon nanotubes at the aggregated portion are aggregated together to form the carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b>. The triangle region <b>14</b> of the carbon nanotube film has a fan-shaped divergence along a direction from the aggregated portion to the dispersed portion. The carbon nanotubes are radially arranged in the triangle region <b>14</b> and have a relatively larger interspace therebetween at the dispersed portion than at the aggregated portion.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b> has good mechanical strength and toughness. It is to be understood, the plurality of carbon nanotubes in the carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b> can be parallel to each other. A length of the carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b> cannot be too large, the length of the carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b> can be not more than 1 centimeter.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In step S<b>4</b>, in the process of cutting off the triangle region <b>14</b> from the carbon nanotube film, the carbon nanotube film can still be in the drawing period and joined with the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b>. In the lengthwise direction, one end of the carbon nanotube film is connected with the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b> by van der Waals attractive force, and the other end is held by the drawing tool <b>18</b>. The section of the carbon nanotube film between the drawing tool <b>18</b> and the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b> is suspended.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In the process of cutting off the triangle region <b>14</b> from the carbon nanotube film, the carbon nanotube film can also separate from the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b>. In the lengthwise direction, one end of the carbon nanotube film is supported by a support cylinder <b>15</b>, and the other end is held by the drawing tool <b>18</b>. The support cylinder <b>15</b> can be made to rotate/roll in place. The surface of the support cylinder <b>15</b> is relatively smooth but still exerts friction. A length of the support cylinder <b>15</b> is equal to or longer than the width of the carbon nanotube film. When contacting the surface of the support cylinder <b>15</b>, the width of the carbon nanotube film is not changed. The carbon nanotube film can contact the surface of the support cylinder <b>15</b> when the support cylinder <b>15</b> is arranged at a higher level than the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b>. The carbon nanotube film can also contact the bottom surface of the support cylinder <b>15</b> when the support cylinder <b>15</b> is at a lower level than the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b>. In the first embodiment, the axis direction of the support cylinder <b>15</b> is substantially parallel to the top surface of the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b> and substantially perpendicular to the pulling direction of the carbon nanotube film.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In the process of cutting off the triangle region <b>14</b> from the carbon nanotube film, the cutting line AB in the carbon nanotube film is suspended. The distance between the cutting line AB and the vertex of the triangle region <b>14</b> can be in a range from about 10 microns to about 5 millimeters. In the first embodiment, the distance between the cutting line AB and the vertex of the triangle region <b>14</b> is in a range from about 10 microns to about 1 millimeter. In one embodiment, the distance between the cutting line AB and the vertex of the triangle region <b>14</b> is 200 microns. The cutting line AB in the carbon nanotube film can be an arc line or a straight line. In one embodiment, the cutting line AB is an arc line as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In step S<b>4</b>, a laser beam is used to irradiate the carbon nanotube film along the cutting line AB, until the triangle region <b>14</b> is cut off from the carbon nanotube film. The laser beam has a power of about 3.6 to about 12 watts and a moving speed of about 1 to about 1000 mm/s. The laser beam can be a YAG laser. The laser beam has a wavelength of 1.06 microns and a bean spot diameter of 20 microns. In one embodiment, the moving speed of the laser beam is in a range from about 10 mm/s to about 90 mm/s.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">It is to be understood, step S<b>4</b> can also be carried out by fixing the laser beam and moving the carbon nanotube film by a computer program.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The length of the cutting line AB can be in a range from about 1 millimeter to about 10 millimeters. In one embodiment, the length of the cutting line AB is in a range from about 1 millimeter to about 5 millimeters.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">It is to be understood, at least two drawing tools <b>18</b> are used to select carbon nanotube segments such that at least two carbon nanotube films can be simultaneously pull out from one carbon nanotube array <b>12</b> along different directions. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, two drawing tools <b>18</b> are used to select carbon nanotube segments such that two carbon nanotube films are simultaneously pull out from one carbon nanotube array <b>12</b> along opposite direction.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, an embodiment of the method for making the carbon nanotube field emitter <b>30</b> is shown where the portion of the carbon nanotube film is twisted to form the carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b>, wherein the carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b> includes the vertex of the triangle region <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In the process of twisting the portion of the carbon nanotube film to form the carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b>, the carbon nanotube film is still being drawn and joined with the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b>. In the length direction, one end of the carbon nanotube film is connected with the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b> by van der Waals attractive force, other end is held by the drawing tool <b>18</b>. The substrate <b>10</b> can be fixed, while the drawing tool <b>18</b> is rotated, the carbon nanotube segments are twisted into the carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b>. The rotation direction is substantially perpendicular to the length direction of the carbon nanotube film. The drawing tool <b>18</b> can be fixed on a rotating machine to pull and rotate simultaneously.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">While rotating the drawing tool <b>18</b>, a pulling force is still applied on the carbon nanotube film, and the plurality of carbon nanotube segments is twisted. Further, by pulling the drawing tool <b>18</b>, more and more carbon nanotubes can be drawn from the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b> to extend the length of the carbon nanotube film. In the second embodiment, the value of twist force is in a range from about 0.00005 Newton to about 0.001 Newton.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, it is to be understood, the carbon nanotube film can be separated from the carbon nanotube array <b>12</b>. In the length direction, one end of the carbon nanotube film is supported by the support cylinder <b>15</b>, and the other end is held by the drawing tool <b>18</b>. The support cylinder <b>15</b> and the drawing tool <b>18</b> are simultaneously twisted along two reverse directions, to twist the portion of the carbon nanotube film into the carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">It is to be understood, the carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b> formed by twisting the portion of the carbon nanotube film includes a plurality of carbon nanotubes helically oriented around an axial direction of the carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b>. Therefore, the carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b> has a larger mechanical strength.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, an embodiment of the method for making the carbon nanotube field emitter <b>30</b> is shown where before cutting off the triangle region <b>14</b> from the carbon nanotube film, the triangle region <b>14</b> is treated to a plurality of carbon nanotube strings <b>34</b> with the organic solvent <b>24</b>. In this embodiment, the carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b> is formed by shrinking the portion of the carbon nanotube film with the organic solvent <b>24</b>. In detail, the triangle region <b>14</b> is soaked by sprinkling the organic solvent <b>24</b>, and some adjacent carbon nanotubes in the triangle region <b>14</b> would be bundled together to form a carbon nanotube string <b>34</b>, due to the action of the surface tension of the organic solvent <b>24</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows a scanning electron microscope image of a carbon nanotube film including some carbon nanotube strings. This is the result of carbon nanotube film that has been treated with the organic solvent <b>24</b> to form some carbon nanotube strings. In one aspect, due to the decrease of the specific surface area via bundling, the mechanical strength and toughness of the triangle region <b>14</b> treated with the organic solvent <b>24</b> are increased, the coefficient of friction of the triangle region <b>14</b> treated with the organic solvent <b>24</b> is reduced. In the other aspect, the sticky property of the triangle region <b>14</b> treated with the organic solvent <b>24</b> is reduced. Therefore, the triangle region <b>14</b> is treated into a plurality of carbon nanotube strings <b>34</b>. One end of the plurality of carbon nanotube strings <b>34</b> is aggregated together and joined with the carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b>. The other end of the plurality of carbon nanotube strings <b>34</b> has a fan-shaped divergence. The carbon nanotube strings <b>34</b> are wire-like structures within the film. Each of the plurality of carbon nanotube strings <b>34</b> includes a plurality of carbon nanotubes joined end-to-end by van der Waals attractive force. The plurality of carbon nanotubes in each of the carbon nanotube strings <b>34</b> is parallel to an axis of each of the carbon nanotube strings <b>34</b>. There is a larger distance between two adjacent carbon nanotube strings <b>34</b>, further reducing the shielding effect between two adjacent carbon nanotube strings <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, an embodiment of the method for making the carbon nanotube field emitter <b>30</b> is shown where before cutting off the triangle region <b>14</b> from the carbon nanotube film, the triangle region <b>14</b> is treated to a plurality of carbon nanotube strings <b>34</b> with the organic solvent <b>24</b>. In this embodiment, the carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b> is formed by twisting the portion of the carbon nanotube film. A method of triangle region <b>14</b> treated to a plurality of carbon nanotube strings <b>34</b> with the organic solvent <b>24</b> is described in above paragraph.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</figref>, the carbon nanotube field emitter <b>30</b> includes a carbon nanotube structure including a plurality of carbon nanotubes joined end-to-end by van der waals attractive force. The carbon nanotube structure has two joined portions. One portion is a triangle shaped carbon nanotube film, which is an electron emitting portion <b>304</b>. The other portion is a carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b>, which is a support portion <b>302</b> of the carbon nanotube field emitter <b>30</b>. The triangle shaped carbon nanotube film has an aggregated portion <b>3042</b> and a dispersed portion <b>3044</b>. The triangle shaped carbon nanotube film has a fan-shaped divergence along a direction from the aggregated portion <b>3042</b> to the dispersed portion <b>3044</b>. The plurality of carbon nanotubes is aggregated together in the aggregated portion <b>3042</b> and adjacent to the carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b> of the support portion <b>302</b>. The plurality of carbon nanotubes is radially arranged in the triangle shaped carbon nanotube film and has a relatively larger interspace therebetween in the dispersed portion <b>3044</b> than in the aggregated portion <b>3042</b>. The end of the plurality of carbon nanotubes in the dispersed portion <b>3044</b> of the triangle shaped carbon nanotube film are a plurality of electron emitting tips <b>306</b> of the electron emitting portion <b>304</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">A distance between two adjacent carbon nanotubes increases gradually along a direction from the aggregated portion <b>3042</b> to the dispersed portion <b>3044</b>, to reduce a shielding effect between two adjacent carbon nanotubes and improve an emission current density of the carbon nanotube field emitter <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b> is formed by twisting a portion of the carbon nanotube film or shrinking a portion of the carbon nanotube film with the organic solvent <b>24</b>. The carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b> has good mechanical strength and bears larger field strength, to support entire carbon nanotube field emitter <b>30</b>. Moreover, the electron emitting portion <b>304</b> has a free-standing structure, improving strength of entire carbon nanotube field emitter <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The plurality of carbon nanotubes in the carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b> can be parallel to each other. In other embodiments, the plurality of carbon nanotubes in the carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b> can be helically oriented around the axial direction of the carbon nanotube wire <b>16</b>. A connection line of the plurality of electron emitting tips <b>306</b> is an arc line as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>. The connection line of the plurality of electron emitting tips <b>306</b> is a straight line as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>. An optical microscope image of the carbon nanotube field emitter <b>30</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, the carbon nanotube field emitter <b>30</b> has good field emission property. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, when an emission voltage of the carbon nanotube field emitter <b>30</b> is 800 volts, an emission current of the carbon nanotube field emitter <b>30</b> is 2 milliamperes. Therefore, the carbon nanotube field emitter <b>30</b> has a larger emission current density.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">It is to be understood that the above-described embodiment is intended to illustrate rather than limit the disclosure. Variations may be made to the embodiment without departing from the spirit of the disclosure as claimed. The above-described embodiments are intended to illustrate the scope of the disclosure and not restricted to the scope of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">It is also to be understood that the above description and the claims drawn to a method may include some indication in reference to certain steps. However, the indication used is only to be viewed for identification purposes and not as a suggestion as to an order for the steps.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A carbon nanotube field emitter, comprising:
<claim-text>a carbon nanotube structure including a plurality of carbon nanotubes joined end-to-end by van der waals attractive force;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the carbon nanotube structure comprises an electron emitting portion and a support portion, the electron emitting portion is a triangle shaped carbon nanotube film, the support portion is a carbon nanotube wire.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The carbon nanotube field emitter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the triangle shaped carbon nanotube film comprises an aggregated portion and a dispersed portion, the triangle shaped carbon nanotube film has a fan-shaped divergence along a direction from the aggregated portion to the dispersed portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The carbon nanotube field emitter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of carbon nanotubes is aggregated together in the aggregated portion and adjacent to the carbon nanotube wire of the support portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The carbon nanotube field emitter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of carbon nanotubes has a relatively larger interspace therebetween in the dispersed portion than in the aggregated portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The carbon nanotube field emitter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the end of the plurality of carbon nanotubes in the dispersed portion of the triangle shaped carbon nantube film are a plurality of electron emitting tips of the electron emitting portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The carbon nanotube field emitter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein a connection line of the plurality of electron emitting tips is an arc line.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The carbon nanotube field emitter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein a connection line of the plurality of electron emitting tips is a straight line.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The carbon nanotube field emitter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein a distance between two adjacent carbon nanotubes increases gradually along a direction from the aggregated portion to the dispersed portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The carbon nanotube field emitter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of carbon nanotubes is radially arranged in the triangle shaped carbon nanotube film.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The carbon nanotube field emitter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of carbon nanotubes in the carbon nanotube wire is parallel to an axis of the carbon nanotube wire.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The carbon nanotube field emitter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of carbon nanotubes in the carbon nanotube wire is helically oriented around an axial direction of the carbon nanotube wire.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The carbon nanotube field emitter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the electron emitting portion has a free-standing structure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The carbon nanotube field emitter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a length of the support portion is less than or equal to 1 centimeter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The carbon nanotube field emitter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein a distance between the plurality of electron emitting tips and the aggregated portion is in a range from about 10 microns to about 5 millimeters.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The carbon nanotube field emitter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein when an emission voltage of the carbon nanotube field emitter is 800 volts, an emission current of the carbon nanotube field emitter is 2 milliamperes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A carbon nanotube field emitter, comprising:
<claim-text>a carbon nanotube structure including a plurality of carbon nanotubes joined end-to-end by van der waals attractive force;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the carbon nanotube structure comprises an electron emitting portion and a support portion, the electron emitting portion is a triangle shaped carbon nanotube film, the support portion is a carbon nanotube wire;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the triangle shaped carbon nanotube film comprises an aggregated portion and a dispersed portion, the triangle shaped carbon nanotube film has a fan-shaped divergence along a direction from the aggregated portion to the dispersed portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The carbon nanotube field emitter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of carbon nanotubes is aggregated together in the aggregated portion and adjacent to the carbon nanotube wire of the support portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The carbon nanotube field emitter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of carbon nanotubes is radially arranged in the triangle shaped carbon nanotube film and has a relatively larger interspace therebetween in the dispersed portion than in the aggregated portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The carbon nanotube field emitter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of carbon nanotubes in the carbon nanotube wire is parallel to an axis of the carbon nanotube wire.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The carbon nanotube field emitter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of carbon nanotubes in the carbon nanotube wire is helically oriented around an axial direction of the carbon nanotube wire.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
