<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622531-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622531</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13615939</doc-number>
<date>20120914</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>2</main-group>
<subgroup>175</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 86</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Ink tank having a single gasket</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5877794</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Takagi</name>
<date>19990300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347 87</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5949458</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Studholme</name>
<date>19990900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347 86</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6234619</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Kiritake</name>
<date>20010500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347 87</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6290345</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Sasaki et al.</name>
<date>20010900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347 86</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6761441</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Lui</name>
<date>20040700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347 86</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6834945</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Ishizawa et al.</name>
<date>20041200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347 86</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7905572</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Anderson et al.</name>
<date>20110300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347 49</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8052267</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Amesbury</name>
<date>20111100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8066363</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Greer et al.</name>
<date>20111100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>16</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 85</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 86</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 87</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 93</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>10</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hochreiter</last-name>
<first-name>Eric Peschan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Rochester</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hensel</last-name>
<first-name>Donald Steven</first-name>
<address>
<city>Rochester</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hochreiter</last-name>
<first-name>Eric Peschan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Rochester</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hensel</last-name>
<first-name>Donald Steven</first-name>
<address>
<city>Rochester</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Watkins</last-name>
<first-name>Peyton C.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Eastman Kodak Company</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Rochester</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Vo</last-name>
<first-name>Anh T. N.</first-name>
<department>2861</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An ink tank includes a free-ink chamber; an ink supply port extending from the tank body, which ink supply port permits passage of ink from the free-ink chamber; a filter disposed in the ink supply port and having a first surface facing the free-ink chamber and a second surface opposite the first surface; a wick disposed in the ink supply port adjacent to the second surface of the filter and downstream of the filter; and a single gasket disposed in the ink supply port adjacent to and downstream of the wick.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="154.43mm" wi="166.37mm" file="US08622531-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="206.16mm" wi="158.41mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622531-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="189.91mm" wi="192.36mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622531-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="203.28mm" wi="167.22mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622531-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="263.06mm" wi="127.25mm" file="US08622531-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="193.04mm" wi="180.68mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622531-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="143.93mm" wi="141.05mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622531-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="223.10mm" wi="179.24mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622531-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention generally relates to free-ink tanks for off-axis printers and more particularly to passing ink from the free-ink tank to the printhead using a select arrangement of a filter, wick and a single gasket.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Inkjet printing systems can be either an on-axis or off-axis printer. In on-axis printing, printheads include inlet ports for receiving ink from one or more ink tanks. The printhead includes arrays of drop ejectors that receive the ink from the inlet ports and that are controlled to make marks of particular sizes, colors, or densities in particular locations on the recording medium in order to print the desired image. In some types of inkjet printing systems the array(s) of dot forming elements extends across the width of the page, and the image can be printed one line at a time, as the recording medium is moved relative to the printhead. Alternatively, in a carriage printing system (whether for desktop printers, large area plotters, etc.) the printhead or printheads are mounted on a carriage that is moved past the recording medium in a carriage scan direction as the dot forming elements are actuated to make a swath of dots. At the end of the swath, the carriage is stopped, printing is temporarily halted and the recording medium is advanced. Then another swath is printed, so that the image is formed swath by swath.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">An inkjet drop ejector includes a nozzle and a drop forming mechanism (such as a resistive heater for thermal inkjet, or a piezoelectric device for piezoelectric inkjet) in order to generate pressure within an ink-filled chamber and eject ink from the nozzle. In page-width inkjet printers, as well as in carriage inkjet printers, the printhead and the recording medium are moved relative to one another as drops are ejected in order to form the image.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">An ink supply can be permanently attached to a printhead, or an ink supply can be replace-ably connected to and disconnected from a printhead. Unlike printheads having permanently attached ink supplies, the printhead having replaceable ink tanks does not need to be discarded for a replaceable ink supply when the ink supply is depleted, so the running costs of the printer are lower for replaceable ink supplies. Ink tanks containing ink are installed into the printhead for supplying the ink needed for printing. Some types of ink tanks include an outlet port having a flange that contains a wick for permitting ink to pass to an inlet port of the printhead by capillary action. The inks tanks are manually mounted into a holding receptacle of the printhead by a pivoting, inwardly and downwardly manual force of the user. Some types of printhead include a flat gasket located on a floor of the holding receptacle, and a bottom of the flange of the outlet port of the ink tank is forced against the flat gasket when the ink tank is installed. Although such a sealing configuration works well in many applications, in some applications sealing against a flat gasket on the floor of the holding receptacle can require excessive installation force.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In an off-axis printing system, the printhead is substantially similar except that there is a primary ink supply and a secondary ink supply that are connected for supplying the ink for printing. The primary ink supply is rigidly mounted on the printer so that it remains stationary, and a secondary ink supply is mounted on the carriage. Ink is transferred from the primary ink supply to the secondary ink supply as needed. In this way, the amount of ink that is moved by the carriage is kept low (so that forces during carriage acceleration and deceleration can be acceptably low) and the user does not need to replace the ink very frequently.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">To refill the secondary ink supply from the primary ink supply, flexible tubing is used, or alternatively the secondary ink supply can be moved near the primary ink supply on an as-needed basis and ink can be transferred to the secondary ink supply. Similar to the on-axis ink tanks, some types of secondary ink supplies include an outlet port having a flange that contains a wick that facilitates ink transfer to the printhead. A replaceable secondary ink supply for an off-axis printing system will be referred to herein as an ink tank, i.e. the same terminology used for the replaceable ink supply for an on-axis printing system.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In both on-axis and off-axis printing systems having replaceable ink supplies, the ink tanks (secondary ink supply for the off-axis) need to be installed. In both cases and particularly for the off-axis printing system, the ink tank can even be removed and replaced for maintenance.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">U.S. Pat. No. 8,066,363 discloses an apparatus for securing an ink tank into a printhead. FIGS. 4a and 4b of U.S. Pat. No. 8,066,363 disclose three single gaskets 34, 45 and 47 and a retainer 30 among other things for securing the ink tank into the printhead. It is readily apparent that this apparatus is complex in design and is prone to failure due to the numerous interconnecting parts.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Consequently, a need exists for securing an ink tank to a printhead with low installation force by an apparatus that is simple in design and reliable over time. The present invention provides such an ink tank that meets this need.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The present invention is directed to overcoming one or more of the problems set forth above. Briefly summarized, according to one aspect of the invention, the invention resides in an ink tank comprising: a free-ink chamber; an ink supply port extending from the tank body, which ink supply port permits passage of ink from the free-ink chamber; a filter disposed in the ink supply port and having a first surface facing the free-ink chamber and a second surface opposite the first surface; a wick disposed in the ink supply port adjacent to the second surface of the filter and downstream of the filter; and a single gasket disposed in the ink supply port adjacent to and downstream of the wick.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">These and other objects, features, and advantages of the present invention will become apparent to those skilled in the art upon a reading of the following detailed description when taken in conjunction with the drawings wherein there is shown and described an illustrative embodiment of the invention.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">ADVANTAGEOUS EFFECT OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The present invention has the advantages of low installation force of the ink tank or secondary ink supply, using a seal that is simple in design and reliable over time.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The above and other objects, features, and advantages of the present invention will become more apparent when taken in conjunction with the following description and drawings wherein identical reference numerals have been used, where possible, to designate identical features that are common to the figures.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">While the specification concludes with claims particularly pointing out and distinctly claiming the subject matter of the present invention, it is believed that the invention will be better understood from the following description when taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective of an interior portion of an off-axis printer;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective of a free ink tank of the present invention having several components shown in their non-installed state;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective of the ink tank of the present invention having the components shown in their installed state;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a perspective of an exterior portion of the single gasket of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective of an interior portion of the single gasket of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a perspective of an exterior portion of a second embodiment of the single gasket of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a perspective of an interior portion of the second embodiment of the single gasket of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a perspective of a holding receptacle for the ink tank of the present invention having the ink tank removed for illustrating other components;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a perspective of the wick installed into the single gasket; and</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a side section view in cross section of the ink tank of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Before turning to the drawings, a brief definition of some of the terms used herein will be defined. As used herein, &#x201c;downstream&#x201d; means in the direction of fluid flow (ink in the present invention) and &#x201c;upstream&#x201d; means in the direction opposite of the fluid flow.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective of an interior portion of an off-axis printer <b>100</b> according to an embodiment of the present invention. Although ink is shown in the preferred embodiment, any liquid is suitable for the present invention. An inkjet printhead <b>105</b> is disposed on a carriage <b>110</b> and includes at least one nozzle array (not visible from the view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) which directs ink droplets onto a recording medium <b>115</b>. A primary ink supply <b>120</b> is rigidly mounted on a support base <b>125</b>. The carriage <b>110</b> moves the inkjet printhead <b>105</b> back and forth across a print region <b>130</b> so that an image (such as letters &#x201c;Eric&#x201d; <b>103</b>) can be printed on the recording medium <b>115</b>. At least one pressure-regulated secondary ink supply <b>150</b> is mounted on the inkjet printhead <b>105</b> which moves in conjunction with the printhead <b>105</b>. In this embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the primary ink supply <b>120</b> includes four ink sources, each having a tubing connector <b>145</b>, although the number of ink sources can vary depending on the particular design. The tubing connectors <b>145</b> extend inside the primary ink supplies <b>120</b> and can extend substantially to the bottom of primary ink supply <b>120</b> so that ink can continue to be withdrawn as it is depleted. Alternatively, in other configurations (not shown) tubing connectors <b>145</b> can be located near the bottom of primary ink supply <b>120</b>, preferably when the primary ink supply <b>120</b> is located above a secondary ink supply <b>150</b> permitting gravity to transport the fluid. In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a pump (not shown) is enclosed within the primary ink supply <b>120</b> for pumping the ink since the location of the primary ink supply <b>120</b> (at or below the elevation of its destination, secondary ink supplies <b>150</b>) does not lend itself to gravitational flow.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Four secondary ink supplies <b>150</b> (e.g. cyan, magenta, yellow and black inks) each include a conduit <b>155</b> and are mounted on the carriage <b>110</b> via the inkjet printhead <b>105</b> for supplying ink to the inkjet printhead <b>105</b> so that the carriage <b>110</b> moves the secondary ink supplies <b>150</b> as well as the inkjet printhead <b>105</b>. As ink is used during printing and maintenance processes, ink is passed from the primary ink supply <b>120</b> through a flexible tubing <b>160</b>, to the conduit <b>155</b> and eventually into the secondary ink supplies <b>150</b> for replenishing the secondary ink supplies <b>150</b>. It is noted for clarity that only one piece of the flexible tubing <b>160</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> so as not to obscure other features. Secondary ink supplies <b>150</b> can be provided as discrete ink supplies, or two or more ink supplies can be bundled together as a multi-chamber ink tank. Secondary ink supplies <b>150</b> are preferably free-ink tanks, which means an interior portion of the free-ink tank contains only ink and is free of any absorbent material that functions to control flow as is well understood in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">A pressure regulator <b>165</b> is disposed extending into the secondary ink supply <b>150</b> for regulating the ink back pressure required by the ejector nozzles and in particular for damping out pressure spikes that occur as the carriage <b>110</b> is moved back and forth during printing.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, there is shown a perspective view of a free-ink tank of the present invention. The free-ink tank <b>150</b> includes a free-ink chamber <b>158</b> for holding ink and an ink supply port <b>200</b> having a free-ink chamber end <b>210</b> extending from the free-ink chamber <b>158</b> and an outlet end <b>220</b> opposite the free-ink chamber end <b>210</b>. The ink supply port <b>200</b> permits passage of ink from the free-ink chamber <b>158</b>. A filter <b>230</b> is disposed in the ink supply port <b>200</b> and having a first surface <b>240</b> facing the free-ink chamber <b>158</b> when installed in the ink supply port <b>200</b> and a second surface <b>250</b> opposite the first surface and facing downstream. A wick <b>260</b> is disposed in the ink supply port <b>200</b> adjacent to the second surface <b>250</b> of the filter <b>230</b> and downstream of the filter <b>230</b>. A single gasket <b>270</b> is disposed in the ink supply port <b>200</b> adjacent to and downstream of the wick <b>260</b>. As used herein, &#x201c;single&#x201d; is used as commonly understood which is only one gasket, which is not in association or in combination with another gasket. It is noted for clarity that this is distinct from U.S. Pat. No. 8,066,363 which uses three individual interconnected gaskets and a retainer, which retainer the present invention does not include or need. The filter <b>230</b> is preferably a porous material that permits ink to flow there-through in a regulated manner and is preferably stainless steel having a plurality of holes or pores that permit ink flow.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, there is shown the filter <b>230</b> (not visible from this view), the wick <b>260</b> and single gasket <b>270</b> installed in the ink supply port <b>200</b>. It can be seen that the design of the present invention is simple in that the parts are few in number and snugly arranged.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, there is shown the single gasket <b>270</b> according to one embodiment of the present invention. The single gasket <b>270</b> includes an annular-shaped body <b>400</b> having an inner surface <b>410</b> that defines an ink passageway and an outer surface <b>420</b> having a bottom portion <b>430</b> that abuts a portion of the printhead standpipe when installed in a printhead. More specifically, the bottom portion <b>430</b> extends into and over a portion of the passageway for forming a relatively large area for permitting it to seat and seal against the standpipe <b>810</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>) more efficiently when installed. As best seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the inner surface <b>410</b> forms at one portion a substantially circular-shaped sleeve portion <b>440</b> as illustrated by the arrows, which is shaped to matingly receive the wick <b>260</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). A tapered portion <b>450</b> extends between the sleeve portion <b>440</b> and the substantially flat bottom portion <b>430</b>. The single gasket <b>270</b> functions to form an air-tight seal or substantially air-tight seal with the standpipe <b>810</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref>, in a second embodiment of the single gasket <b>270</b>, the single gasket <b>270</b> includes the same parts as the first embodiment except that: (1) the flat bottom portion <b>430</b> extends to lesser degree into the passageway as compared to the first embodiment so that a rim portion <b>600</b> fits over and around a top portion of the standpipe <b>810</b> when installed in the printhead; and (2) the bottom portion <b>430</b> is gradually tapered from the sleeve portion <b>440</b> to the rim portion <b>600</b> so that the tapered portion <b>450</b> of the first embodiment is not needed. As in the previous embodiment, the single gasket <b>270</b> functions to form an air-tight seal or substantially air-tight seal with the standpipe <b>810</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, a perspective of a printhead holding receptacle <b>800</b> for the free-ink ink tank <b>150</b> of the present invention is shown. The free-ink tank <b>150</b> is removed in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> so that the interconnection of the standpipe <b>810</b> with the single gasket <b>270</b> and wick <b>260</b> is seen more clearly. It is also noted that preferably a standpipe filter <b>820</b> is disposed in each standpipe <b>810</b> in addition to the ink tank filter <b>230</b> that is disposed in ink supply port <b>200</b> of free ink tank <b>150</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, there is shown a perspective of the wick <b>260</b> installed in the single gasket <b>270</b>. This illustrates the wick <b>260</b> fitting conformingly into the sleeve portion <b>440</b> of the single gasket <b>270</b> for preventing air leakage into the free-ink tank <b>150</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, there is shown a side view of the free-ink tank <b>150</b> of the present invention installed in the printhead holding receptacle <b>800</b>. In this view, the rim portion <b>600</b> of the single gasket <b>270</b> is disposed over and around a top portion of the standpipe <b>810</b>, which is the embodiment of the single gasket <b>270</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref>. In the single gasket embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, the single gasket <b>270</b> would seat firmly against a top portion of the standpipe <b>810</b> as opposed to over and around as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>. The wick <b>260</b> is disposed on the single gasket <b>270</b> and the filter <b>230</b> is disposed on the single gasket <b>270</b>. A printhead die <b>1000</b> is disposed on a bottom portion of the printhead holding receptacle <b>800</b> for permitting ink <b>1010</b> in the free-ink tank <b>150</b> to be dispensed downstream through the filter <b>230</b> and the wick <b>260</b>, into the standpipe <b>810</b> and eventually ejected by the printhead die <b>1000</b> onto a recording medium <b>115</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The invention has been described in detail with particular reference to certain preferred embodiments thereof, but it will be understood that variations and modifications can be effected within the spirit and scope of the invention.</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">PARTS LIST</heading>
<p id="p-0038" num="0000">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0037"><b>100</b> off-axis printer</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0002" num="0038"><b>103</b> Eric</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0003" num="0039"><b>105</b> inkjet printhead</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0004" num="0040"><b>110</b> carriage</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0005" num="0041"><b>115</b> recording medium</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0006" num="0042"><b>120</b> primary ink supply</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0007" num="0043"><b>125</b> support base</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0008" num="0044"><b>130</b> print region</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0009" num="0045"><b>145</b> tubing connector</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0010" num="0046"><b>150</b> secondary ink supply or free-ink tank</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0011" num="0047"><b>155</b> conduit</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0012" num="0048"><b>158</b> free-ink chamber</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0013" num="0049"><b>160</b> flexible tubing</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0014" num="0050"><b>165</b> pressure regulator</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0015" num="0051"><b>200</b> ink supply port</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0016" num="0052"><b>210</b> free-ink chamber end</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0017" num="0053"><b>220</b> outlet end</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0018" num="0054"><b>230</b> filter</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0019" num="0055"><b>240</b> first surface</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0020" num="0056"><b>250</b> second surface</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0021" num="0057"><b>260</b> wick</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0022" num="0058"><b>270</b> single gasket</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0023" num="0059"><b>400</b> annular-shaped body</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0024" num="0060"><b>410</b> inner surface</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0025" num="0061"><b>420</b> outer surface</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0026" num="0062"><b>430</b> bottom portion</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0027" num="0063"><b>440</b> sleeve portion</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0028" num="0064"><b>450</b> tapered portion</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0029" num="0065"><b>600</b> rim portion</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0030" num="0066"><b>800</b> holding receptacle</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0031" num="0067"><b>810</b> standpipe</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0032" num="0068"><b>820</b> filter</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0033" num="0069"><b>1000</b> printhead die</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0034" num="0070"><b>1010</b> ink</li>
</ul>
</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An ink tank comprising:
<claim-text>a free-ink chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an ink supply port extending from the free-ink chamber, which ink supply port permits passage of ink from the free-ink chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a filter disposed in the ink supply port and having a first surface facing the free-ink chamber and a second surface opposite the first surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a wick disposed in the ink supply port adjacent to the second surface of the filter and downstream of the filter; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a single gasket disposed in the ink supply port adjacent to and downstream of the wick; wherein the single gasket includes a sleeve having an inner surface and the wick fits inside and within the inner surface of the sleeve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The ink tank as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the filter is a porous material permitting ink to flow through.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The ink tank as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the filter is stainless steel having a plurality of holes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The ink tank as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the single gasket includes an annular-shaped body having an inner surface that defines a passageway for ink; wherein a portion of the inner surface engages at least a portion of a printhead standpipe when installed in a printhead.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The ink tank as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the single gasket includes a single gasket annular-shaped body having an inner surface that defines a hole for an ink passageway and an outer surface; wherein the outer surface abuts a portion of the printhead conduit when installed in a printhead.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The ink tank as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the single gasket includes a bottom portion for sealing to a standpipe.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The ink tank as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the inner surface of the sleeve is circular shaped and the wick includes a conforming shape for permitting the wick to rest inside and within the inner surface of the sleeve.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The ink tank as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the wick is a single wick.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The inkjet printer as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the single gasket includes a bottom portion for sealing to a standpipe.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. An inkjet printer comprising:
<claim-text>a printhead including a holding receptacle having a standpipe for receiving ink;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a carriage for moving the printhead across a print region;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a primary ink supply mounted on a support base of the printer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a secondary ink supply mounted in the holding receptacle of the printhead, the secondary ink supply including:
<claim-text>a free-ink chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an ink supply port extending from a tank body, which ink supply port permits passage of ink from the free-ink chamber to the standpipe in the holding receptacle of the printhead;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a filter disposed in the ink supply port and having a first surface facing the free-ink chamber and a second surface opposite the first surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a wick disposed in the ink supply port adjacent to the second surface of the filter and downstream of the filter; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a single gasket disposed in the ink supply port adjacent to and downstream of the wick, wherein the single gasket seals against the standpipe and includes a sleeve having an inner surface and the wick fits inside and within the inner surface of the sleeve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The inkjet printer as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the inner surface of the sleeve is circular shaped and the wick includes a conforming shape for permitting the wick to rest inside and within the inner surface of the sleeve.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The inkjet printer as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the wick is a single wick.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The inkjet printer as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the filter is a porous material permitting ink to flow through.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The inkjet printer tank as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the filter is stainless steel having a plurality of holes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The inkjet printer as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the single gasket includes an annular-shaped body having an inner surface that defines a passageway for ink; wherein a portion of the inner surface engages at least a portion of a printhead standpipe when installed in a printhead.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The inkjet printer as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the single gasket includes a single gasket annular-shaped body having an inner surface that defines a hole for an ink passageway and an outer surface; wherein the outer surface abuts a portion of the printhead conduit when installed in a printhead.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
