<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624425-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624425</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13087393</doc-number>
<date>20110415</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2010 1 0602243</doc-number>
<date>20101221</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>478</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>307  6</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Voltage adjustment system</invention-title>
<number-of-claims>17</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>307  6</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120153925</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120621</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Feng</last-name>
<first-name>Lan-Yi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Guo</last-name>
<first-name>Qiang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Feng</last-name>
<first-name>Lan-Yi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Guo</last-name>
<first-name>Qiang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hong Fu Jin Precision Industry (ShenZhen) Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Deberadinis</last-name>
<first-name>Robert L.</first-name>
<department>2836</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A voltage adjustment system includes a power supply for providing an initial voltage signal, a plurality of buck converters for receiving the initial voltage signal and generating one adjustable output voltage signal respectively, a microcontroller for determining one adjustable output voltage signal to output and determining whether a variable voltage signal generated by a buck converter that outputs the adjustable output voltage signal is positive or negative, a display unit for displaying value of the adjustable output voltage signal that is outputted, a plurality of voltage control units corresponding to the plurality of buck converters, and a voltage variation adjustment circuit including two buttons. The variable voltage signal is added to the adjustable output voltage signal generated by the same buck converter. Selection of the two buttons causes the microcontroller to adjust absolute value of the variable voltage signal generated by the buck converter through the corresponding voltage control unit.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="197.27mm" wi="168.40mm" file="US08624425-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="212.51mm" wi="167.47mm" file="US08624425-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="173.48mm" wi="142.32mm" file="US08624425-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="179.07mm" wi="154.86mm" file="US08624425-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="180.76mm" wi="158.83mm" file="US08624425-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="182.71mm" wi="83.06mm" file="US08624425-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to a voltage adjustment system, and particularly to a voltage adjustment system for electrical testing of electronic devices.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Many electronic devices such as computers may require electrical testing before delivery. Different operating circuits of the electronic device require different operating voltages during the electrical testing process. For example, electrical testing an electronic device may require operating voltages of 3.3 volts, 5 volts, and 12 volts, and when testing whether the electronic device works abnormally when the operating voltages have slightly changed, the operating voltages of 3.3 volts, 5 volts, and 12 volts may need to be slightly adjusted.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Different power supplies are needed to provide different operating voltages, and voltage adjustment circuits are needed to slightly adjust the operating voltages. Thus, many testing equipments lead to circuit complexity, and high cost.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Therefore, it is desired to provide a voltage adjustment system which can overcome the above-described deficiencies.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Many aspects of the present voltage adjustment system can be better understood with reference to the following drawings. The components in the various drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the present voltage adjustment system.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram of a voltage adjustment system according to one embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a circuit diagram of one embodiment of a buck converter and a voltage control unit of the voltage adjustment system shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a circuit diagram of one embodiment illustrating electrical connections between a microcontroller, selection switches, a bidirectional switch, and a display unit of the voltage adjustment system shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a circuit diagram of one embodiment of a voltage variation adjustment circuit of the voltage adjustment system shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a circuit diagram of one embodiment illustrating electrical connections between the buck converter and the microcontroller of the voltage adjustment system shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a voltage adjustment system <b>100</b> according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure includes a power supply <b>10</b>, a plurality of buck converters <b>11</b> electronically connected to the power supply <b>10</b>, an analog-to digital converter (ADC) <b>12</b>, a microcontroller <b>13</b>, a demultiplexer <b>14</b>, a plurality of voltage control units <b>15</b>, a voltage variation adjustment circuit <b>16</b>, a plurality of selection switches <b>17</b> corresponding to the plurality of buck converters <b>11</b>, a bidirectional switch <b>18</b>, and a display unit <b>19</b>. The plurality of buck converters <b>11</b> are electronically connected to the ADC <b>12</b>, and each buck converter <b>11</b> is electronically connected to a voltage control unit <b>15</b>. The plurality of voltage control units <b>15</b> are electronically connected to the demultiplexer <b>14</b> and the voltage variation adjustment circuit <b>16</b>. The plurality of buck converters <b>11</b>, the ADC <b>12</b>, the demultiplexer <b>14</b>, the voltage variation adjustment circuit <b>16</b>, the plurality of selection switches <b>17</b>, the bidirectional switch <b>18</b>, and the display unit <b>19</b> are all electronically connected to the microcontroller <b>13</b>. The number of the buck converters <b>11</b>, the voltage control units <b>15</b>, and the selection switches <b>17</b> are the same, and determined by the number of desired output voltage signals. In this embodiment, the number of the desired output voltage signals is four.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, each buck converter <b>11</b> includes a voltage terminal VCC<b>5</b>, a function terminal VMSET/MODE, two general purpose input/output terminals GPIO<b>1</b>/REFIN, GPIO<b>2</b>. Each voltage control unit <b>15</b> includes an n-channel transistor Q<b>1</b>, a digital potentiometer <b>151</b>, and two current limiting resistors R. A drain electrode of the transistor Q<b>1</b> is electronically connected to the voltage terminal VCC<b>5</b>, a source electrode of the transistor Q<b>1</b> is electronically connected to the function terminal VMSET/MODE, and a gate electrode of the transistor Q<b>1</b> is electronically connected to a 5 volts input terminal through a current limiting resistor R.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The digital potentiometer <b>151</b> includes three control terminals <o ostyle="single">INC</o>, <o ostyle="single">CS</o>, U/ <o ostyle="single">D</o> and three resistor terminals RH, RW, RL. The three control terminals <o ostyle="single">INC</o>, <o ostyle="single">CS</o>, U/ <o ostyle="single">D</o> are operable to receive control signals according to which a resistance of the digital potentiometer <b>151</b> is adjusted. The resistor terminal RH is floating, the resistor terminal RW is electronically connected to the function terminal VMSET/MODE, and the resistor terminal RL is grounded through a current limiting resistor R. The digital potentiometer <b>151</b> can be referred to as a rheostat that is digitally controlled, the resistor terminal RW can be referred to as a wiper terminal of the rheostat, and the resistor terminals RH, RL can be referred to as two ends of the rheostat. The operation modes of the digital potentiometer <b>151</b> are shown in the following table, and &#x201c;X&#x201d; in the table is capable of representing any value.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00001" num="00001">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="4">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="49pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="49pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="28pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="91pt" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry> <o ostyle="single">INC</o></entry>
<entry> <o ostyle="single">CS</o></entry>
<entry>U/ <o ostyle="single">D</o></entry>
<entry>Operation</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>high to low</entry>
<entry>low</entry>
<entry>high</entry>
<entry>wiper terminal toward RH</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>high to low</entry>
<entry>low</entry>
<entry>low</entry>
<entry>wiper terminal toward RL</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>High</entry>
<entry>low to high</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>store wiper terminal position</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, in this embodiment, the microcontroller <b>13</b> is a single chip microcomputer. The microcontroller <b>13</b> includes a plurality of pins P<b>1</b>.<b>0</b>&#x2dc;P<b>1</b>.<b>7</b>, P<b>2</b>.<b>0</b>&#x2dc;P<b>2</b>.<b>2</b>, P<b>2</b>.<b>5</b>&#x2dc;P<b>2</b>.<b>6</b>. Each of the pins P<b>1</b>.<b>0</b>&#x2dc;P<b>1</b>.<b>3</b> is grounded through a selection switch <b>17</b>. Each selection switch <b>17</b> is electronically connected to a 5 volts input terminal through a current limiting resistor R. According to switch states of the selection switches <b>17</b>, the pins P<b>1</b>.<b>4</b>, P<b>1</b>.<b>5</b> outputs selection signals to the ADC <b>12</b> and the demultiplexer <b>14</b>. The pin P<b>1</b>.<b>6</b> is electronically connected to the bidirectional switch <b>18</b>. According to selection of the bidirectional switch <b>18</b>, the pin P<b>1</b>.<b>7</b> outputs a voltage variation control signal to the general purpose input/output terminal GPIO<b>1</b>/REFIN. The pin P<b>2</b>.<b>0</b> is electronically connected to the control terminal U/ <o ostyle="single">D</o>. The pins P<b>2</b>.<b>1</b>, P<b>2</b>.<b>2</b> are electronically connected to the voltage variation adjustment circuit <b>16</b>. The pins P<b>2</b>.<b>5</b>, P<b>2</b>.<b>6</b> are electronically connected to the display unit <b>19</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the voltage variation adjustment circuit <b>16</b> includes four n-channel transistors Q<b>2</b>, Q<b>3</b>, Q<b>4</b>, Q<b>5</b>, a plurality of current limiting resistors R, and two buttons SW<b>1</b>, SW<b>2</b>. The control terminal <o ostyle="single">INC</o> of each digital potentiometer <b>151</b> is grounded through the transistor Q<b>2</b>, and the control terminal <o ostyle="single">INC</o> of each digital potentiometer <b>151</b> is also grounded through the transistor Q<b>3</b>. A gate electrode of the transistor Q<b>2</b> and a gate electrode of the transistor Q<b>4</b> are electronically connected to the button SW<b>1</b>. The gate electrode of the transistor Q<b>4</b> is grounded through a current limiting resistor R, a drain electrode of the transistor Q<b>4</b> is electronically connected to the pin P<b>2</b>.<b>1</b>, and a source electrode of the transistor Q<b>4</b> is grounded. A gate electrode of the transistor Q<b>3</b> and a gate electrode of the transistor Q<b>5</b> are electronically connected to the button SW<b>2</b>. The gate electrode of the transistor Q<b>5</b> is grounded through a current limiting resistor R, a drain electrode of the transistor Q<b>5</b> is electronically connected to the pin P<b>2</b>.<b>2</b>, and a source electrode of the transistor Q<b>5</b> is grounded. The two buttons SW<b>1</b>, SW<b>2</b> are electronically connected to a 5 volts input terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the pin P<b>1</b>.<b>7</b> is electronically connected to the general purpose input/output terminal GPIO<b>1</b>/REFIN. The general purpose input/output terminal GPIO<b>1</b>/REFIN is electronically connected to a gate electrode of a transistor Q<b>6</b>. A drain electrode of the transistor Q<b>6</b> is electronically connected to the general purpose input/output terminal GPIO<b>2</b>. A source electrode of the transistor Q<b>6</b> is grounded. The general purpose input/output terminal GPIO<b>2</b> is electronically connected to a 5 volts input terminal through a current limiting resistor R.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-5</figref>, the voltage adjustment system <b>100</b> functions as follows:</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The power supply <b>10</b> sends an initial voltage signal to the four buck converters <b>11</b>. The four buck converters <b>11</b> receive the initial voltage signal and generate four different output voltage signals V<b>1</b>, V<b>2</b>, V<b>3</b>, and V<b>4</b> respectively. When the selection switch <b>17</b> corresponding to the buck converter <b>11</b> that generate the output voltage signal V<b>1</b> is closed, the microcontroller <b>13</b> sends selection signals ADD-A, ADD-B to the ADC <b>12</b> and the demultiplexer <b>14</b> through the pins P<b>1</b>.<b>4</b>, P<b>1</b>.<b>5</b>. According to the selection signals ADD-A, ADD-B, the ADC <b>12</b> collects the output voltage signal V<b>1</b>, converts the output voltage signal V<b>1</b> into a digital signal, and sends the digital signal to the microcontroller <b>13</b>. The microcontroller <b>13</b> sends a display control signal to the display unit <b>19</b>. The display unit <b>19</b> receives the display control signal and displays the value of the output voltage signal V<b>1</b>. The demultiplexer <b>14</b> receives the selection signals ADD-A, ADD-B and sends a low level signal (logic 0) Margin S<b>1</b> to a voltage control unit <b>15</b> connected to the buck converter <b>11</b> that generate the output voltage signal V<b>1</b>. The voltage control unit <b>15</b> receives the low level signal Margin S<b>1</b>, and the low level signal Margin S<b>1</b> is applied to the control terminal <o ostyle="single">CS</o> of the digital potentiometer <b>151</b> and the gate electrode of the transistor Q<b>1</b>. According to the low level signal Margin S<b>1</b>, the transistor Q<b>1</b> turns off, then the function terminal VMSET/MODE is disconnected from the voltage terminal VCC<b>5</b>, and the buck converter <b>11</b> that generate the output voltage signal V<b>1</b> generates a variable voltage signal &#x394;V<sub>OUT </sub>added to the output voltage signal V<b>1</b>. That is the variable voltage signal &#x394;V<sub>OUT </sub>is added to the output voltage signal V<b>1</b> generated by the same buck converter <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">When there is a need to slightly adjust the value of the output voltage signal V<b>1</b>, users may choose to increase or decrease the value of the output voltage signal V<b>1</b> through the bidirectional switch <b>18</b>. If the value of the output voltage signal V<b>1</b> needs to be increased, the microcontroller <b>13</b> sends a low level signal (logic 0) to the general purpose input/output terminal GPIO<b>1</b>/REFIN through the pin P<b>1</b>.<b>7</b>. Then the transistor Q<b>6</b> turns off, the voltage of the general purpose input/output terminal GPIO<b>2</b> is at a high logic level, and then the variable voltage signal &#x394;V<sub>OUT </sub>is positive. If the value of the output voltage signal V<b>1</b> needs to be decreased, the microcontroller <b>13</b> sends a high level signal (logic 1) to the general purpose input/output terminal GPIO<b>1</b>/REFIN through the pin P<b>1</b>.<b>7</b>. Then the transistor Q<b>6</b> turns on, the voltage of the general purpose input/output terminal GPIO<b>2</b> is at a low logic level, and then the variable voltage signal &#x394;V<sub>OUT </sub>is negative.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The adjustment process of the absolute value of the variable voltage signal &#x394;V<sub>OUT </sub>is as follows:</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">If the absolute value of the variable voltage signal &#x394;V<sub>OUT </sub>needs to be increased, the button SW<b>2</b> is pressed. Then the transistors Q<b>3</b>, Q<b>5</b> turn on, the voltage of the control terminal <o ostyle="single">INC</o> changes from logic high to logic low, and the voltage of the pin P<b>2</b>.<b>2</b> changes from logic high to logic low. The microcontroller <b>13</b> sends a low level signal (logic 0) to the control terminal U/ <o ostyle="single">D</o> through the pin P<b>2</b>.<b>0</b>. Referring to the above-mentioned table, the resistance between the resistor terminal RW and the resistor terminal RL is decreased. In this embodiment, the absolute value of the variable voltage signal &#x394;V<sub>OUT </sub>is inversely proportional to the resistance between the resistor terminal RW, and then the absolute value of the variable voltage signal &#x394;V<sub>OUT </sub>is increased.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">If the absolute value of the variable voltage signal &#x394;V<sub>OUT </sub>needs to be decreased, the button SW<b>1</b> is pressed. Then the transistors Q<b>2</b>, Q<b>4</b> turn on, the voltage of the control terminal <o ostyle="single">INC</o> changes from logic high to logic low, and the voltage of the pin P<b>2</b>.<b>1</b> changes from logic high to logic low. The microcontroller <b>13</b> sends a high level signal (logic 1) to the control terminal U/ <o ostyle="single">D</o> through the pin P<b>2</b>.<b>0</b>. Referring to the above-mentioned table, the resistance between the resistor terminal RW and the resistor terminal RL is increased, and then the absolute value of the variable voltage signal &#x394;V<sub>OUT </sub>is decreased. The adjusted output voltage signal V<b>1</b> is displayed on the display unit <b>19</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">As detailed above, according to an initial voltage signal, the voltage adjustment system <b>100</b> generates a plurality of adjustable output voltage signals and is easily operated.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">It is to be further understood that even though numerous characteristics and advantages of the present embodiments have been set forth in the foregoing description, together with details of structures and functions of various embodiments, the disclosure is illustrative only, and changes may be made in detail, especially in matters of shape, size, and arrangement of parts within the principles of the present disclosure to the full extent indicated by the broad general meaning of the terms in which the appended claims are expressed.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A voltage adjustment system, comprising:
<claim-text>a power supply for providing an initial voltage signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of buck converters for receiving the initial voltage signal and generating one adjustable output voltage signal respectively;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a microcontroller for determining one of the adjustable output voltage signals to output and determining whether a variable voltage signal generated by a buck converter that outputs the adjustable output voltage signal is positive or negative;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a display unit for displaying value of the adjustable output voltage signal that is outputted;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of voltage control units; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a voltage variation adjustment circuit including two buttons;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each voltage control unit corresponds to one buck converter; the variable voltage signal is added to the adjustable output voltage signal generated by the same buck converter; selection of the two buttons causes the microcontroller to adjust absolute value of the variable voltage signal generated by the buck converter through the corresponding voltage control unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The voltage adjustment system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each voltage control unit comprises a digital potentiometer electronically connected to the corresponding buck converter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The voltage adjustment system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the voltage variation adjustment circuit further comprises two transistors electronically connected to the digital potentiometer, and two transistors electronically connected to the microcontroller; each button of the voltage variation adjustment circuit is electronically connected to one transistor connected to the digital potentiometer and one transistor connected to the microcontroller.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The voltage adjustment system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the voltage adjustment system further comprises a bidirectional switch electronically connected to the microcontroller, according to selection of the bidirectional switch, the microcontroller determines the variable voltage signal generated by the buck converter is positive or negative.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The voltage adjustment system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein when one of the buttons is pressed, the two transistors electronically connected to the pressed button turns on at the same time.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The voltage adjustment system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein according to the selection of the buttons, the microcontroller sends control signals to the digital potentiometers; according to the control signals, the resistance of the digital potentiometer electronically connected to the buck converter that generate the variable voltage signal is adjusted to increase or decrease the absolute value of the variable voltage signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The voltage adjustment system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the voltage adjustment system further comprises a plurality of selection switches electronically connected to the microcontroller, and each selection switch corresponds to one buck converter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The voltage adjustment system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the voltage adjustment system further comprises a demutiplexer electronically connected to the microcontroller, the demutiplexer is electronically connected to the plurality of voltage control units.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A voltage adjustment system, comprising:
<claim-text>a power supply;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of buck converters for generating a plurality of adjustable output voltage signals;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a microcontroller;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of voltage control units corresponding to the plurality of buck converters;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a voltage variation adjustment circuit electronically connected to the plurality of voltage control units; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a display unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the plurality of buck converters are electronically connected to the power supply; each voltage control unit is electronically connected to the corresponding buck converter; the plurality of buck converters, the voltage variation adjustment circuit, and the display unit are electronically connected to the microcontroller.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The voltage adjustment system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein each voltage control unit comprises a digital potentiometer electronically connected to the corresponding buck converter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The voltage adjustment system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the voltage variation adjustment circuit comprises two buttons, two transistors electronically connected to the digital potentiometer, and two transistors electronically connected to the microcontroller; each button is electronically connected to one transistor connected to the digital potentiometer and one transistor connected to the microcontroller.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The voltage adjustment system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the voltage adjustment system further comprises a bidirectional switch electronically connected to the microcontroller, the microcontroller determines one adjustable output voltage signal to output, and according to selection of the bidirectional switch, the microcontroller determines whether a variable voltage signal generated by the buck converter that output the adjustable output voltage signal is positive or negative.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The voltage adjustment system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the variable voltage signal is added to the adjustable output voltage signal generated by the same buck converter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The voltage adjustment system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein when one of the buttons is pressed, the two transistors electronically connected to the pressed button turns on at the same time.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The voltage adjustment system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein according to the selection of the buttons, the microcontroller sends control signals to the digital potentiometers; according to the control signals, the resistance of the digital potentiometer electronically connected to the buck converter that generate the variable voltage signal is adjusted to increase or decrease the absolute value of the variable voltage signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The voltage adjustment system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the voltage adjustment system further comprises a plurality of selection switches electronically connected to the microcontroller, and each selection switch corresponds to one buck converter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The voltage adjustment system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the voltage adjustment system further comprises a demutiplexer electronically connected to the microcontroller, the demutiplexer is electronically connected to the plurality of voltage control units.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
