<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624233-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624233</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13411125</doc-number>
<date>20120302</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2011-053989</doc-number>
<date>20110311</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>29</main-group>
<subgroup>08</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257 40</main-classification>
<further-classification>438 99</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e61">Organic electroluminescence display device and electronic apparatus</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0273314</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lee</name>
<date>20061200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257 59</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0102369</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Nakanishi et al.</name>
<date>20090400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>313504</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0200875</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Takei</name>
<date>20100800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257 91</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0227100</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kurihara et al.</name>
<date>20110900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257 88</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2003-249375</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20030900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2005-326799</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20051100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>11</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257 40</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>16</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>35</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120228590</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120913</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Matsumi</last-name>
<first-name>Tatsuya</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kanagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Matsumi</last-name>
<first-name>Tatsuya</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kanagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Wolf, Greenfield &#x26; Sacks, P.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Sony Corporation</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Nguyen</last-name>
<first-name>Ha Tran T</first-name>
<department>2829</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Noel</last-name>
<first-name>Paul</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An organic electroluminescence display device includes a pixel isolating film that is provided over a substrate and has a plurality of apertures, and a plurality of pixels provided corresponding to the plurality of apertures. Each of the plurality of pixels has a first electrode, a functional layer including at least an organic light emitting layer, and a second electrode sequentially from the side of the substrate, and part or whole of the first electrode is separate from an edge part of the aperture on the side of the substrate.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="140.63mm" wi="168.99mm" file="US08624233-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="197.95mm" wi="151.72mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624233-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="215.90mm" wi="153.50mm" file="US08624233-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="201.59mm" wi="140.29mm" file="US08624233-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="145.97mm" wi="133.86mm" file="US08624233-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="211.33mm" wi="148.25mm" file="US08624233-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="175.09mm" wi="223.35mm" file="US08624233-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="214.63mm" wi="146.05mm" file="US08624233-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="210.31mm" wi="149.61mm" file="US08624233-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="208.96mm" wi="129.96mm" file="US08624233-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="209.63mm" wi="116.76mm" file="US08624233-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="247.73mm" wi="122.94mm" file="US08624233-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="245.70mm" wi="123.78mm" file="US08624233-20140107-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="242.49mm" wi="167.56mm" file="US08624233-20140107-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00014" num="00014">
<img id="EMI-D00014" he="256.12mm" wi="162.14mm" file="US08624233-20140107-D00014.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00015" num="00015">
<img id="EMI-D00015" he="234.02mm" wi="116.67mm" file="US08624233-20140107-D00015.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00016" num="00016">
<img id="EMI-D00016" he="250.95mm" wi="165.78mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624233-20140107-D00016.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present disclosure relates to an organic electroluminescence (EL) display device that performs image displaying by utilizing an organic electroluminescence phenomenon and electronic apparatus including such an organic EL display device.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">As development of the information communication industry is accelerated, display elements having higher performance are required. Among the display elements, the organic EL element, which is attracting attention as a next-generation display element, has not only advantages of having a wide viewing angle and being excellent in the contrast as a self-luminous display element but also an advantage of having a short response time.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The materials of the functional layers, such as a light emitting layer, to form the organic EL element are classified broadly into low-molecular materials and polymer materials. As the film deposition methods of these materials, for the low-molecular material, a dry method such as a vacuum evaporation method is used. For the polymer material, a discharge printing method such as spin coating, inkjet, and nozzle-jet or a plate printing method such as flexo printing, screen printing, gravure printing, and reverse printing is used.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Among these methods, the dry method such as a vacuum evaporation method is free from the need to dissolve the functional layer material in a solvent and therefore has e.g. an advantage that a step of removing the solvent is unnecessary. However, it is difficult to apply the material onto the respective different areas separately by using a metal mask. Therefore, the dry method is unsuitable for size increase and mass production of the panel particularly in terms of the facility manufacturing cost. So, the printing system, which is capable of addressing size increase and mass production of the panel comparatively easily, is attracting attention.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In a film deposition method based on the printing system, specifically a lower electrode is formed for each pixel over a circuit board including a thin film transistor (TFT) and so forth and thereafter a pixel isolating film (so-called bank) having apertures opposed to the lower electrodes is formed. Then, lyophobic treatment is performed for the deposited pixel isolating film and thereafter a solution containing the above-described functional layer material is applied and dried. Thereby, a functional layer can be formed in each aperture. However, if the functional layer is formed through the step of applying and drying a solution, the functional layer is thinned in the drying near the interface between the pixel isolating film and the lower electrode because the wettability is different between them. This causes the occurrence of electrical short-circuiting, which leads to a problem of the deterioration of the displayed-image quality.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">So, there has been proposed a method in which an inorganic material layer is additionally provided between the above-described pixel isolating film and lower electrode (two-layer structure is employed as the bank structure) to thereby prevent the thinned part generated in the drying step from getting contact with the lower electrode (refer to e.g. Japanese Patent Laid-Open No. 2003-249375 and Japanese Patent Laid-Open No. 2005-326799 (hereinafter referred to as Patent Documents 1 and 2)).</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">However, in this method of Patent Documents 1 and 2, the inorganic material layer needs to be additionally provided (bank needs to be formed by a two-stage step). Thus, there is a problem that the number of steps and the number of parts are increased and realization of cost reduction is difficult.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">There is a need for a technique to provide an organic EL display device capable of suppressing the deterioration of the displayed-image quality while achieving cost reduction.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to an embodiment of the present disclosure, there is provided an organic EL display device including a pixel isolating film configured to be provided over a substrate and have a plurality of apertures, and a plurality of pixels configured to be provided corresponding to the plurality of apertures. Each of the plurality of pixels has a first electrode, a functional layer including at least an organic light emitting layer, and a second electrode sequentially from the side of the substrate, and part or whole of the first electrode is separate from an edge part of the aperture on the side of the substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to another embodiment of the present disclosure, there is provided electronic apparatus including the organic EL display device according to the above-described embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In the organic EL display device and the electronic apparatus according to the embodiments of the present disclosure, in the pixels that are provided corresponding to the respective apertures of the pixel isolating film and each have the first electrode, the functional layer including the organic light emitting layer, and the second electrode in that order from the substrate side, part or whole of the first electrode is separate from the edge part of the aperture. Due to this feature, the thinned part of the functional layer generated in film deposition is readily formed at a position distant from the first electrode (local thickness change of the functional layer occurs less readily in the substantial light emitting area corresponding to the first electrode). Thus, the occurrence of electrical short-circuiting between the first electrode and the second electrode is suppressed.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to the organic EL display device and the electronic apparatus of the embodiments of the present invention, the pixels each having the first electrode, the functional layer including the organic light emitting layer, and the second electrode in that order from the substrate side are provided corresponding to the respective apertures in the pixel isolating film, and part or whole of the first electrode is separate from the edge part of the aperture. Thus, thickness unevenness of the functional layer generated in film deposition can be prevented from being formed opposed to the light emitting area. This can suppress the occurrence of electrical short-circuiting in the light emitting area without additionally forming another layer for short-circuiting prevention between the pixel isolating film and the first electrode. Thus, the deterioration of the displayed-image quality can be suppressed with achievement of cost reduction.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram showing the sectional configuration of an organic EL display device according to one embodiment of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a diagram showing one example of a drive circuit over a substrate shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram showing one example of a pixel drive circuit shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagram showing the detailed sectional configuration of an organic EL element (pixel) shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an enlarged sectional view of the vicinity of an aperture of a bank layer shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a diagram showing one example of the planar configuration of lower electrodes and the bank layer;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A to 7G</figref> are sectional views for explaining a method for manufacturing the organic EL display device shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a sectional view showing the configuration of the major part in an organic EL element according to comparative example 1;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a sectional view showing the configuration of the major part in an organic EL element according to comparative example 2;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a characteristic diagram showing the relationship between the aperture ratio and the distance between the lower electrode and an aperture edge part;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a characteristic diagram showing the relationship between the element lifetime and the distance between the lower electrode and the aperture edge part;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a plan view for explaining the arrangement relationship between the lower electrode and the aperture according to modification example 1;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a sectional view for explaining the arrangement relationship between the lower electrode and the aperture according to modification example 1;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 14A and 14B</figref> are sectional views for explaining the arrangement relationship between the lower electrode and the aperture according to modification example 1;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is a diagram showing the sectional configuration of an organic EL display device according to modification example 2;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref> is a plan view showing the schematic configuration of a module including the display device of the above-described embodiment and so forth;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</figref> is a perspective view showing the appearance of application example 1 of the display device of the above-described embodiment and so forth;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18A</figref> is a perspective view showing the appearance of the front side of application example 2 and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18B</figref> is a perspective view showing the appearance of the back side;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</figref> is a perspective view showing the appearance of application example 3;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</figref> is a perspective view showing the appearance of application example 4; and</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21A</figref> is a front view of the opened state of application example 5, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21B</figref> is a side view of the opened state, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21C</figref> is a front view of the closed state, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21D</figref> is a left side view, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21E</figref> is a right side view, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21F</figref> is a top view, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21G</figref> is a bottom view.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">An embodiment of the present disclosure will be described in detail below with reference to the drawings. The order of the description is as follows.
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0035">1. Embodiment (example in which lower electrode is disposed separately from edge part of aperture of bank layer (lyophobic) on interlayer insulating film (lyophilic))</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0002" num="0036">2. Modification Example 1 (example in which separation distance differs depending on pixel position)</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0003" num="0037">3. Modification Example 2 (example in which organic planarizing film is formed over substrate)</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0004" num="0038">4. Application Examples (examples of application to electronic apparatus)
<br/>
&#x3c;Embodiment&#x3e;
<br/>
[Configuration of Organic EL Display Device]
</li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows the sectional configuration of an organic EL display device according to one embodiment of the present disclosure (organic EL display device <b>1</b>). The organic EL display device <b>1</b> is used as e.g. an organic EL television device capable of full-color displaying. In this organic EL display device <b>1</b>, for example, over a drive board <b>10</b>, organic EL elements <b>10</b>R to emit red light, organic EL elements <b>10</b>G to emit green light, and organic EL elements <b>10</b>B to emit blue light are arranged in a matrix as plural pixels to configure a display area (display area <b>110</b> to be described later). These organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B are each provided in an area (aperture <b>15</b><i>a</i>) defined by a bank layer <b>15</b> as a pixel isolating film over the drive board <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0005" num="0000">(Drive Board <b>10</b>)</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0040">The drive board <b>10</b> is obtained by disposing a drive circuit (pixel drive circuit <b>140</b> to be described later and so forth) including TFTs <b>11</b>, a wiring layer <b>12</b>, and so forth over a substrate <b>10</b><i>a</i>. For example, the TFT <b>11</b> is obtained by stacking electrode wiring layers of the gate, source, drain, and so forth, a semiconductor layer to form the channel, and interlayer insulating films <b>11</b><i>a </i>and <b>11</b><i>b. </i>The wiring layer <b>12</b> is formed on the interlayer insulating film <b>11</b><i>b </i>for example. An interlayer insulating film <b>13</b> (inorganic insulating film) is so provided as to cover these TFTs <b>11</b> and wiring layer <b>12</b>. In the present embodiment, this interlayer insulating film <b>13</b> is the surface on which the organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B and the bank layer <b>15</b> are formed.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0041">The substrate <b>10</b><i>a </i>is formed of e.g. quartz, glass, metal foil, silicon, or plastic. TFT <b>11</b> is equivalent to e.g. a drive transistor Tr<b>1</b> and a write transistor Tr<b>2</b> in the pixel drive circuit <b>140</b> to be described later. Its configuration may be e.g. an inverted-staggered structure (so-called bottom gate type) or a staggered structure (top gate type). The interlayer insulating films <b>11</b><i>a </i>and <b>11</b><i>b </i>are a single-layer film, a multilayer film, or a mixed composition film containing at least one kind of silicon oxide (SiO<sub>2</sub>), silicon nitride (SiN), titanium oxide (TiO<sub>2</sub>), and titanium nitride (TiN). The wiring layer <b>12</b> is composed of an electrically-conductive metal and electrically connected to e.g. the drain of the TFT <b>11</b>. It is desirable for this wiring layer <b>12</b> to have a metal whose contact resistance to the lower electrode <b>14</b> is low or such a metal oxide at the connection surface to the lower electrode <b>14</b>. The wiring layer <b>12</b> is composed of e.g. molybdenum (Mo) or titanium (Ti) or may be composed of aluminum (Al) or copper (Cu) covered by molybdenum or titanium.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0042">The interlayer insulating film <b>13</b> is formed of e.g. a single-layer film or a multilayer film containing at least one kind of silicon oxide, silicon nitride, titanium oxide, and titanium nitride. Alternatively, it may contain silicon oxynitride (SiN<sub>x</sub>O<sub>y</sub>) or aluminum oxide (Al<sub>x</sub>O<sub>y</sub>) and may contain a metal oxide that does not have electrical conductivity. In this interlayer insulating film <b>13</b>, contact holes that penetrate to the surface of the wiring layer <b>12</b> are formed. The lower electrode <b>14</b> is so provided as to fill this contact hole. Thereby, the lower electrode <b>14</b> is electrically connected to the wiring layer <b>12</b> and a predetermined potential is supplied to each of the organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B via the lower electrode <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0043">In the present embodiment, the wettability of this interlayer insulating film <b>13</b> to the organic solvent used in deposition of the functional layer <b>16</b> is higher than that of the bank layer <b>15</b> to be described later, and the interlayer insulating film <b>13</b> functions as a lyophilic film. As described in detail later, the lower electrode <b>14</b> and the bank layer <b>15</b> having lyophobicity are disposed on the surface of such an interlayer insulating film <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows one example of the drive circuit of the drive board <b>10</b>. In the drive board <b>10</b>, the pixel drive circuit <b>140</b> is provided in the display area <b>110</b> and a signal line drive circuit <b>120</b> and a scanning line drive circuit <b>130</b> as drivers for video displaying are provided around the display area <b>110</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows one example of the pixel drive circuit <b>140</b>. The pixel drive circuit <b>140</b> is an active drive circuit formed under the lower electrode <b>14</b> to be described later. This pixel drive circuit <b>140</b> has the drive transistor Tr<b>1</b> and the write transistor Tr<b>2</b> (equivalent to the above-described TFT <b>11</b>) and a capacitor (hold capacitance) Cs between these transistors Tr<b>1</b> and Tr<b>2</b>. Furthermore, the pixel drive circuit <b>140</b> has the organic EL element <b>10</b>R (or organic EL element <b>10</b>G or <b>10</b>B) connected in series to the drive transistor Tr<b>1</b> between a first power supply line (Vcc) and a second power supply line (GND).</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0045">In the pixel drive circuit <b>140</b>, plural signal lines <b>120</b>A are disposed along the column direction and plural scanning lines <b>130</b>A are disposed along the row direction. The intersection of the signal line <b>120</b>A and the scanning line <b>130</b>A corresponds to one of the organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B. Each signal line <b>120</b>A is connected to the signal line drive circuit <b>120</b> and an image signal is supplied from this signal line drive circuit <b>120</b> to the source electrode of the write transistor Tr<b>2</b> via the signal line <b>120</b>A. Each scanning line <b>130</b>A is connected to the scanning line drive circuit <b>130</b> and a scanning signal is sequentially supplied from this scanning line drive circuit <b>130</b> to the gate electrode of the write transistor Tr<b>2</b> via the scanning line <b>130</b>A.</p>
<p id="h-0006" num="0000">(Organic EL Element <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, <b>10</b>B)</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0046">Each of the organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B is obtained by stacking, over the drive board <b>10</b>, the lower electrode <b>14</b> as the anode, the functional layer <b>16</b> including a light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c </i>to be described later, and an upper electrode <b>18</b> as the cathode in that order. These organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B are covered by a protective layer <b>19</b> and a sealing substrate <b>20</b> composed of e.g. glass is bonded onto this protective layer <b>19</b> by an adhesion layer (not shown) formed of e.g. a heat-curable resin or an ultraviolet-curable resin. Thereby, the whole display area is sealed.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0047">The lower electrode <b>14</b> is provided for each of the pixels of the organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B. The thickness of the lower electrode <b>14</b> is e.g. 10 nm to 1000 nm. In the case of the bottom emission type, the lower electrode <b>14</b> is formed of a transparent electrically-conductive film, specifically e.g. a single-layer film composed of any of an oxide of indium and tin (ITO), indium zinc oxide (InZnO), and an alloy of zinc oxide (ZnO) and aluminum (Al) or a multilayer film composed of two or more kinds of these materials. In the case of the top emission type, the lower electrode <b>14</b> is configured by using an electrically-conductive material that is excellent in the light reflectivity (reflectance of 40% or higher is desirable). This lower electrode <b>14</b> is composed of e.g. a single material or an alloy of metal elements such as chromium (Cr), gold (Au), platinum (Pt), nickel (Ni), copper (Cu), tungsten (W), and silver (Ag). Alternatively, the lower electrode <b>14</b> may have a multilayer structure formed of a metal film composed of a single material or an alloy of these metal elements and a transparent electrically-conductive film of e.g. ITO, InZnO, or an alloy of zinc oxide (ZnO) and aluminum (Al). If the lower electrode <b>14</b> functions as the anode, it is desirable that the lower electrode <b>14</b> is composed of a material having high hole injection ability. However, even with a material that does not have such a characteristic (e.g. aluminum alloy), the film made by this material can be used as the lower electrode <b>14</b> by additionally providing a proper hole injection layer.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows one example of the sectional structure of the organic EL element (pixel). As shown in the diagram, if the lower electrode <b>14</b> functions as the anode, the functional layer <b>16</b> is obtained by stacking a hole injection layer <b>16</b><i>a</i>, a hole transport layer <b>16</b><i>b</i>, and the light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c </i>in that order from the side of the lower electrode <b>14</b> for example. As the light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c</i>, a light emitting layer of the corresponding color in each of the organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B (red light emitting layer, green light emitting layer, blue light emitting layer) is provided. On the other hand, the layers in the functional layer <b>16</b> except for the light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c</i>, i.e. the hole injection layer <b>16</b><i>a </i>and the hole transport layer <b>16</b><i>b</i>, are layers common to the respective pixels of the organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B. Between the functional layer <b>16</b> (light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c</i>) and the upper electrode <b>18</b>, an electron transport layer <b>17</b> is provided in common to the respective elements. The sectional structure of the organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B is not limited thereto. Other layers (e.g. electron injection layer) may be provided and part of the light emitting layer may be a common layer. For example, the following structure may be employed. Specifically, in the organic EL elements <b>10</b>R and <b>10</b>G, the red and green light emitting layers corresponding to these elements are provided. In addition, the blue light emitting layer is provided as a layer common to the organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0049">The hole injection layer <b>16</b><i>a </i>is a buffer layer for enhancing the efficiency of hole injection to the light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c </i>and preventing leakage. This hole injection layer <b>16</b><i>a </i>is composed of a polymer material and deposited by a printing method. The weight-average molecular weight (Mw) of the polymer material is typically in the range of 10000 to 300000, and preferably about 5000 to 200000 particularly. Alternatively, an oligomer whose weight-average molecular weight (Mw) is about 2000 to 10000 may be used. However, if the weight-average molecular weight (Mw) is smaller than 5000, possibly the hole injection layer is dissolved in forming the hole transport layer and the subsequent layers. If the weight-average molecular weight (Mw) surpasses 300000, the material is turned into a gel and the film deposition becomes difficult. The weight-average molecular weight (Mw) is the value obtained by employing tetrahydrofuran as the solvent and obtaining the weight-average molecular weight in terms of polystyrene by gel permeation chromatography (GPC). The material of such a hole injection layer <b>16</b><i>a </i>is appropriately selected depending on the relationship with the materials of the electrode and adjacent layer. Examples of the material include polyaniline, oligoaniline, polythiophene, polypyrrole, polyphenylenevinylene, polythienylenevinylene, polyquinoline, polyquinoxaline, and derivatives of them, electrically-conductive polymers such as a polymer including an aromatic amine structure in the main chain or the side chain, metal phthalocyanine (such as copper phthalocyanine), and carbon. The thickness of the hole injection layer <b>16</b><i>a </i>is e.g. 5 nm to 100 nm.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0050">The hole transport layer <b>16</b><i>b </i>is to enhance the efficiency of hole transport to the light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c</i>. This hole transport layer <b>16</b><i>b </i>is also composed of a polymer material and deposited by a printing method similarly to the above-described hole injection layer <b>16</b><i>a</i>. It is preferable that its weight-average molecular weight (Mw) be 50000 to 300000 and it is particularly preferable that it be 100000 to 200000. If the weight-average molecular weight (Mw) is smaller than 50000, a low-molecular component in the polymer material drops off in forming the light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c</i>, and possibly this causes the lowering of the initial performance of the organic EL element and the deterioration of the element. If the weight-average molecular weight (Mw) surpasses 300000, the material is turned into a gel and the film deposition becomes difficult. As the polymer material to configure such a hole transport layer <b>16</b><i>b</i>, a light emitting material that is soluble in an organic solvent to be described later is used. Examples of the material include polyvinylcarbazole, polyfluorene, polyaniline, polysilane, and derivatives of them, polysiloxane derivatives having aromatic amine in the side chain or the main chain, polythiophene and derivatives thereof, and polypyrrole. The thickness of this hole transport layer <b>16</b><i>b </i>is e.g. 10 nm to 200 nm although depending on the whole configuration of the element.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0051">The light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c </i>is to generate light through the occurrence of recombination of electron and hole by application of an electric field. This light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c </i>contains a polymer (light emitting) material and is deposited by a printing method. Examples of the polymer material to configure the light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c </i>include the following substances, shown on each emission color basis. Specifically, regarding the organic EL element <b>10</b>R to emit red light and the organic EL element <b>10</b>G to emit green light, examples of the polymer material of the light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c </i>include polyfluorene-based polymer derivatives, (poly) paraphenylenevinylene derivatives, polyphenylene derivatives, polyvinylcarbazole derivatives, polythiophene derivatives, perylene-based dyes, coumarin-based dyes, rhodamine-based dyes, and substances obtained by doping the above-described polymers with an organic EL material. As the doping material, e.g. rubrene, perylene, 9,10-diphenylanthracene, tetraphenylbutadiene, nile red, and coumarin 6 can be used. For the organic EL element <b>10</b>B to emit blue light, an anthracene derivative can be used as the host material, and e.g. a low-molecular fluorescent material, a phosphorite dye, or a metal complex can be used as the doping material. The thickness of this light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c </i>is e.g. 10 nm to 200 nm although depending on the whole configuration of the element.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0052">In film deposition of these hole injection layer <b>16</b><i>a, </i>hole transport layer <b>16</b><i>b</i>, and light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c</i>, a solution prepared by dissolving any of the above-described polymer materials in an organic solvent containing e.g. at least one kind of the following substances is used: toluene, xylene, anisole, cyclohexanone, mesitylene (1,3,5-trimethylbenzene), pseudocumene (1,2,4-trimethylbenzene), dihydrobenzofuran, 1,2,3,4-tetramethylbenzene, tetralin, cyclohexylbenzene, 1-methylnaphthalene, p-anisyl alcohol, dimethylnaphthalene, 3-methylbiphenyl, 4-methylbiphenyl, 3-isopropylbiphenyl, and monoisopropylnaphthalene.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0053">The electron transport layer <b>17</b> is to enhance the efficiency of electron transport to the light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c</i>. Examples of the material of this electron transport layer <b>17</b> include quinoline, perylene, phenanthroline, bisstyryl, pyrazine, triazole, oxazole, fullerene, oxadiazole, fluorenone, and derivatives and metal complexes of them. Specific examples of the material include tris-(8-hydroxyquinoline)aluminum (abbreviation, Alq3), anthracene, naphthalene, phenanthrene, pyrene, perylene, butadiene, coumarin, C60, acridine, stilbene, 1,10-phenanthroline, and derivatives and metal complexes of them.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0054">The upper electrode <b>18</b> has a thickness of e.g. 2 nm to 200 nm and is formed of a metal electrically-conductive film. Specifically, a film composed of an elemental metal or an alloy containing at least one kind of aluminum (Al), magnesium (Mg), calcium (Ca), and sodium (Na) can be used. Alternatively, a transparent electrically-conductive film of e.g. ITO may be used. This upper electrode <b>18</b> is formed over the functional layer <b>16</b> in such a state as to be insulated from the lower electrode <b>14</b>, and serves as a common electrode of the organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0055">Between the electron transport layer <b>17</b> and the upper electrode <b>18</b>, an electron injection layer (not shown) may be provided. As the electron injection material, e.g. lithium oxide (Li<sub>2</sub>O), which is an oxide of lithium (Li), cesium carbonate (Cs<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub>), which is a composite oxide of cesium (Cs), and a mixture of these oxide and composite oxide can be used. Alternatively, alkaline earth metals such as calcium (Ca) and barium (Ba), alkali metals such as lithium and cesium, and metals having a low work function, such as indium (In) and magnesium, may be used.</p>
<p id="h-0007" num="0000">(Bank Layer <b>15</b>)</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0056">The bank layer <b>15</b> has the plural apertures <b>15</b><i>a </i>and is to ensure insulation between the lower electrode <b>14</b> and the upper electrode <b>18</b> in the above-described organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B and define (isolate) the respective pixel areas. Furthermore, the bank layer <b>15</b> functions also as a partition for applying the functional layer <b>16</b> into the respective different areas separately without the effect on adjacent pixels in print-forming the functional layer <b>16</b> in a manufacturing step to be described later. Such a bank layer <b>15</b> is kept in such a state that its wettability to the organic solvent used in the deposition of the functional layer <b>16</b> is low (lyophobic state). Specifically, the bank layer <b>15</b> is formed of any of a polyimide resin, an acrylic resin, a novolac resin, etc. and predetermined lyophobic treatment (e.g. plasma treatment by use of a fluorine gas) is performed for its surface. Alternatively, the bank layer <b>15</b> may be configured by a lyophobic resin containing fluorine. The thickness of this bank layer <b>15</b> is e.g. 300 nm to 3000 nm.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0057">In the apertures <b>15</b><i>a </i>of this bank layer <b>15</b>, the organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B are provided as described above. In the present embodiment, the lower electrode <b>14</b> is provided at a predetermined position in the aperture <b>15</b><i>a </i>and the functional layer <b>16</b> is so formed as to cover this lower electrode <b>14</b>. The detailed configuration of the vicinity of the aperture <b>15</b><i>a </i>will be described below.</p>
<p id="h-0008" num="0000">(Detailed Configuration of Vicinity of Aperture of Bank Layer <b>15</b>)</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0058"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an enlarged diagram of a sectional structure near the aperture <b>15</b><i>a </i>of the bank layer <b>15</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a top view of the lower electrodes <b>14</b> disposed in the apertures <b>15</b><i>a </i>of the bank layer <b>15</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the configuration of only the major part is shown. As shown in the diagram, in the present embodiment, each of the lower electrodes <b>14</b> of the organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B is disposed separately from an edge part <b>15</b><i>e </i>of the aperture <b>15</b><i>a</i>. In this configuration, the lower electrode <b>14</b> has e.g. a rectangular planar shape and each of end parts <b>14</b><i>e </i>corresponding to four sides of this rectangular shape is disposed at an interval from the edge part <b>15</b><i>e </i>of the aperture <b>15</b><i>a </i>by a distance D (separation distance). That is, in this configuration, part of the surface of the interlayer insulating film <b>13</b> provided on the drive board <b>10</b> is exposed in the area between the bank layer <b>15</b> and the lower electrode <b>14</b>, and the functional layer <b>16</b> is so provided as to cover this exposed area and the lower electrode <b>14</b>. In other words, the bank layer <b>15</b> is provided in contact with not the lower electrode <b>14</b> but the surface of the interlayer insulating film <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0059">As just described, the functional layer <b>16</b> is so provided as to cover the lower electrode <b>14</b> and the area between the lower electrode <b>14</b> and the bank layer <b>15</b>. However, this functional layer <b>16</b> has thickness unevenness generated in the film deposition process. Specifically, the functional layer <b>16</b> is deposited by a printing method and a locally thinned part (thinned part A) is generated in the functional layer <b>16</b> in the step of drying the organic solvent (details will be described later). In the present embodiment, such a thinned part A of the functional layer <b>16</b> is formed in the area between the edge part <b>15</b><i>e </i>of the aperture <b>15</b><i>a </i>and the end part <b>14</b><i>e </i>of the lower electrode <b>14</b> (i.e. area on the exposed interlayer insulating film <b>13</b>). In other words, the functional layer <b>16</b> is formed with a substantially uniform thickness at least in the area opposed to the lower electrode <b>14</b>. This area opposed to the lower electrode <b>14</b> serves as the substantial light emitting area (light emitting area <b>10</b>L).</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0060">It is desirable that the above-described distance D (&#x3bc;m) be equal to or longer than 5 &#x3bc;m specifically, and it is more desirable that the distance D satisfy the following expression (1). It is further more desirable that the distance D satisfy the following expressions (1) and (2). In these expressions, B (&#x3bc;m) is defined as the width between the adjacent lower electrodes <b>14</b>. Specifically, because two kinds of width B (B<b>1</b> and B<b>2</b>) exist along the X direction and the Y direction as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, it is more desirable that the following expressions (1) and (2) be satisfied regarding both of these widths B<b>1</b> and B<b>2</b>.
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>5&#x2266;<i>D&#x2266;</i>(&#xbd;)&#xd7;(<i>B&#x2212;</i>15)&#x2003;&#x2003;(1)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>25&#x2266;B&#x2003;&#x2003;(2)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0061">If the distance D is too short, specifically if it is shorter than 5 &#x3bc;m, the thinned part A is so formed as to overlap with the area directly above the lower electrode <b>14</b>, i.e. the light emitting area <b>10</b>L, and evenness of the film thickness in the light emitting area <b>10</b>L is not obtained. That is, substantially the aperture ratio is lowered. Therefore, it is desirable that the distance D be equal to or longer than 5 &#x3bc;m. On the other hand, if the distance D becomes too long, the area that does not contribute to the light emitting area <b>10</b>L increases and thus the unnecessary material (organic material that does not contribute to light emission in the functional layer <b>16</b>) increases. Furthermore, the need to decrease the size of the lower electrode <b>14</b> itself often arises and thus the aperture ratio is lowered conversely. Therefore, it is desirable to set the upper limit of the distance D as shown by the above-described expression (1). The upper limit of this expression (1) is conditioned on that B is equal to or larger than 15 &#x3bc;m. This is based on the following reason. Specifically, in the film deposition process of the functional layer <b>16</b>, the functional layer material (ink) is dropped into the area surrounded by the bank layer <b>15</b>. At this time, the ink is so dropped as to rise to the top surface of the bank layer <b>15</b> (see e.g. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7D and 7E</figref> to be described later). Therefore, if the interval between the lower electrodes <b>14</b> is too short (B is too small), the ink runs out to the adjacent pixel, which causes light emission failure. It is experimentally known that B equal to or larger than 15 &#x3bc;m suppresses such an influence on the adjacent pixel. Therefore, coupled with this point, the upper limit of the above-described expression (1) is set.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0062">In the diagrammatic representation of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the respective distances from four end parts <b>14</b><i>e </i>of the lower electrode <b>14</b> to the edge part <b>15</b><i>e </i>are equal to each other. However, the respective end parts <b>14</b><i>e </i>of the lower electrode <b>14</b> do not necessarily need to be separate from the edge part <b>15</b><i>e </i>by the same distance and the separation distance may differ for each of the end parts <b>14</b><i>e </i>corresponding to the respective sides. Furthermore, all end parts <b>14</b><i>e </i>do not necessarily need to be separate from the edge part <b>15</b><i>e </i>and it is enough that at least part of the lower electrode <b>14</b> is disposed separately from the bank layer <b>15</b>. For example, the following configuration may be employed. Specifically, part of the lower electrode <b>14</b>, e.g. the end part <b>14</b><i>e </i>corresponding to one side among four sides, is in contact with the edge part <b>15</b><i>e </i>(or is so formed as to overlap with the bank layer <b>15</b>), and the end parts <b>14</b><i>e </i>corresponding to the other three sides are disposed separately from the edge part <b>15</b><i>e. </i></p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0063">The protective layer <b>19</b> has a thickness of e.g. 2 to 3 &#x3bc;m and may be configured by either an insulating material or an electrically-conductive material. As the insulating material, an inorganic amorphous insulating material is preferable. Examples of such a material include amorphous silicon (a-Si), amorphous silicon carbide (a-SiC), amorphous silicon nitride (a-Si<sub>1&#x2212;x</sub>N<sub>x</sub>), and amorphous carbon (a-C). Such an inorganic amorphous insulating material forms no grain and thus has low water permeability. Therefore, a favorable protective film is obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0064">The sealing substrate <b>20</b> is to seal the organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B together with the adhesion layer (not shown). This sealing substrate <b>20</b> is composed of a material, such as glass, that is transparent to the respective color light beams generated by the organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B. The sealing substrate <b>20</b> may be provided with e.g. a color filter and a light blocking film as a black matrix (neither is shown). This can improve the contrast by extracting the respective color light beams generated by the organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B and absorbing ambient light reflected among the organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B and by wiring and so forth. The color filter has red, green, and blue filters disposed corresponding to the organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B and the filter of each color is composed of a resin in which a pigment is mixed. The light blocking film is formed of e.g. a resin film in which a black colorant is mixed or a thin film filter utilizing the interference of a thin film. The thin film filter is obtained by stacking one or more thin films composed of a metal, a metal nitride, or a metal oxide for example and is to attenuate light by utilizing the interference of the thin film.</p>
<p id="h-0009" num="0000">[Method for Manufacturing Organic EL Display Device]</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0065">The above-described organic EL display device <b>1</b> can be manufactured in the following manner for example. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A to 7G</figref> show a method for manufacturing the organic EL display device <b>1</b> in the step order.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0066">First, the drive board <b>10</b> having the interlayer insulating film <b>13</b> composed of an inorganic material as described above as its top surface (having the interlayer insulating film <b>13</b> covering the TFTs <b>11</b> and the wiring layer <b>12</b>) is prepared. The interlayer insulating film <b>13</b> is composed of an inorganic insulating material such as SiO<sub>2 </sub>as described above and can be deposited by e.g. a chemical vapor deposition (CVD) method. In this drive board <b>10</b>, contact holes are formed in the areas corresponding to the wiring layer <b>12</b> in the interlayer insulating film <b>13</b> by using photolithography technique and etching (wet etching or dry etching) technique, and the lower electrodes <b>14</b> composed of the above-described material are so deposited as to fill these contact holes.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0067">Thereafter, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</figref>, the deposited lower electrodes <b>14</b> are patterned into a rectangular shape having predetermined widths W (W<b>1</b>, W<b>2</b>). Subsequently, a resin material to become the bank layer <b>15</b> is deposited across the whole surface of the drive board <b>10</b> and then the apertures <b>15</b><i>a </i>are formed in the areas corresponding to the lower electrodes <b>14</b> by e.g. a photolithography method. At this time, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</figref>, the aperture <b>15</b><i>a </i>is so formed that its edge part <b>15</b><i>e </i>is separate from the end part <b>14</b><i>e </i>of the lower electrode <b>14</b> by the predetermined distance D. It is preferable to adjust the distance D by changing not the size of the lower electrode <b>14</b> but the size of the aperture <b>15</b><i>a </i>of the bank layer <b>15</b>. Specifically, in forming the aperture <b>15</b><i>a</i>, a photomask in which apertures are provided corresponding to the forming positions of the predetermined apertures <b>15</b><i>a </i>is used. The distance D is set by appropriately setting the shape and size of the apertures in the photomask. Furthermore, it is desirable that such a distance D satisfy the above-described expression (1).</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0068">Subsequently, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7C</figref>, lyophobic treatment is performed for the surface of the formed bank layer <b>15</b>. Examples of the lyophobic treatment include parallel-plate plasma treatment by use of a fluorine gas or a mixed gas thereof. In this lyophobic treatment, only the bank layer <b>15</b> composed of an organic material is turned to a lyophobic layer whereas the lower electrode <b>14</b> and the interlayer insulating film <b>13</b>, which are composed of an inorganic material, are not turned to lyophobic components and the lyophilicity is kept.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0069">Next, the functional layer <b>16</b> composed of the above-described material is formed in the plural apertures <b>15</b><i>a </i>of the bank layer <b>15</b> by a printing method (wet method). Specifically, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7D</figref>, first a functional layer material <b>160</b> (in this method, solution or dispersion liquid of e.g. polyaniline or polythiophene as a hole injection material) is applied by using a droplet discharge method or the like. Examples of the droplet discharge method include inkjet method, slit coating method, and nozzle coating method. The functional layer material <b>160</b> dropped in this manner is aggregated in the apertures <b>15</b><i>a </i>of the bank layer <b>15</b> due to the difference in the wettability between the bank layer <b>15</b> and the lower electrode <b>14</b> (and the interlayer insulating film <b>13</b>) (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7E</figref>). As the printing method, a plate printing method and so forth may be used besides the above-described droplet discharge method.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0070">Subsequently, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7F</figref>, heat treatment (drying treatment) is performed to form the functional layer <b>16</b> (in this step, hole injection layer <b>16</b><i>a</i>) in the respective apertures <b>15</b><i>a</i>. Specifically, the solvent or dispersion medium is dried and then heating at a high temperature is performed. If an electrically-conductive polymer such as polyaniline or polythiophene is used as the hole injection material, an air atmosphere or an oxygen atmosphere is preferable. This is because the electrical conductivity is easily developed due to oxidation of the electrically-conductive polymer by the oxygen. The heating temperature is e.g. 150&#xb0; C. to 300&#xb0; C., and the time is e.g. about 5 to 300 minutes although depending on the temperature and the atmosphere.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0071">In this drying step, the vicinity of the interface between layers that are different in the wettability (interface between the bank layer <b>15</b> and the interlayer insulating film <b>13</b>) acts as the origin of film thinning in the drying process and forms part of the above-described thinned part A. In contrast, the film thickness is substantially uniform in the area corresponding to the lower electrode <b>14</b> in the deposited hole injection layer <b>16</b><i>a </i>(light emitting area).</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0072">Thereafter, the hole transport layer <b>16</b><i>b </i>and the light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c </i>are deposited through the respective steps of applying, drying, and heat treatment similar to the above-described steps, to thereby form the functional layer <b>16</b>. In the functional layer <b>16</b>, these hole transport layer <b>16</b><i>b </i>and light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c </i>are sequentially stacked in the track of the shape of the above-described hole injection layer <b>16</b><i>a</i>. Therefore, substantially uniform film thickness is obtained in the light emitting area corresponding to the lower electrode <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0073">In depositing the hole transport layer <b>16</b><i>b</i>, it is preferable that the heat treatment step be performed in an atmosphere composed mainly of nitrogen (N<sub>2</sub>). Because the existence of oxygen and water possibly lowers the emission efficiency and lifetime of the fabricated organic EL display device, it is preferable that the oxygen concentration be set to e.g. 100 ppm or lower. It is desirable to set the heating temperature to e.g. 100&#xb0; C. to 230&#xb0; C. In depositing the light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c, </i>specifically the red light emitting material, the green light emitting material, and the blue light emitting material are each applied to the selected apertures <b>15</b><i>a </i>among the plural apertures <b>15</b><i>a </i>in the applying step so that the respective color light emitting layers may be disposed at predetermined positions. More specifically, a mixed solution or a dispersion liquid obtained by dissolving polymer material and low-molecular material as the constituent material of the respective color light emitting layers in a solvent prepared by mixing xylene and cyclohexylbenzene at a ratio of 2 to 8 for example is applied onto the hole transport layer <b>16</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0074">Next, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7G</figref>, the electron transport layer <b>17</b> and the upper electrode <b>18</b> composed of the above-described materials are formed in that order over the whole surface of the functional layer <b>16</b> by e.g. a vacuum evaporation method. An electron injection layer may be formed between the electron transport layer <b>17</b> and the upper electrode <b>18</b>. These electron transport layer <b>17</b> and upper electrode <b>18</b> (and electron injection layer, if it is formed) are successively deposited in the same film deposition apparatus without being exposed to the air. This successive film deposition prevents the deterioration of the functional layer <b>16</b> due to water in the air.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0075">After the upper electrode <b>18</b> is formed, the protective layer <b>19</b> is formed by e.g. an evaporation method or a CVD method. Thereafter, for example the sealing substrate <b>20</b> is bonded over the protective layer <b>19</b> with the intermediary of the adhesion layer (not shown). Through the above-described steps, the organic EL display device <b>1</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is completed.</p>
<p id="h-0010" num="0000">[Operation and Effects]</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0076">In the organic EL display device <b>1</b>, the scanning signal is supplied from the scanning line drive circuit <b>130</b> to the respective pixels via the gate electrode of the write transistor Tr<b>2</b> and the image signal from the signal line drive circuit <b>120</b> is held in the hold capacitance Cs via the write transistor Tr<b>2</b>. The drive transistor Tr<b>1</b> is on/off-controlled depending on the signal held in this hold capacitance Cs and a drive current Id is injected to the organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B. Thereby, in the organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B, light emission occurs due to recombination of hole and electron in the light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c</i>. In the case of the lower-surface light emission (bottom emission), the light generated in this manner is extracted after being transmitted through the lower electrode <b>14</b> and the drive board <b>10</b>. In the case of the upper-surface light emission (top emission), the light is extracted after being transmitted through the upper electrode <b>18</b>, the color filter (not shown), and the sealing substrate <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0077">In this organic EL display device <b>1</b>, in the present embodiment, the pixel areas corresponding to the respective pixels of R, G, and B are defined by the apertures <b>15</b><i>a </i>of the bank layer <b>15</b>. In this aperture <b>15</b><i>a</i>, the lower electrode <b>14</b> and the functional layer <b>16</b> including the light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c </i>are sequentially provided. In such an aperture <b>15</b><i>a</i>, the lower electrode <b>14</b> is disposed separately from the edge part <b>15</b><i>e </i>of the aperture <b>15</b><i>a. </i>Operation and effects obtained due to this arrangement of the aperture <b>15</b><i>a </i>and the lower electrode <b>14</b> will be described below by taking comparative examples (comparative examples 1 and 2).</p>
<heading id="h-0011" level="1">Comparative Example 1</heading>
<p id="p-0075" num="0078"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> shows the arrangement relationship between the aperture of the bank layer and the lower electrode according to comparative example 1. Also in this comparative example 1, similarly to the present embodiment, a lower electrode <b>104</b> is disposed on an interlayer insulating film <b>103</b> and this lower electrode <b>104</b> is electrically connected to a wiring layer <b>102</b>. A bank layer <b>105</b> for pixel isolation is provided on the interlayer insulating film <b>103</b> and the lower electrode <b>104</b>, and the bank layer <b>105</b> has an aperture <b>105</b><i>a </i>in the area corresponding to the lower electrode <b>104</b>. Furthermore, a functional layer <b>106</b> including a light emitting layer is deposited on the lower electrode <b>104</b> in this aperture <b>105</b><i>a </i>by a printing method including a step of applying a solution containing a functional layer material and a step of drying a solvent. That is, in comparative example 1, an edge part <b>105</b><i>e </i>of the aperture <b>105</b><i>a </i>is disposed on the surface (top surface) of the lower electrode <b>104</b>. Thus, the area corresponding to the part of the lower electrode <b>104</b> exposed by the aperture <b>105</b><i>a </i>serves as the light emitting area (light emitting area <b>100</b><i>a</i>).</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0079">However, if the edge part <b>105</b><i>e </i>of the aperture <b>105</b><i>a </i>is disposed on the lower electrode <b>104</b> like this comparative example 1, the following problem occurs in the film deposition process of the functional layer <b>106</b> (step of drying the solvent). Specifically, in the drying process, film thinning of the functional layer material occurs in such a manner as to originate from the vicinity of the interface between the bank layer <b>105</b> (lyophobic) and the lower electrode <b>104</b> (lyophilic). This forms a thinned part A<b>100</b> near the edge part <b>105</b><i>e </i>of the aperture <b>105</b><i>a</i>. That is, the thinned part A<b>100</b> is formed in the light emitting area <b>100</b><i>a </i>and unevenness of the film thickness arises in the part of the functional layer <b>106</b> contributing to light emission. As a result, electrical short-circuiting between the upper and lower electrodes readily occurs and the displayed-image quality is lowered.</p>
<heading id="h-0012" level="1">Comparative Example 2</heading>
<p id="p-0077" num="0080"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> shows the arrangement relationship between the aperture of the bank layer and the lower electrode (two-stage bank structure) according to comparative example 2. Also in this comparative example 2, similarly to the present embodiment and comparative example 1, the lower electrode <b>104</b> is disposed on the interlayer insulating film <b>103</b> and this lower electrode <b>104</b> is electrically connected to the wiring layer <b>102</b>. The bank layer <b>105</b> for pixel isolation is provided over the interlayer insulating film <b>103</b> and the lower electrode <b>104</b>, and the bank layer <b>105</b> has the aperture <b>105</b><i>a </i>in the area corresponding to the lower electrode <b>104</b>. Furthermore, the functional layer <b>106</b> including a light emitting layer is deposited on the lower electrode <b>104</b> in this aperture <b>105</b><i>a </i>by a printing method including a step of applying a solution containing a functional layer material and a step of drying a solvent. However, in comparative example 2, an inorganic insulating film <b>107</b> composed of e.g. SiO<sub>2 </sub>is provided between the lower electrode <b>104</b> and the bank layer <b>105</b> differently from comparative example 1. Specifically, the inorganic insulating film <b>107</b> having an aperture <b>107</b><i>a </i>is provided on the lower electrode <b>104</b> and the bank layer <b>105</b> is formed on this inorganic insulating film <b>107</b>. That is, in comparative example 2, the edge part <b>105</b><i>e </i>of the bank layer <b>105</b> is disposed on the inorganic insulating film <b>107</b>, and the area corresponding to the part of the lower electrode <b>104</b> exposed by the aperture <b>107</b><i>a </i>of the inorganic insulating film <b>107</b> serves as the light emitting area (light emitting area <b>100</b><i>b</i>).</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0081">If the inorganic insulating film <b>107</b> is provided between the bank layer <b>105</b> and the lower electrode <b>104</b> like in this comparative example 2, film thinning of the functional layer material occurs in such a manner as to originate from the vicinity of the interface between the bank layer <b>105</b> (lyophobic) and the inorganic insulating film <b>107</b> (lyophilic) in the drying process. This forms a thinned part A<b>101</b> near the edge part <b>105</b><i>e </i>of the aperture <b>105</b><i>a</i>. However, the occurrence of film thickness unevenness of the functional layer <b>106</b> is suppressed in the light emitting area <b>100</b><i>b</i>. However, in the method of this comparative example 2, after the lower electrode <b>104</b> is formed, a step of depositing and patterning the inorganic insulating film <b>107</b> is necessary before the bank layer <b>105</b> is formed. Thus, the number of steps and the number of parts increase and it is difficult to realize cost reduction.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0082">In contrast, in the present embodiment, in each aperture <b>15</b><i>a </i>of the bank layer <b>15</b>, the lower electrode <b>14</b> is provided on the interlayer insulating film <b>13</b> in such a manner that part or whole of the lower electrode <b>14</b> is separate from the edge part <b>15</b><i>e </i>of the aperture <b>15</b><i>a </i>as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. That is, the interlayer insulating film <b>13</b> having lyophilicity is exposed in the area between the bank layer <b>15</b> and the lower electrode <b>14</b>. Due to this feature, in depositing the functional layer <b>16</b>, film thinning of the functional layer material (hole injection material, in the embodiment) occurs in such a manner as to originate from the vicinity of the interface between the bank layer <b>15</b> and the exposed interlayer insulating film <b>13</b> (vicinity of the edge part <b>15</b><i>e </i>of the aperture <b>15</b><i>a</i>). Thus, the thinned part A is readily formed at a position distant from the lower electrode <b>14</b> (local thickness change of the functional layer <b>16</b> occurs less readily in the substantial light emitting area <b>10</b>L corresponding to the lower electrode <b>14</b>). This suppresses the occurrence of electrical short-circuiting between the lower electrode <b>14</b> and the upper electrode <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0083">As described above, in the present embodiment, the lower electrode <b>14</b> is disposed separately from the edge part <b>15</b><i>e </i>of the aperture <b>15</b><i>a </i>in the bank layer <b>15</b>. Therefore, the functional layer <b>16</b> is formed with substantially uniform film thickness in the light emitting area <b>10</b>L corresponding to the lower electrode <b>14</b> and thus the occurrence of electrical short-circuiting can be suppressed. Furthermore, a layer for preventing short-circuiting (inorganic insulating film <b>107</b> of the above-described comparative example 2) is not additionally provided, i.e. it is enough to merely adjust the size of the aperture <b>15</b><i>a </i>of the bank layer <b>15</b> (merely change the mask used in patterning the bank layer <b>15</b>). Therefore, the number of steps and the number of parts are not increased. Thus, the displayed-image quality can be enhanced with achievement of cost reduction.</p>
<heading id="h-0013" level="1">Working Example</heading>
<p id="p-0081" num="0084">About a pixel structure in which the lower electrode <b>14</b> was disposed separately from the bank layer <b>15</b> as described above, evaluation was made on the substantial aperture ratio and the lifetime. For this evaluation, first the following sample was formed as a working example. Specifically, a glass substrate (25 mm&#xd7;25 mm) was prepared as the substrate <b>10</b><i>a </i>and an SiO<sub>2 </sub>layer (film thickness 300 nm) as the interlayer insulating film <b>13</b> was formed on this substrate <b>10</b><i>a</i>. Thereafter, ITO (film thickness 60 nm) was deposited and patterning was performed by a photolithography method to thereby form the lower electrode <b>14</b>. Thereafter, a polyimide resin material was used as the bank layer <b>15</b>, and heat treatment (230&#xb0; C., one hour) was performed after the aperture <b>15</b><i>a </i>was formed. Thereafter, the lower electrode <b>14</b> was cleaned by oxygen plasma and then lyophobic treatment for the bank layer <b>15</b> was performed by plasma treatment by use of a CF<sub>4 </sub>gas.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0085">ND1501 (product name) made by Nissan Chemical Industries, Ltd. was applied as the hole injection layer <b>16</b><i>a </i>on the thus formed bank layer <b>15</b> by a nozzle coating method, and baking was performed in the air at 230&#xb0; C. for 30 minutes. Subsequently, a THF solution prepared by dissolving a hole transport material in xylene, a solvent having a boiling point higher than that of xylene, or a mixed solvent was applied as the hole transport layer <b>16</b><i>b </i>by a nozzle coating method. Thereafter, the inside of the applying apparatus was evacuated to a negative pressure state and the solvent was dried in a vacuum, followed by baking at 180&#xb0; C. for 30 minutes. Subsequently, the following materials were used as the light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c. </i>Specifically, for the B pixel, a blue light emitting polymer material BPP containing an iridium complex was used. For the G pixel, a green light emitting polymer material GPP was used. For the R pixel, a red light emitting polymer material RPP and a low-molecular material were used. Also for the light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c</i>, the inside of the applying apparatus was evacuated to a negative pressure state and the solvent was dried in a vacuum, followed by baking at 130&#xb0; C. for 30 minutes. Thereafter, the electron transport layer <b>17</b> and the upper electrode <b>18</b> were each deposited by vacuum evaporation.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0086">In the above-described structure, the distance D between the lower electrode <b>14</b> and the edge part <b>15</b><i>e </i>of the aperture <b>15</b><i>a </i>was changed in a stepwise manner from 1 &#x3bc;m to 15 &#x3bc;m, and the aperture ratio and the element lifetime were measured. These aperture ratio and element lifetime are shown as relative values when the aperture ratio and the element lifetime in the case of employing a two-stage bank structure like that explained in the above-described comparative example 2 are each defined as 100. In the two-stage bank structure (two-stage structure by the inorganic insulating film <b>107</b> and the bank layer <b>105</b>) of comparative example 2, SiO<sub>2 </sub>having a film thickness of 50 nm was used as the inorganic insulating film <b>107</b> and a polyimide resin having a film thickness of 1 &#x3bc;m was used as the bank layer <b>105</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> shows the relationship between the distance D and the aperture ratio measured in this manner. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> shows the relationship between the distance D and the element lifetime.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0087">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, it turns out that the uniformity of the film thickness of the functional layer <b>16</b> is ensured more easily and the aperture ratio and the element lifetime are enhanced as the distance D becomes longer. In particular, it also turns out that effects almost equivalent to those when the two-stage bank structure is formed are achieved if the distance D is equal to or longer than 5 &#x3bc;m. That is, the experiment made it clear that a distance of 5 &#x3bc;m or longer is desirable as the distance D between the lower electrode <b>14</b> and the edge part <b>15</b><i>e </i>of the aperture <b>15</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0088">Modification examples of the above-described embodiment (modification examples 1 and 2) will be described below. The same constituent element as that of the above-described embodiment is given the same numeral and description is accordingly omitted.</p>
<heading id="h-0014" level="1">Modification Example 1</heading>
<p id="p-0086" num="0089"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12 to 18B</figref> are diagrams for explaining the arrangement relationship between the lower electrode <b>14</b> and the aperture <b>15</b><i>a </i>of the bank layer <b>15</b> according to modification example 1. In the explanation of the above-described embodiment, applying the functional layer material by e.g. a droplet discharge method in depositing the functional layer <b>16</b> is described. Specifically, this applying is performed by dropping a predetermined amount of functional layer material from nozzles provided in applying apparatus. Providing the same number of nozzles as the number of pixels (the number of pixel rows) in the applying apparatus causes much size increase of the nozzle head and results in a huge apparatus scale. Therefore, it is desirable to provide a predetermined number of nozzles in the applying apparatus and drop the functional layer material with reciprocation scanning in units of predetermined pixel rows as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> to thereby apply the functional layer material onto the whole substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0090">In the case of dropping the functional layer material with reciprocation scanning in this manner, difference arises in the film thickness of the functional layer <b>16</b> after drying between pixels Pe located at the end part of the bank layer <b>15</b> (specifically, end part as a turning point of the reciprocation scanning) and the other pixels Pc (e.g. pixels located at the center part). Thus, in the present modification example, the distance D between the lower electrode <b>14</b> and the edge part <b>15</b><i>e </i>of the aperture <b>15</b><i>a </i>is so set as to differ depending on the pixel position.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0091">Specifically, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, in the pixel Pc at the center part, both of the widths (distances D) of areas Sa and Sb on both sides of the lower electrode <b>14</b> are d<b>1</b> in the direction along the traveling direction of a scanning direction S<b>1</b>. This is because of the following reason. Specifically, in the pixel located at part other than the end part like the center part, the adjacent pixel exists along the scanning direction S<b>1</b>. Thus, the amount of dropping is equivalent between both sides of the lower electrode <b>14</b> and the film thickness of the functional layer <b>16</b> after applying and drying becomes substantially uniform.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0092">In contrast, in the pixel Pe at the end part, the adjacent pixel does not exist along the traveling direction of the scanning direction S<b>1</b>. Therefore, if both of the distances D of the areas Sa and Sb are set equivalent to that in the pixel Pc (=d<b>1</b>), a thinned part A<b>1</b> is so formed as to overlap with the light emitting area <b>10</b>L on the end part side of the functional layer <b>16</b>, and film thickness unevenness referred to as so-called swath unevenness occurs (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14A</figref>). This is because the dropped part of the functional layer material and the non-dropped part exist in a mixed manner at the end part as a turning point of the reciprocation scanning. Therefore, in such an end-part pixel Pe, the distance D of the area Sb on the end part side (=d<b>2</b>) is set longer than the distance D in the other pixels (=d<b>1</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0093">For locally changing the distance D, it is preferable to adjust the aperture area of the aperture <b>15</b><i>a </i>in the bank layer <b>15</b> without changing the size of the lower electrode <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0094">The distance D may be changed depending on the pixel position like in the present modification example. For example, the distance D can be set relatively long in the pixel located at the scanning end, whereas the distance D can be set relatively short in the pixel located at the center part. Due to this feature, advantageous effects equivalent to those of the above-described embodiment are achieved. In addition, swath unevenness is suppressed and favorable displayed-image quality can be realized in the whole display area.</p>
<heading id="h-0015" level="1">Modification Example 2</heading>
<p id="p-0092" num="0095"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> shows the sectional configuration of an organic EL display device according to modification example 2. In the present modification example, similarly to the above-described embodiment, the bank layer <b>15</b> having the plural apertures <b>15</b><i>a </i>exists over the drive board <b>10</b> and the lower electrode <b>14</b> is disposed in each aperture <b>15</b><i>a </i>separately from the edge part <b>15</b><i>e </i>of the aperture <b>15</b><i>a</i>. The functional layer <b>16</b> including the light emitting layer <b>16</b><i>c </i>is deposited on the lower electrode <b>14</b> by a printing method and the electron transport layer <b>17</b> and the upper electrode <b>18</b> are provided over the functional layer <b>16</b>. The protective film <b>19</b> and the sealing substrate <b>20</b> exist over this upper electrode <b>18</b> although not shown in the diagram.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0096">In the present modification example, an organic planarizing film <b>21</b> is provided in the drive board <b>10</b> together with the interlayer insulating film <b>13</b> in such a manner as to cover the TFTs <b>11</b> and the wiring layer <b>12</b>. In the case of using such an organic planarizing film <b>21</b>, the organic planarizing film <b>21</b> is disposed only under the lower electrode <b>14</b>. Alternatively, it may be disposed under the bank layer <b>15</b>. However, the interlayer insulating film <b>13</b> is exposed in the area opposed to the edge part <b>15</b><i>e </i>of the aperture <b>15</b><i>a </i>of the bank layer <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0097">The organic planarizing film <b>21</b> may be provided in a predetermined area of the drive board <b>10</b> like in the present modification example. Also in such a configuration, the thinned part of the functional layer <b>16</b> can be formed outside the light emitting area and advantageous effects as those of the above-described embodiment can be achieved as long as the interlayer insulating film <b>13</b> composed of an inorganic material is formed opposed to at least the edge part <b>15</b><i>e </i>of the aperture <b>15</b><i>a </i>of the bank layer <b>15</b>.</p>
<heading id="h-0016" level="1">APPLICATION EXAMPLES</heading>
<p id="p-0095" num="0098">Application examples of the organic EL display device explained in the above-described embodiment and modification examples will be described below. The organic EL display device of the above-described embodiment and so forth can be applied to electronic apparatus in every field, such as television devices, digital cameras, notebook personal computers, portable terminal devices typified by cellular phones, and video camcorders. In other words, the organic EL display device of the above-described embodiment and so forth can be applied to electronic apparatus in every field that displays a video signal input from the external or a video signal generated inside as image or video.</p>
<heading id="h-0017" level="1">Module</heading>
<p id="p-0096" num="0099">The organic EL display device of the above-described embodiment and so forth is incorporated into various pieces of electronic apparatus such as application examples 1 to 5 to be described later as a module shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref> for example. This module is obtained e.g. by setting an area <b>210</b> exposed from the sealing substrate <b>20</b> along one side of the drive board <b>10</b> and forming an external connection terminal (not shown) in this exposed area <b>210</b> by extending the wiring of the signal line drive circuit <b>120</b> and the scanning line drive circuit <b>130</b>. The external connection terminal is provided with a flexible printed circuit (FPC) <b>220</b> for signal input/output.</p>
<heading id="h-0018" level="1">Application Example 1</heading>
<p id="p-0097" num="0100"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</figref> shows the appearance of a television device according to application example 1. This television device has e.g. a video display screen section <b>300</b> including a front panel <b>310</b> and a filter glass <b>320</b>, and this video display screen section <b>300</b> is configured by the organic EL display device according to the above-described embodiment and so forth.</p>
<heading id="h-0019" level="1">Application Example 2</heading>
<p id="p-0098" num="0101"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 18A and 18B</figref> show the appearance of a digital camera according to application example 2. This digital camera has e.g. a light emitter <b>410</b> for flash, a display section <b>420</b>, a menu switch <b>430</b>, and a shutter button <b>440</b>, and the display section <b>420</b> is configured by the organic EL display device according to the above-described embodiment and so forth.</p>
<heading id="h-0020" level="1">Application Example 3</heading>
<p id="p-0099" num="0102"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</figref> shows the appearance of a notebook personal computer according to application example 3. This notebook personal computer has e.g. a main body <b>510</b>, a keyboard <b>520</b> for input operation of characters and so forth, and a display section <b>530</b> that displays images, and the display section <b>530</b> is configured by the organic EL display device according to the above-described embodiment and so forth.</p>
<heading id="h-0021" level="1">Application Example 4</heading>
<p id="p-0100" num="0103"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</figref> shows the appearance of a video camcorder according to application example 4. This video camcorder has e.g. a main body section <b>610</b>, a lens <b>620</b> that is provided on the front side of this main body section <b>610</b> and is used for subject photographing, a start/stop switch <b>630</b> about photographing, and a display section <b>640</b>, and the display section <b>640</b> is configured by the organic EL display device according to the above-described embodiment and so forth.</p>
<heading id="h-0022" level="1">Application Example 5</heading>
<p id="p-0101" num="0104"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 21A to 21G</figref> shows the appearance of a cellular phone according to application example 5. This cellular phone is made by coupling an upper chassis <b>710</b> with a lower chassis <b>720</b> by a coupling part (hinge part) <b>730</b> and has a display <b>740</b>, a sub-display <b>750</b>, a picture light <b>760</b>, and a camera <b>770</b>. The display <b>740</b> or the sub-display <b>750</b> is configured by the organic EL display device according to the above-described embodiment and so forth.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0105">Although embodiment, modification examples, and application examples of the present disclosure are described above, the present disclosure is not limited to the embodiment and so forth and various modifications are possible. For example, the materials, thicknesses, film deposition methods, film deposition conditions, and so forth of the respective layers explained in the above-described embodiment and so forth are not limited. Other materials, thicknesses, film deposition methods, and film deposition conditions may be employed.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0106">The above-described embodiment and so forth are explained by taking as an example the case in which the whole lower electrode <b>14</b> (all of four end parts corresponding to all sides of the rectangular shape) is disposed separately from the edge part <b>15</b><i>e </i>of the aperture <b>15</b><i>a </i>of the bank layer <b>15</b>. However, the whole part does not necessarily need to be separated. For example, part of the lower electrode <b>14</b> may be in contact with the bank layer <b>15</b>. For example, the lower electrode <b>14</b> is electrically connected to the wiring layer <b>12</b>, which is provided under the lower electrode <b>14</b> and includes the drain electrode and so forth. This connection part may be formed in contact with the bank layer <b>15</b>. Alternatively, because such a connection part is so formed as to fill the contact hole formed in the interlayer insulating film, normally the electrode material sinks down in the area corresponding to this connection part and a hollow is generated in the lower electrode surface. The bank layer may be so provided as to overlap with such a hollow part.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0107">Furthermore, the above-described embodiment and so forth are explained by specifically describing the configuration of the organic EL elements <b>10</b>R, <b>10</b>G, and <b>10</b>B. However, these elements do not necessarily need to include all layers and may further include another layer. Moreover, in the above-described embodiment and so forth, a display device including red and green organic EL elements as organic EL elements other than blue organic EL elements is explained. However, an embodiment of the present disclosure is not limited thereto and can be applied to the overall display devices in which a functional layer can be formed by using a printing method. For example, an embodiment of the present disclosure can be applied also to a display device including blue organic EL elements and yellow organic EL elements.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0108">In addition, in the above-described embodiment and so forth, an active-matrix display device is explained. However, an embodiment of the present disclosure can be applied also to a passive-matrix display device. Furthermore, the configuration of the pixel drive circuit for active-matrix driving is not limited to that explained in the above-described embodiment and capacitive element and transistor may be added according to need. In this case, corresponding to the change in the pixel drive circuit, a desired drive circuit may be added besides the above-described signal line drive circuit <b>120</b> and scanning line drive circuit <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0109">Furthermore, in the above-described embodiment and so forth, the case in which the organic EL display device is a top emission type or a bottom emission type is explained. However, an embodiment of the present disclosure can be applied also to an organic EL display device of such a type that light is extracted from both upper surface and lower surface.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0110">The present disclosure contains subject matter related to that disclosed in Japanese Priority Patent Application JP 2011-053989 filed in the Japan Patent Office on Mar. 11, 2011, the entire content of which is hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0111">It should be understood by those skilled in the art that various modifications, combinations, sub-combinations and alterations may occur depending on design requirements and other factors insofar as they are within the scope of the appended claims or the equivalents thereof.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is: </us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An organic electroluminescence display device comprising:
<claim-text>a pixel isolating film configured to be provided over a substrate and have a plurality of apertures; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of pixels configured to be provided corresponding to the plurality of apertures, wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of the plurality of pixels has a first electrode, a functional layer including at least an organic light emitting layer, and a second electrode sequentially from a side of the substrate, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>part or whole of the first electrode is separate from an edge part of the aperture on the side of the substrates;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a separation distance between the first electrode and the edge part differs depending on position of the aperture in the pixel isolating film.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The organic electroluminescence display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the pixel isolating film has lyophobicity, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first electrode and the pixel isolating film are provided over the substrate with intermediary of a lyophilic film.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The organic electroluminescence display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>a transistor section that drives the pixels and an interlayer insulating film covering the transistor section exist over the substrate, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the interlayer insulating film serves also as the lyophilic film.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The organic electroluminescence display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>an organic planarizing film is provided in a selective area under the first electrode.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The organic electroluminescence display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the lyophilic film contains at least one kind of a silicon oxide, a silicon nitride, a titanium oxide, and a titanium nitride.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The organic electroluminescence display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the pixel isolating film is composed of any of a polyimide resin, an acrylic resin, and a novolac resin.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The organic electroluminescence display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the functional layer is composed of a polymer material.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The organic electroluminescence display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the first electrode is provided inside the edge part of the aperture on the lyophilic film.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The organic electroluminescence display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the first electrode is provided separately from the edge part of the aperture by at least 5 &#x3bc;m.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The organic electroluminescence display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the functional layer has a locally thinned part in an area between the edge part of the aperture and the first electrode.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. Electronic apparatus including an organic electroluminescence display device comprising:
<claim-text>a pixel isolating film configured to be provided over a substrate and have a plurality of apertures; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of pixels configured to be provided corresponding to the plurality of apertures, wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of the plurality of pixels has a first electrode, a functional layer including at least an organic light emitting layer, and a second electrode sequentially from a side of the substrate, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>part or whole of the first electrode is separate from an edge part of the aperture on the side of the substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a separation distance between the first electrode and the edge part differs depending on position of the aperture in the pixel isolating film.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
