<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624101-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624101</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13211244</doc-number>
<date>20110816</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>100124126 A</doc-number>
<date>20110707</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>219</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>042</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>136246</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Adjustable solar power generation apparatus</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4055761</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Shimomura</name>
<date>19771000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>250239</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6064533</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kenin et al.</name>
<date>20000500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>359695</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0277498</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Angel</name>
<date>20091100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>136246</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2010-0004020</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20100100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-cpc-text>F24J 2/38</classification-cpc-text>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO 2010098611</doc-number>
<kind>A2</kind>
<date>20100900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>136246</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>10</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>136246</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>136259</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130008505</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130110</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Pei</last-name>
<first-name>Shao-Kai</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Pei</last-name>
<first-name>Shao-Kai</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Berdichevsky</last-name>
<first-name>Miriam</first-name>
<department>1754</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An adjustable solar power generation apparatus includes a solar power generation unit, a base, and a supporting bar supporting the base. The base accommodates the solar power generation unit. The supporting bar supports the base. The solar power generation unit includes a fixed lens unit and a solar cell. The fixed lens unit includes a converging lens to converge sunlight. The solar cell is located in the fixed lens unit, and is capable of moving toward or away from the converging lens to adjust the light intensity received by the solar cell.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="197.78mm" wi="139.87mm" file="US08624101-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="227.67mm" wi="116.67mm" file="US08624101-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="212.94mm" wi="147.07mm" file="US08624101-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="209.47mm" wi="95.25mm" file="US08624101-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="207.35mm" wi="110.32mm" file="US08624101-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="217.17mm" wi="138.68mm" file="US08624101-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to generation apparatus utilizing solar power, especially relating to an adjustable solar power generation apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Many solar power generation apparatus are equipped with a solar track system to follow the changing of solar position throughout the day to maximize receiving of solar radiation. However, the light intensity received by the solar cells will still fluctuate during the day. Therefore, the solar cells will age quickly, and the power output will fluctuate, influencing the stability of the apparatus. If such solar power generation is equipped with a zooming converged lens assembly to converge sunlight at different location and adjust the light intensity received by the solar cells, it will complicate the control process of the solar power generation apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">What is needed, therefore, is an adjustable solar power generation apparatus that will overcome the afore mentioned shortcomings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Many aspects of the present adjustable solar power generation apparatus can be better understood with reference to the following drawings. The components in the drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the present adjustable solar power generation apparatus. Moreover, in the drawings, like reference numerals designate corresponding parts throughout the views.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view of an adjustable solar power generation apparatus of a first exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a partially exploded view about a solar power generation unit and the apparatus of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows the solar power generation unit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, but shows the solar power generation unit from an opposite view.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a schematic view of an adjustable solar power generation apparatus of a second exemplary embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, an adjustable solar power generation apparatus <b>100</b> provided by a first exemplary embodiment includes a solar power generation unit <b>300</b>, a cover <b>50</b>, a base <b>20</b>, and a supporting bar <b>80</b>. The supporting bar <b>80</b> supports the base <b>20</b>. The supporting bar <b>80</b> is capable of rotating according to the location of the sun. The base <b>20</b> accommodates the solar power generation unit <b>300</b>. The cover <b>50</b> is located in front of the solar power generation unit <b>300</b>. The cover <b>50</b> and the base <b>20</b> may be omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Referring also to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref>, the solar power generation unit <b>300</b> includes a fixed lens unit <b>10</b>, a movable barrel <b>120</b>, a solar cell <b>30</b>, and a drive unit <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The fixed lens unit <b>10</b> has a fixed focal length. The fixed lens unit <b>10</b> includes a fixed barrel <b>101</b>, and a converging lens <b>102</b>. The fixed barrel <b>101</b> has a first end <b>1011</b> and an opposite second end <b>1013</b>. The fixed barrel <b>101</b> includes a rim <b>1012</b>, which surrounds the fixed barrel <b>101</b> at the first end <b>1011</b> thereof. The fixed barrel <b>101</b> does not move relative to the movable barrel <b>120</b>. The converging lens <b>102</b> is placed at the second end <b>1013</b> of the fixed barrel <b>101</b> to receive sunlight. The converging lens <b>102</b> is a plano-convex lens or other kind of converging lens. In one embodiment, the converging lens <b>102</b> is coated with a layer of anti-reflective film (not shown). The fixed barrel <b>101</b> has threads <b>1010</b> in its inner wall. There may be a lens assembly located in the fixed barrel <b>101</b> according to need.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The movable barrel <b>120</b> has an inner bottom surface <b>1201</b> and an outer bottom surface <b>1202</b> at opposite sides of a bottom thereof. The solar cell <b>30</b> is placed at the inner bottom surface <b>1201</b>. The movable barrel <b>120</b> has threads <b>1203</b> in its outer wall. The movable barrel <b>120</b> has a smaller diameter than the fixed barrel <b>101</b>. The movable barrel <b>120</b> is located inside and threadedly engaged with the fixed barrel <b>101</b>. The solar cell <b>30</b> receives sunlight passing through the converging lens <b>102</b> and generates electricity. The electricity is stored by a battery (not shown) and is received via a wire <b>503</b>. There may be more solar cells or a solar panel located in the movable barrel <b>120</b> according to need.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The drive unit <b>40</b> is located outside the movable barrel <b>120</b> to move the movable barrel <b>120</b> forward or backward in reference to the converging lens <b>102</b> for adjusting a light intensity and a light receiving area of the solar cell <b>30</b>. For example, the drive unit <b>40</b> includes a connecting rod <b>14</b> and a stepper motor <b>16</b>. The connecting rod <b>14</b> connects the movable barrel <b>120</b> and the stepper motor <b>16</b>. The stepper motor <b>16</b> is powered by a power source (not shown). The drive unit <b>40</b> may also drive the solar cell <b>30</b> directly in other embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The base <b>20</b> is substantially a cylinder and has an upper surface <b>201</b> and a lower surface <b>202</b> at opposite sides thereof. A central area of the per surface <b>201</b> sinks inwards to define a recess <b>200</b>, and the rim <b>1012</b> of the fixed barrel <b>101</b> is in contact with the upper surface <b>201</b>. The drive unit <b>40</b> is located at the bottom of the recess <b>200</b>. The movable barrel <b>120</b> is capable of moving within the recess <b>200</b>. That is, the recess <b>200</b> provides a moving space for the movable barrel <b>120</b>, and receives the drive unit <b>40</b>. One end of the supporting bar <b>80</b> is connected to the lower surface <b>202</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The cover <b>50</b> is made of glass. The cover <b>50</b> is located over the fixed lens unit <b>10</b> to protect the fixed lens unit <b>10</b> from rain when the optical axis of the converging lens <b>102</b> is perpendicular to the ground when it is rainy. In detail, the cover <b>50</b> is positioned on a light path of incident light of the fixed lens unit <b>10</b>. The cover <b>50</b> includes a light receiving surface <b>500</b> and a back surface <b>502</b> at opposite sides thereof. The light receiving surface <b>500</b> may be coated with an anti-reflective layer <b>501</b> to increase the sunlight transmission intensity. Three connection posts <b>506</b> are interconnected between the upper surface <b>201</b> and the back surface <b>502</b>, so that the cover <b>50</b> is connected to the base <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The solar power generation unit <b>300</b> is capable of adjusting the distance between the solar cell <b>30</b> and the converging lens <b>102</b>. In this embodiment, the converging lens <b>102</b> or a similar converging lens assembly has a definite focal length. Assuming the incident light flux is definite, when the incident light is focused at a small area of the solar cell <b>30</b>, the light intensity for the solar cell <b>30</b> will be high, then the drive unit <b>40</b> will drive the movable barrel <b>120</b> to move away from the focal plane, thus the converged incident light will fall on a bigger area than before, and therefore the light intensity will drop. In this way, the light intensity received by the solar cell <b>30</b> is adjusted to be stable, and the power output will be stable and the solar cell <b>30</b> will have a longer working life. In some embodiments, known methods may be employed to sense the light intensity received by the solar cell <b>30</b> to help the drive unit <b>40</b> decide if it is necessary to move the movable barrel <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, an adjustable solar power generation apparatus <b>700</b> of a second exemplary embodiment further includes a light-concentrating reflector <b>60</b> as well as the solar power generation unit <b>300</b>, the cover <b>50</b>, and the base <b>20</b>. The light-concentrating reflector <b>60</b> is located opposite the solar power generation unit <b>300</b>. The light-concentrating reflector <b>60</b> and the base <b>20</b> are positioned at opposite sides of the cover <b>50</b>. The light-concentrating reflector <b>60</b> includes a reflective surface <b>600</b> for reflecting the sunlight to the solar power generation unit <b>300</b>, and a rim <b>601</b> surrounding the reflective surface <b>600</b>. The reflective surface <b>600</b> is of concave curvature. The solar power generation unit <b>300</b> is located at the focal point of the reflective surface <b>600</b> to receive the sunlight converged by the light-concentrating reflector <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The adjustable solar power generation apparatus <b>700</b> includes a connecting unit <b>504</b> connecting the rim <b>601</b> and the cover <b>50</b> (or alternatively connecting the rim <b>601</b> and the base <b>20</b> as a whole&#x2014;not shown), and two connection poles <b>30</b> connecting the base <b>20</b> and the cover <b>50</b>. The connecting unit <b>504</b> includes three straight bars <b>508</b> in this embodiment. In detail, one end of each of the straight bars <b>508</b> is connected to the rim <b>601</b>, and the other end of each of the straight bars <b>508</b> is connected to the light receiving surface <b>500</b>. One end of each of the connection poles <b>30</b> is connected to the back surface <b>502</b>, and the other end of each of the connection poles <b>30</b> is connected to the base <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">It is understood that the above-described embodiments are intended to illustrate rather than limit the disclosure. Variations may be made to the embodiments without departing from the spirit of the disclosure. Accordingly, it is appropriate that the appended claims be construed broadly and in a manner consistent with the scope of the disclosure.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An adjustable solar power generation apparatus, comprising:
<claim-text>a solar power generation unit comprising:
<claim-text>a fixed lens unit comprising a fixed barrel and a converging lens configured for converging sunlight, the fixed barrel having a first end and an opposite second end, the fixed barrel comprising a rim surrounding the first end thereof, the converging lens positioned at the second end of the fixed barrel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a movable barrel located inside and threadedly engaged with the fixed barrel, the movable barrel comprising an inner bottom surface facing the converging lens and an outer bottom surface, the inner bottom surface and the outer bottom surface located at opposite sides of a bottom of the movable barrel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a solar cell located on the inner bottom surface for receiving the converged sunlight; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a drive unit located outside the movable barrel and connected to the movable barrel:</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a base being substantially a cylinder and comprising an upper surface and a lower surface at opposite sides thereof, the upper surface defining a recess, the rim in contact with the upper surface, the drive unit located at the bottom of the recess and driving the movable barrel to move toward or away from the converging lens so as to move the solar cell toward or away from the converging lens to adjust a light intensity of the converged sunlight received by the solar cell, the recess thereby providing a moving space for the movable barrel to move toward or away from the converging lens; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a supporting bar connected to the lower surface of the base.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The adjustable solar power generation apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the drive unit comprises a connecting rod and a stepper motor, and the connecting rod connects the stepper motor and the movable barrel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The adjustable solar power generation apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, further comprising a cover and three connection posts, wherein the cover comprises a light receiving surface and a back surface at opposite sides thereof, and the connection posts are each interconnected between the upper surface and the back surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The adjustable solar power generation apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the cover is made of glass.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The adjustable solar power generation apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the cover further comprises an anti-reflection layer formed on the light receiving surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. An adjustable solar power generation apparatus, comprising:
<claim-text>a solar power generation unit comprising:
<claim-text>a fixed lens unit comprising a fixed barrel and a converging lens configured for converging sunlight, the fixed barrel having a first end and an opposite second end, the fixed barrel comprising a rim surrounding the first end thereof, the converging lens positioned at the second end of the fixed barrel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a movable barrel located inside and threadedly engaged with the fixed barrel, the movable barrel comprising an inner bottom surface facing the converging lens and an outer bottom surface, the inner bottom surface and the outer bottom surface located at opposite sides of a bottom of the movable barrel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a solar cell located on the inner bottom surface for receiving the converged sunlight; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a drive unit located outside the movable barrel and connected to the movable barrel;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a base being substantially a cylinder and comprising an upper surface and a lower surface at opposite sides thereof, the upper surface defining a recess, the rim in contact with the upper surface, the drive unit located at the bottom of the recess and driving the movable barrel to move toward or away from the converging lens so as to move the solar cell toward or away from the converging lens to adjust a light intensity of the converged sunlight received by the solar cell, the recess thereby providing a moving space for the movable barrel to move toward or away from the converging lens;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cover comprising a light receiving surface and a back surface at opposite sides thereof, the base fixed to the back surface, the fixed lens unit facing the back surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light-concentrating reflector comprising an inwardly curved reflective surface for reflecting sunlight to the converging lens and a rim surrounding the reflective surface; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a connecting unit connecting the rim of the light-concentrating reflector and the light receiving surface.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The adjustable solar power generation apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the converging lens is located at the focal point of the reflective surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The adjustable solar power generation apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the connecting unit comprises three bars, one end of each of the bars is connected to the rim, and the other end of each of the bars is connected to the light receiving surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The adjustable solar power generation apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising two connection poles, wherein one end of each of the connection poles is connected to the back surface, and the other end of each of the connection poles is connected to the base.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The adjustable solar power generation apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the drive unit comprises a connecting rod and a stepper motor, and the connecting rod connects the stepper motor and the movable barrel. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
