<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624763-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624763</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13413406</doc-number>
<date>20120306</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>1</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>M</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>M</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>12</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>341110</main-classification>
<further-classification>341118</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Offset cancellation for analog to digital converters</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6531907</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Dooley et al.</name>
<date>20030300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7548115</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Liu</name>
<date>20090600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7812665</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Eschauzier et al.</name>
<date>20101000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8040180</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Yen et al.</name>
<date>20111000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8223047</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Lai et al.</name>
<date>20120700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>341120</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0316629</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Zhang</name>
<date>20111200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>19</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>341110</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>341118-120</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>341156-159</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12822811</doc-number>
<date>20100624</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8154338</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13413406</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120161991</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120628</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Zhang</last-name>
<first-name>Bo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Rancho Santa Margarita</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Zhang</last-name>
<first-name>Bo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Rancho Santa Margarita</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Sterne, Kessler, Goldstein &#x26; Fox P.L.L.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Broadcom Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Irvine</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Nguyen</last-name>
<first-name>Hieu</first-name>
<department>2817</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An offset cancellation circuit for canceling an offset voltage in an amplifier is provided herein. The offset cancellation circuit includes a current source configured to provide an offset current, a switching stage comprising first and second switches, and a cascode stage. The cascode stage comprises a first cascode device configured to receive the offset current from the first switch and inject the offset current into a first differential end of the amplifier, and a second cascode device configured to receive the offset current from the second switch and inject the offset current into a second differential end of the amplifier. Offset voltages are common to many differential circuits as a result of mismatch. The injection of current by the offset cancellation circuit can reduce or eliminate an offset voltage, while the cascode stage can prevent parasitic capacitance associated with the offset cancellation circuit from creating further mismatch.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="123.61mm" wi="220.56mm" file="US08624763-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="180.68mm" wi="118.19mm" file="US08624763-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="210.74mm" wi="144.02mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624763-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="207.43mm" wi="139.36mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624763-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="224.37mm" wi="139.02mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624763-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="202.27mm" wi="132.33mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624763-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="220.05mm" wi="135.38mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624763-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="220.47mm" wi="135.13mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624763-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="210.90mm" wi="134.96mm" file="US08624763-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 12/822,811, filed on Jun. 24, 2010, which is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This application relates generally to offset cancellation and more particularly to offset cancellation for differential circuits.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">There exist several types of non-idealities that limit the performance of analog circuits. For example, common types of non-idealities include frequency response, noise, nonlinearity, and mismatch. Mismatch is particularly important in the design of high-precision differential circuits, such as differential amplifiers, that include two, ideally symmetric sides. Because of mismatches, the two sides of a differential circuit typically do not exhibit identical properties and bias currents, leading to adverse effects in the performance of these circuits.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In an integrated circuit (IC), mismatches in a differential circuit result from microscopic variations in devices used to implement the differential circuit. For example, random, microscopic variations in the length and width of the gates of two transistors (e.g., MOSFETs) that are identically laid out and used on each side of a differential circuit result in mismatch. In addition, random variances in doping levels in the channels and gates of two identically laid out devices result in threshold (V<sub>TH</sub>) mismatches.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">A traditional approach to reducing the adverse effects of mismatches in a differential circuit is to increase the size of the devices used in its implementation. For example, in a differential circuit that uses MOSFET devices, the width and length of those devices can be increased to reduce their relative mismatches, &#x394;W/W and &#x394;L/L. The magnitude of the relative mismatches decreases because as W and L increase, random variations experience greater &#x201c;averaging.&#x201d; However, increasing W and L correspondingly results in a higher power requirement and/or a lower speed at which these larger devices can operate.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">More specifically, the dynamic power of a MOSFET device is generally given by the following equation:
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>P</i><sub>dynamic</sub><i>=CV</i><sub>DD</sub><sup>2</sup><i>f </i><?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
where C is the channel capacitance (which is proportional to WL), V<sub>DD </sub>is the supply voltage, and f is the switching frequency or average switching frequency of the MOSFET. As can be readily seen, any increase in W or L leads to an increase in the channel capacitance C and a corresponding increase in the dynamic power consumption of the MOSFET. To compensate for the additional power requirement, the frequency or speed at which the device operates can be reduced or additional power can be supplied. Either way, there is a tradeoff between increasing the size of the device to limit the magnitude of relative mismatches and the power and/or speed at which the device operates.
</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Therefore, what is needed is a system for minimizing the adverse effects caused by mismatches used in the implementation of differential circuits, while at the same time limiting additional power requirements and/or speed limitations.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS/FIGURES</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The accompanying drawings, which are incorporated herein and form a part of the specification, illustrate the present invention and, together with the description, further serve to explain the principles of the invention and to enable a person skilled in the pertinent art to make and use the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates an exemplary differential amplifier, according to embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates a limitation imposed on a differential amplifier as a result of an offset voltage caused by random mismatches.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates another limitation imposed on a differential amplifier as a result of an offset voltage caused by random mismatches.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates a differential amplifier configuration with an offset cancellation circuit, according to embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates a differential amplifier configuration with an offset cancellation circuit and the exemplary differential amplifier illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, according to embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates a potential adverse effect of the offset cancellation circuit illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, according to embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates a differential amplifier configuration with an offset cancellation circuit with reduced parasitic capacitance coupling, according to embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> illustrates a variation of the differential amplifier configuration with an offset cancellation circuit illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, according to embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> illustrates one exemplary operating environment or device that can benefit from the use of offset cancellation circuit <b>720</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, according to embodiments of the present invention</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The present invention will be described with reference to the accompanying drawings. The drawing in which an element first appears is typically indicated by the leftmost digit(s) in the corresponding reference number.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In the following description, numerous specific details are set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding of the invention. However, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art that the invention, including structures, systems, and methods, may be practiced without these specific details. The description and representation herein are the common means used by those experienced or skilled in the art to most effectively convey the substance of their work to others skilled in the art. In other instances, well-known methods, procedures, components, and circuitry have not been described in detail to avoid unnecessarily obscuring aspects of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">References in the specification to &#x201c;one embodiment,&#x201d; &#x201c;an embodiment,&#x201d; &#x201c;an example embodiment,&#x201d; etc., indicate that the embodiment described may include a particular feature, structure, or characteristic, but every embodiment may not necessarily include the particular feature, structure, or characteristic. Moreover, such phrases are not necessarily referring to the same embodiment. Further, when a particular feature, structure, or characteristic is described in connection with an embodiment, it is submitted that it is within the knowledge of one skilled in the art to effect such feature, structure, or characteristic in connection with other embodiments whether or not explicitly described.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates an exemplary differential amplifier <b>100</b>, according to embodiments of the present invention. Amplifier <b>100</b> includes a pair of NMOS transistors M<b>1</b> and M<b>2</b> that have their sources coupled to each other and to current source CS. Current source CS behaves as a current sink and draws a predetermined, constant current from transistors M<b>1</b> and M<b>2</b>. The gate of transistor M<b>1</b> receives a first, positive end of differential input signal V<sub>IN </sub>and the gate of M<b>2</b> receives a second, negative end of differential input signal V<sub>IN</sub>. The drains of M<b>1</b> and M<b>2</b> are coupled to supply voltage V<sub>DD </sub>through respective load resistors R<b>1</b> and R<b>2</b>. In an embodiment, load resistors R<b>1</b> and R<b>2</b> are implemented using a current mirror formed from two or more transistors. An output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>is generated by differential amplifier <b>100</b> that corresponds to the voltage difference between the two ends of differential input signal V<sub>IN</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">NMOS transistor M<b>1</b> and load resistor R<b>1</b> form a first side <b>110</b> of differential amplifier <b>100</b> and NMOS transistor M<b>2</b> and load resistor R<b>2</b> form a second side <b>120</b> of differential amplifier <b>100</b>. In an ideal implementation, first side <b>110</b> and second side <b>120</b> are perfectly symmetrical.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In operation, when the magnitude of the positive end of differential input signal V<sub>IN </sub>increases and the magnitude of the negative end of differential input signal V<sub>IN </sub>decreases, the percentage of the current I conducted by transistor M<b>1</b> increases and the percentage of the current I conducted by transistor M<b>2</b> decreases. However, the total current flowing through the two transistors M<b>1</b> and M<b>2</b> remains substantially constant. As a result of the increased current flowing through transistor M<b>1</b>, the voltage drop across resistor R<b>1</b> increases, and as a result of the decreased current flowing through M<b>2</b>, the voltage drop across resistor R<b>2</b> decreases. The increased voltage drop across resistor R<b>1</b> will cause the negative end of output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>to decrease, and the decreased voltage drop across resistor R<b>2</b> will cause the positive end of output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>to increase. Typically, the change in output voltage V<sub>OUT </sub>is much greater than the change in input voltage V<sub>IN</sub>. Differential amplifier <b>100</b> will respond in an opposite manner as described above for a decrease in magnitude of the positive end of differential input signal V<sub>IN </sub>and an increase in magnitude of the negative end of differential input signal V<sub>IN</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In an ideal implementation of differential amplifier <b>100</b>, the two sides <b>110</b> and <b>120</b> are perfectly symmetrical and produce equal currents and output voltages for the same input signal. However, in the presence of mismatches the symmetry between the two sides <b>110</b> and <b>120</b> of differential amplifier <b>100</b> breaks down and the circuit generally will suffer from a dc &#x201c;offset.&#x201d; With perfect symmetry, if V<sub>IN</sub>=0 then V<sub>OUT</sub>=0. However, in the presence of mismatches, if V<sub>IN</sub>=0 then V<sub>OUT</sub>&#x2260;0. The observed value of V<sub>OUT </sub>when V<sub>IN </sub>is zero volts is the dc &#x201c;offset&#x201d; of the circuit. Typically, this dc &#x201c;offset&#x201d; is expressed as an input referred offset voltage V<sub>OFFSET</sub>, which is defined as the input voltage that causes the output voltage to go to zero volts.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In an IC, mismatches in a differential circuit result from microscopic variations in devices. For example, random, microscopic variations in the length and width of the gates of transistors M<b>1</b> and M<b>2</b>, assumed to be identically laid out, result in mismatch. In addition, random variances in doping levels in the respective channels and gates of identically laid out transistors M<b>1</b> and M<b>2</b> result in threshold mismatch.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">It should be noted that exemplary differential amplifier <b>100</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is provided for the purpose of illustration and not limitation. Other equivalent implementations and/or variations of exemplary differential amplifier <b>100</b> are possible as would be understood by a person skilled in the art based on the teachings herein. Equivalent implementations and/or variations may include, for example, variations in transistor type (e.g., PNP, BJT, JFET, BiCMOS, etc.), variations in amplifier configuration (e.g., common-collector, common-base, common-drain, common-gate, Darlington pair, Cascode, Sziklai pair, etc.), and variations in amplifier input/output configuration (e.g., a fully differential implementation). It should be further noted that other types of devices, such as bipolar junction transistors and junction gate field-effect transistors suffer from similar mismatches as the MOSFET devices described above.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates a potential limitation imposed on a differential amplifier, such as differential amplifier <b>100</b>, as a result of an offset voltage caused by random mismatches. Specifically, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates a differential input signal <b>200</b> that swings from +V<sub>0 </sub>to &#x2212;V<sub>0</sub>, a differential amplifier <b>210</b> with an input referred offset voltage V<sub>OFFSET</sub>, and a differential output signal <b>220</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The differential input signal <b>200</b> is received at the input of differential amplifier <b>210</b> and is amplified to produce differential output signal <b>220</b>. As can be seen from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, amplified versions of both differential input signal <b>200</b> and the input referred offset voltage V<sub>OFFSET </sub>are present in differential output signal <b>220</b>. The input referred offset voltage V<sub>OFFSET </sub>essentially shifts the amplified version of differential input signal <b>200</b> at the output of amplifier <b>210</b>. In this specific instance, the input referred offset voltage V<sub>OFFSET </sub>is positive. However, the input referred offset voltage is, in general, randomly defined and can be either positive or negative in value. In instances where amplifier <b>210</b> is used in cascade with another amplifier coupled to the output of amplifier <b>210</b>, the input referred offset voltage V<sub>OFFSET </sub>can result in saturation of the other amplifier and drive it and latter stages into nonlinear operation. This represents one potential limitation imposed by random mismatches.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates another potential limitation imposed on a differential amplifier <b>310</b> as a result of an offset voltage caused by random mismatches. More specifically, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates another potential limitation when differential amplifier <b>310</b> is being used to determine whether one input signal of the amplifier is greater than or less than the other input signal of the amplifier.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a time-varying voltage signal V<sub>IN</sub>, coupled to a first input of differential amplifier <b>310</b>, is essentially being compared to a reference voltage V<sub>REF</sub>, coupled to a second input of differential amplifier <b>310</b>. Differential amplifier <b>310</b>, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, can be used in a comparator or a slicer device, for example. The input referred offset voltage V<sub>OFFSET </sub>limits the minimum difference V<sub>IN</sub>&#x2212;V<sub>REF </sub>that can be reliably detected by differential amplifier <b>310</b>, representing another potential limitation imposed by random mismatches. For example, if the input referred offset voltage V<sub>OFFSET </sub>is 0.2 V, then when V is 4.4 V and V<sub>REF </sub>is 4.45 V a negative, differential output voltage should be produced by differential amplifier <b>310</b> at its output (assuming V<sub>IN </sub>is coupled to the positive input of differential amplifier <b>310</b>). However, because of the 0.2 V input referred offset voltage, when V<sub>IN </sub>is 4.4 V and V<sub>REF </sub>is 4.45 V a positive, differential output voltage is produced by differential amplifier <b>310</b> at its output.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates a differential amplifier configuration <b>400</b> for minimizing the potential limitations caused by mismatches, according to embodiments of the present invention. Differential amplifier configuration <b>400</b> includes a differential amplifier <b>410</b> and an offset cancellation circuit <b>420</b>. Again, it should be noted that V<sub>OFFSET </sub>is randomly defined and can be either positive or negative in value.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In operation, differential amplifier <b>410</b> receives input signals V<sub>IN </sub>and V<sub>REF </sub>and amplifies the difference between these two signals to provide output signal V<sub>OUT</sub>. The input referred offset voltage V<sub>OFFSET </sub>represents the mismatch between the ideally symmetric sides of differential amplifier <b>410</b> (not shown). For example, assuming inputs V<sub>IN </sub>and V<sub>REF </sub>are equal, the current through the ideally symmetrical sides of differential amplifier <b>410</b> is expected to be equal, and therefore the differential output signal V<sub>OUT </sub>is expected to be zero. However, because of random mismatches, these two currents differ. Two exemplary limitations imposed on differential amplifier <b>410</b> because of these mismatches were illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, described above.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Offset cancellation circuit <b>420</b> is configured to reduce or eliminate any difference between the amount of current flowing in the two sides of differential amplifier <b>410</b> for the same given input value received by both sides by injecting current into one side of differential amplifier <b>410</b>. More specifically, in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, offset cancellation circuit <b>420</b> is configured to inject current into the side of differential amplifier <b>410</b> that produces a higher output voltage for the same given input signal, such that the two sides produce substantially equal output values when V<sub>IN </sub>is equal to V<sub>REF</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Offset cancellation circuit <b>420</b> includes two NMOS devices M<b>3</b> and M<b>4</b>, coupled together at their sources to a current mode digital-to-analog converter (DAC) and at their drains to respective ends of the differential output V<sub>OUT </sub>of differential amplifier <b>410</b>. At their gates, NMOS devices M<b>3</b> and M<b>4</b> are respectively coupled to control signals CV<sub>P </sub>and CV<sub>N</sub>. The two control signals turn one of the two NMOS devices M<b>3</b> and M<b>4</b> on at any given time, depending on which side of differential amplifier <b>410</b> requires an additional injection of current. More specifically, the NMOS device on the side of differential amplifier <b>410</b> that requires an additional injection of current (thereby lowering its output voltage) is turned on, while the other NMOS device is turned off. The amount of current injected by offset cancellation circuit <b>420</b> is controlled by the current controlled DAC.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">For example, assuming that the side of differential amplifier <b>410</b> that provides the positive end of differential output V<sub>OUT </sub>requires the additional injection of current, control signal CV<sub>P </sub>will be controlled to turn transistor M<b>3</b> on and control signal CV<sub>N </sub>will be controlled to turn transistor M<b>4</b> off. The additional injection of current will lower the voltage output produced at the positive end of differential output V<sub>OUT </sub>for any given input value of V<sub>IN</sub>. The current controlled DAC of offset cancellation circuit <b>420</b> can be controlled to provide the necessary current to substantially cancel the effect of the input referred offset voltage V<sub>OFFSET</sub>, such that when V<sub>IN</sub>=V<sub>REF</sub>, V<sub>OUT</sub>=0.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In an embodiment, the current controlled DAC is constructed from a number of parallel current sources that can be independently switched on or off to control the amount of current provided. In another embodiment, the current controlled DAC can be replaced by any dependent current source that is controlled to provide the appropriate amount of current (to one side of differential amplifier <b>410</b>) necessary to eliminate the input referred offset voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates the differential amplifier configuration <b>400</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> with differential amplifier <b>410</b> implemented as the exemplary differential amplifier <b>100</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, according to embodiments of the present invention. The embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates in further detail the coupling of offset cancellation circuit <b>420</b> to this exemplary implementation of differential amplifier <b>410</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">As noted above, offset cancellation circuit <b>420</b> is configured to inject current into the side of differential amplifier <b>410</b> that produces a higher output voltage for the same given input signal, such that the two sides produce substantially equal output values when V<sub>IN </sub>is equal to V<sub>REF</sub>. For example, assuming the side of differential amplifier <b>410</b>, illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, that includes resistor R<b>2</b> produces a larger output voltage than the opposite side of differential amplifier <b>410</b>, then offset cancellation circuit can inject (or pull) more current through resistor R<b>2</b>, thereby lowering that sides output voltage for any given input signal. The amount of current injected (or pulled) in one side of differential amplifier <b>410</b> can be controlled to substantially cancel or eliminate the input referred offset voltage V<sub>OFFSET</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">It should be noted that exemplary differential amplifier <b>410</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is provided for the purpose of illustration and not limitation. Other equivalent implementations and/or variations of exemplary differential amplifier <b>410</b> are possible as would be understood by a person skilled in the art based on the teachings herein. Equivalent implementations and/or variations may include, for example, variations in transistor type (e.g., PNP, BJT, JFET, BiCMOS etc.), variations in amplifier configuration (e.g., common-collector, common-base, common-drain, common-gate, Darlington pair, Cascode, Sziklai pair, etc.), and variations in amplifier input/output configuration (e.g., a fully differential implementation). It should be further noted that other types of devices, such as bipolar junction transistors and junction gate field-effect transistors suffer from similar mismatches as the MOSFET devices described above.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Referring back to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, although offset cancellation circuit <b>420</b> can substantially eliminate the effects of mismatch that result because of manufacturing variations in the devices used to implement differential amplifier <b>410</b>, offset cancellation circuit <b>420</b> can actually create additional mismatch in differential amplifier <b>410</b> as will be explained further below. More specifically, a parasitic capacitance C<sub>P </sub>of offset cancellation circuit <b>420</b> exists between the source coupled nodes of NMOS transistors M<b>3</b> and M<b>4</b> and the current DAC as illustrated. This parasitic capacitance C<sub>P </sub>is the result of coupling between NMOS transistors M<b>3</b> and M<b>4</b>, and the load of the current DAC, for example. Because only one of either NMOS transistor M<b>3</b> or M<b>4</b> is on at any given time, this parasitic capacitance essentially is coupled to only one side of the output of differential amplifier <b>410</b>. In particular, parasitic capacitance C<sub>P </sub>is coupled to the side of differential amplifier <b>410</b> that corresponds to the NMOS transistor M<b>3</b> or M<b>4</b> that is on. The NMOS transistor that is off imposes a high impedance path between the output of differential amplifier <b>410</b> and the parasitic capacitance C<sub>P</sub>, while the NMOS transistor that is on imposes a low impedance path between the output of differential amplifier <b>410</b> and the parasitic capacitance C<sub>P</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The parasitic capacitance C<sub>P </sub>generally is very small. However, this small parasitic capacitance C<sub>P </sub>can become relevant very quickly as the speed at which differential amplifier <b>410</b> is operated increases. For example, at operating speeds in the GHz range, the uneven coupling of parasitic capacitance C<sub>P </sub>to one side of differential amplifier <b>410</b> can become significant as explained further below in regard to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">It should be noted that offset cancellation circuit <b>420</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> represents an NMOS presentation of this device. However, as will be appreciated by one of ordinary skill in the art, a PMOS presentation of offset cancellation circuit <b>420</b>, utilizing PMOS devices, can be constructed and used without departing from the scope and spirit of the present invention. In addition, it should be further noted that equivalent implementations and/or variations of offset cancellation circuit <b>420</b> may include variations in transistor type (e.g., PNP, BJT, MET, BiCMOS etc.) without departing from the scope and spirit of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates the adverse effect that parasitic capacitance C<sub>P </sub>can have on the operation of differential amplifier <b>410</b>, according to embodiments of the present invention. Assuming the example input signal <b>600</b> of V<sub>IN </sub>and V<sub>REF </sub>is received by differential amplifier <b>410</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the ideal output signal <b>610</b> of each end of differential output V<sub>OUT </sub>is shown. As can be seen, ideal output signal <b>610</b> shows that each input signal V<sub>IN </sub>and V<sub>REF </sub>is amplified and remains in the same, relative proportion to each other. In other words, input signals V<sub>IN </sub>and V<sub>REF </sub>are equivalently amplified and maintain the same magnitude relationship over time.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">If it is now further assumed that offset cancellation circuit <b>420</b> is injecting current into the end of differential output V<sub>OUT </sub>that provides the amplified version of V<sub>IN </sub>(to compensate for an input referred offset voltage), then the potential or actual output signal produced is shown as <b>620</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. In the specific instance, where offset cancellation circuit <b>420</b> is injecting current into the end of differential output V<sub>OUT </sub>that provides the amplified version of V<sub>IN</sub>, the NMOS device M<b>3</b> is on and the N MOS device M<b>4</b> is off. This on/off configuration of the NMOS devices M<b>3</b> and M<b>4</b> results in the coupling of parasitic capacitance C<sub>P </sub>to the end of differential output V<sub>OUT </sub>providing the amplified version of V<sub>IN</sub>, thereby creating a mismatch between the two sides of differential amplifier <b>410</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">If differential amplifier <b>410</b> is operating at a sufficient speed such that the parasitic capacitance C<sub>P </sub>is non-negligible, the potential or actual output of differential amplifier <b>410</b> for input signal <b>600</b> may more closely resemble output signal <b>620</b>, rather than that of output signal <b>610</b>. As can be seen from output signal <b>620</b>, the second upswing of amplified V<sub>IN </sub>is slow to rise to its full, expected value above amplified V<sub>REF</sub>. The slow upswing is the result of parasitic capacitance C<sub>P</sub>, which after a large downswing of amplified V<sub>IN </sub>may be discharged and may take considerable time to recharge during the upswing. The slow recharging of parasitic capacitance may prevent amplified V<sub>IN </sub>from reaching its full expected value above amplified V<sub>REF </sub>in the time allotted.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">More specifically, assuming that differential amplifier <b>410</b> is used in a comparator that compares input signal V<sub>IN </sub>to input reference voltage V<sub>REF</sub>, and the comparator provides a 1-bit output that is either high or low depending on whether V<sub>IN </sub>is less than or greater than V<sub>REF</sub>, then each comparison result or output sample is typically performed in some predetermined time period. In some devices, the comparator can be pushed to generate results or samples at a frequency in the multi-GHz range. Due to the high operating frequency, the extra time it takes for amplified V<sub>IN </sub>to swing back up to its expected value above amplified V<sub>REF </sub>because of the loading effects of parasitic capacitance C<sub>P</sub>, may result in an ultimate output value of the comparator (implementing differential amplifier <b>410</b>) being incorrect. In other words, because V<sub>IN </sub>may not reach its expected value above amplified V<sub>REF </sub>in time, the comparator may determine incorrectly that V<sub>IN </sub>is less than V<sub>REF</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Sample outputs of such a comparator for the ideal output signal <b>610</b> of differential amplifier <b>410</b> and the potential or expected output signal <b>620</b> of differential amplifier <b>410</b> are further illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. Specifically, signal <b>630</b> illustrates the ideal output of a comparator implementing differential amplifier <b>410</b> and receiving input signal <b>600</b>, and signal <b>640</b> illustrates the potential or actual output of a comparator implementing differential amplifier <b>410</b> and receiving input signal <b>600</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates a differential amplifier configuration <b>700</b> with an offset cancellation circuit <b>720</b> with reduced parasitic capacitance coupling, according to embodiments of the present invention. The implementation of differential amplifier configuration <b>700</b> can reduce or eliminate the loading effects of parasitic capacitance C<sub>P </sub>posed by offset cancellation circuit <b>420</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, differential amplifier configuration <b>700</b> includes differential amplifier <b>710</b> and offset cancellation circuit <b>720</b>. Differential amplifier configuration <b>700</b> has a substantially similar construction as differential amplifier configuration <b>400</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. However, offset cancellation circuit <b>720</b> has been modified to include an additional cascode stage <b>730</b> and two saturation maintenance current sources CS<b>1</b> and CS<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Cascode stage <b>720</b> includes two NMOS transistors M<b>5</b> and M<b>6</b> whose source/drain terminals are respectively coupled between the drains of NMOS transistors M<b>3</b> and M<b>4</b> and the two ends of differential output signal V<sub>OUT</sub>. The NMOS transistors M<b>5</b> and M<b>6</b> are further coupled at their respective gates to bias voltage V<sub>BIAS</sub>. Bias voltage V<sub>BIAS</sub>, in combination with current sources CS<b>1</b> and CS<b>2</b> maintain NMOS transistors M<b>5</b> and M<b>6</b> in saturation. The two NMOS transistors M<b>5</b> and M<b>6</b>, in saturation, have a high output impedance and provide reverse isolation. That is, NMOS transistors M<b>5</b> and M<b>6</b> in saturation block the signal charge from signal V<sub>OUT </sub>into the parasitic capacitance C. By blocking signal charge into parasitic capacitance C<sub>P</sub>, the mismatched loading effect is eliminated.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">It should be noted that exemplary cascode stage <b>720</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is provided for the purpose of illustration and not limitation. Other equivalent implementations and/or variations of exemplary cascode stage <b>720</b> are possible as would be understood by a person skilled in the art based on the teachings herein. Equivalent implementations and/or variations may include, for example, variations in transistor type (e.g., PNP, BJT, JFET, etc.) and number.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In an embodiment current sources CS<b>1</b> and CS<b>2</b> provide equal amounts of current. In a further embodiment, the amount of current provided by CS<b>1</b> and CS<b>2</b> can be relatively small in magnitude compared to the total current in the two branches of differential amplifier <b>710</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> illustrates a variation on differential amplifier configuration <b>700</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, according to embodiments of the present invention. More specifically, offset cancellation circuit <b>720</b> can be implemented and coupled to the input, as opposed to the output, of differential amplifier <b>710</b> to reduce or eliminate the effects of the input referred offset voltage as will be recognized by one of ordinary skill in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> illustrates one exemplary operating environment or device that can benefit from the use of offset cancellation circuit <b>720</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, according to embodiments of the present invention. Specifically, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> illustrates a block diagram of an n-bit flash ADC <b>900</b>. Flash ADC <b>900</b> includes a voltage reference module <b>910</b>, a comparator module <b>920</b>, and a thermometer to binary module <b>930</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">In operation, flash ADC <b>900</b> is configured to receive and convert an analog voltage (or current) <b>940</b> into a binary code <b>950</b> having n-bits of precision. Binary code <b>950</b> is a digital number that is proportional to the magnitude of analog voltage <b>940</b>. During the conversion process, analog voltage <b>940</b> typically is compared in parallel to 2<sup>n</sup>&#x2212;1 voltage references provided by voltage reference module <b>910</b>. In an embodiment, voltage reference module <b>910</b> is a linear voltage ladder that provides 2<sup>n</sup>&#x2212;1 evenly spaced voltage references to comparator module <b>920</b>. The linear voltage ladder can be constructed from equal valued resistors coupled in series between two voltage sources V<sub>REF</sub>+ and V<sub>REF</sub>&#x2212; as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>. In another embodiment, the linear voltage ladder can be provided by capacitive voltage division.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Comparator module <b>920</b> typically includes 2<sup>n</sup>&#x2212;1 comparators and each comparator compares analog voltage <b>940</b> to a different one of the 2<sup>n</sup>&#x2212;1 voltage references provided by voltage reference module <b>910</b>. The comparators determine whether analog voltage <b>940</b> is less than or greater than each voltage reference. In an embodiment, each comparator is configured to produce a logical one if analog voltage <b>940</b> is greater than the voltage reference and a logical zero if analog voltage <b>940</b> is less than the voltage reference. The results of these comparisons form what is referred to as a thermometer code at the output of comparator module <b>920</b>. A thermometer code generally has one digital level for each possible, non-zero output code of flash ADC <b>900</b> (i.e., 2<sup>n</sup>&#x2212;1 digital levels for an n-bit ADC). Ideally, for any given analog voltage <b>940</b>, all digital levels below the value of analog voltage <b>940</b> are a logical one and all above are a logical zero. The point in the thermometer code where a logical one transitions to a logical zero is commonly referred to as the top, and the digital level at this transition point is the digital level that closely or most accurately represents analog voltage <b>940</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The final stage of the conversion process is performed by thermometer to binary module <b>930</b>. Thermometer to binary module <b>930</b> receives the thermometer code produced by comparator module <b>920</b> and converts this code into binary code <b>950</b>. Implementations of thermometer to binary module <b>130</b> are explained further below.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Ideally, there is at most a single top in any thermometer code produced. However, because of random mismatches between transistors used to implement the comparators of comparator module <b>920</b>, additional tops or what are commonly referred to as bubbles are produced in the thermometer code. These bubbles can result in large sparkle errors, which degrade the bit error rate (BER) of a flash ADC, such as flash ADC <b>900</b>. An offset correction circuit, such as offset correction circuit <b>720</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> can be implemented by one or more of the comparators of comparator module <b>920</b> to reduce or eliminate the effects of random mismatches as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">It should be noted that flash ADC <b>900</b> is provided as one exemplary operating environment for offset correction circuit <b>720</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> and is provided for the purpose of illustration and not limitation. Other operating environments are possible as would be understood by a person skilled in the art based on the teachings herein.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">It is to be appreciated that the Detailed Description section, and not the Abstract section, is intended to be used to interpret the claims. The Abstract section may set forth one or more but not all exemplary embodiments of the present invention as contemplated by the inventor(s), and thus, is not intended to limit the present invention and the appended claims in any way.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The present invention has been described above with the aid of functional building blocks illustrating the implementation of specified functions and relationships thereof. The boundaries of these functional building blocks have been arbitrarily defined herein for the convenience of the description. Alternate boundaries can be defined so long as the specified functions and relationships thereof are appropriately performed.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The foregoing description of the specific embodiments will so fully reveal the general nature of the invention that others can, by applying knowledge within the skill of the art, readily modify and/or adapt for various applications such specific embodiments, without undue experimentation, without departing from the general concept of the present invention. Therefore, such adaptations and modifications are intended to be within the meaning and range of equivalents of the disclosed embodiments, based on the teaching and guidance presented herein. It is to be understood that the phraseology or terminology herein is for the purpose of description and not of limitation, such that the terminology or phraseology of the present specification is to be interpreted by the skilled artisan in light of the teachings and guidance.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The breadth and scope of the present invention should not be limited by any of the above-described exemplary embodiments, but should be defined only in accordance with the following claims and their equivalents.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An analog-to-digital converter (ADC) for converting an analog voltage into a binary code, the ADC comprising:
<claim-text>a voltage reference module configured to generate a plurality of voltage references;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparator module configured to compare the analog voltage to the plurality of voltage references to generate a thermometer code, wherein the comparator module comprises an offset cancellation circuit for canceling an input referred offset voltage in a differential amplifier used to compare the analog voltage to one of the plurality of voltage references; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a thermometer to binary module configured to convert the thermometer code into the binary code,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the offset cancellation circuit comprises:
<claim-text>a current source configured to provide an offset current: and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a switching stage comprising a first switch configured to couple the offset current to a first differential end of the differential amplifier, and a second switch configured to couple, the offset current to a second differential end of the differential amplifier.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The ADC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the current source is a current mode digital-to-analog (DAC) converter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The ADC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second switches are field effect transistors or bipolar junction transistors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The ADC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first differential end is a positive output of the differential amplifier and the second differential end is a negative output of the differential amplifier.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The ADC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first differential end is a positive input of the differential amplifier and the second differential end is a negative input of the differential amplifier.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The ADC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second switches are controlled such that only one of the first and second switches is on at any given point in time.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The ADC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the offset cancellation circuit further comprises:
<claim-text>a cascode stage comprising a first cascode device and a second cascade device, wherein the first cascode device is configured to receive the offset current from the first switch and inject the offset current into the first differential end of the differential amplifier, and the second cascode device is configured to receive the offset current from the second switch and inject the offset current into the second differential end of the differential amplifier.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The ADC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the offset cancellation circuit further comprises:
<claim-text>a first current source coupled between the first switch and the first cascode device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second current source coupled between the second switch and the second cascode device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The ADC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second current sources are respectively configured to maintain the first and second cascode devices in a saturation region of operation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The ADC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second cascode devices are at least one of a field effect transistor and a bipolar junction transistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. An analog-to-digital converter (ADC) for converting an analog voltage into a binary code, the ADC comprising:
<claim-text>a comparator configured to compare an analog voltage to a voltage reference to generate a portion of a thermometer code,</claim-text>
<claim-text>an offset cancellation circuit configured to cancel an input referred offset voltage in the comparator, the offset cancellation circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a current source configured to provide an offset, current, and
<claim-text>a switching stage comprising a first switch configured to couple the offset current to a first differential end of the comparator, and a second switch configured, to couple the offset current to a second differential end of the comparator; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a thermometer to binary module configured to convert the thermometer code into the binary code.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The ADC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the current source is a current mode digital-to-analog (DAC) converter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The ADC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second switches are field effect transistors or bipolar junction transistors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The ADC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the first differential end is a positive output of the comparator and the second differential end is a negative output of the comparator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The ADC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the first differential end is a positive input of the comparator and the second differential end is a negative input of the comparator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The ADC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second switches are controlled such that only one of the first and second switches is on at any given point in time.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The ADC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the offset cancellation circuit further comprises:
<claim-text>a cascode stage comprising a first cascode device and a second cascode device, wherein the first cascode device is configured to receive the offset current from the first switch and inject the offset current into the first differential end of the comparator, and the second cascode device is configured to receive the offset current from the second switch and inject the offset current into the second differential end of the comparator.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The ADC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the offset cancellation circuit further comprises:
<claim-text>a first current source coupled between the first switch and the first cascode device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second current source coupled between the second switch and the second cascode device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. An analog-to-digital converter (ADC) for converting an analog voltage into a binary code, the ADC comprising:
<claim-text>a comparator configured to compare an analog voltage to a voltage reference to generate a portion of a thermometer code; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an offset cancellation circuit configured to cancel an input referred offset voltage in the comparator, wherein the offset cancellation circuit comprises a cascode stage configured to reduce parasitic coupling between the comparator and the offset cancellation circuit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a thermometer to binary module configured to convert the thermometer code into the binary code. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
