<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622732-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622732</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13020010</doc-number>
<date>20110202</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>99116304 A</doc-number>
<date>20100521</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>255</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>29</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>49</main-group>
<subgroup>56</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4254514</main-classification>
<further-classification>4254515</further-classification>
<further-classification>425161</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4878828</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Wollschlager et al.</name>
<date>19891100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5551862</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Allred, Jr.</name>
<date>19960900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>425532</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>M326468</doc-number>
<date>20080200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>M333294</doc-number>
<kind>U</kind>
<date>20080600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>I317322</doc-number>
<kind>B</kind>
<date>20091100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>M390865</doc-number>
<kind>U1</kind>
<date>20101000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>11</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>425161</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4254514</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4254515</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-cpc-text>B29C 49/56</classification-cpc-text>
<classification-cpc-text>B29C 33/22</classification-cpc-text>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110287121</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20111124</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tsay</last-name>
<first-name>Der-min</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chen</last-name>
<first-name>Hsin-pao</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chen</last-name>
<first-name>Shih-han</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tsay</last-name>
<first-name>Der-min</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chen</last-name>
<first-name>Hsin-pao</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chen</last-name>
<first-name>Shih-han</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chiang</last-name>
<first-name>Cheng-Ju</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>National Sun Yat-Sen University</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Gupta</last-name>
<first-name>Yogendra</first-name>
<department>1744</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Hindenlang</last-name>
<first-name>Alison</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds is provided and includes a single cam, a first side connection rod assembly located on a first side of the cam, a first mold actuated by the first side connection rod assembly, a linkage connection rod, a second side connection rod assembly located on a second side of the cam and actuated by the linkage connection rod, and a second mold actuated by the second side connection rod assembly. The multi-rod mechanism only uses the single cam to simultaneously actuate the first and second molds, so that the structure of the multi-rod mechanism can be simplified, while the vibration, loading, noise and abrasion of components during operation can be relatively reduced.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="130.64mm" wi="168.40mm" file="US08622732-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="240.54mm" wi="167.30mm" file="US08622732-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="168.99mm" wi="152.48mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622732-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="165.44mm" wi="154.77mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622732-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="189.31mm" wi="158.67mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622732-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="185.42mm" wi="159.60mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622732-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to a multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds, and more particularly to a multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds, which is used to simplify the structure of the multi-rod mechanism, reduce the abrasion of a cam and elongate the lifetime of the cam.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Nowadays, bottle blow-molding machines are widely applied to fabrications of various plastic bottles (such as PET bottles). A traditional bottle blow-molding machine comprises various different mechanical parts, such as a mechanism for opening and closing molds, a mechanism for feeding material and blowing bottles, a mechanism for ejecting bottles, a mechanism for conveying and etc., wherein the mechanism for opening and closing molds can be designed and driven by selectively using various different power sources (such as motor, pneumatic cylinder, hydraulic cylinder or cam).</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">For example, Taiwan Utility Model Patent No. M326468 discloses a &#x201c;Mechanism for Opening and Closing Molds of Bottle Blow-Molding Machine&#x201d;, wherein a machine base of a bottle blow-molding machine is provided with two opposite mold bases which can horizontally slide back and forth, and each of the mold bases is linked to the machine base through a toggle assembly. Each of the two toggle assemblies is pivotally connected to a first connection rod assembly which is driven by a first cam and a second cam of a cam assembly, respectively. Thus, the two mold bases can be simultaneously driven to be opened or closed. Furthermore, a lower mold base which can longitudinally slide back and forth is linked to a second connection rod assembly which is driven by a third cam of the cam assembly. Thus, the lower mold base can be simultaneously driven to be opened or closed.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">However, there are some problems existing in the actual use of the traditional mechanism for opening and closing molds, as follows: during opening or closing the mold bases, a downward push force fed back from the mold bases and connection rods of the first connection rod assemblies will directly abut against each of the cam surfaces on the cam assembly. After the cam surfaces are long-term used and worn, the precision of the first connection rod assemblies for pushing the two mold bases to close will be affected. In other words, when closing the mold bases, a gap may exist between two contact surfaces of the two mold bases, so as to affect the yield of subsequently feeding material and blowing bottles. Moreover, because the downward push force from the connection rods of the first connection rod assemblies during opening the mold bases will directly abut against each of the cam surfaces on the cam assembly, the cam assembly needs a greater rotation power to push the connection rods of the first connection rod assemblies for opening the mold bases. Meanwhile, the excess push loading transmitted through the connection rods may cause the bending of the connection rods or the pivotal vibrations, noise or abrasion on various pivotal points. In addition, for simultaneously driving the two first connection rod assemblies and the second connection rod assembly, the cam assembly must have three types of different cams, and thus the purchase cost of the cam assembly will be increased. Besides, if installation angles between the three cams are changed, the mold opening and closing operations of the two mold bases and the lower mold base will be affected and can not coordinate with each other, resulting in affecting the yield of subsequently feeding material and blowing bottles. Furthermore, the cam assembly belongs to one of components having higher cost, so that the abrasion of the cam assembly will cause higher maintenance and replacement cost.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">As a result, it is necessary to provide a multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds to solve the problems existing in the conventional technologies, as described above.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">A primary object of the present invention is to provide a multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds, wherein a first mold at a first side of a cam is actuated by a first side connection rod assembly, while a second side connection rod assembly and a second mold at a second side of the cam are actuated by a linkage connection rod. The multi-rod mechanism only uses the single cam to simultaneously actuate the first and second molds, so that the structure of the multi-rod mechanism can be simplified; the vibration, loading, noise and abrasion of components during operation can be relatively reduced; the operational speed and productivity of the multi-rod mechanism can be enhanced; the lifetime of the multi-rod mechanism can be elongated; and the maintenance and replacement rate of the multi-rod mechanism can be lowered.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">A secondary object of the present invention is to provide a multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds, wherein a plurality of connection rods of a connection rod assembly are arranged along a common vertical line in the mold opening operation (or the mold closing operation), while a horizontal extension line defined by a cam follower and a following connection rod is substantially vertical to the vertical line. Thus, during the mold opening operation (or the mold closing operation), it can prevent a downward push force fed back from the reciprocally longitudinal swing of the connection rod assembly from completely focusing on and transmitting to a cam follower and a cam. In other words, the abrasion problem of the cam due to tightly abutment between the cam follower and a cam surface will be relatively reduced. Thus, it is advantageous to reduce the abrasion of the cam surface, elongate the lifetime of the cam, ensure the precision of mold closing operation, and increase the yield of bottle blow-molding.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">To achieve the above object, the present invention provides a multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds, which comprises: a cam rotating to generate a driving power; a cam follower actuated by the cam to linearly move back and forth; a first side connection rod assembly actuated by the cam follower to swing; a first mold actuated by the first side connection rod assembly to linearly move back and forth; a linkage connection rod actuated by the first side connection rod assembly to swing; a second side connection rod assembly actuated by the linkage connection rod to swing; and a second mold actuated by the second side connection rod assembly to linearly move back and forth; wherein the second mold cooperates with the corresponding first mold which linearly moves back and forth opposite to the second mold, so that the second mold is close to or away from the first mold for carrying out a mold closing operation or a mold opening operation.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In one embodiment of the present invention, the first side connection rod assembly comprises a quadruple joint connection rod, a first push connection rod, a first support connection rod and a first mold connection rod; and wherein the quadruple joint connection rod is actuated by the cam follower to pivotally rotate, so that the first push connection rod then longitudinally pushes (or pulls) the first support connection rod and the first mold connection rod which thus actuates the first mold to carry out the mold opening operation (or the mold closing operation).</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In one embodiment of the present invention, the quadruple joint connection rod has a pivotal fulcrum, a following pivotal point, a linkage pivotal point and a push pivotal point; and wherein the pivotal fulcrum is pivotally connected to a first pivotal base, the following pivotal point is pivotally connected to the cam follower, the linkage pivotal point is pivotally connected to the linkage connection rod, and the push pivotal point is pivotally connected to the first push connection rod.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In one embodiment of the present invention, the cam follower has a following connection rod to be pivotally connected to the following pivotal point of the quadruple joint connection rod.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In one embodiment of the present invention, the first push connection rod and the push pivotal point, the pivotal fulcrum and the linkage pivotal point of the quadruple joint connection rod are longitudinally arranged along a common first vertical line in the mold opening operation (or the mold closing operation).</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In one embodiment of the present invention, a horizontal extension line defined by the cam follower and the following connection rod is substantially vertical to the first vertical line.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In one embodiment of the present invention, the second side connection rod assembly comprises a triple joint connection rod, a second push connection rod, a second support connection rod and a second mold connection rod; and wherein the triple joint connection rod is actuated by the linkage connection rod to pivotally rotate, so that the second push connection rod then longitudinally pushes (or pulls) the second support connection rod and the second mold connection rod which thus actuates the second mold to carry out the mold opening operation (or the mold closing operation).</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In one embodiment of the present invention, the triple joint connection rod has a pivotal fulcrum, a linkage pivotal point and a push pivotal point; and wherein the pivotal fulcrum is pivotally connected to a second pivotal base, the linkage pivotal point is pivotally connected to the linkage connection rod, and the push pivotal point is pivotally connected to the second push connection rod.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In one embodiment of the present invention, the second push connection rod and the push pivotal point and the pivotal fulcrum of the triple joint connection rod are arranged along a common second vertical line in the mold opening operation (or the mold closing operation).</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In one embodiment of the present invention, the multi-rod mechanism is a mechanism for opening and closing molds of a bottle blow-molding machine.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In one embodiment of the present invention, the first side connection rod assembly further comprises a first sliding connection rod pivotally connected between the quadruple joint connection rod and the first push connection rod.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In one embodiment of the present invention, the second side connection rod assembly further comprises a second sliding connection rod pivotally connected the triple joint connection rod and the second push connection rod.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In one embodiment of the present invention, the first side connection rod assembly comprises a triple joint connection rod, a first push connection rod, a first support connection rod and a first mold connection rod; and wherein the triple joint connection rod is actuated by the cam follower to pivotally rotate, so that the first push connection rod then pushes or pulls the first support connection rod and the first mold connection rod.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In one embodiment of the present invention, the triple joint connection rod has a pivotal fulcrum, a following pivotal point and a push pivotal point; and wherein the pivotal fulcrum is pivotally connected to a first pivotal base, the following pivotal point is pivotally connected to the cam follower, and the push pivotal point is pivotally connected to the first push connection rod and the linkage connection rod, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In one embodiment of the present invention, the cam follower has a following connection rod to be pivotally connected to the following pivotal point of the triple joint connection rod; the first push connection rod and the push pivotal point and the pivotal fulcrum of the triple joint connection rod are arranged along a common first vertical line in the mold opening operation (or the mold closing operation); and a horizontal extension line defined by the cam follower and the following connection rod is vertical to the first vertical line.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In one embodiment of the present invention, the first side connection rod assembly further comprises a first sliding connection rod pivotally connected between the triple joint connection rod and the first push connection rod.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In one embodiment of the present invention, the second side connection rod assembly comprises a double joint connection rod, a second push connection rod, a second support connection rod and a second mold connection rod; and wherein the double joint connection rod is actuated by the linkage connection rod to pivotally rotate, so that the second push connection rod then pushes or pulls the second support connection rod and the second mold connection rod.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In one embodiment of the present invention, the double joint connection rod has a pivotal fulcrum and a push pivotal point; and wherein the pivotal fulcrum is pivotally connected to a second pivotal base, and the push pivotal point is pivotally connected to the second push connection rod and the linkage connection rod, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In one embodiment of the present invention, the second push connection rod and the push pivotal point and the pivotal fulcrum of the double joint connection rod are arranged along a common second vertical line in the mold opening operation (or the mold closing operation).</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In one embodiment of the present invention, the second side connection rod assembly further comprises a second sliding connection rod pivotally connected the double joint connection rod and the second push connection rod.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view of a mold closing operation of a multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds according to a first embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> is a partially enlarged cross-sectional view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> according to the first embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic view of a mold opening operation of the multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds according to the first embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic view of a mold closing operation of a multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds according to a second embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic view of a mold closing operation of a multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds according to a third embodiment of the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a schematic view of a mold closing operation of a multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds according to a fourth embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The structure and the technical means adopted by the present invention to achieve the above and other objects can be best understood by referring to the following detailed description of the preferred embodiments and the accompanying drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, a first embodiment of the present invention discloses a multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds <b>100</b> which is mainly applied to a bottle blow-molding machine for mass production of various plastic bottles, such as PET (polyethylene terephthalate) bottles and etc. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the mechanism for opening and closing molds <b>100</b> comprises: a cam <b>10</b>, a cam follower <b>20</b>, a first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b>, a first mold <b>40</b>, a linkage connection rod <b>50</b>, a second side connection rod assembly <b>60</b> and a second mold <b>70</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In the present invention, it should be noted that the term &#x201c;pivotal connection&#x201d; described hereinafter is used to define that a connection relationship between a first component and a second component is a pivotal connection relationship, wherein the first component can rotate within a predetermined angle in relation to the second component. Meanwhile, the term &#x201c;connection rod&#x201d; is used to define that a rod-like or polygonal component has at least two pivotal points for being pivotally connected to another component (such as a connection rod, a mold or a follower), a pivotal base and etc. Furthermore, various directional terms described by the present invention, such as upper, lower, front, back, left, right, inner, outer, longitudinal, transverse, vertical, horizontal, side and etc., are only directions based on structures in the accompanying drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">For example, the terms &#x201c;first side&#x201d; and &#x201c;second side&#x201d; described in the present invention hereinafter are used to define the relative positions of a left side and a right side of the cam <b>10</b> in each of the accompanying drawings, i.e. a left side close to the first mold <b>40</b> and a right side close to the second mold <b>70</b>, respectively, wherein the terms &#x201c;first side&#x201d; and &#x201c;second side&#x201d; or the foregoing other directional terms are only used to describe and understand the installation relationship of related components of the present invention, but the present invention is not limited thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 1A</figref>, in the first embodiment of the present invention, the cam <b>10</b> is made of wear-resistant metal or alloy material, and the cam <b>10</b> is mounted on a shaft <b>11</b>, wherein the shaft <b>11</b> is actuated by an external power source (such as a driving motor), so as to rotate and thus generate a driving power. The cam <b>10</b> can be an integral one-piece cam or an assembled multi-piece cam. According to the configuration, the cam <b>10</b> can be a rib cam, a grooved cam, a planar cam or any other type of equivalent cam. The number of the cam <b>10</b> is preferably one, but also can be two or more. Furthermore, in the embodiment, the cam follower <b>20</b> is a slide block which can be actuated by the cam <b>10</b> to linearly and transversely move back and forth along a track (unlabeled) on a machine base of the mechanism for opening and closing molds <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">As shown in the partially enlarged cross-sectional view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>, the cam <b>10</b> is preferably a rib cam which has a cross-section preferably having a shallow dish profile for providing a flange <b>12</b>, wherein inner and outer surfaces of the flange <b>12</b> has a predetermined non-circular cam profile. The cam follower <b>20</b> preferably has a pair of rollers <b>21</b> to commonly clamp the flange <b>21</b> of the cam <b>10</b>. Thus, when the cam <b>10</b> rotates, the cam <b>10</b> can actuate the cam follower <b>20</b> to linearly move back and forth along the track. Furthermore, the cam follower <b>20</b> further comprises a following connection rod <b>22</b>, wherein the following connection rod <b>22</b> has a first end pivotally connected to a pivotal point (unlabeled) of the cam follower <b>20</b> and a second end used for actuating the first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b> to swing (i.e. pivotally rotate within a predetermined angle).</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, in the first embodiment of the present invention, the first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b> comprises a quadruple joint connection rod <b>31</b>, a first push connection rod <b>32</b>, a first support connection rod <b>33</b> and a first mold connection rod <b>34</b>; and wherein the quadruple joint connection rod <b>31</b> is actuated by the cam follower <b>20</b> to pivotally rotate, so that the first push connection rod <b>32</b> then longitudinally pushes (or pulls) the first support connection rod <b>33</b> and the first mold connection rod <b>34</b> which thus actuates the first mold <b>40</b> to carry out the mold opening operation (or the mold closing operation).</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">For more details, in the embodiment, the quadruple joint connection rod <b>31</b> is a substantially triangular plate or a connection rod assembly constructed by a plurality of components, wherein the quadruple joint connection rod <b>31</b> has a pivotal fulcrum <b>311</b>, a following pivotal point <b>312</b>, a linkage pivotal point <b>313</b> and a push pivotal point <b>314</b>; wherein the linkage pivotal point <b>313</b>, the pivotal fulcrum <b>311</b> and a push pivotal point <b>314</b> are located at the same side of the triangular plate in turn, while the following pivotal point <b>312</b>, the linkage pivotal point <b>313</b> and the push pivotal point <b>314</b> are preferably located at three corners of the triangular plate, but the relative positions of the foregoing points are not limited thereto. The pivotal fulcrum <b>311</b> is pivotally connected to a first pivotal base <b>35</b>, and the following pivotal point <b>312</b> is pivotally connected to the following connection rod <b>22</b> of the cam follower <b>20</b>. Thus, the following connection rod <b>22</b> can push (or pull) the quadruple joint connection rod <b>31</b> to pivotally rotate within a predetermined angle (such as an optional angle between 15 degree and 60 degree) in relation to the pivotal fulcrum <b>311</b> and the first pivotal base <b>35</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Moreover, the linkage pivotal point <b>313</b> is pivotally connected to the linkage connection rod <b>50</b> for actuating the linkage connection rod <b>50</b> to swing. The push pivotal point <b>314</b> is pivotally connected to the first push connection rod <b>32</b> for actuating the first push connection rod <b>32</b> to push upward (or pull downward). In addition, a first end of the first support connection rod <b>33</b> is pivotally connected to a first support base <b>36</b>, and a second thereof is pivotally connected to a first end of the first mold connection rod <b>34</b>, wherein a second end of the first mold connection rod <b>34</b> is pivotally connected to the first mold <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, in the first embodiment of the present invention, the first mold <b>40</b> has a first mold cavity <b>41</b> having a cavity profile designed according to specifications of to-be-blow-molded plastic bottles. The first mold <b>40</b> is pivotally connected to the second end of the first mold connection rod <b>34</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, when the first support connection rod <b>33</b> and the first mold connection rod <b>34</b> are pulled downward by the quadruple joint connection rod <b>31</b> and the first push connection rod <b>32</b>, the first support connection rod <b>33</b> and the first mold connection rod <b>34</b> are transversely disposed at a common horizontal extension line, wherein the first mold connection rod <b>34</b> actuates the first mold <b>40</b> to horizontally and transversely move to carry out a mold closing operation.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">On the other hand, referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, when the first support connection rod <b>33</b> and the first mold connection rod <b>34</b> are pushed upward by the quadruple joint connection rod <b>31</b> and the first push connection rod <b>32</b>, the first support connection rod <b>33</b> and the first mold connection rod <b>34</b> are pivotally rotated in relation to each other at a predetermined angle which may be greater than, equal to or smaller than 90 degree. Thus, the first mold connection rod <b>34</b> actuates the first mold <b>40</b> to horizontally and transversely move to carry out a mold opening operation. In the mold opening operation, the first push connection rod <b>32</b> and the push pivotal point <b>314</b>, the pivotal fulcrum <b>311</b> and the linkage pivotal point <b>313</b> of the quadruple joint connection rod <b>31</b> are preferably longitudinally arranged along a common first vertical line in turn. Meanwhile, a horizontal extension line defined by the cam <b>10</b>, the cam follower <b>20</b> and the following connection rod <b>22</b> is substantially or closely vertical to the first vertical line.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Thus, during the mold opening/closing operation, the foregoing design can disperse a downward push force fed back from the reciprocally longitudinal swing of the first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b> toward the first pivotal base <b>35</b> and the first support base <b>36</b>, so as to prevent from excessively and transversely transmitting to the following connection rod <b>22</b>, the cam follower <b>20</b> and the cam <b>10</b> along the horizontal extension line. In other words, the abrasion problem of the cam <b>10</b> due to tightly abutment between the rollers <b>21</b> of the cam follower <b>20</b> and the inner and outer surfaces on the flange <b>12</b> of the cam <b>10</b> will be relatively reduced. Thus, it is advantageous to elongate the lifetime of the cam <b>10</b>, ensure the precision of mold closing operation, and increase the yield of bottle blow-molding.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, in the first embodiment of the present invention, the linkage connection rod <b>50</b> is substantially disposed below the cam <b>10</b>, the first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b> and the second side connection rod assembly <b>60</b>. The linkage connection rod <b>50</b> has a first end pivotally connected to the linkage pivotal point <b>313</b> of the quadruple joint connection rod <b>31</b> of the first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b>, and a second end pivotally connected to the second side connection rod assembly <b>60</b>. The linkage connection rod <b>50</b> is actuated by the quadruple joint connection rod <b>31</b> of the first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b> to swing for driving the second side connection rod assembly <b>60</b> to correspondingly swing.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, in the first embodiment of the present invention, the second side connection rod assembly <b>60</b> comprises a triple joint connection rod <b>61</b>, a second push connection rod <b>62</b>, a second support connection rod <b>63</b> and a second mold connection rod <b>64</b>; and wherein the triple joint connection rod <b>61</b> is actuated by the linkage connection rod <b>50</b> to pivotally rotate, so that the second push connection rod <b>62</b> then longitudinally pushes (or pulls) the second support connection rod <b>63</b> and the second mold connection rod <b>64</b> which thus actuates the second mold <b>70</b> to carry out the mold opening operation (or the mold closing operation).</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">For more details, in the embodiment, the triple joint connection rod <b>61</b> is a substantially triangular plate or a connection rod assembly constructed by a plurality of components, wherein the triple joint connection rod <b>61</b> has a pivotal fulcrum <b>611</b>, a linkage pivotal point <b>612</b> and a push pivotal point <b>613</b>, all of which are preferably located at three corners of the triangular plate. Furthermore, the pivotal fulcrum <b>611</b> is pivotally connected to a second pivotal base <b>65</b>, and the linkage pivotal point <b>612</b> is pivotally connected to the linkage connection rod <b>50</b>. Thus, the linkage connection rod <b>50</b> can push (or pull) the triple joint connection rod <b>61</b> to pivotally rotate within a predetermined angle (such as an optional angle between 15 degree and 60 degree without limitation) in relation to the pivotal fulcrum <b>611</b> and the second pivotal base <b>65</b>. The push pivotal point <b>613</b> is pivotally connected to the second push connection rod <b>62</b> for actuating the second push connection rod <b>62</b> to push upward (or pull downward). In addition, a first end of the second support connection rod <b>63</b> is pivotally connected to a second support base <b>66</b>, and a second thereof is pivotally connected to a first end of the second mold connection rod <b>64</b>, wherein a second end of the second mold connection rod <b>64</b> is pivotally connected to the second mold <b>70</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, in the first embodiment of the present invention, the second mold <b>70</b> has a second mold cavity <b>71</b> having a cavity profile designed according to specifications of to-be-blow-molded plastic bottles. The second mold cavity <b>71</b> is corresponding to the first mold cavity <b>41</b> of the first mold <b>40</b>, and the second mold <b>70</b> is pivotally connected to the second end of the second mold connection rod <b>64</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, when the second support connection rod <b>63</b> and the second mold connection rod <b>64</b> are pulled downward by the triple joint connection rod <b>61</b> and the second push connection rod <b>62</b>, the second support connection rod <b>63</b> and the second mold connection rod <b>64</b> are transversely disposed at a common horizontal extension line, wherein the second mold connection rod <b>64</b> actuates the second mold <b>70</b> to horizontally and transversely move to carry out a mold closing operation.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">On the other hand, referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, when the second support connection rod <b>63</b> and the second mold connection rod <b>64</b> are pushed upward by the triple joint connection rod <b>61</b> and the second push connection rod <b>62</b>, the second support connection rod <b>63</b> and the second mold connection rod <b>64</b> are pivotally rotated in relation to each other at a predetermined angle which may be greater than, equal to or smaller than 90 degree. Thus, the second mold connection rod <b>64</b> actuates the second mold <b>70</b> to horizontally and transversely move to carry out a mold opening operation. In the mold opening operation, the second push connection rod <b>62</b> and the push pivotal point <b>613</b> and the pivotal fulcrum <b>611</b> of the triple joint connection rod <b>61</b> are preferably longitudinally arranged along a common second vertical line in turn. Meanwhile, a rod extension line defined by the linkage connection rod <b>50</b> and the second vertical line have an included angle defined therebetween, wherein the included angle is close to 90 degree.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Thus, during the mold opening/closing operation, the foregoing design can disperse a downward push force fed back from the reciprocally longitudinal swing of the second side connection rod assembly <b>60</b> toward the second pivotal base <b>65</b> and the second support base <b>66</b>, so as to prevent from excessively and transversely transmitting to the linkage connection rod <b>50</b> and the first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b> along the extension line of the linkage connection rod <b>50</b>. In other words, the abrasion problem of the inner and outer surfaces on the flange <b>12</b> of the cam <b>10</b> will be relatively reduced. Thus, it is advantageous to elongate the lifetime of the cam <b>10</b>, ensure the precision of mold closing operation, and increase the yield of bottle blow-molding.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, according to the multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds <b>100</b> in the first embodiment of the present invention, the first mold <b>40</b> at the first side of the cam <b>10</b> is actuated by the first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b>, while the second side connection rod assembly <b>60</b> and the second mold <b>70</b> at the second side of the cam are actuated by the linkage connection rod <b>50</b>. The foregoing multi-rod mechanism only uses the single cam <b>10</b> to simultaneously actuate the first and second molds <b>40</b>, <b>70</b>, so that the structure of the cam <b>10</b> can be simplified; the vibration, loading, noise and abrasion of components during operation can be relatively reduced; the operational speed and productivity of the multi-rod mechanism can be enhanced; the lifetime of the multi-rod mechanism can be elongated; and the maintenance and replacement rate of the multi-rod mechanism can be lowered.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds according to a second embodiment of the present invention is illustrated and similar to the first embodiment, so that the second embodiment uses similar terms and numerals of the first embodiment. As shown, the difference of the second embodiment is that: a multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds <b>200</b> of the second embodiment comprises a first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b> which uses a triple joint connection rod <b>37</b> to replace the quadruple joint connection rod <b>31</b>, and a second side connection rod assembly <b>60</b> which uses a double joint connection rod <b>67</b> to replace the triple joint connection rod <b>61</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">For more details, the triple joint connection rod <b>37</b> has a pivotal fulcrum <b>371</b>, a push pivotal point <b>372</b> and a following pivotal point <b>373</b> for being pivotally connected to the first pivotal base <b>35</b>, the first push connection rod <b>32</b> and the following connection rod <b>22</b>, respectively. A first end of the following connection rod <b>22</b> is pivotally connected to a pivotal point (unlabeled) of the cam follower <b>20</b>, and a second end thereof is pivotally connected to the following pivotal point <b>373</b> for actuating the first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b> to swing. Furthermore, the double joint connection rod <b>67</b> has a pivotal fulcrum <b>671</b> and a push pivotal point <b>672</b> for being pivotally connected to the second pivotal base <b>65</b> and the second push connection rod <b>62</b>, respectively. Moreover, the linkage connection rod <b>50</b> is disposed above the cam <b>10</b> and the cam follower <b>20</b> and disposed below the first mold <b>40</b> and the second mold <b>70</b>. Two ends of the linkage connection rod <b>50</b> is pivotally connected to the push pivotal point <b>372</b> and the push pivotal point <b>672</b>, so that the first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b> can smoothly actuate the second side connection rod assembly <b>60</b> to swing.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, in the second embodiment, when the first support connection rod <b>33</b> and the first mold connection rod <b>34</b> are pulled downward by the triple joint connection rod <b>37</b> and the first push connection rod <b>32</b>, the first support connection rod <b>33</b> and the first mold connection rod <b>34</b> are transversely disposed at a common horizontal extension line, wherein the first mold connection rod <b>34</b> actuates the first mold <b>40</b> to carry out a mold closing operation. Meanwhile, the second support connection rod <b>63</b> and the second mold connection rod <b>64</b> are pulled downward by the double joint connection rod <b>67</b> and the second push connection rod <b>62</b>, the second support connection rod <b>63</b> and the second mold connection rod <b>64</b> are transversely disposed at a common horizontal extension line, wherein the second mold connection rod <b>64</b> actuates the second mold <b>70</b> to carry out a mold closing operation.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">On the other hand, when the first support connection rod <b>33</b> and the first mold connection rod <b>34</b> are pushed upward by the triple joint connection rod <b>37</b> and the first push connection rod <b>32</b>, the second support connection rod <b>63</b> and the second mold connection rod <b>64</b> are pushed upward by the double joint connection rod <b>67</b> and the second push connection rod <b>62</b>. At this time, the first support connection rod <b>33</b> and the first mold connection rod <b>34</b> are pivotally rotated in relation to each other at a predetermined angle greater than 90 degree, so that the first mold connection rod <b>34</b> actuates the first mold <b>40</b> to carry out a mold opening operation (not-shown). Meanwhile, the second support connection rod <b>63</b> and the second mold connection rod <b>64</b> are pivotally rotated in relation to each other at a predetermined angle greater than 90 degree, so that the second mold connection rod <b>64</b> actuates the second mold <b>70</b> to carry out a mold opening operation.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In the mold opening operation, the first push connection rod <b>32</b> and the push pivotal point <b>372</b> and the pivotal fulcrum <b>371</b> of the triple joint connection rod <b>37</b> are preferably longitudinally arranged along a common first vertical line (not-shown) in turn. Meanwhile, a horizontal extension line (not-shown) defined by the cam <b>10</b>, the cam follower <b>20</b> and the following connection rod <b>22</b> is substantially or closely vertical to the first vertical line. Thus, during the mold opening/closing operation, the foregoing design can disperse a downward push force fed back from the reciprocally longitudinal swing of the first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b> toward the first pivotal base <b>35</b> and the first support base <b>36</b>, so as to prevent from excessively and transversely transmitting to the triple joint connection rod <b>37</b>, the following connection rod <b>22</b>, the cam follower <b>20</b> and the cam <b>10</b> along the horizontal extension line. In other words, the abrasion problem of the cam <b>10</b> due to tightly abutment between the rollers <b>21</b> of the cam follower <b>20</b> and the inner and outer surfaces on the flange <b>12</b> of the cam <b>10</b> will be relatively reduced. Thus, it is advantageous to elongate the lifetime of the cam <b>10</b>, ensure the precision of mold closing operation, and increase the yield of bottle blow-molding.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Furthermore, in the mold opening operation, the second push connection rod <b>62</b> and the push pivotal point <b>672</b> and the pivotal fulcrum <b>671</b> of the double joint connection rod <b>67</b> are preferably longitudinally arranged along a common second vertical line (not-shown) in turn. Meanwhile, a rod extension line (not-shown) defined by the linkage connection rod <b>50</b> and the second vertical line have an included angle defined therebetween, wherein the included angle is close to 90 degree. Thus, during the mold opening/closing operation, the foregoing design can disperse a downward push force fed back from the reciprocally longitudinal swing of the second side connection rod assembly <b>60</b> toward the second pivotal base <b>65</b> and the second support base <b>66</b>, so as to prevent from excessively and transversely transmitting to the linkage connection rod <b>50</b> and the first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b> along the extension line of the linkage connection rod <b>50</b>. In other words, the abrasion problem of the inner and outer surfaces on the flange <b>12</b> of the cam <b>10</b> will be relatively reduced. Thus, it is advantageous to elongate the lifetime of the cam <b>10</b>, ensure the precision of mold closing operation, and increase the yield of bottle blow-molding.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds according to a third embodiment of the present invention is illustrated and similar to the second embodiment, so that the third embodiment uses similar terms and numerals of the second embodiment. As shown, the difference of the third embodiment is that: the first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b> of a multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds <b>300</b> of the third embodiment further comprises a first sliding connection rod <b>38</b> pivotally connected between the triple joint connection rod <b>37</b> and the first push connection rod <b>32</b>, while the second side connection rod assembly <b>60</b> further comprises a second sliding connection rod <b>68</b> pivotally connected the double joint connection rod <b>67</b> and the second push connection rod <b>62</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">For more details, a first end of the first sliding connection rod <b>38</b> is pivotally connected to the push pivotal point <b>372</b> of the triple joint connection rod <b>37</b>, and a second end thereof is pivotally connected to the first push connection rod <b>32</b> through a first push slider <b>381</b>, wherein the first push slider <b>381</b> can longitudinally move back and forth along a track (unlabeled) on the machine base of the mechanism for opening and closing molds <b>300</b>. Furthermore, a first end of the second sliding connection rod <b>68</b> is pivotally connected to the push pivotal point <b>672</b> of the double joint connection rod <b>67</b>, and a second end thereof is pivotally connected to the second push connection rod <b>62</b> through a second push slider <b>681</b>, wherein the second push slider <b>681</b> can longitudinally move back and forth along a track (unlabeled) on the machine base of the mechanism for opening and closing molds <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, in the third embodiment, when the first support connection rod <b>33</b> and the first mold connection rod <b>34</b> are pulled downward by the triple joint connection rod <b>37</b>, the first sliding connection rod <b>38</b> and the first push connection rod <b>32</b>, the first support connection rod <b>33</b> and the first mold connection rod <b>34</b> are transversely disposed at a common horizontal extension line, wherein the first mold connection rod <b>34</b> actuates the first mold <b>40</b> to carry out a mold closing operation. Meanwhile, the second support connection rod <b>63</b> and the second mold connection rod <b>64</b> are pulled downward by the double joint connection rod <b>67</b>, the second sliding connection rod <b>68</b> and the second push connection rod <b>62</b>, the second support connection rod <b>63</b> and the second mold connection rod <b>64</b> are transversely disposed at a common horizontal extension line, wherein the second mold connection rod <b>64</b> actuates the second mold <b>70</b> to carry out a mold closing operation.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">On the other hand, when the first support connection rod <b>33</b> and the first mold connection rod <b>34</b> are pushed upward by the triple joint connection rod <b>37</b>, the first sliding connection rod <b>38</b> and the first push connection rod <b>32</b>, the first support connection rod <b>33</b> and the first mold connection rod <b>34</b> are pivotally rotated in relation to each other at a predetermined angle greater than 90 degree, so that the first mold connection rod <b>34</b> actuates the first mold <b>40</b> to carry out a mold opening operation (not-shown). Meanwhile, the second support connection rod <b>63</b> and the second mold connection rod <b>64</b> are pushed upward by the double joint connection rod <b>67</b>, the second sliding connection rod <b>68</b> and the second push connection rod <b>62</b>, and then the second support connection rod <b>63</b> and the second mold connection rod <b>64</b> are pivotally rotated in relation to each other at a predetermined angle greater than 90 degree, so that the second mold connection rod <b>64</b> actuates the second mold <b>70</b> to carry out a mold opening operation.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">In the mold opening operation, the first push connection rod <b>32</b>, the first sliding connection rod <b>38</b> and the push pivotal point <b>372</b> and the pivotal fulcrum <b>371</b> of the triple joint connection rod <b>37</b> are preferably longitudinally arranged along a common first vertical line (not-shown) in turn. Meanwhile, a horizontal extension line (not-shown) defined by the cam <b>10</b>, the cam follower <b>20</b> and the following connection rod <b>22</b> is substantially or closely vertical to the first vertical line. Thus, during the mold opening/closing operation, the foregoing design can disperse a downward push force fed back from the reciprocally longitudinal swing of the first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b> toward the first pivotal base <b>35</b> and the first support base <b>36</b>, so as to prevent from excessively and transversely transmitting to the triple joint connection rod <b>37</b>, the following connection rod <b>22</b>, the cam follower <b>20</b> and the cam <b>10</b> along the horizontal extension line. In other words, the abrasion problem of the cam <b>10</b> due to tightly abutment between the rollers <b>21</b> of the cam follower <b>20</b> and the inner and outer surfaces on the flange <b>12</b> of the cam <b>10</b> will be relatively reduced. Thus, it is advantageous to elongate the lifetime of the cam <b>10</b>, ensure the precision of mold closing operation, and increase the yield of bottle blow-molding.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Furthermore, in the mold opening operation, the second push connection rod <b>62</b>, the second sliding connection rod <b>68</b> and the push pivotal point <b>672</b> and the pivotal fulcrum <b>671</b> of the double joint connection rod <b>67</b> are preferably longitudinally arranged along a common second vertical line (not-shown) in turn. Meanwhile, a rod extension line (not-shown) defined by the linkage connection rod <b>50</b> and the second vertical line have an included angle defined therebetween, wherein the included angle is close to 90 degree. Thus, during the mold opening/closing operation, the foregoing design can disperse a downward push force fed back from the reciprocally longitudinal swing of the second side connection rod assembly <b>60</b> toward the second pivotal base <b>65</b> and the second support base <b>66</b>, so as to prevent from excessively and transversely transmitting to the linkage connection rod <b>50</b> and the first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b> along the extension line of the linkage connection rod <b>50</b>. In other words, the abrasion problem of the inner and outer surfaces on the flange <b>12</b> of the cam <b>10</b> will be relatively reduced. Thus, it is advantageous to elongate the lifetime of the cam <b>10</b>, ensure the precision of mold closing operation, and increase the yield of bottle blow-molding.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, a multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds according to a fourth embodiment of the present invention is illustrated and similar to the first and third embodiments, so that the fourth embodiment uses similar terms and numerals of the first and third embodiments. As shown, the difference of the fourth embodiment is that: a multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds <b>400</b> of the fourth embodiment is constructed by a portion of components of the first embodiment and a portion of components of the third embodiment, wherein the multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds <b>400</b> comprises: a cam <b>10</b>, a cam follower <b>20</b>, a first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b>, a first mold <b>40</b>, a linkage connection rod <b>50</b>, a second side connection rod assembly <b>60</b> and a second mold <b>70</b>, wherein the cam <b>10</b> has a shaft <b>11</b> and a flange <b>12</b>; the cam follower <b>20</b> has a pair of rollers <b>21</b> and a following connection rod <b>22</b>; the first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b> has a quadruple joint connection rod <b>31</b>, a first push connection rod <b>32</b>, a first support connection rod <b>33</b>, a first mold connection rod <b>34</b>, a first pivotal base <b>35</b>, a first support base <b>36</b>, a first sliding connection rod <b>38</b> and a first push slider <b>381</b>, wherein the quadruple joint connection rod <b>31</b> has a pivotal fulcrum <b>311</b>, a following pivotal point <b>312</b>, a linkage pivotal point <b>313</b> and a push pivotal point <b>314</b>; the first mold <b>40</b> has a first mold cavity <b>41</b>; the linkage connection rod <b>50</b> is linked between the first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b> and the second side connection rod assembly <b>60</b>; the second side connection rod assembly <b>60</b> has a triple joint connection rod <b>61</b>, a second push connection rod <b>62</b>, a second support connection rod <b>63</b>, a second mold connection rod <b>64</b>, a second pivotal base <b>65</b>, a second support base <b>66</b>, a second sliding connection rod <b>68</b> and a second push slider <b>681</b>, wherein the triple joint connection rod <b>61</b> has a pivotal fulcrum <b>611</b>, a linkage pivotal point <b>612</b> and a push pivotal point <b>613</b>; and the second mold <b>70</b> has a second mold cavity <b>71</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In the fourth embodiment, the first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b> further comprises the first sliding connection rod <b>38</b> pivotally connected between the quadruple joint connection rod <b>31</b> and the first push connection rod <b>32</b>, while the second side connection rod assembly <b>60</b> further comprises a second sliding connection rod <b>68</b> pivotally connected the triple joint connection rod <b>61</b> and the second push connection rod <b>62</b>. Because the principle of the mold opening/closing operations of the multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds <b>400</b> in the fourth embodiment is similar to that of the multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds <b>100</b>, <b>300</b> in the first and third embodiments, the detailed description of the fourth embodiment is thus omitted herein.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">As described above, in comparison with the traditional mechanism for opening and closing molds which has too many cam surfaces and each of the cam surfaces easily lose the mold closing precision after long term use to affect the yield of subsequently feeding material and blowing bottles, the multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds <b>100</b> of the present invention as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 5</figref> is to actuate the first mold <b>40</b> at the first side of the cam <b>10</b> by the first side connection rod assembly <b>30</b> and to actuate the second side connection rod assembly <b>60</b> and the second mold <b>70</b> at the second side of the cam <b>10</b> by the linkage connection rod <b>50</b>. The multi-rod mechanism only uses the single cam <b>10</b> to simultaneously actuate the first and second molds <b>40</b>, <b>70</b>, so that the structure of the multi-rod mechanism can be simplified; the vibration, loading, noise and abrasion of components during operation can be relatively reduced; the operational speed and productivity of the multi-rod mechanism can be enhanced; the lifetime of the multi-rod mechanism can be elongated; and the maintenance and replacement rate of the multi-rod mechanism can be lowered.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The present invention has been described with a preferred embodiment thereof and it is understood that many changes and modifications to the described embodiment can be carried out without departing from the scope and the spirit of the invention that is intended to be limited only by the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds, comprising:
<claim-text>a cam rotating to generate a driving power;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cam follower actuated by the cam to linearly move back and forth;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first side connection rod assembly actuated by the cam follower to swing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first mold actuated by the first side connection rod assembly to linearly move back and forth;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a linkage connection rod actuated by the first side connection rod assembly to swing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second side connection rod assembly actuated by the linkage connection rod to swing, wherein the cam and the cam follower are disposed between the first side connection rod assembly and the second side connection rod assembly; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second mold actuated by the second side connection rod assembly to linearly move back and forth;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second mold cooperates with the corresponding first mold which linearly moves back and forth opposite to the second mold, so that the second mold is close to or away from the first mold for carrying out a mold closing operation or a mold opening operation;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first side connection rod assembly comprises a quadruple joint connection rod, a first push connection rod, a first support connection rod and a first mold connection rod; and wherein the quadruple joint connection rod is actuated by the cam follower to pivotally rotate, so that the first push connection rod then pushes or pulls the first support connection rod and the first mold connection rod;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the quadruple joint connection rod has a pivotal fulcrum, a following pivotal point, a linkage pivotal point and a push pivotal point; and wherein the pivotal fulcrum is pivotally connected to a first pivotal base, the following pivotal point is pivotally connected to the cam follower, the linkage pivotal point is pivotally connected to the linkage connection rod, and the push pivotal point is pivotally connected to the first push connection rod; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the cam follower has a following connection rod to be pivotally connected to the following pivotal point of the quadruple joint connection rod; the first push connection rod and the push pivotal point, the pivotal fulcrum and the linkage pivotal point of the quadruple joint connection rod are arranged along a common first vertical line in the mold opening operation or the mold closing operation; and a horizontal extension line defined by the cam follower and the following connection rod is vertical to the first vertical line.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first side connection rod assembly further comprises a first sliding connection rod pivotally connected between the quadruple joint connection rod and the first push connection rod.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second side connection rod assembly comprises a triple joint connection rod, a second push connection rod, a second support connection rod and a second mold connection rod; and wherein the triple joint connection rod is actuated by the linkage connection rod to pivotally rotate, so that the second push connection rod then pushes or pulls the second support connection rod and the second mold connection rod.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the triple joint connection rod has a pivotal fulcrum, a linkage pivotal point and a push pivotal point; and wherein the pivotal fulcrum is pivotally connected to a second pivotal base, the linkage pivotal point is pivotally connected to the linkage connection rod, and the push pivotal point is pivotally connected to the second push connection rod.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the second push connection rod and the push pivotal point and the pivotal fulcrum of the triple joint connection rod are arranged along a common second vertical line in the mold opening operation or the mold closing operation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the multi-rod mechanism is a mechanism for opening and closing molds of a bottle blow-molding machine.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the second side connection rod assembly further comprises a second sliding connection rod pivotally connected the triple joint connection rod and the second push connection rod.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second side connection rod assembly comprises a double joint connection rod, a second push connection rod, a second support connection rod and a second mold connection rod; and wherein the double joint connection rod is actuated by the linkage connection rod to pivotally rotate, so that the second push connection rod then pushes or pulls the second support connection rod and the second mold connection rod.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the double joint connection rod has a pivotal fulcrum and a push pivotal point; and wherein the pivotal fulcrum is pivotally connected to a second pivotal base, and the push pivotal point is pivotally connected to the second push connection rod and the linkage connection rod, respectively.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the second push connection rod and the push pivotal point and the pivotal fulcrum of the double joint connection rod are arranged along a common second vertical line in the mold opening operation or the mold closing operation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The multi-rod mechanism for opening and closing molds according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the second side connection rod assembly further comprises a second sliding connection rod pivotally connected the double joint connection rod and the second push connection rod. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
