<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625700-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625700</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13435157</doc-number>
<date>20120330</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>375267</main-classification>
<further-classification>342423</further-classification>
<further-classification>343751</further-classification>
<further-classification>375295</further-classification>
<further-classification>375299</further-classification>
<further-classification>375347</further-classification>
<further-classification>455101</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Evaluation device for providing a transceiver system with transceiving performance information thereof</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0047517</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Georgios et al.</name>
<date>20050300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>375267</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0261898</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Huang et al.</name>
<date>20111000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>375295</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>7</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130028310</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130131</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chiang</last-name>
<first-name>Ching-Tai</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wu</last-name>
<first-name>Rong-Ching</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ouyang</last-name>
<first-name>Chen-Sen</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="004" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tsai</last-name>
<first-name>Jong-Ian</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chiang</last-name>
<first-name>Ching-Tai</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wu</last-name>
<first-name>Rong-Ching</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ouyang</last-name>
<first-name>Chen-Sen</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="004" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tsai</last-name>
<first-name>Jong-Ian</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kamrath</last-name>
<first-name>Alan</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Kamrath IP Lawfirm, P.A.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>I-Shou University</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Dsouza</last-name>
<first-name>Adolf</first-name>
<department>2632</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An evaluation device provides a transceiver system with performance information. The transceiver system models channels between a transmitter and a receiver thereof using Nakagami distribution with a fading parameter. The evaluation device includes a setting module, a computing module and an output module. The computing module is operable, based upon the fading parameter, an average SNR of the channels, a number of transmit antennas and a number of receive antennas, to estimate an average output SNR, a bit error rate and an outage probability related to signals received by the receiver. The output module is operable to provide the transceiver system with the average SNR and the estimated information as the performance information.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="146.73mm" wi="135.13mm" file="US08625700-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="204.30mm" wi="131.74mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625700-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="164.34mm" wi="124.63mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625700-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="162.98mm" wi="134.20mm" file="US08625700-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="200.74mm" wi="131.40mm" file="US08625700-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="238.93mm" wi="142.41mm" file="US08625700-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="158.92mm" wi="151.47mm" file="US08625700-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="155.02mm" wi="163.15mm" file="US08625700-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to an evaluation device for providing a transceiver system with performance information thereof, more particularly to an evaluation device for providing a transceiver system, which models a channel thereof using Nakagami distribution, with transceiving performance information thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a conventional transceiver system <b>900</b> under a transmit antenna selection/maximal-ratio combining (TAS/MRC) scheme includes a transmitter (T<sub>X</sub>) and a receiver (R<sub>X</sub>). The transmitter (T<sub>X</sub>) includes a modulator <b>91</b>, a diversity unit <b>92</b> electrically connected to the modulator <b>91</b>, and a plurality of transmit antennas <b>93</b> electrically connected to the diversity unit <b>92</b>. The receiver (R<sub>X</sub>) includes a plurality of receive antennas <b>94</b>, a synthesis unit <b>95</b> electrically connected to the receive antennas <b>94</b>, and a demodulator <b>96</b> electrically connected to the synthesis unit <b>95</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The conventional transceiver system <b>900</b> is operable, in advance, to estimate the channels between the transmitter (T<sub>X</sub>) and the receiver (R<sub>X</sub>), so that the diversity unit <b>92</b> of the transmitter (T<sub>X</sub>) is operable to select one of the transmit antennas <b>93</b>, which results in a channel that has relatively better performance, for transmitting a signal generated by the modulator <b>91</b>. Then, when the receive antennas <b>94</b> of the receiver (R<sub>X</sub>) receive signals from the selected one of the transmit antennas <b>93</b>, the synthesis unit <b>95</b> of the receiver (R<sub>X</sub>) is operable to weight and synthesize the signals received by the receive antennas <b>94</b>. Accordingly, performance of the conventional transceiver system <b>900</b> is optimized, that is to say, the conventional transceiver system <b>900</b> has, for example, a relatively greater diversity gain or a relatively greater average signal-to-noise ratio (SNR).</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">However, the conventional transceiver system <b>900</b> under the TAS/MRC scheme merely has the optimized performance for a single receiver (Rx). When further including additional receivers (Rx), the conventional transceiver system <b>900</b> may not be able to optimize transmission performance between the transmitter (T<sub>X</sub>) and some of the receivers (R<sub>X</sub>), and thus, the overall performance thereof may be decreased.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Accordingly, a transmit generalized selection/maximal-ratio combining (TGS/MRC) scheme is provided as a solution for the above-mentioned drawback of the conventional transceiver system <b>900</b> under the TAS/MRC scheme. In particular, a conventional transceiver system under the TGS/MRC scheme does not have to select one of transmit antennas, which may result in a channel that has relatively better performance, for transmitting signals, and can be operable to transmit signals with a different one of the transmit antennas according to a different situation so as to ensure the overall performance thereof and transmission quality for various receivers.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In &#x201c;Performance of Selection MIMO Systems with Generalized Selection Criterion over Nakagami-m Fading Channels,&#x201d; <i>IEICE Trans. Commun</i>., E89-B(12), pages 3467-3470, 2006, S. Choi and Y. C. Ko proposed a method for evaluating performance of the conventional transceiver system under the TGS/MRC scheme by using Nakagami channel model (see Nakagami distribution shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) to simulate the channels of the conventional transceiver system under the TGS/MRC scheme. In this method, an average output SNR and a bit error rate are computed for evaluating performance of the conventional transceiver system under the TGS/MRC scheme. However, the computational load of the average output SNR and the bit error rate is considerably large, that is to say, a number m&#xd7;L<sub>R </sub>of summation operations are executed for obtaining the average output SNR and the bit error rate, where m is a fading parameter of the Nakagami distribution and L<sub>R </sub>is a number of the receiver antennas. Further, computation of an outage probability of the conventional transceiver system is not provided in this method.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Therefore, an object of the present invention is to provide an evaluation device that requires fewer computations for providing a transceiver system with transceiving performance information thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Accordingly, an evaluation device of the present invention is configured to provide a transceiver system with transceiving performance information thereof. The transceiver system includes a transmitter having a plurality of transmit antennas and a receiver having a plurality of receive antennas for receiving signals from the transmitter, and models channels between the transmitter and the receiver using Nakagami distribution with a fading parameter. The evaluation device comprises a setting module, a computing module and an output module.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The setting module is operable to set an average signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) for the channels between the transmitter and the receiver of the transceiver system. The computing module is operable, based upon the fading parameter, the average SNR, a number of the transmit antennas and a number of the receive antennas, to estimate at least one of an average output SNR, a bit error rate and an outage probability that are related to signals received by the receiver of the transceiver system. The output module is operable to provide the transceiver system with the average SNR and said at least one of the average output SNR, the bit error rate and the outage probability as the transceiving performance information of the transceiver system.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Other features and advantages of the present invention will become apparent in the following detailed description of the preferred embodiment with reference to the accompanying drawings, of which:</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram illustrating a conventional transceiver system;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a plot to illustrate Nakagami distribution;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a block diagram illustrating a transceiver system provided with a preferred embodiment of an evaluation device of this invention;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a block diagram illustrating the evaluation device of the preferred embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a flow chart of an evaluation method implemented by the evaluation device of this embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a simulation plot for illustrating normalized average output signal-to-noise ratios for respective transmit antennas of the transceiver system of the preferred embodiment with respect to fading parameters of Nakagami channel model;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a simulation plot for illustrating normalized average output signal-to-noise ratios for respective transmit antennas of a conventional transceiver system with respect to the fading parameters of the same Nakagami channel model in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a simulation plot for illustrating a relationship between a bit error rate and an average signal-to-noise ratio; and</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a simulation plot for illustrating a relationship between an outage probability and an average signal-to-noise ratio.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a transceiver system <b>100</b> under a transmit generalized selection/maximal-ratio combining (TGS/MRC) scheme includes a transmitter <b>1</b> and a receiver <b>2</b> coupled to the preferred embodiment of an evaluation device <b>200</b> of this invention. For instance, the transmitter <b>1</b> is a base station, and the receiver <b>2</b> is a cell phone. The transmitter <b>1</b> includes a diversity unit <b>11</b> and a number (L<sub>T</sub>, L<sub>T</sub>&#x3e;1) of transmit antennas <b>12</b>, and the receiver <b>2</b> includes a number (L<sub>R</sub>, L<sub>R</sub>&#x3e;1) of receive antennas <b>22</b>, a synthesis unit <b>21</b>, and a channel estimator <b>23</b>. For illustrative purposes, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the transmitter <b>1</b> includes three (L<sub>T</sub>=3) of the transmit antennas <b>12</b>, and the receiver <b>2</b> includes two (L<sub>R</sub>=2) of the receive antennas <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In such a TGS/MRC scheme, there area number (L<sub>T</sub>&#xd7;L<sub>R</sub>) of possible channels, each of which is defined by one of the transmit antennas <b>12</b> and one of the receive antennas <b>22</b> and can be simulated using Nakagami channel model (see Nakagami distribution shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) with a positive fading parameter (m). The channel estimator of the receiver <b>2</b> is operable to estimate an instantaneous output signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) of a synthesized signal generated by the synthesis unit <b>21</b> applying maximal-ratio combining to signals received by the receive antennas <b>22</b> from each one of the transmit antennas <b>12</b>, and to provide the diversity unit <b>11</b> of the transmitter <b>1</b> with a number (L<sub>T</sub>) of the instantaneous output SNRs corresponding respectively to the transmit antennas <b>12</b>. Accordingly, the diversity unit <b>11</b> is operable to sort the instantaneous output SNRs in a specified sequence according to increasing magnitude, and to assign the transmit antennas <b>12</b> with respective positive integer ordinal numbers (l, 1&#x2266;l&#x2266;L<sub>T</sub>) according to the specified sequence. In particular, a smaller one of the ordinal numbers (l) indicates a corresponding one of the transmit antennas <b>12</b> with a smaller instantaneous output SNR.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Under the TGS/MRC scheme, the diversity unit <b>11</b> is operable to select one of the transmit antennas <b>12</b>, which corresponds to one of the ordinal numbers (l), for transmitting signals, and the channels between the selected one of the transmit antennas <b>12</b> and the receive antennas <b>22</b> are simulated using the Nakagami channel model (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) and preferably have a same average signal-to-noise ratio (SNR, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>). When the fading parameter (m) of the Nakagami channel model and the number (L<sub>R</sub>) of the receive antennas <b>22</b> is an integer, an average output SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l)</sub>), a bit error rate (P<sub>BER</sub>) and an outage probability (P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>)) of the synthesized signal outputted by the synthesis unit <b>21</b> can be computed based upon the following Equations (1) to (5).</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Generally, the average output SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l)</sub>) can be expressed as</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">
<maths id="MATH-US-00001" num="00001">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <msub>
          <mover>
            <mi>&#x3b3;</mi>
            <mi>_</mi>
          </mover>
          <mrow>
            <mo>(</mo>
            <mi>l</mi>
            <mo>)</mo>
          </mrow>
        </msub>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mfrac>
            <mrow>
              <mi>l</mi>
              <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <mover>
                    <mi>&#x3b3;</mi>
                    <mi>_</mi>
                  </mover>
                  <mo>/</mo>
                  <mi>m</mi>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <mi>m</mi>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <mstyle>
                      <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                    </mstyle>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>L</mi>
                      <mi>R</mi>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
              <mo>!</mo>
            </mrow>
          </mfrac>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mo>(</mo>
            <mtable>
              <mtr>
                <mtd>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                    <mi>T</mi>
                  </msub>
                </mtd>
              </mtr>
              <mtr>
                <mtd>
                  <mi>l</mi>
                </mtd>
              </mtr>
            </mtable>
            <mo>)</mo>
          </mrow>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <munderover>
              <mo>&#x2211;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mi>n</mi>
                <mo>=</mo>
                <mn>0</mn>
              </mrow>
              <mrow>
                <mi>l</mi>
                <mo>-</mo>
                <mn>1</mn>
              </mrow>
            </munderover>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mtable>
                  <mtr>
                    <mtd>
                      <mrow>
                        <mi>l</mi>
                        <mo>-</mo>
                        <mn>1</mn>
                      </mrow>
                    </mtd>
                  </mtr>
                  <mtr>
                    <mtd>
                      <mi>n</mi>
                    </mtd>
                  </mtr>
                </mtable>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <msup>
                <mrow>
                  <mo>(</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mo>-</mo>
                    <mn>1</mn>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>)</mo>
                </mrow>
                <mi>n</mi>
              </msup>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <munderover>
                  <mo>&#x2211;</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mi>k</mi>
                    <mo>=</mo>
                    <mn>0</mn>
                  </mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <mrow>
                      <mo>(</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <msub>
                          <mi>L</mi>
                          <mi>T</mi>
                        </msub>
                        <mo>-</mo>
                        <mi>l</mi>
                        <mo>+</mo>
                        <mi>n</mi>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>)</mo>
                    </mrow>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <mrow>
                      <mo>(</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <mrow>
                          <mi>m</mi>
                          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                          <mstyle>
                            <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                          </mstyle>
                          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                          <msub>
                            <mi>L</mi>
                            <mi>R</mi>
                          </msub>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>-</mo>
                        <mn>1</mn>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>)</mo>
                    </mrow>
                  </mrow>
                </munderover>
                <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>&#x3b2;</mi>
                    <mi>k</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mfrac>
                    <mrow>
                      <mrow>
                        <mo>(</mo>
                        <mrow>
                          <mrow>
                            <mi>m</mi>
                            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                            <mstyle>
                              <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                            </mstyle>
                            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                            <msub>
                              <mi>L</mi>
                              <mi>R</mi>
                            </msub>
                          </mrow>
                          <mo>+</mo>
                          <mi>k</mi>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>)</mo>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>!</mo>
                    </mrow>
                    <msup>
                      <mrow>
                        <mo>(</mo>
                        <mrow>
                          <msub>
                            <mi>L</mi>
                            <mi>T</mi>
                          </msub>
                          <mo>-</mo>
                          <mi>l</mi>
                          <mo>+</mo>
                          <mi>n</mi>
                          <mo>+</mo>
                          <mn>1</mn>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>)</mo>
                      </mrow>
                      <mrow>
                        <mrow>
                          <mi>m</mi>
                          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                          <mstyle>
                            <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                          </mstyle>
                          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                          <msub>
                            <mi>L</mi>
                            <mi>R</mi>
                          </msub>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>+</mo>
                        <mi>k</mi>
                        <mo>+</mo>
                        <mn>1</mn>
                      </mrow>
                    </msup>
                  </mfrac>
                </mrow>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mn>1</mn>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
where &#x3b2;<sub>0</sub>=1, &#x3b2;<sub>1</sub>=L<sub>T</sub>&#x2212;l+n,
</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">
<maths id="MATH-US-00002" num="00002">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <msub>
    <mi>&#x3b2;</mi>
    <mi>k</mi>
  </msub>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mrow>
    <mfrac>
      <mn>1</mn>
      <mi>k</mi>
    </mfrac>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <mrow>
      <munderover>
        <mo>&#x2211;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>j</mi>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mn>1</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mi>min</mi>
          <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mo>(</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mi>k</mi>
              <mo>,</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mrow>
                  <mi>m</mi>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mstyle>
                    <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                  </mstyle>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                    <mi>R</mi>
                  </msub>
                </mrow>
                <mo>-</mo>
                <mn>1</mn>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
            <mo>)</mo>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </munderover>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mfrac>
          <mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mi>j</mi>
              <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                    <mi>T</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <mi>l</mi>
                  <mo>+</mo>
                  <mi>n</mi>
                  <mo>+</mo>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
            <mo>-</mo>
            <mi>k</mi>
          </mrow>
          <mrow>
            <mi>j</mi>
            <mo>!</mo>
          </mrow>
        </mfrac>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <msub>
          <mi>&#x3b2;</mi>
          <mrow>
            <mi>k</mi>
            <mo>-</mo>
            <mi>j</mi>
          </mrow>
        </msub>
      </mrow>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
for 2&#x2266;k&#x2266;(L<sub>T</sub>&#x2212;l+n)(mL<sub>R</sub>&#x2212;1)&#x2212;1, and &#x3b2;<sub>k</sub>=[(mL<sub>R</sub>&#x2212;1)!]<sup>&#x2212;(L</sup><sup><sub2>T</sub2></sup><sup>&#x2212;l+n) </sup>for k=(L<sub>T</sub>&#x2212;l+n)(mL<sub>R</sub>&#x2212;1).
</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">When the transceiver system <b>100</b> is configured to perform signal modulation using binary phase-shift keying (BPSK), the bit error rate (P<sub>BER</sub>) of the synthesized signal outputted by the synthesis unit <b>21</b> can be expressed as</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">
<maths id="MATH-US-00003" num="00003">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <msub>
          <mi>P</mi>
          <mi>BER</mi>
        </msub>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mfrac>
            <mi>l</mi>
            <mrow>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <mi>m</mi>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <mstyle>
                      <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                    </mstyle>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>L</mi>
                      <mi>R</mi>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
              <mo>!</mo>
            </mrow>
          </mfrac>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mo>(</mo>
            <mtable>
              <mtr>
                <mtd>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                    <mi>T</mi>
                  </msub>
                </mtd>
              </mtr>
              <mtr>
                <mtd>
                  <mi>l</mi>
                </mtd>
              </mtr>
            </mtable>
            <mo>)</mo>
          </mrow>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <munderover>
              <mo>&#x2211;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mi>n</mi>
                <mo>=</mo>
                <mn>0</mn>
              </mrow>
              <mrow>
                <mi>l</mi>
                <mo>-</mo>
                <mn>1</mn>
              </mrow>
            </munderover>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mtable>
                  <mtr>
                    <mtd>
                      <mrow>
                        <mi>l</mi>
                        <mo>-</mo>
                        <mn>1</mn>
                      </mrow>
                    </mtd>
                  </mtr>
                  <mtr>
                    <mtd>
                      <mi>n</mi>
                    </mtd>
                  </mtr>
                </mtable>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <msup>
                <mrow>
                  <mo>(</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mo>-</mo>
                    <mn>1</mn>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>)</mo>
                </mrow>
                <mi>n</mi>
              </msup>
              <mo>&#xd7;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <munderover>
                  <mo>&#x2211;</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mi>k</mi>
                    <mo>=</mo>
                    <mn>0</mn>
                  </mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <mrow>
                      <mo>(</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <msub>
                          <mi>L</mi>
                          <mi>T</mi>
                        </msub>
                        <mo>-</mo>
                        <mi>l</mi>
                        <mo>+</mo>
                        <mi>n</mi>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>)</mo>
                    </mrow>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <mrow>
                      <mo>(</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <mrow>
                          <mi>m</mi>
                          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                          <mstyle>
                            <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                          </mstyle>
                          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                          <msub>
                            <mi>L</mi>
                            <mi>R</mi>
                          </msub>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>-</mo>
                        <mn>1</mn>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>)</mo>
                    </mrow>
                  </mrow>
                </munderover>
                <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>&#x3b2;</mi>
                    <mi>k</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mstyle>
                    <mspace width="0.em" height="0.ex"/>
                  </mstyle>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <msup>
                    <mrow>
                      <mfrac>
                        <mrow>
                          <mrow>
                            <mo>(</mo>
                            <mrow>
                              <mrow>
                                <mi>m</mi>
                                <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                                <mstyle>
                                  <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                                </mstyle>
                                <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                                <msub>
                                  <mi>L</mi>
                                  <mi>R</mi>
                                </msub>
                              </mrow>
                              <mo>+</mo>
                              <mi>k</mi>
                              <mo>-</mo>
                              <mn>1</mn>
                            </mrow>
                            <mo>)</mo>
                          </mrow>
                          <mo>!</mo>
                        </mrow>
                        <msup>
                          <mrow>
                            <mo>(</mo>
                            <mrow>
                              <msub>
                                <mi>L</mi>
                                <mi>T</mi>
                              </msub>
                              <mo>-</mo>
                              <mi>l</mi>
                              <mo>+</mo>
                              <mi>n</mi>
                              <mo>+</mo>
                              <mn>1</mn>
                            </mrow>
                            <mo>)</mo>
                          </mrow>
                          <mrow>
                            <mrow>
                              <mi>m</mi>
                              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                              <mstyle>
                                <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                              </mstyle>
                              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                              <msub>
                                <mi>L</mi>
                                <mi>R</mi>
                              </msub>
                            </mrow>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <mi>k</mi>
                          </mrow>
                        </msup>
                      </mfrac>
                      <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <mo>[</mo>
                        <mrow>
                          <mfrac>
                            <mn>1</mn>
                            <mn>2</mn>
                          </mfrac>
                          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                          <mrow>
                            <mo>(</mo>
                            <mrow>
                              <mn>1</mn>
                              <mo>-</mo>
                              <msqrt>
                                <mfrac>
                                  <mi>&#x3b1;</mi>
                                  <mrow>
                                    <mn>1</mn>
                                    <mo>+</mo>
                                    <mi>&#x3b1;</mi>
                                  </mrow>
                                </mfrac>
                              </msqrt>
                            </mrow>
                            <mo>)</mo>
                          </mrow>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>]</mo>
                      </mrow>
                    </mrow>
                    <mrow>
                      <mrow>
                        <mi>m</mi>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <mstyle>
                          <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                        </mstyle>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <msub>
                          <mi>L</mi>
                          <mi>R</mi>
                        </msub>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>+</mo>
                      <mi>k</mi>
                    </mrow>
                  </msup>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mstyle>
                    <mspace width="0.em" height="0.ex"/>
                  </mstyle>
                  <mo>&#xd7;</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <munderover>
                      <mo>&#x2211;</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <mi>j</mi>
                        <mo>=</mo>
                        <mn>0</mn>
                      </mrow>
                      <mrow>
                        <mrow>
                          <mi>m</mi>
                          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                          <mstyle>
                            <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                          </mstyle>
                          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                          <msub>
                            <mi>L</mi>
                            <mi>R</mi>
                          </msub>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>+</mo>
                        <mi>k</mi>
                        <mo>-</mo>
                        <mn>1</mn>
                      </mrow>
                    </munderover>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <msup>
                      <mrow>
                        <mrow>
                          <mo>(</mo>
                          <mtable>
                            <mtr>
                              <mtd>
                                <mrow>
                                  <mrow>
                                    <mi>m</mi>
                                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                                    <mstyle>
                                      <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                                    </mstyle>
                                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                                    <msub>
                                      <mi>L</mi>
                                      <mi>R</mi>
                                    </msub>
                                  </mrow>
                                  <mo>+</mo>
                                  <mi>k</mi>
                                  <mo>-</mo>
                                  <mn>1</mn>
                                  <mo>+</mo>
                                  <mi>j</mi>
                                </mrow>
                              </mtd>
                            </mtr>
                            <mtr>
                              <mtd>
                                <mi>j</mi>
                              </mtd>
                            </mtr>
                          </mtable>
                          <mo>)</mo>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
                        <mrow>
                          <mo>[</mo>
                          <mrow>
                            <mfrac>
                              <mn>1</mn>
                              <mn>2</mn>
                            </mfrac>
                            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                            <mrow>
                              <mo>(</mo>
                              <mrow>
                                <mn>1</mn>
                                <mo>+</mo>
                                <msqrt>
                                  <mfrac>
                                    <mi>&#x3b1;</mi>
                                    <mrow>
                                      <mn>1</mn>
                                      <mo>+</mo>
                                      <mi>&#x3b1;</mi>
                                    </mrow>
                                  </mfrac>
                                </msqrt>
                              </mrow>
                              <mo>)</mo>
                            </mrow>
                          </mrow>
                          <mo>]</mo>
                        </mrow>
                      </mrow>
                      <mi>j</mi>
                    </msup>
                  </mrow>
                </mrow>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mn>2</mn>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
where &#x3b1;= <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>/[m(L<sub>T</sub>&#x2212;l+n+1)]. Further, when the SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>) is considerably greater than 1 (i.e., the SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>) is greater than a predetermined value), Equation (2) can simplified as Equation (3).
</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">
<maths id="MATH-US-00004" num="00004">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <msub>
          <mi>P</mi>
          <mi>BER</mi>
        </msub>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mfrac>
            <mrow>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <mn>2</mn>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>mlL</mi>
                      <mi>R</mi>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
              <mo>!</mo>
            </mrow>
            <mrow>
              <msup>
                <mrow>
                  <msup>
                    <mn>2</mn>
                    <mrow>
                      <mrow>
                        <mn>2</mn>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <msub>
                          <mi>mlL</mi>
                          <mi>R</mi>
                        </msub>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>-</mo>
                      <mn>1</mn>
                    </mrow>
                  </msup>
                  <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mo>[</mo>
                    <mrow>
                      <mrow>
                        <mo>(</mo>
                        <mrow>
                          <mi>m</mi>
                          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                          <mstyle>
                            <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                          </mstyle>
                          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                          <msub>
                            <mi>L</mi>
                            <mi>R</mi>
                          </msub>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>)</mo>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>!</mo>
                    </mrow>
                    <mo>]</mo>
                  </mrow>
                </mrow>
                <mi>l</mi>
              </msup>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mrow>
                  <mo>(</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>mlL</mi>
                      <mi>R</mi>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>-</mo>
                    <mn>1</mn>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>)</mo>
                </mrow>
                <mo>!</mo>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
          </mfrac>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mo>(</mo>
            <mtable>
              <mtr>
                <mtd>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                    <mi>T</mi>
                  </msub>
                </mtd>
              </mtr>
              <mtr>
                <mtd>
                  <mi>l</mi>
                </mtd>
              </mtr>
            </mtable>
            <mo>)</mo>
          </mrow>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <msup>
            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>
              <mfrac>
                <mi>m</mi>
                <mover>
                  <mi>&#x3b3;</mi>
                  <mi>_</mi>
                </mover>
              </mfrac>
              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>
            <msub>
              <mi>mlL</mi>
              <mi>R</mi>
            </msub>
          </msup>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mn>3</mn>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The outage probability (P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>)) means the probability that the instantaneous channel capacity of the transceiver system <b>100</b> is smaller than a given capacity (R), and can be expressed as</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">
<maths id="MATH-US-00005" num="00005">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <msub>
            <mi>P</mi>
            <mi>out</mi>
          </msub>
          <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mo>(</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mi>R</mi>
              <mo>,</mo>
              <mover>
                <mi>&#x3b3;</mi>
                <mi>_</mi>
              </mover>
            </mrow>
            <mo>)</mo>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mfrac>
            <mi>l</mi>
            <mrow>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <mi>m</mi>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <mstyle>
                      <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                    </mstyle>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>L</mi>
                      <mi>R</mi>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
              <mo>!</mo>
            </mrow>
          </mfrac>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mo>(</mo>
            <mtable>
              <mtr>
                <mtd>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                    <mi>T</mi>
                  </msub>
                </mtd>
              </mtr>
              <mtr>
                <mtd>
                  <mi>l</mi>
                </mtd>
              </mtr>
            </mtable>
            <mo>)</mo>
          </mrow>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <munderover>
              <mo>&#x2211;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mi>n</mi>
                <mo>=</mo>
                <mn>0</mn>
              </mrow>
              <mrow>
                <mi>l</mi>
                <mo>-</mo>
                <mn>1</mn>
              </mrow>
            </munderover>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mtable>
                  <mtr>
                    <mtd>
                      <mrow>
                        <mi>l</mi>
                        <mo>-</mo>
                        <mn>1</mn>
                      </mrow>
                    </mtd>
                  </mtr>
                  <mtr>
                    <mtd>
                      <mi>n</mi>
                    </mtd>
                  </mtr>
                </mtable>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <msup>
                <mrow>
                  <mo>(</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mo>-</mo>
                    <mn>1</mn>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>)</mo>
                </mrow>
                <mi>n</mi>
              </msup>
              <mo>&#xd7;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <munderover>
                  <mo>&#x2211;</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mi>k</mi>
                    <mo>=</mo>
                    <mn>0</mn>
                  </mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <mrow>
                      <mo>(</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <msub>
                          <mi>L</mi>
                          <mi>T</mi>
                        </msub>
                        <mo>-</mo>
                        <mi>l</mi>
                        <mo>+</mo>
                        <mi>n</mi>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>)</mo>
                    </mrow>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <mrow>
                      <mo>(</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <mrow>
                          <mi>m</mi>
                          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                          <mstyle>
                            <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                          </mstyle>
                          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                          <msub>
                            <mi>L</mi>
                            <mi>R</mi>
                          </msub>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>-</mo>
                        <mn>1</mn>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>)</mo>
                    </mrow>
                  </mrow>
                </munderover>
                <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>&#x3b2;</mi>
                    <mi>k</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mfrac>
                    <mrow>
                      <mi>&#x3b3;</mi>
                      <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <mo>(</mo>
                        <mrow>
                          <mrow>
                            <mrow>
                              <mi>m</mi>
                              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                              <mstyle>
                                <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                              </mstyle>
                              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                              <msub>
                                <mi>L</mi>
                                <mi>R</mi>
                              </msub>
                            </mrow>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <mi>k</mi>
                          </mrow>
                          <mo>,</mo>
                          <mrow>
                            <mrow>
                              <mo>[</mo>
                              <mrow>
                                <msub>
                                  <mi>L</mi>
                                  <mi>T</mi>
                                </msub>
                                <mo>-</mo>
                                <mi>l</mi>
                                <mo>+</mo>
                                <mi>n</mi>
                                <mo>+</mo>
                                <mn>1</mn>
                              </mrow>
                              <mo>]</mo>
                            </mrow>
                            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                            <mi>m</mi>
                            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                            <mstyle>
                              <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                            </mstyle>
                            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                            <mrow>
                              <mi>&#x3bb;</mi>
                              <mo>/</mo>
                              <mover>
                                <mi>&#x3b3;</mi>
                                <mi>_</mi>
                              </mover>
                            </mrow>
                          </mrow>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>)</mo>
                      </mrow>
                    </mrow>
                    <msup>
                      <mrow>
                        <mo>[</mo>
                        <mrow>
                          <msub>
                            <mi>L</mi>
                            <mi>T</mi>
                          </msub>
                          <mo>-</mo>
                          <mi>l</mi>
                          <mo>+</mo>
                          <mi>n</mi>
                          <mo>+</mo>
                          <mn>1</mn>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>]</mo>
                      </mrow>
                      <mrow>
                        <mrow>
                          <mi>m</mi>
                          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                          <mstyle>
                            <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                          </mstyle>
                          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                          <msub>
                            <mi>L</mi>
                            <mi>R</mi>
                          </msub>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>+</mo>
                        <mi>k</mi>
                      </mrow>
                    </msup>
                  </mfrac>
                </mrow>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mn>4</mn>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
<br/>
where &#x3b3;( ) is a low-level incomplete Gamma function, and &#x3bb;=2<sup>R</sup>&#x2212;1.
</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Similarly, when the SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>) is considerably greater than 1 (i.e., the SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>) is greater than a predetermined value), Equation (4) can simplified as Equation (5).</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">
<maths id="MATH-US-00006" num="00006">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <msub>
            <mi>P</mi>
            <mi>out</mi>
          </msub>
          <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mo>(</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mi>R</mi>
              <mo>,</mo>
              <mover>
                <mi>&#x3b3;</mi>
                <mi>_</mi>
              </mover>
            </mrow>
            <mo>)</mo>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mfrac>
            <msup>
              <mi>m</mi>
              <msub>
                <mi>mlL</mi>
                <mi>R</mi>
              </msub>
            </msup>
            <msup>
              <mrow>
                <mo>[</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <mo>(</mo>
                    <mrow>
                      <mi>m</mi>
                      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                      <mstyle>
                        <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                      </mstyle>
                      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                      <msub>
                        <mi>L</mi>
                        <mi>R</mi>
                      </msub>
                    </mrow>
                    <mo>)</mo>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>!</mo>
                </mrow>
                <mo>]</mo>
              </mrow>
              <mi>l</mi>
            </msup>
          </mfrac>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mo>(</mo>
            <mtable>
              <mtr>
                <mtd>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                    <mi>T</mi>
                  </msub>
                </mtd>
              </mtr>
              <mtr>
                <mtd>
                  <mi>l</mi>
                </mtd>
              </mtr>
            </mtable>
            <mo>)</mo>
          </mrow>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <msup>
            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>
              <mfrac>
                <mi>&#x3bb;</mi>
                <mover>
                  <mi>&#x3b3;</mi>
                  <mi>_</mi>
                </mover>
              </mfrac>
              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>
            <msub>
              <mi>mlL</mi>
              <mi>R</mi>
            </msub>
          </msup>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mn>5</mn>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">It should be noted that, although the transceiver system <b>100</b> is exemplarily illustrated as the TGS/MRC scheme, configuration thereof may be considered as a transmit antenna selection/maximal-ratio combining (TAS/MRC) scheme when the ordinal number (l) is equal to the number (L<sub>T</sub>) of the transmit antennas <b>12</b>. Further, the Nakagami channel model is able to cover a wide range of fading severity due to variation of the fading parameter (m), and includes the Rayleigh fading channel (i.e., m=1) as a special case.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref>, the evaluation device <b>200</b> of the preferred embodiment is configured for analyzing the synthesized signal from the synthesis unit <b>21</b> so as to provide the transceiver system <b>100</b> with the transceiving performance information of the transceiver system <b>100</b>. The evaluation device <b>200</b> includes a setting module <b>3</b>, a computing module <b>4</b> coupled to the setting module <b>3</b>, and an output module <b>5</b> coupled to the computing module <b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The setting module <b>3</b> is operable to set the average signal-to-noise ratio (&#x3b3;) for the possible channels between the transmitter <b>1</b> and the receiver <b>2</b> of the transceiver system <b>100</b>. Based upon one of the ordinal numbers (l), the fading parameter (m) of Nakagami distribution, the average SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>), the number (L<sub>T</sub>) of the transmit antennas <b>12</b>, and the number (L<sub>R</sub>) of the receive antennas <b>22</b>, the computing module <b>4</b> is operable to estimate at least one of the average output SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l)</sub>), the bit error rate (P<sub>BER</sub>) and the outage probability (P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>)) of the synthesized signal according to an appropriate one of Equations (1) to (5). Then, the output module <b>5</b> is operable to provide the transceiver system <b>100</b> with the average SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>) and said at least one of the average output SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l)</sub>), the bit error rate (P<sub>BER</sub>) and the outage probability (P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>)) as the transceiving performance information of the transceiver system <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">It can be appreciated that, when the computing module <b>4</b> computes the average output SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l)</sub>), the bit error rate (P<sub>BER</sub>) and the outage probability (P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>)) with a finite number of summation operations (&#x3a3;), i.e., Equations (1), (2) and (4), the number of the summation operations is independent from the number (L<sub>R</sub>) of the receive antennas <b>22</b> and the fading parameter (m) of the Nakagami channel model. The following Table 1 shows a comparison of computation of the performance information between this embodiment and the method proposed by S. Choi and Y. C. Ko in &#x201c;Performance of Selection MIMO Systems with Generalized Selection Criterion over Nakagami-m Fading Channels,&#x201d; <i>IEICE Trans. Commun</i>., E89-B (12), pages 3467-3470, 2006.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00001" num="00001">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="42pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="175pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" rowsep="1">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>Number of Summation Operations (&#x3a3;)</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="4">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="42pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="70pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="70pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry> <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l)</sub></entry>
<entry>P<sub>BER</sub></entry>
<entry>P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="6">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="42pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>This</entry>
<entry>Eq. (1)</entry>
<entry>Eq. (2)</entry>
<entry>Eq. (3)</entry>
<entry>Eq. (4)</entry>
<entry>Eq. (5)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Embodiment</entry>
<entry>2</entry>
<entry>3</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>2</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="4">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="42pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="70pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="70pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>S. Choi et al.</entry>
<entry>m &#xd7; L<sub>R</sub></entry>
<entry>m &#xd7; L<sub>R</sub></entry>
<entry>N/A</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">As shown in Table 1, in the method proposed by S. Choi and Y. C. Ko, when the fading parameter (m) is equal to 1, computation of the average output SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l)</sub>) and computation of the bit error rate (P<sub>BER</sub>) both involve twelve summation operations (&#x3a3;) for an ultra-high-speed packet transmission scheme that is proposed by NTT DoCoMo and that includes twelve receive antennas <b>22</b> in the receiver <b>2</b> of the transceiver system <b>100</b>. Compared with the method proposed by S. Choi and Y. C. Ko, the computation of the average output SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l)</sub>) and computation of the bit error rate (P<sub>BER</sub>) performed by the computing module <b>4</b> of this embodiment are considerably less. In addition, computation of the outage probability (P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>)) will not increase when the fading parameter (m) or the number (L<sub>R</sub>) of the receive antennas <b>22</b> is increased.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows a flow chart of an evaluation method implemented by the evaluation device <b>300</b> of this embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In step <b>61</b>, the setting module <b>3</b> is operable to set each of the possible channels with the same average SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>).</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In step <b>62</b>, based upon one of the ordinal numbers (l), the fading parameter (m) of Nakagami distribution, the average SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>), the number (L<sub>T</sub>) of the transmit antennas <b>12</b>, and the number (L<sub>R</sub>) of the receive antennas <b>22</b>, the computing module <b>4</b> is operable to compute one of the average output SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l)</sub>), the bit error rate (P<sub>BER</sub>) and the outage probability (P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>)) according to an appropriate one of Equations (1) to (5). In particular, the computing module <b>4</b> is operable to compute the average output SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l)</sub>) based upon Equation (1). When the average SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>) is greater than the predetermined value, the computing module <b>4</b> is operable to compute the bit error rate (P<sub>BER</sub>) and the outage probability (P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>)) based upon Equations (3) and (5), respectively. Otherwise, the computing module <b>4</b> is operable to compute the bit error rate (P<sub>BER</sub>) and the outage probability (P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>)) based upon Equations (2) and (4), respectively. In practice, the computing module <b>4</b> may be configured to estimate another one of the average output SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l)</sub>), the bit error rate (P<sub>BER</sub>) and the outage probability (P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>)) according to another one of the ordinal numbers (l).</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In step <b>63</b>, the output module <b>5</b> is operable to determine whether there is an instruction of setting another average SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>). The flow goes back step <b>61</b> when the determination is affirmative, and goes to step <b>64</b> when otherwise.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In step <b>64</b>, the output module <b>5</b> is operable to provide the transceiver system <b>100</b> with at least one of the average output SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l)</sub>), the bit error rate (P<sub>BER</sub>) and the outage probability (P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>)) corresponding to each of the average SNRs ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>) set in step <b>61</b> as the transceiving performance information of the transceiver system <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows the average output SNRs ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l)</sub>), which are normalized after estimation according to Equation (1), for the respective transmit antennas <b>12</b> (i.e., according to the respective ordinal number (l)) with respect to fading parameters (m) of the Nakagami channel model when the transceiver system <b>100</b> includes four transmit antennas <b>12</b> (L<sub>T</sub>=4) and four receive antennas <b>22</b> (L<sub>R</sub>=4). <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows the normalized average output SNRs ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l)</sub>) according to the method proposed by S. Choi et al. under a transmission condition same as that in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. It can be appreciated that the simulation results shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref> are almost identical, that is to say, accuracy of the average output SNRs ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l)</sub>) estimated according to Equation (1) is substantially equal to accuracy of the average output SNRs ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l)</sub>) obtained through the method proposed by S. Choi et al. Moreover, from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, when the channels between the transmitter <b>1</b> and the receiver <b>2</b> are relatively stable (i.e., the fading parameters (m) are relatively greater), the influence of the selection of the transmit antennas <b>12</b> on the average output SNRs ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l)</sub>) of the synthesized signal is relatively less. Namely, it is unnecessary for the diversity unit <b>11</b> to select one of the transmit antennas <b>12</b>, which corresponds to a greatest average output SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l)</sub>), for transmitting signals.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> shows the evaluation results for the transceiver system <b>100</b> configured for BPSK modulation. In the case of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the transceiver system <b>100</b> includes four transmit antennas <b>12</b> (L<sub>T</sub>=4) and two receive antennas <b>22</b> (L<sub>R</sub>=2), and the fading parameter (m) of Nakagami distribution is set as 0.5. The symbols &#x25a1;, &#x22c4;, &#x394; and &#x25ef; represent the bit error rates (P<sub>BER</sub>) computed according to Equation (2) when l=1 to 4, respectively, and the dashed lines &#x201c;- - - &#x201d; are respective asymptotes of the bit error rates (P<sub>BER</sub>) estimated from Equation (3). It could be appreciated from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> that the bit error rates (P<sub>BER</sub>) decrease as the average SNRs ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>) increase, that is to say, transmission error of the transceiver system <b>100</b> decreases and the performance thereof is relatively better. Also, the bit error rates (P<sub>BER</sub>) from Equation (3) are almost identical to the bit error rates (P<sub>BER</sub>) from Equation (2) as the average SNRs ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>) increase, that is to say, Equation (3) is practical in computing the bit error rates (P<sub>BER</sub>) when the average SNRs ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>) are greater than a predetermined value.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> shows the evaluation results for the transceiver system <b>100</b>, where the transceiver system <b>100</b> includes four transmit antennas <b>12</b> (L<sub>T</sub>=4) and two receive antennas <b>22</b> (L<sub>R</sub>=2), the fading parameter (m) of Nakagami distribution is set as 0.5, and the given capacity (R) is 2 bits/s/Hz. The symbols &#x25a1;, &#x22c4;, &#x394; and &#x25ef; represent the outage probability (P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>)) estimated from Equation (4) when l=1 to 4, respectively, and the dashed lines &#x201c;- - - &#x201d; are respective asymptotes of the outage probability (P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>)) estimated from Equation (5). Similarly, it could be appreciated from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> that the outage probability (P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>)) estimated from Equation (5) is almost identical to the outage probability (P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>)) estimated from Equation (4) as the average SNRs ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>) increase. Namely, Equation (5) is practical in computing the outage probability (P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>)) when the average SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>) is greater than a predetermined value.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In conclusion, the evaluation device <b>200</b> according to the present invention is capable of computing, based upon Equations (1) to (5), the average output SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l)</sub>), the bit error rate (P<sub>BER</sub>) and the outage probability (P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>)) of the synthesized signal generated by the synthesis unit <b>21</b> of the transceiver system <b>100</b>. Equations (1), (2) and (4) for computing the average output SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l)</sub>), the bit error rate (P<sub>BER</sub>) and the outage probability (P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>)) are relatively simple (i.e., the number of the summation operations (&#x3a3;) is independent from the fading parameter (m) and the number (L<sub>R</sub>) of the receive antennas <b>22</b>), and the simplified Equations (3) and (5) respectively from Equations (2) and (4) are practical when the average SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>) is greater than a predetermined value. Thus, computation of the average output SNR ( <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l)</sub>), the bit error rate (P<sub>BER</sub>) and the outage probability (P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>)) based upon Equations (1) to (5) is relatively less, especially for the case of a relatively large number of the receive antennas <b>22</b> and a relatively large fading parameter (m).</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">While the present invention has been described in connection with what is considered the most practical and preferred embodiment, it is understood that this invention is not limited to the disclosed embodiment but is intended to cover various arrangements included within the spirit and scope of the broadest interpretation so as to encompass all such modifications and equivalent arrangements.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00001" nb-file="US08625700-20140107-M00001.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00001" he="19.39mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08625700-20140107-M00001.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00002" nb-file="US08625700-20140107-M00002.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00002" he="9.57mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08625700-20140107-M00002.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00003" nb-file="US08625700-20140107-M00003.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00003" he="36.66mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08625700-20140107-M00003.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00004" nb-file="US08625700-20140107-M00004.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00004" he="7.79mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08625700-20140107-M00004.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00005" nb-file="US08625700-20140107-M00005.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00005" he="21.17mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08625700-20140107-M00005.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00006" nb-file="US08625700-20140107-M00006.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00006" he="7.79mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08625700-20140107-M00006.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00007" nb-file="US08625700-20140107-M00007.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00007" he="19.05mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08625700-20140107-M00007.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00008" nb-file="US08625700-20140107-M00008.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00008" he="9.57mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08625700-20140107-M00008.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00009" nb-file="US08625700-20140107-M00009.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00009" he="36.32mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08625700-20140107-M00009.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00010" nb-file="US08625700-20140107-M00010.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00010" he="9.57mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08625700-20140107-M00010.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00011" nb-file="US08625700-20140107-M00011.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00011" he="7.45mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08625700-20140107-M00011.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00012" nb-file="US08625700-20140107-M00012.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00012" he="19.05mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08625700-20140107-M00012.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00013" nb-file="US08625700-20140107-M00013.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00013" he="9.57mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08625700-20140107-M00013.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00014" nb-file="US08625700-20140107-M00014.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00014" he="7.79mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08625700-20140107-M00014.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An evaluation device for providing a transceiver system with transceiving performance information thereof, the transceiver system including a transmitter that has a plurality of transmit antennas and a receiver that has a plurality of receive antennas for receiving signals from the transmitter, and modeling channels between the transmitter and the receiver using Nakagami distribution with a fading parameter, said evaluation device comprising:
<claim-text>a setting module operable to set an average signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) for the channels between the transmitter and the receiver of the transceiver system;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a computing module operable, based upon the fading parameter, the average SNR, a number of the transmit antennas and a number of the receive antennas, to estimate at least one of an average output SNR, a bit error rate and an outage probability that are related to signals received by the receiver of the transceiver system; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an output module operable to provide the transceiver system with the average SNR and said at least one of the average output SNR, the bit error rate and the outage probability as the transceiving performance information of the transceiver system;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said computing module is operable to estimate one of the average output SNR, the bit error rate and the outage probability by computing a finite number of summation operations, and the number of the summation operations is independent from the number of the receive antennas and the fading parameter.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The evaluation device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, the transmit antennas of the transmitter being assigned with respective ordinal numbers in a specified sequence,
<claim-text>wherein said computing module is operable, further based upon one of the ordinal numbers of the transmit antennas, to estimate one of the average output SNR, the bit error rate and the outage probability that are related to signals received by the receive antennas from a corresponding one of the transmit antennas that is assigned with said one of the ordinal numbers.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The evaluation device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein said computing module is operable to estimate the average output SNR <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o><sub>(l) </sub>based upon</claim-text>
<claim-text>
<maths id="MATH-US-00007" num="00007">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <msub>
    <mover>
      <mi>&#x3b3;</mi>
      <mi>_</mi>
    </mover>
    <mrow>
      <mo>(</mo>
      <mi>l</mi>
      <mo>)</mo>
    </mrow>
  </msub>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mrow>
    <mfrac>
      <mrow>
        <mi>l</mi>
        <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mo>(</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mover>
              <mi>&#x3b3;</mi>
              <mi>_</mi>
            </mover>
            <mo>/</mo>
            <mi>m</mi>
          </mrow>
          <mo>)</mo>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mo>(</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mi>m</mi>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mstyle>
                <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
              </mstyle>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <msub>
                <mi>L</mi>
                <mi>R</mi>
              </msub>
            </mrow>
            <mo>-</mo>
            <mn>1</mn>
          </mrow>
          <mo>)</mo>
        </mrow>
        <mo>!</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mfrac>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <mrow>
      <mo>(</mo>
      <mtable>
        <mtr>
          <mtd>
            <msub>
              <mi>L</mi>
              <mi>T</mi>
            </msub>
          </mtd>
        </mtr>
        <mtr>
          <mtd>
            <mi>l</mi>
          </mtd>
        </mtr>
      </mtable>
      <mo>)</mo>
    </mrow>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <mrow>
      <munderover>
        <mo>&#x2211;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>n</mi>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mn>0</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mi>l</mi>
          <mo>-</mo>
          <mn>1</mn>
        </mrow>
      </munderover>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mo>(</mo>
          <mtable>
            <mtr>
              <mtd>
                <mrow>
                  <mi>l</mi>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                </mrow>
              </mtd>
            </mtr>
            <mtr>
              <mtd>
                <mi>n</mi>
              </mtd>
            </mtr>
          </mtable>
          <mo>)</mo>
        </mrow>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <msup>
          <mrow>
            <mo>(</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>-</mo>
              <mn>1</mn>
            </mrow>
            <mo>)</mo>
          </mrow>
          <mi>n</mi>
        </msup>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <munderover>
            <mo>&#x2211;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mi>k</mi>
              <mo>=</mo>
              <mn>0</mn>
            </mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                    <mi>T</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <mi>l</mi>
                  <mo>+</mo>
                  <mi>n</mi>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <mi>m</mi>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <mstyle>
                      <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                    </mstyle>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>L</mi>
                      <mi>R</mi>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
          </munderover>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <msub>
              <mi>&#x3b2;</mi>
              <mi>k</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mfrac>
              <mrow>
                <mrow>
                  <mo>(</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mrow>
                      <mi>m</mi>
                      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                      <mstyle>
                        <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                      </mstyle>
                      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                      <msub>
                        <mi>L</mi>
                        <mi>R</mi>
                      </msub>
                    </mrow>
                    <mo>+</mo>
                    <mi>k</mi>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>)</mo>
                </mrow>
                <mo>!</mo>
              </mrow>
              <msup>
                <mrow>
                  <mo>(</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>L</mi>
                      <mi>T</mi>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>-</mo>
                    <mi>l</mi>
                    <mo>+</mo>
                    <mi>n</mi>
                    <mo>+</mo>
                    <mn>1</mn>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>)</mo>
                </mrow>
                <mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <mi>m</mi>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <mstyle>
                      <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                    </mstyle>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>L</mi>
                      <mi>R</mi>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>+</mo>
                  <mi>k</mi>
                  <mo>+</mo>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                </mrow>
              </msup>
            </mfrac>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
<claim-text>where l is said one of the ordinal numbers, m is the fading parameter, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o> is the average SNR, L<sub>T </sub>is the number of the transmit antennas, L<sub>R </sub>is the number of the receive antennas, &#x3b2;<sub>0</sub>=1, &#x3b2;<sub>1</sub>=L<sub>T</sub>&#x2212;l+n,</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>
<maths id="MATH-US-00008" num="00008">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <msub>
    <mi>&#x3b2;</mi>
    <mi>k</mi>
  </msub>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mrow>
    <mfrac>
      <mn>1</mn>
      <mi>k</mi>
    </mfrac>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <mrow>
      <munderover>
        <mo>&#x2211;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>j</mi>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mn>1</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mi>min</mi>
          <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mo>(</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mi>k</mi>
              <mo>,</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mrow>
                  <mi>m</mi>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mstyle>
                    <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                  </mstyle>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                    <mi>R</mi>
                  </msub>
                </mrow>
                <mo>-</mo>
                <mn>1</mn>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
            <mo>)</mo>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </munderover>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mfrac>
          <mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mi>j</mi>
              <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                    <mi>T</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <mi>l</mi>
                  <mo>+</mo>
                  <mi>n</mi>
                  <mo>+</mo>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
            <mo>-</mo>
            <mi>k</mi>
          </mrow>
          <mrow>
            <mi>j</mi>
            <mo>!</mo>
          </mrow>
        </mfrac>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <msub>
          <mi>&#x3b2;</mi>
          <mrow>
            <mi>k</mi>
            <mo>-</mo>
            <mi>j</mi>
          </mrow>
        </msub>
      </mrow>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>for 2&#x2266;k&#x2266;(L<sub>T</sub>&#x2212;l+n)(mL<sub>R</sub>&#x2212;1)&#x2212;1, and &#x3b2;<sub>k</sub>=[(mL<sub>R</sub>&#x2212;1)!]<sup>&#x2212;(L</sup><sup><sub2>T</sub2></sup><sup>&#x2212;l+n) </sup>for k=(L<sub>T</sub>&#x2212;l+n)(mL<sub>R</sub>&#x2212;1).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The evaluation device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein said computing module is operable to estimate the bit error rate P<sub>BER </sub>based upon</claim-text>
<claim-text>
<maths id="MATH-US-00009" num="00009">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <msub>
    <mi>P</mi>
    <mi>BER</mi>
  </msub>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mrow>
    <mfrac>
      <mi>l</mi>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mo>(</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mi>m</mi>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mstyle>
                <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
              </mstyle>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <msub>
                <mi>L</mi>
                <mi>R</mi>
              </msub>
            </mrow>
            <mo>-</mo>
            <mn>1</mn>
          </mrow>
          <mo>)</mo>
        </mrow>
        <mo>!</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mfrac>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <mrow>
      <mo>(</mo>
      <mtable>
        <mtr>
          <mtd>
            <msub>
              <mi>L</mi>
              <mi>T</mi>
            </msub>
          </mtd>
        </mtr>
        <mtr>
          <mtd>
            <mi>l</mi>
          </mtd>
        </mtr>
      </mtable>
      <mo>)</mo>
    </mrow>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <mrow>
      <munderover>
        <mo>&#x2211;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>n</mi>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mn>0</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mi>l</mi>
          <mo>-</mo>
          <mn>1</mn>
        </mrow>
      </munderover>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mo>(</mo>
          <mtable>
            <mtr>
              <mtd>
                <mrow>
                  <mi>l</mi>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                </mrow>
              </mtd>
            </mtr>
            <mtr>
              <mtd>
                <mi>n</mi>
              </mtd>
            </mtr>
          </mtable>
          <mo>)</mo>
        </mrow>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <msup>
          <mrow>
            <mo>(</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>-</mo>
              <mn>1</mn>
            </mrow>
            <mo>)</mo>
          </mrow>
          <mi>n</mi>
        </msup>
        <mo>&#xd7;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <munderover>
            <mo>&#x2211;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mi>k</mi>
              <mo>=</mo>
              <mn>0</mn>
            </mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                    <mi>T</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <mi>l</mi>
                  <mo>+</mo>
                  <mi>n</mi>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <mi>m</mi>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <mstyle>
                      <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                    </mstyle>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>L</mi>
                      <mi>R</mi>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
          </munderover>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <msub>
              <mi>&#x3b2;</mi>
              <mi>k</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <msup>
              <mrow>
                <mfrac>
                  <mrow>
                    <mrow>
                      <mo>(</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <mrow>
                          <mi>m</mi>
                          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                          <mstyle>
                            <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                          </mstyle>
                          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                          <msub>
                            <mi>L</mi>
                            <mi>R</mi>
                          </msub>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>+</mo>
                        <mi>k</mi>
                        <mo>-</mo>
                        <mn>1</mn>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>)</mo>
                    </mrow>
                    <mo>!</mo>
                  </mrow>
                  <msup>
                    <mrow>
                      <mo>(</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <msub>
                          <mi>L</mi>
                          <mi>T</mi>
                        </msub>
                        <mo>-</mo>
                        <mi>l</mi>
                        <mo>+</mo>
                        <mi>n</mi>
                        <mo>+</mo>
                        <mn>1</mn>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>)</mo>
                    </mrow>
                    <mrow>
                      <mrow>
                        <mi>m</mi>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <mstyle>
                          <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                        </mstyle>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <msub>
                          <mi>L</mi>
                          <mi>R</mi>
                        </msub>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>+</mo>
                      <mi>k</mi>
                    </mrow>
                  </msup>
                </mfrac>
                <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <mo>[</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mfrac>
                      <mn>1</mn>
                      <mn>2</mn>
                    </mfrac>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <mrow>
                      <mo>(</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <mn>1</mn>
                        <mo>-</mo>
                        <msqrt>
                          <mfrac>
                            <mi>&#x3b1;</mi>
                            <mrow>
                              <mn>1</mn>
                              <mo>+</mo>
                              <mi>&#x3b1;</mi>
                            </mrow>
                          </mfrac>
                        </msqrt>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>)</mo>
                    </mrow>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>]</mo>
                </mrow>
              </mrow>
              <mrow>
                <mrow>
                  <mi>m</mi>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mstyle>
                    <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                  </mstyle>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                    <mi>R</mi>
                  </msub>
                </mrow>
                <mo>+</mo>
                <mi>k</mi>
              </mrow>
            </msup>
            <mo>&#xd7;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <munderover>
                <mo>&#x2211;</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <mi>j</mi>
                  <mo>=</mo>
                  <mn>0</mn>
                </mrow>
                <mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <mi>m</mi>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <mstyle>
                      <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                    </mstyle>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>L</mi>
                      <mi>R</mi>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>+</mo>
                  <mi>k</mi>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                </mrow>
              </munderover>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <msup>
                <mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <mo>(</mo>
                    <mtable>
                      <mtr>
                        <mtd>
                          <mrow>
                            <mrow>
                              <mi>m</mi>
                              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                              <mstyle>
                                <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                              </mstyle>
                              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                              <msub>
                                <mi>L</mi>
                                <mi>R</mi>
                              </msub>
                            </mrow>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <mi>k</mi>
                            <mo>-</mo>
                            <mn>1</mn>
                            <mo>+</mo>
                            <mi>j</mi>
                          </mrow>
                        </mtd>
                      </mtr>
                      <mtr>
                        <mtd>
                          <mi>j</mi>
                        </mtd>
                      </mtr>
                    </mtable>
                    <mo>)</mo>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mo>[</mo>
                    <mrow>
                      <mfrac>
                        <mn>1</mn>
                        <mn>2</mn>
                      </mfrac>
                      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <mo>(</mo>
                        <mrow>
                          <mn>1</mn>
                          <mo>+</mo>
                          <msqrt>
                            <mfrac>
                              <mi>&#x3b1;</mi>
                              <mrow>
                                <mn>1</mn>
                                <mo>+</mo>
                                <mi>&#x3b1;</mi>
                              </mrow>
                            </mfrac>
                          </msqrt>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>)</mo>
                      </mrow>
                    </mrow>
                    <mo>]</mo>
                  </mrow>
                </mrow>
                <mi>j</mi>
              </msup>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
<claim-text>where l is said one of the ordinal numbers, m is the fading parameter, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o> is the average SNR, L<sub>T </sub>is the number of the transmit antennas, L<sub>R </sub>is the number of the receive antennas, &#x3b1;= <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>/[m(L<sub>T</sub>&#x2212;l+n+1)], &#x3b2;<sub>0</sub>=1, &#x3b2;<sub>1</sub>=L<sub>T</sub>&#x2212;l+n,</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>
<maths id="MATH-US-00010" num="00010">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <msub>
    <mi>&#x3b2;</mi>
    <mi>k</mi>
  </msub>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mrow>
    <mfrac>
      <mn>1</mn>
      <mi>k</mi>
    </mfrac>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <mrow>
      <munderover>
        <mo>&#x2211;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>j</mi>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mn>1</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mi>min</mi>
          <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mo>(</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mi>k</mi>
              <mo>,</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mrow>
                  <mi>m</mi>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mstyle>
                    <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                  </mstyle>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                    <mi>R</mi>
                  </msub>
                </mrow>
                <mo>-</mo>
                <mn>1</mn>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
            <mo>)</mo>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </munderover>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mfrac>
          <mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mi>j</mi>
              <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                    <mi>T</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <mi>l</mi>
                  <mo>+</mo>
                  <mi>n</mi>
                  <mo>+</mo>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
            <mo>-</mo>
            <mi>k</mi>
          </mrow>
          <mrow>
            <mi>j</mi>
            <mo>!</mo>
          </mrow>
        </mfrac>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <msub>
          <mi>&#x3b2;</mi>
          <mrow>
            <mi>k</mi>
            <mo>-</mo>
            <mi>j</mi>
          </mrow>
        </msub>
      </mrow>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>for 2&#x2266;k&#x2266;(L<sub>T</sub>&#x2212;l+n)(mL<sub>R</sub>&#x2212;1)&#x2212;1, and &#x3b2;<sub>k</sub>=[mL<sub>R</sub>&#x2212;1)!]<sup>&#x2212;(L</sup><sup><sub2>T</sub2></sup><sup>&#x2212;l+n) </sup>for k=(L<sub>T</sub>&#x2212;l+n)(mL<sub>R</sub>&#x2212;1).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The evaluation device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein, when the average SNR is greater than a predetermined value, said computing module is operable to estimate the bit error rate P<sub>BER </sub>based upon</claim-text>
<claim-text>
<maths id="MATH-US-00011" num="00011">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <msub>
    <mi>P</mi>
    <mi>BER</mi>
  </msub>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mrow>
    <mfrac>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mo>(</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mn>2</mn>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <msub>
                <mi>mlL</mi>
                <mi>R</mi>
              </msub>
            </mrow>
            <mo>-</mo>
            <mn>1</mn>
          </mrow>
          <mo>)</mo>
        </mrow>
        <mo>!</mo>
      </mrow>
      <mrow>
        <msup>
          <mrow>
            <msup>
              <mn>2</mn>
              <mrow>
                <mrow>
                  <mn>2</mn>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>mlL</mi>
                    <mi>R</mi>
                  </msub>
                </mrow>
                <mo>-</mo>
                <mn>1</mn>
              </mrow>
            </msup>
            <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>[</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mrow>
                  <mo>(</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mi>m</mi>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <mstyle>
                      <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                    </mstyle>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>L</mi>
                      <mi>R</mi>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>)</mo>
                </mrow>
                <mo>!</mo>
              </mrow>
              <mo>]</mo>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
          <mi>l</mi>
        </msup>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mrow>
            <mo>(</mo>
            <mrow>
              <msub>
                <mi>mlL</mi>
                <mi>R</mi>
              </msub>
              <mo>-</mo>
              <mn>1</mn>
            </mrow>
            <mo>)</mo>
          </mrow>
          <mo>!</mo>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mfrac>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <mrow>
      <mo>(</mo>
      <mtable>
        <mtr>
          <mtd>
            <msub>
              <mi>L</mi>
              <mi>T</mi>
            </msub>
          </mtd>
        </mtr>
        <mtr>
          <mtd>
            <mi>l</mi>
          </mtd>
        </mtr>
      </mtable>
      <mo>)</mo>
    </mrow>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <msup>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mfrac>
          <mi>m</mi>
          <mover>
            <mi>&#x3b3;</mi>
            <mi>_</mi>
          </mover>
        </mfrac>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
      <msub>
        <mi>mlL</mi>
        <mi>R</mi>
      </msub>
    </msup>
  </mrow>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
<claim-text>where l is said one of the ordinal numbers, m is the fading parameter, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o> is the average SNR, L<sub>T </sub>is the number of the transmit antennas, and L<sub>R </sub>is the number of the receive antennas.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The evaluation device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein said computing module is operable to estimate the outage probability P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>), which corresponds to a given capacity R and the average SNR <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>, based upon</claim-text>
<claim-text>
<maths id="MATH-US-00012" num="00012">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <mrow>
    <msub>
      <mi>P</mi>
      <mi>out</mi>
    </msub>
    <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
    <mrow>
      <mo>(</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mi>R</mi>
        <mo>,</mo>
        <mover>
          <mi>&#x3b3;</mi>
          <mi>_</mi>
        </mover>
      </mrow>
      <mo>)</mo>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mrow>
    <mfrac>
      <mi>l</mi>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mo>(</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mi>m</mi>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mstyle>
                <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
              </mstyle>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <msub>
                <mi>L</mi>
                <mi>R</mi>
              </msub>
            </mrow>
            <mo>-</mo>
            <mn>1</mn>
          </mrow>
          <mo>)</mo>
        </mrow>
        <mo>!</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mfrac>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <mrow>
      <mo>(</mo>
      <mtable>
        <mtr>
          <mtd>
            <msub>
              <mi>L</mi>
              <mi>T</mi>
            </msub>
          </mtd>
        </mtr>
        <mtr>
          <mtd>
            <mi>l</mi>
          </mtd>
        </mtr>
      </mtable>
      <mo>)</mo>
    </mrow>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <mrow>
      <munderover>
        <mo>&#x2211;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>n</mi>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mn>0</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mi>l</mi>
          <mo>-</mo>
          <mn>1</mn>
        </mrow>
      </munderover>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mo>(</mo>
          <mtable>
            <mtr>
              <mtd>
                <mrow>
                  <mi>l</mi>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                </mrow>
              </mtd>
            </mtr>
            <mtr>
              <mtd>
                <mi>n</mi>
              </mtd>
            </mtr>
          </mtable>
          <mo>)</mo>
        </mrow>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <msup>
          <mrow>
            <mo>(</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>-</mo>
              <mn>1</mn>
            </mrow>
            <mo>)</mo>
          </mrow>
          <mi>n</mi>
        </msup>
        <mo>&#xd7;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <munderover>
            <mo>&#x2211;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mi>k</mi>
              <mo>=</mo>
              <mn>0</mn>
            </mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                    <mi>T</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <mi>l</mi>
                  <mo>+</mo>
                  <mi>n</mi>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <mi>m</mi>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <mstyle>
                      <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                    </mstyle>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>L</mi>
                      <mi>R</mi>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
          </munderover>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <msub>
              <mi>&#x3b2;</mi>
              <mi>k</mi>
            </msub>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mfrac>
              <mrow>
                <mi>&#x3b3;</mi>
                <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <mo>(</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mrow>
                      <mrow>
                        <mi>m</mi>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <mstyle>
                          <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                        </mstyle>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <msub>
                          <mi>L</mi>
                          <mi>R</mi>
                        </msub>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>+</mo>
                      <mi>k</mi>
                    </mrow>
                    <mo>,</mo>
                    <mrow>
                      <mrow>
                        <mo>[</mo>
                        <mrow>
                          <msub>
                            <mi>L</mi>
                            <mi>T</mi>
                          </msub>
                          <mo>-</mo>
                          <mi>l</mi>
                          <mo>+</mo>
                          <mi>n</mi>
                          <mo>+</mo>
                          <mn>1</mn>
                        </mrow>
                        <mo>]</mo>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                      <mi>m</mi>
                      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                      <mstyle>
                        <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                      </mstyle>
                      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <mi>&#x3bb;</mi>
                        <mo>/</mo>
                        <mover>
                          <mi>&#x3b3;</mi>
                          <mi>_</mi>
                        </mover>
                      </mrow>
                    </mrow>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>)</mo>
                </mrow>
              </mrow>
              <msup>
                <mrow>
                  <mo>[</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>L</mi>
                      <mi>T</mi>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>-</mo>
                    <mi>l</mi>
                    <mo>+</mo>
                    <mi>n</mi>
                    <mo>+</mo>
                    <mn>1</mn>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>]</mo>
                </mrow>
                <mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <mi>m</mi>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <mstyle>
                      <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                    </mstyle>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>L</mi>
                      <mi>R</mi>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>+</mo>
                  <mi>k</mi>
                </mrow>
              </msup>
            </mfrac>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
<claim-text>where l is said one of the ordinal numbers, m is the fading parameter, L<sub>T </sub>is the number of the transmit antennas, L<sub>R </sub>is the number of the receive antennas, &#x3b3;( ) is a low-level incomplete Gamma function, &#x3bb;=2<sup>R</sup>&#x2212;1, &#x3b2;<sub>0</sub>=1, &#x3b2;<sub>1</sub>=L<sub>T</sub>&#x2212;l+n,</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>
<maths id="MATH-US-00013" num="00013">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <msub>
    <mi>&#x3b2;</mi>
    <mi>k</mi>
  </msub>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mrow>
    <mfrac>
      <mn>1</mn>
      <mi>k</mi>
    </mfrac>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <mrow>
      <munderover>
        <mo>&#x2211;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>j</mi>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mn>1</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mi>min</mi>
          <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mo>(</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mi>k</mi>
              <mo>,</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mrow>
                  <mi>m</mi>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mstyle>
                    <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                  </mstyle>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                    <mi>R</mi>
                  </msub>
                </mrow>
                <mo>-</mo>
                <mn>1</mn>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
            <mo>)</mo>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </munderover>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mfrac>
          <mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mi>j</mi>
              <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>L</mi>
                    <mi>T</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <mi>l</mi>
                  <mo>+</mo>
                  <mi>n</mi>
                  <mo>+</mo>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
            <mo>-</mo>
            <mi>k</mi>
          </mrow>
          <mrow>
            <mi>j</mi>
            <mo>!</mo>
          </mrow>
        </mfrac>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <msub>
          <mi>&#x3b2;</mi>
          <mrow>
            <mi>k</mi>
            <mo>-</mo>
            <mi>j</mi>
          </mrow>
        </msub>
      </mrow>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>for 2&#x2266;k&#x2266;(L<sub>T</sub>&#x2212;l+n)(mL<sub>R</sub>&#x2212;1)&#x2212;1, and &#x3b2;<sub>k</sub>=[(mL<sub>R</sub>&#x2212;1)!]<sup>&#x2212;(L</sup><sup><sub2>T</sub2></sup><sup>&#x2212;l+n) </sup>for k=(L<sub>T</sub>&#x2212;l+n)(mL<sub>R</sub>&#x2212;1).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The evaluation device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein, when the average SNR is greater than a predetermined value, said computing module is operable to estimate the outage probability P<sub>out</sub>(R, <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>), which corresponds to a given capacity R and the average SNR <o ostyle="single">&#x3b3;</o>, based upon</claim-text>
<claim-text>
<maths id="MATH-US-00014" num="00014">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <mrow>
    <msub>
      <mi>P</mi>
      <mi>out</mi>
    </msub>
    <mo>&#x2061;</mo>
    <mrow>
      <mo>(</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mi>R</mi>
        <mo>,</mo>
        <mover>
          <mi>&#x3b3;</mi>
          <mi>_</mi>
        </mover>
      </mrow>
      <mo>)</mo>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mrow>
    <mfrac>
      <msup>
        <mi>m</mi>
        <msub>
          <mi>mlL</mi>
          <mi>R</mi>
        </msub>
      </msup>
      <msup>
        <mrow>
          <mo>[</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mi>m</mi>
                <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                <mstyle>
                  <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                </mstyle>
                <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                <msub>
                  <mi>L</mi>
                  <mi>R</mi>
                </msub>
              </mrow>
              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>
            <mo>!</mo>
          </mrow>
          <mo>]</mo>
        </mrow>
        <mi>l</mi>
      </msup>
    </mfrac>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <mrow>
      <mo>(</mo>
      <mtable>
        <mtr>
          <mtd>
            <msub>
              <mi>L</mi>
              <mi>T</mi>
            </msub>
          </mtd>
        </mtr>
        <mtr>
          <mtd>
            <mi>l</mi>
          </mtd>
        </mtr>
      </mtable>
      <mo>)</mo>
    </mrow>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <msup>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mfrac>
          <mi>&#x3bb;</mi>
          <mover>
            <mi>&#x3b3;</mi>
            <mi>_</mi>
          </mover>
        </mfrac>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
      <msub>
        <mi>mlL</mi>
        <mi>R</mi>
      </msub>
    </msup>
  </mrow>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
<claim-text>where l is said one of the ordinal numbers, m is the fading parameter, L<sub>T </sub>is the number of the transmit antennas, L<sub>R </sub>is the number of the receive antennas, and &#x3bb;=2<sup>R</sup>&#x2212;1. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
