<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622317-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622317</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13168822</doc-number>
<date>20110624</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>227</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>10</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>239205</main-classification>
<further-classification>239590</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Irrigation sprinkler with twist-and-lock debris screen</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4202499</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Mathews</name>
<date>19800500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>239206</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5174501</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hadar</name>
<date>19921200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>239205</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5423486</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hunter</name>
<date>19950600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>239205</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5785248</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Staylor et al.</name>
<date>19980700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>239237</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6491235</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Scott et al.</name>
<date>20021200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>239206</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6799732</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Sirkin</name>
<date>20041000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>239205</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6848632</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Clark</name>
<date>20050200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>239203</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7303147</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Danner et al.</name>
<date>20071200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>239203</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7677469</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Clark</name>
<date>20100300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>239242</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7861948</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Crooks et al.</name>
<date>20110100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>239237</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0308650</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Clark</name>
<date>20081200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>239204</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>239200-206</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>239590</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2395903</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>10</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Anuskiewicz</last-name>
<first-name>Ronald H.</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Diego</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Anuskiewicz</last-name>
<first-name>Ronald H.</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Diego</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Knobbe, Martens, Olson &#x26; Bear LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hunter Industries, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>San Marcos</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Christopher</first-name>
<department>3752</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An irrigation sprinkler has a generally tubular riser assembly including a nozzle turret rotatably mounted at an upper end of the riser assembly and a drive assembly coupled for rotating the nozzle turret. The riser assembly has at least one locking recess formed in a lower end of the riser assembly. A debris screen is removably mounted to a lower end of the riser assembly. The debris screen is formed with a plurality of apertures for filtering debris from water flowing through the apertures. The debris screen is dimensioned and configured to mate with the lower end of the riser assembly. The debris screen has at least one lock that is dimensioned and configured to be received in the locking recess for holding the debris screen to the riser assembly. In an alternate embodiment, the lock can be located on the lower end of the riser assembly and the recess can be located on the screen.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="233.93mm" wi="146.73mm" file="US08622317-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="254.93mm" wi="177.72mm" file="US08622317-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="234.44mm" wi="159.68mm" file="US08622317-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="239.35mm" wi="154.43mm" file="US08622317-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="227.08mm" wi="155.19mm" file="US08622317-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="251.21mm" wi="200.58mm" file="US08622317-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="184.66mm" wi="170.52mm" file="US08622317-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to sprinklers used to irrigate turf and landscaping.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Many areas of the world have insufficient rainfall during parts of the year to maintain healthy turf and landscaping. Sprinkler systems are therefore widely used in commercial and residential irrigation that include an electronic irrigation controller that executes a watering program. The irrigation controller turns solenoid actuated valves ON and OFF in accordance with the watering program. The valves deliver water through buried pipes to sprinklers located in various zones of the irrigation site. The sprinklers are typically rotor-type sprinklers, rotary stream sprinklers or spray-type sprinklers. Usually the sprinklers include a molded plastic screen to filter sand, grit and other debris from the water to prevent the same from clogging the orifices in the nozzle. Sometimes the screen needs to be removed from the sprinkler and replaced, such as when it becomes clogged. The screen can be cleaned and re-installed if it has not been damaged. The screen can otherwise be replaced with a new screen. Rotor-type sprinklers have heretofore not included debris screens that are easily removed and replaced. Typically in a rotor-type sprinkler one end of the screen is press fit against the inside of a shoulder formed at the lower end of the tubular riser assembly. The user must be grip the screen with pliers and pull out the press fit end of the sprinkler. Alternatively, the user must pry out the press fit end with a screw driver. Both operations are tedious and the user risks damaging the screen. Removal of the screen by prying with a screwdriver or other pointed tool subjects a person to a risk of injuring fingers or the palm of a hand.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In accordance with the present invention an irrigation sprinkler has a generally tubular riser assembly including a nozzle turret rotatably mounted at an upper end of the riser assembly and a drive assembly coupled for rotating the nozzle turret. The sprinkler further has a generally cylindrical debris screen formed with a plurality of apertures for filtering debris from water flowing through the apertures. The debris screen is dimensioned and configured to mate with a lower end of the riser assembly. The sprinkler further includes at least one locking mechanism having a first portion on the lower end of the riser assembly and a second portion on the screen. The first and second portions of the locking mechanism are located so that they can be mated when the debris screen is mated with the lower end of the riser. The first and second portions of the locking mechanism are configured so that they can be positively locked and unlocked by a combination of relative axial and rotational motion between the debris screen and the riser assembly. The locking mechanism holds the debris screen to the riser assembly when locked.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a partially exploded isometric view of a sprinkler with a twist-and-lock debris screen in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-4</figref> are views similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> sequentially illustrating the installation and locking of the debris screen on the lower end of the riser assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a greatly enlarged portion of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrating details of the flexible locking tab and the locking recess of the illustrated embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is an isometric view of the debris screen of the sprinkler of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> taken from above.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a top plan view of the debris screen illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a bottom plan view of the debris screen illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a right side elevation view of the debris screen illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> taken from the right side of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>. The left side elevation view of the debris screen (not shown) is identical to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is front elevation view of the debris screen illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. The rear elevation view of the debris screen (not shown) is identical to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The embodiment of the present invention described hereafter is particularly useful in large rotor-type sprinklers used on golf courses. One such sprinkler is disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 7,677,469 of Michael L. Clark granted Mar. 16, 2010 and entitled &#x201c;Sprinkler with Reversing Planetary Gear Drive&#x201d;, the entire disclosure of which is hereby incorporated by reference. Said patent is assigned to Hunter Industries, Inc., the assignee of the present application. See also U.S. Pat. No. 6,491,235 of Loren W. Scott et al. granted Dec. 10, 2002 and entitled &#x201c;Pop-Up Sprinkler with Top Serviceable Diaphragm Valve Module&#x201d;, also assigned to Hunter Industries, Inc., the entire disclosure of which is also hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Unless otherwise indicated, the parts of the embodiment described and illustrated herein are made of injection molded plastic. Shafts and springs used in the illustrated embodiment are preferably made of steel or other suitable metal. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> a generally tubular riser assembly <b>10</b> includes a nozzle turret <b>12</b> mounted at its upper end and a generally cylindrical debris screen <b>14</b> removably mounted at its lower end. While not illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a drive assembly including a turbine, gear train reduction, and an optional reversing mechanism are mounted inside the riser assembly <b>10</b>. The sprinkler that uses the present invention may be constructed to oscillate the nozzle turret <b>12</b> between pre-set arc limits or it may be constructed to rotate continuously through three hundred and sixty degrees. The sprinkler may also be constructed so that it can be optionally set to operate in a part-circle mode or in a full circle mode. Therefore, the drive assembly need not include a reversing mechanism.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">A stainless steel coil spring <b>16</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) surrounds the riser assembly <b>10</b> and its opposite ends engage the nozzle turret <b>12</b> and an alignment sleeve <b>18</b> loosely surrounding the lower portion of the riser assembly <b>10</b>. The alignment sleeve <b>18</b> has a plurality of circumferentially spaced, vertically extending guide fingers <b>20</b> that fit between ribs molded on an interior surface of an outer case (not illustrated) of the sprinkler. The lower end of the alignment sleeve <b>18</b> is formed with saw-shaped teeth <b>22</b> that engage similar teeth <b>24</b> on a shoulder <b>26</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 5</figref>) formed on the lower portion of the riser assembly <b>10</b>. The coil spring <b>16</b> is compressed when the sprinkler is pressurized with water and the riser assembly <b>10</b> extends from the outer case. When the water is not turned ON, the riser assembly <b>10</b> can be manually raised by lifting the riser assembly <b>10</b> above the outer case using a tool. The riser assembly <b>10</b> can be rotated manually to disengage the teeth <b>24</b> on the shoulder <b>26</b> from the teeth <b>22</b> on the alignment sleeve <b>18</b>. This allows the riser assembly <b>10</b> to be manually rotated within the outer case to set one of the arc limits of rotation of the nozzle turret <b>12</b>. In some cases, depending on the water pressure and/or the size of the sprinkler, the riser can be rotated manually by hand when the water is on. The case is normally buried in the soil and the riser assembly <b>10</b> extends telescopically when the water is turned ON so that adjacent turf can be irrigated. The riser assembly <b>10</b> can serve as a sprinkler without being telescopically mounted in an outer case. When used in this configuration the lower end of the riser assembly <b>10</b> is coupled to a fixed riser (not illustrated) and permanently extends above the ground for watering adjacent shrubs and hillsides.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The debris screen <b>14</b> has a generally cylindrical flange <b>14</b><i>a </i>(<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) and is dimensioned to fit loosely within a cylindrical wall <b>28</b> forming the lower end of the riser assembly <b>10</b>. A locking recess <b>30</b> is formed in the cylindrical wall <b>28</b> of the riser assembly <b>10</b>. A lock <b>32</b> projects radially outwardly from the cylindrical flange <b>14</b><i>a</i>. The locking recess <b>30</b> has a generally L-shaped configuration with a first leg <b>30</b><i>a </i>(<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) that extends in a vertical direction generally parallel to a vertical central axis of the riser assembly <b>10</b>. The locking recess <b>30</b> has a second leg <b>30</b><i>b </i>that extends in a circumferential direction generally perpendicular to the vertical axis of the riser assembly <b>10</b>. An edge <b>33</b> of the cylindrical wall <b>28</b> that defines the upper edge of the second leg <b>30</b><i>b </i>of the locking recess <b>30</b> is formed with a rounded fixed tab <b>34</b>. The lock <b>32</b> is formed with a similarly rounded flexible tab <b>32</b><i>a </i>that can flex in an axially downward direct to move past the fixed tab <b>34</b> upon counter-clockwise rotation (viewed from above the top of the riser assembly <b>10</b>) of the cylindrical flange <b>14</b><i>a </i>of the debris screen <b>14</b> within the cylindrical wall <b>28</b> of the riser assembly <b>10</b>. The flexible tab <b>32</b> is spring-like and flexes back in an axially upward direction behind the fixed tab <b>34</b> to hold the debris screen <b>14</b> to the riser assembly <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the lock <b>32</b> is formed as a generally U-shaped member with a pair of legs <b>32</b><i>b </i>and <b>32</b><i>c</i>, the flexible tab <b>32</b><i>a </i>is formed on the remote end of the leg <b>32</b><i>b</i>. The leg <b>32</b><i>c </i>is formed on the outer surface of the cylindrical flange <b>14</b><i>a </i>of the debris screen <b>14</b>. The debris screen <b>14</b> includes a generally disc-shaped perforated portion <b>14</b><i>b </i>(<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) formed with a plurality of apertures. The disc-shaped portion is generally planar and is surrounded by the cylindrical flange <b>14</b><i>a</i>. The perforated portion <b>14</b><i>b </i>of the debris screen <b>14</b> is made of interconnected rows and columns of molded plastic that define the plurality of apertures. The apertures have a generally rectangular shape and preferably have a maximum dimension of about 0.080 inches. The riser assembly <b>10</b> is designed for use in relatively large rotor-type sprinklers used on golf courses. Such sprinklers are relatively dirt resistant and the debris screen <b>14</b> is designed to filter large chucks of debris such as small pieces of stone and algae. These are often encountered by sprinklers used to irrigate gold courses since the water is frequently pumped from wells and ponds. The lower portion of the cylindrical flange <b>14</b><i>a </i>has an enlarged diameter and is formed with a plurality of circumferentially spaced axially extending ribs <b>36</b> to facilitate manual gripping and rotation of the debris screen <b>14</b> relative to the riser assembly <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-4</figref>, the debris screen <b>14</b> can be vertically slid into the lower end of the riser assembly <b>10</b>, and then twisted about the vertical axis of the riser assembly <b>10</b> so that the lock <b>32</b> slides laterally in the recess <b>30</b> and snaps into place behind the fixed tab <b>34</b> to lock the debris screen <b>14</b> to the riser assembly <b>10</b>. Counter-clockwise twisting of the debris screen <b>14</b> relative to the riser assembly <b>10</b> (viewed from above the riser assembly <b>10</b>) from the position illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> to the position illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> places the lock <b>32</b> above an edge <b>38</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) of the cylindrical wall <b>28</b> of the riser assembly <b>10</b> that defines the lower edge of the second leg <b>30</b><i>b </i>of the recess <b>30</b>. This prevents accidental de-coupling of the debris screen <b>14</b> from the riser assembly <b>10</b> if only axially downward forces are exerted on the debris screen <b>14</b> relative to the riser assembly <b>10</b>. The embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-5</figref> thus provides a reliable twist-and-lock attachment mechanism that allows for quick removal and replacement of the debris screen <b>14</b> from the lower end of the riser assembly. The removal process entails the steps illustrated in reversing the order of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-4</figref> in which the screen is first twisted in a clockwise direction (viewed from above the riser assembly <b>10</b>) and then pulled downwardly. The highly beneficial result of the present invention is that a clogged and/or damaged screen on rotor-type irrigation sprinkler can be more quickly, easily and safely removed and replaced by service personnel.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6-10</figref> illustrate the ornamental design of the debris screen <b>14</b>. The debris screen <b>14</b> can be injection molded out of suitable plastic in a wide variety of configurations depending on the design of the sprinkler and its particular filtering needs.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">While a preferred embodiment of the present invention has been described in detail, variations and adaptations thereof will occur to those skilled in the art. For example, the pattern and size of apertures in the debris screen <b>14</b> can be varied to meet the particular needs of the size and type of irrigation sprinkler. The lock <b>32</b> could be positioned on the lower end of the riser assembly <b>10</b> and the locking recess <b>30</b> could be formed on the cylindrical flange <b>14</b><i>a</i>. The locking recess <b>30</b> need not extend radially all the way through the cylindrical wall <b>28</b> or the cylindrical flange <b>14</b><i>a </i>but could instead be a groove or channel. The lock <b>32</b> could take various other forms such as a bayonet lock or any type of projection that engages a suitable detent or latch. Preferably there are two locks and two locking recesses at spaced one hundred and eighty degrees apart on the circumference of the debris screen <b>14</b> although a single lock and recess could be used or the riser assembly <b>10</b> and the debris screen <b>14</b> could be locked together at more than two locations. Thus the present invention broadly includes a locking mechanism having a first portion on the lower end of the riser assembly and a second portion on a generally cylindrical debris screen that can be mated and positively locked and unlocked by relative axial and rotational motion between the debris screen and the riser assembly. Therefore, the protection afforded the present invention should only be limited in accordance with the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An irrigation sprinkler, comprising:
<claim-text>a generally tubular riser assembly including a nozzle turret rotatably mounted at an upper end of the riser assembly and a drive assembly coupled for rotating the nozzle turret;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a generally cylindrical debris screen formed with a plurality of apertures for filtering debris from water flowing through the apertures, the debris screen being dimensioned and configured to mate with a lower end of the riser assembly; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one locking mechanism having a first portion on the lower end of the riser assembly and a second portion on the debris screen, the first and second portions of the locking mechanism being located so that they can be mated when the debris screen is mated with the lower end of the riser assembly, and the first and second portions of the locking mechanism being configured so that they can be positively aligned with a relative axial motion between the debris screen and the riser assembly, and further locked and unlocked by rotational motion between the debris screen and the riser assembly, the locking mechanism holding the debris screen to the riser assembly when locked;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first portion of the locking mechanism is a locking recess, and wherein the locking recess has a generally L-shaped configuration with a first leg that extends in a direction generally parallel to a vertical axis of the riser assembly and a second leg that extends in a direction generally perpendicular to the vertical axis of the riser assembly.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The sprinkler of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the second portion of the locking mechanism is a lock that slides within the locking recess.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The sprinkler of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> wherein the lock is a generally V-shaped member with a pair of legs, one leg of the legs providing a flexible arm with a flexible locking tab.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The sprinkler of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the locking recess is formed in a cylindrical wall at the lower end of the riser assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The sprinkler of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref> wherein the lock is formed on a cylindrical flange of the screen.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The sprinkler of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> wherein the debris screen includes a generally disc-shaped portion formed with a plurality of apertures that is surrounded by the cylindrical flange.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The sprinkler of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the second leg of the locking recess is formed with a fixed tab and the lock is formed with a flexible tab that can flex in a first axial direction to move past the fixed tab upon rotation of the cylindrical flange of the debris screen within the cylindrical wall of the riser assembly and flex in a second axial direction to hold the debris screen to the riser assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The sprinkler of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref> wherein the flexible tab is formed on one end of a flexible arm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The sprinkler of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the second leg of the locking recess includes a locking cavity, the lock includes a flexible tab, and at least a portion of the flexible tab is configured to releasably engage with the locking cavity to hold the debris screen to the riser assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. An irrigation sprinkler, comprising:
<claim-text>a generally tubular riser assembly including a nozzle turret rotatably mounted at an upper end of the riser assembly and a drive assembly coupled for rotating the nozzle turret, the riser assembly having at least one locking recess formed in a lower end of the riser assembly;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a debris screen formed with a plurality of apertures for filtering debris from water flowing through the apertures, the debris screen being dimensioned and configured to mate with the lower end of the riser assembly; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one lock on the debris screen that is dimensioned and configured to be received in the locking recess via relative axial motion between the debris screen and the riser assembly and configured to lock and unlock with the locking recess via relative rotational motion between the debris screen and the riser assembly to hold the debris screen to the riser assembly;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the lock is a generally U-shaped member with a pair of legs, one leg of the legs providing a flexible arm with a flexible locking tab.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The sprinkler of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref> wherein the debris screen has a generally cylindrical flange dimensioned to mate within a cylindrical wall forming the lower end of the riser assembly, the locking recess is formed in the cylindrical wall of the riser assembly and the lock projects radially outwardly from the cylindrical flange.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The sprinkler of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> wherein the locking recess has a generally L-shaped configuration with a first leg that extends in a direction generally parallel to a vertical axis of the riser assembly and a second leg that extends in a direction generally perpendicular to the vertical axis of the riser assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The sprinkler of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref> wherein the second leg of the locking recess is formed with a fixed tab and the lock is formed with a flexible tab that can flex in a first axial direction to move past the fixed tab upon rotation of the cylindrical flange of the debris screen within the cylindrical wall of the riser assembly and flex in a second axial direction to hold the debris screen to the riser assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The sprinkler of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> wherein the flexible tab is formed on one end of a flexible arm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The sprinkler of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref> wherein the second leg of the locking recess includes a locking cavity and at least a portion of the flexible locking tab is configured to releasably engage with the locking cavity to hold the debris screen to the riser assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The sprinkler of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the pair of legs extend from a base of the U-shaped member, and wherein the base of the U-shaped member has a height that is substantially the same as a height of the second leg in the direction generally perpendicular to the vertical axis of the riser assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The sprinkler of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> wherein the debris screen includes a generally disc-shaped portion formed with a plurality of apertures that is surrounded by the cylindrical flange.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The sprinkler of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref> wherein a perforated portion of the debris screen is made of interconnected rows and columns of molded plastic that define the plurality of apertures.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The sprinkler of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> wherein an outer surface of the cylindrical flange of the disc-shaped portion of the debris screen is formed with a plurality of circumferentially spaced axially extending ribs to facilitate manual gripping and rotation of the debris screen relative to the riser assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. An irrigation sprinkler, comprising:
<claim-text>a generally tubular riser assembly including a nozzle turret rotatably mounted at an upper end of the riser assembly and a drive assembly coupled for rotating the nozzle turret, the riser assembly having at least one locking recess formed in a cylindrical wall at a lower end of the riser assembly;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a debris screen formed with a plurality of apertures for filtering debris from water flowing through the apertures, the debris screen being dimensioned and configured to mate with the lower end of the riser assembly; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one lock on the debris screen that is dimensioned and configured to be received in the locking recess for holding the debris screen to the riser assembly; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the debris screen has a generally cylindrical flange dimensioned to mate within the cylindrical wall at the lower end of the riser assembly, the locking recess is formed in the cylindrical wall of the riser assembly and the lock projects radially outwardly from the cylindrical flange, and further,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the locking recess has a generally L-shaped configuration with a first leg that extends in a direction generally parallel to a vertical axis of the riser assembly and a second leg that extends in a direction generally perpendicular to the vertical axis of the riser assembly, and further</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second leg of the locking recess is formed with a fixed tab and the lock is formed with a flexible tab that can flex in a first axial direction to move past the fixed tab upon rotation of the cylindrical flange of the debris screen within the cylindrical wall of the riser assembly and flex in a second axial direction to hold the debris screen to the riser assembly. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
