<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626208-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626208</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12164544</doc-number>
<date>20080630</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>468</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20090101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>W</subclass>
<main-group>4</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>455466</main-classification>
<further-classification>4554563</further-classification>
<further-classification>4555759</further-classification>
<further-classification>701117</further-classification>
<further-classification>701 70</further-classification>
<further-classification>340901</further-classification>
<further-classification>340932</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Traffic data transmission from a vehicle telematics unit</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5428545</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Maegawa et al.</name>
<date>19950600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>701210</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6996089</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Ruf et al.</name>
<date>20060200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>370349</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2002/0038182</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Wong et al.</name>
<date>20020300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>701213</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0204306</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yamamoto et al.</name>
<date>20031000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>701200</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0203696</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Jijina et al.</name>
<date>20041000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0249569</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Oh</name>
<date>20041200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>701209</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0096020</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Oesterling et al.</name>
<date>20050500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4554142</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0287808</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Breitenberger et al.</name>
<date>20061200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>701117</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>16</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>370312</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>370313</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>370349</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>370464-503</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>701117-209</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4554561</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4554042</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>455466</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20090325612</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20091231</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Oesterling</last-name>
<first-name>Christopher L.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Troy</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ampunan</last-name>
<first-name>Nathan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Novi</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Oesterling</last-name>
<first-name>Christopher L.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Troy</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ampunan</last-name>
<first-name>Nathan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Novi</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Simon</last-name>
<first-name>Anthony Luke</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Reising Ethington P.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>General Motors LLC</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Detroit</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>P&#xe9;rez-Guti&#xe9;rrez</last-name>
<first-name>Rafael</first-name>
<department>2642</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Fang</last-name>
<first-name>Keith</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A method of sending traffic related data to a call center using a telematics unit of a vehicle. The method includes receiving a request at the telematics unit to transmit non-traffic data such as vehicle diagnostic information to the call center. Both the non-traffic data as well as traffic related data is obtained by the telematics unit and embedded into a short message service (SMS) message that is then sent to the call center. The traffic related data can be inserted only if it indicates a traffic problem and can be inserted into an otherwise unused portion of the SMS message. The received traffic related data can then be used by the call center or other remote facility to improve traffic reporting.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="177.46mm" wi="161.04mm" file="US08626208-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="253.83mm" wi="195.92mm" file="US08626208-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="242.65mm" wi="178.90mm" file="US08626208-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="207.86mm" wi="160.78mm" file="US08626208-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates generally to transmitting information regarding traffic to a central location. More particularly, the invention relates to modifying a traffic report promulgated by a call center using data created or measured by a vehicle.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Many users of motor vehicles rely on traffic reports to determine a route in which a driver may take to get to his or her destination. There are many methods for collecting traffic data for the purpose of traffic reporting. Traditionally, methods of observing traffic patterns include the use of airplanes, helicopters, traffic cameras, driver sightings and reportings and the like. Recently, wireless vehicle traffic probes have emerged.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">All of these systems incorporate the use of observing what is perceived to be occurring on the road. However, a difficulty in utilizing many of these systems is that there is not always a way to identify in real time exactly what is occurring in the vehicles and reporting those events in an accurate manner.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">According to an aspect of the invention, there is provided a method of sending traffic information to a call center using a telematics unit of a vehicle. The method begins with transmitting data from the vehicle modules to the telematics unit. A portion of the data transmitted to the telematics unit is identified as traffic related data. A message string containing the traffic related data is created. The message string is embedded into a short message service (SMS) message to be transmitted to the call center.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">According to another aspect of the invention, there is provided a telematics unit for a vehicle comprising a plurality of inputs operatively connected to vehicle system modules to receive data therefrom. The telematics unit also includes a memory for storing data. The telematics unit also includes a processing device capable of identifying the traffic related data. The telematics unit further includes a cellular chipset that is used for transmission of the traffic related data to the call center. The traffic related data is embedded into an SMS text message that is sent to the a call center along with other non-traffic data in response to a request to send the non-traffic data. In this way, traffic related data can be opportunistically sent to the call center with other data without having to incur additional airtime or message transmission charges.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">One or more preferred exemplary embodiments of the invention will hereinafter be described in conjunction with the appended drawings, wherein like designations denote like elements, and wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram depicting an exemplary embodiment of a communications system that is capable of utilizing the method disclosed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a logic chart of an exemplary embodiment of a method for sending traffic related data to a call center; and</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a logic chart of another exemplary embodiment of a method for sending traffic related data to a call center as a part of a communication message being sent to report other, non-traffic data.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT(S)</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The method described below facilitates the transmission of data relating to traffic events that are occurring and detected by vehicle system modules and sensors on the vehicle in a manner to further enhance the traffic reporting capabilities of a call center. This method incorporates the automatic transmission of this information making the reporting capabilities of the call center more accurate and less reliant upon human observation. The method incorporates the transmission of the data through short message service (SMS) text messages that do not increase the costs of communication between the vehicle and the call center.</p>
<p id="h-0006" num="0000">Communications System&#x2014;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, there is shown an exemplary operating environment that comprises a mobile vehicle communications system <b>10</b> and that can be used to implement the method disclosed herein. Communications system <b>10</b> generally includes a vehicle <b>12</b>, one or more wireless carrier systems <b>14</b>, a land communications network <b>16</b>, a computer <b>18</b>, and a call center <b>20</b>. It should be understood that the disclosed method can be used with any number of different systems and is not specifically limited to the operating environment shown here. Also, the architecture, construction, setup, and operation of the system <b>10</b> and its individual components are generally known in the art. Thus, the following paragraphs simply provide a brief overview of one such exemplary system <b>10</b>; however, other systems not shown here could employ the disclosed method as well.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Vehicle <b>12</b> is depicted in the illustrated embodiment as a passenger car, but it should be appreciated that any other vehicle including motorcycles, trucks, sports utility vehicles (SUVs), recreational vehicles (RVs), marine vessels, aircraft, etc., can also be used. Some of the vehicle electronics <b>28</b> is shown generally in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and includes a telematics unit <b>30</b>, a microphone <b>32</b>, one or more pushbuttons or other control inputs <b>34</b>, an audio system <b>36</b>, a visual display <b>38</b>, and a GPS module <b>40</b> as well as a number of vehicle system modules (VSMs) <b>42</b> having sensors (not shown). Some of these devices can be connected directly to the telematics unit <b>30</b> such as, for example, the microphone <b>32</b> and pushbutton(s) <b>34</b>, whereas others are indirectly connected using one or more network connections, such as a communications bus <b>44</b> or an entertainment bus <b>46</b>. Examples of suitable network connections include a controller area network (CAN), a media oriented system transfer (MOST), a local interconnection network (LIN), a local area network (LAN), and other appropriate connections such as Ethernet or others that conform with known ISO, SAE and IEEE standards and specifications, to name but a few.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Telematics unit <b>30</b> is an OEM-installed device that enables wireless voice and/or data communication over wireless carrier system <b>14</b> and via wireless networking so that the vehicle can communicate with call center <b>20</b>, other telematics-enabled vehicles, or some other entity or device. The telematics unit <b>30</b> preferably uses radio transmissions to establish a communications channel (a voice channel and/or a data channel) with wireless carrier system <b>14</b> so that voice and/or data transmissions can be sent and received over the channel. By providing both voice and data communication, telematics unit <b>30</b> enables the vehicle to offer a number of different services including those related to navigation, telephony, emergency assistance, diagnostics, infotainment, etc. Data can be sent either via a data connection, such as via packet data transmission over a data channel, or via a voice channel using techniques known in the art. This includes the communication of data in text format using short message service (SMS) messages. For combined services that involve both voice communication (e.g., with a live advisor or voice response unit at the call center <b>20</b>) and data communication (e.g., to provide GPS location data or vehicle diagnostic data to the call center <b>20</b>), the system can utilize a single call over a voice channel and switch as needed between voice and data transmission over the voice channel, and this can be done using techniques known to those skilled in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">According to one embodiment, telematics unit <b>30</b> utilizes cellular communication according to either GSM or CDMA standards and thus includes a standard cellular chipset <b>50</b> for voice communications like hands-free calling, a wireless modem for data transmission, an electronic processing device <b>52</b>, one or more digital memory devices <b>54</b>, and a dual antenna <b>56</b>. Using these components, telematics unit <b>30</b> can transmit and/or receive data or commands via the various communication approaches noted above, including via SMS messages, wherein the data can be incorporated into, for example, the text message portion (payload) of the SMS message. It should be appreciated that the modem can either be implemented through software that is stored in the telematics unit <b>30</b> and is executed by processor <b>52</b>, or it can be a separate hardware component located internal or external to telematics unit <b>30</b>. The modem can operate using any number of different standards or protocols such as EVDO, CDMA, GPRS, and EDGE. Wireless networking between the vehicle and other networked devices can also be carried out using telematics unit <b>30</b>. For this purpose, telematics unit <b>30</b> can be configured to communicate wirelessly according to one or more wireless protocols, such as any of the IEEE 802.11 protocols, WiMAX, or Bluetooth. When used for packet-switched data communication such as TCP/IP, the telematics unit can be configured with a static IP address or can set up to automatically receive an assigned IP address from another device on the network such as a router or from a network address server.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Processor <b>52</b> can be any type of device capable of processing electronic instructions including microprocessors, microcontrollers, host processors, controllers, vehicle communication processors, and application specific integrated circuits (ASICs). It can be a dedicated processor used only for telematics unit <b>30</b> or can be shared with other vehicle systems. Processor <b>52</b> executes various types of digitally-stored instructions, such as software or firmware programs stored in memory <b>54</b>, which enable the telematics unit <b>30</b> to provide a wide variety of services. For instance, processor <b>52</b> can execute programs or process data to carry out at least a part of the method discussed herein. In one embodiment, the processor <b>52</b> receives data from the VSMs <b>42</b> and segregates the data between traffic related data and non-traffic related data. With the traffic related data, the processor <b>52</b> can further correlate or classify the traffic related data based on the type of traffic data it is. For example, the vehicle <b>12</b> may slow down for a period of time. This data is different than airbag deployment data. The former example identifies increased traffic and the second signifies a possible traffic accident. As is discussed below, this information can be transmitted to the call center <b>20</b> using the cellular chipset <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Telematics unit <b>30</b> can be used to provide a diverse range of vehicle services that involve wireless communication to and/or from the vehicle. Such services include: turn-by-turn directions and other navigation-related services that are provided in conjunction with the GPS-based vehicle navigation module <b>40</b>; airbag deployment notification and other emergency or roadside assistance-related services that are provided in connection with one or more collision sensor interface modules such as a body control module (not shown); diagnostic reporting using one or more diagnostic modules; and infotainment-related services where music, webpages, movies, television programs, videogames and/or other information is downloaded by an infotainment module (not shown) and is stored for current or later playback. The above-listed services are by no means an exhaustive list of all of the capabilities of telematics unit <b>30</b>, but are simply an enumeration of some of the services that the telematics unit is capable of offering. As noted above, the transmission of information from the vehicle <b>12</b> to the call center <b>20</b> or other location can be carried out in various ways including via SMS messages containing the transmitted data. Building and sending of SMS messages containing vehicle data can be done in response to a request at the telematics unit <b>30</b> to send the vehicle data. This request can be the result of a trigger occurring that was previously set on the vehicle, or can be a present request received from the call center or other remote facility. The use of triggers to cause vehicle data reporting via SMS messages can be done as disclosed in U.S. Published Patent Application No. 20040203696A1, the entire contents of which is hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">At least some of the aforementioned vehicle system modules can be implemented in the form of software instructions saved internal or external to telematics unit <b>30</b>, they could be hardware components located internal or external to telematics unit <b>30</b>, or they could be integrated and/or shared with each other or with other systems located throughout the vehicle, to cite but a few possibilities. In the event that the modules are implemented as VSMs <b>42</b> located external to telematics unit <b>30</b>, they could utilize vehicle bus <b>44</b> to exchange data and commands with the telematics unit.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">GPS module <b>40</b> receives radio signals from a constellation <b>60</b> of GPS satellites. From these signals, the module <b>40</b> can determine vehicle position that is used for providing navigation and other position-related services to the vehicle driver. Navigation information can be presented on the display <b>38</b> (or other display within the vehicle) or can be presented verbally such as is done when supplying turn-by-turn navigation. The navigation services can be provided using a dedicated in-vehicle navigation module (which can be part of GPS module <b>40</b>), or some or all navigation services can be done via telematics unit <b>30</b>, wherein the position information is sent to a remote location for purposes of providing the vehicle with navigation maps, map annotations (points of interest, restaurants, etc.), route calculations, and the like. The position information can be supplied to call center <b>20</b> or other remote computer system, such as computer <b>18</b>, for other purposes, such as fleet management. Also, new or updated map data can be downloaded to the GPS module <b>40</b> from the call center <b>20</b> via the telematics unit <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Apart from the audio system <b>36</b> and GPS module <b>40</b>, the vehicle <b>12</b> can include other vehicle system modules (VSMS) <b>42</b> in the form of electronic hardware components that are located throughout the vehicle and typically receive input from one or more sensors and use the sensed input to perform diagnostic, monitoring, control, reporting and/or other functions. Each of the VSMs <b>42</b> is preferably connected by communications bus <b>44</b> to the other VSMs, as well as to the telematics unit <b>30</b>, and can be programmed to run vehicle system and subsystem diagnostic tests. As examples, one VSM <b>42</b> can be an engine control module (ECM) that controls various aspects of engine operation such as fuel ignition and ignition timing, another VSM <b>42</b> can be a powertrain control module that regulates operation of one or more components of the vehicle powertrain, and another VSM <b>42</b> can be a body control module that governs various electrical components located throughout the vehicle, like the vehicle's power door locks and headlights. According to one embodiment, the engine control module is equipped with on-board diagnostic (OBD) features that provide myriad real-time data, such as that received from various sensors including vehicle emissions sensors, and provide a standardized series of diagnostic trouble codes (DTCs) that allow a technician to rapidly identify and remedy malfunctions within the vehicle. As is appreciated by those skilled in the art, the above-mentioned VSMs are only examples of some of the modules that may be used in vehicle <b>12</b>, as numerous others are also possible.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Vehicle electronics <b>28</b> also includes a number of vehicle user interfaces that provide vehicle occupants with a means of providing and/or receiving information, including microphone <b>32</b>, pushbuttons(s) <b>34</b>, audio system <b>36</b>, and visual display <b>38</b>. As used herein, the term &#x2018;vehicle user interface&#x2019; broadly includes any suitable form of electronic device, including both hardware and software components, which is located on the vehicle and enables a vehicle user to communicate with or through a component of the vehicle. Microphone <b>32</b> provides audio input to the telematics unit to enable the driver or other occupant to provide voice commands and carry out hands-free calling via the wireless carrier system <b>14</b>. For this purpose, it can be connected to an on-board automated voice processing unit utilizing human-machine interface (HMI) technology known in the art. The pushbutton(s) <b>34</b> allow manual user input into the telematics unit <b>30</b> to initiate wireless telephone calls and provide other data, response, or control input. Separate pushbuttons can be used for initiating emergency calls versus regular service assistance calls to the call center <b>20</b>. Audio system <b>36</b> provides audio output to a vehicle occupant and can be a dedicated, stand-alone system or part of the primary vehicle audio system. According to the particular embodiment shown here, audio system <b>36</b> is operatively coupled to both vehicle bus <b>44</b> and entertainment bus <b>46</b> and can provide AM, FM and satellite radio, CD, DVD and other multimedia functionality. This functionality can be provided in conjunction with or independent of the infotainment module described above. Visual display <b>38</b> is preferably a graphics display, such as a touch screen on the instrument panel or a heads-up display reflected off of the windshield, and can be used to provide a multitude of input and output functions. Various other vehicle user interfaces can also be utilized, as the interfaces of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> are only an example of one particular implementation.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Wireless carrier system <b>14</b> is preferably a cellular telephone system that includes a plurality of cell towers <b>70</b> (only one shown), one or more mobile switching centers (MSCs) <b>72</b>, as well as any other networking components required to connect wireless carrier system <b>14</b> with land network <b>16</b>. Each cell tower <b>70</b> includes sending and receiving antennas and a base station, with the base stations from different cell towers being connected to the MSC <b>72</b> either directly or via intermediary equipment such as a base station controller. Cellular system <b>14</b> can implement any suitable communications technology, including for example, analog technologies such as AMPS, or the newer digital technologies such as CDMA (e.g., CDMA2000) or GSM/GPRS. As will be appreciated by those skilled in the art, various cell tower/base station/MSC arrangements are possible and could be used with wireless system <b>14</b>. For instance, the base station and cell tower could be co-located at the same site or they could be remotely located from one another, each base station could be responsible for a single cell tower or a single base station could service various cell towers, and various base stations could be coupled to a single MSC, to name but a few of the possible arrangements.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Apart from using wireless carrier system <b>14</b>, a different wireless carrier system in the form of satellite communication can be used to provide uni-directional or bi-directional communication with the vehicle. This can be done using one or more communication satellites <b>62</b> and an uplink transmitting station <b>64</b>. Uni-directional communication can be, for example, satellite radio services, wherein programming content (news, music, etc.) is received by transmitting station <b>64</b>, packaged for upload, and then sent to the satellite <b>62</b>, which broadcasts the programming to subscribers. Bi-directional communication can be, for example, satellite telephony services using satellite <b>62</b> to relay telephone communications between the vehicle <b>12</b> and station <b>64</b>. If used, this satellite telephony can be utilized either in addition to or in lieu of wireless carrier system <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Land network <b>16</b> may be a conventional land-based telecommunications network that is connected to one or more landline telephones and connects wireless carrier system <b>14</b> to call center <b>20</b>. For example, land network <b>16</b> may include a public switched telephone network (PSTN) such as that used to provide hardwired telephony, packet-switched data communications, and the Internet infrastructure. One or more segments of land network <b>16</b> could be implemented through the use of a standard wired network, a fiber or other optical network, a cable network, power lines, other wireless networks such as wireless local area networks (WLANs), or networks providing broadband wireless access (BWA), or any combination thereof. Furthermore, call center <b>20</b> need not be connected via land network <b>16</b>, but could include wireless telephony equipment so that it can communicate directly with a wireless network, such as wireless carrier system <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Computer <b>18</b> can be one of a number of computers accessible via a private or public network such as the Internet. Each such computer <b>18</b> can be used for one or more purposes, such as a web server accessible by the vehicle via telematics unit <b>30</b> and wireless carrier <b>14</b>. Other such accessible computers <b>18</b> can be, for example: a service center computer where diagnostic information and other vehicle data can be uploaded from the vehicle via the telematics unit <b>30</b>; a client computer used by the vehicle owner or other subscriber for such purposes as accessing or receiving vehicle data or to setting up or configuring subscriber preferences or controlling vehicle functions; or a third party repository to or from which vehicle data or other information is provided, whether by communicating with the vehicle <b>12</b> or call center <b>20</b>, or both. A computer <b>18</b> can also be used for providing Internet connectivity such as DNS services or as a network address server that uses DHCP or other suitable protocol to assign an IP address to the vehicle <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Call center <b>20</b> is designed to provide the vehicle electronics <b>28</b> with a number of different system back-end functions and, according to the exemplary embodiment shown here, generally includes one or more switches <b>80</b>, servers <b>82</b>, databases <b>84</b>, live advisors <b>86</b>, as well as an automated voice response system (VRS) <b>88</b>, all of which are known in the art. These various call center components are preferably coupled to one another via a wired or wireless local area network <b>90</b>. Switch <b>80</b>, which can be a private branch exchange (PBX) switch, routes incoming signals so that voice transmissions are usually sent to either the live adviser <b>86</b> by regular phone or to the automated voice response system <b>88</b> using VoIP. The live advisor phone can also use VoIP as indicated by the broken line in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. VoIP and other data communication through the switch <b>80</b> is implemented via a modem (not shown) connected between the switch <b>80</b> and network <b>90</b>. Data transmissions are passed via the modem to server <b>82</b> and/or database <b>84</b>. Database <b>84</b> can store account information such as subscriber authentication information, vehicle identifiers, profile records, behavioral patterns, and other pertinent subscriber information. Data transmissions may also be conducted by wireless systems, such as 802.11x, GPRS, and the like. Although the illustrated embodiment has been described as it would be used in conjunction with a manned call center <b>20</b> using live advisor <b>86</b>, it will be appreciated that the call center can instead utilize VRS <b>88</b> as an automated advisor or, a combination of VRS <b>88</b> and the live advisor <b>86</b> can be used.</p>
<p id="h-0007" num="0000">Method&#x2014;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Turning now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, there is a logic chart of an embodiment <b>100</b> for sending traffic related data to a call center. The method begins at <b>102</b>. The first step in the method is the receipt of the data from vehicle system modules <b>42</b> by the telematics unit <b>30</b>. The vehicle system modules <b>42</b> may include sensors that measure certain activities. A non-exhaustive list of activities that might be sensed and reported to the telematics unit <b>30</b> includes mileage, component usage, diagnostic trouble codes (DTCs), the deployment of airbags, rapid decelerations, violent oversteer, and measuring extended periods of time in which the vehicle <b>12</b> is driving at five miles an hour or less.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Some of this data is considered traffic related data that can be indicative of a traffic problem or situation for which reporting is desired. Other of this data, however, is vehicle-related information concerning, for example, the operating condition of the vehicle or one or more of its components or systems. Therefore, the telematics unit <b>30</b> can identify the data it receives from the vehicle system modules <b>42</b> as either traffic related data or non-traffic data, and can segregate the data on this basis, as indicated at step <b>106</b>. It will be appreciated by those skilled in the art that it is not necessary in all embodiments that the traffic related data be separately identified or segregated, but only that it be identifiable as traffic related data so that the call center knows what it is and, thus, how it can then be used. The telematics unit <b>30</b> can process and use the non-traffic data in ways known to those skilled in the art. For the traffic related data, the telematics unit <b>30</b> then identifies or correlates this data to a type of event at <b>108</b>. If desired, different types of traffic related data may be identified and any one type of traffic related data occurring once may not require the notification of the call center <b>20</b> that a traffic related incident worthy of reporting has occurred. By way of example, the detection of a vehicle stopped while on a limited-access highway may be worthy of reporting as a traffic related incident or event. A single rapid deceleration may, however, not be considered worthy of a traffic related event and will only be reported if multiple rapid decelerations occur within a certain period of time. Thus, the method can include processing steps such as steps <b>110</b>-<b>118</b> to determine whether the traffic related data should be reported to the call center. These steps are used to process the traffic related data to determine if it meets at least one predefined criterion. In the example below, the method tests to determine if a particular traffic event (e.g., a rapid vehicle deceleration) occurs more than a predefined number of times within a certain time period. This could be used to determine that a traffic slowdown worth reporting has occurred where, for example, the vehicle undergoes two large slowdowns from highway speeds within a five minute period.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Once the traffic related data received by the telematics unit <b>30</b> is correlated or otherwise related to an event (e.g., highway slowdowns), the number of occurrences is counted at <b>110</b>. This correlation can include more than just analysis of vehicle speeds and acceleration/deceleration, but could include an analysis of vehicle location to determine, for example, whether or not the vehicle is currently on a highway or other high speed roadway. As stated above, each type of event could have a different number for its occurrence count at which the traffic related data is to be reported to the call center. Thus, for example, stoppage of a vehicle while on a highway might use an occurrence count of only one so that a vehicle coming to full stop while on a highway or on the shoulder would be reported, whereas, a rapid deceleration while on the highway would not be reported unless it occurs two or more times within a short period of time. Thus, at step <b>112</b>, it is determined whether the occurrence of the event has exceeded a predetermined threshold. If the predetermined threshold has not been exceeded, the method <b>100</b> loops back to step <b>104</b>. If, however, the occurrence of an event has exceeded its predetermined threshold, the method then proceeds to step <b>114</b> and determines whether a time period for collection of the traffic data has expired (e.g., the five minute period). If the time period for collecting traffic data has expired, the occurrence counter is reset at <b>116</b>, the timer is reset at <b>118</b>, and the method <b>100</b> loops back to step <b>104</b>. As with the occurrence of events, the time period for collecting traffic data for a particular type of event, if used at all, will vary from event to event. All of these occurrences predetermine thresholds and time periods can be stored in the memory <b>54</b> of the telematics unit <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">If the occurrence of the events exceeds the predetermined threshold (identified at step <b>112</b>) and the time period for collecting traffic data has not expired (at <b>114</b>) based on the traffic data being collected, the traffic related data will be reported to the call center and a message string based on the data is therefore created at <b>120</b>. The message string can be, for example, a text string identifying the type of traffic data collected and when it was collected. It is contemplated that in some embodiments the traffic related events can be characterized with the use of only three or four bits therefore potentially only requiring a single alphanumeric character to transmit the traffic related data. In other embodiments, the traffic data can be much longer.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Once the message string is created, additional data can be attached or merged with the message string at <b>122</b>. The additional data can be a timestamp and/or GPS data gathered by the GPS module <b>40</b>. Once this additional data is attached to the message string, the message string is embedded into a short message service (SMS) message at <b>124</b>. It can be incorporated into the text message part (payload) of the SMS message or into another portion such as a buffer in the SMS message that is not used for anything related to the transmission of data. This buffer is used to ensure as much of the SMS message is transmitted to its desired destination in as complete and error-free form as possible. By adding the data to the SMS message buffer, the traffic information may be transmitted to the call center <b>20</b> in an SMS message that is generated for another purpose. In this way, an SMS message may have two functions, that being the primary message of the SMS message and the (secondary) traffic data of the SMS message. Because the traffic data is something that is desired by the call center and not necessarily desired by the operator of the vehicle <b>12</b>, the use of the SMS message buffer is advantageous because it results no additional message delivery charges back to the call center or operator of the vehicle <b>12</b>. Thus, this allows the traffic event data to be transmitted from the vehicle <b>12</b> to the call center <b>20</b> using a message created via SMS, thereby allowing the call center <b>20</b> to create a more accurate traffic report to be utilized by other drivers of other vehicles, all without incurring any extra airtime or message charges.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, there is shown one exemplary method in which the traffic related data is incorporated into a communication message being sent to the call center for other purposes. In step <b>202</b>, the telematics unit receives a request to send non-traffic data from the telematics unit to the call center. This can be, for example, a request resulting from the occurrence of a trigger on the vehicle to report diagnostic or other such information. Thus, at step <b>204</b>, the telematics unit receives the non-traffic data from one or more of the vehicle system modules. A communication message is then generated at step <b>206</b>. The system determines if there is any traffic related data at the vehicle that should be sent to the call center, step <b>208</b>. If so, the telematics unit receives that traffic related data and embeds it into the message, as indicated at steps <b>210</b> and <b>212</b>. Since there may be no request to send non-traffic data at the time that the traffic related data is generated, the system can temporarily store the traffic related data in memory, such as memory <b>54</b>, so that it is available the next time a transmission request occurs. Steps <b>208</b> and <b>210</b> can be carried out prior to step <b>206</b> so that the embedding of the traffic related data at step <b>212</b> can be done as a part of originally generating the communication message at step <b>206</b>. Once the message is created it is then transmitted to the call center, as indicated at step <b>214</b>. Although this traffic data reporting method is particularly useful for transmission of traffic related data via SMS messaging, it will be appreciated that any suitable communication approach can be used.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Traffic related data received by the call center can then be used in a variety of ways to improve traffic reported, whether that is done by the call center itself or by some other entity. For this purpose, the traffic related data received from the vehicle can be combined with like information from other vehicles and used to more accurately identify traffic incidents. Such information can then be reported back to drivers having service subscriptions with the call center to provide them more accurate, timely information concerning traffic conditions.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">It is to be understood that the foregoing is a description of one or more preferred exemplary embodiments of the invention. The invention is not limited to the particular embodiment(s) disclosed herein, but rather is defined solely by the claims below. Furthermore, the statements contained in the foregoing description relate to particular embodiments and are not to be construed as limitations on the scope of the invention or on the definition of terms used in the claims, except where a term or phrase is expressly defined above. Various other embodiments and various changes and modifications to the disclosed embodiment(s) will become apparent to those skilled in the art. All such other embodiments, changes, and modifications are intended to come within the scope of the appended claims.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">As used in this specification and claims, the terms &#x201c;for example,&#x201d; &#x201c;for instance,&#x201d; &#x201c;such as,&#x201d; and &#x201c;like,&#x201d; and the verbs &#x201c;comprising,&#x201d; &#x201c;having,&#x201d; &#x201c;including,&#x201d; and their other verb forms, when used in conjunction with a listing of one or more components or other items, are each to be construed as open-ended, meaning that the listing is not to be considered as excluding other, additional components or items. Other terms are to be construed using their broadest reasonable meaning unless they are used in a context that requires a different interpretation.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method for sending traffic information to a call center using a telematics unit of a vehicle, the method comprising:
<claim-text>(a) transmitting data measured by vehicle system modules to the telematics unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) identifying a portion of the data transmitted to the telematics unit in step (a) as traffic related data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) detecting that vehicle deceleration occurs more than a predefined number of times within a certain time period;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) determining, based on the vehicle deceleration occurring more than a predefined number of times within a certain time period, that the portion of the data that has been identified as traffic related data will be transmitted to the call center; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) creating a message string containing the traffic related data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(f) generating a short message system (SMS) message;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(g) automatically determining if there is any non-traffic related data at the vehicle to be sent to the call center using the telematics unit in response to generating the SMS message and, if so:
<claim-text>(g1) receiving the non-traffic related data at the telematics unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(g2) automatically embedding the message string containing the traffic related data into a portion of the SMS message that is unused by a short message service and including non-traffic related data obtained at the vehicle in a payload section of the SMS message; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>(h) transmitting the message to the call center using the telematics unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A method as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, including the step of attaching GPS coordinate information to the message string prior to embedding the message string in the SMS message.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A method as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, including the step correlating the traffic related data to a type of traffic event to create correlated traffic data.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A method as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, including the step of counting correlated traffic data to create an occurrence value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A method as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, including the step of comparing the occurrence value to a predetermined threshold.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A method as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, including the step of measuring time for the occurrence value to exceed the predetermined threshold.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A method as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, including the step of resetting the occurrence value to zero when the occurrence value fails to exceed the predetermined threshold within a time period.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A method as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, including the step of establishing a time period for each type of traffic data measured.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A method as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising the step of determining that the vehicle is on a high-speed roadway based on the vehicle location.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A method for sending traffic information to a call center using a telematics unit of a vehicle, the method comprising:
<claim-text>(a) receiving a request to send non-traffic related data that relates to the operating condition of a vehicle from a telematics unit to a call center;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) receiving the non-traffic related data at the telematics unit from one or more vehicle system modules;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) generating a short message system (SMS) message containing the non-traffic related data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) automatically determining if there is any traffic related data at the vehicle to be sent to the call center using the telematics unit in response to the generated communication message containing the non-traffic related data and, if so:
<claim-text>(d1) receiving traffic related data at the telematics unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(d2) creating a message string containing the traffic related data and embedding the message string into a portion of the SMS message that is unused by a short message service; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) transmitting the message to the call center.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A method as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, including the step of embedding GPS coordinate information into the message along with the traffic related data.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. A method as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, including the step correlating the traffic related data to a type of traffic event to create correlated traffic data.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A method as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, including the step of counting correlated traffic data to create an occurrence value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A method as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, including the step of comparing the occurrence value to a predetermined threshold.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A method as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, including the step of resetting the occurrence value to zero when the occurrence value fails to exceed the predetermined threshold within a time period.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A method as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein step (d) further comprises obtaining the traffic related data at the vehicle and determining if it meets at least one predefined criterion. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
