<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626907-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626907</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13385866</doc-number>
<date>20120309</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2012-013057</doc-number>
<date>20120125</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>16</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>709224</main-classification>
<further-classification>709227</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e61">Information processing unit, program execution method, and program for controlling electric appliance</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0197989</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hori et al.</name>
<date>20050900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>706 47</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0286722</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Aboba et al.</name>
<date>20051200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>380277</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0259184</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hayes et al.</name>
<date>20061100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>700221</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0318699</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Gao-Saari et al.</name>
<date>20101200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>710 72</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2012/0290694</doc-number>
<kind>A9</kind>
<name>Marl et al.</name>
<date>20121100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>709223</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2005-109746</doc-number>
<date>20050400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010097587</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20100400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>6</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>10</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130191529</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130725</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sugaya</last-name>
<first-name>Shunji</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sugaya</last-name>
<first-name>Shunji</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>BainwoodHuang</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>OPTiM Corporation</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Saga</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Etienne</last-name>
<first-name>Ario</first-name>
<department>2457</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Williams</last-name>
<first-name>Clayton R</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An information processing unit, a program execution method, and a program are capable of identifying the type of an electric appliance and then automatically performing the setting operation, the setting information viewing, and the like of the electric appliance in order to enhance the user convenience. The information processing unit detects the electric appliance connected with a network and then determines the model related information of the detected electric appliance. The information processing unit selects a program corresponding to the model related information based on the determined model related information and then executes the selected program in a device communicatively connected with the electric appliance.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="199.39mm" wi="176.36mm" file="US08626907-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="212.68mm" wi="178.82mm" file="US08626907-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="178.65mm" wi="171.87mm" file="US08626907-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="201.00mm" wi="148.67mm" file="US08626907-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="236.73mm" wi="150.45mm" file="US08626907-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="234.36mm" wi="158.83mm" file="US08626907-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="92.46mm" wi="161.88mm" file="US08626907-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="244.43mm" wi="165.61mm" file="US08626907-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is based on and claims the benefit of priority from Japanese Patent Application No. 2012-013057, filed on Jan. 25, 2012, the content and teachings of which are incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to an information processing unit, a program execution method, and a program for controlling an electric appliance connected with a network.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND ART</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Recently, a method and a device has been known in which the device such as a router or a gateway automatically identifies the type of an electric appliance connected with a home or office network</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">For example, PLT 1 discloses that an information processing unit transmits and receives network protocols to and from an electric appliance, and then conducts scoring based on response packets specific to the electric appliance to identify the type of the electric appliance.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">CITATION LIST</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Patent Literature</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">PLT 1: Japanese Unexamined Patent Application 2010-097587</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">SUMMARY OF INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">However, this information processing unit is preoccupied with identifying the type of an electric appliance. Accordingly, the subsequent action has to be done by a person such as an administrator who runs the network. After the type of the electric appliance is identified, a setting operation for this electric appliance is often required to be performed, or software related to this electric appliance to be executed.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">At present, the wide variety and numbers of electric appliances are connected with a network and generally have different ways of the setting operation and the setting information viewing. Therefore, some users who use such electric appliances may often take time in the setting operation and the setting information viewing and may not always know these operations or use these electric appliances properly.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">An objective of the present disclosure is to provide an information processing unit, a program execution method, and a program capable of identifying the type of an electric appliance and then automatically performing the setting operation, the setting information viewing, and the like of the electric appliance in order to enhance the user convenience.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to one embodiment, an information processing unit executing a predetermined process in response to connecting an electric appliance with a network includes:</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">a detection module configured to detect the electric appliance connected with a network;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">a model related information determination module configured to determine the model related information of the detected electric appliance; and</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">a program execution module configured to select a program corresponding to the model related information based on the determined model related information and to execute the selected program in a device communicatively connected with the electric appliance.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">According to one embodiment, an information processing unit executing a predetermined process in response to connecting an electric appliance with a network detects the electric appliance connected with a network, determines the model related information of the detected electric appliance, selects a program corresponding to the model related information based on the determined model related information, and executes the selected program in a device communicatively connected with the electric appliance.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Accordingly, these embodiments can identify the type of an electric appliance and then perform the setting operation, the setting information viewing, and the like of the electric appliance by executing a predetermined program.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">According to one embodiment, in the information processing unit, the program execution module executes a program to generate one URL address corresponding to the electric appliance and a page corresponding to the URL address, the page describing the model related information of the electric appliance, and to allow the page to be viewed from other devices.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Accordingly, this embodiment can identify the type of an electric appliance and then perform the setting operation, the setting information viewing, and the like of the electric appliance.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">According to one embodiment, in the information processing unit,</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">the program execution module selects a corresponding program based on the model related information as well as input history for the electric appliance or web page information referenced from the electric appliance.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Accordingly, this embodiment can identify the type of an electric appliance and then execute an appropriate program based on the input history and the referenced information.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Embodiments of the present invention can provide an information processing unit, a program execution method, and a program capable of identifying the type of an electric appliance and then automatically performing the setting operation, the setting information viewing, and the like of the electric appliance in order to enhance the user convenience.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows an overall schematic diagram of an example program execution system.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a functional block diagram of an example information processing unit, an example electric appliance, and an example access terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a flow chart illustrating an example program execution process executed by the information processing unit and the electric appliance.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a flow chart illustrating an example program selection process executed by the information processing unit.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows an example schedule execution program correspondence table stored in the information processing unit.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows an example reference data web page provided by the reference server.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows an example reference data correspondence program table stored in the information processing unit.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is an example screen image of the input history data screen displayed on the electric appliance.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is an example screen image of the network map displayed on the access terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is an example screen image of the unique page displayed on the access terminal.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Hereinafter, embodiments of the present invention will be described with reference to the attached drawings. However, this is illustrative only, and the technological scope of the present invention is not limited thereto.</p>
<p id="h-0008" num="0000">System Configuration of Program Execution System</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a system configuration diagram of the program execution system <b>1</b>. The program execution system <b>1</b> includes information processing units <b>10</b><i>a</i>, <b>10</b><i>b</i>, and <b>10</b><i>c </i>(hereinafter referred to as &#x201c;<b>10</b>&#x201d; unless they are clearly specified), electric appliances <b>50</b><i>a </i>and <b>50</b><i>b </i>(hereinafter referred to as &#x201c;<b>50</b>&#x201d; unless they are clearly specified), a public network <b>3</b> (e.g. the Internet, a third and a fourth generation communication networks), and an access terminal <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The information processing unit <b>10</b> is communicatively connected with the electric appliance <b>50</b> and the access terminal <b>30</b> through a public network <b>3</b> or a local area network <b>5</b>. The communication in the program execution system <b>1</b> may be wireless or wired communication. The information processing unit <b>10</b> may be communicatively connected with a public network <b>3</b> through a network device such as a router.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The information processing unit <b>10</b> may be a device performing a general computer processing, such as a server <b>10</b><i>c</i>, a mobile phone, or a smart phone <b>10</b><i>a</i>. The information processing unit <b>10</b> may also be a network device <b>10</b><i>b </i>such as a router or a gateway. The information processing unit <b>10</b> may also be a complex printer or a television, a home electric appliance such as a refrigerator or a washing machine. The information processing unit <b>10</b> may also be a general information appliance such as a telephone, a netbook terminal, a slate terminal, an electronic book terminal, an electronic dictionary terminal, a portable music player, or a portable player capable of recording and playing back contents.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The electric appliance <b>50</b> is a home or office electric appliance capable of data communication. The electric appliance <b>50</b> includes information appliances such as a personal computer <b>50</b><i>a</i>, a television, a telephone, a computer, a mobile phone, a handheld terminal, a net book terminal, a slate terminal, an electronic book terminal, a portable music player, an audio component, a content player, a printer <b>50</b><i>b</i>, a facsimile machine, a copy machine, a scanner machine, and a multi-function peripheral device or a multi-function printer (hereinafter referred to as &#x201c;MFP&#x201d;). The electric appliance <b>50</b> also includes home electric appliances such as a refrigerator, a washing machine, a dishwasher, a fan, an air conditioner, an electric stove, a rice cooker, and a microwave oven. The electric appliance <b>50</b> also includes a light, a server, a router <b>10</b><i>b</i>, a gateway, and a network attached storage (hereinafter referred to as &#x201c;NAS&#x201d;).</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The access terminal <b>30</b> is a general information terminal used by an administrator who supports the electric appliance <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0009" num="0000">Functions</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a functional block diagram of the information processing unit <b>10</b>, the electric appliance <b>50</b>, and the access terminal <b>30</b>, illustrating the relationship between individual functions.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The information processing unit <b>10</b> and the access unit <b>30</b> include a control unit provided with a central processing unit (hereinafter referred to as &#x201c;CPU&#x201d;), random access memory (hereinafter referred to as &#x201c;RAM&#x201d;), and read only memory (hereinafter referred to as &#x201c;ROM&#x201d;). The information processing unit <b>10</b> and the access unit <b>30</b> also include a communication unit such as Wireless Fidelity&#xae; or WiFi&#xae; enabled device complying with, for example, IEEE 802.11, or a wireless device complying with the IMT-2000 standard such as a third or fourth generation mobile communication system. The communication unit may be achieved through fixed LAN connection.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Furthermore, the information processing unit <b>10</b> and the access unit <b>30</b> also include an output unit, such as a display unit, to output and display data and images that are controlled by the control unit. The information processing unit <b>10</b> and the access unit <b>30</b> also include an input unit, such as a touch panel, a keyboard, or a mouse, to receive input from a user and an operator. The information processing unit <b>10</b> and the access unit <b>30</b> also include a memory unit such as a hard disk or semiconductor memory to store data.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The information processing unit <b>10</b> stores the schedule execution program correspondence table and the reference data correspondence table in the memory unit, as described below in connection with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</figref>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In the information processing unit <b>10</b>, the control unit reads a predetermined program, cooperating with the communication unit, the output unit, the input unit, and the memory unit to achieve an electric appliance access module <b>13</b> and a first program execution module <b>17</b>. The electric appliance access module <b>13</b> includes an electric appliance detection module <b>11</b> detecting the communicatively connected electric appliance <b>50</b> and a model related information determination module <b>12</b> determining the detected electric appliance <b>50</b>. The first program execution module <b>17</b> includes a program selection module <b>14</b> selecting a program to be executed, a URL generation module <b>15</b> generating a unique uniform resource locator (hereinafter referred to as URL), and a page generation module <b>16</b> generating a unique page corresponding to the generated URL.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In the access terminal <b>30</b>, the control unit reads a predetermined program, cooperating with the communication unit, the output unit, the input unit, and the memory unit to achieve a page viewing and operation module <b>31</b> such as a web browser.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Like the information processing unit <b>10</b> and the access unit <b>30</b>, the electric appliance <b>50</b> includes a control unit provided with a CPU, RAM, and ROM. The electric appliance <b>50</b> also include a communication unit such as WiFi&#xae; enabled device complying with, for example, IEEE 802.11, or a wireless device complying with the IMT-2000 standard such as a third or fourth generation mobile communication system. The communication unit may be achieved through fixed LAN connection. The electric appliance <b>50</b> may also include a memory unit such as a hard disk or semiconductor memory to store data.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Furthermore, the electric appliance <b>50</b> may also include an output unit, such as a display unit, to output and display data and images that are controlled by the control unit. The electric appliance <b>50</b> also includes an input unit, such as a touch panel, a keyboard, or a mouse, to receive input from a user and an operator.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In the electric appliance <b>50</b>, the control unit reads a predetermined program, cooperating with the communication unit, the output unit, the input unit, and the data storage unit to achieve a response module <b>51</b> responding to a packet transmitted from the information processing unit <b>10</b> and a second program execution module <b>52</b> executing the selected predetermined program.</p>
<p id="h-0010" num="0000">Program Execution Process</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The program execution process is a process, in which the information processing unit <b>10</b> determines the model related information of the electric appliance <b>50</b> by transmitting and receiving a predetermined packet and then executes a program based on the model related information and its related information. The model related information is information on the device types, such as the model name and the manufacturer name of the electric appliance <b>50</b>. In the present process, the process to determine the types of electric appliances connected with a network by transmitting and receiving a packet may be used, as described in Japanese Unexamined Patent Application 2010-97587. The process to determine the model related information in the way disclosed in this patent will be explained below in connection with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The electric appliance detection module <b>11</b> of the information processing unit <b>10</b> transmits a detection packet to the electric appliance <b>50</b> (Step S<b>20</b>). The detection packet may be a packet transmitted from a command such as ping. Each electric appliance <b>50</b> that has received a detection packet executes the detection response process by returning the IP address in response to the received packet (Step S<b>21</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">After the electric appliance <b>50</b> is detected, the model related information determination module <b>12</b> of the information processing unit <b>10</b> transmits a request packet to the detected electric appliance <b>50</b> (Step S<b>22</b>). The request packet is a packet for the information processing unit <b>10</b> to determine the model related information of the electric appliance <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">For example, the request packet may be a commands such as Address Resolution Protocol (hereinafter referred to as &#x201c;ARP&#x201d;), NETSTAT, Internet Control Message Protocol (hereinafter referred to as &#x201c;ICMP&#x201d;), or Simple Network Management Protocol (hereinafter referred to as &#x201c;SNMP&#x201d;). The request packet may be a protocol complying with Universal Plug and Play (hereinafter referred to as &#x201c;uPnP&#x201d;) and Digital Living Network Alliance (hereinafter referred to as &#x201c;DLNA&#x201d;).</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The electric appliance <b>50</b> transmits a response packet to the received request packet (Step S<b>23</b>). For example, Media Access Control (hereinafter referred to as &#x201c;MAC&#x201d;) address is acquired as a response in response to an ARP command. Moreover, the port numbers in use and the port occupancy of TCP/IP are identified by the command of NETSTAT.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Based on the response packet, the model related information determination module <b>12</b> of the information processing unit <b>10</b> determines the model related information of the electric appliance <b>50</b> that has transmitted the request packet (Step S<b>24</b>). The model related information is determined by scoring the response packet.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">As one example, determination whether the model related information of the electric appliance <b>50</b> is the model name A or B will be explained. The scores corresponding to the respective response packets to be received from each of the respective devices with the model names A and B are stored in the respective definition files for these model names. For example, in the case of the model name A, receiving the response packet (the TCP port <b>5000</b> is in use) for the request packet (NETSTAT) defines the score as &#x201c;1,&#x201d;, and receiving other responses for a plurality of respective request packets (response packets for such as ARP as well as NETSTAT) as &#x201c;0,&#x201d; in the definition file for the model name A. A response packet received from the electric appliance <b>50</b> is scored based on each of the respective definition files with the model names A and B. The model name from the definition file with higher score is determined as the model related information.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">For example, in the case of the model name A, receiving the response packet (the TCP port <b>5000</b> is in use) for the request packet (NETSTAT) defines the score as &#x201c;1,&#x201d; and receiving other responses as &#x201c;0.&#x201d; On the other hand, in the case of the model name B, receiving the response packet (the TCP port <b>5000</b> is not in use) for the request packet (NETSTAT) defines the score as &#x201c;1,&#x201d; and receiving other responses as &#x201c;0.&#x201d;</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">In this case, when the response packet (the TCP port <b>5000</b> is not in use) is received from the electric appliance <b>50</b>, the score is &#x201c;0&#x201d; as calculated based on the definition file for the model name A, and the score is &#x201c;1&#x201d; as for the model name B. Therefore, the model name B is the model related information. In this case, the model name B is determined based on only the request packet NETSTAT. However, other request packets (e.g., ARP) are also scored in the same way, and the model related information is determined based on the total score of NETSTAT and ARP.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The above-mentioned definition file may be stored in not the information processing unit <b>10</b> but a server communicatively connected with the information processing unit <b>10</b>. The information processing unit <b>10</b> transmits a response packet that has received from the electric appliance <b>50</b> to the server to request the model related information from the server. In this case, the server determines the model related information upon request. The model related information determination module <b>12</b> of the information processing unit <b>10</b> acquires the model related information determined by this server and then executes the subsequent process.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The model related information determination module <b>12</b> preferably determines the model related information by scoring based on a plurality of request packets as described above. The request packet may simply be a command of ICMP, SNMP, or the like. Accordingly, the model related information determination module <b>12</b> may determine the model related information only based on a response packet to such a request packet by transmitting uPnP.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">When the model related information is determined, the program selection module <b>14</b> of the information processing unit <b>10</b> executes the program selection process (Step S<b>25</b>). In the program selection process, the program selection module <b>14</b> references the schedule execution program correspondence table shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. For example, when the model related information is determined as &#x201c;A-<b>01</b>,&#x201d; the schedule execution program is determined as &#x201c;PROGRAM A (FILTERING CONFIGURATION)&#x201d; from the schedule execution program correspondence table.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">This &#x201c;PROGRAM A&#x201d; is to be executed on &#x201c;DETECTED DEVICE.&#x201d; Accordingly, the program selection module <b>14</b> transmits the program A to the detected electric appliance <b>50</b> so that the electric appliance <b>50</b> can execute the program A. The second program execution module <b>52</b> of the electric appliance <b>50</b> executes the received program A (Step S<b>26</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">When the program A is previously stored in the electric appliance <b>50</b>, the information processing unit <b>10</b> may transmit a command to start the program A instead of transmitting the program A to the electric appliance <b>50</b> so that the electric appliance <b>50</b> can execute the program A.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The program to be executed like the program A may be a program to perform a predetermined configuration of the electric appliance <b>50</b>, such as the filtering configuration of the web page. The program may be a program to install software such as a driver or a module in the electric appliance <b>50</b>. The program may be a program to install software such as a driver or a module associated with the electric appliance <b>50</b> in the information processing unit <b>10</b>. For example, the program to be installed in the information processing unit <b>10</b> may be software for a remote control operating the electric appliance <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the information processing unit <b>10</b> may display the communicatively connected electric appliance <b>50</b> in a network map and the program execution status <b>82</b>, by accessing the information processing unit <b>10</b> from the access terminal <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">For example, when the model related information is determined as &#x201c;B<b>003</b>,&#x201d; the schedule execution program is determined as &#x201c;PROGRAM B (PAGE GENERATION)&#x201d; from the. schedule execution program correspondence table. Since this &#x201c;PROGRAM B&#x201d; is to be executed in &#x201c;DETECTION EXECUTION DEVICE,&#x201d; the information processing unit <b>10</b> executes the program B. The process of the program B executed on the information processing unit <b>10</b> will be described in the steps S<b>27</b> to S<b>29</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The target device to execute the selected program may be any device communicatively connected with the information processing unit <b>10</b> and the electric appliance <b>50</b> as long as it is associated in the schedule execution program correspondence table.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The URL generation module <b>15</b> of the information processing unit <b>10</b> executes the URL generation process provided for the detected electric appliance <b>50</b> (Step S<b>27</b>). The URL generation process is a process to generate a URL that is an address for a unique web page to the electric appliance <b>50</b>. Specifically, the URL generation process is a process to newly generate each directory (path name) for a hostname preliminarily acquired for a URL. For example, the URL address with the hostname &#x201c;http://www.AAA.JP/&#x201d; and the model related information &#x201c;B<b>003</b>&#x201d; is generated as &#x201c;http://www.AAA.JP/B003/.&#x201d;</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The page generation module <b>16</b> generates a unique page for this electric appliance <b>50</b> (Step S<b>28</b>). The unique page is a web page for the electric appliance <b>50</b> associated with the generated URL address, in which the model related information of and other information of the electric appliance <b>50</b> are described. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> shows a screen image of the unique page displayed on the access terminal <b>30</b>. The information processing unit <b>10</b> may acquire information on the detected electric appliance <b>50</b> to be described in the unique page from other devices based on the model related information of the electric appliance <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">In the method of generating the unique page, information on the detected electric appliance <b>50</b> is added to patterned HTML data previously stored in the information processing unit <b>10</b> to generate the unique page. The generated unique page is stored as a file in the directory falling under &#x201c;http://www.AAA.JP/B003/&#x201d;. The file name is determined as &#x201c;B003.html&#x201d; based on the model related information of the electric appliance <b>50</b>. In this case, the resulting URL address is &#x201c;http://www.AAA.JP/B003/B003.html/.&#x201d; The information processing unit <b>10</b> functions as a web server allowing access from the access terminal <b>30</b> to the unique page.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">Specifically, the page generation module <b>16</b> of the information processing unit <b>10</b> receives viewing and operation of the unique page from the access terminal <b>30</b> while the unique page is accessible (Step S<b>29</b>). The access terminal <b>30</b> can access the unique page by executing the page viewing and operation module <b>31</b> functioning as a web browser. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, the web browser of the access terminal <b>30</b> displays the page &#x201c;B<b>003</b>&#x201d; <b>90</b> corresponding to the detected electric appliance <b>50</b>. For this display, the URL address <b>91</b> generated in the above-mentioned process is specified.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">Therefore, the unique page is automatically generated after the model related information so that the setting operation and the setting information viewing of the electric appliance <b>50</b> can be easily performed.</p>
<p id="h-0011" num="0000">Program Selection Process</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">Another example program selection process will be explained in reference to the flow chart of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">The program selection module <b>14</b> of the information processing unit <b>10</b> determines whether or not the reference server <b>300</b> is required to be accessed (Step S<b>31</b>). If the reference server <b>300</b> is required to be accessed (Step S<b>31</b>: &#x201c;YES&#x201d;), the process is moved to the step S<b>32</b>. If not (Step S<b>31</b>: &#x201c;NO&#x201d;), the process is moved to the step S<b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">The program selection module <b>14</b> determines the model related information and then references the schedule execution program correspondence table as described above. For example, in the case of the model related information &#x201c;PS-<b>01</b>,&#x201d; the schedule execution program is &#x201c;ACCESS TO REFERENCE SERVER&#x201d; associated with the URL address of the reference server &#x201c;http://www.XXXXX.&#x201d; If the model related information corresponds to &#x201c;ACCESS TO REFERENCE SERVER&#x201d; in the schedule execution program correspondence table, the step S<b>31</b> returns &#x201c;YES,&#x201d; and then the reference server <b>300</b> is accessed based on the associated URL address. If not, the step S<b>31</b> returns &#x201c;NO,&#x201d; and then the process is moved to the step S<b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The program selection module <b>14</b> acquires reference data from the reference server <b>300</b> (Step S<b>32</b>) and then selects an execution program based on the reference data (Step S<b>33</b>). For example, the reference data may be data on the software modification page of the electric appliance <b>50</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is an example of the web page with reference data. For example, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the program selection module <b>14</b> accesses the software modification page <b>60</b> of the electric appliance <b>50</b> with the device related information &#x201c;PS-<b>01</b>&#x201d; based on the URL address, references this page, and then checks the latest file name of the update module (e.g., &#x201c;fix<b>012</b>&#x201d;). In this case, the reference data is the file name &#x201c;fix<b>012</b>&#x201d; of this update module.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The program selection module <b>14</b> references the reference data correspondence program table based on the file name of the update module acquired from the reference server <b>300</b> to select a predetermined program. For example, in the case of the reference data &#x201c;fix<b>011</b>,&#x201d; PROGRAM C is executed. In the case &#x201c;fix<b>012</b>,&#x201d; PROGRAM D is executed.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">Assume that the update modules of &#x201c;fix<b>011</b>&#x201d; and older versions are previously installed in the information processing unit <b>10</b>. In this case, when the checked latest file name is &#x201c;fix<b>012</b>,&#x201d; the module &#x201c;fix<b>012</b>&#x201d; is acquired from the reference server <b>300</b> or the like by PROGRAM D and then set in the information processing unit <b>10</b>. When the checked latest file name is not &#x201c;fix<b>012</b>&#x201d; but &#x201c;fix<b>011</b>&#x201d; unlike <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, PROGRAM D to set &#x201c;fix<b>012</b>&#x201d; does not required to be executed. Instead of PROGRAM D, PROGRAM C is executed but not to set the update module.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The program selection module <b>14</b> of the information processing unit <b>10</b> determines whether or not input history is required to be referenced (Step S<b>34</b>). If input history is required to be referenced (Step S<b>34</b>: &#x201c;YES&#x201d;), the process is moved to the step S<b>35</b>. If not (Step S<b>34</b>: &#x201c;NO&#x201d;), the process is moved to the step S<b>37</b>. In the step S<b>37</b>, the program selection module <b>14</b> of the information processing unit <b>10</b> references the schedule execution program correspondence table and then selects program only based on the model related information, as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">For example, the program selection module <b>14</b> determines the model related information and then references the schedule execution program correspondence table, as described above. For example, in the case of the model related information &#x201c;DE<b>004</b>,&#x201d; the schedule execution program is &#x201c;REFERENCE INPUT HISTORY OF WINDOW A.&#x201d; The window A is one window being displayed on the electric appliance <b>50</b> with the model related information determined as &#x201c;DE<b>004</b>.&#x201d;</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> shows the screen image <b>70</b> where the window A is a window for setting operation of the configuration software list. For example, the electric appliance <b>50</b> is a personal computer. A user checks the checkboxes to set desired software from the configuration software list being displayed on the electric appliance <b>50</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the checkboxes of sharing software, e-mail software, and music software are checked.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">The program selection module <b>14</b> acquires the input history for the electric appliance <b>50</b> (Step S<b>35</b>), and then selects a program based on the input history (Step S<b>36</b>). Specifically, the program selection module <b>14</b> downloads the checked sharing software, e-mail software, and music software and then starts an install program.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">The input history may include not only checking the checkboxes as described above but also inputting text messages. The input history may also include selecting by pull-down menus, radio buttons, or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">An appropriate program is selected and executed automatically based on the result of accessing the reference server <b>300</b> and the input history for the electric appliance <b>50</b> so that the user convenience can be enhanced.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">To achieve the functionality as described above, a computer (including a CPU, an information processing unit, or various terminals) reads and executes a predetermined program. For example, a program is provided recorded on a computer-readable storage medium such as a floppy disk, a CD (e.g., CD-ROM), or a DVD (e.g., DVD-ROM or DVD-RAM), or the like. In this case, a computer reads a program from the storage medium, forwards the program to an internal or external memory device to store the program in such a memory device, and executes the program. For example, the program may be previously recorded in a memory device (storage medium) such as a magnetic disk, an optical disk, or a magnetic optical disk, and then provided from the memory device to a computer through a communication line.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">The embodiments of the present invention are described above, but the present invention is not limited thereto. The effects described in the embodiments of the present invention are merely listed as the most suitable effects produced from the present invention. The effects of the present invention are not limited to those described in the embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<heading id="h-0012" level="1">REFERENCE SIGNS LIST</heading>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084"><b>1</b> program execution system</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085"><b>3</b> public network</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086"><b>10</b> information processing unit</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087"><b>30</b> access terminal</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088"><b>50</b> electric appliance</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>I claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An apparatus comprising memory and a processor configured to execute a predetermined process in response to connecting an electric appliance with a network, the predetermined process including:
<claim-text>a detection module configured to detect the electric appliance connected with the network;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a model related information determination module configured to determine model related information of the detected electric appliance; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a program execution module configured to select a program based on the determined model related information and to execute the selected program in a device communicatively connected with the electric appliance;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein:
<claim-text>the model related information determination module is configured to determine the model related information of the detected electric appliance by:
<claim-text>transmitting a plurality of request packets to the detected electric appliance over the network;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a plurality of response packets from the detected electric appliance over the network in response to the plurality of request packets; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>scoring each response packet of the plurality of response packets with respect to a plurality of model types, scoring information for each model type being stored in a definition file for that model type; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>the program execution module is configured to select the program by:
<claim-text>referencing a program execution table using the model related information as an index;</claim-text>
<claim-text>if a program execution value indexed by the model related information indicates a web address, then selecting the program based on reference data provided by a web server located at the web address;</claim-text>
<claim-text>otherwise, if the program execution value indexed by the model related information references a display window, then selecting the program based on an input history of the display window; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>otherwise, selecting a program indexed by the model related information to be executed on a target device indexed by the model related information.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the program execution module executes a program to generate one URL address corresponding to the electric appliance and a page corresponding to the URL address, the page describing the electric appliance, and to allow the page to be viewed from other devices.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the program execution module selects a corresponding program based on the model related information as well as input history for the electric appliance or web page information referenced from the electric appliance.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. An apparatus comprising memory and a processor configured to execute a predetermined process in response to connecting an electric appliance with a network, the predetermined process including:
<claim-text>a detection module configured to detect the electric appliance connected with the network;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a model related information determination module configured to determine model related information of the detected electric appliance by communicating with a server; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a program execution module configured to select a program based on the determined model related information and to execute the selected program in a device communicatively connected with the electric appliance;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein:
<claim-text>the model related information determination module is configured to determine the model related information of the detected electric appliance by:
<claim-text>transmitting a plurality of request packets to the detected electric appliance over the network;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a plurality of response packets from the detected electric appliance over the network in response to the plurality of request packets;</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending the plurality of response packets to the server over a network connection, each of the plurality of response packets to be scored by the server with respect to a plurality of model types, scoring information for each model type being stored on the server in a definition file for that model type; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the model related information from the server over the network in response to sending the plurality of response packets to the server; and the program execution module is configured to select the program by:</claim-text>
<claim-text>referencing a program execution table using the model related information as an index;</claim-text>
<claim-text>if a program execution value indexed by the model related information indicates a web address, then selecting the program based on reference data provided by a web server located at the web address;</claim-text>
<claim-text>otherwise, if the program execution value indexed by the model related information references a display window, then selecting the program based on an input history of the display window; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>otherwise, selecting a program indexed by the model related information to be executed on a target device indexed by the model related information.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A method in response to connecting an electric appliance with a network, the method comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>detecting the electric appliance connected with the network;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining model related information of the detected electric appliance; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting a program based on the determined model related information and executing the selected program in a device comprising a memory and a processor communicatively connected with the electric appliance;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein:
<claim-text>determining the model related information of the detected electric appliance includes:
<claim-text>transmitting a plurality of request packets to the detected electric appliance over the network;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a plurality of response packets from the detected electric appliance over the network in response to the plurality of request packets; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>scoring each response packet of the plurality of response packets with respect to a plurality of model types, scoring information for each model type being stored in a definition file for that model type; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting the program includes:
<claim-text>referencing a program execution table using the model related information as an index;</claim-text>
<claim-text>if a program execution value indexed by the model related information indicates a web address, then selecting the program based on reference data provided by a web server located at the web address;</claim-text>
<claim-text>otherwise, if the program execution value indexed by the model related information references a display window, then selecting the program based on an input history of the display window; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>otherwise, selecting a program indexed by the model related information to be executed on a target device indexed by the model related information.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A computer program product for use in an information processing unit executing a predetermined process in response to connecting an electric appliance with a network, comprising a non-transitory computer usable medium having a set of instructions physically embodied therein, the set of instructions including computer readable code, which when executed by the information processing unit causes the information processing unit to:
<claim-text>detect the electric appliance connected with the network;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determine model related information of the detected electric appliance; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>select a program based on the determined model related information and to execute the selected program in a device communicatively connected with the electric appliance;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein:
<claim-text>determining the model related information of the detected electric appliance includes:
<claim-text>transmitting a plurality of request packets to the detected electric appliance over the network;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a plurality of response packets from the detected electric appliance over the network in response to the plurality of request packets; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>scoring each response packet of the plurality of response packets with respect to a plurality of model types, scoring information for each model type being stored in a definition file for that model type; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting the program includes:
<claim-text>referencing a program execution table using the model related information as an index;</claim-text>
<claim-text>if a program execution value indexed by the model related information indicates a web address, then selecting the program based on reference data provided by a web server located at the web address;</claim-text>
<claim-text>otherwise, if the program execution value indexed by the model related information references a display window, then selecting the program based on an input history of the display window; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>otherwise, selecting a program indexed by the model related information to be executed on a target device indexed by the model related information.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
