<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626283-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626283</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13729064</doc-number>
<date>20121228</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2012 1 0549851</doc-number>
<date>20121218</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>08</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>607  3</main-classification>
<further-classification>600548</further-classification>
<further-classification>128907</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e61">Electronic device and method for providing tactile stimulation</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4016870</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Lock</name>
<date>19770400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>600548</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7489973</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Shah</name>
<date>20090200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>607149</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8050776</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Shah</name>
<date>20111100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>607149</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8355790</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Naroditsky et al.</name>
<date>20130100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>607 46</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>10</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>607  3</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>600548</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>128907</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Fu Tai Hua Industry (Shenzhen) Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Zhou</last-name>
<first-name>Shang-Qing</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Fu Tai Hua Industry (Shenzhen) Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Kahelin</last-name>
<first-name>Michael</first-name>
<department>3762</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A method for providing tactile stimulation is applied in an electronic device. The electronic device includes a touch-sensitive screen and a tactile stimulation multilayer connected to the touch-sensitive screen. The tactile stimulation multilayer includes a number of electrodes. The method includes the steps of: providing a first user interface on the touch-sensitive screen for a user to select one body part for massage, and providing a second user interface for the user to select at least one acupuncture point of the selected body part; displaying a model of the selected body part and the selected acupuncture point thereof; according to the detected outline, adjusting a position of the selected acupuncture point to match the outline of the body part actually touching the screen; and energizing at least one electrode.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="165.35mm" wi="105.41mm" file="US08626283-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="104.39mm" wi="145.37mm" file="US08626283-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="92.12mm" wi="134.87mm" file="US08626283-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="178.99mm" wi="120.48mm" file="US08626283-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="126.41mm" wi="169.50mm" file="US08626283-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="128.86mm" wi="166.37mm" file="US08626283-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="188.81mm" wi="108.54mm" file="US08626283-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="129.20mm" wi="168.15mm" file="US08626283-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="232.24mm" wi="187.37mm" file="US08626283-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to electronic devices, and particularly, to an electronic device and a method for providing tactile stimulation adapted for the electronic device.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Many electronic devices, such as mobile phones, tablet computers, and multimedia players, employ touch-sensitive screens as input interfaces. When a user presses one virtual button or icon displayed on a touch-sensitive screen, the button or icon does not provide tactile feedback to the user, as a conventional keyboard does, which has a greater key-travel distance for a keystroke when operated.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In order to improve the user experience, a number of vibrating mechanical members are arranged under the touch-sensitive screen. When sensing a touch operation on the touch-sensitive screen, the vibrating mechanical member at the point of touch begins to vibrate to provide tactile feedback to the user. The technology of enabling the touch-sensitive screen to provide tactile feedback is realized by delivering an electrosensory sensation in response to a touch operation on the touch-sensitive screen. However, there are almost no developments on how the vibration-based tactile feedback or the electrosensory tactile feedback can be applied with a touch-sensitive screen to allow the electronic device to perform massaging functions.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Therefore, what is needed is a means to solve the problem described above.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Many aspects of the present disclosure can be better understood with reference to the following drawings. The modules in the drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the present disclosure. Moreover, in the drawings, like reference numerals designate corresponding portions throughout the views.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a touch-sensitive screen included in an electronic device, in accordance with an exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view of a tactile stimulation multilayer connected to the touch-sensitive screen of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, in accordance with an exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a block diagram of a tactile stimulation system applied to the electronic device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, in accordance with an exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic view of a first user interface provided by the tactile stimulation system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, showing how to select a body member for massage, in accordance with an exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a schematic view of a second user interface provided by the tactile stimulation system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, showing how to select acupuncture points for massage, in accordance with an exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a schematic view showing a selected body member and selected acupuncture points in the body member displayed on the touch-sensitive screen of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, in accordance with an exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a schematic view of a third user interface provided by the tactile stimulation system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, showing how to select stimulation options for energizing electrodes of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, in accordance with an exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a flowchart of a method for providing tactile stimulation, in accordance with an exemplary embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a touch-sensitive screen <b>10</b> of an electronic device <b>100</b> according to an exemplary embodiment. The electronic device <b>100</b> may be a mobile phone, a tablet computer, or a multimedia player for example. A tactile stimulation multilayer <b>20</b> is connected to the screen <b>10</b>, and is arranged above or under the screen <b>10</b>. The multilayer <b>20</b> includes a number of electrodes <b>220</b> (further shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) which can be independently controlled. The electronic device <b>100</b> further includes a storage unit <b>30</b> and a processor <b>40</b> (further shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>). The storage unit <b>30</b> stores at least one model of a human body part, for example a palm model, and a first position relationship between each model and acupuncture points of the model. The storage unit <b>30</b> further stores a second position relationship between a number of positions of the screen <b>10</b> and the electrodes <b>220</b>. Each position corresponds to one electrode <b>220</b>. The storage unit <b>30</b> further stores a tactile stimulation system <b>1</b>. The system <b>1</b> includes a variety of modules executed by the processor <b>40</b> to provide the functions of the system <b>1</b>. In this embodiment, the system <b>1</b> is executed by the processor <b>40</b> to energize the electrodes <b>220</b> in the multilayer <b>20</b> corresponding to at least one selected acupuncture point to provide a tactile stimulation to a body member touching the screen <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows that the multilayer <b>20</b> includes an insulation layer <b>21</b> and an electrode layer <b>22</b>. The electrodes <b>220</b> are included in the electrode layer <b>22</b>. The electrodes <b>220</b> are connected to a power supply unit <b>23</b>, and can be independently energized via the power supply unit <b>23</b>. The insulation layer <b>21</b> includes a number of insulators <b>210</b>, and each insulator <b>210</b> corresponds to one electrode <b>220</b>. In the embodiment, the multilayer <b>20</b> is arranged under the screen <b>10</b>, and the insulation layer <b>21</b> is arranged between the multilayer <b>20</b> and the electrode layer <b>22</b>. Furthermore, when a body member, which is a relatively good insulator when dry, touches the multilayer <b>20</b>, the body member and the multilayer <b>20</b> cooperatively form a capacitor. When the system <b>1</b> energizes the corresponding electrodes <b>220</b> via the power supply unit <b>23</b>, static electrical charges flow to the body member because of a capacitive coupling between the energized electrode <b>220</b> and the body member, and a tactile stimulation is delivered to the body member.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows that in the embodiment, the system <b>1</b> includes an interface module <b>11</b>, a control module <b>12</b>, a touch determining module <b>13</b>, and an adjusting module <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The interface module <b>11</b> provides a first user interface <b>111</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) on the screen <b>10</b>. The first user interface <b>111</b> includes a variety of model options for a user to select one model for massage. When one model is selected, the interface module <b>11</b> further provides a second user interface <b>112</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) on the screen <b>10</b>. The second user interface <b>111</b> includes a variety of acupuncture point options for the user to select at least one acupuncture point of the selected model.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The control module <b>12</b> displays the selected model and the selected acupuncture point of the selected model according to the first position relationship (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The touch determining module <b>13</b> determines whether the displayed model is touched by a body member according to signals from the screen <b>10</b>. If yes, the touch determining module <b>13</b> further determines an outline of the body member touching the displayed model, and determines whether the determined outline of the body member is the same type as in the displayed model. For example, if the displayed model is a palm of a left hand, and the body member touching the displayed model is also a palm of a left hand, the touching determining module <b>15</b> determines that the outline of the body member touching the displayed model is the same type as in the displayed model.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The adjusting module <b>14</b> determines any difference between the determined outline and the displayed model if the determined outline of the body member is the same type as in the displayed model, and adjusts the position of the selected acupuncture point according to such difference, to make sure that the selected acupuncture point corresponds to the actual acupuncture point of the body member touching the screen <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The control module <b>12</b> further determines at least one electrode <b>220</b> corresponding to the position of the selected acupuncture point (adjusted if required) according to the second position relationship between the positions and the electrodes <b>220</b>, and energizes the determined electrode <b>220</b> via the power supply unit <b>23</b>. Thus, tactile stimulation is provided to the selected acupuncture point of the body member touching the screen <b>10</b>, and a massage is provided. In this embodiment, the interface module <b>11</b> provides a third user interface <b>113</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>) on the screen <b>10</b> for a user to select stimulation options for energizing the electrodes <b>220</b>, and the control module energizes the determined electrode <b>220</b> via the power supply unit <b>23</b> according to the selected stimulation options. In the embodiment, the stimulation options include the strength of the stimulation, the total number of the stimulations, and the time interval between each two adjacent stimulations. Different strengths of the tactile stimulation are realized by altering the amplitude or wave frequency of electrical current energizing the electrodes <b>220</b>. In an alternative embodiment, the control module <b>12</b> may energize the determined electrode <b>220</b> according to default stimulation options, that is, the strength of the stimulation, the total number of the stimulations, and the time interval between each two adjacent stimulations are preset.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a flowchart of a method for providing tactile stimulation, in accordance with an exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In step S<b>81</b>, the interface module <b>11</b> provides a first user interface <b>111</b> on the screen <b>10</b> for a user to select one model of a human body part for massage and then provides a second user interface <b>112</b> on the screen <b>10</b> when one model is selected, for the user to select at least one acupuncture point of the selected model of the body part which the user wants to be massaged.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In step S<b>82</b>, the control module <b>12</b> displays the selected model and the selected acupuncture points of the selected model according to the first position relationship.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In step S<b>83</b>, the touch determining module <b>13</b> determines whether the displayed model is touched by a body member according to signals from the screen <b>10</b>, if any touch occurs (yes), the procedure goes to step S<b>84</b>; otherwise, the procedure goes back to step S<b>83</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In step S<b>84</b>, the touch determining module <b>13</b> determines an outline of the body member actually touching the displayed model and then determines whether the determined outline of the body member is the same type as in the displayed model, if yes, the procedure goes to step S<b>85</b>; otherwise, the procedure goes back to step S<b>83</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In step S<b>85</b>, the adjusting module <b>14</b> determines any difference between the determined outline and the model displayed, and adjusts the position of the selected acupuncture point according to any difference to make sure that the selected acupuncture point corresponds to the actual acupuncture point of the body member touching the screen <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In step S<b>86</b>, the control module <b>12</b> determines at least one electrode <b>220</b> corresponding to the position of the selected acupuncture point (adjusted if required) according to the second position relationship between the positions and the electrodes <b>220</b>, and energizes the determined electrodes <b>220</b> via the power supply unit <b>23</b>. In this embodiment, the control module <b>12</b> energizes the determined electrode <b>220</b> via the power supply unit <b>23</b> according to stimulation options selected by the user through a third user interface <b>113</b>. The stimulation options includes the strength of the stimulation, the total number of stimulations, the time interval between each two adjacent stimulations. The different ways in which the determined electrode <b>220</b> can be energized are realized by altering the amplitude or wave frequency of electrical current energizing the electrodes <b>220</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">It is believed that the present embodiments and their advantages will be understood from the foregoing description, and it will be apparent that various changes may be made thereto without departing from the spirit and scope of the disclosure or sacrificing all of its material advantages, the examples hereinbefore described merely being exemplary embodiments of the present disclosure.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An electronic device comprising:
<claim-text>a touch-sensitive screen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a tactile stimulation multilayer connected to the touch-sensitive screen, the tactile stimulation multilayer comprising a plurality of electrodes;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a storage unit storing a plurality of modules, a first position relationship between at least one model of a human body part and acupuncture points of each model, and a second position relationship between a plurality of positions of the touch-sensitive screen and the electrodes, each position corresponding to one of the electrodes; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a processor configured to execute a plurality of modules, and the plurality of modules comprising an interface module, a control module, a touch determining module, and an adjusting module;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the interface module is configured to provide a first user interface on the touch-sensitive screen for a user to select one model for massage, and further provide a second user interface for the user to select at least one acupuncture point of the selected model;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the control module is configured to display the selected model and the selected acupuncture point of the selected model according to the first position relationship;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the touch determining module is configured to determine whether the displayed model is touched by a body member according to signals from the touch-sensitive screen, determine an outline of the body member touching the displayed model if the displayed model is touched, and determine whether the determined outline of the body member is the same type as in the displayed model;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the adjusting module is configured to determine any difference between the determined outline and the displayed model if the determined outline of the body member is the same type as in the displayed model, and adjust a position of the selected acupuncture point according to the difference; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the control module is further configured to determine at least one electrode corresponding to the adjusted position of the selected acupuncture point according to the second position relationship and energize the determined electrodes via a power supply unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The electronic device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the interface module is further configured to provide a third user interface on the touch-sensitive screen for the user to select stimulation options for energizing the determined electrode, and the control module is further configured to energize the determined electrode via the power supply unit according to the selected stimulation options.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The electronic device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the stimulation options comprise a strength of the stimulation, a total number of the stimulations, and a time interval between each two adjacent stimulations.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The electronic device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein different strength of the stimulation is realized by altering an amplitude or wave frequency of electrical current energizing the electrodes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The electronic device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the control module energizes the determined electrode according to default stimulation options.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A method for providing tactile stimulation applied in an electronic device, the electronic device comprising a touch-sensitive screen and a tactile stimulation multilayer connected to the touch-sensitive screen, the tactile stimulation multilayer comprising a plurality of electrodes, the method comprising:
<claim-text>providing a first user interface on the touch-sensitive screen for a user to select one model for massage, and providing a second user interface for the user to select at least one acupuncture point of the selected model;</claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying the selected model and the selected acupuncture point of the selected model according to a first position relationship between at least one model of a human body part and acupuncture points of each model;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining whether the displayed model is touched by a body member according to signals from the touch-sensitive screen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining an outline of the body member touching the displayed model if the displayed model is touched, and determining whether the determined outline of the body member is the same type as in the displayed model;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining any difference between the determined outline and the displayed model if the determined outline of the body member is the same type as in the displayed model, and adjusting a position of the selected acupuncture point according to the difference; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining at least one electrode corresponding to the adjusted position of the selected acupuncture point according to a second position relationship between a plurality of positions of the touch-sensitive screen and the electrodes and energizing the determined electrodes.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the step determining at least one electrode corresponding to the adjusted position of the selected acupuncture point according to a second position relationship between a plurality of positions of the touch-sensitive screen and the electrodes and energizing the determined electrodes further comprises:
<claim-text>providing a third user interface on the touch-sensitive screen for the user to select stimulation options for energizing the determined electrode; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining at least one electrode corresponding to the adjusted position of the selected acupuncture point according to a second position relationship between a plurality of positions of the touch-sensitive screen and the electrodes and energizing the determined electrode via the power supply unit according to the selected stimulation options.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein, wherein the stimulation options comprise a strength of the stimulation, a total number of the stimulations, and a time interval between each two adjacent stimulations.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein different strength of the stimulation is realized by altering an amplitude or wave frequency of electrical current energizing the electrodes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A non-transitory storage medium storing a plurality of modules, the plurality of modules comprising instructions executable by a processor of an electronic device to perform a method for providing tactile stimulation, the electronic device comprising a touch-sensitive screen and a tactile stimulation multilayer connected to the touch-sensitive screen, the tactile stimulation multilayer comprising a plurality of electrodes, the method comprising:
<claim-text>providing a first user interface on the touch-sensitive screen for a user to select one model for massage, and providing a second user interface for the user to select at least one acupuncture point of the selected model;</claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying the selected model and the selected acupuncture point of the selected model according to a first position relationship between at least one model of a human body part and acupuncture points of each model;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining whether the displayed model is touched by a body member according to signals from the touch-sensitive screen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining an outline of the body member touching the displayed model if the displayed model is touched, and determining whether the determined outline of the body member is the same type as in the displayed model;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining any difference between the determined outline and the displayed model if the determined outline of the body member is the same type as in the displayed model, and adjusting a position of the selected acupuncture point according to the difference; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining at least one electrode corresponding to the adjusted position of the selected acupuncture point according to a second position relationship between a plurality of positions of the touch-sensitive screen and the electrodes and energizing the determined electrodes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
