<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624671-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624671</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13313273</doc-number>
<date>20111207</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2010 1 0624729</doc-number>
<date>20101229</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>50</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>45</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>330253</main-classification>
<further-classification>330252</further-classification>
<further-classification>330257</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Audio amplifying circuit with improved noise performance</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7671674</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Freeke</name>
<date>20100300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>330 69</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>21</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>330252-261</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120169421</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120705</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Zhong</last-name>
<first-name>GuoHua</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Li</last-name>
<first-name>XiangSheng</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Zhong</last-name>
<first-name>GuoHua</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Li</last-name>
<first-name>XiangSheng</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Gardere Wynne Sewell LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>STMicroelectronics (Shenzhen) R&#x26;D Co. Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Nguyen</last-name>
<first-name>Hieu</first-name>
<department>2817</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An amplifying circuit includes a first circuit component configured to receive and amplify first and second input voltages to generate an output voltage. The first circuit component is formed by a first amplifier and a second amplifier. A second circuit component is configured to provide a first offset current that is associated with a first input current of the first amplifier. The first offset current compensates for variation in the first input current. A third circuit component is configured to provide a second offset current that is associated with a second input current of the second amplifier. The second offset current compensates for variation in the second input current.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="115.82mm" wi="132.16mm" file="US08624671-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="234.36mm" wi="171.79mm" file="US08624671-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="215.48mm" wi="159.26mm" file="US08624671-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="231.39mm" wi="167.47mm" file="US08624671-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="229.11mm" wi="174.16mm" file="US08624671-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">PRIORITY CLAIM</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority from Chinese Application for Patent No. 201010624729.8 filed Dec. 29, 2010, the disclosure of which is hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This invention relates generally to electronic circuits, and more particularly to an amplifying circuit used in audio systems.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Many audio amplifying circuits may generate an audible sound when operation state of the audio amplifying circuits transfers from play to mute or from mute to play. The main reason for this is that input currents at input nodes of the audio amplifying circuits do not match with each other, which introduces a voltage difference into the circuit. Typically, this sound is audible as a popping sound. As this popping sound is a disturbance to users, it would be desirable to eliminate or at least reduce this popping noise.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows an audio amplifying circuit incorporating popping noise countermeasure. The amplifying circuit comprises a first operational amplifier <b>11</b> and a second operational amplifier <b>12</b>, which together serve as a differential amplifying circuit. A non-inverting input node <b>41</b> of the first amplifier <b>11</b> is coupled to a first terminal <b>51</b> via a first capacitor <b>13</b>. A non-inverting input node <b>42</b> of the second amplifier <b>12</b> is coupled to a second terminal <b>52</b>, and a second capacitor <b>14</b> is coupled between the second terminal <b>52</b> and ground. The first terminal <b>51</b> is configured to receive audio signals while the second terminal <b>52</b> is configured as an AC ground relative to the audio signals received at the first terminal <b>51</b>. A first output node <b>45</b> of the first amplifier <b>11</b> is coupled to an inverting input <b>43</b> of the first amplifier <b>11</b> via a first resistor <b>15</b>. A second output node <b>46</b> of the second amplifier <b>12</b> is coupled to an inverting input <b>44</b> of the second amplifier <b>12</b> via a second resistor <b>16</b>. The output nodes <b>45</b> and <b>46</b> of the amplifiers <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> are coupled across a load <b>17</b>, typically a loudspeaker able to give out sounds according to the current flowing therethrough. A third resistor <b>18</b> and a fourth resistor <b>19</b> coupled in series are interposed between the inverting inputs <b>43</b>, <b>44</b> of the first and second amplifiers <b>11</b>, <b>12</b>. The common node of the third resistor <b>18</b> and the fourth resistor <b>19</b> is coupled to ground via a fifth resistor <b>20</b> and a third capacitor <b>21</b> coupled in series. The series-coupled fifth resistor <b>20</b> and third capacitor <b>21</b> have the function of filtering noise and adjusting frequency response of the amplifying circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The amplifying circuit further comprises a reference circuit component providing a reference voltage to the non-inverting input <b>41</b>, <b>42</b> of the amplifiers <b>11</b>, <b>12</b>. The reference circuit component comprises a sixth resistor <b>22</b>, a seventh resistor <b>23</b>, an eighth resistor <b>24</b>, a fourth capacitor <b>25</b>, a ninth resistor <b>26</b> and a tenth resistor <b>27</b>. The sixth resistor <b>22</b> and the seventh resistor <b>23</b> forming a divider are series-coupled between a supply power VCC and ground, which set the voltage at node <b>53</b> to a reference voltage. For example, the reference voltage may be chosen to be equal to VCC/2 and the values of resistor <b>22</b>, <b>23</b> are then set to a same value. The common node of the resistors <b>22</b> and <b>23</b>, that is, the node <b>53</b>, is coupled to a first node of the eighth resistor <b>24</b>, and the other node of the eighth resistor <b>24</b> serves as a reference node <b>54</b>, which is coupled to ground via the fourth capacitor <b>25</b>. The fourth capacitor <b>25</b> has the function of rejecting power noise from the supply power VCC. The reference node <b>54</b> is coupled to the non-inverting input node <b>41</b> of the first amplifier <b>11</b> via the ninth resistor <b>26</b>, and coupled to the non-inverting input node <b>42</b> of the second amplifier <b>12</b> via the tenth resistor <b>27</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The amplifying circuit is such designed to reduce the popping noise. Usually, audio circuits are fit to more than one channel, for example 2 or 4 channels, in the purpose of reproducing sounds more vividly and accurately. Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the amplifying circuit is fit to a four-channel audio amplifier. As a result, it is required that a second input current I<sub>in2 </sub>flowing from the input node <b>42</b> into the second capacitor <b>14</b> should be four times bigger than a first input current I<sub>in1 </sub>flowing from the input node <b>41</b> into the first capacitor <b>13</b>. As is known, when there are no signals received at the input nodes <b>41</b> and <b>42</b>, there should be no voltage difference between these two nodes. Therefore, the ratio of the capacitors <b>13</b> and <b>14</b> should be four in accordance with the ratio of the input currents and I<sub>in1 </sub>and I<sub>in2</sub>. At the same time, in order to achieve the requirement of current matching, the ninth resistor <b>26</b> and the tenth resistor <b>27</b> that are separately coupled to the non-inverting inputs should be set in accordance with the currents flowing therethrough. That is, the value of the ninth resistor <b>26</b> should be four times bigger than that of the tenth resistor <b>27</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">However, it is difficult to assure the first and second capacitors <b>13</b>, <b>14</b> to satisfy the requirement. Mismatch between the first and second capacitors <b>13</b>, <b>14</b> frequently happens. The mismatch between capacitors <b>13</b> and <b>14</b> may significantly influence the normal operation of the amplifying circuit, and the popping noise cannot be fully eliminated, especially when the supply power fluctuates greatly, for example, the output of supply power in a car changes a lot when the car is starting.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows the evolution of voltages along time at given points of the amplifying circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, when there is a big pulse from the supply power. Curve Vs shows the variation of the supply voltage along time. Curve V<sub>in1 </sub>shows the variation of the voltage at the input node <b>41</b> along time. Curve V<sub>in2 </sub>shows the variation of the voltage at the input node <b>42</b> along time. The settle time, that is, the rise or fall time of the voltage at the input node <b>41</b> is mainly determined by the values of the capacitor <b>13</b> and the input current I<sub>in1</sub>, and the settle time of the voltage at the input node <b>42</b> is determined by the values of the capacitor <b>14</b> and the input current I<sub>in2</sub>. However, the ratio of the capacitors does not always accord with the ratio of the input currents flowing into the capacitors, which leads to different settle times for input nodes <b>41</b>, <b>42</b>, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, curve V<sub>in1</sub>&#x2212;V<sub>in2 </sub>shows the voltage difference between voltages at the input nodes <b>41</b> and <b>42</b>. Further, the voltage difference is reflected on the load <b>17</b>, multiplied by the amplifying gain of the amplifying circuit. Due to a high amplifying gain, the voltage applied to the load <b>17</b> is often sufficient to cause a characteristic audible and unpleasant noise.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Moreover, the device mismatch between the first capacitor <b>13</b> and the second capacitor <b>14</b> can also introduce electromagnetic noise such as global system for mobile communication (GSM) noise into the amplifying circuit, which is amplified to a bigger noise by the subsequent amplifiers <b>11</b> and <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Thus, there is a need for improving the noise performance of the audio amplifying circuit.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In one embodiment, an amplifying circuit comprises a first circuit component configured to receive and amplify a first input voltage and a second input voltage and to generate an output voltage, wherein the first circuit component comprises a first amplifier and a second amplifier; a second circuit component configured to provide a first offset current associated with a first input current of the first amplifier to compensate for variation in the first input current; and a third circuit component configured to provide a second offset current associated with a second input current of the second amplifier to compensate for variation in the second input current.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to an embodiment, the first offset current is substantially equal to the first input current and the second offset current is substantially equal to the second input current.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to an embodiment, the second circuit component comprises a first current mirror configured to mirror the first input current, and the third circuit component comprises a second current mirror configured to mirror the second input current.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">According to an embodiment, the first amplifier comprises a first pair of bipolar transistors serving as an input stage, which is biased by a first MOS transistor configured to provide a first reference current, and the first current mirror comprises a first bipolar transistor, a second MOS transistor, a third MOS transistor, and a fourth MOS transistor, wherein the second MOS transistor is configured to provide a second reference current, the source of the second MOS transistor is coupled to an emitter of the first bipolar transistor, the collector of the first bipolar transistor is coupled to a first supply node with a source of the third MOS transistor and a source of the fourth MOS transistor, a base of the first bipolar transistor is coupled to a drain and gate of the third MOS transistor and a gate of the fourth MOS transistor, and a drain of the fourth MOS transistor is coupled to the first input node; and the second current mirror has the a structure as the first current mirror.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The foregoing has outlined, rather broadly, features of the present disclosure. Additional features of the disclosure will be described, hereinafter, which form the subject of the claims of the invention. It will be appreciated by those skilled in the art that the conception and specific embodiment disclosed may be readily utilized as a basis for modifying or designing other structures or processes for carrying out the same purposes of the present invention. It will also be realized by those skilled in the art that such equivalent constructions do not depart from the spirit and scope of the invention as set forth in the appended claims.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">For a more complete understanding of the present disclosure, and the advantages thereof, reference is now made to the following descriptions taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows an audio amplifying circuit;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref> show the evolution of voltages along time at given points of the audio amplifying circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows an amplifying circuit according to an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows an example of architecture of an amplifying circuit according to another embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows a simulation result of PSRR performance according to the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows the evolution of voltages along time at given points of the amplifying circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> when power supply fluctuates;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> shows the evolution of voltages along time at given points of the amplifying circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> when power supply fluctuates;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> shows a detailed schematic of the first amplifier and the second circuit component of the amplifying circuit in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Corresponding numerals and symbols in different Figures generally refer to corresponding parts unless otherwise indicated. The Figures are drawn to clearly illustrate the relevant aspects of embodiments of the present disclosure and are not necessarily drawn to scale. To more clearly illustrate certain embodiments, a letter indicating variations of the same structure, material, or process step may follow a Figure number.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The making and using of embodiments are discussed in detail below. It should be appreciated, however, that the present invention provides many applicable inventive concepts that may be embodied in a wide variety of specific contexts. The specific embodiments discussed are merely illustrative of specific ways to make and use the invention, and do not limit the scope of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows an amplifying circuit according to an embodiment. In the embodiment, the amplifying circuit is used for amplifying signals such as audio signals, and the amplifying circuit is supplied by power source such as car batteries. In some other embodiments, the amplifying circuit can be used in conditions such as television sets, mobile phones or other electronic products and supplied by correspondent power sources.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the amplifying circuit according to the embodiment comprises a first circuit component <b>101</b> configured to receive and amplify a first input voltage and a second input voltage and to generate an output voltage, wherein the first circuit component <b>101</b> comprises a first amplifier <b>111</b> and a second amplifier <b>112</b>. In the embodiment, the first amplifier <b>111</b> and the second amplifier <b>112</b> are operational amplifiers with two input nodes respectively, that is, non-inverting input node and inverting input node of operational amplifiers. The two operational amplifiers of the first circuit component <b>101</b> are bridge-connected and serve as a differential amplifying circuit to amplify a voltage difference between the first input voltage received by the first amplifier <b>111</b> and the second input voltage received by the second amplifier <b>112</b>. Thus, the output voltage generated by the first circuit component <b>101</b> is given by the voltage difference and a gain of the differential amplifying circuit, which will be further described in the following paragraphs.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The amplifying circuit further comprises a second circuit component <b>102</b> configured to provide a first offset current I<sub>os1 </sub>associated with a first input current I<sub>in1 </sub>of the first amplifier <b>111</b> to compensate for variation in the first input current I<sub>in1</sub>; and a third circuit component <b>103</b> configured to provide a second offset current I<sub>os2 </sub>associated with a second input current I<sub>in2 </sub>of the second amplifier to compensate for variation in the second input current I<sub>in2</sub>. In an embodiment, the first input current I<sub>in1 </sub>is the current flowing into one of the input nodes of the first amplifier <b>111</b> and the second input current I<sub>in2 </sub>is the current flowing into one of the input nodes of the second amplifier <b>112</b>. Since the offset currents are associated with the input currents, that is, the offset currents changes with the input current respectively, for example, the offset current is proportional to the input currents, and the variation in the input currents is compensated and will not flow into coupling capacitors or input capacitors coupled to the input nodes. Thus, there will exist null or at least reduced voltage difference when no input signals have been received. In a preferred embodiment, the first offset current I<sub>os1 </sub>is substantially equal to the first input current I<sub>in1 </sub>and the second offset current I<sub>os2 </sub>is substantially equal to the second input current I<sub>in2</sub>, and therefore the variation in the input current can be fully compensated by the offset currents respectively. For amplifiers in the first circuit component, the variation in the input currents could be induced by the fluctuation of supply powers, and then the amplifying circuit has a better power supply rejection ratio (PSRR) performance than the amplifying circuit in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows an example of architecture of an amplifying circuit according to another embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the amplifying circuit comprises a circuit component comprising a first amplifier <b>111</b> having a first input node <b>141</b>, a third input node <b>143</b> and a first output node <b>145</b>, and a second amplifier <b>112</b> having a second input node <b>142</b>, a fourth input node <b>144</b> and a second output node <b>146</b>. In the embodiment, the first input node <b>141</b> and the second input node <b>142</b> are non-inverting input nodes of the amplifiers, and the third input node <b>143</b> and the fourth input node <b>144</b> are inverting input nodes of the amplifiers. As mentioned in the preceding paragraphs, the first amplifier <b>111</b> receives a first input voltage and a first input current at the first input node <b>141</b>, and the second amplifier <b>112</b> receives the second input voltage and the second input current at the second input node <b>142</b>. The third input node <b>143</b> is coupled to the first output node <b>145</b> via a first resistor <b>114</b>, the fourth input node <b>144</b> is coupled to the second output node <b>146</b> via a second resistor <b>116</b>, and the third input node <b>143</b> is coupled to the fourth input node <b>144</b> via an impedance component <b>107</b>. The first circuit component is such configured as a differential amplifying circuit, and then the amplifying circuit generates the output voltage between the first and second output nodes <b>145</b>, <b>146</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In a preferred embodiment, the first circuit component further comprises a load <b>117</b> coupled between the first and second output nodes <b>145</b>, <b>146</b>, typically a loudspeaker able to give out sounds according to the current flowing therethrough. The expression of the output voltage V<sub>out </sub>across the load <b>117</b> is given by the following equation:
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>V</i><sub>out</sub><i>=V</i><sub>o1</sub><i>&#x2212;V</i><sub>o2</sub>=(<i>R</i><sub>1</sub><i>+R</i><sub>2</sub><i>+Z</i>)/<i>Z</i>&#xd7;(<i>V</i><sub>in1</sub><i>&#x2212;V</i><sub>in2</sub>)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Where R<sub>1 </sub>and R<sub>2 </sub>are the respective values of resistor <b>114</b> and <b>116</b>, and Z is the impedance of the impedance component <b>107</b>, and V<sub>o1</sub>, V<sub>o2</sub>, V<sub>in1 </sub>and V<sub>in2 </sub>are the voltages at the output nodes <b>145</b>, <b>146</b> and the input nodes <b>141</b>, <b>142</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The impedance component <b>107</b> can comprise resistors and/or capacitors. In an embodiment, the impedance component <b>107</b> comprises a resistor with its two nodes coupled to the third input node <b>143</b> and the fourth input node <b>144</b> respectively. In another embodiment, the impedance component <b>107</b> comprises a fourth resistor <b>118</b>, a fifth resistor <b>119</b>, a sixth resistor <b>120</b> and a first capacitor <b>121</b>, wherein the fourth and fifth resistors <b>118</b>, <b>119</b> are coupled in series between the third and fourth input nodes <b>143</b>, <b>144</b>, and a common node of the fourth and fifth resistor <b>118</b>, <b>119</b> is coupled to a first supply node via the series coupled sixth resistor <b>120</b> and first capacitor <b>121</b>. The first supply node can be ground or a negative power supply node. The series-coupled sixth resistor <b>120</b> and first capacitor <b>121</b> have the function of filtering noise and adjusting frequency response of the amplifying circuit. It should be understood that the schematic of the first circuit component is merely an example, any circuit serving as an amplifying circuit with two input nodes is within the scope of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The amplifying circuit in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> further comprises another circuit component configured to provide a reference voltage to the first circuit component. This circuit component comprises a divider <b>105</b> having a seventh resistor <b>122</b> and an eighth resistor <b>123</b> coupled in series between a second supply node and the first supply node. The second supply node can be a positive power supply node. The common node of the seventh resistor <b>122</b> and the eighth resistor <b>123</b> provides the reference voltage via a ninth resistor <b>126</b> to the first amplifier <b>111</b> and to the second amplifier <b>112</b> via a tenth resistor <b>127</b>, which sets the input nodes of the first circuit component in normal operation. In a specific embodiment, the ninth resistor <b>126</b> has a same resistance as the tenth resistor <b>127</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In a preferred embodiment, another circuit component comprises a low-pass filter <b>106</b>, which is configured to filter high frequency noise in the reference voltage before supplying the reference voltage to the first circuit component. Optionally, the low-pass filter <b>106</b> comprises an eleventh resistor <b>124</b> and a fourth capacitor <b>125</b>, and the fourth capacitor <b>125</b> can be coupled to the first supply node.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">According to the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the amplifying circuit further comprises a second capacitor <b>113</b> and a third capacitor <b>114</b>. A first node of the second capacitor <b>113</b> is coupled to the first input node <b>141</b> and the other node of the second capacitor <b>113</b> is configured to receive the first input voltage V<sub>in1</sub>, and therefore the second capacitor <b>113</b> serves as a coupling capacitor to filter low frequency noise in the first input voltage V<sub>in1</sub>. A first node of the third capacitor <b>114</b> is coupled to the second input node <b>142</b> and the other node of the third capacitor <b>114</b> is coupled to the first supply node, and therefore the third capacitor <b>114</b> severs as a coupling capacitor configured to filter high frequency noise in the second input voltage V<sub>in2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">As mentioned in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the second circuit component <b>102</b> and the third circuit component <b>103</b> are configured to compensate for variations in the input currents at the input nodes <b>141</b>, <b>142</b>, respectively. According to the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the second circuit component comprises a first current mirror <b>130</b> configured to mirror the first input current I<sub>in1</sub>, and the third circuit component comprises a second current mirror <b>131</b> configured to mirror the second input current I<sub>in2</sub>. Since the input currents are fully mirrored, the input currents can be fully drawn into the first supply node by the respective current mirrors, and no input currents will flow into the coupling capacitors <b>113</b> and <b>114</b>. As a result, when the input voltages includes no alternating components, that is, no signals such as audio signal are being received, the voltage applied on the capacitors <b>113</b> and <b>114</b> will not change and then the input mismatch is fully compensated.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows a simulation result of PSRR performance according to the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. The curve PSRR<sub>1 </sub>shows the PSRR performance along frequency of the amplifying circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, and the curve PSRR<sub>2 </sub>shows the PSRR performance along frequency of the amplifying circuit according to the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. Compared with the conventional amplifying circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the amplifying circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> has a better noise rejection at low frequencies. Since the bandwidth of audio signals is generally around 20 kHz and the noise existed in power supplies concentrates at low frequencies, the amplifying circuit in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> has a better PSRR performance.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</figref> show the evolution of voltages along time at given points of the amplifying circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 5</figref> when power supply fluctuates. Curve V<sub>con </sub>shows the variation of the output voltage across the load <b>17</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, and curve V<sub>pre </sub>shows the variation of the output voltage across the load <b>117</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. The variation of output voltage is produced by the operation state of the circuits transferring from mute to play or reversely. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the output voltage across the load <b>117</b> according to the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> changes little compared with the conventional amplifying circuit in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, and therefore the sound given out by the load can be ignored.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, in an optional embodiment, the capacitors <b>113</b> and <b>114</b> can have a same capacitance. As a result, an electromagnetic noise, for example, a GSM noise coupled by the capacitors <b>113</b>, <b>114</b> applies a same voltage to the input nodes <b>141</b>, <b>142</b>, therefore the voltage difference between the two input nodes is quite small and will not generate a measurable output voltage across the load <b>117</b>. This configuration further improves the noise performance of the amplifying circuit according to the embodiment when electromagnetic noise occurs.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> shows a detailed schematic of the first amplifier and the second circuit component of the amplifying circuit in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. The schematic structure of the second amplifier and the third circuit component can be the same as the first amplifier and the second circuit component.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the first amplifier comprises a first pair of bipolar transistors <b>166</b>, <b>167</b> serving as an input stage, which is biased by a first reference current I<sub>ref1 </sub>provided by a first MOS transistor <b>161</b>. In an embodiment, a gate of first MOS transistor <b>161</b> is coupled to a gate of a fifth MOS transistor <b>168</b>, and the gate and source of the fifth MOS transistor <b>168</b> is coupled to a first current source <b>170</b>. The first MOS transistor <b>161</b> and the fifth MOS transistor <b>168</b> is such configured as a current mirror. When the amplifying circuit is working, the first current source <b>170</b> generates a constant current I<sub>cc </sub>which flows through the fifth MOS transistor <b>168</b>, and then the first reference current I<sub>ref1 </sub>associated with the constant current I<sub>cc </sub>will be generated by the current mirror. The expression of the first reference current I<sub>ref1 </sub>is given by the following equation:</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">
<maths id="MATH-US-00001" num="00001">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <msub>
    <mi>I</mi>
    <mrow>
      <mi>ref</mi>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <mn>1</mn>
    </mrow>
  </msub>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mrow>
    <mfrac>
      <msub>
        <mrow>
          <mo>(</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mi>W</mi>
            <mo>/</mo>
            <mi>L</mi>
          </mrow>
          <mo>)</mo>
        </mrow>
        <mn>1</mn>
      </msub>
      <msub>
        <mrow>
          <mo>(</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mi>W</mi>
            <mo>/</mo>
            <mi>L</mi>
          </mrow>
          <mo>)</mo>
        </mrow>
        <mn>5</mn>
      </msub>
    </mfrac>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <msub>
      <mi>I</mi>
      <mi>cc</mi>
    </msub>
  </mrow>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Where (W/L)<sub>1 </sub>is the ratio of the width and length of the first MOS transistor <b>161</b>, and (W/L)<sub>5 </sub>is the ratio of the width and length of the fifth MOS transistor <b>168</b>. The first reference current I<sub>ref1 </sub>is further supplied to the bipolar transistors <b>166</b>, <b>167</b>. Accordingly, the input currents of the first amplifier is given by the following equation:
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>I</i><sub>in1</sub><i>=I</i><sub>ref1</sub>/2&#x3b2;<sub>6,7 </sub><?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Where &#x3b2;<sub>6,7 </sub>is the ratio of the current flowing through the collector of bipolar transistors <b>166</b>, <b>167</b> and the current flowing through the base of the bipolar transistors <b>166</b>, <b>167</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">On the other hand, the first current mirror of the second circuit component comprises a first bipolar transistor <b>165</b>, a second MOS transistor <b>162</b>, a third MOS transistor <b>163</b>, and a fourth MOS transistor <b>164</b>, wherein the second MOS transistor <b>162</b> is configured to provide a second reference current I<sub>ref2 </sub>associated with a constant current. In a preferred embodiment, the second reference current I<sub>ref2 </sub>can be generated from the same current source I<sub>cc</sub>, and then the expression of the second current I<sub>ref2 </sub>is given by the following equation:</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">
<maths id="MATH-US-00002" num="00002">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <msub>
    <mi>I</mi>
    <mrow>
      <mi>ref</mi>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <mn>2</mn>
    </mrow>
  </msub>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mrow>
    <mfrac>
      <msub>
        <mrow>
          <mo>(</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mi>W</mi>
            <mo>/</mo>
            <mi>L</mi>
          </mrow>
          <mo>)</mo>
        </mrow>
        <mn>1</mn>
      </msub>
      <msub>
        <mrow>
          <mo>(</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mi>W</mi>
            <mo>/</mo>
            <mi>L</mi>
          </mrow>
          <mo>)</mo>
        </mrow>
        <mn>2</mn>
      </msub>
    </mfrac>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <msub>
      <mi>I</mi>
      <mi>cc</mi>
    </msub>
  </mrow>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Where (W/L)<sub>2 </sub>is the ratio of the width and length of the second MOS transistor <b>162</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In order to generate the first offset current I<sub>os1 </sub>associated with the first input current I<sub>in1</sub>, especially a substantially equal offset current, the source of the second MOS transistor <b>162</b> is coupled to an emitter of the first bipolar transistor <b>165</b>, the collector of the first bipolar transistor <b>165</b> is coupled to a first supply node with a source of the third MOS transistor <b>163</b> and a source of the fourth MOS transistor <b>164</b>, a base of the first bipolar transistor <b>165</b> is coupled to a drain and gate of the third MOS transistor <b>163</b> and a gate of the fourth MOS transistor <b>164</b>, and a drain of the fourth MOS transistor <b>164</b> is coupled to the first input node <b>141</b>. As a result, the expression of the first offset current I<sub>os1 </sub>is given by the following equation:
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>I</i><sub>os1</sub><i>=I</i><sub>ref2</sub>/&#x3b2;<sub>5 </sub><?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Where &#x3b2;<sub>5 </sub>is the ratio of the current flowing through the collector of bipolar transistors <b>165</b> and the current flowing through the base of the bipolar transistor <b>165</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In a preferred embodiment, the second reference current I<sub>ref2 </sub>can be half of the first reference current I<sub>ref1</sub>, for example, (W/L)<sub>2 </sub>of the second MOS transistor <b>162</b> can be half of (W/L)<sub>1 </sub>of the first MOS transistor <b>161</b>, and the first bipolar transistor <b>165</b> can be identical to each of the first pair of bipolar transistors <b>166</b>, <b>167</b> which lead to a same value for &#x3b2;<sub>5 </sub>and &#x3b2;<sub>6,7</sub>. It should be understood any combination of the W/L and &#x3b2; which makes the second reference current I<sub>ref2 </sub>half of the first reference current I<sub>ref1 </sub>is within the scope of the present invention. Therefore, the first offset current I<sub>os1 </sub>is substantially equal to the first input current I<sub>in1</sub>. When the first input current I<sub>in1 </sub>varies, the first offset current I<sub>os1 </sub>will changes accordingly, and then the first input current I<sub>in1 </sub>will not flow into the capacitor <b>113</b>. As a result, when the input voltage includes no alternating components, the first input voltage applied to the first input node will not change. Similarly, the second input voltage applied to the second input will not change as well, and therefore the input mismatch will be fully compensated.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In another embodiment, the amplifying circuit can be configured to amplify signals of different channels in audio systems. Therefore, the first circuit component can further comprise one or more amplifiers configured to receive one or more input voltages respectively, and the amplifying circuit generates one or more output voltages associated with voltage differences between the one or more input voltages and the second input voltage respectively. Accordingly, the amplifying circuit further comprises one or more circuit components configured to provide offset currents associated with input currents of the one or more amplifiers to compensate for variation in the input currents respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">It will also be readily understood by those skilled in the art that materials and methods may be varied while remaining within the scope of the present invention. It is also appreciated that the present invention provides many applicable inventive concepts other than the specific contexts used to illustrate embodiments. Accordingly, the appended claims are intended to include within their scope such processes, machines, manufacturing, compositions of matter, means, methods, or steps.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00001" nb-file="US08624671-20140107-M00001.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00001" he="6.69mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624671-20140107-M00001.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00002" nb-file="US08624671-20140107-M00002.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00002" he="6.69mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08624671-20140107-M00002.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An amplifying circuit, comprising:
<claim-text>a first circuit component configured to receive at first and second input nodes and amplify a first input voltage and a second input voltage, respectively, wherein the first circuit component comprises a first amplifier having a first input current at the first input node and a second amplifier having a second input current at the second input node;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second circuit component configured to provide a first offset current summed with the first input current at the first input node of the first amplifier to compensate for variation in the first input current; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third circuit component configured to provide a second offset current summed with the second input current at the second input node of the second amplifier to compensate for variation in the second input current;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first offset current is mirrored from a reference current of the first amplifier and the second offset current is mirrored from a reference current of the second amplifier.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The amplifying circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first input current has a different value from the second input current.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The amplifying circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising: a fourth circuit component configured to provide a reference voltage to the first circuit component.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. An amplifying circuit, comprising:
<claim-text>a first circuit component configured to receive at first and second input nodes and amplify a first input voltage and a second input voltage, respectively, wherein the first circuit component comprises a first amplifier having a first input current at the first input node and a second amplifier having a second input current at the second input node;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second circuit component configured to provide a first offset current summed with the first input current at the first input node of the first amplifier to compensate for variation in the first input current; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third circuit component configured to provide a second offset current summed with the second input current at the second input node of the second amplifier to compensate for variation in the second input current;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second circuit component comprises a first current mirror configured to mirror a first current in generating the first input current, and the third circuit component comprises a second current mirror configured to mirror a second current in generating the second input current.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The amplifying circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the first amplifier comprises a first pair of bipolar transistors serving as an input stage, which is biased by a first reference current provided by a first MOS transistor, and the first current mirror comprises a first bipolar transistor, a second MOS transistor, a third MOS transistor, and a fourth MOS transistor, wherein the second MOS transistor is configured to provide a second reference current, a source of the second MOS transistor is coupled to an emitter of the first bipolar transistor, the collector of the first bipolar transistor is coupled to a first supply node with a source of the third MOS transistor and a source of the fourth MOS transistor, a base of the first bipolar transistor is coupled to a drain and gate of the third MOS transistor and a gate of the fourth MOS transistor, and a drain of the fourth MOS transistor is coupled to a first input node configured to receive the first input voltage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The amplifying circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the second reference current is half of the first reference current, and the first bipolar transistor is identical to each of the first pair of bipolar transistors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The amplifying circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second reference currents are generated from a same current source.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. An amplifying circuit, comprising:
<claim-text>a first circuit component configured to receive at first and second input nodes and amplify a first input voltage and a second input voltage, respectively, wherein the first circuit component comprises a first amplifier having a first input current at the first input node and a second amplifier having a second input current at the second input node;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second circuit component configured to provide a first offset current summed with the first input current at the first input node of the first amplifier to compensate for variation in the first input current; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third circuit component configured to provide a second offset current summed with the second input current at the second input node of the second amplifier to compensate for variation in the second input current;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first amplifier has a first input node, a third input node and a first output node, and the second amplifier has a second input node, a fourth input node and a second output node, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first amplifier is configured to receive the first input voltage and the first input current at the first input node, the second amplifier is configured to receive the second input voltage and the second input current at the second input node; the third input node is coupled to the first output node via a first resistor, the fourth input node is coupled to the second output node via a second resistor, the third input node is coupled to the fourth input node via an impedance component, and the amplifying circuit generates an output voltage between the first and second output nodes.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The amplifying circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the impedance component comprises a resistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The amplifying circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the impedance component comprises a fourth resistor, a fifth resistor, a sixth resistor and a first capacitor, wherein the fourth and fifth resistors are coupled in series between the third and fourth input nodes, and a common node thereof is coupled to a first supply node via the series coupled sixth resistor and first capacitor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The amplifying circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising a load coupled between the first and second output nodes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. An amplifying circuit, comprising:
<claim-text>a first circuit component configured to receive at first and second input nodes and amplify a first input voltage and a second input voltage, respectively, wherein the first circuit component comprises a first amplifier having a first input current at the first input node and a second amplifier having a second input current at the second input node;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second circuit component configured to provide a first offset current summed with the first input current at the first input node of the first amplifier to compensate for variation in the first input current;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third circuit component configured to provide a second offset current summed with the second input current at the second input node of the second amplifier to compensate for variation in the second input current; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth circuit component configured to provide a reference voltage to the first circuit component;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the fourth circuit component comprises a divider having a seventh resistor and an eighth resistor coupled in series between a second supply node and the first supply node, the common node of the seventh and eighth resistors providing the reference voltage via a ninth resistor to the first amplifier and via a tenth resistor to the second amplifier.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The amplifying circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the fourth circuit component further comprises a low-pass filter configured to filter the reference voltage before supplying to the first circuit component.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The amplifying circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the ninth resistor has a same resistance as the tenth resistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. An amplifying circuit, comprising:
<claim-text>a first circuit component configured to receive at first and second input nodes and amplify a first input voltage and a second input voltage, respectively, wherein the first circuit component comprises a first amplifier having a first input current at the first input node and a second amplifier having a second input current at the second input node;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second circuit component configured to provide a first offset current summed with the first input current at the first input node of the first amplifier to compensate for variation in the first input current;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third circuit component configured to provide a second offset current summed with the second input current at the second input node of the second amplifier to compensate for variation in the second input current;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth circuit component configured to provide a reference voltage to the first circuit component; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second capacitor and a third capacitor, wherein a first node of the second capacitor is coupled to the first input node and a second node of the second capacitor is configured to receive the first input voltage; and a first node of the third capacitor is coupled to the second input node and a second node of the third capacitor is coupled to the first supply node.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the second capacitor and the third capacitor have a same capacitance.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. An amplifying circuit, comprising:
<claim-text>a pair of transistors coupled in a differential configuration;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first current source coupled to source a first reference current to the pair of transistors;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first current sink configured to sink an offset current from a control terminal of one transistor in said pair of transistors; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second current source coupled to source a second reference current,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first and second reference currents are mirrored currents derived from a third reference current; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the offset current is derived from the second reference current.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The amplifying circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the offset current is mirrored from the second reference current.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. An amplifying circuit, comprising:
<claim-text>a differential amplifier circuit component having a first input voltage node configured to receive an input voltage and a second input voltage node configured to receive a feedback signal and to an output voltage node, wherein said first input voltage node is further configured to receive a first input current; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an offset current generator configured to provide a first offset current that is sunk from said first input voltage node, wherein the first offset current is summed with said first input current at the first input voltage node to compensate for variation present in the first input current;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the offset current generator comprises a first current mirror configured to mirror a reference current of the differential amplifier circuit to generate the first offset current.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The amplifying circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the first current mirror is configured to generate the first offset current from a first reference current.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The amplifying circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, wherein the differential amplifier circuit is operable responsive to a second reference current, wherein the first and second reference currents are mirrored currents derived from a third reference current. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
