<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625388-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625388</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11640589</doc-number>
<date>20061218</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>1728</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>22</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>367 20</main-classification>
<further-classification>367153</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Voltage leakage detection for serially connected electrical nodes in a seismic surveying system</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4166270</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Brastins et al.</name>
<date>19790800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>367 13</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4503526</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Beauducel et al.</name>
<date>19850300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>367 20</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5117426</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>McAdams</name>
<date>19920500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>714721</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5883856</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Carroll et al.</name>
<date>19990300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>367 13</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7176589</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Rouquette</name>
<date>20070200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>307 17</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0233051</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Nemeth</name>
<date>20061000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>367 76</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0008041</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Pettersen et al.</name>
<date>20080100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>367 76</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>CA</country>
<doc-number>2593640</doc-number>
<date>20070600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
<classification-cpc-text>G01V 1/20</classification-cpc-text>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>CA</country>
<doc-number>2593103</doc-number>
<date>20070700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
<classification-cpc-text>G01V 1/20</classification-cpc-text>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00010">
<othercit>Specification, Claims, Abstract, Drawings for U.S. Appl. No. 11/640,786.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00011">
<othercit>Office Action mailed Dec. 3, 2008 for U.S. Appl. No. 11/640,786.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>26</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>367 20</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>367153</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>367154</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>367 13</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>11</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>60806622</doc-number>
<date>20060705</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080008030</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20080110</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Pettersen</last-name>
<first-name>Jostein Fonneland</first-name>
<address>
<city>Oslo</city>
<country>NO</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>NO</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Petithomme</last-name>
<first-name>Sylvain</first-name>
<address>
<city>Oslo</city>
<country>NO</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>NO</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Pettersen</last-name>
<first-name>Jostein Fonneland</first-name>
<address>
<city>Oslo</city>
<country>NO</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Petithomme</last-name>
<first-name>Sylvain</first-name>
<address>
<city>Oslo</city>
<country>NO</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>WesternGeco L.L.C.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Houston</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Lobo</last-name>
<first-name>Ian J</first-name>
<department>3645</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A seismic survey apparatus includes a plurality of serially connected electrical nodes; a power supply capable of supplying power to the electrical nodes and detecting a voltage leakage among the electrical nodes; and a software component capable of locating the leakage upon its detection. A method for use in seismic surveying includes powering a plurality of serially connected electrical nodes in a seismic surveying system; automatically detecting a voltage leakage among the electrical nodes on the power domain; and automatically locating the detected voltage leakage.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="58.93mm" wi="108.97mm" file="US08625388-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="229.45mm" wi="165.52mm" file="US08625388-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="227.67mm" wi="150.96mm" file="US08625388-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="222.76mm" wi="174.33mm" file="US08625388-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="225.21mm" wi="169.67mm" file="US08625388-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The current non-provisional patent application claims the priority of co-pending provisional patent application, attorney docket number 14.303-U.S.-PRO, Ser. No. 60/806,622, filed on Jul. 5, 2006 by the same inventors, with the same title.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention pertains to voltage leakage detection in seismic electrical systems and, more particularly, leakage detection seismic surveying systems comprising serially connected nodes.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Seismic surveying is a method for determining the structure of subterranean formations in the earth. Seismic surveying typically utilizes seismic energy sources which generate seismic waves and seismic receivers which detect seismic waves. The seismic waves propagate into the formations in the earth, where a portion of the waves reflects from interfaces between subterranean formations. The seismic receivers detect the reflected seismic waves and convert the reflected waves into representative electrical signals. The signals are typically transmitted by electrical, optical, radio or other means to devices which record the signals. Through analysis of the recorded signals (or traces), the shape, position and composition of the subterranean formations can be determined.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">One concern in a land-based seismic survey is &#x201c;earth leakage&#x201d;, a condition which may expose a person or animal to dangerous voltage levels. A seismic survey system is typically laid out with a series of units connected together by a seismic cable in between. Cables, connectors and units transferring or relaying electrical power in a seismic survey system are subject to earth leakage situations. There can be several hundred units in each power domain and <b>10</b>s of meters of cable between them, making the whole power domain span several kilometers. Thus, not only are there typically a very large number of places in which earth leakage might occur, but they usually are spread out over large distances. Locating and fixing an earth leakage condition can therefore be a time consuming and difficult task.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Seismic survey systems therefore usually provide for some kind of automatic detection of and protection from earth leakage. Conventional earth leakage detection/protection systems introduce a ground wire and force the output voltage to balance around earth. The current in the ground wire should nominally be close to, or at, zero. This current is monitored, and if it increases beyond a set limit, switches turn off the voltage to the whole power domain.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Conventional earth leakage detection and protection systems, although helpful and desirable, have several drawbacks. When an earth leakage occurs, the whole line of units in the affected power domain loses power. There is no way to automatically diagnose where along the line the earth leakage is located, meaning it will take a long time to find the faulty segment. Intermittent failures that come and go and failures of short duration are even harder to find unless the system is taken back to camp and tested in a water tank or similar apparatus. Thus, while such systems are suitable for their intended purpose, improvement in these respects would be desirable.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The present invention is directed to resolving, or at least reducing, one or all of the problems mentioned above.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The invention includes, in its various aspects and embodiments, a seismic surveying apparatus and a method for use in a seismic survey. The seismic survey apparatus includes a plurality of serially connected electrical nodes; a power supply capable of supplying power to the electrical nodes and detecting a voltage leakage among the electrical nodes; and a software component capable of locating the leakage upon its detection. The method for use in seismic surveying includes powering a plurality of serially connected electrical nodes in a seismic surveying system; automatically detecting a voltage leakage among the electrical nodes on the power domain; and automatically locating the detected voltage leakage.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The invention may be understood by reference to the following description taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, in which like reference numerals identify like elements, and in which:</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> depicts a portion of a seismic survey spread in which the present invention is applied;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> conceptually illustrates one of the seismic sensors positioned as in a setup for a seismic survey;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref> conceptually illustrate selected portions of a data collection unit as may be used to implement the power supply in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A-FIG</figref>. <b>4</b>B depict a leakage detection circuit as it may be used in the power supply of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> charts software-implemented technique used to locate a detected leakage in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> depicts a second portion of a seismic survey spread in which the present invention may be applied;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> charts software-implemented technique used to locate a detected leakage in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8-FIG</figref>. <b>9</b> illustrate a towed streamer and a seabed marine survey, respectively, in which the present invention may be employed.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">While the invention is susceptible to various modifications and alternative forms, the drawings illustrate specific embodiments herein described in detail by way of example. It should be understood, however, that the description herein of specific embodiments is not intended to limit the invention to the particular forms disclosed, but on the contrary, the intention is to cover all modifications, equivalents, and alternatives falling within the spirit and scope of the invention as defined by the appended claims.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Illustrative embodiments of the invention are described below. In the interest of clarity, not all features of an actual implementation are described in this specification. It will of course be appreciated that in the development of any such actual embodiment, numerous implementation-specific decisions must be made to achieve the developers' specific goals, such as compliance with system-related and business-related constraints, which will vary from one implementation to another. Moreover, it will be appreciated that such a development effort, even if complex and time-consuming, would be a routine undertaking for those of ordinary skill in the art having the benefit of this disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> depicts a portion <b>100</b> of a seismic survey spread (not otherwise shown) in which the present invention is applied. The portion <b>100</b> includes a power supply <b>103</b> and a power domain <b>106</b> receiving power from the power supply <b>103</b>. A seismic survey spread may, and typically will, comprise several power domains <b>106</b>. The power domain <b>106</b> encompasses a seismic cable <b>109</b> comprising a plurality of seismic sensors <b>112</b> (only one indicated) connected by line segments <b>115</b> (only one indicated). Each seismic sensor <b>112</b> represents a node within the power domain <b>106</b>. Each line segment <b>115</b>, in the illustrated embodiment, may include a connector <b>118</b> (only one indicated) on either end. The seismic sensors <b>112</b> are serially connected on the seismic cable <b>109</b>. The line segments <b>115</b> and connectors <b>118</b> may be implemented in conventional fashion. The particular implementation may vary depending on the context in which the particular embodiment is employed. For instance, in a seabed survey, electrical connections must be water tight at depth, which may not be true of a land-based survey.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> conceptually illustrates one of the seismic sensors <b>112</b> positioned on a surface <b>200</b> of the ground <b>203</b>. The seismic sensors <b>112</b> of the illustrated embodiment are built substantially the same, although the invention does not require this. The seismic sensor <b>112</b> generally comprises a sensing element <b>206</b> and a set of electronics <b>209</b> situated in a housing <b>212</b>. The housing <b>212</b> includes a spike <b>215</b> to help ensure good coupling between the sensing element <b>206</b> and the ground <b>203</b>. Note that the invention is not limited by the structure or design of the housing <b>212</b>. The sensing element <b>206</b> may be implemented in, for example, a conventional geophone as is common and well known in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The electronics <b>209</b> are conventional except for the inclusion of a power switch <b>218</b>. The power switch <b>218</b>, conceptually shown as a double pole, single throw switch. The power switch <b>218</b> is a double pole switch so that both the positive and negative terminal are disconnected in an earth leakage situation. The power switch <b>218</b> controls the flow of power from the power supply <b>103</b> to sensors <b>112</b> downstream, i.e., down the seismic cable <b>115</b> in the direction away from the power supply <b>103</b>. The invention admits variation in the implementation of the power switch <b>218</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The power supply <b>103</b> is an isolated power supply, i.e., isolated from the earth, loosely balanced around the earth, e.g., if the power supply <b>103</b> is a 100 V power supply, it will output &#xb1;50 V relative to the earth's potential. The power supply <b>103</b> is, in the illustrated embodiment, implemented in the data collection unit for the seismic survey. As those in the art will appreciate, a seismic survey typically includes a data collection unit that performs several functions. It sends command and control signals, for example, that control the operation of the components in the seismic survey system. The data collection unit provides power; receives data generated by the seismic sensors; and sometimes processes or pre-processes the data. In this embodiment, the data collection unit is used to provide power to the power domain <b>106</b>. However, in alternative embodiments, the power supply <b>103</b> might be implemented in, for example, a power supply that is not a part of the data collection unit.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref> illustrate selected portions of the hardware and software architecture of one particular embodiment of the power supply unit <b>103</b>. The power supply <b>103</b> includes a processor <b>305</b> communicating with storage <b>310</b> over a bus system <b>315</b>. The storage <b>310</b> may include a hard disk, a flash disk and/or random access memory (&#x201c;RAM&#x201d;) and/or removable storage such as a floppy magnetic disk <b>317</b> and an optical disk <b>320</b>. The storage <b>310</b> is encoded an interface application <b>311</b>, an application <b>312</b>, an operating system <b>313</b>, and some hardware drivers <b>314</b>. The processor <b>305</b> runs under the control of the operating system <b>313</b>, which may be practically any operating system known to the art. The application <b>312</b> is invoked by the operating system <b>313</b> upon power up, reset, or both, depending on the implementation of the operating system <b>313</b>. The power supply <b>103</b> communicates with a user interface <b>320</b> (e.g., a PC- or UNIX-based workstation) over a port <b>325</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The power supply <b>103</b> is equipped with a voltage leakage detection circuit <b>400</b>, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref>. The voltage leakage detection circuit <b>400</b> comprises a bridge <b>403</b> through which the supply voltage <b>406</b> is transmitted over the seismic cable <b>109</b> to the seismic sensors <b>112</b>, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The bridge <b>403</b> comprises four high impedance (for example, 1 M&#x3a9;) resistors <b>409</b>-<b>412</b> and is grounded to earth as shown. As long as there is no earth leakage, the bridge <b>403</b> is symmetrical and the error voltage V<sub>e </sub>is zero. The power supply <b>406</b> itself is free floating relative to earth potential, so the left resistor pair <b>409</b>, <b>410</b> divides the supply voltage <b>406</b> in two halves having opposite polarities seen from the earth reference. When one of the supply wires <b>415</b>, <b>416</b> touches conductive earth, an imbalance is introduced to the bridge <b>403</b>. In the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref>, the lower left bridge resistor <b>410</b> is paralleled by the leakage <b>415</b> when a leakage occurs, as is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">More particularly, assume the system in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is up and running with no earth leakage. Assume that there are n seismic sensors <b>112</b> on the seismic cable <b>109</b>, i.e., seismic sensors <b>112</b><sub>1</sub>-<b>112</b><sub>n</sub>. Since there is no earth leakage, the power supply <b>103</b> balances around the earth and the error voltage V<sub>e </sub>is close to 0. Then an earth leakage occurs somewhere along the power domain <b>106</b>. This means one terminal touches conductive earth or something with low resistivity to earth. As a result, an imbalance in the detection bridge <b>403</b> is generated as mentioned above, which gives an error voltage V<sub>e</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The error voltage V<sub>e </sub>triggers a software-implemented search <b>500</b>, illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, by the application <b>312</b>, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>. The power supply <b>103</b> sends a command (at <b>503</b>) to seismic sensor <b>112</b><sub>n&#x2212;1</sub>, telling it to open its power switch <b>218</b><sub>n&#x2212;1</sub>, thereby removing the relay of power to seismic sensor <b>112</b><sub>n</sub>. The command is sent in the form of an electronic command and control signal over the seismic cable <b>109</b>. Seismic sensor <b>112</b><sub>n </sub>is then without power. If the earth leakage goes away (at <b>506</b>) when the power switch <b>218</b><sub>n&#x2212;1 </sub>is opened, the earth leakage is located (at <b>509</b>) between seismic sensor <b>112</b><sub>n&#x2212;1 </sub>and seismic sensor <b>112</b><sub>n</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">If the error voltage V<sub>e </sub>persists after the power switch <b>218</b><sub>n&#x2212;1 </sub>is opened, then the earth leakage is not between the seismic sensors <b>112</b><sub>n&#x2212;1 </sub>and <b>112</b><sub>n</sub>. The power supply <b>103</b>, through the application <b>312</b>, then instructs (at <b>503</b>) the seismic sensor <b>112</b><sub>n-2 </sub>to open its power switch <b>218</b><sub>n-2</sub>. If the error voltage V<sub>e </sub>goes to 0 (at <b>506</b>), the earth leakage is located (at <b>509</b>) between seismic sensor <b>112</b><sub>n-2 </sub>and seismic sensor <b>112</b><sub>n&#x2212;1</sub>. If the error voltage V<sub>e </sub>persists, the power supply <b>103</b> iterates (at <b>512</b>) the process, walking its way back &#x201c;up&#x201d; the seismic cable <b>109</b> through each of the seismic sensors <b>112</b> until the earth leakage is located. The earth leakage is now located and must be changed before power can be re-applied to the seismic sensors <b>112</b> &#x201c;downstream&#x201d; from it. The seismic sensors <b>112</b> are &#x201c;downstream&#x201d; from the power supply <b>103</b> in the sense that power flows to them from the power supply <b>103</b>. (Similarly, the seismic sensor <b>122</b><sub>n </sub>is downstream from the seismic sensor <b>122</b><sub>n&#x2212;1 </sub>in the sense that power flows from the power supply <b>103</b> to the seismic sensor <b>122</b><sub>n </sub>through the seismic sensor <b>122</b><sub>n&#x2212;1</sub>.) Conversely, the power supply <b>103</b> is &#x201c;upstream&#x201d; from the seismic sensors <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">As previously mentioned, the invention admits variation in implementation. For instance, consider the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. A portion <b>600</b> of a seismic survey spread (not otherwise shown) in including two power supplies <b>103</b><sub>M</sub>, <b>103</b><sub>S </sub>one on either end of the seismic cable <b>109</b>. A leakage detection circuit <b>400</b>, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref>, is placed in both the power supplies <b>103</b>. In this particular embodiment, an error voltage V<sub>e </sub>detected in either power supply <b>103</b> triggers a software-implemented search <b>700</b>, illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, by the application <b>312</b>, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In this particular embodiment, the seismic sensors <b>112</b> are powered from two sides and a binary search is performed. One of the power supplies <b>103</b><sub>M </sub>is designated the &#x201c;master power supply.&#x201d; Assume again there are n seismic sensors <b>112</b><sub>1</sub>-<b>112</b><sub>n </sub>and there are n+1 line segments <b>115</b><sub>1</sub>-<b>115</b><sub>n+1</sub>. In the following discussion, to open switch i is to open the switch <b>218</b> in the seismic sensor <b>112</b> to the right of the line segment <b>115</b><sub>i</sub>. The master power supply <b>103</b><sub>M </sub>commands seismic sensor <b>112</b><sub>(n+1)/2</sub>, telling it to open its power switch <b>218</b><sub>(n+1)/2 </sub>(at <b>703</b>). (Note that if i is odd, such that it is not evenly divisible, the illustrated embodiment rounds down.) Since the system is powered from two sides, all seismic sensors <b>112</b> are still receiving power either from the left or the right side, but only one of the power supplies <b>103</b> will see the earth leakage now. It then follows that the earth leakage is located between the seismic sensor <b>112</b><sub>(n+1)/2 </sub>and the power supply <b>103</b> seeing the earth leakage.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The master power supply <b>103</b><sub>M </sub>tells seismic sensor <b>112</b><sub>(n+1)/2 </sub>to close (at <b>706</b>) its power switch <b>218</b><sub>(n+1)/2 </sub>again. The line segment <b>115</b> containing the earth leakage is again divided in two using a binary search. So, if the earth leakage occurred between the master power supply <b>103</b><sub>M </sub>and the seismic sensor <b>112</b><sub>(n+1)/2</sub>, then the master power supply <b>103</b><sub>M </sub>instructs the seismic sensor <b>112</b><sub>(n+1)/4 </sub>to open its power switch <b>218</b><sub>(n+1)/4</sub>. On the other hand, if the earth leakage is between the master power supply <b>103</b><sub>S </sub>and the seismic sensor <b>112</b><sub>(n+1)/2</sub>, the master power supply <b>103</b><sub>M </sub>tells the seismic sensor <b>112</b><sub>3n/4 </sub>to open its power switch <b>218</b><sub>(3n+1)/4</sub>. Again, all seismic sensors <b>112</b> receive power either from the left or the right side while only one of the power supplies <b>103</b> sees the earth leakage. The process iterates until the earth leakage is located and disconnected (at <b>709</b>). The line segment <b>115</b> on which the earth leakage is located is now unpowered. Operation will still be possible, even before the line segment <b>115</b> is changed. This way the operational impact of the earth leakage is minimal.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">More specifically, with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, If V<sub>eM</sub>&#x3e;0 or V<sub>eS</sub>&#x3e;0 (at <b>710</b>), then the indexes i,j are set (at <b>711</b>) such that i=(n+1)/2 and j=(n+1)/2. The switch i (rounding down if needed) is then opened (at <b>703</b>). If (at <b>712</b>) j is not &#x2266;0.5, then j=j/2 (at <b>713</b>). If (at <b>714</b>) V<sub>eM</sub>&#x3e;0, then i=i&#x2212;j (at <b>715</b>); otherwise, i=i+j (at <b>716</b>). The opened switch is then closed (at <b>706</b>) and the next switch i is then opened (at <b>703</b>) at the process iterates.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">If (at <b>712</b>) j&#x2266;0.5 and V<sub>eM</sub>=0 (at <b>717</b>), the voltage leakage is on the line segment <b>115</b> to the right of the seismic sensor <b>112</b><sub>i</sub>, otherwise it is on the line segment <b>115</b> to the left of the seismic sensor <b>112</b><sub>i</sub>. To disconnect the line segment <b>115</b> (at <b>718</b>) to the left, close switch i, open switch i&#x2212;1, close left switch in i. To disconnect the line segment <b>115</b> (at <b>719</b>) to the right, open (at <b>719</b>) the left switch in i+1. The line segment <b>115</b> with earth leakage is now disconnected (at <b>709</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Note that the invention admits variation in how the search is performed. For instance, the binary search described above for use in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> may be employed in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> instead of the linear search described. Any suitable searching technique known to the art may be employed. However, the binary search will generally be the fastest.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">An earth leakage detection system such as the earth leakage detection circuit <b>400</b> is employed even though the power supply is isolated from earth. For instance, in an earth leakage situation, there could be a current path from one terminal through the earth leakage, then from earth through a conductive element (e.g., a person) touching the other terminal. Two unrelated faults are needed to incur this potentially dangerous situation. Therefore the time to react to and remove the first fault is relaxed (e.g., a few seconds) compared to the conventional approach (e.g., 20-50 milliseconds).</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Furthermore, the locating functionality is in the application <b>312</b>, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, which executes the particular search strategy of a given implementation. Those in the art having the benefit of this disclosure will appreciate that this is not necessary to the practice of the invention. The searching functionality may, for instance, be executed a process or thread controlled by the operating system <b>313</b>, in alternative embodiments. Any suitable software component known to the art may also be used to implement the locating functionality.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Still further, the above discussion identifies the seismic sensors <b>112</b> as the serially connected electrical nodes. However, the invention is not so limited, and contemplates that other components of the seismic survey spread might also constitute electrical nodes within the meaning of the invention. For instance, the power supply <b>103</b> may constitute a serially connected electrical node in some embodiments. Some embodiments may also employ survey spreads with a higher degree of sophistication in data collection, e.g., a networked spread that employs packet messages and data routers. The data routers in such embodiments may also be serially connected electrical nodes.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The above embodiments in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> are both land based surveys. However, the invention is not so limited. Marine seismic surveys come in two basic types&#x2014;towed streamer surveys and seabed surveys. The invention may be employed in either type of marine survey. Both streamers and ocean bottom cables used in seabed surveys may be considered &#x201c;seismic cables&#x201d;, although some aspects of their structure, operation, and use differ from that of seismic cables used in land-based surveys in ways well known to the art. Consequently, matters of design, construction and operation not relevant to the present invention are not further discussed for the sake of clarity and so as not to obscure the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">More particularly, in towed streamer surveys, such as the survey <b>800</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, arrays <b>803</b> of seismic streamers <b>806</b> (only one indicated) containing seismic sensors <b>112</b><i>a </i>(only one indicated) are towed by a survey vessel <b>810</b> at or near the water's surface <b>809</b>. The sensing element (not shown) of the seismic sensors <b>112</b><i>a </i>may be, for example, hydrophones and the electronics (not shown) of each includes a power switch <b>218</b>, such as that shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. Power is supplied to the seismic sensors <b>112</b><i>a </i>from a data collection unit (not shown) on the vessel <b>810</b> through the tow cable <b>811</b> and the streamers <b>806</b>. In such a survey, each streamer <b>806</b> may, for example, constitute a separate power domain <b>106</b><i>a</i>, in which the electronics of the seismic sensors <b>112</b><i>a </i>comprise a plurality of serially connected nodes. The leak detection works as is described above for the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In seabed surveys such as that shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, ocean bottom cables (&#x201c;OBCs&#x201d;) <b>812</b> (only one indicated) are arrayed on the seabed <b>815</b> from the vessel <b>810</b> at the water's surface <b>809</b>. Each OBC <b>812</b> comprises a plurality of seismic sensors <b>112</b><i>b</i>. The sensing elements (not shown) of the seismic sensors <b>112</b><i>b </i>may be, for example, either hydrophones or geophones. The electronics (not shown) of each will include a power switch <b>218</b>, such as that shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. Each OBC <b>812</b> includes a power supply <b>103</b><i>a</i>, as well, which provides power to the seismic sensors <b>112</b><i>b </i>over the OBCs <b>812</b>. Each OBC <b>812</b> may define a power domain <b>106</b><i>b</i>, in which the electronics of the seismic sensors <b>112</b><i>b </i>comprises a plurality of serially connected nodes. The leak detection works as is described above for the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The present invention is therefore broader than detecting earth leakage in a land-based seismic survey. Accordingly, a seismic surveying apparatus, comprises a plurality of serially connected electrical nodes; a power supply capable of supplying power to the electrical nodes and detecting a voltage leakage among the electrical nodes; and a software component capable of locating the leakage upon its detection. In the method of the invention, a plurality of serially connected electrical nodes in a seismic surveying system is powered; a voltage leakage is automatically detected among the electrical nodes on the power domain; and the detected voltage leakage is automatically detected.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The present invention accordingly provides a voltage leakage detection in seismic electrical systems and, more particularly, voltage leakage detection for seismic electrical systems comprising serially connected nodes. The present invention, relative to conventional approaches:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0002-0001" num="0045">provides automatic location of the voltage leakage;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0002" num="0046">prevents disruption in operation in some embodiments (e.g., the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>); and</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0003" num="0047">intermittent failures can be reported without the need to shut down the line of units.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0048">Note that not all embodiments will manifest all of these advantages. Furthermore, those skilled in the art having the benefit of this disclosure may appreciate advantages not set forth above.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0049">This concludes the detailed description. The particular embodiments disclosed above are illustrative only, as the invention may be modified and practiced in different but equivalent manners apparent to those skilled in the art having the benefit of the teachings herein. Furthermore, no limitations are intended to the details of construction or design herein shown, other than as described in the claims below. It is therefore evident that the particular embodiments disclosed above may be altered or modified and all such variations are considered within the scope and spirit of the invention. Accordingly, the protection sought herein is as set forth in the claims below.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A seismic surveying apparatus, comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of serially connected electrical nodes;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a power supply capable of supplying power to the electrical nodes and detecting a voltage leakage among the electrical nodes; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a software component capable of locating the leakage upon its detection.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The seismic surveying apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the electrical nodes comprise at least one of seismic sensors, power supplies, and data routers.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The seismic surveying apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein power supply is one of the electrical nodes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The seismic surveying apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the electrical nodes include a power switch that may be opened upon instruction from the software component.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The seismic surveying apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the power supply includes a leakage detection circuit by which it detects the voltage leakage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The seismic surveying apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the leakage detection circuit comprises a bridge across which the leakage will induce an error voltage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The seismic surveying apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the power supply comprises a portion of the data collection unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The seismic surveying apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the software component resides on a storage of the data collection unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The seismic surveying apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the software component performs a linear search or a binary search for the voltage leakage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The seismic surveying apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a second power supply capable of supplying power to the electrical nodes and detecting the voltage leakage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A method for use in seismic surveying, comprising:
<claim-text>powering a plurality of serially connected electrical nodes in a seismic surveying system;</claim-text>
<claim-text>automatically detecting a voltage leakage among the electrical nodes on the power domain; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>automatically locating the detected voltage leakage.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein powering the electrical nodes includes powering the electrical nodes from a single side.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein powering the electrical nodes includes powering the electrical nodes from a both sides.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein powering the electrical nodes comprises powering at least one of seismic sensors, power supplies, and data routers.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein automatically detecting the voltage leakage includes automatically instructing the electrical nodes to open a respective power switch therefore.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein automatically detecting the voltage leakage includes automatically detecting an earth leakage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein automatically detecting the voltage leakage includes detecting an error voltage generated by the voltage leakage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein automatically locating the detected voltage leakage includes performing a linear search or a binary search.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. An apparatus for use in seismic surveying, comprising:
<claim-text>means for powering a plurality of serially connected electrical nodes in a seismic surveying system;</claim-text>
<claim-text>means for automatically detecting a voltage leakage among the electrical nodes on the power domain; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>means for automatically locating the detected voltage leakage.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the powering means includes means for powering the electrical nodes from a single side.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the powering means includes powering the electrical nodes from a both sides.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the powering means includes means for powering at least one of seismic sensors, power supplies, and data routers.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein automatic detection means leakage includes means for automatically instructing the electrical nodes to open a respective power switch therefore.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the automatic detection means includes means for automatically detecting an earth leakage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text>25. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the automatic detection means includes means for detecting an error voltage generated by the voltage leakage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text>26. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the automatic location means includes means for performing a linear search or a binary search. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
