<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626047-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626047</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13238676</doc-number>
<date>20110921</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-231515</doc-number>
<date>20101014</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>212</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>20</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>399329</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Fixing device for fixing developer to recording material and image forming apparatus equipped with the same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7546078</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Okuda et al.</name>
<date>20090600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>399329</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7890038</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Chikugo et al.</name>
<date>20110200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>399323</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2005-227463</doc-number>
<date>20050800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006-284874</doc-number>
<date>20061000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-204222</doc-number>
<date>20100900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>6</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>399329</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>399323</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120093549</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120419</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nakamura</last-name>
<first-name>Hirokazu</first-name>
<address>
<city>Osaka</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nakamura</last-name>
<first-name>Hirokazu</first-name>
<address>
<city>Osaka</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Renner, Otto, Boisselle &#x26; Sklar, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Sharp Kabushiki Kaisha</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Osaka</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Grainger</last-name>
<first-name>Quana M</first-name>
<department>2852</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A fixing device includes: a fixing belt in an endless form; a fixing roller; a separating roller for separating, from the fixing belt, a paper sheet onto which a developer is fixed and fused; a heating roller for heating the fixing belt; a pressurizing roller for forming a fixing nip portion between the fixing belt and the pressurizing roller; a first lever to which the fixing roller and the separating roller are fixed, the first lever pivoting around a first supporting point used as the center point; a second lever to which the fixing roller and the heating roller are fixed, the second lever pivoting around a second supporting point used as the center point; a first spring for biasing the first lever; and a second spring for biasing the second lever.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="120.31mm" wi="146.56mm" file="US08626047-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="185.50mm" wi="155.53mm" file="US08626047-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="243.92mm" wi="171.03mm" file="US08626047-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="183.39mm" wi="141.48mm" file="US08626047-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="107.02mm" wi="155.53mm" file="US08626047-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="192.53mm" wi="157.99mm" file="US08626047-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This Nonprovisional application claims priority under 35 U.S.C. &#xa7;119(a) on Patent Application No. 2010-231515 filed in Japan on Oct. 14, 2010, the entire contents of which are hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a fixing device for fixing a developer to a recording material and also relates to an image forming apparatus provided with such a fixing device.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">An electrophotographic image forming apparatus includes a fixing device so as to fix and fuse a toner image transferred onto a sheet. In a conventional fixing device, a pressurizing roller is usually brought into pressure contact with a heating roller.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Recently, individual parts in image forming apparatuses have been improved to meet the needs of speeding up image formation (printing). A fixing device has been improved to increase a nip length of a fixing nip portion in order to provide an amount of heat necessary for a toner image to be fixed and fused onto a sheet conveyed at a high speed. For example, Japanese Patent Laid-Open Publication No. 2005-227463, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, discloses a fixing device provided with: a heating roller <b>1001</b>; a pressurizing roller <b>1002</b> that is pressed against the heating roller <b>1001</b>; a belt stretching roller <b>1003</b> that is disposed on an upstream side in a paper conveying direction with respect to the pressurizing roller <b>1002</b> and is arranged on the pressurizing roller <b>1002</b> to be biased in the direction of an arrow G through a tension spring (not shown); a belt <b>1004</b> that is wrapped around the outer peripheries of the pressurizing roller <b>1002</b> and the belt stretch roller <b>1003</b> and moves while forming a fixing nip portion <b>1005</b> between the heating roller <b>1001</b> and the belt itself; and a preload spring (not shown) that biases the belt stretching roller <b>1003</b> in the direction of an arrow J and brings the belt stretch roller <b>1003</b> into contact with the heating roller <b>1001</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">According to the fixing device described in Japanese Patent Laid-Open Publication No. 2005-227463, the belt <b>1004</b> is always stretched because the belt stretching roller <b>1003</b> is biased in the direction of the arrow G by the tension spring. For this reason, as the belt <b>1004</b> is extended in connection with a continuous use of the fixing device for a long period of time, the belt stretching roller <b>1003</b> moves to a position shown by a chain double-dashed line, and the nip length of the fixing nip portion <b>1005</b> changes (the nip length becomes longer in this case). As a result, a problem of exerting an adverse influence on toner fixation is caused.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In view of the above-stated problem, it is an object of the present invention to provide a fixing device capable of stably performing a fixing process without changing a nip length of a fixing nip portion and to provide an image forming apparatus including the fixing device.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">A fixing device according to the present invention includes a fixing belt, a fixing roller, a separating roller, a heating roller, a pressurizing roller, a first lever, a second lever, a first biasing member, and a second biasing member.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The fixing belt is formed into an endless belt. The fixing roller suspends the fixing belt with the separating roller and the heating roller. The separating roller separates a recording material from the fixing belt. The pressurizing roller presses against the fixing roller and the separating roller through the fixing belt to form a fixing nip portion between the fixing belt and the roller itself. The heating roller includes a core metal portion and a heat source for heating the core metal portion, suspends the fixing belt by the core metal portion, and heats the fixing belt. The first lever, to which a rotating shaft of the fixing roller and a rotating shaft of the separating roller are fixed, pivots around the rotating shaft of the fixing roller by using the rotating shaft as a supporting point. The second lever, to which the rotating shaft of the fixing roller and a rotating shaft of the heating roller are fixed, pivots around the rotating shaft of the fixing roller by using the rotating shaft as a supporting point. The first biasing member biases the first lever and causes the separating roller to press against the pressurizing roller. The second biasing member biases the second lever and causes the fixing belt to stretch over the heating roller.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">With this structure, the nip length of the fixing nip portion is always constant because the fixing roller and the separating roller that are in pressure contact with the pressurizing roller have respective rotating shafts that are fixed to the first lever. A developer can be thus stably fixed and fused on a recording material.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In addition, the fixing belt, by using the fixing roller as a supporting point, is stretched with a constant tension by the separating roller fixed to the first lever and the heating roller fixed to the second lever. Therefore, the fixing belt can be prevented from being deflected in the fixing nip portion. Even if the fixing belt bends or extends with time, an interaction between the first lever and the second lever can stretch the fixing belt with a constant tension.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Moreover, the heating roller includes no elastic layer, and the fixing belt is suspended by the core metal portion of the heating roller. For that reason, the heating roller has a small heat capacity and can heat the core metal portion and the fixing belt with a little energy and a short time. The adoption of a fixing belt having a small heat capacity and the rotation of the fixing belt at a high speed can also improve the heat transfer characteristics to the fixing nip portion. Thus, the fixing process can be performed in a short time after starting.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Furthermore, the distance from the heating roller to the fixing roller, that is, the distance to the fixing nip portion, is always constant because each of the rotating shafts of the fixing roller and the heating roller is fixed to the second lever. In the case where the fixing belt is moved (rotated) at a constant speed, the time until a portion of the fixing belt heated by the heating roller reaches the fixing nip portion becomes constant, so that the amount of heat given to a recording material in the fixing nip portion can be made constant. A developer can be thus stably fixed and fused on the recording material.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The fixing device of the above-stated invention includes a third lever and a third biasing member. The third lever, to which a rotating shaft of the pressurizing roller is fixed, pivots around a point that is separated, by a predetermined distance, from the pressurizing roller by using the point as a third supporting point. The third biasing member, in the third lever, is attached as opposed to the third supporting point with the pressurizing roller held therebetween, biases the third lever to cause the pressurizing roller to press against the fixing roller.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The structure enables the third biasing member to bias the third lever with a small power by the principle of the lever. In addition, the positional adjustment of the pressurizing roller with respect to other rollers is not required, and the pressurizing roller can be easily attached.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The fixing device of the above-stated invention includes a heat source provided in the pressurizing roller. Heating the fixing belt by the heat source of the pressurizing roller in an auxiliary manner can surely fix and fuse toner.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">An image forming apparatus of the present invention includes the fixing device of the above-stated invention, and an image forming portion. The image forming portion transfers a developer to the recording material conveyed to the fixing device to thereby form an image.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">This structure prevents faulty fixation from occurring and can form an image of good quality because the image that the image forming portion forms on the recording material is stably and surely fixed and fused by the fixing device.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The foregoing and other features and attendant advantages of the present invention will become more apparent from the reading of the following detailed description of the invention in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a structure of an image forming apparatus according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a sectional view showing a structure of a fixing device according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a sectional view showing a structure related to formation of a fixing nip portion of the fixing device according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a sectional view of a fixing belt.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a sectional view showing a structure of a conventional fixing device.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the image forming apparatus <b>100</b> is a tandem-type color image forming apparatus including a first image forming unit <b>1</b> for forming a yellow toner image, a second image forming unit <b>2</b> for forming a magenta toner image, a third image forming unit <b>3</b> for forming a cyan toner image, and a fourth image forming unit <b>4</b> for forming a black toner image. Hereinafter, the four image forming units that the image forming apparatus <b>100</b> includes are collectively referred to as an image forming unit group <b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a primary transfer belt (an endless belt) <b>6</b> is disposed above the image formation unit group <b>5</b>. The primary transfer belt <b>6</b> is passed over a support roller <b>61</b> and a primary transfer belt drive roller <b>62</b> to be stretched in a looped shape, and rotates in a direction indicated by an arrow R. The primary transfer belt <b>6</b> is made of resin such as polyimide or polyamide with an electrically conductive material having electronic conductivity being included therein and is formed in a shape of a thin film.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The image forming unit group <b>5</b> includes the first image forming unit <b>1</b>, the second image forming unit <b>2</b>, the third image forming unit <b>3</b>, and the fourth image forming unit <b>4</b>, which are disposed in this order along the primary transfer belt <b>6</b> in the direction of the arrow R.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">On the inner peripheral side of the primary transfer belt <b>6</b> are disposed primary transfer rollers <b>71</b>, <b>72</b>, <b>73</b>, <b>74</b> for respectively transferring, onto the primary transfer belt <b>6</b>, the single color toner images that are respectively formed by the image forming unit group <b>5</b>. The primary transfer rollers <b>71</b>, <b>72</b>, <b>73</b>, <b>74</b> around which the primary transfer belt <b>6</b> is stretched, are respectively disposed, with the primary transfer belt <b>6</b> held therebetween, as opposed to photoreceptor drums <b>161</b>, <b>162</b>, <b>163</b>, <b>164</b> installed in the image forming unit group <b>5</b>. The single color toner images that are respectively formed by the image forming unit group <b>5</b> are sequentially transferred (primarily transferred) onto the primary transfer belt <b>6</b> in such a manner as to be overlapped to form one color toner image. The primary transfer belt <b>6</b>, corresponding to an image bearing member, conveys the primarily transferred toner image to a secondary transfer position. Hereinafter, in the primary transfer belt <b>6</b>, the support roller <b>61</b> side is referred to as the upstream side, and the primary transfer belt drive roller <b>62</b> side is referred to as the downstream side.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In the secondary transfer position as opposed to the primary transfer belt drive roller <b>62</b> with the primary transfer belt <b>6</b> held therebetween, a secondary transfer unit <b>51</b> is disposed. The color toner image that has been formed on the primary transfer belt <b>6</b> is transferred onto a paper sheet (a recording material) P by an electrostatic force in the secondary transfer position where the primary transfer belt drive roller <b>62</b> and the secondary transfer unit <b>51</b> are opposed to each other.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In a position opposed to the support roller <b>61</b> with the primary transfer belt <b>6</b> held therebetween, a primary transfer belt cleaning unit <b>10</b> for cleaning the surface of the primary transfer belt <b>6</b> is installed. The primary transfer belt cleaning unit <b>10</b> includes: a belt cleaning brush <b>11</b> that is disposed in contact with the primary transfer belt <b>6</b>; and a belt cleaning blade <b>12</b>, and removes toner and the like that remain on the primary transfer belt <b>6</b> without having been transferred onto the paper sheet P.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a tray <b>14</b> for storing the paper sheet P therein is disposed in the lower part of the image formation unit group <b>5</b>. The paper sheet P in the tray <b>14</b> is conveyed, by a plurality of pairs of feed rollers <b>131</b> to <b>134</b> that are disposed in a conveying path <b>130</b>, in a conveying direction indicated by an arrow Y to the secondary transfer position in which the secondary transfer unit <b>51</b> is opposed to the primary transfer belt <b>6</b>, and then the color toner image on the primary transfer belt <b>6</b> is secondarily transferred onto the paper sheet P in the secondary transfer position.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The paper sheet P, onto which the color toner image that has been secondarily transferred, is conveyed to the fixing device <b>15</b>. Then, the paper sheet P, after the color toner image having been fixed and fused thereon by the fixing device <b>15</b>, is output from the image forming apparatus <b>100</b> by a pair of paper output rollers <b>135</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Subsequently, a specific structure of the fixing device <b>15</b> according to an embodiment of the present invention is described. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows the overall structure of the fixing device <b>15</b>, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a structure related to formation of the fixing nip portion of the fixing device <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The fixing device <b>15</b> includes: a fixing belt <b>21</b>; a fixing roller <b>22</b>; a separating roller <b>23</b>; a heating roller <b>24</b>; a pressurizing roller <b>25</b>; a first lever <b>26</b>; a second lever <b>27</b>; a third lever <b>28</b>; a first spring <b>29</b> as a first biasing member; a second spring <b>30</b> as a second biasing member; and a third spring <b>31</b> as a third biasing member. The fixing device <b>15</b> also includes a first temperature sensor <b>32</b> and a second temperature sensor <b>33</b>. Further, the fixing device <b>15</b> includes sheet guides <b>151</b> to <b>153</b>. Additionally, the fixing device <b>15</b> includes a control portion <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The fixing belt <b>21</b> is an endless belt and is suspended by the fixing roller <b>22</b>, the separating roller <b>23</b>, and the heating roller <b>24</b>. The fixing belt <b>21</b> is configured to form a triangular shape having rounded corners, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In the fixing device <b>15</b>, the pressurizing roller <b>25</b> is a drive roller that is rotated at a constant speed by a motor <b>34</b>; and the fixing roller <b>22</b>, the separating roller <b>23</b>, and the heating roller <b>24</b> are idle rollers that are rotated at a constant speed by the fixing belt <b>21</b> in conjunction with the rotation of the pressurizing roller <b>25</b>. The control portion <b>20</b> controls the motor <b>34</b> for rotating the pressurizing roller <b>25</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the fixing belt <b>21</b> has a three-layered structure, and includes: a base material <b>211</b>, an elastic layer <b>212</b>, and a separating layer <b>213</b> that are laminated in order from the inner peripheral side to the outer peripheral side. The base material <b>211</b> is composed of a thin film of polyimide, stainless steel (SUS), or nickel (Ni). The elastic layer <b>212</b> is formed of silicone rubber. The separating layer <b>213</b> is formed of polytetrafluoroethylene (PFA), which is tetrafluoroethylene resin; and has characteristics such as non-stickiness and self-lubricating properties. As the fixing belt <b>21</b>, a thin belt is used to reduce thermal capacity. The thickness of the fixing belt <b>21</b> ranges from 150 &#x3bc;m to 500 &#x3bc;m, for example. Each thickness of the base material <b>211</b>, the elastic layer <b>212</b>, and the separating layer <b>213</b> may be set according to the conditions such as a conveying speed of the paper sheet P and a heating temperature.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> again, the fixing roller <b>22</b> includes a rotating shaft <b>221</b>, a core metal portion <b>222</b>, and an elastic layer <b>223</b>. The rotating shaft <b>221</b> extends from the both ends of the fixing roller <b>22</b>. The core metal portion <b>222</b> is a hollow cylinder formed of metal such as iron (Fe) and aluminum (Al). The elastic layer <b>223</b> is formed of material such as urethane sponge and silicone rubber and is provided around the core metal portion <b>222</b>. The fixing roller <b>22</b> holds the paper sheet (the recording material) P therebetween with the pressurizing roller <b>25</b> through the fixing belt <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The separating roller <b>23</b> includes a rotating shaft <b>231</b> and a core metal portion <b>232</b>. The rotating shaft <b>231</b> extends from the both ends of the separating roller <b>23</b>. The separating roller <b>23</b> separates, from the fixing belt <b>21</b>, the paper sheet P on which toner (a developer) is fixed and fused.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The heating roller <b>24</b> includes a rotating shaft <b>241</b>, a heat source <b>242</b>, and a core metal portion <b>243</b>. The rotating shaft <b>241</b> extends from the both ends of the heating roller <b>24</b>. The heating roller <b>24</b> heats the core metal portion <b>243</b> by the heat source <b>242</b>. The heat source <b>242</b> is made of a heating wire or a halogen lamp (a heater lamp) and is installed in the central part of the heating roller <b>24</b> in order to uniformly heat the core metal portion <b>243</b>. The core metal portion <b>243</b> is a hollow cylinder formed of metal such as iron (Fe) and aluminum (Al), and has a radial thickness of 0.4 mm to 1.2 mm and a small heat capacity. The heating roller <b>24</b> suspends the fixing belt <b>21</b> by the core metal portion <b>243</b> and heats the fixing belt <b>21</b>. The first temperature sensor <b>32</b> measures a surface temperature of the heating roller <b>24</b>. The control portion <b>20</b> controls operation of the heat source <b>242</b> by turning the heat source <b>242</b> ON and OFF and by adjusting the amount of heat according to the surface temperature of the heating roller <b>24</b>, measured by the first temperature sensor <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The pressurizing roller <b>25</b> includes a rotating shaft <b>251</b>, a heat source <b>252</b>, a core metal portion <b>253</b>, and an elastic layer <b>254</b>. The rotating shaft <b>251</b> extends from the both ends of the pressurizing roller <b>25</b>. The pressurizing roller <b>25</b> heats the core metal portion <b>253</b> by the heat source <b>252</b>. The heat source <b>252</b> is made of a heating wire or a halogen lamp (a heater lamp), and is installed in the central part of the heating roller <b>24</b> in order to uniformly heat the core metal portion <b>253</b> and the elastic layer <b>254</b>. The core metal portion <b>253</b> is a hollow cylinder formed of metal such as iron (Fe) and aluminum (Al). The elastic layer <b>254</b> is formed of material such as urethane sponge and silicone rubber and is provided around the core metal portion <b>253</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The pressurizing roller <b>25</b> presses against the fixing roller <b>22</b> and the separating roller <b>23</b> through the fixing belt <b>21</b> to form a fixing nip portion <b>215</b> between the fixing belt <b>21</b> and the roller itself. The fixing nip portion <b>215</b> has a length from a portion where the fixing roller <b>22</b> is in contact with the pressurizing roller <b>25</b> through the fixing belt <b>21</b> to a portion where the separating roller <b>23</b> is in contact with the pressurizing roller <b>25</b> through the fixing belt <b>21</b>. The pressurizing roller <b>25</b> fixes and fuses toner on the paper sheet P in the fixing nip portion <b>215</b>. The second temperature sensor <b>33</b> measures a surface temperature of the pressurizing roller <b>25</b>. The control portion <b>20</b> controls amount of heat of the heat source <b>252</b> by turning the heat source <b>252</b> ON and OFF and by adjusting the amount of heat according to the surface temperature of the pressurizing roller <b>25</b>, measured by the second temperature sensor <b>33</b>. In the fixing nip portion <b>215</b>, heat and pressure are applied to the paper sheet P in which toner has been transferred to fix and fuse the toner onto the paper sheet P.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In the present invention, the surface (the elastic layer <b>254</b>) of the pressurizing roller <b>25</b> is heated by the heat source <b>252</b>. Thereby, the fixing performance of the fixing device <b>15</b> can be improved.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The first lever <b>26</b> (<b>26</b>A, <b>26</b>B) is installed in the both side parts of the fixing roller <b>22</b> and the separating roller <b>23</b>. The rotating shaft <b>221</b> of the fixing roller <b>22</b> and the rotating shaft <b>231</b> of the separating roller <b>23</b> are freely and rotatably fixed to the first lever <b>26</b> in a predetermined interval. The first lever <b>26</b> can freely pivot by using the rotating shaft <b>221</b> of the fixing roller <b>22</b> as a supporting point <b>261</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">One end of the first spring <b>29</b> is fixed to an end on the opposite side of the supporting point <b>261</b> of the first lever <b>26</b>, that is, a point <b>262</b> on the opposite side of the first supporting point <b>261</b> with the separating roller <b>23</b> held therebetween. The other end of the first spring <b>29</b> is fixed to a point <b>283</b> of the third lever <b>28</b>. The first spring <b>29</b> always biases the first lever <b>26</b> with a predetermined force, the first lever <b>26</b> pivots in the direction in which the lever approaches the pressurizing roller <b>25</b> by using the supporting point <b>261</b> as the center point, and the separating roller <b>23</b> is brought into pressure contact with the pressurizing roller <b>25</b> through the fixing belt <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The second lever <b>27</b> (<b>27</b>A, <b>27</b>B) is installed in the both side parts of the fixing roller <b>22</b> and the heating roller <b>24</b>. The rotating shaft <b>221</b> of the fixing roller <b>22</b> and the rotating shaft <b>241</b> of the heating roller <b>24</b> are freely and rotatably fixed to the second lever <b>27</b> in a predetermined interval. The second lever <b>27</b> can freely pivot by using the rotating shaft <b>221</b> of the fixing roller <b>22</b> as a supporting point <b>271</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">One end of the second spring <b>30</b> is fixed to an end on the opposite side of the supporting point <b>271</b> of the second lever <b>27</b>, that is, a point <b>272</b> on the opposite side of the second supporting point <b>271</b> with the heating roller <b>24</b> held therebetween. The other end of the second spring <b>30</b> is fixed to a point <b>101</b> of the main body of the image forming apparatus <b>100</b>. The second spring <b>30</b> always biases the second lever <b>27</b> with a predetermined force, the second lever <b>27</b> pivots in the direction in which the lever separates from the separating roller <b>23</b> by using the supporting point <b>271</b> as the center point, and the heating roller <b>24</b> stretches the fixing belt <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The third lever <b>28</b> (<b>28</b>A, <b>28</b>B) is installed in the both side parts of the pressurizing roller <b>25</b>. A rotating shaft <b>251</b> of the pressurizing roller <b>25</b> is freely and rotatably fixed to the third lever <b>28</b>. The third lever <b>28</b> can freely pivot around a point (a lower point of the rotating shaft <b>251</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) that is separated, by a predetermined distance, from the pressurizing roller <b>25</b> by using the point as a third supporting point <b>281</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">One end of the third spring <b>31</b> is fixed to an end on the opposite side of the supporting point <b>281</b> of the third lever <b>28</b>, that is, a point <b>282</b> on the opposite side of the third supporting point <b>281</b> with the pressurizing roller <b>25</b> held therebetween. The other end of the third spring <b>31</b> is fixed to a point <b>411</b> of a fixing portion <b>41</b> installed near a sheet guide <b>152</b> (as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). The third spring <b>31</b> always biases the third lever <b>28</b> with a predetermined force, the third lever <b>28</b> pivots in the direction in which the lever approaches the fixing roller <b>22</b> by using the supporting point <b>281</b> as the center point, and the pressurizing roller <b>25</b> is brought into pressure contact with the fixing roller <b>22</b> through the fixing belt <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The sheet guides <b>151</b> to <b>153</b> restrict the conveying direction of the paper sheet P.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In the present invention, characteristic operational effects can be achieved by the characteristic structure of the fixing device <b>15</b>. The following summarizes the content.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">(1) The nip length of the fixing nip portion <b>215</b> is always constant without changing, so that the fixing process can be stably performed.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Since the rotating shaft <b>221</b> of the fixing roller <b>22</b> and the rotating shaft <b>231</b> of the separating roller <b>23</b> are fixed to the first lever <b>26</b>, the interval between the fixing roller <b>22</b> and the separating roller <b>23</b> does not change. Therefore, the nip length of the fixing nip portion <b>215</b> formed by the fixing belt <b>21</b>, the fixing roller <b>22</b>, the separating roller <b>23</b>, and the pressurizing roller <b>25</b> is always constant without changing, so that the fixing process can be stably performed. In addition, no adjustment of the nip length is required, and assembling work efficiency is improved.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">(2) The fixing belt <b>21</b> can be prevented from being deflected in the fixing nip portion <b>215</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The fixing belt <b>21</b>, by using the fixing roller <b>22</b> as a supporting point, is stretched with a constant tension by the separating roller <b>23</b> fixed to the first lever <b>26</b>, and the heating roller <b>24</b> fixed to the second lever <b>27</b>. Thereby, the fixing belt <b>21</b> can be prevented from being deflected in the fixing nip portion <b>215</b>. In addition, even if the fixing belt <b>21</b> extends, the nip length of the fixing nip portion <b>215</b> and the tension force of the fixing belt <b>21</b> are constant, and no positional adjustment of each roller is required.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">(3) An inexpensive spring having a small biasing force can be used, so that the cost can be reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The rotating shaft <b>231</b> of the separating roller <b>23</b> is fixed to the first lever <b>26</b>. In the first lever <b>26</b>, an end on the opposite side of the fixing roller <b>22</b> (a supporting point) with the separating roller <b>23</b> held therebetween is biased by the first spring <b>29</b>. Thus, by the principle of the lever, the separating roller <b>23</b> can be pressed against the pressurizing roller <b>25</b> by a smaller force than a force used when the separating roller is directly pressed against the pressurizing roller, which enables an inexpensive spring having a small biasing force to be used, so that the cost can be reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Similarly, the rotating shaft <b>241</b> of the heating roller <b>24</b> is fixed to the second lever <b>27</b>. In the second lever <b>27</b>, an end on the opposite side of the fixing roller <b>22</b> (a supporting point) with the heating roller <b>24</b> held therebetween is biased by the second spring <b>30</b>. Thus, by the principle of the lever, the heating roller <b>24</b> can be biased by a force smaller than a force used when the rotating shaft of the heating roller <b>24</b> is directly biased, which enables an inexpensive spring having a small biasing force to be used, so that the cost can be reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Similarly, the rotating shaft <b>251</b> of the pressurizing roller <b>25</b> is fixed to the third lever <b>28</b>. The third lever <b>28</b> has a supporting point <b>281</b> and a point of application <b>282</b> which hold the heating roller <b>24</b> therebetween, and the point of application is biased by the third spring <b>31</b> around the supporting point <b>281</b> used as the center point. Thus, by the principle of the lever, a force that causes the pressurizing roller <b>25</b> to press against the fixing roller <b>22</b> can be made smaller than a force used when the pressurizing roller is pressed directly, which enables an inexpensive spring having a small biasing force to be used.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">(4) The fixing roller <b>22</b> has elasticity, so that the nip length of the fixing nip portion <b>215</b> can be secured and the fixing performance can be improved.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">In a structure in which a fixing belt is suspended by two rollers, a heating roller needs to face a pressurizing roller. In the present invention, the fixing belt <b>21</b> is suspended by the three rollers: the fixing roller, the pressurizing roller, and the heating roller. Thus, the fixing roller <b>22</b> having no heating function and including an elastic layer <b>223</b> can be faced to the pressurizing roller <b>25</b> and the heating roller <b>24</b> can be installed upstream from the fixing roller <b>22</b> in the conveying direction of the fixing belt <b>21</b>. Thereby, the fixing roller <b>22</b> has elasticity, so that the fixing nip portion can be secured and the fixing performance can be improved. Since no elastic layer needs to be installed in the heating roller <b>24</b>, the radial thickness can be made thin and then the heat capacity can be small. In addition, the adoption of a belt having a small heat capacity as the fixing belt <b>21</b> and the rotation of the fixing belt <b>21</b> at a high speed can improve the heat transfer characteristics to the fixing nip portion <b>215</b>. Thereby, the heating roller <b>24</b> and the fixing belt <b>21</b> can be heated with a little energy and a short time. Accordingly, the fixing process can be started in a short time, which improves the operability of the fixing device <b>15</b> and the image forming apparatus <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">(5) The amount of heat given to toner in the fixing nip portion <b>215</b> can be stabilized.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Since the rotating shaft <b>221</b> of the fixing roller <b>22</b> and the rotating shaft <b>241</b> of the heating roller <b>24</b> are fixed to the second lever <b>27</b>, the interval of the fixing roller <b>22</b> and the heating roller <b>24</b> does not change. The fixing belt <b>21</b> rotates at a constant speed, so that the time until a portion of the fixing belt <b>21</b> heated by the heating roller <b>24</b> reaches the fixing nip portion <b>215</b> becomes constant, and the amount of heat given to toner in the fixing nip portion <b>215</b> can be stabilized. Therefore, the fixing process can be stably performed. In addition, no adjustment of the interval between the fixing roller <b>22</b> and the heating roller <b>24</b> is required, and assembling work efficiency is improved.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">(6) The heat source <b>252</b> is provided in the pressurizing roller <b>25</b>, so that toner can be surely fixed and fused by heating the fixing belt <b>21</b> in an auxiliary manner by the heat source <b>252</b> of the pressurizing roller <b>25</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">While certain embodiments have been described, these embodiments have been presented by way of example only, and are not intended to limit the scope of the inventions. Indeed, the novel embodiments described herein may be embodied in a variety of other forms; furthermore, various omissions, substitutions, and changes in the form of the embodiments described herein may be made without departing from the spirit of the inventions. The accompanying claims and their equivalents are intended to cover such forms or modifications as would fall within the scope and spirit of the inventions.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A fixing device comprising:
<claim-text>a fixing belt in an endless form;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fixing roller for suspending the fixing belt;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a separating roller for suspending the fixing belt and separating a recording material from the fixing belt;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pressurizing roller for pressing against the fixing roller and the separating roller through the fixing belt to form a fixing nip portion between the fixing belt and the pressurizing roller;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a heating roller including:
<claim-text>a core metal portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a heat source for heating the core metal portion, the heating roller suspending the fixing belt by the core metal portion, and heating the fixing belt;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first lever to which a rotating shaft of the fixing roller and a rotating shaft of the separating roller are fixed, the first lever pivoting around the rotating shaft of the fixing roller used as a first supporting point;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second lever to which the rotating shaft of the fixing roller and a rotating shaft of the heating roller are fixed, the second lever pivoting around the rotating shaft of the fixing roller used as a second supporting point;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first biasing member for biasing the first lever and causing the separating roller to press against the pressurizing roller; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second biasing member for biasing the second lever and causing the fixing belt to stretch over the heating roller.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The fixing device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a third lever to which a rotating shaft of the pressurizing roller is fixed, the third lever pivoting around a point that is separated, by a predetermined distance, from the pressurizing roller by using the point as a third supporting point; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third biasing member attached, in the third lever, as opposed to the third supporting point with the pressurizing roller held therebetween, the third biasing member biasing the third lever and causing the pressurizing roller to press against the fixing roller.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The fixing device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the pressurizing roller includes a heat source therein.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. An image forming apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>the fixing device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an image forming portion for forming an image by transferring a developer to a recording material conveyed to the fixing device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. An image forming apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>the fixing device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an image forming portion for forming an image by transferring a developer to a recording material conveyed to the fixing device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. An image forming apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>the fixing device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an image forming portion for forming an image by transferring a developer to a recording material conveyed to the fixing device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
