<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624617-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624617</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13163750</doc-number>
<date>20110620</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2010 1 0557466</doc-number>
<date>20101124</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>437</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>32475511</main-classification>
<further-classification>32475502</further-classification>
<further-classification>324149</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Test probe</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4491788</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Zandonatti</name>
<date>19850100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>324 725</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4716365</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Pool</name>
<date>19871200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>32475414</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5041781</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kawada et al.</name>
<date>19910800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>32475511</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>324149</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>32475502</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120126842</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120524</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Huang</last-name>
<first-name>Mao-Sheng</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tu-Cheng</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yue</last-name>
<first-name>Chuang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Huang</last-name>
<first-name>Mao-Sheng</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tu-Cheng</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yue</last-name>
<first-name>Chuang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Fu Tai Hua Industry (Shenzhen) Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Tang</last-name>
<first-name>Minh N</first-name>
<department>2867</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A test probe for testing an object electrically includes a main body, a first probe pin mounted to and protruding out of the main body, and at least one second probe pin coupled to the main body. The at least one second probe pin is changeable from a first state of being folded into the main body to a second state of being unfolded to protrude out of the main body. When the at least one second probe pin is in the first state, the first probe pin is used to contact the object, and when the at least one second probe pin is in the second state, the at least one second probe pin takes the place of the first probe pin in making electrical connection with the object.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="138.51mm" wi="334.35mm" file="US08624617-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="188.72mm" wi="172.38mm" file="US08624617-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="224.03mm" wi="176.70mm" file="US08624617-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="213.87mm" wi="168.91mm" file="US08624617-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="172.47mm" wi="165.95mm" file="US08624617-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="159.43mm" wi="173.06mm" file="US08624617-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to test probes.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A typical test probe for testing resistance, for example in semiconductor circuits, often includes a probe pin for making electrical contact with the object. However, the probe pin is generally made of hard metal, such as tungsten or its alloys, and is always tined. Thus, the surface of some objects (for example the copper coated pathways on PCBs) may very easily be scraped by the tined end of the probe pin.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Therefore, there is room for improvement in the art.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Many aspects of the embodiments can be better understood with references to the following drawings. The components in the drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the embodiments. Moreover, in the drawings, like reference numerals designate corresponding parts throughout the five views.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a test probe in accordance with an embodiment; the test probe is be used in a first state.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a disassembled perspective view of the test probe of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, but viewed from another aspect.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a perspective view showing the test probe of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> being used in a second state.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross-sectional view taken along line V-V of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The disclosure is illustrated by way of example and not by way of limitation in the figures of the accompanying drawings in which like references indicate similar elements. It should be noted that references to &#x201c;an&#x201d; or &#x201c;one&#x201d; embodiment in this disclosure are not necessarily to the same embodiment, and such references mean at least one.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a test probe <b>100</b> in accordance with an embodiment is shown. The test probe <b>100</b> includes a main body <b>10</b>, a conductive post <b>20</b> mounted to the main body <b>10</b>, a first probe pin <b>30</b> mounted to an end of the conductive post <b>20</b> and protruding out of the main body <b>10</b>, and a number of second probe pins <b>40</b> electrically connected to the conductive post <b>20</b>. The second probe pin <b>40</b> are rotatably coupled to the main body <b>10</b>, are arranged circumferentially around the main body <b>10</b>, and are capable of being rotated outwards approximately one hundred and eighty degrees from a first position within the main body <b>10</b> to a second extended or protruded position out of the main body <b>10</b>. The manner of operation of each of the second probe pins <b>40</b> is similar to that of a flick-knife. In the embodiment, the conductive post <b>20</b>, the first probe pin <b>30</b> and the second probe pins <b>40</b> are conductors, and are made of conductive metal such as copper.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-3</figref>, the main body <b>10</b> includes a cylindrical portion <b>120</b> and a head portion <b>140</b> mounted to the cylindrical portion <b>120</b>. The cylindrical portion <b>120</b> is hollow and has an axis A (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). An end of the cylindrical portion <b>120</b> adjacent to the head portion <b>140</b> recesses to define a receiving space <b>121</b> extending along the axis A, and the other end of the cylindrical portion <b>120</b> defines a fixing hole <b>122</b> extending along the axis A and communicating with receiving space <b>121</b>. The fixing hole <b>122</b> is used to mount the conductive post <b>20</b> thereinto. The outer surface of the cylindrical portion <b>120</b> defines a number of receiving slots <b>124</b> extending in a direction parallel to the axis A. The receiving slots <b>124</b> are arranged evenly at the end of the cylindrical portion <b>120</b> adjacent to the head portion <b>140</b>, and are used for receiving and containing the second probe pins <b>40</b> respectively. An end of each receiving slot <b>124</b> adjacent to the head portion <b>140</b> includes a receiving portion <b>126</b>. The receiving portions <b>126</b> are substantially spherical in cross section. One end of each second probe pin <b>40</b> is rotatably received in a corresponding receiving portion <b>126</b>, such that the second probe pins <b>40</b> are rotatably coupled to the main body <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The cylindrical portion <b>120</b> further defines a guiding slot <b>127</b>. The guiding slot <b>127</b> is substantially L-shaped and is arranged radially in the main body <b>10</b> between two adjacent receiving slots <b>124</b>. The guiding slot <b>127</b> includes a guiding portion <b>128</b> parallel to the axis A and a limiting portion <b>129</b> communicating with the guiding portion <b>128</b>. The limiting portion <b>129</b> extends in a direction perpendicular to the axis A.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The head portion <b>140</b> is substantially in the shape of a frustum in the embodiment, and is coaxial with the cylindrical portion <b>120</b>. The head portion <b>140</b> is mounted to an end of the cylindrical portion <b>120</b> defining the receiving space <b>121</b>. The head portion <b>140</b> defines a guiding hole <b>142</b> along the axis A. The diameter of the guiding hole <b>142</b> is larger than that of the conductive post <b>20</b>, but is less than that of the receiving space <b>121</b>. The head portion <b>140</b> defines a number of latching slots <b>143</b> respectively corresponding to the receiving slots <b>124</b>. The latching slots <b>143</b> are arranged evenly at the outer surface of the head portion <b>140</b>, and are used to limit the movement of the second probe pins <b>40</b> when the second probe pins <b>40</b> rotate outwards to the second position.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The conductive post <b>20</b> is cylindrical and is fixed coaxially to the main body <b>10</b> by means of the fixing hole <b>122</b>. A portion of the conductive post <b>20</b> is received in the main body <b>10</b>. An end of the conductive post <b>20</b> is received in the guiding hole <b>142</b> and is substantially coplanar with the end of the head portion <b>140</b> farthest from the cylindrical portion <b>120</b>, and the other end of the conductive post <b>20</b> protrudes out of the cylindrical portion <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The tine of the first probe pin <b>30</b> is substantially conical. An end of the first probe pin <b>30</b> is mounted coaxially to the end of the conductive post <b>20</b> received in the guiding hole <b>142</b>, and the other end of the first probe pin <b>30</b> protrudes from the head portion <b>140</b>. The extension of the first probe pin <b>30</b> from the end of the conductive post <b>20</b> is integral in this embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The second probe pins <b>40</b> are electrically connected to the conductive post <b>20</b>. The length of the second probe pins <b>40</b> when protruding out of the main body <b>10</b> is less than that of the first probe pin <b>30</b> protruding out of the main body <b>10</b>. Each second probe pin <b>40</b> includes a rotating portion <b>410</b> and an end portion <b>420</b> opposite to the rotating portion <b>410</b>. The rotating portion <b>410</b> is substantially spherical, and is rotatably received in the corresponding receiving portion <b>126</b> of the receiving slots <b>124</b>. The end portion <b>420</b> is blunt, and is used to make contact with the object to be tested (as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). A magnetic member <b>430</b> is arranged at an end of each second probe pin <b>40</b> adjacent to the end portion <b>420</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The test probe <b>100</b> further includes a sliding member <b>50</b>, an elastic element <b>60</b>, and an operating member <b>70</b>. The sliding member <b>50</b> is slidably received in the main body <b>10</b>. The elastic element <b>60</b> is received in receiving space <b>121</b> and resists the sliding member <b>50</b> to provide an elastic force between the sliding member <b>50</b> and the cylindrical portion <b>120</b> when pressed by the sliding member <b>50</b>. The operating member <b>70</b> is fixed to the sliding member <b>50</b> and is slidably received in the guiding slot <b>127</b>. The operating member <b>70</b> is used to drive the sliding member <b>50</b> to slide relative to the main body <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> again, the sliding member <b>50</b> includes a sleeve <b>510</b>, a first magnet <b>520</b>, and a second magnet <b>530</b>. The sleeve <b>510</b> is hollow and may slide along the conductive post <b>20</b>. The first magnet <b>520</b> is substantially in the shape of a frustum in the embodiment, and defines a round hole <b>522</b> extending along an axis thereof. The first magnet <b>520</b> sleeves on an end of the sleeve <b>510</b> via the round hole <b>522</b>. The second magnet <b>530</b> is substantially in the shape of a disk, and sleeves on an end of the sleeve <b>510</b> opposite to the first magnet <b>520</b>. The diameter of the first magnet <b>520</b> is larger than that of the guiding hole <b>142</b>. The diameter of the second magnet <b>530</b> is larger than that of the guiding hole <b>142</b>, but is less that that of the receiving space <b>121</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Furthermore, the test probe <b>100</b> includes a plurality of weights <b>80</b>. The weights <b>80</b> are substantially cylindrical and are made of insulation material or covered with insulation material. Each weight <b>80</b> defines a hole <b>810</b> extending in an axis thereof. The hole <b>810</b> is used to receive the conductive post <b>20</b>, whereby the weights <b>80</b> sleeve on the conductive post <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In assembly, the conductive post <b>20</b> is fixed to the cylindrical portion <b>120</b>. The elastic element <b>60</b>, the second magnet <b>530</b> and the sleeve <b>510</b> are sleeved on the conductive post <b>20</b> in order and are further received in the receiving space <b>121</b>. The rotating portions <b>410</b> are received in the corresponding receiving portion <b>126</b>, and the head portion <b>140</b> is mounted to the cylindrical portion <b>120</b>, thus, the second probe pins <b>40</b> are rotatably coupled to the main body <b>10</b>. The first probe pin <b>30</b> is mounted to the conductive post <b>20</b>. The first magnet <b>520</b> sleeves on an end of the sleeve <b>510</b> opposite to the second magnet <b>530</b>. Finally, the operating member <b>70</b> extends through the guiding slot <b>124</b> and is mounted to the sleeve <b>510</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> again, the test probe <b>100</b> in a first state is shown. In the first state, the second probe pins <b>40</b> are folded and are resting in their corresponding receiving slots <b>124</b>, the operating member <b>70</b> is at an end of the sliding portion <b>128</b> opposite to the limiting portion <b>129</b> of the guiding slot <b>127</b>, and the sliding member <b>50</b> is in the main body <b>10</b> with the first magnet <b>520</b> resisting against the head portion <b>140</b> and the second magnet <b>520</b> at an end of the receiving space <b>121</b> away from the head portion <b>140</b>. The attractive force of the second magnet <b>530</b> on the magnetic members <b>430</b> causes the second probe pins <b>40</b> to remain retracted in the receiving slots <b>124</b>, and the first probe pin <b>30</b> protruding out of the main body <b>10</b> is capable of being used to test an object. In the first state, the elastic element <b>60</b> may be in an original state.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4-5</figref>, the test probe <b>100</b> in a second state is shown. In the second state, the operating member <b>70</b> slides to the limit imposed by the limiting portion <b>129</b> (as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>), the sliding member <b>50</b> slides toward the first probe pin <b>30</b> with the first magnet <b>520</b> sliding away from the head portion <b>140</b> and covering the first probe pin <b>30</b>, the second magnet <b>530</b> slides to a position adjacent to the head portion <b>140</b>, and the elastic element <b>60</b> is stretched by the sliding member <b>50</b>. The movement of the second magnet <b>530</b> to a position adjacent to the head portion <b>140</b> decreases the force of magnetic attraction between the second magnet <b>530</b> and the magnetic members <b>430</b>. Thus, if the first probe pin <b>30</b> is pointing vertically downwards, the second probe pins <b>40</b> may be driven by gravity to rotate approximately one hundred and eighty degrees outwards towards the head portion <b>140</b> and be received in the limiting slots <b>143</b>, and the second probe pins <b>40</b>, experiencing the magnetic force of the first magnet <b>520</b>, may then remain in place. Therefore, the second probe pins <b>40</b> having blunt ends can substitute for the first probe pin <b>30</b> in making electrical contact with the object to be tested, thereby protecting the object from scrape-damage caused by the first probe pin <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">By virtue of the test probe <b>100</b>, the second probe pins <b>40</b>, of various materials, types, and profiles, are individually selectable in substituting for the first probe pin <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">It is to be understood, even though information and advantages of the present embodiments have been set forth in the foregoing description, together with details of the structures and functions of the present embodiments, the disclosure is illustrative only; and that changes may be made in detail, especially in matters of shape, size, and arrangement of parts within the principles of the present embodiments to the full extent indicated by the broad general meaning of the terms in which the appended claims are expressed.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A test probe for testing an object, comprising:
<claim-text>a main body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first probe pin mounted to and protruding out of the main body; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one second probe pin rotatably coupled to the main body, the at least one second probe pin being changeable from a first state being folded to a second state being unfolded to protrude out of the main body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein when the at least one second probe pin is changed to the first state, the first probe pin is used to contact the object, and when the at least one second probe pin is changed to the second state, the at least one second probe pin is used to contact the object.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The test probe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the main body comprises a cylindrical portion defining at least one receiving slot and a head portion mounted coaxially to the cylindrical portion, and the head portion defines at least one limiting slot corresponding to the at least one receiving slot.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The test probe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one second probe pin is resting in the at least one receiving slot when being in the first state, and is limited to the at least limiting slot and protrudes out of the main body when being in the second state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The test probe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the length of the first probe pin protruding out of the main body is less than the length of the at least one second probe pin protruding out of the main body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The test probe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one receiving slot comprises a receiving portion for rotatably receiving an end of the at least one second probe pin, and the receiving portion is arranged at an end of the at least one receiving slot adjacent to the head portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The test probe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a conductive post mounted to the main body, the first probe pin electrically mounted to an end of the conductive post and protruding out of the main body, the at least one second probe pin electrically connected to the conductive post.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The test probe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, further comprising a sliding member slidably received in the main body and slidably sleeved on the conductive post, the sliding member capable of sliding out of the main body to hide the first probe pin and sliding into the main body to expose the first probe pin.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The test probe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the sliding member comprises a first magnet and a second magnet, the first magnet and the second magnet are arranged at opposite ends of the sliding member, the first magnet is arranged out of the main body and is used to attract the at least one second probe pin when the at least one second probe pin is in the second state; and the second magnet is slidalby received in the main body and is used to attract the at least one second probe pin when the at least one second probe pin is in the first state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The test probe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising an operating member, the operating member being mounted to the sliding member and used to drive the sliding member sliding relatively the main body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The test probe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising an elastic element connecting the sliding member to the main body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The test probe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein a portion of the conductive post protrudes out of an end of the main body opposite to first probe pin.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The test probe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising a plurality of weights, the weights sleeving on the portion of the conductive post protruding out of the main body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A test probe capable of being used in a first state and a second state, comprising:
<claim-text>a main body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first probe pin mounted to and protruding out of the main body; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one second probe pin rotatably coupled to the main body, the at least one second probe pin capable of rotating from a first position being received in the main body to a second position protruding out of the main body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein when the at least one second probe pin rotates to the first position, the first probe pin is exposed and is used to contact an object, and the test probe is used in the first state; and when the at least one second probe pin rotates to the second position, the at least one second probe pin hides the first probe pin and is used to contact the object, and the test probe is used in the second state.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The test probe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the main body comprises a cylindrical portion defining at least one receiving slot and a head portion mounted coaxially to the cylindrical portion and defining at least one limiting slot corresponding to the at least one receiving slot.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The test probe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one second probe pin is received in the at least one receiving slot when being in the first position, and is limited to the at least limiting slot and protrudes out of the main body when being in the second position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The test probe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the length of the first probe pin protruding out of the main body is less than the length of the at least one second probe pin protruding out of the main body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The test probe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further comprising a conductive post mounted to the main body, the first probe pin electrically mounted to an end of the conductive post and protruding out of the main body, the second probe pin electrically connected to the main body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The test probe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, further comprising a sliding member slidably received in the main body and slidably sleeve on the conductive post, the sliding member capable of sliding out of the main body to hide the first probe pin and sliding into the main body to expose the first probe pin.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The test probe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the sliding member comprises a first magnet and a second magnet, the first magnet and the second magnet are arranged at opposite ends of the sliding member, the first magnet is arranged out of the main body and is used to attract the at least one second probe pin when the at least one second probe pin is in the second state; the second magnet is slidalby received in the main body and is used to attract the at least one second probe pin when the at least one second probe pin is in the first state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The test probe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, further comprising a plurality of weights, the weights sleeved on the conductive post protruding out of the main body.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
