<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626528-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626528</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13212124</doc-number>
<date>20110817</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>168</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20120101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>Q</subclass>
<main-group>50</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>705  2</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Intelligent alarms</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2002/0169636</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Eggers et al.</name>
<date>20021100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>705  3</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0069725</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Al-Ali</name>
<date>20100300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>600301</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00003">
<othercit>Merriam-Webster on-line dictionary: definintion for the word &#x201c;critical&#x201d;.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>7</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>705  2</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>705  3</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>600301</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>1</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>2</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130046158</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130221</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bisera</last-name>
<first-name>Joe</first-name>
<address>
<city>Camarillo</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tang</last-name>
<first-name>Wanchun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Palm Desert</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bisera</last-name>
<first-name>Joe</first-name>
<address>
<city>Camarillo</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tang</last-name>
<first-name>Wanchun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Palm Desert</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cohen</last-name>
<first-name>Lawrence S.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Weil Institute of Critical Care Medicine</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Rancho Mirage</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Pauls</last-name>
<first-name>John</first-name>
<department>3686</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A patient in intensive care is monitored by connecting the outputs of a plurality of sensors to a computer, where the sensors all relate to one mode of functioning such as heart beating, respiration, infusion of a liquid into the patient, etc. The sensor outputs are delivered to a computer that sounds an alarm, only if all sensors that indicate one function (e.g. heart beating) indicate dangerously low operation of that function. This avoids many false alarms caused by one sensor having a low output such as due to accidental disconnection of a wire.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="92.79mm" wi="227.67mm" file="US08626528-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="232.41mm" wi="170.77mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626528-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">False sound alarms are one of the greatest annoyances in critical care settings, such as an ICU (intensive care unit) environment. In fact, more than 97% of sound alarms are false positive alarms. Sometimes caregivers disable the alarms, which can result in preventable fatal events. A system that minimized false alarms while sounding legitimate alarms, would be of value.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention provides apparatus and methods for reducing and prioritizing alarms based on sensors that sense cardiovascular patterns, respiratory patterns, electrocardiogram patterns, pulse rate and pulse strength, oxygen saturation such as is sensed by a pulse oximeter, and arterial pressure. Sensors can include those that sense central venous pressure, pulse morphology as well as arterial pressure wave forms, end tital PCO<sub>2 </sub>(partial pressure of CO<sub>2</sub>), operation of a ventilator, and operation of an infusion pump. By providing a plurality of sensors that each indicates one function, the failure of one sensor can be overridden by the outputs of other sensor(s).</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The novel features of the invention are set forth with particularity in the appended claims. The invention will be best understood from the following description when read in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is view of a patient in an ICU environment, with sensors that sense functioning related to beating of a patient's heart.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a view similar to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, with sensors related to infusion.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a patient P in an intensive care environment <b>10</b>, wherein the patient is coupled to several sensors that monitor the functioning of various systems of the patient's body. These sensors include heart function sensors comprising a patient heart sensor <b>20</b> whose output <b>22</b> includes electrical pulses <b>24</b> of measurable height <b>26</b> and measurable spacing <b>28</b>. The output of the sensor is delivered to a first input <b>31</b> of a computer <b>30</b> which measures the height and spacing of the heart pulses. If the pulse height <b>26</b> is below a selected height or the spacing <b>28</b> has increased to more than a predetermined spacing then the computer generates a failure signal on an output <b>32</b>. Another sensor <b>40</b> senses the blood pressure, indicated at <b>41</b>, of the patient. A signal representing the blood pressure is delivered to computer input <b>44</b>. If the signal <b>41</b> indicates failure (e.g. the difference, between systolic and diastolic pressure is less than a certain minimum), a blood pressure signal output <b>34</b> is delivered. The outputs <b>32</b>, <b>34</b> delivered to part <b>36</b> of the computer results in sound alarm signal <b>38</b> only if all outputs <b>32</b>, <b>42</b> indicate failure of patient heart functioning.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Another sensor <b>50</b> senses the oxygen saturation of the patient's blood and delivers a signal to computer input <b>51</b>. Still another sensor <b>52</b> senses the PCO<sub>2 </sub>(partial pressure of carbon dioxide) in the patient's blood and delivers a corresponding signal to computer input <b>53</b>. A pulse oximeter can be used to sense PCO<sub>2</sub>. If the output <b>51</b> of the sensor <b>50</b> shows at least a limited level of oxygen in the patient's blood, then this means that the heart is beating to circulate the blood through the lungs to pick up oxygen. If the output <b>53</b> of sensor <b>52</b> shows at least a predetermined minimum of carbon dioxide then this indicates that the patient's blood is circulating. The computer will not generate an emergency sound alarm so long as one of the sensors <b>20</b>, <b>40</b>, <b>50</b>, <b>52</b> indicates that the patient's heart is beating regularly, or at least does not indicate failure.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">If the patient's heart is not beating regularly, then this is a critical failure that should be rectified immediately. The term &#x201c;critical&#x201d; means life threatening, or danger of death. If the output <b>22</b> of sensor <b>20</b> shows a pulse spacing <b>28</b> greater than a predetermined limit such as less than one pulse per three seconds, or shows a pulse height <b>26</b> less than one-fourth of the average previous height when a nurse determined that the heart was beating appropriately, then this indicates a critical failure that should be rectified immediately. However, if the output of the blood pressure sensor <b>40</b> or the output of sensor <b>50</b> or <b>52</b> is more than a minimal level, then this indicates that the heart is beating properly, or at least is beating sufficiently that this is not a critical situation. Actually, an improper output of only one sensor such as sensor <b>20</b>, indicates that one of the wires that connects to the heart rate sensor <b>20</b> has been disconnected or is not connected in a low resistance connection. Functioning of the other sensors <b>50</b>, <b>52</b> indicate that the heart is beating. When the computer senses a bad output, or failure from one sensor but other sensors indicate otherwise, then the computer <b>30</b> generates a visual indication such as at <b>70</b> that the heart rate sensor <b>20</b> or the blood pressure sensor <b>40</b> or other sensors such as <b>50</b> or <b>52</b> indicate improper heart functioning then lights at <b>72</b>, <b>74</b> light up. It is easier for a nurse to check these sensors which cause a light <b>70</b>, <b>72</b> etc. to light up when he/she has time, than to treat a poor sensor output as an emergency that requires he/she to drop everything to concentrate on the emergency.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Another function that is commonly monitored in an ICU is patient respiration. Sensors that indicate breathing include a chest vertical expansion-contraction sensor <b>100</b>, an air flow sensor <b>102</b>, an oxygen saturation sensor <b>104</b> and a PCO<sub>2 </sub>sensor <b>106</b>. If any of these respiration sensors indicate respiration, then no alarm will be sounded, although a visual indication will be generated that the sensor is not functioning properly.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Another function that is commonly monitored in an ICU is proper operation of an infusion pump that infuses one to several different fluids, including a saline solution, an antimicrobial fluid, etc. For those infusions that are critical, applicant can provide sensors including a sensor <b>110</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) that detects the level of fluid in a container <b>112</b> from which the fluid in introduced into the patient. The computer <b>30</b> sounds an alarm if the level does not decrease as expected, from the initial level existing when a nurse first connected the fluid container to the infusion pump, and other sensor(s) also indicate improper infusion. Sensor <b>114</b> senses movement of liquid in an infusion tube. Sensor <b>116</b> senses the pressure of air in the infusion tube.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The visual indicators preferably indicate different levels of importance. In one example, a particular one of a plurality of sensors does not agree with the other sensors for a critical function such as heart rate, breathing, infusion, and that sensor seldom malfunctions. Then, the visual indicator <b>70</b> may be a light that flashes on and off. Other visual indicators may include the continuous display of a color such as from a steady light.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Thus, the invention provides a system for generating alarms, where the system includes a plurality of sensors that sense functioning that indicates the same general condition such as heart beating, respiration, or infusion. The system generates a sound alarm indicating that a caregiver's attention is required immediately, only if all sensors indicate a patient malfunction for the particular condition. If one or more sensors indicate proper functioning, or at least temporarily acceptable functioning, then a visual indicator is operated, but a sound alarm is not sounded.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Although particular embodiments of the invention have been described and illustrated herein, it is recognized that modifications and variations may readily occur to those skilled in the art, and consequently, it is intended that the claims be interpreted to cover such modifications and equivalents.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. Apparatus for use in an intensive care unit of a medical care facility for monitoring a patient, comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of groups of sensors, each group of the plurality of groups of sensors including at least three sensors connected to the patient, wherein each of the at least three sensors of a particular group of sensors monitors a different corresponding physiological condition of the same organ of the patient that can fail is such a way that it threatens the life of the patient;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said apparatus further comprising:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a computer that has a plurality of inputs, each input is connected to a different one of the at least three sensors for each of the plurality of groups of sensors; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, each of the at least three sensors for each of the plurality of groups of sensors has an output that is representative of the corresponding physiological condition, and wherein the computer generates a sensor failure output for a particular sensor when the corresponding physiological condition of the patient is outside of a selected range, above or below a selected limit, or when a particular sensors is no longer connected to either the patient, the computer, or both; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, said computer is configured to operate a visual alarm when one or more of, but not all of, said sensors in one or more of the plurality of groups of sensors has a corresponding sensor failure output generated; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, said computer is further configured to operate a sound alarm only when all of the at least three sensors for at least one of the plurality of groups of sensors has a corresponding sensor failure output generated.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The apparatus described in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein:
<claim-text>said plurality of groups of sensors includes at least a first group of sensors that includes at least three heart function sensors; a second group of sensors that includes at least three breathing function sensors and a third group of sensors that include at least three infusion sensors.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The apparatus described in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> wherein:
<claim-text>said first group of sensors that includes at least three heart function sensors comprising:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first heart function sensor wherein the sensor failure output is generated when the patient heart rate is below a first selected limit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second heart function sensor wherein the sensor failure output is generated when the patient oxygen saturation is below a second selected limit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third heart function sensor wherein the sensor failure output is generated when the patient blood pressure is below a third selected limit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The apparatus described in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> wherein:
<claim-text>said second group of sensors that includes at least three breathing function sensors comprising:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first breathing function wherein the sensor failure output is generated when the patient heart beats below a predetermined magnitude or at a rate below a fourth selected limit, using an electrocardiogram;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second breathing function sensor wherein the sensor failure output is generated when the patient blood pressure is below a fifth selected limit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third breathing function sensor wherein the sensor failure output is generated when the patient partial pressure of CO2 is below a sixth selected limit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The apparatus described in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> wherein:
<claim-text>said third group of sensors that includes at least three infusion sensors comprising:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first infusion sensor that detects the flow rate of a liquid through a tube that leads into the patient and wherein the sensor failure output is generated when the flow rate is below a seventh selected limit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second infusion sensor that detects the height of said liquid in a bottle that connects to the patient and wherein the sensor failure output is generated when the height is below an eighth selected limit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third infusion sensor that detects the back pressure at the infusion site and wherein the sensor failure output is generated when the back pressure is above a ninth selected limit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The apparatus described in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein:
<claim-text>said computer has a recording circuit that records variations in the output of each of the at least three sensors in each of the plurality of groups of sensors over a predetermined time period; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>operates the sound alarm output only when the magnitude of variations for all of the at least three sensors for at least one of the plurality of groups of sensors exceeds a predetermined variation in said time period.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A method for use in an intensive care unit of a medical care facility for monitoring a patient, the method comprising:
<claim-text>providing a plurality of groups of sensors configured to be connected to the patient, wherein each group of the plurality of groups of sensors includes at least three sensors, and wherein each of the at least three sensors of a particular group monitors a different corresponding physiological condition of the same organ of the patient that can fail in a way that threatens the life of the patient;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, each of the at least three sensors for each of the plurality of groups of sensors has an output that is representative of the corresponding physiological condition;</claim-text>
<claim-text>connecting the outputs of each of the at least three sensors of each of said plurality of said groups of sensors, to a different one of a plurality of inputs of a computer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting, via the computer, that the corresponding physiological condition of the patient is outside of a selected range, above or below a selected limit, or that a particular sensor is no longer connected either to the patient or to the computer, or both and in response to the detecting, generating, via the computer, a sensor failure output;</claim-text>
<claim-text>analyzing the sensor outputs, via the computer, wherein the computer is configured to operate a visual alarm when one or more of, but not all of, said sensors in one or more of the plurality of groups of sensors has a corresponding sensor failure output generated, and to operate a sound alarm only when all of the at least three sensors for at least one of the plurality of groups of sensors has a corresponding sensor failure output generated. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
