<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622340-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622340</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13128259</doc-number>
<date>20091109</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>FR</country>
<doc-number>08 06381</doc-number>
<date>20081114</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>304</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>042</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>F</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>042</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>244 53B</main-classification>
<further-classification>137 151</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Air inlet of an aeroengine having unducted pusher propellers</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3765623</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Donelson et al.</name>
<date>19731000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>244 53 B</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3946830</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kutney et al.</name>
<date>19760300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4953812</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Van Der Hoeven</name>
<date>19900900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5156353</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Gliebe et al.</name>
<date>19921000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>244 54</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5743488</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Rolston et al.</name>
<date>19980400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>244 53 B</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5915403</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>McConachie et al.</name>
<date>19990600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>137 151</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6129309</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Smith et al.</name>
<date>20001000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>244 53 B</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7086219</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Stretton et al.</name>
<date>20060800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 602261</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0176052</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Chanez et al.</name>
<date>20070800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0258005</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Gall et al.</name>
<date>20081000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>FR</country>
<doc-number>2 892 705</doc-number>
<date>20070500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00012">
<othercit>International Search Report issued Mar. 10, 2010 in PCT/FR09/001295 filed Nov. 9, 2009.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>10</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>244 53 R</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>244 53 B</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>137 151</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110220217</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110915</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bensilum</last-name>
<first-name>Stephane Emmanuel Daniel</first-name>
<address>
<city>Alfortville</city>
<country>FR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>FR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bensilum</last-name>
<first-name>Stephane Emmanuel Daniel</first-name>
<address>
<city>Alfortville</city>
<country>FR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Oblon, Spivak, McClelland, Maier &#x26; Neustadt, L.L.P.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>SNECMA</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Paris</city>
<country>FR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Swiatek</last-name>
<first-name>Rob</first-name>
<department>3643</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/FR2009/001295</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20091109</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20110509</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2010/055224</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20100520</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An air intake for an aeroplane engine of type with unducted propellers, which intake can be connected by a pylon to a fuselage of an aeroplane, a local length of the air intake, measured parallel to the axis of the engine between a point on a leading edge of the air intake and a transverse plane situated at an inlet impeller of the engine compressor, is longer in a region of the air intake connected to the pylon and shorter in a region of the air intake opposite the pylon.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="109.47mm" wi="119.46mm" file="US08622340-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="180.59mm" wi="154.94mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622340-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="225.55mm" wi="148.76mm" file="US08622340-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="248.58mm" wi="154.60mm" file="US08622340-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="164.17mm" wi="137.58mm" file="US08622340-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to an air inlet of an aeroengine, and in particular an aeroengine having unducted pusher propellers (also known as an &#x201c;open-rotor pusher&#x201d; or a &#x201c;pusher unducted fan&#x201d;).</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">An engine of that type has two contrarotating turbines, each of which is constrained to rotate with a propeller that is situated outside the nacelle of the engine, the two propellers being arranged on a common axis one behind the other at the downstream end of the engine.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The engine is connected to an airplane via a pylon that extends substantially radially relative to the longitudinal axis of the engine and that has its radially inner end connected to the upstream end of the nacelle of the engine, i.e. to the air inlet of the engine.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The pylon must be at a sufficient axial distance from the propellers and from the upstream end or leading edge of the air inlet, in particular for aerodynamic reasons. In the prior art, it is necessary to lengthen the air inlet of the engine in the axial direction in order to enable the pylon to be connected to the air inlet and to the engine, and that gives rise to a significant increase in the weight of the nacelle and in the drag it generates in operation.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In the prior art, the air inlet of an engine having unducted pusher propellers is generally axisymmetric, i.e. its leading edge lies in a plane perpendicular to the axis of the engine. An axisymmetric air inlet has a ratio L/D that is constant all around its circumference, where L is the local length of the air inlet measured parallel to the axis of the engine between a point of the leading edge and a plane located at the upstream rotor of the engine, and where D is the inside diameter of the air inlet, at the position of said upstream rotor.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">When the air inlet is not axisymmetric, its leading edge defines a surface that is approximately plane and that is referred to as a &#x201c;capture&#x201d; section (also known as a &#x201c;hilite&#x201d; or &#x201c;high light&#x201d;). That type of air inlet has a defined overall air inlet length that is equal to the distance between the transverse plane at the upstream rotor of the engine and the point of intersection between the capture plane of the air inlet and the axis of the engine.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">For example, aeroengine air inlets are known that are of a chamfered (or &#x201c;scarfed&#x201d;) type in which the capture plane presents a marked angle of inclination relative to the longitudinal axis of the engine, the bottom portion of the air inlet projecting axially upstream relative to its top portion. An air inlet of that type is defined by a &#x201c;global&#x201d; L/D ratio (global length divided by diameter) and it presents a &#x201c;local&#x201d; L/D ratio (local length divided by diameter) that varies linearly around the circumference of the air inlet.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">That particular chamfered shape for the air inlet serves essentially to limit the noise emitted upstream by the engine towards the ground. The longer bottom portion of the chamfered air inlet serves to reflect and deflect upwards a large fraction of the noise that is emitted upstream by the engine while it is in operation. That type of engine is generally connected under the wing of an airplane by means of a pylon that is connected to the air inlet via its shorter top portion.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">A particular object of the invention is to propose a solution that is simple, effective, and inexpensive, to the above-mentioned problems associated with incorporating a pylon with the air inlet of an aeroengine having unducted pusher propellers.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">To this end, the invention proposes an air inlet of an aeroengine of the type having unducted pusher propellers, the engine being for connection via a pylon to the fuselage of an airplane, the air inlet being characterized in that the local length of the air inlet, measured parallel to the axis of the engine between a point of the leading edge of the air inlet and a transverse plane situated level with an upstream rotor of the compressor of the engine, is longer in the zone of the air inlet that is connected to the pylon, and shorter in the zone of the air inlet opposite from the pylon.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The local length of the air inlet of the invention varies around the circumference of the air inlet, being at a maximum in the zone connected to the pylon, and at a minimum in the opposite zone, unlike the prior art in which the shorter top portion of the chamfered air inlet is connected to the connection pylon. The shape and the dimensions of the air inlet zone connected to the pylon are optimized as a function of dimensioning the pylon, whereas the shape and the dimensions of the remainder of the air inlet are optimized independently of the pylon so as to limit the weight of the air inlet and the drag generated by the engine nacelle in operation.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The variation in the local length of the air inlet is non-linear around the circumference of the air inlet. Unlike the prior art, the capture section of the air inlet is not plane, and it is not possible to define the length of the air inlet of the invention by means of a &#x201c;global&#x201d; L/D ratio.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The &#x201c;local&#x201d; L/D ratio of the air inlet of the invention preferably lies in the range approximately 2.5 to 0.9 between the zone connected to the pylon and the opposite zone of the air inlet, where L is the local length of the air inlet, and D is its inside diameter, L and D being measured as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Advantageously, in a direction perpendicular to a midplane containing the axis of the pylon and the axis of the engine, the leading edge of the air inlet has an outline that is substantially in the form of a dihedral. By way of example, the angle at the apex of the dihedral lies in the range approximately 90&#xb0; to 175&#xb0;. The apex of the dihedral may present a concave rounded shape beside the opening of the dihedral. The sides of the dihedral may be substantially rectilinear, or they may be curved, being concave or convex.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Preferably, the air inlet is symmetrical relative to a midplane containing the axis of the pylon and the axis of the engine. The leading edge of the air inlet of the invention then defines two dihedrals situated on either side of that midplane and connected to each other via rounded portions.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The upstream sides of those two dihedrals lie in a first air inlet plane that is inclined relative to the axis of the engine, and the downstream sides of the dihedrals lie in a second air inlet plane that is inclined at a larger angle relative to the axis of the engine. Those two planes intersect, with the line of intersection between those two planes passing substantially through the apexes of the dihedrals. The air inlet of the invention is thus defined by two air inlet planes, unlike the single air inlet plane in the prior art.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In another aspect of the invention, the air inlet includes an axial projection, the pylon being designed to extend substantially axially and radially relative to the axis of the engine from said projection of the air inlet. The shape and the dimensions of this projection are determined as a function of the shape and the dimensions of the pylon. This projection may also be used for installing other bulky pieces of equipment of the engine.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The leading edge and/or the trailing edge of the pylon may be inclined at an angle lying in the range approximately 10&#xb0; to 35&#xb0; relative to a transverse plane.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The invention also provides an aeroengine having unducted pusher propellers, the engine including an air inlet as defined above.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Finally, the engine also provides an airplane, characterized in that it has two or more engines of the above-described type, the engines being connected to the rear of the airplane fuselage by means of pylons, on either side thereof. When the airplane has two engines, the connection pylon of each engine is preferably inclined at an angle lying in the range 5&#xb0; to 45&#xb0;, and for example at about 20&#xb0;, relative to a horizontal plane passing substantially through the end of the pylon that is connected to the fuselage. When the airplane has an additional engine, the pylon connecting that engine may lie in a plane that is substantially vertical. The third engine may be situated above the airplane fuselage.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The invention can be better understood and other details, characteristics, and advantages of the present invention appear more clearly on reading the following description that is given by way of non-limiting example and with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagrammatic axial section view of an engine having unducted pusher propellers;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a diagrammatic perspective view of an airplane fitted with two engines of the invention having unducted pusher propellers;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a view on a larger scale of one of the engines of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagrammatic perspective view of the nacelle and of the pylon of the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> engine;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a fragmentary diagrammatic side view of the nacelle and of the pylon of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, on a larger scale; and</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a fragmentary diagrammatic side view of another embodiment of the nacelle and of the pylon according to the invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Reference is made initially to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, which shows an aeroengine <b>10</b> having unducted pusher fans, the engine <b>10</b> comprising a turbomachine surrounded by a substantially axisymmetric nacelle <b>12</b> having an upstream end that forms an air inlet <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">From upstream to downstream in the flow direction of gas through the engine, the turbomachine comprises a compressor <b>14</b>, a combustion chamber <b>16</b>, an upstream high pressure turbine <b>18</b>, and two contrarotating low-pressure downstream turbines <b>20</b> and <b>22</b>, i.e. turbines that rotate in opposite directions about the longitudinal axis A of the engine.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Each downstream turbine <b>20</b>, <b>22</b> is constrained to rotate with an external propeller <b>24</b>, <b>26</b> that extends substantially radially outside the nacelle <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The air stream <b>28</b> that penetrates into the air inlet <b>13</b> passes through the compressor <b>14</b> where it is compressed, and is then mixed with fuel and burnt in the combustion chamber <b>16</b>, with the combustion gas then being injected into the turbines in order to drive the propellers <b>26</b>, <b>28</b> in rotation, which propellers provide the major fraction of the thrust from the engine. The combustion gas <b>30</b> leaving the turbines <b>20</b>, <b>22</b> is then ejected through a downstream nozzle <b>32</b> in order to increase the thrust from the engine.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The propellers <b>24</b>, <b>26</b> are situated in the vicinity of the downstream end of the engine and they are said to be pusher or propulsion propellers as opposed to external propellers situated upstream from the engine that would then be said to be puller propellers.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">This type of engine is connected to a portion of an airplane, such as its fuselage, by means of a pylon <b>34</b>, which pylon extends substantially radially relative to the axis A, outside the nacelle <b>12</b>, and needs to be at an axial distance X<b>1</b> that is sufficient from the leading edges of the blades of the upstream propeller <b>24</b> and at an axial distance X<b>2</b> that is sufficient from the leading edge <b>38</b> of the air inlet, in particular for aerodynamic reasons. It has therefore been necessary in the prior art to lengthen the air inlet <b>13</b> axially in order to enable the pylon <b>34</b> of the engine to be incorporated.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the air inlet <b>13</b> drawn in continuous lines presents an optimum minimum length in particular for channeling air to the compressor <b>16</b>, while the air inlet <b>13</b>&#x2032; drawn in discontinuous lines has been lengthened so as to allow the pylon <b>34</b> to be incorporated with the engine <b>10</b>. Nevertheless, lengthening the air inlet significantly increases the weight of the engine and the drag it generates in flight.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The air inlet <b>13</b> of the engine is profiled, and its upstream end or leading edge <b>38</b> that engages the air presents a section of convex rounded shape.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">An air inlet of an aeroengine may be defined in particular by a &#x201c;local&#x201d; L/D ratio, which in the example shown is constant over the entire circumference of the air inlet. D is the inside diameter of the air inlet <b>13</b> measured level with the first rotor or upstream rotor of the compressor <b>14</b>, and L is the local length of said air inlet measured parallel to the axis A between a point of the leading edge <b>38</b> and a transverse plane P situated level with the upstream rotor of the compressor <b>14</b>. In this example the air inlet <b>13</b> is axisymmetric and all of the points of the leading edge <b>38</b> are situated in the same transverse plane P<b>1</b> (or P<b>2</b> for the air inlet <b>13</b>&#x2032; having a leading edge <b>38</b>&#x2032;), referred to as its capture plane or section.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">An air inlet of an aeroengine may be defined in particular by a &#x201c;local&#x201d; L/D ratio, which in the example shown is constant over the entire circumference of the air inlet. D is the inside diameter of the air inlet <b>13</b> measured level with the first rotor or upstream rotor of the compressor <b>14</b>, and L is the local length of said air inlet measured parallel to the axis A between a point of the leading edge <b>38</b> and a transverse plane P situated level with the upstream rotor of the compressor <b>14</b>. In this example the air inlet <b>13</b> is axisymmetric and all of the points of the leading edge <b>38</b> are situated in the same transverse plane P<b>1</b> (or P<b>2</b> for the air inlet <b>13</b>&#x2032;), referred to as its capture plane or section.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The air inlet <b>13</b> drawn in continuous lines has a length L<b>1</b> (measured between P and P<b>1</b>) and it is defined by the ratio L<b>1</b>/D, and the air inlet <b>13</b>&#x2032; drawn in discontinuous lines has a length L<b>2</b> (measured between P and P<b>2</b>) and it is defined by the ratio L<b>2</b>/D.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The invention makes it possible to remedy the above-mentioned problems associated with lengthening the air inlet of the engine by means of an air inlet in which the ratio L/D is not constant but varies in non-linear manner around the circumference of the air inlet, the zone of the air inlet that has the greatest length being connected to the pylon.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 to 5</figref> show a preferred embodiment of the invention, in which the elements described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> are given the same numerical references, plus one hundred.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The airplane <b>140</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is fitted with two engines <b>110</b> having unducted pusher propellers, these engines being connected by pylons <b>134</b> to the rear of the airplane fuselage <b>141</b>, on either side thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">At its upstream end, the nacelle <b>112</b> of each engine <b>110</b> includes an air inlet <b>113</b> of the invention that has an axial projection <b>142</b> for connection with the pylon <b>134</b>. The pylon <b>134</b> extends substantially radial relative to the axis A of the engine, from the projection <b>142</b> of the air inlet outwards as far as the airplane fuselage <b>141</b>. The projection <b>142</b> of the air inlet is thus situated beside the airplane fuselage <b>141</b>. The pylon <b>134</b> is inclined at an angle &#x3b1; lying in the range 5&#xb0; to 45&#xb0;, and for example equal to about 20&#xb0;, relative to a horizontal plane passing substantially through the end of the pylon <b>134</b> connected to the fuselage <b>141</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The projection <b>142</b> is generally triangular or trapezoidal in shape with its apex or its small base situated upstream and with its (large) base situated downstream. The downstream base of the projection <b>142</b> extends angularly around the axis A over an angle that is less than or equal to about 180&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">This projection <b>142</b> forms the air inlet zone of greatest axial length, and its length measured in the above-mentioned plane P and in a transverse plane P<b>2</b>&#x2032; passing through the upstream end of the projection is referenced Lmax. This length Lmax is substantially equal to the length L<b>2</b> of the air inlet <b>13</b>&#x2032; of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, this air inlet <b>13</b>&#x2032; being lengthened in order to enable the pylon <b>34</b> to be incorporated with the engine.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The length Lmax serves to calculate the maximum value of the ratio L/D of the air inlet, which is equal to Lmax/D, and has a value of about 2.5, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The projection <b>142</b> is connected to a substantially annular portion <b>144</b> of the air inlet that extends around the axis A, and that defines the shortest zone of the air inlet. This portion <b>144</b> is diametrically opposite the projection <b>142</b>. The length of this portion <b>144</b>, measured between the plane P and a transverse plane P<b>1</b>&#x2032; passing through the downstream end of said portion, is referenced Lmin (the downstream end of the portion <b>144</b> being diametrically opposite the upstream end of the projection <b>142</b>). This length Lmin is substantially equal to the length L<b>1</b> of the air inlet <b>13</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, i.e. to the optimum minimum value for said air inlet, as determined independently of the pylon.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The length Lmin serves to calculate the minimum value of the ratio L/D of the air inlet, which ratio is equal to Lmin/D and has a value of about 0.9, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">When the air inlet <b>113</b> is seen from the side or in a direction perpendicular to the midplane passing through the axis A of the engine and the axis of the pylon <b>134</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the leading edge <b>138</b> defines a dihedral on either side of the axis A presenting a relatively large angle &#x3b2;, i.e. an angle greater than 90&#xb0;. This angle &#x3b2; is about 120&#xb0; to 150&#xb0; in the example shown.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The leading edge <b>138</b> of the air inlet thus defines, on either side of the midplane, a plurality of different air inlet lengths L&#x2032;, L&#x2033;, lying in the range Lmin to Lmax. These lengths make it possible to vary the ratio L/D of the air inlet all around its circumference. Unlike the prior art, the variation of this ratio is not linear (as it would be if the leading edge were to extend in a single inclined air-inlet plane), but rather it is non-linear, and for example is approximately hyperbolic or parabolic. This particular configuration of the leading edge <b>138</b> makes it possible to define at least two air inlet planes.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the leading edge <b>138</b> of the air inlet defines two intersecting planes P<b>3</b>, P<b>4</b> that are inclined relative to the axis A. The upstream first plane P<b>3</b> is defined by the portion of the leading edge of the projection <b>142</b> (or the upstream sides of the above-mentioned dihedral) and is inclined at an angle lying in the range approximately 15&#xb0; to 50&#xb0; relative to the axis A. The downstream second plane P<b>4</b> is defined by the portion of the leading edge of the air inlet portion <b>144</b> (or the downstream sides of the dihedral) and is inclined at an angle of about 70&#xb0; to 90&#xb0; relative to the axis A. These two planes P<b>3</b>, P<b>4</b> intersect substantially in the junction zones between the projection <b>142</b> and the annular portion <b>144</b> of the air inlet.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">As can also be seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the junction zone <b>146</b> between the air inlet <b>113</b> and the leading edge of the pylon <b>134</b> is situated in a transverse plane that extends between the transverse planes P<b>1</b>&#x2032; and P<b>2</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In the variant shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the leading edge <b>238</b> of the air inlet <b>213</b> of the nacelle <b>212</b> having an axial projection <b>242</b> defines, on either side of the axis A, a dihedral having an angle &#x3b2;&#x2032;, e.g. lying in the range about 90&#xb0; to 175&#xb0;. This angle &#x3b2;&#x2032; is about 170&#xb0; in the example shown.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">In the variant shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the leading edge <b>238</b> of the air inlet <b>213</b> defines, on either side of the axis A, a dihedral having an angle &#x3b2;&#x2032;, e.g. lying in the range about 90&#xb0; to 175&#xb0;. This angle &#x3b2;&#x2032; is about 170&#xb0; in the example shown.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In this example, the leading edge <b>250</b> of the pylon <b>234</b> is inclined relative to a plane perpendicular to the axis A of the engine, at an angle &#x3b3; lying in the range approximately 10&#xb0; to 35&#xb0;, and is preferably 20&#xb0;. The trailing edge <b>252</b> of the pylon <b>234</b> is also inclined relative to a plane perpendicular to the axis A, at an angle &#x3b3;&#x2032; lying in the range approximately 10&#xb0; to 35&#xb0;, and is preferably 20&#xb0;. The values of the angles &#x3b3; and &#x3b3;&#x2032; may be identical or different.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The pylon for connecting the engine to the airplane may also be inclined relative to a radial plane passing via the axis of the engine.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">In a variant embodiment of the invention, the axial projection of the air inlet enables bulky equipment of the engine to be incorporated other than a pylon.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An air inlet of an aeroengine including unducted pusher propellers, the engine being for connection via a pylon to a fuselage of an airplane,
<claim-text>wherein a local length of the air inlet, measured parallel to an axis of the engine between a point of a leading edge of the air inlet and a transverse plane situated level with an upstream rotor of the compressor of the engine is longer in a zone of the air inlet that is connected to the pylon, and shorter in a zone of the air inlet opposite from the pylon.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. An air inlet according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the ratio L/D lies in a range approximately 2.5 to 0.9 between the zone of the air inlet that is connected to the pylon and the opposite zone of the air inlet, L being the local length of the air inlet, and D being its inside diameter measured level with the upstream rotor of the engine compressor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. An air inlet according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein in a direction perpendicular to a midplane including the axis of the pylon and the axis of the engine, the leading edge of the air inlet has an outline that is substantially in a form of a dihedral.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. An air inlet according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the angle at the apex of the dihedral lies in a range 90&#xb0; to 175&#xb0;.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. An air inlet according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the apex of the dihedral has a concave rounded shape beside an open side of the dihedral.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. An air inlet according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, comprising an axial projection projecting upstream, the pylon configured to extend substantially radially relative to the axis of the engine from the projection.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. An air inlet according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the air inlet is symmetrical about a plane including a midplane of the pylon containing the axis of the engine.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. An air inlet according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the leading edge and/or the trailing edge of the pylon are/is inclined at an angle lying in a range approximately 10&#xb0; to 35&#xb0;, relative to a transverse plane.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. An aeroengine including unducted pusher propellers, the aeroengine being for connection via a pylon to a fuselage of an airplane and comprising:
<claim-text>an air inlet,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a local length of the air inlet, measured parallel to an axis of the engine between a point of a leading edge of the air inlet and a transverse plane situated level with an upstream rotor of the compressor of the engine is longer in a zone of the air inlet that is connected to the pylon, and shorter in a zone of the air inlet opposite from the pylon.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. An airplane comprising at least two engines according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, the two engines connected by pylons to a rear of the fuselage of the airplane, on either side thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
