<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625171-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625171</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13285066</doc-number>
<date>20111031</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-254391</doc-number>
<date>20101115</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>252</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>23</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>358474</main-classification>
<further-classification>358300</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Image forming apparatus</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5062003</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kawabata</name>
<date>19911000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>358300</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>06-305185</doc-number>
<date>19941100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>11-231244</doc-number>
<date>19990800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2005-192076</doc-number>
<date>20050700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>8</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>358474</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>358300</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>11</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>13</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120120459</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120517</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ono</last-name>
<first-name>Yasuhiro</first-name>
<address>
<city>Osaka</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ono</last-name>
<first-name>Yasuhiro</first-name>
<address>
<city>Osaka</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Renner, Otto, Boiselle &#x26; Sklar, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Sharp Kabushiki Kaisha</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Osaka</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Baker</last-name>
<first-name>Charlotte M</first-name>
<department>2672</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Grisham</last-name>
<first-name>Rury</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A cover member holds an optical scanning device and is supported on A main body in such a manner as to be pivotable between an open position and a closed position. The optical scanning device has a shutter member, a housing, and a dustproof member. The main body has a contact member which is capable of coming into contact with the shutter member through an opening. The contact member causes the shutter member to be displaced between an optical path closing position and an optical path opening position. The shutter member includes a closing portion which closes the opening when the shutter member assumes the optical path closing position. The dustproof member is disposed to extend around the opening on the outside and is configured to press against an entire periphery of the contact member when the cover member assumes the closed position.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="102.36mm" wi="196.85mm" file="US08625171-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="220.22mm" wi="186.27mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625171-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="171.45mm" wi="180.34mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625171-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="208.87mm" wi="180.09mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625171-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="231.31mm" wi="180.34mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625171-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="213.53mm" wi="175.85mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625171-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="212.85mm" wi="174.41mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625171-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="237.24mm" wi="178.82mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625171-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="240.20mm" wi="175.18mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625171-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="251.29mm" wi="179.58mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625171-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="254.68mm" wi="160.19mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625171-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="249.77mm" wi="128.61mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625171-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This Nonprovisional application claims priority under 35 U.S.C.&#xa7;119(a) on patent application Ser. No. 2010-254391 filed in Japan on Nov. 15, 2010, the entire contents of which are hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to an image forming apparatus including a main body and a cover member which are pivotally supported on each other at their one end for pivotal movement relative to each other, and an optical scanning device held by the cover member.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">An electrophotographic image forming apparatus includes an optical scanning device and an image forming section. Laser light emitted from the optical scanning device is applied onto an electrostatic latent image bearing member incorporated in the image forming section and the resulting electrostatic latent image is subjected to an electrophotographic process for forming an image on a recording sheet.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Preferably, such an image forming apparatus is easily openable to expose the interior thereof so that the image forming section and like sections can be subjected to maintenance. On the other hand, the image forming apparatus has to prevent laser light from leaking out during the maintenance because the laser light is narrowed down to form a very small spot and hence has high energy.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In attempt to satisfy such requirements, a known image forming apparatus, as described in Japanese Patent Laid-Open Publication No. HEI6-305185 for example, includes a main body and a cover member which are coupled to each other at their one end for pivotal movement relative to each other, and a shutter member disposed on the optical path of laser light so as to be movable up and down, wherein when the cover member is closed, a projection presses up the shutter member to open the optical path, whereas when the cover member is opened, the projection retracts to cause the shutter member to move down by its own weight thereby to close the optical path.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">With the image forming apparatus described in Japanese Patent Laid-Open Publication No. HEI6-305185, however, the projection provided on the main body passes through a through-hole provided in the cover member along an arcuate locus as the main body and the cover member pivot relative to each other about their one end and, therefore, the projection and the through-hole have to define a clearance therebetween. For this reason, the clearance defined between the projection and the through-hole may allow dust to pass therethrough and enter the inside of the optical scanning device.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Accordingly, a feature of the present invention is to provide an image forming apparatus capable of preventing dust from entering the inside of an optical scanning device provided with a shutter member which is displaceable between an optical path closing position and an optical path opening position.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">An image forming apparatus according to the present invention includes a main body and a cover member. The cover member holds an optical scanning device and is supported on the main body in such a manner as to be pivotable between a predetermined open position and a predetermined closed position. The optical scanning device has a light source for emitting laser light, a shutter member which is displaceable between an optical path closing position for closing an optical path of the laser light and an optical path opening position for opening the optical path, a housing accommodating the light source and the shutter member therein and having an opening at a bottom surface facing the main body, and a dustproof member having elasticity. The main body has a contact member which is capable of coming into contact with the shutter member through the opening and which becomes positioned away from the shutter member to cause the shutter member to assume the optical path closing position when the cover member assumes the open position while coming into contact with the shutter member to cause the shutter member to assume the optical path opening position when the cover member assumes the closed position. The shutter member includes a closing portion which closes the opening from inside the housing when the shutter member assumes the optical path closing position. The dustproof member is disposed on an outer side of the housing in such a manner as to extend around the opening and is configured to press against an entire periphery of the contact member when the cover member assumes the closed position.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">With this arrangement, when the image forming apparatus is in normal operation, namely, when the cover member assumes the closed position, the contact member comes into contact with the shutter member to cause the shutter member to assume the optical path opening position, so that an image forming process is ready to be carried out. By the dustproof member pressing against the entire periphery of the contact member, the opening is closed from outside the housing. On the other hand, when the image forming apparatus is subjected to maintenance, namely, when the cover member assumes the open position, the contact member is positioned away from the shutter member to cause the shutter member to assume the optical path closing position. Accordingly, laser light, even when emitted from the light source by malfunction or the like, is blocked within the housing of the optical scanning device and hence can be prevented from leaking out of the housing. In addition, the shutter member closes the opening from inside the optical scanning device. Thus, the opening is closed during both of the normal operation and the maintenance.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to the present invention, it is possible to prevent dust from entering the inside of the optical scanning device provided with the shutter member which is displaceable between the optical path closing position and the optical path opening position.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> is a sectional side elevational view schematically illustrating the structure of an image forming apparatus in a closed condition according to an embodiment of the present invention, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> is a sectional side elevational view schematically illustrating the structure of the image forming apparatus in an open condition according to the embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a sectional plan view schematically illustrating the structure of an optical scanning device;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view, as viewed from the rear side, of the optical scanning device in a state in which a shutter member is in an optical path opening position while a housing is partially removed;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is an enlarged view illustrating a first end portion of the shutter member shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an enlarged view illustrating a second end portion of the shutter member shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a perspective view, as viewed from the rear side, of the optical scanning device in a state in which the shutter member is in an optical path closing position while the housing is partially removed;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is an enlarged view illustrating the first end portion of the shutter member shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is an enlarged view illustrating the second end portion of the shutter member shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a perspective view, as viewed from the rear side, of a cover member in an inverted position;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10A</figref> is a partially enlarged sectional view of the image forming apparatus in the closed condition, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10B</figref> is a partially enlarged sectional view of the image forming apparatus in transition from the closed condition to the open condition; and</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a sectional side elevational view of the image forming apparatus in a state in which some parts are removed.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Hereinafter, embodiments of the present invention will be described with reference to the attached drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A and 1B</figref>, an image forming apparatus <b>10</b> includes a main body <b>20</b> and a cover member <b>30</b>. One end portion of the cover member <b>30</b> is pivotally supported on one end portion of the main body <b>20</b> in such a manner that the cover member <b>30</b> can pivot relative to the main body <b>20</b> within a predetermined range. Thus, when the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> is placed with the main body <b>20</b> positioned below the cover member <b>30</b>, the cover member <b>30</b> can pivot relative to the main body <b>20</b> to assume a closed position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> and an open position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref>. During image formation, the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> is in a closed condition in which the cover member <b>30</b> is in the closed position. During maintenance for replacement of a developing unit <b>73</b> to be described later, for replacement of a photoreceptor unit including a photoreceptor drum <b>71</b> to be described later, or for other maintenance operations, on the other hand, the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> is in an open condition in which the cover member <b>30</b> is in the open position.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The cover member <b>30</b> holds therein a scanner unit <b>40</b> and an optical scanning device <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The scanner unit <b>40</b> is placed in an upper portion of the cover member <b>30</b>. The scanner unit <b>40</b> includes a document platen <b>41</b>, a document platen cover <b>42</b>, and a CIS (contact image sensor) <b>43</b>. The CIS <b>43</b>, which is an example of an image reading section, may be replaced with a scanning unit incorporating a CCD (charge coupled device) sensor and optical components.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The document platen cover <b>42</b> can pivot about an axis extending along an end portion on the same side as the end portion about which the main body <b>20</b> and the cover member <b>30</b> are pivotally supported relative to each other, thereby opening and closing the top surface of the document platen <b>41</b>. The CIS <b>43</b> is located below the document platen <b>41</b> and reads an image from a document placed on the document platen <b>41</b> to generate image data by moving along the document platen <b>41</b> in a secondary scanning direction.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The optical scanning device <b>50</b> is disposed in a bottom portion of the cover member <b>30</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the optical scanning device <b>50</b> includes a semiconductor laser (i.e., light source) <b>51</b>, a collimator lens <b>52</b>, a cylindrical lens <b>53</b>, a polygon mirror <b>54</b>, a first f&#x3b8; lens <b>55</b>, a second f&#x3b8; lens <b>56</b>, a reflecting mirror <b>57</b>, a shutter member <b>60</b>, and a housing <b>58</b> accommodating these components therein. The housing <b>58</b> has dustproof glass <b>59</b> below the reflecting mirror <b>57</b>, the dustproof glass <b>59</b> being elongated in a primary scanning direction <b>91</b>, which is a scanning direction of laser light.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The polygon mirror <b>54</b> is driven by a non-illustrated motor to rotate at a high velocity in a predetermined direction. The semiconductor laser <b>51</b> emits laser light according to the image data. The laser light emitted from the semiconductor laser <b>51</b> passes through the collimator lens <b>52</b> and cylindrical lens <b>53</b> and is then deflected at an equiangular velocity by the polygon mirror <b>54</b>, which is deflecting means. Thereafter, the laser light becomes incident on the first f&#x3b8; lens <b>55</b> and on the second f&#x3b8; lens <b>56</b> and is then directed by the reflecting mirror <b>57</b> toward the main body <b>20</b> through the dustproof glass <b>59</b> to perform scanning at a constant velocity in the primary scanning direction <b>91</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The shutter member <b>60</b> is disposed on the optical path between the second f&#x3b8; lens <b>56</b> and the reflecting mirror <b>57</b>. The shutter member <b>60</b> will be specifically described later.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The main body <b>20</b> includes an electrophotographic processing section <b>70</b> and a sheet feeding section <b>80</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The electrophotographic processing section <b>70</b> includes the photoreceptor drum <b>71</b> as an electrostatic latent image bearing member, an electrostatic charger device <b>72</b>, a developing unit <b>73</b>, a transfer device <b>74</b>, a cleaning unit <b>75</b>, and a fixing device <b>76</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The electrostatic charger device <b>20</b> is configured to electrostatically charge a peripheral surface of the photoreceptor drum <b>71</b> to a predetermined potential. The laser light emitted from the semiconductor laser <b>51</b> passes through the dustproof glass <b>59</b> and is then applied onto the peripheral surface of the photoreceptor drum <b>71</b> to form thereon an electrostatic latent image according to the image data.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The developing unit <b>73</b> is removably mounted on the main body <b>20</b>. The developing unit <b>73</b> is configured to develop the electrostatic latent image into a toner image by supplying toner (i.e., developer) to the peripheral surface of the photoreceptor drum <b>71</b>. The transfer device <b>74</b> is configured to transfer the toner image onto a recording sheet fed from the sheet feeding section <b>80</b>. The cleaning unit <b>75</b> is configured to recover residual toner that remains on the peripheral surface of the photoreceptor drum <b>71</b> after the transfer of the toner image onto the recording sheet. The fixing device <b>76</b> is configured to fix the toner image to the recording sheet securely by heating and pressurizing the recording sheet bearing the toner image thereon.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the shutter member <b>60</b> is elongated in the primary scanning direction <b>91</b> and is pivotally supported on the housing <b>58</b> at its opposite end portions in the primary scanning direction <b>91</b>. The shutter member <b>60</b> is displaceable between an optical path opening position for opening the optical path of the laser light as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 to 5</figref> and an optical path closing position for closing the optical path of the laser light as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 to 8</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The shutter member <b>60</b> has through-holes <b>61</b> and <b>62</b> at its opposite end portions which are located outside a region extending in the primary scanning direction <b>91</b> through which the laser light passes (hereinafter will be referred to as &#x201c;optical path region&#x201d;) at the position of the shutter member <b>60</b>. The housing <b>58</b> is provided with guide portions <b>581</b> and <b>582</b> inserted in the respective through-holes <b>61</b> and <b>62</b>. The guide portions <b>581</b> and <b>582</b> have a slightly smaller dimension in the primary scanning direction <b>91</b> than the through-holes <b>61</b> and <b>62</b>. The guide portions <b>581</b> and <b>582</b> extend in the direction in which the shutter member <b>60</b> is displaceable and have such a length as can be inserted in the through-holes <b>61</b> and <b>62</b> whether the shutter member <b>60</b> is in the optical path opening position or in the optical path closing position. This feature can prevent the shutter member <b>60</b> from being displaced in the primary scanning direction <b>91</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The opposite end portions of the shutter member <b>60</b> in the primary scanning direction <b>91</b> are provided with coil springs <b>63</b> and <b>64</b> (of which the coil spring <b>63</b> is not shown) as exemplary biasing members. The coil springs <b>63</b> and <b>64</b> bias the shutter member <b>60</b> in the direction from the optical path opening position toward the optical path closing position.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the housing <b>58</b> has openings <b>583</b> and <b>584</b> at its bottom surface facing the main body <b>20</b>. The openings <b>583</b> and <b>584</b> are located at positions which lie outside the optical path region and are opposed to the opposite end portions of the shutter member <b>60</b> in the primary scanning direction <b>91</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The shutter member <b>60</b> has closing portions <b>65</b> and <b>66</b> at positions opposed to the respective openings <b>583</b> and <b>584</b>. When the shutter member <b>60</b> is in the optical path closing position, the closing portions <b>65</b> and <b>66</b> close the openings <b>583</b> and <b>584</b>, respectively, from inside the optical scanning device <b>50</b>. The closing portions <b>65</b> and <b>66</b> are each shaped like a plate for example.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A</figref>, <b>1</b>B, <b>10</b>A and <b>10</b>B, the closing portions <b>65</b> and <b>66</b> have projections <b>67</b> and <b>68</b>, respectively, which project toward the main body <b>20</b>. (The projection <b>67</b> is not shown.)</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The main body <b>20</b> is provided with contact members <b>21</b> and <b>22</b> projecting toward the cover member <b>30</b> (of which the contact member <b>21</b> is not shown). The contact members <b>21</b> and <b>22</b> are capable of coming into contact with the respective projections <b>67</b> and <b>68</b> of the shutter member <b>60</b> through the respective openings <b>583</b> and <b>584</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">When the cover member <b>30</b> assumes the closed position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>, the contact members <b>21</b> and <b>22</b> come into contact with the respective projections <b>67</b> and <b>68</b> through the respective openings <b>583</b> and <b>584</b> to press up the shutter member <b>60</b> into the optical path opening position, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10A</figref>. This allows the laser light to be applied to the photoreceptor drum <b>71</b> without blockage by the shutter member <b>60</b> during normal operation, namely, when the cover member <b>30</b> is in the closed position.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Dustproof members <b>585</b> and <b>586</b> having elasticity are disposed on the outer side of the housing <b>58</b> so as to extend around the respective openings <b>583</b> and <b>584</b>. (The dustproof member <b>585</b> is not shown.) Each of the dustproof members <b>585</b> and <b>586</b> is shaped annular and extends around the entire periphery of the associated one of the openings <b>583</b> and <b>584</b>. Each of the dustproof members <b>585</b> and <b>586</b> is designed to press against the entire periphery of the associated one of the contact members <b>21</b> and <b>22</b> when the cover member <b>30</b> is in the closed position. The dustproof members <b>585</b> and <b>586</b> are formed from urethane sponge for example. Since each of the dustproof members <b>585</b> and <b>586</b> presses against the entire periphery of the associated one of the contact members <b>21</b> and <b>22</b> when the cover member <b>30</b> is in the closed position, the openings <b>583</b> and <b>584</b> are closed from outside the housing <b>58</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">When the cover member <b>30</b> starts being displaced from the closed position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> toward the open position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref>, the optical scanning device <b>50</b> becomes positioned away from the contact members <b>21</b> and <b>22</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10B</figref>, so that the shutter member <b>60</b> is caused to pivot down into the optical path closing position by the elastic force of the coil springs <b>63</b> and <b>64</b>. Thus, the closing portions <b>65</b> and <b>66</b> of the shutter member <b>60</b> are pressed against the openings <b>583</b> and <b>584</b> from inside the housing <b>58</b>. After the closing portions <b>65</b> and <b>66</b> have come into contact with the respective openings <b>583</b> and <b>584</b>, the dustproof members <b>585</b> and <b>586</b> are separated from the peripheries of the respective contact members <b>21</b> and <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">During maintenance, namely, when the cover member <b>30</b> is in the open position, the shutter member <b>60</b> assumes the optical path closing position. For this reason, laser light, even when emitted from the semiconductor laser <b>51</b> by malfunction or the like, is blocked within the housing <b>51</b> and hence can be prevented from leaking out of the housing <b>58</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">When the cover member <b>30</b> is in the open position, the closing portions <b>65</b> and <b>66</b> of the shutter member <b>60</b> are pressed against the openings <b>583</b> and <b>584</b> from inside the housing <b>58</b> and, hence, the openings <b>583</b> and <b>584</b> are closed from inside the housing <b>58</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The image forming apparatus <b>10</b> thus constructed is capable of preventing laser light from leaking out of the housing <b>58</b> during maintenance while applying laser light onto the photoreceptor drum <b>71</b> during normal operation. Further, since the openings <b>583</b> and <b>584</b> are closed during both of the normal operation and the maintenance, the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> is capable of preventing the entry of dust into the housing <b>58</b> of the optical scanning device <b>50</b> provided with the shutter member <b>60</b> which is displaceable between the optical path closing position and the optical path opening position. Therefore, the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> can avoid degradation in image quality due dust entering the inside of the housing <b>58</b> of the optical scanning device <b>50</b> and floating over the optical path of laser light.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Preferably, the length of the contact members <b>21</b> and <b>22</b> and the thickness of the dustproof members <b>585</b> and <b>586</b> are established such that when the cover member <b>30</b> moves from the open position to the closed position, the closing portions <b>65</b> and <b>66</b> open the respective openings <b>583</b> and <b>584</b> after the dustproof members <b>585</b> and <b>586</b> have come into contact with the peripheries of the respective contact members <b>21</b> and <b>22</b>, whereas when the cover member <b>30</b> moves from the closed position to the open position, the dustproof members <b>585</b> and <b>586</b> are separated from the peripheries of the respective contact members <b>21</b> and <b>22</b> after the closing portions <b>65</b> and <b>66</b> have closed the openings <b>583</b> and <b>584</b>. This feature allows the openings <b>583</b> and <b>584</b> to be constantly closed from outside or inside the housing <b>58</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Alternatively, the length of the contact members <b>21</b> and <b>22</b> and the thickness of the dustproof members <b>585</b> and <b>586</b> may be established such that when the cover member <b>30</b> moves from the open position to the closed position, the shutter member <b>60</b> is displaced from the optical path closing position to the optical path opening position after the dustproof members <b>585</b> and <b>586</b> have come into contact with the peripheries of the respective contact members <b>21</b> and <b>22</b>, whereas when the cover member <b>30</b> moves from the closed position to the open position, the dustproof members <b>585</b> and <b>586</b> are separated from the peripheries of the respective contact members <b>21</b> and <b>22</b> after the shutter member <b>60</b> has been displaced from the optical path opening position to the optical path closing position.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Though the closing portions <b>65</b> and <b>66</b> need not necessarily be provided with the projections <b>67</b> and <b>68</b>, the provision of the projections <b>67</b> and <b>68</b> on the closing portions <b>65</b> and <b>66</b> makes it possible to shorten the projecting length of the contact members <b>21</b> and <b>22</b> by a length equal to the length of the projections <b>67</b> and <b>68</b>, thereby to suppress degradation in user's handleability due to the contact members <b>21</b> and <b>22</b> projecting long.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The contact members <b>21</b> and <b>22</b> are preferably located on the developing unit <b>73</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A and 1B</figref>. The developing unit <b>73</b> is removably mounted on the main body <b>20</b> as described above. Therefore, with the developing unit <b>73</b> being removed from the main body <b>20</b>, the shutter member <b>60</b> is always in the optical path closing position without displacement to the optical path opening position. Thus, laser light, even when emitted from the semiconductor laser <b>51</b> by malfunction or the like, is blocked within the housing <b>58</b> of the optical scanning device <b>50</b> and hence can be prevented from leaking out of the housing <b>58</b> of the optical scanning device <b>50</b> when the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> is not ready to carry out the image forming process.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Since the guide portions <b>581</b> and <b>582</b> have such a length as can be inserted in the through-holes <b>61</b> and <b>62</b> whether the shutter member <b>60</b> is in the optical path opening position or in the optical path closing position, the shutter member <b>60</b> can be prevented from being displaced in the primary scanning direction <b>91</b>. Accordingly, it is possible to prevent communication between the inside and the outside of the housing <b>58</b> that occurs due to displacement of the closing portions <b>65</b> and <b>66</b> relative to the openings <b>583</b> and <b>584</b>. This feature can also prevent dust from entering the inside of the housing <b>58</b> of the optical scanning device <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Since the shutter member <b>60</b> is pivotally supported on the housing <b>58</b> of the optical scanning device <b>50</b> as described above, the shutter member <b>60</b> pivots between the optical path closing position and the optical path opening position. For this reason, the optical scanning device <b>50</b> can be made smaller in size than an optical scanning device having a shutter member designed to move linearly.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Preferably, the optical scanning device <b>50</b> is supported on the cover member <b>30</b> so as to be shakable within a predetermined range while being biased in a direction away from the cover member <b>30</b> by springs <b>31</b> to <b>34</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>) forming an exemplary elastic member, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>. In the present embodiment, the optical scanning device <b>50</b> is supported on the cover member <b>30</b> by means of stepped screws <b>35</b> to <b>38</b> so as to be movable toward and away from the cover member <b>30</b> within a predetermined range while being biased in a direction away from the cover member <b>30</b> by springs <b>31</b> to <b>34</b> fitted over the respective stepped screws <b>31</b> to <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">With the arrangement in which the optical scanning device <b>50</b> is supported on the cover member <b>30</b> so as to be shakable within the predetermined range while being biased in the direction away from the cover member <b>30</b>, the optical scanning device <b>50</b> is pressed against the main body <b>20</b> when the cover member <b>30</b> is in the closed position. Thus, the distance between the optical scanning device <b>50</b> and the photoreceptor drum <b>71</b> is made constant when the cover member <b>30</b> is in the closed position. Therefore, the positional precision of scanning by the optical scanning device <b>50</b> relative to the peripheral surface of the photoreceptor drum <b>71</b> can be enhanced.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Further, with the arrangement in which the optical scanning device <b>50</b> is supported on the cover member <b>30</b> so as to be shakable within the predetermined range while being biased in the direction away from the cover member <b>30</b>, the dustproof members <b>585</b> and <b>586</b> and the main body <b>20</b> are pressed against each other at an increased pressure when the cover member <b>30</b> is in the closed position, so that the openings <b>583</b> and <b>584</b> are closed with improved tightness.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Even when the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> is placed with its main body <b>20</b> positioned above the cover member <b>30</b>, the openings <b>583</b> and <b>584</b> can be closed reliably during both of the normal operation and the maintenance and, hence, the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> can exercise the effect of preventing dust from entering the inside of the housing <b>58</b> of the optical scanning device <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Even when only one pair of the through-hole <b>61</b> or <b>62</b> and the guide portion <b>581</b> or <b>582</b> is provided at one of the opposite end portions in the primary scanning direction <b>91</b>, the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> can exercise the effect of preventing the shutter member <b>60</b> from being displaced in the primary scanning direction <b>91</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Further, the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> may have a feature such that the shutter member <b>60</b> is provided with a biasing member at its one end portion only in the primary scanning direction <b>91</b> so as to be biased in the direction from the optical path opening position toward the optical path closing position.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The image forming apparatus <b>10</b> may be provided with only one pair of the opening <b>583</b> or <b>584</b> and the closing portion <b>65</b> or <b>66</b> which is located at one end portion of the shutter member <b>60</b> in the primary scanning direction <b>91</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">In the present invention, the provision of the scanner unit <b>40</b> is not an essential requirement.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The foregoing embodiments are illustrative in all points and should not be construed to limit the present invention. The scope of the present invention is defined not by the foregoing embodiments but by the following claims. Further, the scope of the present invention is intended to include all modifications within the scopes of the claims and within the meanings and scopes of equivalents.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An image forming apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a main body; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cover member holding an optical scanning device and supported on the main body in such a manner as to be pivotable between a predetermined open position and a predetermined closed position, wherein:</claim-text>
<claim-text>the optical scanning device has a light source for emitting laser light, a shutter member which is displaceable between an optical path closing position for closing an optical path of the laser light and an optical path opening position for opening the optical path, a housing accommodating the light source and the shutter member therein and having an opening at a bottom surface facing the main body, and a dustproof member having elasticity;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the main body has a contact member which is capable of coming into contact with the shutter member through the opening and which becomes positioned away from the shutter member to cause the shutter member to assume the optical path closing position when the cover member assumes the open position while coming into contact with the shutter member to cause the shutter member to assume the optical path opening position when the cover member assumes the closed position;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the shutter member includes a closing portion which closes the opening from inside the housing when the shutter member assumes the optical path closing position; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the dustproof member is disposed on an outer side of the housing in such a manner as to extend around the opening and is configured to press against an entire periphery of the contact member when the cover member assumes the closed position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The image forming apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the length of the contact member and the thickness of the dustproof member are established such that when the cover member moves from the open position to the closed position, the closing portion opens the opening after the dustproof member has come into contact with the periphery of the contact member, whereas when the cover member moves from the closed position to the open position, the dustproof member is separated from the periphery of the contact member after the closing portion has closed the opening.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The image forming apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the length of the contact member and the thickness of the dustproof member are established such that when the cover member moves from the open position to the closed position, the shutter member is displaced from the optical path closing position to the optical path opening position after the dustproof member has come into contact with the periphery of the contact member, whereas when the cover member moves from the closed position to the open position, the dustproof member is separated from the periphery of the contact member after the shutter member has been displaced from the optical path opening position to the optical path closing position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The image forming apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the shutter member has a projection for contact with the contact member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The image forming apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the main body has a removable developing unit configured to develop an electrostatic latent image formed by the optical scanning unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the contact member is provided on the developing unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The image forming apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the shutter member is pivotally supported on the housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The image forming apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the shutter member has a through-hole; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the housing has a guide portion inserted in the through-hole to inhibit the shutter member from moving in a scanning direction of the laser light.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The image forming apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the optical scanning device is supported on the cover member in such a manner as to be shakable within a predetermined range while being biased by an elastic member in a direction away from the cover member. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
