<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624338-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624338</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13101443</doc-number>
<date>20110505</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>162</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>29</main-group>
<subgroup>82</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257415</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Multi-nanometer-projection apparatus for lithography, oxidation, inspection, and measurement</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8003982</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Wang et al.</name>
<date>20110800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257 43</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0176947</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>An et al.</name>
<date>20050800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>536 237</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0273424</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Wodnicki et al.</name>
<date>20081100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>367180</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0199392</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Singh et al.</name>
<date>20090800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 29594</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2012/0228995</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Mohamadi</name>
<date>20120900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>310319</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00006">
<othercit>Y.R. Ma et al., &#x201c;Tip-Induced Local Anodic Oxidation on the Native SiO2 Layer of Si(111) Using an Atomic Force Microscope&#x201d;, Physical Review B, vol. 64, 195324-1 through 195324-5, 2001.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00007">
<othercit>A. Majumdar et al., &#x201c;Nanometer-Scale Lithography Using the Atomic Force Microscope&#x201d;, Appl. Phys. Letter 61, (19) Nov. 9, 1992, pp. 2293-2295.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>19</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257415</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120280333</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121108</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tsai</last-name>
<first-name>Fei-Gwo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tainan</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yu</last-name>
<first-name>Chwen</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tsai</last-name>
<first-name>Fei-Gwo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tainan</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yu</last-name>
<first-name>Chwen</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Haynes and Boone, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company, Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Hsin-Chu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Tran</last-name>
<first-name>Thien F</first-name>
<department>2895</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An apparatus, method for manufacturing the apparatus, and method for processing a substrate using the apparatus are disclosed. An exemplary apparatus includes a substrate having a plurality of cells, wherein each cell includes a cell structure. The cell structure includes a piezoelectric film portion and a tip disposed over the piezoelectric film portion. The tip is physically coupled with the piezoelectric film portion.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="144.27mm" wi="247.48mm" file="US08624338-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="182.63mm" wi="162.73mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624338-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="255.02mm" wi="152.48mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624338-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="152.48mm" wi="153.84mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624338-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="216.58mm" wi="153.84mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624338-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="214.71mm" wi="158.92mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624338-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="201.85mm" wi="149.35mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624338-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The semiconductor integrated circuit (IC) industry has experienced rapid growth. In the course of IC evolution, functional density (i.e., the number of interconnected devices per chip area) has generally increased while geometry size (i.e., the smallest component (or line) that can be created using a fabrication process) has decreased. This scaling down process generally provides benefits by increasing production efficiency and lowering associated costs. Such scaling down has also increased the complexity of processing and manufacturing ICs and, for these advances to be realized, similar developments in IC manufacturing are needed.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure is best understood from the following detailed description when read with the accompanying figures. It is emphasized that, in accordance with the standard practice in the industry, various features are not drawn to scale and are used for illustration purposes only. In fact, the dimensions of the various features may be arbitrarily increased or reduced for clarity of discussion.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a top view of an apparatus that uses multiple tips to process a device substrate according to various aspects of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view of a portion of the apparatus of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> according to various aspects of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view of a cell of the apparatus of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> according to various aspects of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a perspective view of a process performed on a device substrate using an apparatus having multiple tips according to various aspects of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective view of another process performed on a device substrate using an apparatus having multiple tips according to various aspects of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flow chart of a method for processing a device substrate using an apparatus having multiple tips according to various aspects of the present disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The following disclosure provides many different embodiments, or examples, for implementing different features of the invention. Specific examples of components and arrangements are described below to simplify the present disclosure. These are, of course, merely examples and are not intended to be limiting. For example, the formation of a first feature over or on a second feature in the description that follows may include embodiments in which the first and second features are formed in direct contact, and may also include embodiments in which additional features may be formed between the first and second features, such that the first and second features may not be in direct contact. In addition, the present disclosure may repeat reference numerals and/or letters in the various examples. This repetition is for the purpose of simplicity and clarity and does not in itself dictate a relationship between the various embodiments and/or configurations discussed.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Further, spatially relative terms, such as &#x201c;beneath,&#x201d; &#x201c;below,&#x201d; &#x201c;lower,&#x201d; &#x201c;above,&#x201d; &#x201c;upper&#x201d; and the like, may be used herein for ease of description to describe one element or feature's relationship to another element(s) or feature(s) as illustrated in the figures. The spatially relative terms are intended to encompass different orientations of the device in use or operation in addition to the orientation depicted in the figures. For example, if the device in the figures is turned over, elements described as being &#x201c;below&#x201d; or &#x201c;beneath&#x201d; other elements or features would then be oriented &#x201c;above&#x201d; the other elements or features. Thus, the exemplary term &#x201c;below&#x201d; can encompass both an orientation of above and below. The apparatus may be otherwise oriented (rotated 90 degrees or at other orientations) and the spatially relative descriptors used herein may likewise be interpreted accordingly.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a top view of an apparatus <b>100</b> according to various aspects of the present disclosure. The apparatus <b>100</b> uses multiple tips to process a device substrate (wafer), for example, an integrated circuit device substrate. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> has been simplified for the sake of clarity to better understand the inventive concepts of the present disclosure. Additional features can be added in the apparatus <b>100</b>, and some of the features described below can be replaced or eliminated in other embodiments of the apparatus <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The apparatus <b>100</b> includes a substrate (wafer) <b>110</b>. In the depicted embodiment, the substrate <b>110</b> is a silicon substrate. The substrate <b>110</b> may be made of any silicon-containing material. Alternatively or additionally, the substrate <b>110</b> includes an elementary semiconductor, such as germanium; compound semiconductor including silicon carbide, gallium arsenic, gallium phosphide, indium phosphide, indium arsenide, and/or indium antimonide; an alloy semiconductor including SiGe, GaAsP, AlInAs, AlGaAs, GaInAs, GaInP, and/or GaInAsP; or combinations thereof. In yet another alternative, the substrate <b>110</b> is a semiconductor on insulator (SOI).</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Alignment marks <b>120</b> are disposed in the substrate <b>110</b>. The alignment marks <b>120</b> are configured so that the substrate <b>110</b> may be aligned with the device substrate to be processed. The alignment marks <b>120</b> may include a polysilicon structure, a metal structure, a dielectric structure, or a combination thereof. The apparatus <b>100</b> may include fewer or more alignment marks <b>120</b> than those illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The substrate <b>110</b> includes cells <b>130</b>. As discussed further below, each cell <b>130</b> includes a cell structure that includes a tip that may be used for processing the device substrate. For example, the tip may be used to perform lithography processes, oxidation processes, inspection processes, measurement processes, other suitable process, or combinations thereof, on the device substrate. In the depicted embodiment, each cell <b>130</b> has a substantially square shape. In an example, a length of each cell <b>130</b> is about 60 &#x3bc;m to about 140 &#x3bc;m, and a width of each cell <b>130</b> is about 60 &#x3bc;m to about 140 &#x3bc;m. In an example, each cell <b>130</b> has a length of about 100 &#x3bc;m and a width of about 100 &#x3bc;m. Alternatively, the cells <b>130</b> may have shapes other than substantially square shaped.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Isolation features <b>140</b> are disposed in the substrate <b>110</b>. In the depicted embodiment, an isolation feature <b>140</b> surrounds each cell <b>130</b>, isolating the cells <b>130</b> from one another. The isolation features <b>140</b> utilize isolation technology, such as local oxidation of silicon (LOCOS) and/or shallow trench isolation (STI), to define and/or electrically isolate the various cells <b>130</b> and/or other regions of the substrate <b>110</b>. In the depicted embodiment, the isolation features <b>140</b> are trenches, specifically shallow trench isolation trenches, that are filled with a dielectric material, such as silicon oxide, silicon nitride, silicon oxynitride, other suitable material, or combinations thereof. The isolation features <b>140</b> may be formed by any suitable process. As one example, forming an STI includes using a lithography process to expose portions of the substrate, etching a trench in each respective exposed portion of the substrate (for example, by using a dry etching process and/or a wet etching process), and filling the trench (for example, by using a chemical vapor deposition process) with one or more dielectric materials. For example, the filled trench may have a multi-layer structure, such as a thermal oxide liner layer filled with silicon nitride or silicon oxide.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view of a portion <b>160</b> of the apparatus <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> according to various aspects of the present disclosure. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> has been simplified for the sake of clarity to better understand the inventive concepts of the present disclosure. For example, in the depicted embodiment, the substrate <b>110</b> and isolation features <b>140</b> are omitted from the perspective view of the portion <b>160</b> of the apparatus <b>100</b>. Additional features can be added in the portion <b>160</b> of the apparatus <b>100</b>, and some of the features described below can be replaced or eliminated in other embodiments of the portion <b>160</b> of the apparatus <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The portion <b>160</b> of the apparatus <b>100</b> includes four cells <b>130</b> including cell structures. Alternative examples may include more of less cells <b>130</b> than illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. Each cell <b>130</b> includes a piezoelectric feature <b>170</b>. The piezoelectric feature <b>170</b> includes a piezoelectric material, such as berlinite (AlPO<sub>4</sub>), quartz (SiO<sub>2</sub>), gallium orthophosphate (GaPO<sub>4</sub>), langasite (La<sub>3</sub>Ga<sub>5</sub>SiO<sub>14</sub>), barium titanate (BaTiO<sub>3</sub>), lead titanate (PbTiO<sub>3</sub>), lead zirconate titanate (Pb[Zr<sub>x</sub>Ti<sub>1-x</sub>]O<sub>3</sub>) (PZT), potassium niobate (KNbO<sub>3</sub>), lithium niobate (LiNbO<sub>3</sub>), lithium tantalate (LiTaO<sub>3</sub>), sodium tungstate (Na<sub>2</sub>WO<sub>3</sub>), Ba<sub>2</sub>NaNb<sub>5</sub>O<sub>5</sub>, Pb<sub>2</sub>KNb<sub>5</sub>O<sub>15</sub>, sodium potassium niobate (NaKNb), bismuth ferrite (BiFeO<sub>3</sub>), sodium niobate (NaNbO3), other piezoelectric material, or combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Each cell <b>130</b> also includes a tip that is physically coupled with the piezoelectric feature <b>170</b>. In the depicted embodiment, the tip includes a base portion <b>172</b> and a tip portion <b>174</b>. The base portion <b>172</b> is disposed over the piezoelectric film portion <b>170</b>, and the tip portion <b>174</b> is disposed over the base portion <b>172</b>. In the depicted embodiment, the base portion <b>172</b> includes a semiconductor material, such as silicon. The silicon base portion <b>172</b> may be doped n-type or p-type. Alternatively or additionally, the base portion <b>172</b> may include other materials, such as silicon nitride. Further, in the depicted embodiment, the tip portion <b>174</b> includes a conductive material, such as platinum. Alternatively or additionally, the tip portion <b>174</b> may include other conductive material, such as PtIr or TiN. In an example, the tip has a curvature radius of about 5 nm to about 10 nm. In an example, an area of each tip is about 0.01 mm<sup>2</sup>. In an example, each tip can write a line width of about 10 nm to about 20 nm.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Various biasing features <b>180</b>, <b>182</b>, <b>184</b>, and <b>186</b> are electrically coupled with respective piezoelectric features <b>170</b>. In the depicted embodiment, the biasing features <b>180</b>, <b>182</b>, <b>184</b>, and <b>186</b> include a conductive material, such as copper, aluminum, other suitable conductive material, or combinations thereof. The biasing features <b>180</b>, <b>182</b>, <b>184</b>, and <b>186</b> may apply a bias voltage to respective piezoelectric features <b>170</b> to change a shape of the respective piezoelectric features <b>170</b>. By biasing the piezoelectric features <b>170</b>, each piezoelectric feature <b>170</b> controls a position (and movement) of its respective tip, specifically a position (and movement) of the base portion <b>172</b> and the tip portion <b>174</b>. More specifically, each tip may be moved in an x direction, y direction, and/or z direction by biasing its respective piezoelectric feature <b>170</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view of a cell <b>130</b> of the apparatus <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> according to various aspects of the present disclosure. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> has been simplified for the sake of clarity to better understand the inventive concepts of the present disclosure. For example, in the depicted embodiment, the substrate <b>110</b> and isolation features <b>140</b> are omitted from the perspective view of the cell <b>130</b> of the apparatus <b>100</b>. Additional features can be added in the cell <b>130</b> of the apparatus <b>100</b>, and some of the features described below can be replaced or eliminated in other embodiments of the cell <b>130</b> of the apparatus <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The cell <b>130</b> includes a cell structure having the piezoelectric feature <b>170</b> and a tip physically coupled with the piezoelectric feature <b>170</b>. The tip includes the base portion <b>172</b> and the tip portion <b>174</b>. In the depicted embodiment, biasing features <b>190</b> and <b>192</b> are electrically coupled with the piezoelectric feature <b>170</b>. Similar to biasing features <b>180</b>, <b>182</b>, <b>184</b>, and <b>186</b>, the biasing features <b>190</b> and <b>192</b> may apply a bias voltage to piezoelectric feature <b>170</b> to change a shape of the piezoelectric feature <b>170</b>. By biasing the piezoelectric feature <b>170</b>, the piezoelectric feature <b>170</b> can control a position (and movement) of the tip, specifically a position (and movement) of the base portion <b>172</b> and the tip portion <b>174</b>. More specifically, each tip may be moved in an x direction, y direction, and/or z direction by biasing the piezoelectric feature <b>170</b>. In the depicted embodiment, a biasing feature <b>194</b> is electrically coupled with the tip (base portion <b>172</b>/tip portion <b>174</b>). The biasing feature <b>194</b> may apply a bias voltage to the tip so that the tip processes the device substrate according to the applied bias voltage. In an example, a bias voltage of about 10 V to about 100 V may be applied to the tip via the biasing feature <b>194</b> to achieve various processing of the device substrate. For example, the bias voltage may be tuned, such that the tips write a particular line width.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a perspective view of a process performed on a device substrate using an apparatus <b>200</b> having multiple tips according to various aspects of the present disclosure. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> has been simplified for the sake of clarity to better understand the inventive concepts of the present disclosure. Additional features can be added in the apparatus <b>200</b> and the device substrate, and some of the features described below can be replaced or eliminated in other embodiments of the apparatus <b>200</b> and the device substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The apparatus <b>200</b> includes a substrate (wafer) <b>210</b> having an array of cell structures <b>230</b>. Each cell structure includes a piezoelectric feature <b>232</b> and a tip having a base portion <b>234</b> and a tip portion <b>236</b>. The tip is physically coupled with the piezoelectric feature <b>232</b>. The substrate <b>210</b>, piezoelectric feature <b>232</b>, base portion <b>234</b>, and tip portion <b>236</b> are respectively similar to the substrate <b>110</b>, piezoelectric feature <b>170</b>, base portion <b>172</b>, and tip portion <b>174</b> described above. Biasing features (not illustrated) are electrically coupled with each cell structure <b>230</b>. In an example, each cell structure <b>230</b> includes a biasing feature electrically coupled with the piezoelectric feature <b>232</b> and a biasing feature electrically coupled with the tip (base portion <b>234</b>/tip portion <b>236</b>). The apparatus <b>200</b> further includes conductive features <b>240</b> electrically coupled with the substrate <b>210</b>, which can be used to apply the various bias voltages to the biasing features, and thus to the piezoelectric features <b>232</b> and tips of the apparatus <b>200</b>, to achieve processing of the device substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The apparatus <b>200</b> is positioned over a wafer stage <b>250</b>, which has a device substrate <b>260</b> positioned thereon. The device substrate may be a semiconductor substrate, a mask blank, a glass substrate, a flat panel substrate, or other suitable substrate. The device substrate may include a recording medium, such as an energy sensitive resist (or material) layer, formed thereon. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the apparatus <b>200</b> performs a lithography process on the device substrate <b>260</b> without using a mask. The lithography process is performed by applying various biases to each cell structure <b>230</b> of the apparatus <b>200</b> to expose the device substrate <b>260</b>, such that the device substrate <b>260</b> records a pattern (or design) therein. In the depicted embodiment, the exposed device substrate <b>260</b> has been developed, such that it includes various patterns <b>262</b>. The patterns <b>262</b> may be formed by trenches disposed in the device substrate <b>260</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">More specifically, various biasing voltages are applied to the piezoelectric features <b>232</b> of each cell structure <b>230</b> to position each corresponding tip in the x-direction, y-direction, and/or z-direction. Various biasing voltages are also applied to the tips to achieve the desired patterns <b>262</b> as the apparatus <b>200</b> is scanned across the device substrate <b>260</b>. As the apparatus <b>200</b> is brought in close proximity to the device substrate <b>260</b>, the various bias voltages applied to the array of cell structures <b>230</b> can cause electron reactions between the apparatus <b>200</b> and the device substrate <b>260</b> at various locations. For example, various biases can be applied to the tips of the cell structures <b>230</b> to cause the tips to act as an electron beam writer, such that electrons emitted from the tips of the cell structures <b>230</b> break chemical bonds of an energy sensitive layer disposed over the device substrate <b>260</b>. Where the patterns <b>262</b> formed in the device substrate <b>260</b>, the tips of the cell structures <b>230</b> corresponding with the patterns <b>262</b> were positioned proximate to the device substrate <b>260</b> via the biasing voltages applied to the corresponding piezoelectric features <b>232</b>, and the tips were biased to cause an electron reaction between the apparatus <b>200</b> and certain locations of the device substrate <b>260</b>, such that bonds of the exposed device substrate <b>260</b> were broken down. Essentially, the tips of the apparatus <b>200</b> facilitate an electron beam type reaction between the apparatus <b>200</b> and the device substrate <b>260</b>. It is understood that a biasing voltage may also be applied to the device substrate <b>260</b>. Accordingly, various biasing may be applied to the apparatus <b>200</b> and the device substrate <b>260</b> to achieve various patterning results.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective view of another process performed on a device substrate using the apparatus <b>200</b> having multiple tips according to various aspects of the present disclosure. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> has been simplified for the sake of clarity to better understand the inventive concepts of the present disclosure. Additional features can be added in the apparatus <b>200</b> and the device substrate, and some of the features described below can be replaced or eliminated in other embodiments of the apparatus <b>200</b> and the device substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the apparatus <b>200</b> is positioned over the wafer stage <b>250</b>, which has a device substrate <b>270</b> positioned thereon. The device substrate <b>270</b> is similar to the device substrate <b>260</b>. In the depicted embodiment, the device substrate <b>270</b> is a semiconductor substrate including silicon. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the apparatus <b>200</b> performs an oxidation process on the device substrate <b>270</b> without using a mask. The oxidation process is performed by applying various biases to each cell structure <b>230</b> of the apparatus <b>200</b> to form oxide features <b>272</b>, such as silicon oxide features, over the device substrate <b>270</b>. More specifically, various biasing voltages are applied to the piezoelectric features <b>232</b> of each cell structure <b>230</b> to position each corresponding tip in the x-direction, y-direction, and/or z-direction. Various biasing voltages are also applied to the tips to achieve the desired oxide features <b>272</b> as the apparatus <b>200</b> is scanned across the device substrate <b>270</b>. As the apparatus <b>200</b> is brought in close proximity to the device substrate <b>270</b>, the various bias voltages applied to the array of cell structures <b>230</b> can cause electron reactions between the apparatus <b>200</b> and the device substrate <b>270</b> at various locations. For example, where the oxide features <b>272</b> form over the device substrate <b>270</b>, the tips of the cell structures <b>230</b> corresponding with the oxide features <b>272</b> were positioned proximate to the device substrate <b>270</b> via the biasing voltages applied to the corresponding piezoelectric features <b>232</b>, and the tips were biased to cause an electron reaction between the apparatus <b>200</b> and the device substrate <b>270</b>, such that the various oxide features <b>272</b> were formed. Essentially, the tips of the apparatus <b>200</b> facilitate an electron beam type reaction between the apparatus <b>200</b> and the device substrate <b>270</b>. It is understood that a biasing voltage may also be applied to the device substrate <b>270</b>. Accordingly, various biasing may be applied to the apparatus <b>200</b> and the device substrate <b>270</b> to achieve various oxidation results.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flow chart of a method <b>300</b> for processing a device substrate using an apparatus having multiple tips according to various aspects of the present disclosure. The method <b>300</b> begins at block <b>310</b> where a first substrate is provided over a second substrate for processing. The first substrate has a plurality of cells, each cell including a piezoelectric portion and a tip coupled with the piezoelectric portion. The first substrate may be the apparatus described herein, such as the apparatus <b>100</b> or the apparatus <b>200</b>. The second substrate <b>200</b> may be a device substrate, such as an integrated device substrate. At block <b>320</b>, a first bias voltage is applied to the piezoelectric portion of each cell, such that each tip is positioned for a process to be performed on the second substrate. For example, each tip may be positioned in the x-direction, the y-direction, and/or the z-direction. At block <b>330</b>, a second bias voltage is applied to the tip of each cell, such that the process is performed on the second substrate. The first and second bias voltages may achieve a lithography process (in other words, patterns the second substrate such as that described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) or an oxidation process (in other words, forms oxide features over the second substrate such as that described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) on the second substrate. Using the first substrate, the lithography and oxidation processes may be performed on the second substrate without using a mask. The first and second bias voltages may also perform a measurement process (for example, a process that evaluates a profile of the second substrate) or an inspection process (for example, a process that evaluates the profile for defects and/or contamination). The first and second voltages may also perform various other process on the second substrate. Additional steps can be provided before, during, and after the method <b>300</b>, and some of the steps described can be replaced or eliminated for other embodiments of the method.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In an example, a test substrate that is similar to the first substrate may be pre-scan the second substrate before performing the process on the second substrate. The test substrate includes a plurality of cells, each cell including a piezoelectric portion and a tip coupled with the piezoelectric portion. The test substrate may be the apparatus described herein, such as the apparatus <b>100</b> or the apparatus <b>200</b>. In contrast to the first substrate, the test substrate includes tips that are larger than the tips of the first substrate. The pre-scan with the test substrate may remove particles from the second substrate before the first substrate performs the process. This can advantageously extend the life of the first substrate for device substrate processing.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In an example, the first substrate includes tips that write line widths of about 10 nm to about 20 nm on the second substrate. The line width written can be adjusted by varying the bias current or position height applied to the tips of each cell. For example, the bias current of a tip of the first substrate may be varied to write line widths of about 10 nm to about 20 nm on a first stripe. If a line width greater than 20 nm is desired, adjacent first and second tips may be biased to achieve the desired line width. For example, to write a line having a width of about 23 nm on the second substrate, a bias current of the first tip of the first substrate may be adjusted to write a line having a width of about 11 nm as a first stripe on the second substrate, and a bias current of the adjacent second tip of the first substrate may be adjusted to write a line width of about 12 nm as a second stripe on the second substrate. The first and second stripes would combine to form a line (or stripe) on the second substrate that has a width of about 23 nm.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The disclosed multi-tip apparatus is particularly useful for processing as technology nodes continually scale down, such as to 20 nm technology nodes and below. For example, lithography processes and oxidation processes may be performed with the multi-tip apparatus described herein without using a mask, which can reduce processing time and costs. Further, using the apparatus for performing the oxidation process can eliminate thermal budgets typically required in conventional processing. The multi-tip apparatus can also be used to perform inspection and measurement processes. It has also been observed that the multi-tip apparatus can facilitate electron beam type reactions with the processed substrate without suffering from issues that typically arise in conventional electron beam writing, such as electron space charging effects and/or secondary electron defects. Different embodiments may have different advantages, and no particular advantage, such as those described above, is necessarily required of any embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The present disclosure provides for many different embodiments. For example, an apparatus for processing a substrate (or wafer) is disclosed. An exemplary apparatus includes a substrate having a plurality of cells. Each cell includes a cell structure having a piezoelectric film portion, and a tip disposed over the piezoelectric film portion. The tip is physically coupled with the piezoelectric film portion. The apparatus may further include a first biasing feature electrically coupled with the piezoelectric film portion, where the piezoelectric film portion and the first biasing feature are configured such that a position of the tip adjusts when the first biasing feature varies a first bias applied to the piezoelectric film portion. The apparatus may further include a second biasing feature electrically coupled with the tip, where the tip and the second biasing feature are configured such that the tip processes another substrate according to a second bias applied to the tip by the second biasing feature. The first biasing feature may include aluminum, copper, or a combination thereof. The second biasing feature may include aluminum, copper, or a combination thereof. The substrate may include silicon. In an example, the tip includes a first portion disposed over the piezoelectric film portion, and a second portion disposed over the first portion. The first portion may include a semiconductor material, such as silicon. The second portion includes a conductive material, such as platinum. In an example, the tip has a curvature radius of about 5 nm to about 10 nm. The tip may have a tip area of about 0.01 mm<sup>2</sup>. The plurality of cells may be isolated from one another by an isolation features, such as a shallow trench isolation (STI) feature.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In another example, a method for processing a substrate (or wafer) with the apparatuses described herein is provided. An exemplary method includes providing a first substrate over a second substrate for processing, wherein the first substrate has a plurality of cells, each cell including a piezoelectric portion and a tip coupled with the piezoelectric portion; applying a first bias voltage to the piezoelectric portion of each cell, such that each tip is positioned for a process to be performed on the second substrate; and applying a second bias voltage to the tip of each cell, such that the process is performed on the second substrate. The method may further include varying the first bias to the piezoelectric portion of each cell during the process performed on the second substrate. Applying the first bias to the piezoelectric portion of each cell such that each tip is positioned for the process to be performed on the second substrate may include controlling movement of each tip in an x, y, and z direction. Applying the second bias to the tip of each cell such that the process is performed on the second substrate may include performing a lithography process on the second substrate, performing an oxidation process on the second substrate, or performing one of a measurement process and an inspection process to the second substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In yet another example, a method for fabricating the apparatuses described herein is provided. An exemplary method includes forming a plurality of piezoelectric features on a substrate; and forming a plurality of tips over the plurality of piezoelectric features, such that each piezoelectric feature is physically coupled with one of the plurality of tips. The method may further include forming a plurality of first biasing features, such that each piezoelectric feature is electrically coupled with one of the plurality of first biasing features. The method may further include forming a plurality of second biasing features, such that each tip is electrically coupled with one of the plurality of second biasing features.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The foregoing outlines features of several embodiments so that those skilled in the art may better understand the aspects of the present disclosure. Those skilled in the art should appreciate that they may readily use the present disclosure as a basis for designing or modifying other processes and structures for carrying out the same purposes and/or achieving the same advantages of the embodiments introduced herein. Those skilled in the art should also realize that such equivalent constructions do not depart from the spirit and scope of the present disclosure, and that they may make various changes, substitutions, and alterations herein without departing from the spirit and scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a substrate having a plurality of cells, wherein each cell includes a cell structure having:
<claim-text>a piezoelectric film portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a tip disposed over the piezoelectric film portion, the tip being physically coupled with the piezoelectric film portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first biasing feature electrically coupled with the piezoelectric film portion, the piezoelectric film portion and the first biasing feature being configured such that a position of the tip adjusts when the first biasing feature varies a first bias applied to the piezoelectric film portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further including a second biasing feature electrically coupled with the tip, the tip and the second biasing feature configured such that the tip processes another substrate according to a second bias applied to the tip by the second biasing feature.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> wherein the first biasing feature and the second biasing feature include one of aluminum and copper.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the substrate includes silicon.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the tip includes a first portion disposed over the piezoelectric film portion and a second portion disposed over the first portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> wherein:
<claim-text>the first portion includes a semiconductor material; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second portion includes a conductive material.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> wherein:
<claim-text>the semiconductor material is silicon; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the conductive material is platinum.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the tip has a curvature radius of about 5 nm to about 10 nm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the tip has a tip area of less than or equal to about 0.01 mm<sup>2</sup>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the plurality of cells are isolated from one another by a shallow trench isolation (STI) feature.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. An apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a substrate having a plurality of cells, wherein each cell includes a cell structure having:
<claim-text>a piezoelectric film portion formed of a first material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a tip disposed over the piezoelectric film portion, the tip being physically coupled with the piezoelectric film portion, wherein the tip is formed of a second material that is different than the first material; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a biasing feature electrically coupled with the piezoelectric film portion, wherein the biasing feature applies a bias to the piezoelectric film portion to change a shape of the piezoelectric film portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the second material includes a semiconductor material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the second material includes a conductive material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the second material includes a semiconductive material and a conductive material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the second material includes a conductive material disposed over and physically contacting a semiconductive material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. An apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a substrate having a plurality of cells, wherein the plurality of cells are isolated from one another by an isolation feature, wherein each cell includes a cell structure having:
<claim-text>a piezoelectric film portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a tip disposed over the piezoelectric film portion, the tip being physically coupled with the piezoelectric film portion, wherein the tip includes a conductive portion disposed over a semiconductive portion, wherein the conductive portion is different than the semiconductive portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the isolation feature includes a shallow trench isolation feature.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the conductive portion physically contact the semiconductive portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, further comprising a biasing feature electrically coupled with the piezoelectric film portion, wherein the biasing feature applies a bias to the piezoelectric film portion to change a shape of the piezoelectric film portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
