<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08621771-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08621771</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12589559</doc-number>
<date>20091026</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>549</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>09</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>17</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 40218</main-classification>
<further-classification>116173</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Machine for controllably flying a flag in the absence of natural wind</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2122766</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Wiemer</name>
<date>19380700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 40215</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5692328</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Pettit</name>
<date>19971200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 40218</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7017510</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Nair</name>
<date>20060300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>116173</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>19</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 40218</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>116173</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>116174</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>25</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110094133</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110428</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Amalaha</last-name>
<first-name>Leonard Dozie</first-name>
<address>
<city>Alexandria</city>
<state>VA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Amalaha</last-name>
<first-name>Leonard Dozie</first-name>
<address>
<city>Alexandria</city>
<state>VA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Silbermann</last-name>
<first-name>Joanne</first-name>
<department>3611</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A machine for controllably flying a flag indoors or outdoors in the absence of natural wind; said machine constituted of a base member having enough depth to house and protect electronic and/or electro-mechanical drive components etc.; said drive components including, but not limited to at least one electric motor mechanically coupled to a drive shaft of a cylindrical centrifugal fan via pulleys; said fan, as well as an air foil member and a flag pole housed in a long tubular wind pipe rigidly secured atop aforementioned base member in such a manner that when the aforesaid motor(s) actuates the aforesaid fan member via the aforesaid shaft, air pulled in through holes on the wind pipe is blown past the aforesaid airfoil, and then past the flagpole and attached flag, thereby causing said flag to rise and flap in the natural manner; an airfoil angle of attack knob atop the aforementioned wind pipe, in conjunction with a motor speed control knob atop the aforementioned base member, providing affective means of changing or modifying the flying pattern or flapping of aforesaid flag; a synthesized music circuit consisting of several songs preferably national anthems or state songs programmed into its memory is looped together with a programmable timer and an LCD display and control panel for permitting timed actuations of the machine ala electronic alarms.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="182.37mm" wi="115.49mm" file="US08621771-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="181.27mm" wi="196.17mm" file="US08621771-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="120.48mm" wi="188.30mm" file="US08621771-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="156.29mm" wi="194.65mm" file="US08621771-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="152.40mm" wi="188.55mm" file="US08621771-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="130.05mm" wi="172.47mm" file="US08621771-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="183.56mm" wi="174.24mm" file="US08621771-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="241.13mm" wi="208.87mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621771-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="237.57mm" wi="197.95mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621771-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This invention discloses a means of flying a flag in the absence of natural wind. The means for producing wind is achieved by a long body centrifugal fan having a long shaft which is driveably coupled to a motor in the enclosure housing of the base member. An airfoil member confronting the fan permits the change of angle of attack of the air blown past a long flag pole and an attached flag at its upper portion thereof, thereby changing the way the flag flies. The angle of attack of the airfoil is changed by turning a knob atop the wind pipe housing which encloses the fan, the airfoil and flag pole. A motor speed control potentiometer type knob is mounted atop the base member and allow variation of motor speed and hence the amount of air the fan can blow past the flag, thereby helping to modify the flag's behavior as well. Adjusting the angle of attack via the knob can result in balance or unbalancing of the aerodynamic forces acting on either side of the flag in such a manner as to cause it to fly straight, lean, sway gently or develop a unique flapping pattern, or a combination of the above attitudes.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This invention can be used indoors or outdoors. The indoors version can be placed on a night stand in a bedroom, an office table or any suitable flat surface. The outdoors version can be mounted on a concrete base with large bolts and having a windpipe about the height of standard street flag poles. The main difference between the two types is that owing to the great height of the outdoors version's pole, angle of attack adjustments is achieved via two different methods. The first method employs a hand crank mounted atop the base and coupled to the shaft of the airfoil via gears. The second method employs a stepper motor mounted atop aforesaid base and coupled mechanically to the airfoil shaft via gears. This motor may be remotely operated as well.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In another embodiment of this invention, the electronic circuit includes in addition to the motor circuit, an automatic battery charging circuit which permits A/C power charging via an adapter, a digital timing circuit for setting actuation times which are displayed on an LCD screen mounted on the lower edge of the wind pipe or atop the base, and a microcomputer chip controlled musical tunes generating circuit; said musical tunes pre-programmed in the chip's memory, selectable and preferably several national anthems of several countries and/or popular state adopted or nationally popular songs. Examples of such songs may include, but not limited to &#x2018;Living in America&#x2019; by James Brown, &#x2018;Georgia on My Mind&#x2019; by Ray Charles, &#x2018;God Bless the USA/Proud to be an American&#x2019; by Lee Greenwood, &#x2018;West Virginia/Take Me Home Country Roads&#x2019; by John Denver, etc. The electrical/electronic arrangement may be such that the sequential actuation of the flag and the music constitute an alarm system that can be programmed to come on at a predetermined time and play one or more songs before the duration settings in the control chip's memory cuts it out.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In yet another embodiment of this invention, the drive motor in the base drives the fan shaft directly via bevel gears, thereby reducing the number of the moving parts. However, direct drive gear systems are naturally inherently noisier than belt driven systems and may therefore be suitable for the outdoor's version.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In one more embodiment of this invention, a pivoting lamp and a control switch are mounted atop the base. The switch is an on/off switch which when in the ON position, allows the light to come on together with the actuation of the flag or on its own, while illuminating the flag in each case.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Still another embodiment of this invention provides a means for &#x2018;secure hold&#x2019; of an angle of attack selected via the knob from being changed by aerodynamic lift coefficient forces acting on the airfoil; said &#x2018;secure hold&#x2019; means consisting of a spring loaded position selector pin movably attached to the lower end of the airfoil shaft via a hole thru said shaft such that a grooved stator arrestingly permits several positions to be selected.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In one last, but not least embodiment of this invention, a method is presented for rigidly coupling a drive shaft to a cylindrical centrifugal fan without welding and/or screws. The shaft and fan arrangement according to my teachings permits stacking of several fans which may be rigidly and quickly riveted together such that the resultant long stacked fan array is considerably stronger than a single long fan. This arrangement is necessary to reduce unwanted fan oscillations in large long length systems. These fans can be molded out of plastics in the conventional manner or made of metals such as steel or aluminum. Two blade configurations are presented, namely inwardly and outwardly canted blades. Fan end shaft coupling holes have at least one flat side, half moon shape to match and tightly fit the drive shaft which is rigidly coupled to the fan's end flanges by means of C or E clips for quick assembly and disassembly.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a machine for controllably flying a flag in the absence of natural wind.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref></p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a sectional view taken along line Y-Y<b>1</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> to show movement of air around airfoil by coanda effect.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a sectional view of the angle of attach selection mechanism.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a top plan view of the angle of attack selection mechanism depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a view of the inner face of the top cover of the wind pipe depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> and taken along line X-X<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a view into the base member of the flag flying machine depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> and taken along line Z-Z<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a perspective view of another embodiment of this invention showing a direct drive arrangement of the fan shaft shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, employing bevel gears and located along line V-V<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a sectional view showing the method of coupling the flange of the wind pipe to the top of the base member.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a top view of the angle of attack knob shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, showing adjustment markings.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a top view of the motor speed control knob shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, showing adjustment markings.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a perspective view of a conventional static slot tensioner used to tension the drive belt of this invention.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a view of the inner face of the bottom cover of the base member shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is a sectional view of another embodiment of this invention depicting a hand crank method for modifying angle of attack on the outdoors model.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is a sectional view of another embodiment of this invention depicting an angle of attack modifying means for the outdoors model, employing a stepper motor.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15A</figref> is a top cross-sectional view of the gear arrangements shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> or <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref> is a possible configuration for the control panel for this invention, intended for explanatory purposes, but not limiting.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</figref> is an exploded view of a cylindrical (centrifugal) fan assembly employed in this invention as another embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</figref> is a top plan view of a fan assembly having outwardly canted blades.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</figref> is a top plan view of a fan assembly having inwardly canted blades.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</figref> is a sectional view of a pulley and fan shaft coupling method employing a locking nut.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</figref> is a partial cross-section of the fan arrangement shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</figref>, assembled.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</figref> is an exploded view of airfoil and its shaft employed in this invention to modify angle of attack.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</figref> is a schematic block diagram of the programmable electronic control circuit of the flag flying machine depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</figref> is a schematic block diagram of another embodiment of this invention depicting a non-programmable control circuit of the flag flying machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the machine for flying a flag in the absence of natural wind A has a base member A<b>1</b> and a wind pipe A<b>2</b>. The base member A<b>1</b> has a top mounted lamp <b>17</b> pivotably mounted on a mounting bracket <b>17</b>A and a lamp switch <b>38</b> for turning on the lamp if desired, for illuminating the flag <b>36</b>. There is a motor speed control knob <b>16</b> for adjusting motor speed. <b>40</b> represents the electronic control panel while <b>41</b> represents the LCD panel mounted above the flange <b>26</b> of the wind pipe <b>25</b>. The pipe <b>25</b> is provided with air vents <b>34</b> from which the fan sucks in air. The top cover <b>30</b> of the wind pipe <b>25</b> is held in place by screws <b>37</b>. The angle of attack knob is represented by <b>31</b> while <b>33</b> represents the crown of the flag pole <b>24</b> which retains the flag <b>36</b>. The base A<b>1</b> is provided with short legs <b>5</b> which gives it clearance from the ground so that sound waves from the speaker as well as heat dissipation from vent holes can emanate therefrom. <b>39</b> represents the power ON/OFF switch. An A/C adapter <b>43</b> and power chord <b>42</b> are used to supply power from the mains to the unit.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the machine for flying a flag in the absence of natural wind A, has a base member A<b>1</b> atop of which is mounted, a wind pipe A<b>2</b>. The said wind pipe A<b>2</b> is provided with a dividing/reinforcing wall <b>28</b> and a lower edge flange <b>26</b> for coupling to the top flat wall <b>1</b> of the aforesaid base member A<b>1</b> which forms into a tubular wall housing <b>2</b> and a lower edge flange <b>3</b>. Integrally molded or machined studs <b>10</b> permit a cover plate <b>4</b> to be rigidly secured to the aforesaid edge flange <b>3</b> by means of screws <b>9</b>. By means of screws <b>27</b> the wind pipe A<b>2</b> is rigidly secured atop the base member A<b>1</b>. The bottom cover <b>4</b> is preferably molded out of plastic materials such as nylon which would be advantageous to the shafts <b>21</b> and <b>23</b>A which respectively are coupled to the fan <b>22</b> and the airfoil <b>23</b> and rotate in their respective holes on the raised annular ledges <b>8</b> and <b>7</b>. By means of pulleys <b>18</b> and <b>20</b> and belt <b>19</b>, the motor <b>12</b> is coupled to the fan shaft <b>21</b>. The bottom cover <b>4</b> has integrally molded legs <b>5</b> and is provided as well with vent holes <b>6</b>. A short tube <b>11</b> protrudes into the base and has a half moon shape. The matching splined lower edge of the flag pole <b>24</b> sits inside said tube <b>11</b>, thereby steadying the pole and negating torsional divergence (twisting torque) resulting from the force of the air from the fan. The threaded upper edge <b>32</b> is coupled to the crown <b>33</b> by means of matching threading and/or bonding with a suitable bonding agent. The flag pole <b>24</b> is dropped in from the top thru a hole on the top cover <b>30</b>, thru a second hole on the dividing wall <b>28</b> of the wind pipe A<b>2</b> such that the lower edge sits inside the tube <b>11</b>. The potentiometer <b>15</b> is mounted on the inside of the top surface <b>1</b> of the base while the adjusting knob <b>16</b> sits on top. The lamp <b>17</b> is pivotably mounted on top of the base as well by means of the bracket <b>17</b>A. Atop the cover <b>30</b> of the wind pipe A<b>2</b> sits the angle of attack knob <b>31</b> coupled to the shaft <b>23</b>A by means of threading. This allows the knob <b>31</b> to be easily screwed on or unscrewed during assembly or disassembly. The shaft <b>23</b>A passes thru a hole on the cover <b>30</b>, thru a second hole on the dividing wall <b>28</b>, thru a third hole on the top surface <b>1</b> of the base A<b>1</b> and into the matching hole on the raised ledge <b>7</b> of the bottom cover <b>4</b>. The shaft <b>23</b>A is rigidly bonded to the airfoil <b>23</b> by means of a suitable bonding agent such as epoxy resins. The fan <b>22</b> is rigidly coupled to the shaft <b>21</b> and positioned such that it confronts the airfoil <b>23</b>. The upper end of the shaft <b>21</b> is rotatably connected to a matching hole on the raised annular ledge <b>8</b>D of the cover <b>30</b> which is preferable made of nylon and serves as a bearing. The shaft <b>21</b> also passes thru a ball bearing <b>29</b> located in a matching recess on the dividing wall <b>28</b>, thru a hole on the top surface <b>1</b> of the base A<b>1</b>, thru the pulley which it is rigidly coupled to and into a matching hole on the annular raised ledge <b>8</b> of the bottom cover <b>4</b> which is preferably molded out of nylon and serves as a bearing. An arrest means <b>13</b> mounted under the top surface <b>1</b> of the base A<b>1</b> is provided with a spring loaded pin <b>14</b>, which goes thru a hole in the shaft <b>23</b>A such that it permits selectable adjustments of the angle of attack via the top mounted knob <b>31</b>. The wind pipe A<b>2</b> is provided with air suction holes <b>34</b> which are preferably located about the ends of the fan <b>22</b>; said air suction holes having integrally molded mesh <b>35</b> to keep fingers from reaching the rotating blades of the fan <b>22</b>. During operation, air is sucked into the wind pipe A<b>2</b> via the suction holes <b>34</b> by the fan <b>22</b> and blown at the airfoil <b>23</b> which by Coanda effect permits air to be blown past the flag <b>36</b> which rises and flies in a controlled determinable manner. The flag <b>36</b> is preferably made of silk or stretch fabrics. However, other materials that are not stiff may be employed. The ends of the fan shaft <b>21</b> may be coupled to ball bearings located on covers <b>4</b> and <b>30</b> respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> which is taken along line Y-Y<b>1</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the wind pipe A<b>2</b> is provided with air suction holes <b>34</b> for the fan <b>22</b> which is coupled to the shaft <b>21</b>. The solid body <b>25</b> of the wind pipe A<b>2</b> is also provided with mounting holes <b>37</b>A for the top cover <b>30</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The solid body <b>25</b> is preferably molded out of plastic materials like PVC, ABS, Delrin or the like, or cast out of aluminum or stamped steel. The shaft <b>22</b> of the airfoil <b>23</b> positions it in such a manner that its leading edge confronts the fan <b>22</b> and its trailing edge confronts the flag pole <b>24</b> and attached flag <b>36</b> in the neutral position. The fan <b>22</b> is placed very close to an inwardly extending protuberance wall section <b>44</b> and away from a gently tapered opposite inner wall <b>45</b>. The arrangement creates throats <b>46</b> and <b>47</b> on either side of the leading edge of the airfoil <b>23</b> and exit mouths <b>48</b> and <b>49</b> respectively on either side of the trailing edge of said airfoil <b>23</b>. In operation, clockwise rotation of the fan <b>22</b> causes air to be drawn in thru the air holes <b>34</b> and blown at the leading edge of the airfoil <b>23</b>. By coanda effect, the air accelerates under increased pressure at the throats <b>46</b> and <b>47</b> respectively, hugs the curvature of the airfoil <b>23</b> and exit the mouths <b>48</b> and <b>49</b>, thereby causing the flag <b>36</b> to rise. The airfoil <b>23</b> which is essentially a phase plug, depending on a selected angle of attack can balance or unbalance the air loads acting on either side of the flag <b>36</b> thereby permitting the manipulation of its attitude in the wind. <b>28</b> represents the centrally located dividing/reinforcing wall.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the angle of attack selection mechanism is provided with a tensioner body <b>13</b> having a mounting flange <b>13</b>A and mounted under the top surface <b>1</b> of the base. The shaft <b>23</b>A is passed thru a hole on the said top surface <b>1</b> of the base. A retaining pin <b>14</b> passes thru a hole on the shaft <b>23</b>A and is provided with a ball shaped head <b>14</b>A which under tension of the spring <b>14</b>B arrestingly retains a selected angle of attack such that the aerodynamic lift forces acting on the airfoil <b>23</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) don't change it.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the airfoil shaft is represented by <b>22</b> while <b>14</b> represents the retaining pin provided with a ball shaped head <b>14</b>A under the tension of the spring <b>14</b>B. The tensioner body is represented by <b>13</b> and is provided with selector position grooves <b>52</b> and a mounting flange <b>13</b>A; said mounting flange having a slot <b>50</b> and held in place by a screw <b>51</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the top cover of the wind pipe is represented by <b>30</b>. It is provided with an annular raised ledge <b>8</b>D having a hole <b>8</b>A for accepting the fan shaft <b>21</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The mounting holes are represented by <b>37</b>B. The airfoil shaft <b>23</b>A and flag pole <b>24</b> respectively pass thru the holes <b>8</b>B and <b>8</b>C.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> which is a view into the base from the bottom, with the cover removed and taken along line Z-Z<b>1</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The drive motor <b>12</b> is mounted as shown with screws <b>12</b>A. The motor pulley <b>18</b> is driveably connected to the fan shaft <b>21</b> and pulley <b>20</b> by means of a serpentine belt <b>19</b> which connects two other pulleys mounted in the conventional manner. The one pulley <b>68</b> is permanently set while the other pulley <b>69</b> is a conventional static slot type tensioner which is slideably adjustable between raised walls <b>70</b> and set with the screw <b>69</b>A. The belt <b>19</b> is surrounded by the raised wall <b>71</b> with breaks at terminate ends <b>71</b>B and <b>71</b>C to create an opening for the mounting flange <b>13</b>A of the tensioner body <b>13</b> of the angle of attack selection mechanism. There is a mounting screw <b>51</b> in a slot and a retaining pin <b>14</b> having a ball shaped head <b>14</b>A. Pin <b>14</b> passes thru a hole on the angle of attack shaft <b>23</b>A and held thereon by the spring <b>14</b>B such that the ball shaped head <b>14</b>A sits in grooved sections of the tensioner body <b>13</b>, thereby permitting different angle of attack selections to be made. <b>61</b> represent an auxiliary circuit board unto which the speaker <b>63</b> may be mounted by means of bonding agents or screws. It is mounted on studs <b>62</b>A by means of screws <b>62</b>. The screws <b>64</b> hold the lamp and brackets on the opposite side. The cables from the lamp are passed thru a hole <b>65</b> to the main circuit board <b>59</b>. Wires <b>67</b> from the potentiometer <b>15</b> and the ON/OFF switches <b>39</b> and <b>66</b> are passed between the wall <b>71</b>A which partially surrounds the motor <b>12</b> and the inner diametrical wall of the edge flange <b>3</b> to the main circuit board <b>59</b> which is mounted on studs <b>60</b>A by means of screws <b>60</b>. A battery compartment (not shown) is positioned underneath the main circuit board <b>59</b>. The securing screw on the pulley <b>20</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</figref>) may be tightened or removed by employing a screw driver along the axis W-W<b>1</b>. The studs <b>72</b> aid in rigidly coupling the wind pipe (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) to the base. The bottom cover is attached to the base using the threaded studs <b>10</b>. The flag pole's lower edge sits inside the half moon shaped tube <b>11</b> to keep it from making radial movements during operation. The use of a serpentine belt drive system results in quiet operation. In the event that the belt <b>19</b> should break while in operation, the surrounding wall <b>71</b> provides containment and prevents damage to other system components housed in the base A<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the arrangement shown, as an alternate gear coupled direct drive system can be located along line V-V<b>1</b> axis of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>. The motor is represented by <b>12</b> and mounted with a strap <b>160</b> and bolts <b>161</b>. The motor shaft is preferably coupled to a bearing <b>162</b> and a bevel gear <b>163</b>; said bevel gear <b>163</b> directly and rotatably connected to a second bevel gear <b>164</b> rigidly attached to the fan shaft <b>21</b>. Even though smooth V groove pulley and belt systems as well as direct drive gear systems are depicted, this in no way limits the scope of the drive systems possible. Toothed belts and matching sprocket pulley (timing) arrangements are possible. Also the fan shaft can be driven directly by the motor.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the solid body wall <b>25</b> of the wind pipe terminates into an edge flange <b>26</b> provided with short threaded studs <b>25</b>A for coupling with matching unthreaded hole studs <b>72</b>. The studs <b>72</b> are integrally molded with belt surrounding raised wall <b>71</b> and top base surface <b>1</b> such that both entities are rigidly held together by the screws <b>27</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, the angle of attack knob <b>31</b> shows that adjustments from low to high are possible.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, the motor speed control knob <b>16</b> (potentiometer) shows possible adjustment markings.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, the conventional static slot tensioner has a freely rotating pulley <b>69</b>, a coupling flange <b>69</b>B and a racetrack type slot <b>69</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, the bottom cover plate <b>4</b> for the base A<b>1</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows the configuration of the inner face. It is provided with raised annular ledges <b>7</b> and <b>8</b> respectively provided with non thru holes <b>7</b>A and <b>8</b>A which serve as bearings for the respective shafts of the airfoil and fan. The adjoining perforations <b>6</b>A are for air circulation to the bearings and shafts. The perforations <b>6</b>B circulate air to the motor. The raised wall <b>71</b>D surround the motor pulley <b>18</b> and a portion of the belt <b>19</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>). The perforations <b>6</b>C confront the speaker for enhancing audio outputs. The holes <b>9</b>A are mounting holes.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref>, the airfoil shaft <b>23</b>A is coupled to a drive gear <b>55</b> which meshes with a static gear <b>56</b> connected to a hand crank <b>57</b> set above the base surface <b>1</b> provided with an edge flange <b>3</b>. The hand crank <b>57</b> permits manual adjustments of the angle of attack of the airfoil in outdoor systems.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref>, the airfoil shaft <b>23</b>A is coupled to drive gear <b>55</b> which meshes with a static gear <b>56</b> which is directly coupled to a stepper drive motor <b>58</b> which is mounted atop the base surface <b>1</b> provided with an edge flange <b>3</b>. The motor <b>58</b> may be operated by remote control or by switches placed atop the surface <b>1</b> thereby permitting motorized adjustments of the angle of attack of the airfoil in indoor or outdoor systems. The motor <b>58</b> may also be mounted within the base with the gears <b>55</b> and <b>56</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15A</figref>, the airfoil shaft <b>23</b>A is rigidly coupled to the rack type drive gear <b>55</b> which meshes with the pinion static gear <b>56</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref>, the control panel <b>40</b> depicts a sample button arrangement but possible button configuration for the control panel is legion and as such is not critical. However, switch panel <b>63</b>A is used for increment or decrement. Buttons <b>63</b> are for programming the timer <b>62</b>. Buttons <b>64</b> and <b>65</b> are for music reproduction and A/DC switches respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</figref>, the fan assembly <b>22</b> depicts outwardly canted blades <b>22</b>A integrally molded on either side of the radial edge flanges <b>22</b>B provided each with centrally located D shaped holes <b>22</b>G, which form into the inwardly extending short tubular stems <b>22</b>C which integrally connects arms <b>22</b>F via reinforcing flanges <b>22</b>D. Several holes <b>22</b>E equidistantly located on the radial edge flanges <b>22</b>B serve to permit stacking of several fans <b>22</b>, by means of rivets or bolts, thereby easily increasing length and rigidity without substantially increasing the unwanted oscillations inherent in long length cylindrical or centrifugal fans. The drive shaft <b>21</b> has a cross-section that matches and mates with the holes <b>22</b>G on the fan <b>22</b> in such a manner that the grooves <b>22</b>J on the shaft <b>21</b> accept C-Clips <b>53</b> in a rigid lock connection thereby preventing any play of the shaft in the axial direction. Radial motion of the shaft <b>21</b> is prevented by the flat side <b>22</b>H of the holes <b>22</b>G. A dimple <b>20</b>C on the shaft <b>21</b> accepts a locking nut (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</figref>) and keeps a drive pulley <b>20</b> from slipping.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</figref>, a fan assembly is depicted according to this invention, having outwardly canted blades <b>22</b>A. Arms <b>22</b>F connect outer edge flange <b>22</b>B to inner flange having a D shaped hole <b>22</b>G having at least one flat side <b>22</b>H for accepting a matching drive shaft. <b>22</b>E represents holes for rivets or bolts which permit the stacking of several fans. D is the true effective diameter of this fan configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</figref>, a fan assembly is depicted according to this invention, having inwardly canted blades <b>22</b>A. Connecting arms <b>22</b>F connect outer edge flange <b>22</b>B to inner flange having shaped hole <b>22</b>G having at least one flat side <b>22</b>H for accepting a matching drive shaft. <b>22</b>E represents holes for rivets or bolts which permit the stacking of several fans. D<b>1</b> is the true effective diameter of this fan configuration. Diameters D<b>1</b> and D should be equal if interchangeable and employed in the same system.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</figref>, a v-grooved pulley <b>20</b> is depicted. There is an integral raised stem <b>20</b>A provided with a threaded hole for a locking set screw <b>2013</b> which engages a dimple on the shaft <b>21</b> and prevents the pulley from slipping. A well known conventional variable reluctance speed sensor system (not shown) attached to the fan shaft pulley may be used to detect a loose (slipping), worn or broken drive belt.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</figref>, the fan blades are represented by <b>22</b>A which is integrally molded with the outer edge flange <b>2213</b> and the centrally located tubular stub <b>22</b>C which are connected to the arms <b>22</b>F and strengthened by reinforcing flags <b>22</b>D. The drive shaft <b>21</b> matches and rigidly mates with the centrally located holes formed by the tubes <b>22</b>C and locked in place by a C-Clips <b>53</b> such that axial movements by the shaft <b>21</b> are negated. The fan assembly <b>22</b> depicted has an outwardly extended blade profile.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">In reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</figref>, the depicted airfoil <b>23</b> which is of conventional design, is provided with a hole <b>23</b>D which runs its length and permits a tight fit of the shaft <b>23</b>A which is bonded thereon. One end of the shaft <b>23</b>A is provided with a short flat side <b>23</b>B which may also be threaded, for the purpose of accepting an adjusting knob. On the opposite end of the shaft <b>23</b>A is positioned, a thru hole <b>23</b>C for the purpose of accepting a spring loaded pin used to effect selectability of various angles of attack. Various NACA airfoils may be employed in this invention. It should be mentioned in passing that in fluid mechanics, it is a well known phenomena that all airfoil surfaces and particularly those employed in aircraft suffer some degree of loss of lift coefficient due to boundary layer separation on said surfaces. Elaborate boundary layer control techniques are usually employed to resolve these problems. This invention employs airfoils similar to aircraft types. In small systems, this problem may not be severe. However, in large systems, the same problems that affect airfoils in general when angles of attack become steep will come to bear and must be addressed in those situations. If the maximum selectable angle of attack is below about 17&#xb0;, laminar flow or boundary layer separation (turbulent flow) problems may not occur to diminish performance of the system.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">I now refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</figref> which is a programmable control circuit for the flag flying machine of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. This circuit's emphasis is on the integration of a drive motor(s), a lighting system, a synthesized music reproducer, a rechargeable battery arrangement and a timing circuit, under the control of a CPU micro-controller, rather than emphasizing a flow chart instructional assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Power from the standard AC outlet is stepped down to 5V from 115V or 220V. Power is transferred to a battery charging circuit P via capacitor C<b>5</b> and resistor R<b>5</b>. The charging circuit P is driven by an adjustable output charging chip which is a Texas instrument BQ25010 having voltage range from 0.7V to 4.2V. <b>59</b> is an inline fuse. Though the battery charging circuit shown in P has been modified for this overall system, it is largely after Texas Instruments. Output capacitor C out inputs 4.2 volts into the non-inverting input of an op amp <b>61</b>, an Intersil LM741 having a negative feedback loop in the traditional manner and employing resistors R<b>10</b> and R<b>11</b>. Output voltages from about +6V to +16V are supplied to a programmable timer <b>62</b> which is preferably a National Semiconductor CD4541BC or a similar one of comparable performance. The programming circuit Q which includes said timer <b>62</b>, a control panel <b>40</b> having programming switches (round buttons) <b>63</b>, music selection switches <b>64</b> and control switches <b>65</b> (square buttons) coupled as shown to an LCD display. The programming circuit Q is connected to the control circuit R via an Analog to Digital Converter ADC <b>67</b> which is preferably a National Semiconductor 08118, 8 bit, 11 channel model with serial I/D. Via the wires <b>67</b>A, the internal switches SW<b>2</b> are brought to the control panel switch array <b>65</b>. SWI is an ON/OFF switch while <b>66</b> represents the entire group of switches for the shown functions. The ADC <b>67</b> is connected to the central processing unit <b>68</b>. The actuation switches SW<b>2</b> for the functions represented by <b>66</b>, as well as the ON/OFF switch SW<b>1</b> are preferably brought to the control panel <b>40</b> at the lower row of buttons represented by <b>65</b>, via wires <b>67</b>A. CPU<b>68</b> is preferably an Intel 83C51FA/80C51FA or 8XC51FX equivalent CHMOS, 8 bit micro-controller. Together, the ADC<b>67</b> and the CPU<b>68</b> constitute the control circuit R. They control the synthesized music circuit T as well as the controlled variables S, which include the fan motor <b>12</b>, the stepper motor <b>74</b> (optional) for manipulating the airfoil, and a flag illuminating lamp <b>17</b>. The CPU<b>68</b> is also connected to the control panel <b>40</b>. The stepper motor <b>74</b> is under the control of a relay and a controller/driver circuit <b>73</b> and has an LED<b>1</b>. An optional auxiliary display provided with switches <b>72</b> may be coupled to the CPU via couplers <b>70</b> and <b>71</b>, and a relay. In another embodiment of this invention, a variable reluctance sensor <b>60</b> and a warning lamp <b>70</b> may be used to monitor fan shaft speed, for the purpose of determining belt slippage and/or wear. The sensor <b>60</b> may be coupled to the CPU<b>68</b> via an optocoupler. The fan shaft drive motor <b>12</b> is coupled to the CPU via an optocoupler connected to a potentiometer used to manipulate motor speed. Power to the motor <b>12</b> arrives via a capacitor C<b>6</b>. There is an overload protection circuit and an LED<b>2</b>. The illuminating lamp <b>17</b> for the flag is under the control of a relay switch with a single pole, double throw (SPDT) and an ON/OFF switch SW<b>4</b>. The lamp <b>17</b> is preferably provided with two separate bulbs inside the lens housing and provided with the filaments F<b>1</b> and F<b>2</b>. Power to the respective bulbs come via resistors R<b>8</b> and R<b>9</b> respectively. The arrangement is such that F<b>1</b> may be turned on at any time by closing the switch SW<b>4</b> while F<b>2</b> comes on only when the relay energizes and connects the armature to the other contact. An optocoupler couples the lamp <b>17</b> to the CPU<b>68</b>. Power ON, OFF and AUTO LEDs are provided for display and are also connected to the CPU<b>68</b>. The CPU<b>68</b> is provided with memory instructions as well as alterable memory storage constants.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The synthesized music circuit T is also under the control of the CPU<b>68</b>. It is provided with a micro-computer <b>76</b> having the desired music notes programmed in its memory. It is preferably a National Semiconductor model COP420/COP421. The micro computer <b>76</b> receives a 5 volt output from a constant voltage regulator <b>75</b> coupled to the CPU<b>68</b>. The regulator <b>75</b> is provided with capacitors C<b>7</b> and C<b>8</b>. Any music tone programmed in the memory of the micro-computer <b>76</b> may be selected by using the switches SW<b>3</b> on the switch console <b>77</b>. However, these switches SW<b>3</b> are preferably brought to the control panel <b>40</b> via wires <b>77</b>A and are represented on the said control panel <b>40</b> by the group of switches <b>64</b>. The wires <b>78</b> are configured in such a manner that their outputs are connected to an output circuit <b>79</b> employing a single loudspeaker <b>80</b>. The output circuit <b>79</b> constitutes a high gain darlington pair T<b>1</b> and T<b>2</b> and coupling resistors R<b>6</b> and R<b>7</b> and a diode D<b>3</b>. The regulator <b>75</b> may be connected directly to the output from the operational amplifier <b>61</b>. The regulator <b>75</b> is preferably an Analog Devices Model ADM663A/ADM666A. When a given type of musical note has been selected using the switches <b>64</b>, the switch group <b>65</b> are used to select the variables represented by <b>66</b>. The round button switches on the upper section <b>63</b> of the control panel U are used to digitally program the timer <b>62</b> such that selected variables are displayed on the LCD and the system is activated at a selected time. The four way switch <b>63</b>A is used for increment or decrement. The programmable timer <b>62</b> is preferably a National Semiconductor Model CD4541BC. When the system activates at a selected time (clock alarm fashion), the fan motor <b>12</b> drives the fan which blows air over the flag, causing it to rise. At the same time, the relay turns on the lamp <b>17</b> and the selected music note begins to play through the loudspeaker <b>80</b>. When the musical note which is programmed to play its entire length has finished playing, the CPU<b>68</b> automatically shuts off the system unless repeat is selected during the programming process.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</figref> which is a non-programmable control circuit, an AC or battery power may be used to drive the fan motor <b>12</b> and the micro-controller <b>76</b>. As is shown, an adapter steps down the mains AC voltage to about 12 volts which is then supplied to a solid state timer <b>62</b>A via a fixed voltage regulator <b>75</b>A with a 9V output. The various commercially available models is legion. The timer <b>62</b>A which has a voltage range of 5 volts/6 volts DC has a selectable range of 6 minutes to 60 minutes. It is an Omron H3FA-SBU. The timer's output is stored by the capacitor C<b>5</b> and supplied simultaneously to the fan motor <b>12</b>, the stepper motor <b>74</b> (if employed), the illumination lamp <b>17</b> and the synthesized music circuit T. The stepper's circuit consists of a relay, a controller/drive circuit <b>73</b> and an LED<b>1</b>. The fan motor's circuit consists of a relay, a potentiometer, an overload protection circuit, a capacitor C<b>6</b> and an LED<b>2</b>. Together, the two motor circuits constitute the flag actuating circuit S. The lamp <b>17</b> as aforementioned is preferably a two bulb arrangement inside a lens but is not restricted to this configuration. The lamp <b>17</b> is under the control of a relay switch with a single pole, double throw (SPDT) and an ON/OFF switch SW<b>4</b>. The respective bulbs have filaments F<b>1</b> and F<b>2</b>. Power to the respective bulbs come via resistors R<b>8</b> and R<b>9</b> respectively. The arrangement is such that F<b>1</b> may be turned on at any time by closing the switch SW<b>4</b> while F<b>2</b> comes on only when the relay energizes and connects the armature to the other contact. Power to the micro-computer <b>76</b> of the synthesized music circuit T comes from a fixed voltage regulator <b>75</b> which supplies a 5V output to the micro-computer <b>76</b>, which is preferably a National Semiconductor Model COP420/COP421 or equivalent. The regulator <b>75</b> is preferably, an Analog Devices Model ADM663A/ADM666A. The output channels of <b>76</b> connected to the output transistor T, resistors R<b>3</b> and R<b>4</b> and diode D<b>1</b> such as to permit only one speaker to be used to reproduce a selected musical note by depressing the switches SW<b>3</b> on the console <b>77</b>. The said switches SW<b>3</b> are preferably brought to a switch panel U<b>1</b> mounted on the machine via wires <b>77</b>A. In operation, when the unit is plugged into the AC outlet and one of the button type switches on the switch panel U<b>1</b> is depressed to select a musical note programmed into the memory of the micro-controller (eg. #1 may be US Star Spangled Banner), and the timer <b>62</b>A has been set to say 60 minutes, then when ON/OFF switch is closed, the motor <b>12</b> will run and drive the fan which blows air over the flag, causing it to rise. The music comes on and plays in its entirety and the timer <b>62</b>A shuts off the system. After 60 minutes or whatever time was preset, the system will activate again and repeat. If no music button is depressed in either circuit configuration, the flag will still be made to fly but without the benefit of a musical note activating as well. This feature may aide in the conservation of power. Individuals skilled in electronic control circuits and systems may find it necessary to improve on or modify the circuits thus described and depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 23 and 24</figref> without deviating from or defeating the basic concepts of this invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>I claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A machine for controllably flying a flag in the absence of the natural wind, comprising:
<claim-text>a long cylindrical centrifugal fan and shaft assembly driven by a motor mounted inside a housing of a base unit by means of pulleys and a serpentine belt;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a tubular windpipe attached to the base unit and surrounding the fan and shaft assembly, an airfoil, and a flag pole,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a shaft of the fan and shaft assembly is rotatably supported by bearings;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the airfoil is positioned between a fan of the fan and shaft assembly and the flag pole and has an adjustable angle of attack, altering air blowing past it and thereby permitting the controlled manipulation of the attitude of a flag mounted on the flag pole.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The machine for controllably flying a flag in the absence of natural wind according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a non-programmable solid state output timer that controls flying of a flag in the absence of natural wind.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A machine for controllably flying a flag in the absence of natural wind according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the machine is capable of indoor or outdoor use.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A machine for controllably flying a flag in the absence of natural wind according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a base mounted stepper motor configured to change the angle of attack of the airfoil.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A machine for controllably flying a flag in the absence of natural wind according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising bevel gears, wherein the fan and shaft assembly is driven directly by the motor by means of the bevel gears.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A machine for controllably flying a flag in the absence of natural wind according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a knob coupled to a shaft of the airfoil for changing the airfoil's angle of attack, wherein the airfoil is held in a selected position by a retaining pin under spring tension and a tensioner body having selector position grooves.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A machine for controllably flying a flag in the absence of natural wind according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a base-mounted hand crank configured to change the angle of attack of the airfoil.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A machine for controllably flying a flag in the absence of natural wind having a drive belt according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said serpentine belt is surrounded by protective raised flange walls, whereby in the event of a catastrophic belt break, damage to surrounding components is minimized.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A machine for controllably flying a flag in the absence of natural wind according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising control panel and an LCD display mounted in the base unit for selecting songs as well as programming flying of the flag.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A machine for controllably flying a flag in the absence of natural wind according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said fan has inwardly or outwardly canted blades.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A machine for controllably flying a flag in the absence of natural wind according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said airfoil shape is a NACA airfoil.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. A machine for controllably flying a flag in the absence of natural wind according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a variable reluctance sensor configured to monitor the fan's speed as a means for determining belt slippage or damage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A machine for controllably flying a flag in the absence of natural wind according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the bearings are nylon sleeve bearings and/or ball bearings.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A machine for controllably flying a flag in the absence of natural wind according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the wind pipe is shaped to create a throat and mouth arrangement around the airfoil, such that the airfoil behaves like a movable phase plug within said mouth, thereby enhancing the efficiency of the air blown over the flag.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the flag is mounted edgewise on the flag pole and the flag pole is removable.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising holes on the windpipe opposite the flagpole through which air can be drawn in by the fan.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising an adjusting knob placed atop a top cover of the windpipe, wherein the adjusting knob is configured to change the angle of attack of the airfoil, whereby the flag's attitude blown air may be altered at will.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising an illuminating lamp mounted atop the base unit and configured to illuminate the flag.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a synthesized music circuit comprising several songs programmed in its memory and looped together with a programmable timer and an LCD display and a control panel configured for timed actuation of the machine.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
