<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622333-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622333</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13353688</doc-number>
<date>20120119</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>65</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>16</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>242598</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Toilet tissue roll holder capacity extender</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2370821</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Stott</name>
<date>19450300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2424224</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2546820</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Grant</name>
<date>19510300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2425991</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2571321</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Wettley</name>
<date>19511000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2425994</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5718404</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Greer</name>
<date>19980200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2483092</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7316369</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Phelps</name>
<date>20080100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2425964</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0228209</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Burnett</name>
<date>20071000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>242599</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>2</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>242598</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2425982</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2425983</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2425984</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2425985</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>242599</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2425991</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2425993</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2425994</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2425967</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2425975</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>242596</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2425968</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2425978</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>7</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation-in-part>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12887001</doc-number>
<date>20100921</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8201770</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13353688</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation-in-part>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120111989</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120510</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Dermo</last-name>
<first-name>Mario</first-name>
<address>
<city>Warren</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Dermo</last-name>
<first-name>Mario</first-name>
<address>
<city>Warren</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Young Basile Hanlon &#x26; MacFarlane PC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Sang</first-name>
<department>3654</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Campos, Jr.</last-name>
<first-name>Juan</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A toilet tissue roll holder extender which extends the roll diameter capacity of the holder by adhesively attaching flat plastic extender bodies to the inside surfaces of the conventional toilet tissue roll holder arms. In the preferred embodiment, the extenders have compound diameter spindle-receiving holes formed therein and the combination can be used with a toilet tissue core restoring insert of rigid plastic.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="105.49mm" wi="157.06mm" file="US08622333-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="224.28mm" wi="171.70mm" file="US08622333-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="234.78mm" wi="159.60mm" file="US08622333-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="160.27mm" wi="151.21mm" file="US08622333-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation-in-part of the co-pending U.S. patent application Ser. No. 12/887,001 filed Sep. 21, 2010 and claims the benefit of that application.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This invention relates to devices for increasing the roll diameter capacity of a toilet paper roll holder.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Toilet paper roll holders are available in a variety of configurations including a one-piece construction comprising a base plate adapted to be attached by screws or adhesive to a wall or partition. Integral with said base plate are two outwardly extending, spaced-apart arms which are parallel to one another in use and may either be fixed or collapsible. A spindle (also called a &#x201c;roller&#x201d;) is provided, resiliently adjustable in length for mounting between said arms, the opposite end pins of the spindle extending into receptacles near the outward distal ends of said arms.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Toilet paper roll holders are also available in various styles and comprising two totally separate posts which can be independently attached to a wall or partition. When mounted, a spindle is mounted between them to accommodate a roll of toilet paper.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In both of the roll holder types described above, the roll diameter capacity is limited by the distance between the spindle axis and either the base plate or the wall or partition. Toilet paper rolls are now available in &#x201c;jumbo&#x201d; size rolls of 5 or more inches in diameter, too large to be carried by some toilet paper roll holders; i.e., the outer surface of the roll hits the wall or base surface and will not rotate.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The present invention provides an apparatus for simply and inexpensively increasing the roll diameter capacity of any type of conventional toilet paper roll holder having opposed arms or posts adapted to receive a spindle therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In accordance with an illustrative embodiment of the invention, the extender bodies include an elongate, thin portion having a thicker section at one end. The thin portion has a continuous, flat inner surface and a stepped outer surface, the step defining the transition between the thinner and thicker sections. The thinner part of the stepped surface may also be provided with an adhesive, generally in the form of a two-sided tape with a protective layer in place prior to installation, to facilitate attaching the extender body to the inside surface of a conventional roll holder in a way that covers up the conventional spindle hole. Replacement holes, either blind holes or through holes, are formed in the surface of a thicker section to receive a spindle an inch or more outside of the now-covered-up conventional hole. Generally, the spindle is telescopic and spring-biased in one of the conventional fashions; i.e., the spindle pin itself may be telescopically depressible into the spindle body or the spindle itself can be made into two pieces which telescope over one another and are held apart by means of a spring, both designs being conventional.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In the preferred form, the spindle receptacle holes are formed with two distinct diameter portions, a first, larger diameter hole portion which is closest to the inside surface of the extender and a second, smaller diameter portion coaxial with the first portion but farther away from the inside surface. This double diameter arrangement accommodates spindles of different sizes as well as spindles with nibs on the outer surface.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Another aspect of the invention, usable in combination with the roll extenders described above, is a rigid plastic hollow cylinder designed to fit precisely within a cardboard core of a conventional toilet tissue roll. This hollow cylinder is used to advantage where shipment and packaging has flattened the cardboard cores or one or more rolls of a multi-roll package and effectively restores the core to round shape so as to coact more effectively with the spindle and roll more easily thereover.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">These and other advantages of the present invention will be best understood from a reading of the following specification which is to be taken with the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The description herein makes reference to the accompanying drawings wherein like reference numerals refer to like parts throughout the several views and wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of one embodiment of my invention as applied to a one-piece roll holder;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view of one of the extenders in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a side view of a variation on the extender of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a perspective view of another extender with a multi-diameter spindle hole;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an side view of the extender of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrating in detail the arrangement of the two-diameter spindle hole configuration;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a perspective view of a toilet tissue roll core insert; and</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a sectional view of a roll of toilet tissue with the insert of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> installed therein.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE ILLUSTRATIVE EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref>, there is shown a toilet paper roll holder <b>10</b> of the type comprising a base <b>12</b> with integral forwardly extending arms <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. The base plate <b>12</b> is secured to a wall, partition or the like by means of screws <b>14</b>. Alternatives such as adhesive attachments or slide-in brackets can also be used. The arms <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> are spaced approximately 5 inches apart, are parallel and extend generally at right angles to the base <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Receptacles <b>20</b> are formed proximate the distal ends of the arms <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> to receive the pins <b>24</b> of a spindle <b>22</b> therebetween in normal use; i.e., before the holder <b>10</b> is modified as described below. A toilet paper roll can be mounted on the spindle <b>22</b> in conventional fashion. Spindle <b>22</b> is also called a &#x201c;roller&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In accordance with the invention, capacity extenders <b>26</b>, <b>28</b> are adhesively secured to the inside surfaces of the arms <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> in such a way as to extend the spindle axis away from the base <b>12</b> by a distance D<sub>e </sub>such that the increased roll diameter capacity is represented by the quantity D<sub>c</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">As better shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, each extender comprises a molded plastic body having opposite surfaces <b>30</b>, <b>32</b> and a blind hole receptacle <b>34</b> formed in the surface <b>32</b> near one of the opposite distal ends of each body. The outside surface <b>30</b> has a step <b>36</b> formed therein to help locate the body <b>26</b> on the end of the arm <b>16</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and to provide a smooth integrated appearance. A strip <b>38</b> of two-sided adhesive is secured to the surface <b>30</b> for attaching the extender <b>26</b> or <b>28</b> to the flat inside surface of the respective arms <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. This attachment covers the normal spindle receptacles <b>20</b> and provides new locations <b>34</b> for receiving the spindle pins <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In use, the purchaser of the extenders <b>26</b>, <b>28</b> removes a protective layer from the adhesive strip <b>38</b> and locates the extender, either <b>26</b> or <b>28</b> on the end of the appropriate arms <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> with the adhesive against the flat inside surface of the original arm and the step <b>36</b> against the end of the arm. Thereafter, the spindle <b>22</b> is newly located in the receptacles <b>34</b>, a distance D<sub>e </sub>away from the old axis of rotation. This distance may be typically on the order of one inch.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, there is shown a second embodiment of the extender in the form of a molded plastic body having a flat inside surface <b>40</b>, a flat parallel outside surface <b>42</b> terminating in a shoulder <b>44</b> and a second flat surface <b>46</b> on a portion <b>47</b> of enlarged thickness. A spindle hole <b>50</b> is formed in the enlarged thickness portion <b>47</b>. A strip of two-sided adhesive <b>48</b> is attached to the flat surface <b>42</b> so that the extender may be installed in the manner shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> with the flat surface <b>42</b> and the adhesive strip <b>48</b> against the inside surface of the toilet tissue roll holder so that the surface <b>42</b> covers up the stock hole <b>20</b> of the conventional toilet tissue roll holder. The shoulder <b>44</b> butts up against the end of the extended arm <b>16</b> and the hole <b>50</b> receives the pin or axle portion of the spindle <b>22</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, hole <b>50</b> is of a compound nature; it comprises a first larger diameter portion which opens to the surface <b>40</b> and a second smaller diameter portion which opens to the surface <b>46</b>. Portions <b>50</b> and <b>52</b> are coaxial and contiguous. The result is the ability to accommodate spindles of various sizes and diameters therein.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref>, there is shown a second implement which can be used to advantage either alone or with the extenders of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-5</figref>. This implement is a plastic hollow cylinder <b>54</b> having a through hole <b>56</b> adapted to fit snugly within the cardboard core <b>60</b> of a standard or jumbo roll <b>58</b> of toilet tissue. The cylinder <b>54</b> is preferably four or more inches long but not greater in length than the width of the toilet tissue roll <b>58</b> and on the order of 1&#x215d; inches in diameter. It is preferably made of an acrylic plastic or a clear polycarbonate but any relatively rigid, inexpensive material will do. With the dimensions described above, it fits snugly within the toilet tissue roll as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> to reconstitute and reshape a core <b>60</b> which has been flattened by the compression forces often experienced in packaging, shipping and storing of conventional bundles of toilet tissue rolls.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">It is to be understood that the invention has been described with respect to preferred embodiments illustrating the invention or inventions in particular forms and shapes. These specific forms and shapes may be altered by the designer according to specific desired end results.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. Apparatus for increasing the roll diameter capacity of a toilet tissue roll holder of the type having first and second opposed parallel arms, each of which has a flat inside surface and an end surface, the opposed parallel arms adapted to receive a spindle therebetween wherein the apparatus comprises:
<claim-text>a pair of molded plastic extender bodies that are fully separate from one another and each having substantially flat and parallel inside and outside surfaces, the outside surfaces being stepped and having a strip of adhesive secured thereto such that the outside surface may be attached flat against the inside surface of a toilet tissue roll holder arm so as to cover a spindle receptacle hole in said arm, the stepped outside surface having a shoulder which, in the installed condition, abuts the end surface of the toilet tissue roll holder arm to which the extender is attached, each extender having a spindle receiving hole formed in the inside surface to receive a spindle therein, wherein each spindle receiving hole is a compound hole having a first inside portion of a first axially constant diameter and a second contiguous and coaxial portion of a second axially constant smaller diameter wherein the first diameter portion extends only partially into the extender body and the second portion extends farther into the extender body, said compound holes each having a step defining a transition from the first diameter portion to the second diameter portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. Apparatus as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising a shape-restoring toilet tissue roll core insert comprising a hollow, rigid plastic, open-ended cylinder having a length and a diameter to fit snugly and wholly within the cardboard core of a standard toilet tissue roll, the spindle extending through the hollow, rigid plastic cylinder and being rotatable relative thereto, said cylinder being unattached to the extender bodies. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
