<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624432-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624432</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13861330</doc-number>
<date>20130411</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>12</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>307 46</main-classification>
<further-classification>307 44</further-classification>
<further-classification>307 48</further-classification>
<further-classification>307 80</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Power assist using ambient heat</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3535543</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Dailey</name>
<date>19701000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7528502</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Maeda</name>
<date>20090500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0260668</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Maeda</name>
<date>20091000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2012/0256492</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Song et al.</name>
<date>20121000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>307 46</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>307 44</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>307 48</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>307 80</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12384601</doc-number>
<date>20090407</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8432064</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13861330</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<continuation-in-part>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11262616</doc-number>
<date>20051031</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7528502</doc-number>
<date>20090505</date>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12384601</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation-in-part>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130234519</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130912</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Maeda</last-name>
<first-name>Ryuji</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Diego</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Maeda</last-name>
<first-name>Ryuji</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Diego</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Excelsior Patent Group</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hare</last-name>
<first-name>Bruce</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Kaplan</last-name>
<first-name>Hal</first-name>
<department>2836</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An energy boost circuit adapted to provide power to a load is described. The circuit includes a pair of thermoelectric generators (TEGs) for converting thermal energy from a heat source into electrical energy; a pair of capacitor banks arranged in parallel, each coupled to one of the TEGs for storing the electrical energy generated by the TEG; a power converter; a first switching element coupled between a first capacitor bank in the pair of capacitor banks and the power converter; a second switching element coupled between a second capacitor bank in the pair of capacitor banks and the power converter; and a monitor/controller coupled to the first and second switching elements and adapted to selectively switch the switching elements in order to provide a power boost to the load, where the monitor/controller automatically switches the switching elements based at least partly on charge levels measured at the capacitor banks.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="136.65mm" wi="249.94mm" file="US08624432-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="248.24mm" wi="186.35mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624432-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="198.54mm" wi="171.45mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624432-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="168.23mm" wi="165.35mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624432-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="247.31mm" wi="179.41mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624432-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="192.02mm" wi="154.43mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624432-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="215.05mm" wi="179.92mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624432-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="217.68mm" wi="159.60mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624432-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="254.34mm" wi="159.43mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624432-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation-in-part of prior U.S. patent application Ser. No. 11/262,616, filed on Oct. 31, 2005.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The invention generally relates to power systems and means for providing power to various electronic systems or devices. More particularly, the invention relates to an energy source, such as a battery, fuel cell, generator, and/or hybrid power supply, and a system and circuit for providing power to an electronic system or device which extends the operational life of the energy source, thereby allowing the energy source to provide power to the electronic system or device for an extended period of time.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Electronic systems, devices and applications are continually developing. From cellular phones, portable computers, and compact fuel-cell based generators, to electrical vehicles, the list of electronic systems, devices and applications seems endless. As the number of systems and devices continues to increase, and the applications in which they are used continue to grow, the demand for efficient energy/power supplies that are able to power these systems and devices over extended periods of time has also increased. More specifically, as high performance electronic systems and devices with high power consumption are introduced rapidly to the market place and/or as natural resource scarcity gradually intensifies and the cost of energy consequently increases, the ability to efficiently provide and utilize power is ever increasing.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a conventional drive system <b>113</b> for providing power to drive a load. The load may be any type of known electronic system or device such as a graphics display, a microprocessor, a memory, a conventional laptop computer or an electric motor. The drive system includes an energy or power source <b>109</b> (such as a battery, a fuel cell, a solar cell, etc.) for driving the load <b>112</b>. The system further includes a regulator/converter <b>108</b>, and may further include current control elements <b>110</b> and <b>115</b>, which may also be omitted. Here it is noted that <b>108</b> may be a regulator and/or a converter, and each may be used interchangeably as they are equivalent in the context of this document. A regulator maintains its output constant within a specified range regardless of changes to its output loading condition, shifts in environment condition (such as temperature, humidity, etc.), or/and variations in its input level. A converter is a known electrical element that takes an input parameter, such as a voltage and produces a prescribed output parameter(s), such as a desired voltage at the output. For example, in a case where the desired conversion is from a low input voltage to a higher output voltage, a step up (boost) voltage converter can be used to achieve the desired output voltage. Alternatively, in the case where the desired conversion is from a high input voltage to a lower output voltage, a step down (buck) voltage converter can be used to achieve the desired output voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Current control elements <b>110</b> and <b>115</b> are optional elements and are preferably set to control the amount of current provided to the load <b>112</b>. Examples of elements that can be used as a current control element are a diode, field-effect transistors (MOS FET, JFET, etc.), a bipolar transistor, an insulated gate bipolar transistor, a silicon controlled rectifier, and/or a relay switch. One or more of these elements can be connected in series and/or parallel to act as a current control element and placed in any electrical path(s) within the system.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">One problem with this system is that as the load increases in complexity and functionality, the amount of power required for driving the load increases. While conventional power/energy supplies, such as disposable and/or rechargeable batteries are always improving in order to extend the length of the battery life, recent advances in high capacity batteries has not resulted in considerably longer battery life because the increase in power consumption of these electronic systems and devices more than offsets the improvement in battery life.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">U.S. Pat. No. 6,570,632 issued to Estes, et al. (hereinafter referred to as &#x201c;the Estes Patent&#x201d;) proposes one solution for extending the life of a rechargeable battery used to charge/power a portable system--such as a cellular phone. The Estes Patent teaches using heat generated by at least one electrical component which is resident on a printed circuit board (PCB) within the system, and converting this heat into electrical energy. The Estes Patent further teaches using this electrical energy to directly recharge the main power source&#x2014;a rechargeable battery.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">There are several disadvantages to the solution proposed by the Estes Patent. First, the</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Estes Patent uses the electrical energy to directly recharge a main energy/power source&#x2014;the rechargeable battery&#x2014;such as a lithium-ion battery&#x2014;which can only be accomplished through carefully controlling a complex electrochemical process. Thus, the Estes Patent requires that the main power source be a rechargeable battery and further requires complex battery charging, conditioning and maintenance system circuitry, which must be built into the system. Second, using the electrical energy to recharge the main power source can be inefficient in situations where the system is in use and the main power source must continue to provide energy/power to the load. Accordingly, recharging of the battery would likely occur optimally at a time when the system is not in use and is not taxing or drawing charge from the battery; however, at such time the electrical device(s) in the system is not likely to generate much heat. Therefore, the Estes Patent does not make optimal use of the heat generated by the system when it is active. Finally, rechargeable batteries lose their charging/storage efficiency over time as they are repeatedly charged-discharged and/or continually used. Accordingly, in the solution proposed by the Estes Patent, the efficiency and longevity of the life of the main power source&#x2014;the rechargeable battery&#x2014;may actually be decreased and system may become less efficient if the system is continually attempting to recharge the battery whenever it is turned on.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Therefore, there exist needs in the art for a system and method that extends the life of a main power source and provides for more efficient power use without requiring significant additional complex circuitry. There further exists a need for such a system to be able to be implemented in situations where the main power source may not be a rechargeable battery. There further exists a need for such a system where heat generated by the system may be efficiently converted into electrical energy at optimal times and stored for future use, thereby improving the efficiency of such a system.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The invention consists of a power generating circuit which is coupled in parallel with a main energy/power source to a load. Instead of recharging the main energy/power source, the power generating circuit will provide power directly to the load, thereby reducing the amount of power drawn from the main energy/power source without requiring complex circuitry. Preferably, the power generating circuit includes a heat source, a cooling element, a thermoelectric generator (TEG) for converting thermal energy into electrical energy, a capacitor, at least one switching element, and a monitor/controller for monitoring the electronic system and controlling operation of the power generator circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Described briefly in words, an electrical load is coupled to a main energy/power source and the object of the invention is to extend the life of this main energy/power source and reduce the amount of power drawn from the main energy/power source. Utilizing a second energy/power source whose energy is obtained by converting heat into electrical power (along with a capacitor, several switching elements, and a monitor/controller), energy/power drawn from the main energy/power source is reduced, thereby extending the operational life of the main energy/power source. In order to accomplish this objective, heat (which would be otherwise wasted) is converted into electrical energy or power by using a thermoelectric generator (TEG) and this electrical energy or power is then stored in a capacitor. The converted and stored energy or power is then used to supply power directly to an electrical load, thereby reducing power drawn from the main energy/power source. In a preferred embodiment, the heat can be produced by the main energy/power source, the electrical load itself, or any other internal or external (to the circuit or system in which the present invention is utilized) element that can produce heat.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a conventional drive system for providing power to drive a load;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</figref><i>a</i>-<i>b </i>each illustrate block diagrams which demonstrate the power saving process embodied in the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates an entire drive system which includes a power saving circuit for providing power to an electronic system or device which extends the life of a main energy/power source, in accordance with a preferred-embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates an alternate embodiment of the power saving circuit illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> in which there are double charging stages;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates an alternative embodiment of an entire drive system which includes an alternative power saving circuit for providing power to an electronic system or device which extends the life of a main energy/power source, in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates an alternate embodiment of the power saving circuit illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> in which there are parallel charging stages; and</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates yet another alternative embodiment of an entire drive system which includes an alternative power saving circuit for providing power to an electronic system or device which extends the life of a main energy/power source, in accordance with the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The present invention improves power efficiency and can extend the operating life of a main energy/power source, such as a disposable battery, a rechargeable battery, a fuel cell, a power generator, a reactor, and/or any combination of these, i.e., hybrid power source(s), used to provide power to an electrical system or application. The main energy/power source can be either internal or external to the electrical system and may also be any form of power supply, such as power from an electrical outlet connected to a power grid.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In a preferred embodiment of the present invention the power efficiency of electrical systems is improved by reducing the power drawn from the main energy/power source as described in the following sections. It is also possible to supply extra power to an electrical load(s) with the embodiments of the claimed subject matter described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Furthermore, it is possible to increase the operational life (&#x201c;battery life&#x201d;) and the power efficiency of electrical systems by combining techniques/methods known in the art with the embodiments described herein. Examples known in the art include powering down the unutilized portion of an electrical system, reducing the power consumption of system portions(s) under lenient conditions, and/or reducing the clock frequency of a digital circuitry when high processing performance is not required.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</figref><i>a</i>-<i>b </i>each illustrate block diagrams which demonstrate the power saving process embodied in the present invention. As shown in both figures, an electrical load <b>210</b> is coupled to a main energy/power source <b>200</b> via converter <b>205</b>, and the object of the invention is to extend the life of this main energy/power source <b>200</b> by reducing the amount of power/energy drawn from the main energy/power source <b>200</b>. In order to accomplish this objective, heat <b>211</b> (which would be otherwise wasted) is converted into an electrical charge by using a heat to electricity converter (which includes a thermoelectric generator (TEG), a cooling element, and several interface elements). The electrical charge is then stored in a capacitor <b>202</b>. The converted and stored charge is then used to supply energy/power to the electrical load <b>210</b>, thereby reducing power drawn from the main energy/power source <b>200</b>. In a preferred embodiment, the heat <b>211</b> can be produced by the main power source <b>200</b>, the electrical load itself <b>210</b>, or any other internal or external (to the circuit or system in which the present invention is utilized) element that can produce heat.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Because energy is the time integral of power, a considerably large energy can be developed and stored on the capacitor <b>202</b> if enough time is allowed to lapse and the capacitor <b>202</b> has high energy storage capability. The capacitor <b>202</b> can be any of those currently known and available, such as a supercapacitor or supercap. For the capacitor <b>202</b>, it is understood that any various combinations of parallel and/or series electrical connections are possible using a plurality of capacitors.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">When the power/current from the capacitor <b>202</b> is supplied to the electrical load <b>210</b>, the power/current originated and drawn from the main energy/power source <b>200</b> is reduced, thereby extending the life of the main energy/power source <b>200</b> and reducing the amount of charge or power drawn from the main energy/power <b>200</b> source over time.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>a</i>, when the main energy/power source <b>200</b> and the converter <b>205</b> are first activated, they work together in order to deliver current or power to the electrical load <b>210</b> at time t<b>1</b> (set arbitrary to 0 as a starting point). At this point in time, the current flowing into the electrical load <b>210</b> is i1 (with switching element <b>204</b>, <b>209</b> set to conduct a current.) and the current from converter <b>207</b>, i2 is zero or approximately zero (i.e., no power saving) because not enough energy/charge has not been accumulated in the capacitor <b>202</b>. In this particular embodiment, monitor/controller <b>206</b> monitors the parameter(s)/state(s) of the main energy/power source <b>200</b>, heat to electricity converter <b>201</b>, and capacitor <b>202</b>. The monitor/controller <b>206</b> controls the switching elements <b>203</b>,<b>204</b>, <b>208</b>, <b>209</b> and converters <b>205</b>, <b>207</b> based on the parameter(s) or state(s) measured or estimated and by generating and sending out control signals at appropriate times.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>b</i>, as time progresses the heat to electricity converter <b>201</b> starts to generate a potential difference, which is converted to an electrical charge stored on the capacitor <b>202</b>. When a predetermined high voltage (or charge) is developed on the capacitor <b>202</b> at time t<b>2</b>, the monitor/controller <b>206</b> turns on the switching element <b>203</b>, <b>208</b> and the converter <b>207</b> (in an appropriate order) so that current i2 with non-zero value flows to the electrical load <b>210</b>. As current i2 flows to the electrical load, the current drawn from the main power source decreases to i1-i2 times the proportionality factor determined by the conversion ratio of the converter <b>205</b>, which is indicated as k1 in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>b</i>. As the charge in the capacitor <b>202</b> depletes and the voltage (or charge) at the capacitor <b>202</b> drops below a predetermined low threshold, the monitor/controller <b>206</b> then shuts off the switching element <b>203</b>, <b>208</b> and/or the converter <b>207</b> and the process of charging-discharging repeats.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a system and circuit for providing power to an electronic system or device which extends the life of a main energy/power supply, in accordance with a preferred embodiment of the present invention, thereby allowing the main energy/power supply to provide power to an electronic system or device (hereinafter referred to as &#x201c;the load&#x201d;) for an extended period of time. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the main system and circuit <b>313</b> consists of a main energy/power source <b>309</b> (such as a disposable or rechargeable battery, a fuel cell, a hybrid cell, a solar cell, etc.) for driving a load <b>312</b>, which may be any known electronic device or system (such as a microprocessor, memory, a laptop computer, a graphics display, or an electric motor).</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The main system and circuit <b>313</b> further includes a regulator/converter <b>308</b>, and current control elements <b>310</b> and <b>316</b>. Here it is noted that the element <b>308</b> may be a regulator and/or a converter, and each may be used interchangeably as they are equivalent in the context of this document. A regulator maintains its output constant within a specified range regardless of changes to its output loading condition, shifts in environmental conditions (such as temperature, humidity, etc.), and/or variations at its input.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Current control elements <b>310</b> and <b>316</b> are used to control the amount of current provided to the load <b>312</b>. Examples of elements that can be used as a current control element are a diode, field-effect transistors (MOS FET, JFET, etc.), a bipolar transistor, an insulated gate bipolar transistor, a silicon controlled rectifier, and/or a relay switch. One of more of these elements can be connected in series and/or parallel to act as a current control element and placed in any electrical path(s) within a system.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the system and circuit further includes a power generating circuit <b>317</b> having a power generating means <b>306</b> consisting of a heat source <b>300</b>, a thermoelectric generator (TEG) <b>302</b>, a cooler <b>304</b>, a heat source to TEG interface element <b>301</b>, and a TEG to cooler interface element <b>303</b>. The heat source <b>300</b> can be the main energy/power source <b>309</b>, or heat generated by the electrical load <b>312</b> itself, or any other elements that produce heat. Preferably, thermoelectric generator (TEG) <b>302</b> is an element that produces a potential difference (voltage) when a temperature difference exists between its &#x201c;hot&#x201d; and &#x201c;cold&#x201d; sides of the element. Presently, the majority of thermoelectric generators used for room temperature range utilize Bi&#x2014;Te compounds semiconductor materials. The embodiments described herein do not preclude the use of TEG element(s) based on other materials or implementations that may emerge in a future time frame as improved, more efficient TEG materials develop. It is understood that although <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates only a single TEG element, multiple thermoelectric generators (TEG) <b>302</b> elements may be electrically connected in series or/and parallel to achieve desired voltage, current, source impedance, and/or other characteristics. Furthermore, intermediate stages such as switching element(s) can be inserted between the TEGs and controlled by a controller. Note that a heat source can be thermally connected (coupled) to the cold side of a TEG and a cooler can be thermally connected (coupled) to the hot side of a TEG. In that case, a voltage with reversed polarity will be produced but those in the skilled art should be able to utilize the voltage appropriately.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In a preferred embodiment, cooler <b>304</b> is an element that releases heat from the cold side of the TEG so that the temperature on the cold side of the TEG is kept within a prescribed range. There are numerous ways known in the art to implement a cooler, for examples, heat sink (electrically passive or/and active with convection or/and thermoelectric cooler (TEC)), radiator (heat exchanger), liquid coolant (including water produced as a byproduct of a fuel cell), phase changing material, heat pipe, vapor chamber, human body, or/and atmosphere of a planet or a moon. The main purpose of utilizing heat source to TEG interface element <b>301</b> and TEG to cooler interface element <b>303</b> is two fold: 1) to facilitate the efficient transfer of heat and 2) to establish mechanical support and interface for the elements they are interfacing to/from. The heat source to TEG interface element <b>301</b> and the TEG to cooler interface element <b>303</b> may be made of metals, ceramics, or/and graphite and are thermally connected to the elements they are interfacing to/from. Thermal grease-based materials and/or phase changing films can be applied to these elements if deemed desirable. The heat source to TEG interface element <b>301</b> and the TEG to cooler interface element <b>303</b> may be omitted if deemed unnecessary. Note that it is possible to combine the functions of the TEG to cooler interface element <b>303</b> and the cooler <b>304</b>, for example by utilizing flexible graphite material to efficiently conduct and dissipate heat</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the power generating circuit <b>317</b> further includes a capacitor <b>305</b> coupled to the TEG <b>302</b>. As the heat source <b>300</b> produces increased heat, the temperature difference between the cold side of the TEG and the heated side of the TEG increases, causing the TEG to produce electrical potential, which then charges the capacitor <b>305</b>. It should be noted that in the context of this document, charge storage and energy storage are used interchangeably. If necessary, a plurality of capacitors <b>305</b> can be electrically connected in series or/and in parallel to achieve the desired electrical and/or mechanical characteristics. Voltage balancing circuit(s) (either passive or active) can be used to ensure the voltage applied to each capacitor is maintained within a desired range. Furthermore, although not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, current/voltage limiter(s) may be inserted between the thermoelectric generators (TEG) <b>302</b> and the capacitor <b>305</b>, if necessary, in order to control the amount of charge or energy being transferred to and stored on the capacitor <b>305</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the power generating circuit <b>317</b> further includes a converter <b>315</b> coupled between load <b>312</b> and capacitor <b>305</b>. Preferably, converter <b>315</b> is coupled to load <b>312</b> via current control element <b>311</b> and coupled to capacitor <b>305</b> via current control element <b>314</b>. Current control elements <b>314</b> and <b>311</b> control the amount of current drawn from capacitor <b>305</b> into converter <b>315</b> and then provided from converter <b>315</b> to load <b>312</b>. Converter <b>315</b> is an element that takes an input parameter, such as voltage and produces a prescribed parameter(s) such as voltage at the output. In the case where the desired conversion is from a low input voltage to a higher output voltage, a step up (boost) voltage converter can be used. In the case where the desired conversion is from a high input voltage to a lower output voltage, a step down (buck) voltage converter can be used. Alternatively, an inverter can be used if DC to AC conversion is desired. Various implementations of converters (or regulators) are known in the art and the invention is not intended to be limited to any one particular implementation.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> the power generating circuit <b>317</b> also includes a monitor/controller <b>307</b> coupled to capacitor <b>305</b> for monitoring properties of the capacitor <b>305</b> such as the voltage, current, or/and temperature of capacitor <b>305</b>. The monitor/controller <b>307</b> may also be used to monitor parameters, such as voltage or/and temperature of the main energy/power source <b>309</b> and/or the amount of current or power provided to the load from the main energy/power source <b>309</b>. In cases where the main energy/power source <b>309</b> is a fuel cell, the monitor/controller <b>307</b> may also be connected directly to the fuel cell in order to control the amount or rate of fuel supplied to the fuel cell.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">As is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the monitor/controller <b>307</b> is coupled to current control elements <b>310</b>, <b>316</b> and current control elements <b>314</b>, <b>311</b>. The current control elements <b>310</b>, <b>311</b>, <b>314</b>, and <b>316</b> are essentially switching elements which control the flow of current/power to the load based on control signal(s) received from the monitor/controller <b>307</b>. The current control elements <b>310</b> <b>311</b>, <b>314</b>, and <b>316</b> can be implemented with various types of electrical devices such as a field-effect transistor (FET), a bipolar transistor (BJT), an insulated gate bipolar transistor (IGBT), a silicon controlled rectifier (SCR) or/and electromechanical devices. In operation, controller <b>307</b> is configured to monitor and control operations of these current control elements in order to achieve the objectives of the invention. Higher number of current control elements can be utilized if desired.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, as the voltage across the capacitor <b>305</b> reaches a predetermined voltage &#x201c;high&#x201d; level (or a predetermined charge high level), the monitor/controller <b>307</b> enables the current control elements <b>311</b>, <b>314</b> (in an appropriate order) and a current starts to flow into the electrical load <b>312</b> (also assuming the predetermined voltage level is higher or equal to the minimum operating voltage of the converter <b>315</b>) and the current drawn from regulator <b>308</b> is now reduced by the amount of current equal or substantially equal to the current from the converter <b>315</b> output since the regulator <b>308</b> and the converter <b>315</b> outputs are connected in parallel and their output voltages are kept within a prescribed range. Therefore, the current drawn from the energy/power source <b>309</b> is reduced approximately (assuming high efficiency and/or low implementation loss) by the amount of current provided from the converter <b>315</b> times the conversion factor, Vout/Vin of the regulator <b>308</b>. The power saving process continues until the charge (or voltage) in the capacitor <b>305</b> drops below a predetermined low threshold level. It should be noted that the energy stored in the capacitor <b>305</b> can be used to &#x201c;boost&#x201d; the operation of the electrical load <b>312</b> by providing more available power to the load. Either one, or both, of the current control elements <b>311</b> and <b>314</b> can be set to shut off current when the charging process initially starts or during a recharging process.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In order to achieve effective power reduction on the main energy/power source <b>309</b>, the proper current sharing between the converter <b>315</b> and regulator <b>308</b> is required and their output voltages must be properly set and controlled. A small difference in voltages may make one of them completely &#x201c;take over&#x201d; the current supplying process. For example, if the output voltage of the regulator <b>308</b> is 5% higher than the output voltage of the converter <b>315</b>, the regulator <b>308</b> is likely to supply the majority of the current to the electrical load <b>312</b> even though the capacitor <b>305</b> may have been accumulated a large amount of energy over time.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">There are many ways known in the art to implement good current sharing. One implementation utilizes a series resistive element (such as a resistor or a FET) as a sensor element in each converter output current path to sense current, a high gain amplifier such as an operational amplifier, and an integrator to produce an error control signal, which is input to the control port of the converter <b>315</b> and controls the voltage of the converter <b>315</b> so that the output should follow the regulator <b>308</b> output within a specified range. The error is used to adjust the output of the converter <b>315</b> until the current in each path (or the voltage across the sense resistive element) is within a predetermined range. Therefore, by using this technique, the voltage from the regulator <b>315</b> output can be adjusted to follow the voltage from the regulator <b>308</b> output within a desired range once each path starts to conduct current. The current control elements <b>310</b> and <b>311</b> themselves can be used as the series resistive sensor elements to sense (detect) currents/voltages.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Those in the skilled art can select a desired ratio of current sharing between the converter <b>315</b> and the regulator <b>308</b> to suit to the ones' particular applications. For instance, the output voltage of the converter <b>315</b> may be deliberately set at slightly higher voltage than the output voltage of the regulator <b>308</b> so that the converter <b>315</b> can supply majority of the current into the electrical load <b>312</b> once sufficient energy has been stored in the capacitor <b>305</b>. With that being the case, high reduction in power on the main energy/power source <b>309</b> is achievable until the charge stored in the capacitor <b>305</b> drops below a predetermined low threshold level. Under a heavy electrical loading condition, however, the current on the electrical load <b>312</b> may require a current which exceeds the maximum current supply capability of the converter <b>315</b> and/or that of the capacitor <b>305</b>. With this being the case, the output voltage of the converter <b>315</b> may drop and become lower than the output voltage of the regulator <b>308</b> (due to the limiting action of the converter <b>315</b>) and the current control/switching element <b>311</b> (such as a diode) cuts off the electrical path to the electrical load <b>312</b>, forcing the regulator <b>308</b> to supply again the entire current to the electrical load <b>312</b>. More specifically, as more charge is stored on capacitor <b>305</b>, more power and current can be provided from the capacitor <b>305</b> to load <b>312</b> via converter <b>315</b> and current control elements <b>311</b> and <b>314</b>. Monitor/controller <b>307</b> measures this power/current as it increases and is then able to control the current/power provided by main energy/power source <b>309</b> to the load <b>312</b> via current control elements <b>310</b> and <b>316</b>. Accordingly, as the power/current provided from capacitor <b>305</b> increases, the amount of power/current which must be drawn from the main energy/power source <b>309</b> and provided to load <b>312</b> decreases, using less of the energy from the main energy/power source <b>309</b> over time and extending the life of the main energy/power source. Additionally, the energy stored in the capacitor <b>305</b> may be used to supply current or power to the load <b>312</b> as a backup or uninterrupted power source when the main energy/power source <b>309</b> fails to operate properly or is temporarily removed/disconnected from the system (e.g., replacing the battery of a laptop computer without disrupting the operation of the system).</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">If the main energy/power source <b>309</b> is a disposable battery or a hybrid cell, a battery life extension results by reducing the power drawn from the main energy/power source <b>309</b> attributed to the power saving process as described herein. Suppose that the main energy/power source <b>309</b> is a battery with 1000 mAh capacity and the load <b>312</b> draws average current of 500 mA at 5V. If the converter <b>315</b> can supply 56 mA of average current (at 5V) to the load <b>312</b>, then 5V times 0.0056 A=0.28 W of power out of 2.5 W (=5V times 0.5 A) is supplied by the converter <b>315</b> until the voltage (or charge) drops below a predetermined low threshold. Assuming 90% efficiency of the regulator <b>308</b>, that corresponds to 0.28 W/0.9=0.31 W of power delivered by the main energy/power source <b>309</b>. Without the current (or power) from the converter <b>315</b>, the battery life is 1000 mAh/500 mA=2 hours. However, if it takes, for example 35 minutes to first charge the capacitor <b>305</b> to a predetermined high level and 5 minutes to deplete the charge to a predetermined low level and then 15 minutes to recharge to the predetermined high level thereafter, the average current drawn from the battery becomes approximately 488.3 mA and the battery life becomes 1000 mAh/488.3 mA=2.05 hours. To reduce the long initial charging time on an uncharged capacitor, the main energy/power source <b>309</b> (with the appropriate current control elements and monitoring schemes) may be used to rapidly charge the capacitor <b>305</b>. Charging from the main energy/power source <b>309</b> may be useful for maintaining a certain amount of charge (energy) in the capacitor <b>305</b> when heat is not available (such as during power down).</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In a preferred embodiment, monitor/controller <b>307</b> can be purely implemented in hardware (for example, by using a comparator with hysteresis, a reference voltage generator, and a switch element driver) or in a combination of hardware and software (for example, using a CPU, an ADC, switch element driver(s), and memory with embedded software). Indeed, the monitor <b>307</b> can include and utilize analog to digital converters (ADCs), digital to analog converters (DACs), negative voltage generator(s), or/and level shift circuitries with switch element drivers and they can be all integrated into a single integrated circuit (IC). A clock signal for the monitor/controller <b>307</b> can be generated by a low power oscillator whose power is supplied by either the main energy/power source <b>309</b> or the capacitor <b>305</b>. The monitor/controller <b>307</b> can be powered up by the main energy/power source <b>309</b>, the capacitor <b>305</b>, or an external source.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">If the monitor/controller <b>307</b> is implemented in software, portions of the control software may comprise an ordered listing of executable instructions for implementing logical functions, and can be embodied in any computer-readable medium for use by or in connection with an instruction execution system, apparatus, or device, such as a computer-based system, processor-containing system, or other system that can fetch the instructions from the instruction execution system, apparatus, or device and execute the instructions.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows an alternate embodiment of a power saving circuit for the present invention in which there are double charging stages. This particular configuration has two capacitors <b>405</b> and <b>405</b>&#x2032;, two converters <b>406</b> and <b>406</b>&#x2032;, a monitor/controller <b>407</b> and two switching elements <b>411</b> and <b>411</b>&#x2032;. As with the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, switching elements <b>411</b> and <b>411</b>&#x2032; are controlled by the monitor/controller <b>407</b> so that they are set to conduct currents as well as to shut off currents at appropriate times. The monitor/controller <b>407</b> monitors various parameters of the capacitors <b>405</b> and <b>405</b>&#x2032;, such as voltage, current, temperature, etc. In the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the capacitor <b>405</b>&#x2032; can be a main charge reservoir and the switching elements <b>411</b> and <b>411</b>&#x2032; can isolate the charge reservoir from the rest of the system/circuit when the load is turned off (or the main system is powered down) so as to prevent depletion of the charge stored on capacitor <b>405</b>&#x2032; due to leakage during power shut off. The capacitances of the capacitors <b>405</b>, <b>405</b>&#x2032; as well as other factors must be carefully considered and analyzed to not incur instability of the converters <b>406</b>, <b>406</b>&#x2032;. Also, there exist ways to charge capacitors and produce a voltage higher than the voltage from which they operate. One example is the use of a charge-pump (or sometimes called as voltage multiplier) utilizing a plurality of capacitors, switching elements, and clock signal(s). These charging or voltage generating techniques can be used if deemed desirable. A clock signal for the charge-pump can be generated by a low power oscillator whose power is supplied by either the main energy/power source <b>309</b> or the capacitor <b>305</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, in a first state, switch <b>411</b> is initially open, allowing charge to build up quickly on capacitor <b>405</b>. When that charge reaches a certain high or fully charged level, switch <b>411</b> is closed and the charge is transferred to capacitor <b>405</b>&#x2032;. Once the charge has been fully switched over to capacitor <b>405</b>&#x2032;, switch <b>411</b> may open. In this state, charge builds up on capacitor <b>405</b>, while the charge which was transferred to capacitor <b>405</b>&#x2032; may then be supplied to the load. Again, once the charge on storage element <b>405</b> reaches a certain high or fully charged level and once charge at capacitor <b>405</b>&#x2032; has been fully exhausted or drops below a certain threshold level, the charge from capacitor <b>405</b> is then switched to capacitor <b>405</b>&#x2032; and the process repeats itself. In this way, the system can build-up charge/energy while at the same time providing charge/energy, thereby making the system more efficient. As in the previous embodiment, a main energy source can be used to charge capacitor <b>405</b> or/and capacitor <b>405</b>&#x2032; if desired.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows an alternate embodiment of a system of the present invention having a slightly simpler structure. As in the previous embodiment described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, it has power generation means <b>565</b>, capacitor <b>555</b>, converter <b>556</b>, monitor/controller <b>557</b>, main power/energy source <b>559</b>, current control element <b>561</b>, and electrical load <b>562</b>. Unlike the embodiment shown with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the alternative embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> further includes a sensor <b>563</b>, which senses the difference between the voltages from the main power/energy source <b>559</b> and the converter <b>556</b> output and produces an error control signal that is used to adjust the output voltage of the converter <b>556</b> so that the output voltage can follow the voltage from the main energy source <b>559</b> within an acceptable range. As mentioned previously, one can utilize implementations known in the art in order to achieve this feedback/control. One such example is placing a series resistive element (such as a resistor or a FET) as a sensor or sensing element in each output current path to sense current, a high gain amplifier such as an OP amp and an integrator to integrate the difference voltage and produce an error signal to controls the feedback voltage of the converter <b>556</b>. The feedback voltage is varied by the error control signal until the current in each path (or the voltage across the sense resistive element) is within a predetermined range.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Preferably, the sensor <b>563</b> is designed so that it controls the output of converter <b>556</b> to supply the proper voltage at the electrical load <b>562</b>. This is important especially if the current control element <b>561</b> introduces a non-constant voltage drop. Therefore, instead of monitoring the voltage at the converter <b>556</b> output, monitoring the voltage at the output of the current control element <b>561</b> (or at the electrical load <b>562</b>) is perhaps a better way. If this is done, then a resistive sensing element is preferably inserted between the current control element <b>561</b> and the electrical load <b>562</b>. Alternatively, the current control element <b>561</b> can be used as a sensing resistive element for the sensor <b>563</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">It should be noted that the sensor <b>563</b> is needed assuming an unregulated, varying voltage from the main energy/power source <b>559</b>. The sensor <b>563</b> can be driven and/or powered by the main energy/power source <b>559</b>, the capacitor <b>555</b>, the converter <b>556</b>, or from any other external source. The functionality of the sensor <b>563</b> can be integrated into the monitor/controller <b>557</b> as in the form of a module consisting of discrete components or/and various integrated circuits. It is also possible that the sensor <b>563</b> can be interfaced with and controlled by the monitor/controller <b>557</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">As in the previous embodiment described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the monitor/controller <b>557</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> monitors various parameters in the system such as the voltage, current, or/and temperature of an element and for this embodiment, the monitor <b>557</b> monitors the voltage at the capacitor <b>555</b> and controls the current control element <b>561</b> with current control signal(s). It is also possible to configure the monitor/controller <b>557</b> such that it controls the operation, properties, or/and the state of the converter <b>556</b>, the heat source <b>550</b>, or any other element shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. Furthermore, it is also possible to implement the monitor/controller <b>557</b> to monitor and control a plural of the element(s) shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> (not necessarily simultaneously) and also interface with the sensor <b>563</b> and/or external element(s). The monitor/controller <b>557</b> can be purely implemented in hardware (for example, by using a comparator with hysteresis, a reference voltage generator, and a switch element driver) or in a combination of hardware and software (for example, using a CPU, an ADC, switch element driver, and memory with embedded software). Indeed, the monitor/controller <b>557</b> can include and utilize analog to digital converters (ADCs), digital to analog converters ([DACs), negative voltage generator(s), or/and level shift circuitries with switch element drivers, clock generator(s), and they can be all integrated into a single integrated circuit (IC).</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The power generating means <b>565</b> preferably consists of heat source <b>550</b>, a thermoelectric generator (TEG) <b>552</b>, a cooler <b>554</b>, a heat source to TEG interface element <b>551</b>, and TEG to cooler interface element <b>553</b>. Again, the heat source <b>550</b> can be the main power source <b>559</b>, the electrical load <b>562</b>, or/and any other elements internal or external to the system and circuit that produce or possess heat.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">As the main power/energy source <b>559</b> is electrically connected to the electrical load <b>562</b>, heat is generated, for instance from the main power source <b>559</b> and/or the electrical load <b>562</b> and either one or both of them can be used as the heat source <b>550</b>. As heat is produced and the cooler <b>554</b> removes the heat from the cold side of the TEG <b>552</b> or/and TEG to cooler interface element <b>553</b>, a temperature difference is produced between the cold and the hot sides of the TEG <b>552</b> and in turn it produces a potential difference (i.e., voltage) that charges the capacitor <b>555</b>. Charge (or energy) is built up in the capacitor <b>555</b> in order to provide current and/or power to the electrical load <b>562</b>, which up until such time remains driven by the main power/energy source <b>559</b> without power saving.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Once a predetermined amount of charge is built up on the capacitor <b>555</b>, the converter <b>556</b> starts to produce an output voltage which is approximately equal to the output voltage of the main power/energy source <b>559</b> and if the monitor/controller <b>557</b> determines that the charge stored in the capacitor <b>555</b> has reached a predetermined high value, it enables the current control element <b>561</b> and the current flows to the electrical load <b>562</b>, thereby reducing the current (and hence the corresponding power) drawn from the main power/energy source <b>559</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">As the current flows from the converter <b>556</b> to the electrical load <b>562</b>, the sensor <b>563</b> improves the accuracy of tracking and the proper current sharing is maintained. For even a simpler embodiment, the monitor/controller <b>557</b> can be omitted and a diode can be used as the current control element <b>561</b>. The sensor <b>563</b> must take into account the voltage drop associated with the diode for that case.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">As in the previous embodiment, there could be intermediate stages between the power generation means <b>565</b> and the capacitor <b>555</b> for efficient charging of the capacitor. By way of example, such intermediate stages may include any one or combination of circuits such as charge-pump or voltage multipliers. Also, charging of multiple storage elements with multiple heat sources or power generating means is possible.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">In cases where the electrical load <b>562</b> is an inverter (DC to AC converter), which subsequently can drives AC loads such as an AC motor, a home appliance, and etc. it is possible to achieve highly efficient power utilization. For example, for an electric car whose main energy supply is the main power/energy source <b>559</b> (such as fuel cell), heat generated from main power/energy source <b>559</b> or/and regenerated energy during braking can charge capacitor <b>555</b>. The energy collected then can be used to assist the main power/energy source <b>559</b> in delivering power to the electrical load <b>562</b> and its subsequent loads such as AC motor(s). Again, it is possible to boost the power of the electrical loads if desired. As another example, an AC generator to supply power to AC equipment (television, heater, lamps, etc.) in outdoor environments or places where AC outlet is not available can be powered up by the main/power energy source <b>559</b> (fuel cell etc.). The heat generated by the energy source <b>559</b> or any other heat source can be transformed to electrical energy which is then collected and stored in the capacitor <b>555</b>. The stored energy can be used to assist the energy source <b>559</b> in delivering power to the electrical load <b>562</b> and its subsequent loads such as lamps.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows an alternate embodiment of a power saving circuit for the present invention in which there are parallel charging stages which are used in an alternating fashion in order to increase the life and efficiency of a main power/energy source. This particular configuration has two capacitors <b>602</b> and <b>603</b>, a single converter <b>605</b>, a monitor/controller <b>607</b>, a switching element <b>606</b> and two main switching elements <b>601</b>, <b>604</b> (each having at least two individual switches that can be independently controlled by the monitor/controller <b>607</b>). As with the embodiments illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref>, switching elements <b>601</b>, <b>604</b>, <b>606</b> are controlled by the monitor/controller <b>607</b> so that they are set to conduct currents as well as to shut off currents at appropriate times. The monitor/controller <b>607</b> monitors various parameters of the capacitors <b>602</b> and <b>603</b>, such as voltage, current, temperature, etc. It is understood that the capacitors <b>602</b> and <b>603</b> can each consist of a plurality of capacitors electrically connected in series and/or parallel.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, in a first or initial state switching element <b>601</b> is configured such that one switch is configured to allow charge to build up quickly on capacitor <b>602</b> while the other switch remains open. In this initial state, the first switch in switching element <b>604</b> is open, while the second switch may be closed. When the charge on capacitor <b>602</b> reaches a certain high or fully charged level, the first switch in switching element <b>601</b> is then opened and the second switch in switching element <b>601</b> is then closed. Additionally, the first switch in switching element <b>604</b> is then closed, while the second switch in switching element <b>604</b> is then open. In this state, charge builds up on capacitor <b>603</b>, while the charge which was built up on capacitor <b>602</b> may then be supplied to the load. Again, once the charge on capacitor <b>603</b> reaches a certain high or fully charged level and once charge at capacitor <b>602</b> has been fully exhausted or drops below a certain low level, the individual switches in switching elements <b>601</b> and <b>604</b> are then alternated, closing the first switch and opening the second switch in switching element <b>601</b>, while opening the first switch and closing the second switch in switching element <b>604</b>. In this state, the charge build up on capacitor <b>603</b> is then applied to the load while capacitor <b>602</b> is recharged (assuming switching element <b>606</b> is set to conduct current). In this way, the system can build-up charge/energy while at the same time providing charge/energy, thereby making the system more efficient. It is understood that switching element <b>601</b> can be connected to multiple TEGs each having own heat source and cooler and the monitor/controller <b>607</b> selects/enables appropriate electrical path(s) to charge capacitor(s). In a system, heat generated by its constituents may differ and may also be time dependent. The monitor/controller <b>607</b> can monitor the state of the capacitors and the temperature of the constituents and charge/discharge the capacitors in an optimal way.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Finally, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, there is illustrated yet another alternative embodiment of an entire drive system which includes an alternative power saving circuit for providing power to an electronic system or device which extends the life of a main energy/power source, in accordance with the present invention. As shown, the circuit includes a common heat source <b>701</b> which is coupled to two different TEGs, which convert the heat generated by the source <b>701</b> into power. As with the previous described embodiments, the heat source can be any known heat source&#x2014;such as heat generated by the load itself. Using the heat generated by the heat source <b>701</b>, each of the two TEGs produce a potential difference (voltage).</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">As further shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, each of these TEGs is coupled to a separate capacitor <b>703</b><i>a </i>and <b>703</b><i>b</i>, which are arranged in parallel relative to the load to which the circuit is coupled. As each TEG converts the heat from the heat source into an electrical potential, this potential charges the respective capacitor to which that TEG is coupled.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, each of the capacitors <b>703</b><i>a </i>and <b>703</b><i>b </i>is in turn coupled to a converter <b>704</b> via switching elements <b>705</b><i>a</i>, <b>705</b><i>b</i>. The power converter <b>704</b> is designed to generate a predetermined and regulated power (voltage and current) output level. It is understood that the switching elements <b>705</b><i>a</i>, <b>705</b><i>b </i>may be separate or integrated into a single switch, just so long as they are each capable of operating separately. Each of the individual switching elements is coupled to a monitor/controller <b>708</b> that controls operations of the individual switching elements. The converter <b>704</b> is coupled to the load via a current control element <b>706</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">In operation, the monitor/controller <b>708</b> monitors the current through current control element <b>706</b> and the voltage at capacitors <b>703</b><i>a </i>and <b>703</b><i>b</i>. As the load draws more current from either one of the capacitors <b>703</b><i>a </i>and <b>703</b><i>b</i>, the voltage on said capacitor will drop and the current which passes through control element <b>706</b> will also begin to drop. Once the current drawn by the load (passing through current control element <b>706</b>) and/or the voltage at the relative capacitor from which it is provided, falls below an acceptable and/or predetermined level then the monitor/controller <b>708</b> will switch between <b>705</b><i>a </i>and <b>705</b><i>b</i>. Accordingly, for example, in an initial state the circuit may be configured to have switching element <b>705</b><i>a </i>closed and <b>705</b><i>b </i>open. In this configuration, both capacitors <b>703</b><i>a </i>and <b>703</b><i>b </i>are charged but only voltage from capacitor <b>703</b><i>a </i>is used to drive the load. The monitor/controller <b>708</b> continues to monitor the voltage at this capacitor <b>703</b><i>a </i>and the current through current control element <b>706</b>&#x2014;i.e. the current drawn by the load. As the voltage on capacitor <b>703</b><i>a </i>drops, the current drawn by the load through current control element <b>706</b> will also drop. Once the voltage on capacitor <b>703</b><i>a </i>or the current drawn to the load (passing through element <b>706</b>) drops below a certain and predetermined level, the monitor/controller <b>708</b> will then switch between <b>705</b><i>a </i>and <b>705</b><i>b</i>, opening <b>705</b><i>a </i>and closing <b>705</b><i>b</i>. Once this is done, voltage from capacitor <b>703</b><i>b </i>will be used to drive the load. The monitor/controller <b>708</b> then monitors the voltage at capacitor <b>703</b><i>b </i>and the current through current control element <b>706</b>&#x2014;i.e. the current drawn by the load. As the voltage on capacitor <b>703</b><i>b </i>drops, the current drawn by the load through current control element <b>706</b> will also drop. Once the voltage on capacitor <b>703</b><i>b </i>or the current drawn to the load (passing through element <b>706</b>) drops below a certain and predetermined level, the monitor/controller <b>708</b> will then switch back between <b>705</b><i>a </i>and <b>705</b><i>b</i>, closing <b>705</b><i>a </i>and opening <b>705</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">One advantage of the circuit described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is that capacitors <b>703</b><i>a </i>and <b>703</b><i>b </i>will continue to store charge, as needed, at all times the circuit is in operation. The switching elements <b>705</b><i>a </i>and <b>705</b><i>b </i>are selectively and alternatively activated in order to drive the load, with their switching being activated by a monitor/controller <b>708</b> which monitors the voltage on capacitors <b>703</b><i>a </i>and <b>703</b><i>b</i>, as well as the current drawn to the load (i.e. the current passing through element <b>706</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">While the description above contains many specifics, these should not be construed as limitations on the scope of the invention, but rather as exemplifications of particular embodiments thereof One of ordinary skill in the art may make many changes, modifications, and substitutions without necessarily departing from the spirit and scope of the invention. Accordingly, the scope of the invention should be determined not by the embodiments described above, but by the appended claims and their legal equivalents.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An energy boost circuit adapted to provide a power to a load, the circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a pair of thermoelectric generators (TEGs), each TEG coupled to a heat source and each adapted to convert thermal energy from the heat source into electrical energy;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first capacitor bank and a second capacitor bank arranged in parallel, each capacitor bank coupled to one of the TEGs and adapted to store electrical energy generated by the TEG to which the capacitor bank is coupled;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first switching element coupled to the first capacitor bank;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second switching element coupled to the second capacitor bank;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a power converter connected to the first and second capacitor banks; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a monitor/controller coupled to the first and second switching elements and adapted to selectively switch the first and second switching elements in order to provide a power boost to the load,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the monitor/controller automatically switches the first and second switching elements based at least partly on charge levels measured at the first and second capacitor banks.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The energy boost circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising a main power source coupled to the load in order to provide power to the load.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The energy boost circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> further comprising a third switching element coupled between the power converter and the load, wherein the monitor/controller is further coupled to the third switching element and is further adapted to switch the third switching element.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The energy boost circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> further comprising a regulator coupled between the main power source and the load.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The energy boost circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the main power source comprises one of a battery, a fuel cell, and a solar cell.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The energy boost circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the main power source acts as the heat source.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The energy boost circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the load acts as the heat source.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A boost circuit adapted to provide power to a load, the boost circuit comprising:
<claim-text>an energy converting circuit having a pair of thermoelectric generators (TEGs), each coupled to a heat source and each adapted to convert thermal energy from the heat source into electrical energy;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first capacitor bank and a second capacitor bank arranged in parallel, each of the first and second capacitor banks coupled to one of the TEGs, each of the first and second capacitor banks adapted to store the electrical energy generated by the TEG to which the capacitor bank is coupled;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first power converter coupled to the first capacitor bank;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first switching element coupled between the first power converter and the load;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second power converter coupled to the second capacitor bank;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second switching element coupled between the second power converter and the load; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a monitor/controller coupled to the first and second switching elements adapted to selectively switch the first and second switching elements in order to provide a power boost to the load; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the monitor/controller switches the first and second switching elements based at least partly on charge levels measured at the first and second capacitor banks.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The boost circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>a third switching element coupled between the first power converter and the first capacitor bank; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth switching element coupled between the second power converter and the second capacitor bank,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the monitor/controller is further adapted to selectively switch the third and fourth switching elements in order to provide power from each of the capacitor banks to each of the power converters and the monitor/controller switches among the third and fourth switching elements based at least partly on charge levels measured at the first and second capacitor banks.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The boost circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> further comprising a main power source coupled to the load and capable of providing power to the load.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The boost circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the main power source comprises one of a battery, a fuel cell, and a solar cell.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The boost circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the main power source acts as the heat source.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The boost circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref> further comprising a regulator coupled between the main power source and the load.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The boost circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the load acts as the heat source.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A method adapted to efficiently provide a power boost to a load, the method comprising:
<claim-text>providing a pair of thermoelectric generators (TEGs), each TEG coupled to a heat source and each adapted to convert thermal energy from the heat source into electrical energy;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a first capacitor bank and a second capacitor bank connected in parallel, each capacitor bank coupled to one of the TEGs;</claim-text>
<claim-text>storing the electrical energy generated by each of the TEGs using the capacitor bank to which the TEG is coupled;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a first switching element coupled between the first capacitor bank and the load;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a second switching element coupled between the second capacitor bank and the load;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing at least one power converter between the first and second switching elements and the load; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>switching the first and second switching elements in order to provide a power boost to the load, the switching being performed at least partly based on charge levels measured at the first and second capacitor banks.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>providing a third switching element coupled between the power converter and the load; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>switching the third switching element in order to provide a power boost to the load.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref> further comprising providing a regulator coupled between a main power source and the load.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the main power source comprises one of a battery, a fuel cell, and a solar cell.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the main power source acts as the heat source.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the load acts as the heat source.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
