<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623267-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623267</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12770363</doc-number>
<date>20100429</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>113</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>29</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>49</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>264523</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Pressure vessel</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5287987</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Gaiser</name>
<date>19940200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>220589</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5568878</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>LeBreton</name>
<date>19961000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>220 6219</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>7</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11829204</doc-number>
<date>20070727</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>ABANDONED</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12770363</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>60820688</doc-number>
<date>20060728</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20100212815</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20100826</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kanach</last-name>
<first-name>Roman</first-name>
<address>
<city>River Falls</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kanach</last-name>
<first-name>Roman</first-name>
<address>
<city>River Falls</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Johnston, Esq.</last-name>
<first-name>R. Blake</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>DLA Piper LLP US</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Ecowater Systems LLC</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Woodbury</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Huson</last-name>
<first-name>Monica</first-name>
<department>1742</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An improved molded, reinforced pressure vessel having a winding foot on the liner tank which includes a head, disposed away from the tank and a narrowed neck extending between the head and the tank wherein outer radial dimensions of the head are greater than outer radial dimension of the neck. The improved foot design allows windings to cover more of the liner tank that maximizes the reinforcement provided by the winding and in blow molded liner tanks, the narrow neck restricts the migration of material out of and away from the foot, thus producing a stronger liner tank.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="198.20mm" wi="85.68mm" file="US08623267-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="213.53mm" wi="130.81mm" file="US08623267-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="198.37mm" wi="101.52mm" file="US08623267-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="212.51mm" wi="173.99mm" file="US08623267-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a divisional of U.S. application Ser. No. 11/829,204, filed Jul. 27, 2007, now abandoned that claims priority from U.S. Provisional Patent Application Ser. No. 60/820,688, filed Jul. 28, 2006.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to containers for holding pressurized contents and more particularly to molded, reinforced pressure vessels.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Pressurized vessels have been used for many years. One form of pressurized vessel has a gas-tight liner with a cylindrical central section and two rounded, generally semispherical end portions. It is common for a port to be located at one longitudinal end of the vessel, at the center of one of the semispherical ends. Fibers are wound around the exterior surface of the liner, thereby strengthening the liner to form a vessel capable of containing pressurized contents. Such pressurized contents may be water, or other liquids, or gasses.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In construction, the liner is generally molded from plastic. One common form of molding liners is blow molding, where plastic (or other desirable liner material) is extruded or pre-formed into a tube or other desirable shape and then placed in a mold at an elevated temperature. Air is then forced into the center of the plastic, thereby forcing the soft plastic outward against the walls of the mold. The outer surface of the plastic takes the shape of the mold, while the inner surface of the plastic loosely follows the contours of the outer surface, thus forming a generally smooth inner surface.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">One common problem with blow molded containers is the development of thin spots due to stretching of material around corners of the mold. The thin spots create weak portions of the liner, thus limiting its capability to hold pressurized material.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">One feature that is used during the manufacturing process of the pressure vessels described above is a &#x201c;foot&#x201d; located at one longitudinal end of the liner (usually the end opposing the port of the container). The liner is gripped at the foot during winding of the fibers. Some manufacturers mold the liner and then affix a foot to the liner after molding. The extra step of adding the foot adds cost and time to the liner making process. To overcome this, some manufacturers have tried to mold a foot onto the liner during the blow molding process. Thin spots are located proximate the inside corners and the center of the foot. These thin spots lead to weakening of the liner, and thus decreased stress resistance and reduced performance of the pressure vessel.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Generally, resin coated fibers are wound around the liner in various directions. Fibers are wound radially around the tubular center section of the liner. The radial windings may form one or more layers and usually do not cover the end portions of the liner. Fibers are also wound longitudinally around the liner. The longitudinal windings are generally wrapped around the ends of the vessel in a number of directions, thereby encircling the foot and providing structural reinforcement to the covered portions. Radial windings may be applied first, followed by longitudinal windings, or vice versa. The windings are wrapped tangentially around the foot to cover the entire end of the vessel. Once the fibers are wrapped, the resin is cured to provide a strong pressure vessel.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Generally, fibers are not wound over the foot, leaving an unreinforced portion at one end of the liner. Thus, the foot presents a potential weak spot in the pressure vessel. It would be beneficial to provide a vessel design which minimizes the unreinforced area and thin spots in the liner.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">For the purpose of illustrating the invention, the drawings show forms of the invention that are presently preferred. However, it should be understood that this invention is not limited to the precise arrangements and instrumentalities shown in the drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a side elevational view of a pressure vessel according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a bottom plan view of a pressure vessel according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a top plan view of a pressure vessel according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a side elevational view of a pressure vessel having a radial winding, according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a front elevational view of a pressure vessel, having a radial winding and a partial longitudinal winding, according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Referring now to the drawings where like numerals indicate like elements, there is shown an exemplary embodiment of a pressure vessel according to the present invention, which is generally referred to by the numeral <b>10</b>. The pressure vessel <b>10</b> is primarily intended for use as a container for pressurized liquids or gasses. In a particularly preferred embodiment, the pressure vessel is used as a pressurized container in water softener or water treatment devices and applications.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-5</figref> show pressure vessels <b>10</b> constructed according to an embodiment of the present invention. The vessels <b>10</b> have a liner tank <b>12</b>, covered by radial windings <b>14</b> and longitudinal windings <b>16</b>, as is best seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>. The vessel <b>10</b>, which generally follows the shape of the liner tank <b>12</b>, has a generally tubular center section <b>18</b> with rounded end portions <b>20</b>, <b>22</b> at opposing longitudinal ends of the center section <b>18</b>. The end portions <b>20</b>, <b>22</b> may be semispherical or have some other rounded configuration, without sharp edges, that facilitates the longitudinal winding of fibers around the liner tank <b>12</b>. A port <b>30</b> is disposed at the first end of the vessel <b>10</b> and a foot <b>24</b> is disposed at the second end <b>22</b>. Those skilled in the art will recognize that the vessel may have a number of variations from the general shape described above without departing from the scope of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The figures show various views of the second longitudinal end <b>22</b> of a liner tank <b>12</b>. The foot <b>24</b> extends longitudinally away from the second end <b>22</b>. As best shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the foot <b>24</b> has a head <b>26</b> and a neck <b>28</b> extending between the head <b>26</b> and the liner tank <b>12</b>. The foot <b>24</b> has a generally oblong profile, with the head <b>26</b> being wider and longer than the neck <b>28</b>. The head <b>26</b> is sized and shaped to facilitate the engagement of the foot <b>24</b> with equipment used to wind the fibers <b>14</b>, <b>16</b> around the liner tank <b>12</b>. The shape of the foot <b>24</b> may vary as long as a narrow neck <b>28</b> portion is provided with a head <b>26</b> which is dimensionally larger than the neck <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">On prior art vessels, neck portions were at least as large as the head. However, in the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-5</figref>, the neck <b>28</b> is narrower than the head <b>26</b>. The narrow neck <b>28</b> allows the longitudinal windings <b>16</b> to cover more of the second end <b>22</b> of the vessel, thus strengthening the vessel <b>10</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref> show longitudinal windings <b>16</b> wrapped around the neck <b>28</b>, under the head <b>26</b>. Thus, the vessel <b>12</b> has increased strength, due to the increased area covered by the longitudinal winding <b>16</b>, over vessels of the prior art.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In vessels that are constructed using blow molding, such as the one shown in the figures, the narrow neck <b>28</b> design also adds strength by minimizing thin spots in the liner tank <b>12</b>. During the molding process, the liner tank material fills the foot portion <b>24</b> of a mold. When pressurized gas, such as air, is blown into the center of the material, the liner material expands to the walls of the mold. In the present embodiment, during molding, the liner material thickness in the second end <b>22</b> stays constant because the foot portion <b>24</b> has a narrow neck <b>28</b> which restricts the flow of air into the foot portion <b>24</b> and the migration of liner material out of the foot portion <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">An interior surface <b>32</b> of the liner tank <b>12</b> defines the interior of the vessel <b>10</b>. As mentioned above, the liner wall <b>40</b> thickness is generally constant across the second end <b>22</b>. During molding, a small impression (not shown) forms inside of the liner tank <b>12</b>, adjacent the foot <b>24</b>. The impression is shallow enough that there are no thin spots formed in the liner wall <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The improvements shown in the vessel <b>10</b> in view of those formed using other prior art techniques is highlighted in that weak spots in a prior art vessel are formed at the tip of the foot and where there are sharp corners formed on the foot. In the present invention the foot <b>24</b> has a narrow neck <b>28</b>, thus restriction the migration of material away from the foot <b>24</b> during molding. This leads to a robust second end <b>22</b> and a stronger vessel <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In summary, the vessel <b>10</b> is stronger than those seen in the prior art because of the design of foot <b>24</b>, for example. The foot <b>24</b> has a narrow neck <b>28</b>, thus allowing windings to cover more of the liner tank <b>12</b>, maximizing the reinforcement provided by the winding. Furthermore, in blow molded liner tanks, the narrow neck <b>28</b> restricts the migration of material out of and away from the foot <b>24</b>, thus producing a stronger liner tank <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Although the invention has been described and illustrated with respect to the exemplary embodiments thereof, it should be understood by those skilled in the art that the foregoing and various other changes, omissions and additions may be made therein and thereto, without parting from the spirit and scope of the present invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method of making a pressure vessel comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>a) providing a mold featuring walls defining a generally tubular center section and two generally rounded end portions located one each at opposing longitudinal ends of the center section, said mold walls also defining a foot portion in communication with a first one of the rounded end portions of the mold, said foot portion having a head portion and a neck portion with the neck portion extending between the head portion and the first one of the rounded end portions of the mold, said neck portion of the mold being dimensionally narrower than the head portion of the mold;</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) inserting a material into the mold;</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) blowing pressurized gas into the center of the material so that the material expands to the walls of the mold so that a pressure vessel is formed;</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) restricting the flow of air into the foot portion of the mold using the neck portion of the mold so that migration of material out of the foot portion of the mold is restricted so that the material entirely fills the foot portion of the mold so that the foot portion of the mold forms a closed end of the vessel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the material includes a plastic.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>radially winding a fiber material about a center section of the pressure vessel; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>longitudinally winding the fiber material outwardly of the radial winding and in a general longitudinal direction about the pressure vessel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref> wherein the fiber is a resin coated fiber.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the pressure vessel formed in step c) has a material thickness that is generally constant across a generally rounded end portion upon which the foot is formed.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the head portion of the mold has an oblong profile.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> further comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>e) providing equipment for winding fibers about the vessel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>f) engaging the foot with the equipment;</claim-text>
<claim-text>g) winding fibers about the vessel using the equipment. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
