<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624366-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624366</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13456660</doc-number>
<date>20120426</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>100114747 A</doc-number>
<date>20110427</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>23</main-group>
<subgroup>495</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257675</main-classification>
<further-classification>257691</further-classification>
<further-classification>257706</further-classification>
<further-classification>257796</further-classification>
<further-classification>438112</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e61">Semiconductor package structure and method of fabricating the same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7241645</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Zhao et al.</name>
<date>20070700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438122</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8097943</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Badakere et al.</name>
<date>20120100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257691</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>5</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257675</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257691</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257706</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257796</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E23033</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E21599</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438112</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>19</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120273930</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121101</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tseng</last-name>
<first-name>Tzyy-Jang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hu</last-name>
<first-name>Dyi-Chung</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hu</last-name>
<first-name>Yu-Shan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tseng</last-name>
<first-name>Tzyy-Jang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hu</last-name>
<first-name>Dyi-Chung</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hu</last-name>
<first-name>Yu-Shan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Edwards Wildman Palmer LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Corless</last-name>
<first-name>Peter F.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="03" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Jensen</last-name>
<first-name>Steven M.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Unimicron Technology Corporation</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Doan</last-name>
<first-name>Theresa T</first-name>
<department>2814</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A semiconductor package structure is provided, including: a semiconductor chip having electrode pads disposed thereon and metal bumps disposed on the electrode pads; an encapsulant encapsulating the semiconductor chip; a dielectric layer formed on the encapsulant and having a plurality of patterned intaglios formed therein for exposing the metal bumps; a wiring layer formed in the patterned intaglios of the dielectric layer and electrically connected to the metal bumps; and a metal foil having a plurality of metal posts disposed on a surface thereof such that the metal foil is disposed on the encapsulant with the metal posts penetrating the encapsulant so as to extend to the inactive surface of the semiconductor chip. Compared with the prior art, the present invention reduces the overall thickness of the package structure, increases the electrical transmission efficiency and improves the heat dissipating effect.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="60.62mm" wi="161.04mm" file="US08624366-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="126.07mm" wi="159.68mm" file="US08624366-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="150.96mm" wi="142.24mm" file="US08624366-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="163.58mm" wi="148.84mm" file="US08624366-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="249.34mm" wi="160.78mm" file="US08624366-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="257.47mm" wi="164.25mm" file="US08624366-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCES TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims under 35 U.S.C. &#xa7;119(a) the benefit of Taiwanese Application No. 100114747, filed Apr. 27, 2011, the entire contents of which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to semiconductor package structures and methods of fabricating the same, and, more particularly, to a semiconductor package structure having reduced thickness and a method of fabricating the same.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">While electronic products are becoming low-profiled and compact-sized, their package structures need to meet Joint Electronic Device Engineering Council (JEDEC) specifications. For example, although dynamic random access memory (DRAM) chips have been developed by a 40 nm (or less) process technology, the package structures of such chips need to be kept the same so as to have a ball pitch of 0.8 mm for PCB mounting. For such a package structure, a fan-out type wafer level packaging method can be used. In addition, DDR3 SDRAM (Double-Data-Rate Three Synchronous Dynamic Random Access Memory) is the latest computer memory specification, in which a window ball grid array (wBGA) packaging method can be used.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a cross-sectional view of a conventional wBGA semiconductor package structure. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the wBGA semiconductor package structure comprises a packaging substrate <b>10</b> and a semiconductor chip <b>11</b>. The packaging substrate <b>10</b> has at least a cavity <b>100</b> formed therethrough. The semiconductor chip <b>11</b> has an active surface <b>11</b><i>a </i>and an opposite inactive surface <b>11</b><i>b</i>, and a plurality of electrode pads <b>111</b> are disposed on the active surface <b>11</b><i>a</i>. The semiconductor chip <b>11</b> is disposed on a surface of the packaging substrate <b>10</b> through the active surface <b>11</b><i>a </i>thereof so as to cover one end of the cavity <b>100</b>. Then, through the use of wire bonding technology, a plurality of gold wires <b>12</b> are passed through the cavity <b>100</b> for electrically connecting the electrode pads <b>111</b> of the semiconductor chip <b>11</b> to conductive pads <b>13</b> formed on the other surface of the substrate <b>10</b>. Further, a first encapsulant material <b>14</b> is formed to encapsulate the gold wires <b>12</b>, and a second encapsulant material <b>15</b> is formed on the packaging substrate <b>10</b> to encapsulate the semiconductor chip <b>11</b>. Finally, a plurality of solder balls <b>16</b> are disposed on the exposed conductive pads <b>13</b> of the packaging substrate <b>10</b>. With this configuration, the overall height of the package structure (including the solder balls <b>16</b>) is 1.1-1.2 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">However, in the above-described semiconductor package structure, the gold wires <b>12</b> passing through the cavity <b>100</b> for electrically connecting the electrode pads <b>111</b> of the semiconductor chip <b>11</b> and the conductive pads <b>13</b> on the other surface of the substrate <b>10</b> are quite long, thereby adversely affecting the signal transmission efficiency. Further, the gold wires <b>12</b> lead to higher material costs as the price of gold on the international market has risen significantly recently. Furthermore, since the gold wires <b>12</b> and the semiconductor chip <b>11</b> are encapsulated by the first encapsulant material <b>14</b> and the second encapsulant material <b>15</b>, respectively, heat generated by the semiconductor chip <b>11</b> cannot be effectively dissipated. In addition, the package is not ideal for portable electronic products due to the relatively large thickness of the overall package structure.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Therefore, there is a need to provide a semiconductor package structure and a method of fabricating the same so as to overcome the above-described drawbacks.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In view of the above-described drawbacks, the present invention provides a semiconductor package structure having reduced thickness and increased reliability and a fabrication method thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In order to achieve the above and other objectives, the present invention provides a semiconductor package structure, which comprises: a semiconductor chip having an active surface and an opposite inactive surface, a plurality of electrode pads formed on the active surface, and a plurality of metal bumps disposed on the electrode pads, respectively; an encapsulant encapsulating the semiconductor chip, with the active surface of the semiconductor chip being exposed therefrom; a dielectric layer formed on the active surface of the semiconductor chip and the encapsulant and having a plurality of patterned intaglios formed therein for exposing the metal bumps; a wiring layer formed in the patterned intaglios of the dielectric layer and electrically connected to the metal bumps, wherein the wiring layer extends to an area greater than the active surface of the semiconductor chip by means of the presence of the encapsulant and the dielectric layer; an insulating protective layer formed on the dielectric layer and the wiring layer and having a plurality of openings for exposing portions of the wiring layer; and a metal foil having a plurality of metal posts disposed on a surface thereof, wherein the metal foil is disposed on the encapsulant with the metal posts penetrating the encapsulant so as to extend to the inactive surface of the semiconductor chip, thereby effectively dissipating heat generated by the semiconductor chip to the ambient.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The present invention further provides a method of fabricating a semiconductor package structure, comprising: providing a carrier board having a first adhesive layer formed on a surface thereof; providing a plurality of semiconductor chips, each of which has an active surface and an opposite inactive surface, a plurality of electrode pads formed on the active surface, and a plurality of metal bumps disposed on the electrode pads, respectively; adhering the semiconductor chips to the first adhesive layer through the active surfaces thereof; forming an encapsulant on the first adhesive layer to encapsulate the semiconductor chips; providing a metal foil having a plurality of metal posts disposed on a surface thereof, and attaching the metal foil to the encapsulant through the surface thereof such that the metal posts penetrate the encapsulant and extend to the inactive surfaces of the semiconductor chips; removing the carrier board and the first adhesive layer; forming a dielectric layer on the encapsulant and the semiconductor chips, wherein the dielectric layer has a plurality of patterned intaglios formed therein for exposing the metal bumps, respectively; forming a wiring layer in the patterned intaglios of the dielectric layer such that the wiring layer is electrically connected to the metal bumps; forming an insulating protective layer on the dielectric layer and the wiring layer, wherein the insulating protective layer has a plurality of openings for exposing portions of the wiring layer; removing portions of the metal foil such that the metal foil is separated corresponding to the semiconductor chips to form dicing lines; and cutting the encapsulant, the dielectric layer and the insulating protective layer along the dicing lines of the metal foil such that a plurality of semiconductor package structures are formed.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Since the present invention uses the dielectric layer as the base of the semiconductor package structure and eliminates the need to use gold wires for electrical transmission as in the prior art, the overall thickness of the semiconductor package structure is reduced. Further, the metal posts extending to the inactive surface of the semiconductor chip can directly transfer heat generated by the semiconductor chip to the metal foil having a large area, thereby facilitating heat dissipation of the overall semiconductor package. Furthermore, by dispensing with the conventional long gold wires for electrical signal transmission, the present invention increases the electrical transmission efficiency, improves the reliability of final products and reduces material costs.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a cross-sectional view of a conventional wBGA semiconductor package structure;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A to 2C</figref> are cross-sectional views illustrating a semiconductor chip of a semiconductor package structure and a method of fabricating the same according to the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A to 3D</figref> are cross-sectional views illustrating a metal foil of a semiconductor package structure and a method of fabricating the same according to the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A to 4K</figref> are cross-sectional views illustrating a semiconductor package structure and a method of fabricating the same according to the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The following illustrative embodiments are provided to illustrate the disclosure of the present invention, these and other advantages and effects will be apparent to those in the art after reading this specification.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Generally, the present invention is divided into three phases. Firstly, a plurality of semiconductor chips are prepared. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A to 2C</figref> show a semiconductor chip of a semiconductor package structure and a method of fabricating the same according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, a semiconductor wafer <b>20</b> having an active surface <b>20</b><i>a </i>and an opposite inactive surface <b>20</b><i>b </i>is provided, and a plurality of electrode pads <b>21</b> and a buffer layer <b>22</b> are formed on the active surface <b>20</b><i>a </i>of the semiconductor wafer <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>, a plurality of metal bumps <b>23</b> are disposed on the electrode pads <b>21</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2C</figref>, the semiconductor wafer <b>20</b> is thinned from the inactive surface <b>20</b> thereof and is singulated into a plurality of semiconductor chips <b>20</b>&#x2032;. Each of the semiconductor chips <b>20</b>&#x2032; has an active surface <b>20</b><i>a</i>&#x2032; and an opposite inactive surface <b>20</b><i>b</i>&#x2032;, a plurality of electrode pads <b>21</b> and a buffer layer <b>22</b> are formed on the active surface <b>20</b><i>a</i>&#x2032;, and a plurality of metal bumps <b>23</b> are disposed on the electrode pads <b>21</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Secondly, a metal foil is prepared. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A to 3D</figref> are cross-sectional views illustrating a metal foil of a semiconductor package structure and a method of fabricating the same according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, a metal board <b>30</b> made of, for example, copper is prepared.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, a resist layer <b>31</b> that has a plurality of patterned opening areas <b>310</b> is formed on the metal board <b>30</b>, allowing portions of the metal board <b>30</b> to be exposed from the patterned opening areas <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref>, the exposed portions of the metal board <b>30</b> in the patterned opening areas <b>310</b> are etched, thus forming a metal foil <b>30</b>&#x2032; and a plurality of metal posts <b>301</b> disposed thereon.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3D</figref>, the resist layer <b>31</b> is removed.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Finally, assembling and packaging processes are performed, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A to 4K</figref>, which are cross-sectional views of a semiconductor package structure and a method of fabricating the same according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref>, a carrier board <b>40</b> is provided, which has a second adhesive layer <b>411</b>, a plastic film <b>410</b> and a first adhesive layer <b>412</b> sequentially formed on a surface thereof. In an embodiment, the second adhesive layer <b>411</b>, the plastic film <b>410</b> and the first adhesive layer <b>412</b> may constitute a double-sided adhesive layer <b>41</b> first, and then the double-sided adhesive layer <b>41</b> is adhered to the carrier board <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</figref>, the plurality of semiconductor chips <b>20</b>&#x2032; are adhered to the first adhesive layer <b>412</b> through the active surfaces <b>20</b><i>a</i>&#x2032; thereof with the metal bumps <b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4C</figref>, an encapsulant <b>42</b> is formed on the first adhesive layer <b>412</b> to encapsulate the semiconductor chips <b>20</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4D</figref>, the metal foil <b>30</b>&#x2032; is attached to the encapsulant <b>42</b> through the surface thereof having the metal posts <b>301</b> such that the metal posts <b>301</b> penetrate the encapsulant <b>42</b> and are connected to the inactive surfaces <b>20</b><i>b</i>&#x2032; of the semiconductor chips <b>20</b>&#x2032; for dissipating heat generated by the semiconductor chips <b>20</b>&#x2032;. It should be noted that it is not necessary for the metal posts <b>301</b> to come into contact with the inactive surfaces <b>20</b><i>b</i>&#x2032; of the semiconductor chips <b>20</b>&#x2032;. For example, even if the metal posts <b>301</b> are 50-300 &#x3bc;m away from the inactive surface <b>20</b><i>b</i>&#x2032;, the metal posts <b>301</b> can still dissipate heat.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4E</figref>, the carrier board <b>40</b> and the double-sided adhesive layer <b>41</b> are removed.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4F</figref>, a dielectric layer <b>43</b> is formed on the encapsulant <b>42</b> and the semiconductor chips <b>20</b>&#x2032;, and has a plurality of patterned intaglios <b>430</b> formed therein for exposing the metal bumps <b>23</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4G</figref> a wiring layer <b>44</b> that is electrically connected to the metal bumps <b>23</b> is formed in the patterned intaglios <b>430</b> of the dielectric layer <b>43</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4H</figref>, an insulating protective layer <b>45</b> is formed on the dielectric layer <b>43</b> and the wiring layer <b>44</b> and has a plurality of openings <b>450</b> for exposing portions of the wiring layer <b>44</b>. Further, a cap layer <b>47</b> is formed on the metal foil <b>30</b>&#x2032; and is separated corresponding to the semiconductor chips <b>20</b>&#x2032; to form dicing lines <b>470</b> for exposing portions of the metal foil <b>30</b>&#x2032;. The cap layer <b>47</b> can be made of an insulating material or a metallic material.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4I</figref>, the portions of the metal foil <b>30</b>&#x2032; exposed from the dicing lines <b>470</b> of the cap layer <b>47</b> are removed to form dicing lines <b>300</b>&#x2032; such that the metal foils <b>30</b>&#x2032; is separated corresponding to the semiconductor chips <b>20</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4J</figref>, a plurality of solder balls <b>46</b> are disposed on the portions of the wiring layer <b>44</b> exposed from the openings <b>450</b> of the insulating protective layer <b>45</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4K</figref>, the encapsulant <b>42</b>, the dielectric layer <b>43</b> and the insulating protective layer <b>45</b> are cut along the dicing lines <b>300</b>&#x2032; of the metal foil <b>30</b>&#x2032; such that a plurality of semiconductor package structures <b>4</b> are formed.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The present invention further discloses a semiconductor package structure, which has: a semiconductor chip <b>20</b>&#x2032; having an active surface <b>20</b><i>a</i>&#x2032; and an opposite inactive surface <b>20</b><i>b</i>&#x2032;, a plurality of electrode pads <b>21</b> formed on the active surface <b>20</b><i>a</i>&#x2032;, and a plurality of metal bumps <b>23</b> disposed on the electrode pads <b>21</b>, respectively; an encapsulant <b>42</b> encapsulating the semiconductor chip <b>20</b>&#x2032;, with the active surface <b>20</b><i>a</i>&#x2032; of the semiconductor chip <b>20</b>&#x2032; exposed therefrom; a dielectric layer <b>43</b> formed on the active surface <b>20</b><i>a</i>&#x2032; of the semiconductor chip <b>20</b>&#x2032; and the encapsulant <b>42</b> and having a plurality of patterned intaglios <b>430</b> formed therein for exposing the metal bumps <b>23</b>; a wiring layer <b>44</b> formed in the patterned intaglios <b>430</b> of the dielectric layer <b>43</b> and electrically connected to the metal bumps <b>23</b>, wherein the wiring layer <b>44</b> extends to an area greater than the active surface <b>20</b><i>a</i>&#x2032; of the semiconductor chip <b>20</b>&#x2032; by means of the presence of the encapsulant <b>42</b> and the dielectric layer <b>43</b>; an insulating protective layer <b>45</b> formed on the dielectric layer <b>43</b> and the wiring layer <b>44</b> and having a plurality of openings <b>450</b> for exposing portions of the wiring layer <b>44</b>; and a metal foil <b>30</b>&#x2032; having a plurality of metal posts <b>301</b> disposed on a surface thereof, wherein the metal foil <b>30</b>&#x2032; is disposed on the encapsulant <b>42</b> with the metal posts <b>301</b> penetrating the encapsulant <b>42</b> such that the metal posts <b>301</b> extend to the inactive surface <b>20</b><i>b</i>&#x2032; of the semiconductor chip <b>20</b>&#x2032;, thereby effectively dissipating heat generated by the semiconductor chip <b>20</b>&#x2032; to the ambient.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The above-described semiconductor package structure can further have a cap layer <b>47</b> formed on a top surface of the metal foil <b>30</b>&#x2032;. The cap layer <b>47</b> can be made of an insulating material or a metallic material.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The semiconductor package structure can further have a plurality of solder balls <b>46</b> disposed on the portions of the wiring layer <b>44</b> exposed from the openings <b>450</b> of the insulating protective layer <b>45</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The semiconductor package structure can further have a buffer layer <b>22</b> formed on the active surface <b>20</b><i>a</i>&#x2032; of the semiconductor chip <b>20</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Since the present invention uses the dielectric layer as the base of the semiconductor package structure and eliminates the need to use gold wires for electrical transmission as in the prior art, the overall thickness of the semiconductor package structure is reduced. Further, the metal posts extending to the inactive surface of the semiconductor chip can directly transfer heat generated by the semiconductor chip to the metal foil having a large area, thereby facilitating heat dissipation of the overall semiconductor package. Furthermore, by dispensing with the conventional long gold wires for electrical signal transmission, the present invention increases the electrical transmission efficiency, improves the reliability of final products and reduces material costs.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The above-described descriptions of the detailed embodiments are provided to illustrate the preferred implementation according to the present invention, and are not intended to limit the scope of the present invention. Accordingly, many modifications and variations completed by those with ordinary skill in the art will fall within the scope of present invention as defined by the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A semiconductor package structure, comprising:
<claim-text>a semiconductor chip having an active surface and an opposite inactive surface, a plurality of electrode pads formed on the active surface, and a plurality of metal bumps disposed on the electrode pads, respectively;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an encapsulant encapsulating the semiconductor chip, with the active surface of the semiconductor chip being exposed therefrom;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a dielectric layer formed on the active surface of the semiconductor chip and the encapsulant and having a plurality of patterned intaglios for exposing the metal bumps;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a wiring layer formed in the patterned intaglios of the dielectric layer and electrically connected to the metal bumps, wherein the wiring layer extends to an area greater than the active surface of the semiconductor chip by means of the presence of the encapsulant and the dielectric layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an insulating protective layer formed on the dielectric layer and the wiring layer and having a plurality of openings for exposing portions of the wiring layer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a metal foil having a plurality of metal posts disposed on a surface thereof, wherein the metal foil is disposed on the encapsulant with the metal posts penetrating the encapsulant so as to extend to the inactive surface of the semiconductor chip, thereby effectively dissipating heat generated by the semiconductor chip to the ambient.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The structure of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a cap layer formed on a top surface of the metal foil.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The structure of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the cap layer is made of an insulating material or a metallic material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The structure of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a plurality of solder balls disposed on the portions of the wiring layer exposed from the openings of the insulating protective layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The structure of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a buffer layer formed on the active surface of the semiconductor chip.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
