<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625355-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625355</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13316608</doc-number>
<date>20111212</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-283607</doc-number>
<date>20101220</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>115</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>11</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>16</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36518522</main-classification>
<further-classification>36518525</further-classification>
<further-classification>365200</further-classification>
<further-classification>365201</further-classification>
<further-classification>365203</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Semiconductor memory device and method of operating the same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7738296</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Lin</name>
<date>20100600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36518511</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8365030</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Choi et al.</name>
<date>20130100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>714746</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0286308</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Nagashima</name>
<date>20051200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36518522</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0003058</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kang</name>
<date>20090100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36518503</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-027141</doc-number>
<date>20100200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36518522</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36518525</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>365200</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>365201</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>365203</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>13</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>13</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120155186</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120621</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chokan</last-name>
<first-name>Tomohito</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yokohama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sudou</last-name>
<first-name>Naoaki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yokohama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chokan</last-name>
<first-name>Tomohito</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yokohama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sudou</last-name>
<first-name>Naoaki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yokohama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Volentine &#x26; Whitt, PLLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si, Gyeonggi-do</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Yoha</last-name>
<first-name>Connie</first-name>
<department>2827</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A semiconductor memory device operate during a program verification operation to apply a read voltage to a word line and a pre-charge voltage to a bit line in order to provide output data. A number of fail cells is determined in view of the output data, wherein the number of fail cells is directly related to an increase in voltage on a common source line (CSL) connected to memory cells providing the output data. During a subsequent program verification operation, the level of at least one of the read voltage and the pre-charge voltage is adjusted in response to the number of fail cells.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="167.22mm" wi="268.39mm" file="US08625355-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="286.09mm" wi="194.82mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625355-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="254.08mm" wi="165.52mm" file="US08625355-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="275.25mm" wi="188.72mm" file="US08625355-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="286.77mm" wi="194.82mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625355-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="285.41mm" wi="189.40mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625355-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="180.51mm" wi="192.79mm" file="US08625355-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="273.81mm" wi="197.53mm" file="US08625355-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="136.23mm" wi="177.12mm" file="US08625355-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="178.48mm" wi="179.15mm" file="US08625355-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="234.36mm" wi="160.10mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625355-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="203.03mm" wi="177.12mm" file="US08625355-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="194.14mm" wi="168.91mm" file="US08625355-20140107-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="193.46mm" wi="176.45mm" file="US08625355-20140107-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This U.S. non-provisional patent application claims priority under 35 U.S.C. &#xa7;119 to Japanese Patent Application No. 2010-0283607 filed on Dec. 20, 2010, the subject matter of which is hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present inventive concept relates to semiconductor memory devices and methods of operating the same.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Nonvolatile memory devices have the capability of retaining stored data in the absence of applied power. There are different types of nonvolatile memory devices. However, so-called flash memory, including several types of electrically erasable nonvolatile memory, has become an important component of many contemporary digital data and consumer electronics devices. NAND type flash memory is configured using a plurality of memory strings, wherein each memory string includes a plurality of series-connected memory cells arranged between intersecting bit lines and word lines.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Figure (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a partial schematic view of a typical NAND flash memory. The memory cell array shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> includes N+1 bit lines (BL<b>0</b>-BLN), n+1 word lines (WL<b>0</b>-WLn), and N+1 memory strings (ST<b>0</b>-STN) connected between a common source line CSL and a corresponding bit line BL. Each memory string ST includes n+1 series-connected nonvolatile memory cells (MC<b>0</b>-MCn). Each nonvolatile memory cell MC is assumed to have a floating gate structure that may be electrically rewritten to a desired data state.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Within this configuration, the drain of each memory cell MCn is connected to a corresponding bit line BL<b>0</b> through a string select transistor SS<b>1</b>. The source of memory cell MC<b>0</b> is connected to a common source line CSL through a ground select transistor GS<b>1</b>. Control gates of the memory cells MC in a particular row are commonly connected to a word line WL.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In the memory cell array of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, an erase operation is performed by applying a high voltage (e.g., 20V) to a constituent semiconductor substrate while applying 0V to the word lines WL<b>0</b>-WLn. Under these voltage conditions, electrons are removed from a floating gate (i.e., an electrical charge accumulation layer) typically formed of polysilicon. In this manner, the threshold voltage of memory cell MC may be set to an erase threshold voltage VthL (e.g., &#x2212;1V).</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">During a write (or programming) operation, electrons are injected onto the floating gate from the semiconductor substrate by applying 0V to the semiconductor substrate while a high voltage (e.g., 20V) is applied to the control gate (selected word line WL). In this manner, the threshold voltage of memory cell MC may be increased from the erase threshold voltage VthL.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Certain data values are ascribed to respective programmed threshold voltage states. In a binary memory cell MC, a data value of &#x201c;1&#x201d; may be ascribed to the erase threshold voltage VthL, and a data value of &#x201c;0&#x201d; may be ascribed to a higher (programmed) threshold voltage VthH (e.g., 3V).</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">During a read operation directed to a particular memory cell, after pre-charging all of the bit lines (BL<b>0</b>-BLN) to a predetermined voltage, a read voltage (e.g., 2V) between the higher threshold voltage VthH and the erase threshold voltage VthL is applied to a control gate of selected memory cell through the word line connected to a memory cell MC. A voltage higher than the read voltage is applied to control gates of memory cells MC except the selected memory cell, the string select transistor SS<b>1</b> and the ground select transistor GS<b>1</b>. The memory cells MC except the selected memory cell, the string select transistor SS<b>1</b> and the ground select transistor GS<b>1</b> are turned ON.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">When a data value for the selected memory cell is &#x201c;1&#x201d;, a cell current flows through the corresponding memory cell. When a data value for the selected memory cell is &#x201c;0&#x201d;, the cell current does not flow. Thus, the written data value for a selected memory cell may be read on the basis of whether or not the cell current flows in response to the read operation voltage conditions.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">During a read operation in the memory cell array of NAND flash memory shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the voltage of the common source line CSL increases according to the amount of current flowing from each memory string to the common source line CSL. As a result, the threshold voltage of the selected memory cell may unintentionally change. That is, a voltage increase on the common source line CSL may drive the voltage of the common source line CSL above ground voltage due to the voltage drop caused by current flowing to the common source line CSL and a parasitic resistance inherent in the common source line CSL.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">For example, in the memory cell array of the NAND type memory cell shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, it is assumed that a data value of &#x201c;0&#x201d; has been written to selected memory cells MCa, MCb and MCc. Then, a verify read operation is performed on the selected memory cells MCa, MCb and MCc. It is further assumed that each of the memory cells MCa, MCb and MCc is insufficiently written, a threshold voltage Vtha of the memory cell MCa is equal to a threshold voltage Vthb of the memory cell MCb and a threshold voltage Vthc of the memory cell MCc is greater than the threshold voltage Vtha and the threshold voltage Vthb (i.e., Vtha=Vthb&#x3c;Vthc). Finally, it is assumed that each of the threshold voltages Vtha, Vthb and Vthc is less than a verifying read voltage Vvfy which will be described later (i.e., Vtha, Vthb, Vthc&#x3c;Vvfy).</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Under these assumptions, the verifying read voltage Vvfy is applied to a word line WL commonly connected to control gates of the memory cells MCa, MCb and MCc. A read voltage Vread is applied to other word lines WL. Memory cells connected to the word line WL to which the read voltage Vread is applied enter a pass state (i.e., a state wherein current may flow). The string select transistor SS<b>1</b> and the ground select transistor GS<b>1</b> are turned ON.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The verifying read voltage Vvfy is applied to the control gates of the memory cells MCa, MCb and MCc. Since the verifying read voltage Vvfy is greater than the threshold voltages Vtha, Vthb and Vthc, the memory cells MCa, MCb and MCc will be turned ON.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">However, when the verifying read voltage Vvfy is applied, the memory cells MCa and MCB having the threshold voltages Vtha and Vthb less than the threshold voltage Vthc of the memory cell MCc are turned ON first. A cell current Ia and a cell current Ib flow in the common source line CSL through the memory cells MCa and MCb. At this time, a voltage increase (referred to as &#x201c;CLS noise&#x201d;) on the common source line CSL having a parasitic resistance occurs.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">A voltage VGS between a gate and a source of the memory cell MCc and a voltage VDS between a drain and a source of the memory cell MCc are reduced (i.e., the threshold voltage Vthc becomes relatively high) and thereby a current does not flow through the memory cell MCc. As a result, it becomes difficult if not impossible to correctly determine whether the memory cell MCc is an OFF-cell, despite its (intended) programmed data state of &#x201c;0&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, inclusive of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8A</figref>, <b>8</b>B, and <b>8</b>C, further illustrates the effect that the voltage increase (i.e., the CSL noise) on the common source line CSL has on the voltage VGS between the gate and source and the voltage VDS between a drain and a source. In a memory cell MC illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</figref>, when CSL noise does not exist in the common source line CSL. Then, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8B</figref>, a pre-charge voltage of 0.6V is applied to the drain of the memory cell MC through a bit line BL. A voltage of 1.0V is applied to the gate of the memory cell MC through a word line WL. A voltage of 0V is applied to the source via the common source line CSL. Under these assumed conditions, a voltage between the drain and source of the memory cell MC is 0.6V (i.e., VDS=0.6V).</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">When CSL noise of 0.3V occurs in the common source line CSL, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8C</figref>, the source voltage of the memory cell MC increases by 0.3V. Thus, the voltage VGS between the gate and source of the memory cell MC becomes 0.7V. A voltage VDS between the drain and source of the memory cell MC becomes 0.3V. When CSL noise occurs in the common source line CSL, the voltage VGS and the voltage VDS are reduced and thereby the current flowing through the memory cell MC is reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a graph further illustrating the change in drain current relative to the voltage VDS between the drain and source of the memory cell described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>. A characteristic curve A represents a case of when CSL noise does not exist and a characteristic curve B represents a case of when CSL noise exists. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, even though applying a same word line voltage, the voltage VGS between the gate and source of memory cell is reduced due to the CSL noise and thereby a characteristic curve of drain current varies from a characteristic curve A to a characteristic curve B. Thus, a cell current reduced from a drain current of when the CSL noise does not exists (i.e., a drain current corresponding to a point a<b>1</b> on the characteristic curve A) to a drain current of when the CSL noise exists (i.e., a drain current corresponding to a point b<b>1</b> on the characteristic curve B).</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Even though a similar word line voltage is applied to a memory cell, if the value of the resulting drain current is slightly lower reduced from the current corresponding to the point al on the characteristic curve A, the programmed state of the memory cell may be misjudged depending upon whether the CSL noise exists or not. That is, a read operation directed to such a memory cell may fail due to the presence of CSL noise.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">As described above, when CSL noise exists, the threshold voltage of a read cell is increased, the degree of accuracy for the read operation and write operation may be deteriorated. According to a conventional response, after pre-charging a plurality of bit lines BL before performing a read operation, a dummy read voltage lower than a predetermined read voltage is applied to the plurality of selected memory cells connected to a selected word line. At this time, current flows through a plurality of memory cells connected to an unselected word line. Charge on the bit line BL connected to a selected memory cell having a threshold voltage sufficiently less than a read voltage are discharged through the selected memory cell and the common source line CSL. Thus, the CSL noise is reduced and thereby unintended variations in threshold voltage may be prevented. That is, according to the conventional remedy to the foregoing problem, read operation accuracy may be improved by performing the read operation only after reducing (or eliminating) an accompanying increase in electric potential from the common source line CSL when the CSL noise exists.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In one embodiments, the inventive concept provides a semiconductor memory device comprising; a memory cell array including a plurality of memory strings, each memory string including memory cells series-connected between a string select transistor and a ground select transistor, wherein the round select transistor is connected to a common source line (CSL), a plurality of word lines including a selected word line, wherein the selected word line is commonly connected to gates of a row of memory cells extending across the plurality of memory strings, a plurality of bit lines including a selected bit line, wherein each one of the plurality of bit lines is connected to a corresponding one of the plurality of memory strings, a page buffer that provides output data from selected memory cells associated with at least one of the selected word line and the selected bit line during a verify read operation, a fail bit counter that determines a number of fail cells among the selected memory cells, a voltage controller that generates a read voltage applied to the selected word line during the verify read operation and a pre-charge voltage applied to selected bit line during the read verify operation, and a control circuit that controls the voltage controller in response to the number of fail cells.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In another embodiment, the inventive concept provides a method of operating a semiconductor memory device comprises; during a program verification operation, applying a read voltage to a selected word line and applying a pre-charge voltage to a selected bit line, and providing output data in response to the read voltage and pre-charge voltage, determining a number of fail cells in view of the output data, wherein the number of fail cells is directly related to an increase in voltage on a common source line (CSL) connected to memory cells providing the output data, and during a subsequent program verification operation, adjusting at least one of the read voltage and the pre-charge voltage in response to the number of fail cells.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In another embodiment, the inventive concept provides a system comprising; a controller that controls the operation of a semiconductor memory device. The semiconductor memory device comprises; a memory cell array including a plurality of memory strings, each memory string including memory cells series-connected between a string select transistor and a ground select transistor, wherein the round select transistor is connected to a common source line (CSL), a plurality of word lines including a selected word line, wherein the selected word line is commonly connected to gates of a row of memory cells extending across the plurality of memory strings, a plurality of bit lines including a selected bit line, wherein each one of the plurality of bit lines is connected to a corresponding one of the plurality of memory strings, a page buffer that provides output data from selected memory cells associated with at least one of the selected word line and the selected bit line during a verify read operation, a fail bit counter that determines a number of fail cells among the selected memory cells, a voltage controller that generates a read voltage applied to the selected word line during the verify read operation and a pre-charge voltage applied to selected bit line during the read verify operation, and a control circuit that controls the voltage controller in response to the number of fail cells.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Preferred embodiments of the inventive concept will be described below in more detail with reference to the accompanying drawings. The embodiments of the inventive concept may, however, be embodied in different forms and should not be constructed as limited to the embodiments set forth herein. Rather, these embodiments are provided so that this disclosure will be thorough and complete, and will fully convey the scope of the inventive concept to those skilled in the art. Like numbers refer to like elements throughout.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram illustrating a semiconductor memory device in accordance with an embodiment of the inventive concept.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a graph showing a relationship between the number of ON-cells and a common source line voltage when performing a program verification.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a flow chart summarizing a correction method for a word line voltage and a bit line pre-charge voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a block diagram illustrating another semiconductor memory device in accordance with an embodiment of the inventive concept.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a block diagram illustrating yet another semiconductor memory device in accordance with an embodiment of the inventive concept.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a graph describing a correction voltage approach using a correction voltage table.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a drawing illustrating a memory cell array comprised of NAND type flash memories.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a drawing illustrating an effect of a CSL noise on a voltage VGS between a gate and a source and a voltage VDS between a drain and a source.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a graph showing a change of drain current by a CSL noise.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a drawing illustrating an example of applying a flash memory system in accordance with some embodiments of the inventive concept to a memory card.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a drawing illustrating an example of applying a voltage correction operation in accordance with some embodiments of the inventive concept to solid state drive (SSD).</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a block diagram illustrating a constitution of the SSD controller illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an example of embodying a voltage correction operation in accordance with some embodiments of the inventive concept in a flash memory module.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Embodiments of inventive concepts will be described more fully hereinafter with reference to the accompanying drawings. This inventive concept may, however, be embodied in many different forms and should not be construed as being limited to only the illustrated embodiments. Rather, these embodiments are provided so that this disclosure will be thorough and complete, and will fully convey the scope of the inventive concept to those skilled in the art. Throughout the written description and drawings, like reference numbers and labels refer to like or similar elements.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">During a write (or program) operation directed to a selected memory cell in a NAND type flash memory device, data is programmed using an incrementally increasing program voltage over a sequence of programming loops, a program verification operation (a &#x201c;verify read operation&#x201d;) associated with each loop is typically required to carefully control the resulting threshold voltage distribution of the selected memory cell. When performing the verify read operation, current flows through the memory string including the selected memory cell to a connected common source line CSL, and accordingly, common source line noise (CSL noise) may occur. As noted above, the threshold voltage of the memory cell is relatively increased due to the CSL noise, so that the accuracy of the verify read operation is deteriorated. To address this deterioration in accuracy of a &#x201c;current&#x201d; verify read operation in a semiconductor memory device of the inventive concept, a number of &#x201c;fail cells&#x201d; and &#x201c;inhibit cells&#x201d; is counted. Then, during a &#x201c;next&#x201d; verify read operation in the ongoing sequence of verify read operations performed during a programing verification operation, a voltage applied to a word line and a pre-charge voltage applied to a bit line may be corrected according to the number of fail cells and inhibit cells.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">As is conventionally appreciated, an inhibit cell is a memory cell other than the selected memory cell in the memory string that is not intended to be programmed (i.e., a cell that should maintain its current erase or programmed state). As a result, during a verify read operation, an inhibit cell will pass more current than a properly programmed memory cell.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The term fail cell is used to denote a memory cell that was intended to be programmed during a write operation, but as yet fails to exhibit the intended programming state. As a result, during the verify read operation a fail cell will also pass more current than a properly (non-fail) memory cell.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Hence, semiconductor memory devices in accordance with certain embodiments of the inventive concept count the number of fail cells and inhibit cells during a program verification operation. One or more &#x201c;correction voltage(s)&#x201d; may then applied to the word line and/or bit line in accordance with the number of fail cells and inhibited cells. As a result and contrary to the conventional remedy described above, it is not necessary to provide a dummy read period. This allows semiconductor memory devices according to the inventive concept to run at relatively higher speeds with improved data read/write accuracy.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram of a semiconductor memory device in accordance with an embodiment of the inventive concept.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The semiconductor memory device <b>1</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is assumed to be a NAND type flash memory. The semiconductor memory device <b>1</b> generally comprises in relevant portion a memory cell array <b>10</b>, a control circuit <b>11</b>, a row (X) decoder <b>12</b>, a page buffer (PB) controller <b>13</b>, a page buffer (PB) <b>14</b>, a fail bit counter <b>21</b>, a high voltage controller <b>22</b>, an input/output (I/O) buffer <b>24</b> and an input/output (I/O) pad <b>25</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The control circuit <b>11</b> controls the respective and interrelated operations of the row (X) decoder <b>12</b>, the page buffer (PB) controller <b>13</b>, the page buffer (PB) <b>14</b>, the fail bit counter <b>21</b> and the high voltage controller <b>22</b>. The control circuit <b>11</b> controls the overall operation of the semiconductor memory device <b>1</b> during read, write (program) and erase operations. The controller circuit <b>11</b> receives an address signal or a control command signal from the input/output buffer <b>24</b>. The control circuit <b>11</b> receives information indicating the number of fail cells and/or the number of inhibit cells from the fail bit counter <b>21</b>. A BL correction value for the pre-charge voltage subsequently applied to a bit line BL or a WL correction value for the voltage applied to a word line WL may then be defined by the control circuit on the basis of this information.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The row decoder <b>12</b> receives an address signal from the input/output buffer <b>24</b> through the control circuit <b>11</b>. The row decoder <b>12</b> decodes the received address signal to select a word line connected to a memory cell in which read, write and erase operations of data will be performed. The row decoder <b>12</b> receives a voltage signal VSEL from the high voltage controller <b>22</b> to apply a voltage corresponding to read, write and erase operations of data to a word line WL.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The page buffer controller <b>13</b> controls an operation of the page buffer <b>14</b>. The page buffer controller <b>13</b> receives a voltage signal VBSLT of bit line BL corresponding to read, write and erase operations of data to output the voltage signal VBSLT to the page buffer <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">A plurality of memory cell blocks of page unit (e.g., 8 bit unit) is disposed in parallel to constitute the memory cell array <b>10</b>. For example, 32768 bit lines (BL<b>0</b>-BL<b>327670</b> may be disposed in the memory cell array <b>10</b>. The memory cell block of page unit may therefore assume n+1 bit lines, where n=7 like the exemplary NAND type flash memory already described in relation to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>. That is, the memory cell block of page unit may include, as one working example, 8 memory strings ST<b>0</b>-ST<b>7</b> respectively associated with 8 bit lines BL<b>0</b>-BL<b>7</b> and word lines WL<b>0</b>-WLn, as well as a common source line CSL.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Each of the memory strings ST<b>0</b>-ST<b>7</b> includes a number of series-connected nonvolatile memory cells MC<b>0</b>-MCn having a floating gate structure. The drain of memory cell MCn is connected to a corresponding bit line BL through a first string select transistor SS<b>1</b>. The source of memory cell MC<b>0</b> is connected to the common source line CSL through a ground select transistor GS<b>1</b>. The common source line CSL is connected to ground through a transistor NT. The transistor NT is turned ON/OFF in accordance with a control signal CR applied to its gate. The transistor NT is turned ON during a verify read operation.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In the memory cell array <b>10</b>, a bit line BL corresponding to each memory string ST is connected to the page buffer <b>14</b> to perform read and write operations on a page unit basis. The page buffer <b>14</b> is comprised of a page buffer block (PBX<b>8</b>) <b>14</b>A and a page buffer converter <b>14</b>B that are disposed in parallel.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The page buffer block <b>14</b>A includes a pre-charge circuit receiving a control command and a signal of pre-charge voltage from the page buffer controller <b>13</b> to apply a pre-charge voltage to a bit line BL. The page buffer block <b>14</b>A includes a sense amplifier circuit to read out data written in a memory cell MC. The page buffer block <b>14</b>A outputs data read from a memory cell MC to the input/output buffer <b>24</b> through the buffer converter <b>14</b>B and an output data bus DOUTBUS[<b>63</b>:<b>0</b>]. The page buffer block <b>14</b>A performs an operation of writing data in a memory cell MC from the page buffer converter <b>14</b>B. Read, write and erase operations are performed using the page buffer block <b>14</b>A, the page buffer converter <b>14</b>B, the row decoder <b>12</b>, the page buffer controller <b>13</b> and the high voltage controller <b>22</b> as controlled by the control circuit <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The page buffer converter <b>14</b>B receives an address signal and a write data signal from the input/output buffer <b>24</b> through an input data bus DINBUS[<b>63</b>:<b>0</b>]. The page buffer converter <b>14</b>B performs the function of a column decoder selecting a designated page buffer block <b>14</b>A by page unit on the basis of the received address signal. The page buffer converter <b>14</b>B outputs the write data signal received from the input/output buffer <b>24</b> to the page buffer block <b>14</b>A. The page buffer converter <b>14</b>B outputs data of memory cell MC read by the page buffer block <b>14</b>A to the input/output buffer <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The fail bit counter <b>21</b> counts a number of fail bits respectively indicating a fail cell as the result of a current (i.e., an ongoing) verify read operation. For example, the fail bit counter <b>21</b> may count the number of cells becoming an ON cell among the inhibit cells. In turn, the number of inhibit cells may be set in accordance with address data during the write (program) operation. Information regarding the number of inhibit cells may be stored in the control circuit <b>1</b> lusing a register or scratch pad memory.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Under these conditions, the fail bit counter <b>21</b> may count the number of inhibit cells becoming an ON-cell on the basis of the information numbering the inhibit cells. That is, the fail bit counter <b>21</b> may be used to determine a number of inhibit cells becoming an ON-cell and provide this number to the control circuit <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The high voltage controller <b>22</b> may be used to generate voltage(s) used during the read, write and erase operations. For example, the high voltage controller <b>22</b> may be used to generate one or more boosted voltage(s) greater than an externally provided power supply voltage. Such voltages, as provide by the high voltage controller <b>22</b>, may be provided to the row decoder <b>12</b> as a selection signal VSEL and to the buffer controller <b>13</b> as a bias signal VBLSLT. The operation of the high voltage controller <b>22</b> may be controlled by the control circuit <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The input/output buffer <b>24</b> is a buffer circuit used when inputting data, an address signal and a control command and outputting data. The input/output buffer <b>24</b> is connected to the input/output (I/O) pad <b>25</b> that is connection terminal to an external circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">As described above, the semiconductor memory device <b>1</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> according to an embodiment of the inventive concept provides the capability of correcting (or adjusting) the level of a pre-charge voltage applied to a bit line BL and a WL voltage applied to a word line WL in response to detected CSL noise. This provision will be generally referred to as a &#x201c;correction operation&#x201d; and will be described in some additional detail hereafter.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">A program verification operation may be performed in the semiconductor memory device <b>1</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> as part of a write (or program) operation. It is common to use an iterative sequence of loops to program data to the semiconductor memory device, wherein each successive programming lop uses an incrementally increased programming voltage. A subsequent verification of programmed bit(s) during each loop is required to control the distribution of the memory cell threshold voltage. Within the context of the inventive concept, when performing a program verification, the WL voltage applied to a word line WL and pre-charge voltage applied to a bit line BL may be corrected using an approach like the one described below.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">During a (first) or current program verification operation, the fail counter <b>21</b> counts a number of inhibit cells becoming, respectively, an ON-cell as the result of the data being written to the memory cell array <b>10</b>. The fail counter <b>21</b> outputs this &#x201c;fail-bit information&#x201d; to the control circuit <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The control circuit <b>11</b> already knows the number of inhibit cells from the data being written to the memory cell array <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Then , during a (second) or next program verification operation, the control circuit <b>11</b> may control the operation of the high voltage controller <b>22</b> in accordance with the fail bit information and the number of inhibit cells obtained during the first program verification operation. The WL voltage applied to a word line WL may be corrected and applied through the row decoder <b>12</b>. The pre-charge voltage applied to a bit line BL may be corrected and applied through the page buffer controller <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Then, during a (third) next subsequent program verification operation, the control circuit <b>11</b> may be similarly used to correct the WL voltage and pre-charge voltage based on an updated number of fail cells obtained during the second program verification operation.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">An incremental level (&#x394;V) for a correction voltage calculated during the first and second program verification operations may be expressed as: (&#x394;V=&#x394;VCSL&#xd7;the number of all ON-cells), wherein the number of all the ON-cells is equal to (the number of fail bits+the number of inhibit cells).</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The &#x394;VCSL is a corresponding voltage increase per ON-cell occurring in a common source line CSL. That is, the increased voltage &#x394;V with respect to the common source line CSL becomes a correction level for a pre-charge voltage applied to the bit line BL and a read voltage applied to the word line WL.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">Although the voltage on the common source line CSL is increased by the CSL noise, the control circuit <b>11</b> may correct the read voltage applied to the word line WL and the pre-charge voltage applied to the bit line BL with respect to this increased voltage. That is, a gate-source voltage VGS and a drain-source voltage VDS may be corrected according to the voltage increase caused by the CSL noise. Thus, the conventional relative migration in the threshold voltage of memory cell MC may be prevented. As a result, during a program verification operation, a distribution due to the difference between a threshold voltage Vth of memory cell MC passed during a first verification operation and a threshold voltage Vth of memory cell MC passed during a last verification operation may be reduced and thereby the degree of accuracy associated with the write operation may be improved.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, including <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</figref>, further illustrates a relationship between a number of ON-cells and a common source line voltage with respect to a number of verification operations assuming the use of an incremental step pulse-program (ISPP) method. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the horizontal axis represents the number of verification operations and the vertical axis represents the number of ON-cells and a common source line voltage (a source voltage VCSL of memory cell).</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">As is conventionally understood, the ISPP is a method for performing a write operation using a stepped voltage applied to the gate of a selected memory cell. The ISPP is a method of writing data in the selected memory cell using a repeated loop approach that includes: applying a write voltage to the gate of the selected memory cell; performing a verification operation; increasing the write voltage; and then applying the increased write voltage to the gate of the selected memory cell until it has been properly programmed.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">Writing data in a memory cell means that a high voltage (e.g., 20V) is applied to a control gate (selected word line WL) to inject electrons into a floating gate and thereby a threshold voltage is increased.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, the number (n<b>1</b>) of ON-cells is the sum of the number of fail cells (cells maintaining an &#x201c;ON&#x201d; state) when the first program verification operation is performed and the number of inhibit cells. The number (n<b>2</b>) of ON-cells represents the number of inhibit cells when a program verification operation is finished. A voltage VCSL<b>1</b> represents an increase in voltage of the common source line CSL generated by currents flowing through fail cells and inhibit cells when the first program verification operation is performed. A voltage VCSL<b>2</b> represents a voltage of the common source line CSL generated by currents flowing through inhibit cells when a program verification operation is finished.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, when the first pass is performed, there are too many fail cells. Thus, the sum of fail bits and inhibit cells becomes n<b>1</b>. A voltage of the common source line CSL increases to VCSL<b>1</b> by currents flowing from a bit line BL to the common source line CSL through the fail cells and the inhibit cells. Here, the voltage VCSL<b>1</b> becomes a correction level &#x394;V, when a next program verification operation is performed, a voltage applied to a word line WL and a pre-charge voltage applied to a bit line BL are corrected based on the correction level &#x394;V.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>, assume that a source voltage 0.0V, a gate voltage 1.0V and a drain voltage 0.6V are applied to respective terminals of memory cell MC. If a common source line voltage VCSL is increased by 0.3V by a CSL noise, then 0.3V becomes an appropriate correction level &#x394;V.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">A read voltage applied to a word line WL and a pre-charge voltage applied to a bit line BL are corrected based on the correction level &#x394;V. As a result, the source voltage becomes 0.3V, the gate voltage becomes 1.3V and the drain voltage becomes 0.9V. That is, when a next verify read operation is performed, the correction level &#x394;V is added to the various bias voltages applied to the gate voltage and drain voltage is applied to a word line WL and a bit line.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, as the number of program verification operations increases, the number of memory cells becoming fail bit (fail cells) decreases. Thus, the common source line voltage VCSL may be gradually reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">When a program verification operation is finished, that is, when all bits are passed, the common source line voltage VCSL becomes VCSL<b>2</b> by currents flowing through inhibit cells and thereby a correction level &#x394;V becomes VCSL<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a flow chart summarizing a method of correcting a read word line voltage and a bit line pre-charge voltage used during a program verification operation according to an embodiment of the inventive concept. The program verification operation may be controlled by the control circuit <b>11</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">When starting a program verification operation, the control circuit <b>11</b> counts the number of inhibit cells becoming an ON-cell by the fail bit counter <b>21</b> (S<b>1</b>). The number of inhibit cells may be calculated in advance on the basis of information about inhibit cells kept in the control circuit <b>11</b>. The control circuit <b>11</b> calculates a correction level &#x394;V from the number of inhibit cells. A correction voltage that the correction level &#x394;V is added to a verifying read voltage applied to a bit line BL and a word line WL is calculated (S<b>2</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">The control circuit <b>11</b> controls the high voltage controller <b>22</b>, a row decoder <b>12</b> and the page buffer controller <b>13</b>. Data is written in a memory cell MC by applying a voltage to a word line WL and a bit line BL (S<b>3</b>). Here, a write operation is performed to condition a threshold voltage of the selected memory cell MC.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">After writing data in a memory cell MC, the page buffer <b>14</b> reads data from the selected memory cell MC. The fail bit counter <b>21</b> compares and verifies data read from the selected memory cell MC which becomes a target of write operation and data which is written (S<b>4</b>). The fail bit counter <b>21</b> detects memory cells (fail cells) in which data are not identical to each other to count the number of fail cells (S<b>5</b>). Information about the number of fail cells counted by the fail bit counter <b>21</b> is output to the control circuit <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">The control circuit <b>11</b> determines whether the number of fail cells is 0 or not on the basis of the information about the number of fail cells received from the fail bit counter <b>21</b> (S<b>6</b>). If no fail cells exist, it is considered that data are normally written in all the memory cells MC. Thus, a program verification operation is finished.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">However, if a fail cells exists, a correction level &#x394;V is calculated based on the number of fail cells and inhibit cells counted by the fail bit counter <b>21</b>. A correction voltage that the calculated correction level &#x394;V is added to a verifying read voltage is calculated (S<b>7</b>). The correction voltage calculated in the S<b>7</b> is used to verify data in the S<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">In the control circuit <b>11</b>, a write voltage applied to a bit line BL and a word line WL are adjusted (S<b>8</b>) and the correction method goes back to the S<b>3</b>. In the S<b>3</b>, the voltage adjusted in S<b>8</b> is applied to a bit line BL and a word line WL and then data is written in a memory cell MC.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">According to this correction method, when a verify read operation is performed, a voltage applied to a bit line BL and/or a voltage applied to a word line WL may be corrected based on the number of fail cells and inhibit cells. Thus, when a verify read operation is performed on a memory cell MC, it is less affected by a CSL noise generated in a common source line CSL. The overall time required in a program verification operation may be reduced while maintaining a high degree of accuracy in reading data from memory cell. The degree of accuracy of writing data may be improved by improving the degree of accuracy of verify read operation.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">In certain embodiments of the inventive concept such as those described above, the correction of both a voltage applied to a word line WL and a pre-charge voltage applied to a bit line BL may be accomplished. However, the present inventive concept is not limited to only this particular approach. For example, only the pre-charge voltage applied to a bit line BL may be corrected according to the number of fail cells and inhibit cells. Similarly, only a read voltage applied to a word line WL may be corrected according to the number of fail cells and inhibit cells.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">In another embodiment of the inventive concept, it is further assumed that the level of CSL noise is not uniform over an entire memory cell array <b>10</b>. For example, a plurality of common source lines CSL may be established in the memory cell array <b>10</b> and the memory cell array may be divided into a plurality of areas associated with different common source lines. In this case, it is necessary to correct a verifying read voltage by counting the number of fail cells and inhibit cells in every area.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">However, since a voltage applied to a word line WL is common in each area, a voltage applied to a word line WL in each area cannot be corrected. Thus, an effect by a CSL noise is reduced by correcting a pre-charge voltage of bit line BL.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a block diagram illustrating another semiconductor memory device in accordance with an embodiment of the inventive concept.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">A semiconductor memory device <b>2</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> has the same constitution as the semiconductor memory device <b>1</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> except that the page buffer <b>14</b> is divided into four areas and fail bit number latches <b>30</b>-<b>33</b> are added. Thus, like reference numbers refer to like elements throughout and the description of common features already discussed will be omitted for brevity.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the memory cell array <b>10</b> is divided into a plurality of areas (four areas in the present embodiment). The page buffer <b>14</b> is divided into a page buffer area (Area <b>0</b>)<b>140</b> corresponding to an area <b>0</b>, a page buffer area (Area <b>1</b>) <b>141</b> corresponding to an area <b>1</b>, a page buffer area (Area <b>2</b>) <b>142</b> corresponding to an area <b>2</b> and a page buffer area (Area <b>3</b>) <b>143</b> corresponding to an area <b>3</b>. The fail bit counter <b>21</b> counts the number of fail bits and inhibit cells at each area. The fail bit counter <b>21</b> stores a count result of area <b>0</b> in the fail bit number latch <b>30</b>, a count result of area <b>1</b> in the fail bit number latch <b>31</b>, a count result of area <b>2</b> in the fail bit number latch <b>32</b> and a count result of area <b>3</b> in the fail bit number latch <b>33</b>. Information about the count number in the fail bit number latches <b>30</b>-<b>33</b> is output to the control circuit <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">In the semiconductor memory device <b>2</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a pre-charge voltage of bit line BL is corrected according to a sequence below.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">During a first program verification operation, the fail bit counter <b>21</b> calculates the number of ON-cells and inhibit cells in the areas <b>0</b>-<b>3</b> from data written in the memory cell array <b>10</b>. The fail bit counter <b>21</b> stores the number of inhibit cells in the area <b>0</b> in the fail bit number latch <b>30</b>, the number of inhibit cells in the area <b>1</b> in the fail bit number latch <b>31</b>, the number of inhibit cells in the area <b>2</b> in the fail bit number latch <b>32</b> and the number of inhibit cells in the area <b>3</b> in the fail bit number latch <b>33</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">Information about the number of inhibit cells in the fail bit number latches <b>30</b>-<b>33</b> is output to the control circuit <b>11</b>. The number of fail bits may be calculated in the control circuit <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">During a second program verification operation, the control circuit <b>11</b>, according to the number of inhibit cells counted in the areas <b>0</b>-<b>3</b>, corrects a pre-charge voltage applied to a bit line BL by the page buffer controller <b>13</b> using a correction level &#x394;V as calculated above.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">During a third program verification operation, when performing a program verification operation after the next time, a correction level &#x394;V is calculated from the number of inhibit cells in the areas <b>0</b>-<b>3</b> and cells failed in a program verification operation. Thus, a pre-charge voltage applied to a bit line BL is corrected in every area <b>0</b>-<b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a block diagram illustrating a yet another semiconductor memory device in accordance with an embodiment of the inventive concept.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">A semiconductor memory device <b>1</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> has the same constitution as the semiconductor memory device <b>1</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> except that a correction voltage table <b>23</b> is added. Thus, like reference number refer to like elements throughout and the description of common features already discussed will be omitted for brevity.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">A correction voltage of a bit line BL and a word line WL corresponding to an increased voltage (the counted number of fail cells and inhibit cells) of common source line CSL calculated in the inhibit cells and fail cells is stored in the correction voltage table <b>23</b>. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, a correction value for an increased voltage of the common source line CSL is not calculated using a preset approach like the one described above. Rather, a voltage correction value corresponding to the increased voltage of the common source line CSL may be read from the correction voltage table <b>23</b> and a read verification operation performed by a voltage corrected using the read voltage correction value.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">If the control circuit <b>11</b> receives information about the number of ON-cells (the number of fail-cells and inhibit cells) from the fail bit counter <b>21</b>, the control circuit <b>11</b> reads a voltage correction value corresponding to the ON-cells from the correction voltage table <b>23</b> on the basis of the information about the number of ON-cells. The high voltage controller <b>22</b>, the row decoder <b>12</b> and the page buffer controller <b>13</b> are controlled based on the read voltage correction value to correct a pre-charge voltage applied to a bit line BL and a voltage applied to a word line WL.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">A pre-charge of bit line is done by a voltage which is the sum of a voltage correction value for a bit line BL read from the correction voltage table <b>23</b> and a pre-charge voltage of when a verify read operation is performed. A voltage which is the sum of a voltage correction value for a word line WL read from the correction voltage table <b>23</b> and a read voltage of when a verify read operation is performed is applied to a word line WL.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a graph further describing a voltage correction value derivation approach using the correction voltage table <b>23</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the horizontal axis represents a drain voltage VDS and the vertical axis represents a drain current ID. Also, the graph illustrates a relationship between the drain voltage VDS and drain current ID when a gate-source voltage VGS is V<b>1</b>, V<b>2</b> and V<b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, when the gate-source voltage VGS is V<b>1</b>, a point A represents a drain current ID of when applying a verifying read voltage when a voltage increase does not occur. A point B represents a drain current ID of when applying a verifying read voltage when a voltage increase occurs.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">A voltage correction value &#x394;VDS corresponding to a drain voltage VDS is stored in the correction voltage table <b>23</b> so that whenever a voltage is increased due to a CLS noise, a drain current value (point C) greater than a read acceptance value is obtained like when a voltage increase in the common source line CSL does not occur.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">A voltage correction value &#x394;(VGS=V<b>3</b>-V<b>2</b>) corresponding to a gate-source voltage VGS indicated by the correction voltage table <b>23</b> so that whenever a voltage is increased due to a CLS noise, a drain current value (point D) greater than a read acceptance value is obtained like when a voltage increase in the common source line CSL does not occur.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">By using the correction voltage table <b>23</b>, a correction voltage corresponding to an increased voltage of common source line CSL is read from the correction voltage table <b>23</b> and a write verification operation may be performed using the correction voltage. Thus, a correction voltage corresponding to an increased voltage of common source line CSL (that is, a voltage applied to a bit line BL and a word line WL) may be easily and rapidly set.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">A voltage correction value contained in the correction voltage table <b>23</b> is a predetermined value based on a relationship of a drain current ID relative to a drain voltage VDS and a gate-source voltage VGS of memory cell calculated in a simulation or an actual measurement value.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">The semiconductor memory device according to embodiments of the inventive concept corresponds to the semiconductor memory device of the embodiment described in relation to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The memory cells of the inventive concept correspond to the memory cells MC<b>0</b>-MCn (hereinafter memory cell MC) illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> and the memory strings of the inventive concept correspond to the memory strings ST<b>0</b>-STN (hereinafter memory string ST). The bit lines of the inventive concept correspond to the bit lines BL<b>0</b>-BLN (hereinafter bit line BL), the word lines of the inventive concept correspond to the word lines WL<b>0</b>-WLn (hereinafter word line WL) and the common source line of the inventive concept corresponds to the common source line CSL.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">The string select transistor of the inventive concept corresponds to the string select transistor SS<b>1</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> and the ground select transistor of the inventive concept corresponds to the ground select transistor GS<b>1</b>. The control circuit of the inventive concept corresponds to the control circuit <b>11</b>. The control circuit <b>11</b> controls operations of the row decoder <b>12</b>, the page buffer controller <b>13</b>, the page buffer <b>14</b>, the fail bit counter <b>21</b> and the high voltage controller <b>22</b> and controls the whole operation of the semiconductor memory device <b>1</b> when reading and erasing data from a memory cell MC and writing data in a memory cell MC.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">In the semiconductor memory device <b>1</b>, the memory strings ST in which memory cells MC are serially connected to each other are disposed in parallel, one end of each of the memory strings ST is connected to a corresponding bit line BL through the string select transistor SS<b>1</b> and control gates of memory cells MC on a same row are connected to a common word line WL. The semiconductor memory device <b>1</b> includes the control circuit <b>11</b> correcting a voltage pre-charging a bit line BL according to a voltage increase of common source line CSL caused by a current flowing from the memory string ST to the common source line CSL when reading data from a memory cell MC by pre-charging a bit line BL and then applying a predetermined read voltage to a word line WL.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">In the semiconductor memory device <b>1</b>, the control circuit <b>11</b> corrects a voltage pre-charging a bit line BL according to a voltage (CSL noise) of common source line CSL increased by a current flowing from the memory string ST to the common source line CSL.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111">As a result, when reading data from a memory cell MC, an effect (a problem that a threshold voltage Vth becomes high in appearance) by a voltage increase occurring in a common source line CSL is reduced and thereby a memory cell MC in which a data write operation is not finished is properly detected. When reading data from a memory cell MC, a time required to perform a program verification repeating a read operation and a write operation may be shortened by correcting a voltage pre-charged in a bit line BL while maintaining the degree of accuracy of reading data without preparing the aforementioned dummy read period.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">The control circuit <b>11</b> corrects a read voltage of the word line WL with respect to a common source line voltage increased by a current flowing through the common source line CSL.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">In the semiconductor memory device <b>1</b>, a voltage (a read voltage of selected cell) applied to a word line WL is corrected according to a voltage increase (CSL noise) of the common source line CSL caused by a current flowing from a memory string ST to the common source line CSL. As a voltage applied to a word line WL is corrected, a voltage pre-charged in a bit line BL may be corrected according to a voltage increase (CSL noise) of the common source line CSL.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">Thus, when reading data from a memory cell MC, an effect an effect (a problem that a threshold voltage Vth becomes high in appearance) by a voltage increase occurring in a common source line CSL may be reduced. A memory cell MC in which a data write operation is not finished can be properly detected. When reading data from a memory cell MC, a time required to perform a program verification repeating a read operation and a write operation may be shortened by correcting a voltage applied to a word line WL while maintaining the degree of accuracy of reading data without preparing the aforementioned dummy read period.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">The correction voltage table <b>23</b> may be prepared that contains a correction value for read voltage of the word line WL corresponding to a voltage increase of the common source line CSL. The control circuit <b>11</b> reads a correction value from the correction voltage table <b>23</b> and corrects the read voltage using the read correction value to apply the corrected read voltage to the word line WL.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116">A voltage of word line WL corresponding to an increased voltage of the common source line CSL may be easily and rapidly set.</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0117">As described above, in a semiconductor memory device consistent with an embodiment of inventive concept, a dummy read period used in a conventional nonvolatile semiconductor memory device is not required and when performing a program verification operation, a speed of reading data of memory cell and the degree of accuracy of reading data of memory cell may be improved.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0118">The semiconductor memory device <b>1</b> in accordance with some embodiments of the inventive concept may be applied to various products. A host <b>1100</b> may be constituted by a computer, a digital camera, a cell phone, a MP3 player, a PMP, a game machine and so on. A flash storage device <b>1200</b> may be constituted by a solid state drive SSD, a flash memory card or a flash memory module based on a flash memory. The host <b>1100</b> and the flash storage device <b>1200</b> may be connected to each other through a standardized interface such as ATA, SATA, PATA, USB, SCSI, ESDI, PCI express or IDE interface.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0119"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a drawing illustrating an example of applying a flash memory system <b>1000</b> in accordance with some embodiments of the inventive concept to a memory card. The memory card system <b>1000</b> includes a host <b>1100</b> and a memory card <b>1200</b>. The host <b>1100</b> includes a host controller <b>1110</b> and a host connection unit <b>1120</b>. The memory card <b>1200</b> includes a card connection unit <b>1210</b>, a card controller <b>1220</b> and a flash memory <b>1230</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0120">The host connection unit <b>1120</b> and the card connection unit <b>1210</b> include a plurality of pins. Those pins include a command pin, a clock pin and a power supply pin. The number of pins may be different depending on the type of memory card <b>1200</b>. For example, a SD card has 9 pins.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0121">The host <b>1100</b> writes data in the memory card <b>1200</b> or reads data stored in the memory card <b>1200</b>. The host controller <b>1110</b> transfers a command (e.g., a write command), a clock signal CLK generated from a clock generator (not shown) in the host <b>1100</b> and data DATA to the memory card <b>1200</b> through the host connection unit <b>1120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0122">The card controller <b>1220</b> stores data in the memory <b>1230</b> in synchronized with a clock signal generated from a clock generator (not shown) in the card controller <b>1220</b> in response to a write command received through the card connection unit <b>1210</b>. The memory <b>1230</b> stores data transferred from the host <b>1100</b>. For example, if the host <b>1100</b> is a digital camera, the memory <b>1230</b> stores image data.</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0123">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, the card controller <b>1220</b> may correct a voltage applied to a bit line and a word line by counting the number of inhibit cells and fail cells when performing a verify read operation of data. That is, the memory card system illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> may support the voltage correction operation described above.</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0124"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a drawing illustrating an example of applying a voltage correction operation in accordance with some embodiments of the inventive concept to solid state drive (SSD). Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, the SSD system <b>2000</b> includes a host <b>2100</b> and a SSD <b>2200</b>. The SSD <b>2200</b> exchanges a signal with the host <b>2100</b> through a signal connector <b>2231</b> and receives a power through a power connector <b>2221</b>. The SSD <b>2200</b> includes a plurality of nonvolatile memory devices <b>2201</b>-<b>220</b><i>n</i>, a SSD controller <b>2210</b> and an auxiliary power supply <b>2220</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0125">The plurality of nonvolatile memory devices <b>2201</b>-<b>220</b><i>n </i>is used as a storage unit of the SSD <b>2200</b>. The plurality of nonvolatile memory devices <b>2201</b>-<b>220</b><i>n </i>may be embodied by a flash memory device having a mass storage capacity. The SSD <b>220</b> mainly uses a flash memory.</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0126">The plurality of nonvolatile memory devices <b>2201</b>-<b>220</b><i>n </i>may be connected to the SSD controller <b>2210</b> through a plurality of channels CH<b>1</b>-CHn. One or more memory devices may be connected to one channel. Memory devices connected to one channel may be connected to a same data bus. A flash defragmentation is performed in a type of super block bringing a plurality of memory blocks together or in a type of super page bringing a plurality of pages together.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0127">The SSD controller <b>2210</b> exchanges signal SGL with the host <b>2100</b> through the signal connector <b>2231</b>. The signal SGL may include a command, an address and data. The SSD controller <b>2210</b> writes data in a corresponding memory device or reads data from a corresponding memory device according to a command of the host <b>2100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0128">The auxiliary power supply <b>2220</b> is connected to the host <b>2100</b> through the power connector <b>2221</b>. The auxiliary power supply <b>2220</b> may receive a power from the host <b>2100</b> to be charged. The auxiliary power supply <b>2220</b> may be located inside the SSD <b>2200</b> or outside the SSD <b>2200</b>. For example, the auxiliary power supply <b>2220</b> may be located at a main board and may provide an auxiliary power to the SSD <b>2200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0129"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a block diagram illustrating a constitution of the SSD controller illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, the SSD controller <b>2210</b> includes a NVM interface <b>2211</b>, a host interface <b>2212</b>, an ECC <b>2213</b>, a central processing unit (CPU) <b>2214</b> and a buffer memory <b>2215</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0130">The NVM interface <b>2211</b> scatters data transferred from the buffer memory <b>2215</b> to each of channels CH<b>1</b>-CHn. The NVM interface <b>2211</b> transfers data read from the nonvolatile memory devices <b>2201</b>-<b>220</b><i>n </i>to the buffer memory <b>2215</b>. The NVM interface <b>2211</b> may use an interface method of NAND flash memory. That is, the SSD controller <b>2210</b> may perform a program, read or erase operation according to the interface method of NAND flash memory.</p>
<p id="p-0132" num="0131">The host interface <b>2212</b> may interface with the SSD <b>2200</b> according to a protocol of the host <b>2100</b>. The host interface <b>2212</b> may communicate with the host <b>2100</b> using a universal serial bus (USB), a small computer system interface (SCSI), a PCI express, an ATA, a parallel ATA (PATA), a serial ATA (SATA) and a serial attached ACSI (SAS). The host interface <b>2212</b> may perform a function of a disk emulation supporting so that the host <b>2100</b> recognizes the SSD <b>220</b> as a hard disk HDD.</p>
<p id="p-0133" num="0132">The central processing unit (CPU) <b>2214</b> analyses and processes a signal SGL inputted from the host <b>2100</b>. The central processing unit (CPU) <b>2214</b> controls the host interface <b>2212</b> or the nonvolatile memories <b>2201</b>-<b>220</b><i>n </i>through the host interface <b>2212</b> or the NVM interface <b>2211</b>. The central processing unit (CPU) <b>2214</b> controls operations of the NVM interface <b>2211</b> according to a firmware for driving the SSD <b>2200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0134" num="0133">The buffer memory <b>2215</b> temporally stores writing data provided from the host <b>2100</b> or data read from the nonvolatile memory devices <b>2201</b>-<b>220</b><i>n</i>. The buffer memory <b>2215</b> may store meta data or cache data to be stored in the nonvolatile memory devices <b>2201</b>-<b>220</b><i>n</i>. When a sudden power off operation is performed, meta data or cache data stored in the buffer memory <b>2215</b> are stored in the nonvolatile memory devices <b>2201</b>-<b>220</b><i>n</i>. The buffer memory <b>2215</b> may be a DRAM or a SRAM.</p>
<p id="p-0135" num="0134">The SSD <b>2000</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11 and 12</figref> may support the voltage correction operation described before.</p>
<p id="p-0136" num="0135"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an example of embodying a voltage correction operation in accordance with some embodiments of the inventive concept in a flash memory module. A flash memory module <b>3100</b> may be used to be connected to a personal computer PC, a notebook computer, a cell phone, a personal digital assistant and a camera.</p>
<p id="p-0137" num="0136">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, the flash memory module <b>3000</b> includes a memory system <b>3100</b>, a power supply <b>3200</b>, an auxiliary power supply <b>3250</b>, a central processing unit (CPU) <b>3300</b>, a RAM <b>3400</b> and a user interface <b>3500</b>. The flash memory module <b>3000</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> may support a voltage correction operation.</p>
<p id="p-0138" num="0137">The scope of the inventive concept is not limited to only the illustrated embodiments and many modifications are possible without materially departing from the novel teachings and advantages described above.</p>
<p id="p-0139" num="0138">For example, in the embodiments described above, the semiconductor memory device having a nonvolatile memory is described as an illustration. However, the semiconductor memory device may be applied to semiconductor memory devices having a CLS noise such that a voltage of common source line increases.</p>
<p id="p-0140" num="0139">In certain embodiments, the constitution that a pre-charge voltage applied to a bit line BL and a read voltage applied to a word line WL may be corrected as described. However, only a read voltage applied to a word line WL may be corrected according to the number of fail cells and inhibit cells.</p>
<p id="p-0141" num="0140">According to the inventive concept, when reading data from a memory cell in a memory string, an effect of voltage increase (CSL noise) of common source line by a current flowing from the memory string to the common source line may be reduced by correcting a voltage applied to the memory cell. Thus, a time required to perform a program verification repeating a read operation and a write operation may be shortened while maintaining the degree of accuracy of reading data without preparing a dummy read period suppressing a voltage increase of common source line.</p>
<p id="p-0142" num="0141">The above-disclosed subject matter is to be considered illustrative, and not restrictive, and the appended claims are intended to cover all such modifications, enhancements, and other embodiments, which fall within the scope of the inventive concept. Thus, to the maximum extent allowed by law, the scope of the inventive concept is to be determined by the broadest permissible interpretation of the following claims and their equivalents, and shall not be restricted or limited by the foregoing detailed description.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A semiconductor memory device comprising:
<claim-text>a memory cell array including a plurality of memory strings, each memory string including memory cells series-connected between a string select transistor and a ground select transistor, wherein the ground select transistor is connected to a common source line (CSL);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of word lines including a selected word line, wherein the selected word line is commonly connected to gates of a row of memory cells extending across the plurality of memory strings;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of bit lines including a selected bit line, wherein each one of the plurality of bit lines is connected to a corresponding one of the plurality of memory strings;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a page buffer that programs data in selected memory cells associated with at least one of the selected word line and the selected bit line during a program operation, and that reads the programmed data from the selected memory cells during a verify read operation of a program verification operation;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fail bit counter that determines a number of fail cells among the selected memory cells based on the read data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a voltage controller that generates a read voltage applied to the selected word line during the verify read operation and a pre-charge voltage applied to selected bit line during the read verify operation; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control circuit that controls the voltage controller to correct at least one of the read voltage and the pre-charge voltage to be applied during a subsequent verify read operation of the program verification operation in response to the number of fail cells.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The semiconductor memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the number of fail cells determined by the fail bit counter is defined by a voltage level of the CSL, and the control circuit corrects the pre-charge voltage in response to the number of fail cells.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The semiconductor memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the number of fail cells determined by the fail bit counter is defined by a voltage level of the CSL, and the control circuit corrects the read voltage in response to the number of fail cells.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The semiconductor memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the number of fail cells determined by the fail bit counter is defined by a voltage level of the CSL, and the control circuit corrects the pre-charge voltage and the read voltage in response to the number of fail cells.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The semiconductor memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the control circuit stores a number of inhibit cells and controls the voltage controller in response to the number of inhibit cells and the number of fail cells.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The semiconductor memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a corrected voltage table that stores correction voltage values, wherein the control circuit controls the voltage controller by referencing at least one correction voltage value in the corrected voltage table in response to the number of fail cells.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The semiconductor memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the control circuit stores a number of inhibit cells and controls the voltage controller in response to the number of inhibit cells and the number of fail cells.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The semiconductor memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the number of fail cells determined by the fail bit counter is defined by a voltage level of the CSL, and the control circuit corrects the pre-charge voltage in response to the number of fail cells and the number of inhibit cells.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The semiconductor memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the number of fail cells determined by the fail bit counter is defined by a voltage level of the CSL, and the control circuit corrects the read voltage in response to the number of fail cells and the number of inhibit cells.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The semiconductor memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the number of fail cells determined by the fail bit counter is defined by a voltage level of the CSL, and the control circuit corrects the pre-charge voltage and the read voltage in response to the number of fail cells and the number of inhibit cells.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A method of operating a semiconductor memory device comprises:
<claim-text>during a program verification operation, applying a read voltage to a selected word line and applying a pre-charge voltage to a selected bit line, and providing output data in response to the read voltage and pre-charge voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a number of fail cells in view of the output data, wherein the number of fail cells is directly related to an increase in voltage on a common source line (CSL) connected to memory cells providing the output data; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>during a subsequent program verification operation, adjusting at least one of the read voltage and the pre-charge voltage in response to the number of fail cells.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein both of the read voltage and the pre-charge voltage are adjusted in response to the number of fail cells.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the number of fail cells is determined further in view of a number of inhibit cells.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the number of fail cells is determined with reference to a corrected voltage table storing correction voltage values.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A system comprising:
<claim-text>a controller that controls the operation of a semiconductor memory device, wherein the semiconductor memory device comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a memory cell array including a plurality of memory strings, each memory string including memory cells series-connected between a string select transistor and a ground select transistor, wherein the ground select transistor is connected to a common source line (CSL);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of word lines including a selected word line, wherein the selected word line is commonly connected to gates of a row of memory cells extending across the plurality of memory strings;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of bit lines including a selected bit line, wherein each one of the plurality of bit lines is connected to a corresponding one of the plurality of memory strings;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a page buffer that programs data in selected memory cells associated with at least one of the selected word line and the selected bit line during a program operation, and that reads the programmed data from the selected memory cells during a verify read operation of a program verification operation;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fail bit counter that determines a number of fail cells among the selected memory cells based on the read data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a voltage controller that generates a read voltage applied to the selected word line during the verify read operation and a pre-charge voltage applied to selected bit line during the read verify operation; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control circuit that controls the voltage controller to correct at least one of the read voltage and the pre-charge voltage to be applied during a subsequent verify read operation of the program verification operation in response to the number of fail cells.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the number of fail cells determined by the fail bit counter is defined by a voltage level of the CSL, and the control circuit corrects the pre-charge voltage in response to the number of fail cells.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the number of fail cells determined by the fail bit counter is defined by a voltage level of the CSL, and the control circuit corrects the read voltage in response to the number of fail cells.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the number of fail cells determined by the fail bit counter is defined by a voltage level of the CSL, and the control circuit corrects the pre-charge voltage and the read voltage in response to the number of fail cells.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the control circuit stores a number of inhibit cells and controls the voltage controller in response to the number of inhibit cells and the number of fail cells.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a corrected voltage table that stores correction voltage values, wherein the control circuit controls the voltage controller by referencing at least one correction voltage value in the corrected voltage table in response to the number of fail cells. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
