<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625536-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625536</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13203240</doc-number>
<date>20100225</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2009-043190</doc-number>
<date>20090225</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>314</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20090101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>W</subclass>
<main-group>4</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>370331</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Communication system, communication control device, radio base station, and communication control method</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0192682</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Matsumoto et al.</name>
<date>20080800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>370328</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0163223</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Casey</name>
<date>20090600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>455453</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0067450</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Balachandran et al.</name>
<date>20100300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>370329</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0069091</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>El-Saidny</name>
<date>20100300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4554563</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0244874</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Fodor et al.</name>
<date>20111000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>455450</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2003-078938</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20030300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006-005502</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20060100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2007-116716</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20070500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2008-211645</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20080900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00010">
<othercit>International Search Report and Written Opinion dated Jun. 8, 2010 issued by the Japanese Patent Office for International Application No. PCT/JP2010/053009.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00011">
<othercit>Notification of Reasons for Refusal dated May 7, 2013 issued in counterpart Japanese Application No. 2011-501652.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>11</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110305166</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20111215</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ootani</last-name>
<first-name>Taro</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yokohama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ootani</last-name>
<first-name>Taro</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yokohama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Procopio, Cory, Hargreaves &#x26; Savitch LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>KYOCERA Corporation</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Kyoto</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Shah</last-name>
<first-name>Chirag</first-name>
<department>2477</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Persaud</last-name>
<first-name>Amar</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/JP2010/053009</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20100225</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20110824</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2010/098410</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20100902</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">For each radio base stations (<b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C), a communication control device (<b>1</b>) collects information on the number of unused EPS bearers passing through the radio base station, and transmits the numbers to the radio base stations (<b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C). Further, based on the received number of unused EPS bearers, the radio base stations (<b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C) perform control to select, as a connection destination radio base station of a radio terminal (<b>3</b>), the radio base station other than the radio base station having unused EPS bearers passing through is not larger than a predetermined number.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="200.74mm" wi="147.32mm" file="US08625536-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="210.90mm" wi="154.43mm" file="US08625536-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="244.26mm" wi="178.31mm" file="US08625536-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="253.92mm" wi="187.11mm" file="US08625536-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="174.16mm" wi="146.98mm" file="US08625536-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="199.90mm" wi="171.37mm" file="US08625536-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="171.45mm" wi="161.97mm" file="US08625536-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to: a radio communication system that includes a radio terminal, multiple radio base stations each configured to perform radio communications with the radio terminal, and a communication control device configured to control the multiple radio base stations, and establishes a logical communication path between the radio terminal and the communication control device through one of the radio base stations; a communication control device in the communication system; a radio base station in the communication system; and a radio communication method in the communication system.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND ART</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">LTE (Long Term Evolution) in 3GPP (3rd Generation Partnership Project) is a technique after the 3rd generation mobile phone (3G) communication schemes such as W-CDMA and CDMA 2000, which are currently in widespread use, and before the upcoming 4th generation mobile phone (4G) communication scheme. LTE is also known as the 3.9th generation mobile phone (3.9G) communication scheme.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">A radio communication system employing LTE establishes a logical communication path called an EPS (Evolved Packet System) bearer between a radio terminal and a communication control device through a radio base station (see, Patent Document 1, for example). The number of EPS bearers passing through a radio base station is predetermined based on how the radio base station is used. The radio terminal, the radio base station, and the communication control device can use multiple bearers for communication in accordance with the amount of data to be transmitted.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">PRIOR ART DOCUMENT</heading>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">Patent Document</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0000">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0004">PATENT DOCUMENT 1: Japanese Patent Application Publication NO. 2007-116716</li>
</ul>
</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In the above-described communication system, the communication control device sometimes requests the radio base station to add the EPS bearer depending on the communication state such as QoS state. In such case, the radio base station determines whether the addition is possible based on the state of use of the EPS bearers passing therethrough, and notifies the communication control device of the determination result. When the EPS bearer cannot be added, the communication continues with the EPS bearers established so far and the communication quality degrades.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The call connection request from the radio terminal to the radio base station makes the radio base station determine whether the call can be connected based on the state of use of the EPS bearers passing therethrough. The call that cannot be connected is released.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In view of the above problem, an object of the present invention is to provide a communication system, a communication control device, a radio base station, and a communication control method with which logical communication paths can be appropriately established.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">To solve the above problem, the present invention has following features. A first feature of the present invention is summarized as a communication system (radio communication system <b>10</b>) including a radio terminal (radio terminal <b>3</b>), a plurality of radio base stations (radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C) configured to perform radio communication with the radio terminal, and a communication control device (communication control device <b>1</b>) controlling the plurality of radio base stations, in which logical communication paths are established between the radio terminal and the communication control device through each of the radio base stations, wherein the communication control device includes: a collector (state of use collector <b>152</b>) configured to collect, for each of the radio base stations, a state of use of the logical communication paths passing through the radio base station; and a state-of-use transmitter (state-of-use transmitter <b>154</b>) configured to transmit, to the plurality of radio base stations, the state of use of the logical communication paths passing through each of the radio base stations collected for the radio base station by the collector, and each of the radio base stations includes: a state-of-use receiver (state-of-use receiver <b>252</b>) configured to receive the state of use of the logical communication paths passing through each of the radio base stations from the communication control device; and a selection controller (selection controller <b>254</b>) configured to perform a control to determine the radio base station to which the radio terminal is to be connected based on the state of use of the logical communication paths passing through each of the radio base stations received by the state-of-use receiver.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In such a communication system, the communication control device collects and transmits to each of the radio base stations, the state of use of the logical communication paths passing through each of the radio base stations. Then, the radio base stations performs a control so that a radio base station to which the radio terminal is to be connected is selected based on the received state of use of the logical communication paths. Thus, each of the radio base stations can perform control so that the radio base station to which the radio terminal is to be connected is selected in consideration of not only the state of use of the logical communication paths passing therethrough but also the state of use of logical communication paths passing through the other radio base stations.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Therefore, degradation of communication quality due to the shortage of the unused logical communication paths passing through a radio base station rejecting the request from the communication control device for increasing the logical communication path to the radio base station is prevented. Moreover, when the radio terminal requests call connection to a radio base station, the call is not released due to the shortage of the unused logical communication paths passing through the radio base station.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">A second aspect according to the first feature is summarized as that the selection controller performs a control to select, as a connection destination of the radio terminal, a radio base station other than the radio base station of which the number of unused logical communication paths passing through the radio base station among the logical communication paths passing therethrough is not larger than a predetermined number.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">A third feature according to the second feature is summarized as that the state-of-use transmitter transmits, to the plurality of radio base stations, information on the radio base station of which the number of unused logical communication paths passing therethrough among the logical communication paths passing through the radio base station is not larger than the predetermined number, and the state-of-use receiver receives, from the communication controller, the information on the radio base station of which the number of unused logical communication paths passing therethrough among the logical communication paths passing through the radio base station is not larger than the predetermined number.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">A fourth feature according to the third feature is summarized as that the selection controller selects the radio base station that is not the radio base station of which the number of unused logical communication paths passing therethrough is not larger than the predetermined number from the communication control device as the connection destination of the radio terminal, and transmits information on the radio base station that is the connection destination of the radio terminal to the radio terminal, and the radio terminal includes: a connection destination receiver (receiver <b>352</b>) configured to receive the information on the radio base station that is the connection destination of the radio terminal from the communication control device; and a connection controller (connection destination controller <b>354</b>) configured to perform a control to select the connection destination of the radio terminal based on the information on the radio base station that is the connection destination of the radio terminal received by the connection receiver.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">A fifth feature according to the third feature is summarized as that the selection controller transmits to the radio terminal, the information on the radio base station of which the number of unused logical communication paths passing therethrough is not larger than the predetermined number from the communication control device, and the radio terminal includes: a base station information receiver (receiver <b>352</b>) configured to receive the information on the radio base station of which the number of unused logical communication paths passing therethrough is not larger than the predetermined number; and a connection controller (connection destination controller <b>354</b>) configured to perform control to select, as the connection destination of the radio terminal, a radio base station other than the radio base station of which the number of unused logical communication paths passing through the radio base station among the logical communication paths passing therethrough is not larger than the predetermined number, based on the information on the radio base station of which the unused number of logical communication paths passing therethrough is not larger than the predetermined number.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">A sixth feature according to any one of the first to fifth features is summarized as that each of the radio base stations further includes an unused number transmitter (alarm information transmitter <b>251</b>) configured to transmit the number of unused logical communication paths passing therethrough to the communication control device when the number of unused logical communication paths passing through the radio base station is not larger than the predetermined number.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">A seventh feature of the present invention is summarized as a communication control device controlling a plurality of radio base stations communicating with a radio terminal, the communication control device including: a collector configured to collect, for each of the radio base stations, a state of use of the logical communication paths passing through the radio base station; and a state-of-use transmitter configured to transmit, to the plurality of radio base stations, the state of use of the logical communication paths passing through each of the radio base stations collected for the radio base station by the collector.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">An eighth feature of the present invention is summarized as a radio base station configured to perform radio communications with a radio terminal and being controlled by a communication control device, the radio base station including: a state-of-use receiver configured to receive the state of use of the logical communication paths passing through each of a plurality of radio base stations from the communication control device; and a selection controller configured to perform a control to determine the radio base station to which the radio terminal is to be connected based on the state of use of the logical communication paths passing through each of the radio base stations received by the state-of-use receiver.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">A ninth feature of the present invention is summarized as a communication method in a communication system including a radio terminal, a plurality of radio base stations configured to perform radio communications with the radio terminal, and a communication control device controlling the plurality of radio base stations, in which a logical communication paths are established between the radio terminal and the communication control device through each of the radio base stations, the method including the steps of: collecting, for each of the radio base stations, a state of use of the logical communication paths passing through the radio base station by the communication control device; transmitting, by the communication control device, the collected state of use of the logical communication paths passing through each of the radio base stations collected for the radio base station by the collector to the plurality of radio base stations; receiving, by each of the radio base stations, the state of use of the logical communication paths passing through each of the radio base stations from the communication control device; and performing a control, by each of the radio base stations, to determine the radio base station to which the radio terminal is to be connected based on the received state of use of the logical communication paths passing through each of the radio base stations.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">A tenth feature of the present invention is summarized as a radio base station, configured to perform radio communication with a radio terminal and controlled by a communication control device, in a communication system employing LTE, the radio base station including a transmitter configured to transmit error information on the radio base station to the communication control device.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">A eleventh feature of the present invention is summarized as a communication control device controlling a plurality of radio base stations performing radio communications with a radio terminal in a communication system employing LTE, the communication control device including a transmitter configured to transmit, to the plurality of radio base stations, information on a radio base station to which the connection from the radio terminal for handover is barred.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">A twelfth feature of the present invention is summarized as a communication method in a communication system including a radio terminal, a plurality of radio base stations configured to perform radio communications with the radio terminal, and a communication control device controlling the plurality of radio base stations, in which logical communication paths are established between the radio terminal and the communication control device through each of the radio base stations, the method including the steps of: transmitting, by the radio base stations, error information on the radio base stations to the communication control device; and transmitting, by the communication control device, information on a radio base station to which the connection from the radio terminal for handover is barred, to the plurality of radio base stations.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">According to the present invention, logical communication paths can be appropriately established.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an overall schematic configuration view of a radio communication system according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a configuration view of a communication control device according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram showing an example of alarm information according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagram showing a list of non-connectable radio base stations according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a configuration view of a radio base station according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a configuration view of a radio terminal according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a sequence diagram showing a first operation of the radio communication system according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a sequence diagram showing a second operation of the radio communication system according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a sequence diagram showing a third operation of the radio communication system according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">MODES FOR CARRYING OUT THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">An embodiment of the present invention is described with reference to the drawings. Specifically, descriptions are given on (1) Configuration of Radio Communication System, (2) Operation of Radio communication system, (3) Operation and Effect, and (4) Other Embodiment. In the description of the drawings in the embodiment below, the same or similar parts are given the same or similar reference numerals.</p>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">(1) Configuration of Radio Communication System</heading>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">First, the configuration of a radio communication system according to an embodiment of the present invention is described below in the order of (1.1) Overall Schematic Configuration of Radio Communication System, (1.2) Configuration of Communication Control Device, (1.3) Configuration of Radio Base Station, and (1.4) Configuration of Radio Terminal.</p>
<p id="h-0009" num="0000">(1.1) Overall Schematic Configuration of Radio Communication System</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an overall schematic configuration diagram of a radio communication system <b>10</b> according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The radio communication system <b>10</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a radio communication system employing LTE. The radio communication system <b>10</b> includes network apparatuses, namely: a communication control device <b>1</b>; radio base stations <b>2</b>A, <b>2</b>B, and <b>2</b>C; and a radio terminal <b>3</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, an EPS bearer, which is a logical communication path, is established between the communication control device <b>1</b> and the radio terminal <b>3</b> through the radio base station <b>2</b>A. The communication control device <b>1</b> and the radio terminal <b>3</b> can communicate with each other using the EPS bearer through the radio base station <b>2</b>A. For example, the communication control device <b>1</b> and the radio terminal <b>3</b> can use the maximum of six EPS bearers with each of the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C.</p>
<p id="h-0010" num="0000">(1.2) Configuration of Communication Control Device</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a configuration diagram of the communication control device <b>1</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the communication control device <b>1</b> includes a controller <b>102</b>, a storage unit <b>103</b>, a wired communication unit <b>104</b>, a wired communication unit <b>106</b>, and an antenna <b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The controller <b>102</b> is formed of a CPU for example, and controls various functions of the communication control device <b>1</b>. The storage unit <b>103</b> is formed of a memory for example, and stores therein various pieces of information used for the control in the communication control device <b>1</b> or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The wired communication unit <b>104</b> transmits and receives data to and from an unillustrated upper level network. The wired communication unit <b>106</b> transmits and receives data to and from the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The controller <b>102</b> includes a state of use collector <b>152</b> and a state-of-use transmitter <b>154</b>. The state of use collector <b>154</b> receives alarm information including the number of unused EPS bearers passing through each of the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C from each of the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C through the wired communication unit <b>106</b>. The state of use collector <b>154</b> stores the received alarm information in the storage unit <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram showing an example of the alarm information. The alarm information shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> includes an ID of the radio base station (base station ID) that has transmitted the alarm information and the number of unused EPS bearers passing through the radio base station. As described later, the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C transmits the alarm information to the communication control device <b>1</b> when the number of unused bearers passing therethrough is not larger than a predetermined number (e.g., not larger than two).</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The state-of-use transmitter <b>154</b> reads out alarm information stored in the storage unit <b>103</b> to generate the list of non-connectable radio base stations listing the alarm information. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows an example of the list of non-connectable radio base stations.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The EPS bearers passing therethrough the radio base station, which transmits the alarm information, having the unused number not larger than the predetermined number are preferably left unused considering the EPS addition request from the communication control device <b>1</b> and the call connection request from the radio terminal <b>3</b> made later. Thus, the state-of-use transmitter <b>154</b> regards unusable the EPS bearers passing through the radio base station of which the unused number is not larger than the predetermined number and identified by the base station ID in the alarm information. Then, the state-of-use transmitter <b>154</b> generates the list of non-connectable radio base stations that lists the alarm information indicating that the unused number is not larger than the predetermined number.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The state-of-use transmitter <b>154</b> transmits the generated list of non-connectable radio base stations to the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C through the wired communication unit <b>106</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0011" num="0000">(1.3) Configuration of Radio Base Station</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a configuration view of the radio base station <b>2</b>A. The radio base station <b>2</b>A shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> includes a controller <b>202</b>, a storage unit <b>203</b>, a wired communication unit <b>204</b>, a radio communication unit <b>206</b>, and an antenna <b>208</b>. The radio bases stations <b>2</b>B and <b>2</b>C have the configuration similar to the radio base station <b>2</b>A and description thereof is omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The controller <b>202</b> is formed of a CPU for example and controls various functions of the radio base station <b>2</b>A. The storage unit <b>203</b> is formed of a memory for example, and stores therein various pieces of information used for the control in the radio base station <b>2</b>A or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The wired communication unit <b>204</b> transmits and receives data to and from the communication control device <b>1</b>. The radio communication unit <b>206</b> includes an RF circuit, a base band circuit, and the like, performs modulation/demodulation and encoding/decoding, and transmits and receives a radio signal to and from the radio terminal <b>3</b> through the antenna <b>208</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The controller <b>202</b> includes an alarm information transmitter <b>251</b>, a state-of-use receiver <b>252</b>, and a selection controller <b>254</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The alarm information transmitter <b>251</b> periodically identifies the unused number of EPS bearers passing through the own radio base station. Then, when the unused number of EPS bearers passing through the own radio base station is not larger than a predetermined number, the alarm information transmitter <b>251</b> generates the alarm information including the unused number and the base station ID of the own radio base station. Moreover, the alarm information transmitter <b>251</b> transmits the generated alarm information to the communication control device <b>1</b> through the wired communication unit <b>204</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The state-of-use receiver <b>252</b> receives the list of non-connectable radio base stations from the communication control device <b>1</b> through the wired communication unit <b>204</b>. Then, the state-of-use receiver <b>252</b> stores the received list of non-connectable radio base stations in the storage unit <b>203</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Based on the list of non-connectable radio base stations stored in the storage unit <b>203</b>, the selection controller <b>254</b> performs a control so that a radio base station which is not the radio base station of which the number of unused EPS bearers among the EPS bearers passing through the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C is not larger than a predetermined number is selected as the connection destination of the radio terminal <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Specifically, the selection controller <b>254</b> reads out the list of non-connectable radio base stations from the storage unit <b>203</b> and transmits the list of non-connectable radio base stations to the radio terminal <b>3</b> through the radio communication unit <b>206</b> and the antenna <b>208</b>. Here, the radio terminal <b>3</b> is located in any one of the cells provided by the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C. Thus, the radio base station <b>3</b> receives the list of non-connectable radio bases stations from any one of the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C providing the cell in which the radio terminal <b>3</b> is located.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Alternatively, the selection controller <b>254</b> receives the communication quality information from the radio terminal <b>3</b> communicating with the own radio base station through the antenna <b>208</b> and the radio communication unit <b>206</b>. The communication quality information is information such as RSSI indicating the quality of communication between the radio terminal <b>3</b> and any one of the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The selection controller <b>254</b> regards that the radio terminal <b>3</b> needs to be handed over if the communication quality indicated by the communication quality information is not higher than the predetermined level. Then, based on the list of non-connectable radio base stations readout from the storage unit <b>203</b>, the selection controller <b>254</b> selects the radio base station of which the number of unused EPS bearers among the EPS bearers passing through the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C is not larger than a predetermined number as the new connection destination, i.e., handover destination, of the radio terminal <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">For example, the storage unit <b>203</b> stores therein base station IDs of the peripheral radio base stations. The selection controller <b>254</b> specifies as the base station ID of the radio base station to serve as the handover destination, the base station ID not included in the list of non-connectable radio base stations from among the base station IDs stored in the storage unit <b>203</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The presence of the multiple base station IDs not included in the list of non-connectable radio base stations among the base station IDs stored in the storage unit <b>203</b> allows the selection controller <b>254</b> to acquire the locations of the radio terminal <b>3</b> and the peripheral radio base stations and specify the base station ID of the radio base station closest to the radio terminal <b>3</b> except for the own radio base station from among the multiple base station IDs as the base station ID of the radio base station to serve as the hand over destination, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Then, the selection controller <b>254</b> generates and transmits to the handover destination radio base station information including the base station ID of the radio base station to serve as the handover destination for the radio terminal <b>3</b> through the radio communication unit <b>206</b> and the antenna <b>208</b>. As described above, the radio terminal <b>3</b> is located in any one of the cells provided by the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C. Thus, the radio terminal <b>3</b> receives the handover destination radio base station information from any one of the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C providing the cell in which the radio terminal <b>3</b> is located.</p>
<p id="h-0012" num="0000">(1.4) Configuration of Radio Terminal</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a configuration view of the radio terminal <b>3</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the radio terminal <b>3</b> includes a controller <b>302</b>, a storage unit <b>303</b>, a radio communication unit <b>306</b>, an antenna <b>308</b>, a monitor <b>310</b>, a microphone <b>312</b>, a speaker <b>314</b>, and an operation unit <b>316</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The controller <b>302</b> is formed of a CPU for example and controls various functions of the radio terminal <b>3</b>. The storage unit <b>303</b> is formed of a memory for example and stores therein various pieces of information used for the control in the radio terminal <b>3</b> or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The radio communication unit <b>306</b> includes an RF circuit, a base band circuit and the like, performs modulation/demodulation and coding/decoding, and transmits and receives a radio signal to and from the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The monitor <b>310</b> displays thereon an image and operation (input phone number and addresses) received through the controller <b>302</b>. The microphone <b>312</b> collects sound and outputs sound data based on the collected sound to the controller <b>302</b>. The speaker <b>314</b> outputs sound based on the sound data acquired from the controller <b>302</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The operation unit <b>316</b> is formed of ten-keys, function keys, and the like and is an interface through which a user operation is input.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The controller <b>302</b> includes a receiver <b>352</b>, a connection destination controller <b>354</b>, and a communication quality measurement unit <b>356</b>. The receiver <b>352</b> receives the list of non-connectable radio base stations or the handover destination radio base station information from any one of the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C providing the cell in which the own radio terminal <b>3</b> is located through the antenna <b>308</b> and the radio communication unit <b>306</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">When the receiver <b>352</b> receives the list of non-connectable radio base stations, the connection destination controller <b>354</b> specifies the radio base station of which the number of unused EPS bearers among the EPS bearers passing through the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C is not larger than a predetermined number as the connection destination radio base station.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">For example, the radio terminal <b>3</b> receives a pilot signal and the like from the peripheral radio base stations and the connection destination controller <b>354</b> can acquire the base station IDs of the peripheral radio base stations included in the pilot signal. In this case, the connection destination controller <b>354</b> may specify the base station ID not included in the list of non-connectable radio base stations from among the acquired base station IDs as the base station ID of the connection destination radio base station.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">When the connection destination controller <b>354</b> specifies the connection destination radio base station, the controller <b>302</b> cooperates with the controller <b>101</b> in the communication control device <b>1</b> to establish the EPS bearer passing through the connection destination radio base station.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">When the receiver <b>352</b> receives the handover destination radio base station information, the connection destination controller <b>354</b> specifies the radio base station corresponding to the base station ID included in the handover destination radio base station information.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">When the connection destination controller <b>354</b> specifies the radio base station that is the handover destination, the controller <b>302</b> cooperates with the controller <b>101</b> in the communication control device <b>1</b> to establish the EPS bearer passing through the handover destination radio base station.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The communication quality measurement unit <b>356</b> measures the quality of communications between the radio terminal <b>3</b> and any one of the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C. Moreover, the communication quality measurement unit <b>356</b> transmits the communication quality to any one of the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C serving as the communication partner through the radio communication unit <b>306</b> and the antenna <b>308</b>.</p>
<heading id="h-0013" level="1">(2) Operation of Radio Communication System</heading>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">Operations of the radio communication system <b>10</b> are described below. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a sequence diagram showing the first operation of the radio communication system <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">In Step <b>101</b>, the controller <b>202</b> in each of the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C identifies the number of unused EPS bearers passing through the own radio base station. In Step <b>102</b>, the controller <b>202</b> in each of the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C transmits the alarm information including the unused number and the base station ID of the own radio base station to the communication control device <b>1</b> when the identified unused number is not larger than the predetermined number. Here, the controller <b>202</b> in the radio base station <b>2</b>B transmits the alarm information to the communication control device <b>1</b>. The controller <b>102</b> in the communication control device <b>1</b> receives the alarm information from the radio base station <b>2</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">In Step S<b>103</b>, the controller <b>102</b> in the communication control device <b>1</b> generates the list of non-connectable radio base stations that lists the received alarm information. Here, the list of non-connectable radio base station includes the alarm information from the radio base station <b>2</b>B only.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">In Step S<b>104</b>, the controller <b>102</b> in the communication control device <b>1</b> transmits the list of non-connectable radio base stations to the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C through broadcast communication. The controller <b>202</b> in each of the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C receives the list of non-connectable radio base stations.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a sequence diagram showing a second operation of the radio communication system <b>10</b>. The operation shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is preceded by the operation in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the radio terminal <b>3</b> is assumed to be located in the cell provided by the radio base station <b>2</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">In Step S<b>201</b>, the controller <b>202</b> in the radio base station <b>2</b>A transmits the list of non-connectable radio base stations from the communication control device <b>1</b> to the radio terminal <b>3</b>. The controller <b>302</b> in the radio terminal <b>3</b> receives the list of non-connectable radio base stations.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">In Step S<b>202</b>, the controller <b>302</b> in the radio terminal <b>3</b> specifies the radio base station (radio base station <b>2</b>A herein) of which the base station ID is not included in the received list of non-connectable radio base stations as the connection destination.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">Then, the EPS bearer is established between the communication control device <b>1</b> and the radio terminal <b>3</b> through the radio base station <b>2</b>A by a conventional method.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">More specifically, in Step S<b>203</b>, the controller <b>202</b> in the radio base station <b>2</b>A and the controller <b>302</b> in the radio terminal <b>3</b> establish a control channel between the radio base station <b>2</b>A and the radio terminal <b>3</b>. In Step S<b>204</b>, the controller <b>202</b> in the radio base station <b>2</b>A and the controller <b>302</b> in the radio terminal <b>3</b> establish a signal radio (SR) bearer between the radio base station <b>2</b>A and the radio terminal <b>3</b>. In Step S<b>205</b>, the controller <b>202</b> in the radio base station <b>2</b>A and the controller <b>302</b> in the radio terminal <b>3</b> establish a security between the radio base station <b>2</b>A and the radio terminal <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">In Step S<b>206</b>, the controller <b>202</b> in the radio base station <b>2</b>A and the controller <b>102</b> in the communication control device <b>1</b> establish the S1 bearer between the radio base station <b>2</b>A and the communication control device <b>1</b>. In Step S<b>207</b>, the controller <b>202</b> in the radio base station <b>2</b>A and the controller <b>302</b> in the radio terminal <b>3</b> establish the SR bearer <b>1</b> and the data radio (DR) bearer between the radio base station <b>2</b>A and the radio terminal <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">Then in Step S<b>208</b>, the controller <b>202</b> in the radio base station <b>2</b>A and the controller <b>102</b> in the communication control device <b>1</b> establish the EPS bearer passing through the radio base station <b>2</b>A between the communication control device <b>1</b> and the radio terminal <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a sequence diagram showing a third operation of the radio communication system <b>10</b>. The operation shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is preceded by the operation shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the radio terminal <b>3</b> is assumed to be located in the cell provided by the radio base station <b>2</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">In Step S<b>301</b>, the radio base station <b>2</b>A and the radio terminal <b>3</b> are in communication with each other. During the communication, in Step S<b>302</b>, the controller <b>102</b> in the communication control device <b>1</b> periodically transmits the list of non-connectable radio base stations to the radio terminals <b>2</b>A and <b>2</b>C. The controller <b>202</b> in each of the radio base stations <b>2</b>A and <b>2</b>C receives the list of non-connectable radio base stations.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">In Step S<b>303</b>, the controller <b>302</b> in the radio terminal <b>3</b> transmits the communication quality information to the communication partner, i.e., the radio base station <b>2</b>A. The controller <b>202</b> in the radio base station <b>2</b>A receives the communication quality information.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">In Step S<b>304</b>, the controller <b>202</b> in the radio base station <b>2</b>A selects a radio base station (here, the radio base station <b>2</b>C) of which the base station ID is not included in the list of non-connectable radio base stations as the handover destination radio base station when the communication quality information indicates that the communication quality is not higher than a predetermined level.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">In Step S<b>305</b>, the controller <b>202</b> in the radio base station <b>2</b>A transmits handover destination radio base station information including the base station ID of the handover destination radio base station to the radio terminal <b>3</b>. The controller <b>302</b> in the radio terminal <b>3</b> receives the handover destination radio base station information.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">In Step S<b>306</b>, the controller <b>302</b> in the radio terminal <b>3</b> specifies the radio base station (here the radio base station <b>2</b>C) of which the base station ID is included in the received handover destination radio base station information as the handover destination.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">Then, the EPS bearer passing through the radio base station <b>2</b>C is established between the communication control device <b>1</b> and the radio terminal <b>3</b> through the processing similar to that in Step <b>203</b> to Step S<b>208</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>.</p>
<heading id="h-0014" level="1">(3) Operation and Effect</heading>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">In the radio communication system <b>10</b> according to the embodiment of the present invention, the communication control device <b>1</b> collects the number of unused EPS bearers passing through each of the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C and transmits the numbers to the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C. Then, the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C perform a control so that the radio base station with the number of unused EPS bearers passing therethrough being not larger than a predetermined number is selected as the radio base station to which the radio terminal <b>3</b> is to be connected on the basis of the received numbers of unused EPS bearers.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">Thus, each of the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C can perform control so that the radio base station to which the radio terminal <b>3</b> is to be connected is selected in consideration of not only the state of use of the EPS bearers passing therethrough but also the state of use of EPS bearers passing through the other radio base stations.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">Therefore, degradation of communication quality due to the shortage of the unused EPS bearers passing through a radio base station rejecting the request by the communication control device <b>1</b> for increasing EPS bearers to the radio base station is prevented. Moreover, when the radio terminal <b>3</b> requests call connection to a radio base station, the call is not released due to the shortage of the unused EPS bearers passing through the radio base station.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">Each of the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C transmits alarm information to the communication control device <b>1</b> when the number of unused EPS bearers passing therethrough is not larger than the predetermined number (two for example). The communication control device <b>1</b> transmits the list of non-connectable radio base stations that lists the alarm information to the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">The number of EPS bearers passing through a radio base station is more likely to be higher than the predetermined number rather than to be not larger than the predetermined number to adversely affect the EPS addition request from the communication control device <b>1</b> and the call connection from the radio terminal <b>3</b>. Thus, alarm information and the list of non-connectable radio base stations are communicated only when the number of unused EPS bearers in the radio base stations <b>2</b>A to <b>2</b>C is not larger than a predetermined number. Accordingly, the communication amount can be reduced for the efficient use of communication path.</p>
<heading id="h-0015" level="1">(4) Other Embodiments</heading>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">As described above, the details of the present invention have been described by using the embodiment of the present invention. However, it should not be understood that the description and drawings which constitute part of this disclosure limit the present invention. From this disclosure, various alternative embodiments, examples, and operation techniques will be easily found by those skilled in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">In the embodiment, the radio base station <b>2</b>A selects the handover destination for the radio terminal <b>3</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, and thus the handover is conducted by the radio base station. Instead, the handover may be conducted by the radio terminal <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">In this case, the radio terminal <b>3</b> compares the reception level of the pilot signal and the like from the radio base station serving as the communication partner with the reception level of the pilot signal and the like from the other radio base station. The radio base station <b>3</b> specifies the other radio base station as the handover destination when the reception level of the pilot signal and the like from the other radio base station is higher. Then, the EPS bearer passing through the radio base station as the handover destination is established between the communication control device <b>1</b> and the radio terminal <b>3</b> trough the processing similar to that in Steps S<b>203</b> to S<b>208</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">As described above, the present invention naturally includes various embodiments which are not described herein. Accordingly, the technical scope of the present invention should be determined only by the matters to define the invention in the scope of claims regarded as appropriate from the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">Note that the entire content of Japanese Patent Application No. 2009-043190 (filed on Feb. 25, 2009) is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0016" level="1">INDUSTRIAL APPLICABILITY</heading>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">A communication system, a communication control device, a radio base station, and a communication control method of the present invention can appropriately establish logical communication paths and useful for the communication system etc.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A communication system comprising a radio terminal, a plurality of radio base stations configured to perform radio communication with the radio terminal, and a communication control device controlling the plurality of radio base stations, in which logical communication paths are established between the radio terminal and the communication control device through each of the radio base stations, wherein
<claim-text>the communication control device includes:
<claim-text>a collector configured to collect, for each of the radio base stations, a state of use of the logical communication paths passing through the radio base station; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a state-of-use transmitter configured to transmit, to the plurality of radio base stations, the state of use of the logical communication paths passing through each of the radio base stations collected for the radio base station by the collector, wherein the state-of-use transmitter transmits, to the plurality of radio base stations, information on the radio base station of which the number of unused logical communication paths passing therethrough among the logical communication paths passing through the radio base station is not larger than the predetermined number, and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of the radio base stations includes:
<claim-text>a state-of-use receiver configured to receive the state of use of the logical communication paths passing through each of the radio base stations from the communication control device, wherein the state-of-use receiver receives, from the communication controller, the information on the radio base station of which the number of unused logical communication paths passing therethrough among the logical communication paths passing through the radio base station is not larger than the predetermined number; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a selection controller configured to perform a control to determine the radio base station to which the radio terminal is to be connected based on the state of use of the logical communication paths passing through each of the radio base stations received by the state-of-use receiver, and wherein the selection controller performs a control to select, as a connection destination of the radio terminal, a radio base station other than the radio base station of which the number of unused logical communication paths passing through the radio base station among the logical communication paths passing therethrough is not larger than a predetermined number.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The communication system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the selection controller selects the radio base station that is not the radio base station of which the number of unused logical communication paths passing therethrough is not larger than the predetermined number from the communication control device as the connection destination of the radio terminal, and transmits information on the radio base station that is the connection destination of the radio terminal to the radio terminal, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the radio terminal includes:
<claim-text>a connection destination receiver configured to receive the information on the radio base station that is the connection destination of the radio terminal from the communication control device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a connection controller configured to perform a control to select the connection destination of the radio terminal based on the information on the radio base station that is the connection destination of the radio terminal received by the connection receiver.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The communication system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein each of the radio base stations further includes an unused number transmitter configured to transmit the number of unused logical communication paths passing therethrough to the communication control device when the number of unused logical communication paths passing through the radio base station is not larger than the predetermined number.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The communication system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the selection controller transmits to the radio terminal, the information on the radio base station of which the number of unused logical communication paths passing therethrough is not larger than the predetermined number from the communication control device, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the radio terminal includes:
<claim-text>a base station information receiver configured to receive the information on the radio base station of which the number of unused logical communication paths passing therethrough is not larger than the predetermined number; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a connection controller configured to perform control to select, as the connection destination of the radio terminal, a radio base station other than the radio base station of which the number of unused logical communication paths passing through the radio base station among the logical communication paths passing therethrough is not larger than the predetermined number, based on the information on the radio base station of which the unused number of logical communication paths passing therethrough is not larger than the predetermined number.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The communication system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein each of the radio base stations further includes an unused number transmitter configured to transmit the number of unused logical communication paths passing therethrough to the communication control device when the number of unused logical communication paths passing through the radio base station is not larger than the predetermined number.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The communication system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of the radio base stations further includes an unused number transmitter configured to transmit the number of unused logical communication paths passing therethrough to the communication control device when the number of unused logical communication paths passing through the radio base station is not larger than the predetermined number.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The communication system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a first radio base station comprises a transmitter configured to transmit error information on the first radio base station to the communication control device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The communication system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the communication control device comprises a transmitter configured to transmit, to the plurality of radio base stations, information on a radio base station to which the connection from the radio terminal for handover is barred.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The communication system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of the radio base stations further includes an unused number transmitter configured to transmit the number of unused logical communication paths passing therethrough to the communication control device when the number of unused logical communication paths passing through the radio base station is not larger than the predetermined number.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A communication method in a communication system including a radio terminal, a plurality of radio base stations configured to perform radio communications with the radio terminal, and a communication control device controlling the plurality of radio base stations, in which logical communication paths are established between the radio terminal and the communication control device through each of the radio base stations, the method comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>collecting, for each of the radio base stations, a state of use of the logical communication paths passing through the radio base station by the communication control device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting, by the communication control device, the collected state of use of the logical communication paths passing through each of the radio base stations collected for the radio base station by the collector to the plurality of radio base stations, and transmitting to the plurality of radio base stations, information on the radio base station of which the number of unused logical communication paths passing therethrough among the logical communication paths passing through the radio base station is not larger than the predetermined number;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving, by each of the radio base stations, the state of use of the logical communication paths passing through each of the radio base stations from the communication control device, and receiving from the communication controller, the information on the radio base station of which the number of unused logical communication paths passing therethrough among the logical communication paths passing through the radio base station is not larger than the predetermined number; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>performing a control, by each of the radio base stations, to determine the radio base station to which the radio terminal is to be connected based on the received state of use of the logical communication paths passing through each of the radio base stations, and performing a control to select, as a connection destination of the radio terminal, a radio base station other than the radio base station of which the number of unused logical communication paths passing through the radio base station among the logical communication paths passing therethrough is not larger than a predetermined number.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The communication method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>transmitting, by the radio base stations, error information on the radio base stations to the communication control device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting, by the communication control device, information on a radio base station to which the connection from the radio terminal for handover is barred, to the plurality of radio base stations. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
