<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08621928-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08621928</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13772638</doc-number>
<date>20130221</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2009-126595</doc-number>
<date>20090526</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>P</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>125</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7350415</main-classification>
<further-classification> 7351432</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e61">Sensor for detecting acceleration and angular velocity</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5488863</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Mochida et al.</name>
<date>19960200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6415663</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Mochida et al.</name>
<date>20020700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6691571</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Willig et al.</name>
<date>20040200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 7350412</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6742390</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Mochida et al.</name>
<date>20040600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 7350414</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2001/0015101</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Iwaki et al.</name>
<date>20010800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0154788</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Willig et al.</name>
<date>20030800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0164040</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Willig et al.</name>
<date>20030900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0183007</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Willig et al.</name>
<date>20031000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0217377</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ao</name>
<date>20051000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 73510</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0071247</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Konaka</name>
<date>20090300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0005884</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Weinberg et al.</name>
<date>20100100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>07-294262</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19951100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2000-74673</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20000300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006-105698</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20060400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00015">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2008-39614</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20080200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00016">
<othercit>Office Action dated Mar. 20, 2013 in the co-pending U.S. Appl. No. 12/781,852.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00017">
<othercit>Office Action mailed on Mar. 8, 2011 issued from the Japanese Patent Office in the corresponding Japanese Patent Application No. 2009-126595 (English translation attached).</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00018">
<othercit>Notice of Allowance dated Jul. 11, 2013 in the co-pending U.S. Appl. No. 12/781,852.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>11</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7350415</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>2</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12781852</doc-number>
<date>20100518</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13772638</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130152684</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130620</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>DENSO CORPORATION</orgname>
<address>
<city>Kariya</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gotoh</last-name>
<first-name>Keisuke</first-name>
<address>
<city>Toyohashi</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Posz Law Group, PLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>DENSO CORPORATION</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Kariya</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Williams</last-name>
<first-name>Hezron E</first-name>
<department>2856</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Shabman</last-name>
<first-name>Mark A</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A sensor includes an acceleration detector, an angular velocity detector, a driver, and first to fourth springs. Each detector includes a pair of fixed electrodes, a pair of movable electrodes, and a pair of supporting members for supporting the movable electrodes. The driver causes the supporting members to vibrate in opposite phases in a first direction. The first spring couples the supporting members of the acceleration detector and has elasticity in a second direction perpendicular to the first direction. The second spring couples the supporting members of the acceleration detector to a base and has elasticity in both directions. The third spring couples the supporting members of the acceleration detector to the supporting members of the angular velocity detector and has elasticity in both directions. The fourth spring couples the supporting members to the movable electrodes of the angular velocity detector and has elasticity in the second direction.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="197.61mm" wi="157.14mm" file="US08621928-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="221.40mm" wi="178.39mm" file="US08621928-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="185.08mm" wi="194.06mm" file="US08621928-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a divisional of U.S. application Ser. No. 12/781,852 filed on May 18, 2010, which is based on and claims priority to Japanese Patent Application No. 2009-126595 filed on May 26, 2009, the disclosures of which are incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a sensor for detecting acceleration and angular velocity.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">For example, JP-2008-39614A discloses a sensor for detecting acceleration and angular velocity. The sensor includes a vibrator configured to be displaced in both a drive direction and a detection direction perpendicular to the drive direction, a driver for causing the vibrator to vibrate in the drive direction, and detection electrodes for detecting a displacement of the vibrator in the detection direction based on a change in its capacitance.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The sensor disclosed in JP-2008-39614A detects acceleration and angular velocity by detecting the capacitance change of the detection electrodes. That is, both acceleration and angular velocity are detected based on the capacitance change of the detection electrodes. Therefore, it is difficult to determine a structural resonance, which is in proportion to the square root of a spring constant and in inverse proportion to the square root of the mass, suitable for both acceleration and angular velocity detection.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The detection electrodes are arranged in parallel to the drive direction and coupled together by a detection spring having elasticity in the detection direction. Further, the detection electrodes are coupled together in the drive direction by a coupling link spring.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">JP-2008-39614A describes as follows: &#x201c;When acceleration is applied, the detection spring is displaced in the same phase in the detection direction. Therefore, resonance frequency (structural resonance) at the time of detection of acceleration depends on the detection spring. In contrast, when angular velocity is applied, the detection spring is displaced in opposite phases in the detection direction. Therefore, the resonance frequency at the time of detection of angular velocity depends on both the detection spring but also the coupling link spring. For this reason, the resonance frequency at the time of detection of acceleration and the resonance frequency at the time of detection of angular velocity can be separated from each other by adjusting a spring constant of the coupling link spring&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">However, unless the detection electrodes are ideally displaced in the same phase in the detection direction, the resonance frequency at the time of detection of acceleration may depend on not only the detection spring but also the coupling link spring. In practice, the detection electrodes cannot be ideally displaced in the same phase in the detection direction due to factors such as manufacturing variations. If the detection electrodes are not ideally displaced in the same phase in the detection direction, the detection electrodes are obliquely positioned with respect to each other. As a result, since biasing force of the coupling link spring acts on the detection electrodes in the detection direction, the coupling link spring contributes to the structural resonance at the time of detection of acceleration. Therefore, the structural resonance at the time of detection of acceleration substantially depends on both the detection spring and the coupling link spring.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">As described above, according to the sensor disclosed in JP-2008-39614A, each of the resonance frequency at the time of detection of acceleration and the resonance frequency at the time of detection of angular velocity depends on both the detection spring and the coupling link spring. Therefore, it is difficult to determine the structural resonance suitable for both acceleration and angular velocity detection.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">For example, when the structural resonance (i.e., spring constant) is reduced, it becomes likely that the detection electrodes are displaced by an inertial force. As a result, the amount of the capacitance change of the detection electrodes due to the inertial force is increased so that a sensitivity characteristic of the acceleration sensor can be improved. However, in this case, since it becomes likely that the detection electrodes are displaced by an external force, an impact resistance of the angular velocity sensor may be reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Conversely, when the structural resonance (i.e., the spring constant) is increased, it becomes less likely that the detection electrodes are displaced by the inertial force. As a result, it becomes less likely that the detection electrodes are displaced by the external force so that the impact resistance of the angular velocity sensor can be improved. However, in this case, since it becomes less likely that the detection electrodes are displaced by the inertial force, the sensitivity characteristic of the acceleration sensor may be reduced.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In view of the above, it is an object of the present invention to provide a sensor having an acceleration detector and an angular velocity detector, and configured to prevent a reduction in a sensitivity characteristic of the acceleration detector and a reduction in an impact resistance of the angular velocity detector.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to an aspect of a present invention, a sensor for detecting acceleration and angular velocity includes an acceleration detector, an angular velocity detector, a driver, a first spring, a second spring, a third spring, and a fourth spring. The acceleration detector includes a pair of first fixed electrodes, a pair of first movable electrodes, a pair of weights, and a pair of first supporting members. The pair of first supporting members supports the pair of first movable electrodes and is joined to the pair of weights. The angular velocity detector includes a pair of second fixed electrodes, a pair of second movable electrodes, and a pair of second supporting members. The pair of second supporting members supports the pair of second movable electrodes. The driver causes the pair of first supporting members to vibrate in opposite phases in a first direction and causes the pair of second supporting members to vibrate in opposite phases in the first direction. The first spring couples the pair of first supporting members together and has elasticity in a second direction perpendicular to the first direction. The second spring couples the pair of first supporting members to a base and has elasticity in both the first direction and the second direction. The third spring couples the pair of first supporting members to the pair of second supporting members and has elasticity in both the first direction and the second direction. The fourth spring couples the pair of second supporting members to the pair of second movable electrodes and has elasticity in the second direction.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to another aspect of a present invention, a sensor for detecting acceleration and angular velocity includes an acceleration detector, an angular velocity detector, a driver, a first spring, a second spring, a third spring, a fourth spring, and a fifth spring. The acceleration detector includes a pair of first fixed electrodes, a pair of first movable electrodes, a pair of weights, and a pair of first supporting members. The pair of first supporting members supports the pair of first movable electrodes and is joined to the pair of weights. The angular velocity detector includes a pair of second fixed electrodes, a pair of second movable electrodes, and a pair of second supporting members. The pair of second supporting members supports the pair of second movable electrodes. The driver causes the pair of first supporting members to vibrate in opposite phases in a first direction and causes the pair of second supporting members to vibrate in opposite phases in the first direction. The first spring couples the pair of first supporting members together and has elasticity in the first direction. The second spring couples the pair of first supporting members to the base and has elasticity in both the first direction and a second direction perpendicular to the first direction. The third spring couples the pair of first supporting members to the pair of second supporting members and has elasticity in both the first direction and the second direction. The fourth spring couples the pair of second supporting members to the pair of second movable electrodes and has elasticity in the second direction. The fifth spring couples the pair of second supporting members together and has elasticity in the first direction.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The above and other objectives, features and advantages of the present invention will become more apparent from the following detailed description made with check to the accompanying drawings. In the drawings:</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram illustrating a plan view of a sensor according to an embodiment of the present invention, and</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a diagram illustrating a plan view of a sensor according to a modification of the embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">A sensor <b>100</b> according to an embodiment of the present invention is described below with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The sensor <b>100</b> is configured to detect acceleration and angular velocity.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the sensor <b>100</b> includes an acceleration detector <b>10</b> for detecting acceleration, an angular velocity detector <b>30</b> for detecting angular velocity, and a driver <b>50</b> for causing drive frames <b>11</b>, <b>31</b> to vibrate in a X direction as a first direction. The sensor <b>100</b> has symmetry with respect to a line L<b>1</b> indicated by a dashed line in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The line L<b>1</b> is parallel to the X-direction. The sensor <b>100</b> is a microelectromechanical systems (MEMS) device forming by micromachining a semiconductor substrate such as a SOI substrate by a known exposure technique. That is, the acceleration detector <b>10</b>, the angular velocity detector <b>30</b>, and the driver <b>50</b> are integrated on a base <b>70</b> equivalent to the semiconductor substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The acceleration detector <b>10</b> includes a first drive frame <b>11</b>, a first movable electrode <b>12</b>, a first fixed electrode <b>13</b>, and a weight <b>14</b>. The first movable electrode <b>12</b> is joined to the first drive frame <b>11</b>. The first fixed electrode <b>13</b> is joined to a wall <b>71</b> of the base <b>70</b> and located facing the first movable electrode <b>12</b> in a Y-direction as a second direction perpendicular to the first direction. The weight <b>14</b> is joined to the first drive frame <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The first drive frame <b>11</b> includes a first pair of supporting members <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>11</b><i>b </i>and a first spring <b>11</b><i>c</i>. Each of the supporting members <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>11</b><i>b </i>has one X-direction portion parallel to the X-direction and two Y-direction portions parallel to the Y-direction. The X-direction portion and the Y-direction portions are joined together so that each of the supporting members <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>11</b><i>b </i>can have a rectangular C-shape in cross-section taken along a XY-plane defined by the X-direction and the Y-direction. The first spring <b>11</b><i>c </i>couples ends of the supporting member <b>11</b><i>a </i>to ends of the supporting member <b>11</b><i>b</i>. The first spring <b>11</b><i>c </i>can be displaced in the Y-direction. Each of the supporting members <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>11</b><i>b </i>has rigidity.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The weight <b>14</b> and an extension <b>51</b><i>a </i>of a first vibrating portion <b>51</b> are joined to the X-direction portion. The first movable electrode <b>12</b> is joined to each of the Y-direction portions. A second spring <b>15</b> is joined to the wall <b>71</b> of the base <b>70</b> and allows the drive frame <b>11</b> to be displaced in the X-direction and in the Y-direction. Accordingly, the first movable electrode <b>12</b> can be displaced with respect to the wall <b>71</b> (i.e., the first fixed electrode <b>13</b>) of the base <b>70</b> in the X-direction and in the Y-direction. It is noted that the second spring <b>15</b> includes a X-direction spring <b>15</b><i>a </i>and a Y-direction spring <b>15</b><i>b </i>joined to the X-direction spring <b>15</b><i>a</i>. The X-direction spring <b>15</b><i>a </i>can be displaced in the X-direction, and the Y-direction spring <b>15</b><i>b </i>can be displaced in the Y-direction. That is, the X-direction spring <b>15</b><i>a </i>has elasticity in the X-direction, and the Y-direction spring <b>15</b><i>b </i>has elasticity in the Y-direction. In the example shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, six second springs <b>15</b> are joined to the wall <b>71</b> to couple the first drive frame <b>11</b> to the wall <b>71</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the first movable electrode <b>12</b> has a first tooth portion <b>12</b><i>a </i>extending in the X-direction from the first pair of supporting members <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>11</b><i>b </i>toward the first fixed electrode <b>13</b>. The first fixed electrode <b>13</b> has a second tooth portion <b>13</b><i>a </i>extending in the X-direction from the wall <b>71</b> toward the first movable electrode <b>12</b>. The first tooth portion <b>12</b><i>a </i>and the second tooth portion <b>13</b><i>a </i>are located facing each other in the Y-direction to form a first pair of capacitors C<b>1</b><i>a</i>, C<b>1</b><i>b</i>. The first pair of capacitors C<b>1</b><i>a</i>, C<b>1</b><i>b </i>has symmetry with respect to the line L<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Since the first movable electrode <b>12</b> is coupled to each of the first spring <b>11</b><i>c </i>and the second spring <b>15</b>, the first movable electrode <b>12</b> can be displaced with respect to the wall <b>71</b> in the X-direction and in the Y-direction. A displacement of the first movable electrode <b>12</b> in the X-direction depends on the second spring <b>15</b>, and the displacement of the first movable electrode <b>12</b> in the Y-direction depends on both the first spring <b>11</b><i>c </i>and the second spring <b>15</b>. In contrast, since the first fixed electrode <b>13</b> is fixed to the wall <b>71</b>, the first fixed electrode <b>13</b> cannot be displaced with respect to the wall <b>71</b>. Therefore, a capacitance of the capacitors C<b>1</b><i>a</i>, C<b>1</b><i>b </i>change depending on the displacement of the first movable electrode <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">As described above, the displacement of the first movable electrode <b>12</b> in the X-direction depends on the second spring <b>15</b>. Therefore, the capacitance change of the capacitors C<b>1</b><i>a</i>, C<b>1</b><i>b </i>due to a change in a facing area (i.e., an overlapping area) between the first movable electrode <b>12</b> and the first fixed electrode <b>13</b> depends on the second spring <b>15</b>. In contrast, the displacement of the first movable electrode <b>12</b> in the Y-direction depends on both the first spring <b>11</b><i>c </i>and the second spring <b>15</b>. Therefore, the capacitance change of the capacitors C<b>1</b><i>a</i>, C<b>1</b><i>b </i>due to a change in a distance between the first movable electrode <b>12</b> and the first fixed electrode <b>13</b> depends on both the first spring <b>11</b><i>c </i>and the second spring <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">It is noted that each clearance between the first tooth portion <b>12</b><i>a </i>and the wall <b>71</b> and between the second tooth portion <b>13</b><i>a </i>and the first pair of supporting members <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>11</b><i>b </i>is larger than the maximum amplitude of vibration of the first drive frame <b>11</b> (i.e., the first movable electrode <b>12</b>). Thus, when the first movable electrode <b>12</b> vibrates in the X-direction, the first tooth portion <b>12</b><i>a </i>does not hit against the wall <b>71</b>, and the second tooth portion <b>13</b><i>a </i>does not hit against the first pair of supporting members <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>11</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The distance between the first tooth portion <b>12</b><i>a </i>and the second tooth portion <b>13</b><i>a </i>is greater than the maximum displacement of the first drive frame <b>11</b> (i.e., the first movable electrode <b>12</b>) in the Y-direction. Thus, when the first movable electrode <b>12</b> is displaced in the Y-direction, the first tooth portion <b>12</b><i>a </i>does not hit against the second tooth portion <b>13</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Further, a facing length (i.e., overlapping length) between the first tooth portion <b>12</b><i>a </i>and the second tooth portion <b>13</b><i>a </i>in the X-direction is greater than the maximum amplitude of vibration of the first drive frame <b>11</b> (i.e., the first movable electrode <b>12</b>). Thus, when the first movable electrode <b>12</b> vibrates in the X-direction, the facing area between the first movable electrode <b>12</b> and the first fixed electrode <b>13</b> becomes greater than zero so that a considerable reduction in the capacitance of the capacitors C<b>1</b><i>a</i>, C<b>1</b><i>b </i>can be prevented.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The angular velocity detector <b>30</b> is located in a region surrounded by the first drive frame <b>11</b>. The angular velocity detector <b>30</b> includes a second drive frame <b>31</b>, a third spring <b>32</b>, a fourth spring <b>33</b>, a second movable electrode <b>34</b>, and a second fixed electrode <b>35</b>. The second drive frame <b>31</b> is coupled to the first drive frame <b>11</b> by the third spring <b>32</b>. The third spring <b>32</b> can be displaced in the X-direction and in the Y-direction. The second movable electrode <b>34</b> is coupled to the second drive frame <b>31</b> by the fourth spring <b>33</b>. The fourth spring <b>33</b> can be displaced in the Y-direction. The second fixed electrode <b>35</b> is joined to a bottom <b>72</b> of the base <b>70</b> and located facing the second movable electrode <b>34</b> in the Y-direction.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The second drive frame <b>31</b> includes a second pair of supporting members <b>31</b><i>a</i>, <b>31</b><i>b</i>. Each of the supporting members <b>31</b><i>a</i>, <b>31</b><i>b </i>has two X-direction portions parallel to the X-direction and two Y-direction portions parallel to the Y-direction. The X-direction portions and the Y-direction portions of the supporting members <b>31</b><i>a</i>, <b>31</b><i>b </i>are joined together so that each of the supporting members <b>31</b><i>a</i>, <b>31</b><i>b </i>can have a rectangular ring shape in cross-section taken along the XY-plane. Each of the supporting members <b>31</b><i>a</i>, <b>31</b><i>b </i>has rigidity. The third spring <b>32</b> is joined to outer surfaces of the Y-direction portions of the supporting members <b>31</b><i>a</i>, <b>31</b><i>b</i>. The fourth spring <b>33</b> is joined to inner surfaces of the X-direction portions of the supporting members <b>31</b><i>a</i>, <b>31</b><i>b</i>. Thus, the second pair of supporting members <b>31</b><i>a</i>, <b>31</b><i>b </i>can vibrate in a coupled manner in the X-direction, and the second movable electrode <b>34</b> can be displaced in the Y-direction.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The second movable electrode <b>34</b> has a detection frame <b>34</b><i>a </i>and a third tooth portion <b>34</b><i>b</i>. The detection frame <b>34</b><i>a </i>has two X-direction portions parallel to the X-direction and two Y-direction portions parallel to the Y-direction. The X-direction portions and the Y-direction portions of the second movable electrode <b>34</b> are joined together so that the second movable electrode <b>34</b> can have a rectangular ring shape in cross-section taken along the XY-plane. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the second movable electrode <b>34</b> has symmetry with respect to the line L<b>1</b>. The third tooth portion <b>34</b><i>b </i>is joined to an inner surface of the Y-direction portion of the detection frame <b>34</b><i>a </i>and extends in the X-direction toward the center of the detection frame <b>34</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The second fixed electrode <b>35</b> has an extension <b>35</b><i>a </i>and a fourth tooth portion <b>35</b><i>b</i>. The extension <b>35</b><i>a </i>extends in the Y-direction. The fourth tooth portion <b>35</b><i>b </i>is joined to the extension <b>35</b><i>a </i>and extends in the X-direction. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the second fixed electrode <b>35</b> has symmetry with respect to the line L<b>1</b>. The third tooth portion <b>34</b><i>b </i>of the second movable electrode <b>34</b> and the fourth tooth portion <b>35</b><i>b </i>of the second fixed electrode <b>35</b> are located facing each other in the Y-direction to form a second pair of capacitors C<b>2</b><i>a</i>, C<b>2</b><i>b</i>. The second pair of capacitors C<b>2</b><i>a</i>, C<b>2</b><i>b </i>has symmetry with respect to the line L<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The second movable electrode <b>34</b> is joined to the wall <b>71</b> of the base <b>70</b> through the fourth spring <b>33</b>, the second drive frame <b>31</b>, the third spring <b>32</b>, the first drive frame <b>11</b>, and the second spring <b>15</b>. Therefore, the second movable electrode <b>34</b> can be displaced with respect to the bottom <b>72</b> in the X-direction and in the Y-direction. A displacement of the second movable electrode <b>34</b> in the X-direction depends on both the second spring <b>15</b> and the third spring <b>32</b>, and the displacement of the second movable electrode <b>34</b> in the Y-direction depends on both the third spring <b>32</b> and the fourth spring <b>33</b>. In contrast, since the second fixed electrode <b>35</b> is fixed to the bottom <b>72</b>, the second fixed electrode <b>35</b> cannot be displaced with respect to the bottom <b>72</b>. Therefore, a capacitance of the capacitors C<b>2</b><i>a</i>, C<b>2</b><i>b </i>changes depending on the displacement of the second movable electrode <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">As described above, the displacement of the second movable electrode <b>34</b> in the X-direction depends on both the second spring <b>15</b> and the third spring <b>32</b>. Therefore, the capacitance change of the capacitors C<b>2</b><i>a</i>, C<b>2</b><i>b </i>due to a change in a facing area (i.e., an overlapping area) between the second movable electrode <b>34</b> and the second fixed electrode <b>35</b> depends on both the second spring <b>15</b> and the third spring <b>32</b>. In contrast, the displacement of the second movable electrode <b>34</b> in the Y-direction depends on both the third spring <b>32</b> and the fourth spring <b>33</b>. Therefore, the capacitance change of the capacitors C<b>2</b><i>a</i>, C<b>2</b><i>b </i>due to a change in a distance between the second movable electrode <b>34</b> and the second fixed electrode <b>35</b> depends on both the third spring <b>32</b> and the fourth spring <b>33</b>. Specifically, the displacement of the second movable electrode <b>34</b> in the Y-direction depends on also the second spring <b>15</b>. However, contribution of the second spring <b>15</b> to the displacement of the second movable electrode <b>34</b> in the Y-direction is small enough to be negligible. Therefore, it can be considered that the displacement of the second movable electrode <b>34</b> in the Y-direction depends on both the third spring <b>32</b> and the fourth spring <b>33</b>. It is noted that the second spring <b>15</b> mainly distributes to the displacement of the first drive frame <b>11</b> in the Y-direction.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">It is noted that each clearance between the third tooth portion <b>34</b><i>b </i>and the extension <b>35</b><i>a </i>and between the fourth tooth portion <b>35</b><i>b </i>and the detection frame <b>34</b><i>a </i>is larger than the maximum amplitude of vibration of the second drive frame <b>31</b> (i.e., the second movable electrode <b>34</b>). Thus, when the second movable electrode <b>34</b> vibrates in the X-direction, the third tooth portion <b>34</b><i>b </i>does not hit against the extension <b>35</b><i>a</i>, and the fourth tooth portion <b>35</b><i>b </i>does not hit against the detection frame <b>34</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">A distance between the third tooth portion <b>34</b><i>b </i>and the fourth tooth portion <b>35</b><i>b </i>is greater than the maximum displacement of the second drive frame <b>31</b> (i.e., the second movable electrode <b>34</b>) in the Y-direction. Thus, when the second drive frame <b>31</b> (i.e., the second movable electrode <b>34</b>) is displaced in the Y-direction, the third tooth portion <b>34</b><i>b </i>does not hit against the fourth tooth portion <b>35</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Further, a facing length (i.e., overlapping length) between the third tooth portion <b>34</b><i>b </i>and the fourth tooth portion <b>35</b><i>b </i>in the X-direction is greater than the maximum amplitude of vibration of the second drive frame <b>31</b> (i.e., the second movable electrode <b>34</b>). Thus, when the second movable electrode <b>34</b> vibrates in the X-direction, the facing area between the second movable electrode <b>34</b> and the second fixed electrode <b>35</b> becomes greater than zero so that a considerable reduction in the capacitance of the capacitors C<b>2</b><i>a</i>, C<b>2</b><i>b </i>can be prevented.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The driver <b>50</b> causes the first and second drive frames <b>11</b>, <b>31</b> to vibrate in the X-direction. The driver <b>50</b> includes a first driver <b>51</b> and a second driver <b>52</b>. The first driver <b>51</b> causes the first pair of supporting members <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>11</b><i>b </i>to vibrate. The second driver <b>52</b> causes the second pair of supporting members <b>31</b><i>a</i>, <b>31</b><i>b </i>to vibrate.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the first driver <b>51</b> has symmetry with respect to the line L<b>1</b>. The first driver <b>51</b> includes an extension <b>51</b><i>a</i>, a fifth tooth portion <b>51</b><i>b</i>, a beam <b>51</b><i>c</i>, an extension <b>51</b><i>d</i>, and a sixth tooth portion <b>51</b><i>e</i>. The extension <b>51</b><i>a </i>is joined to the weight <b>14</b> and extends in the Y-direction toward the second drive frame <b>31</b>. The fifth tooth portion <b>51</b><i>b </i>is joined to the extension <b>51</b><i>a </i>and extends in the X-direction toward the left of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The beam <b>51</b><i>c </i>is joined to the bottom <b>72</b> of the base <b>70</b> and extends in the X-direction. The extension <b>51</b><i>d </i>is joined to the beam <b>51</b><i>c </i>and extends in the Y-direction toward the wall <b>71</b>. The sixth tooth portion <b>51</b><i>e </i>is joined to the extension <b>51</b><i>d </i>and extends in the X-direction toward the right of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. Thus, the fifth tooth portion <b>51</b><i>b </i>and the sixth tooth portion <b>51</b><i>e </i>form comb electrodes.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the second driver <b>52</b> has symmetry with respect to the line L<b>1</b>. The second driver <b>52</b> includes an extension <b>52</b><i>a</i>, a seventh tooth portion <b>52</b><i>b</i>, a beam <b>52</b><i>c</i>, an extension <b>52</b><i>d</i>, and an eighth tooth portion <b>52</b><i>e</i>. The extension <b>52</b><i>a </i>is joined to the X-direction portion of the second drive frame <b>31</b> and extends in the Y-direction toward the weight <b>14</b>. The seventh tooth portion <b>52</b><i>b </i>is joined to the extension <b>52</b><i>a </i>and extends in the X-direction toward the left of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The beam <b>52</b><i>c </i>is joined to the bottom <b>72</b> of the base <b>70</b> and extends in the X-direction. The extension <b>52</b><i>d </i>is joined to the beam <b>52</b><i>c </i>and extends in the Y-direction toward the second drive frame <b>31</b>. The eighth tooth portion <b>52</b><i>e </i>is joined to the extension <b>52</b><i>d </i>and extends in the X-direction toward the right of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. Thus, the seventh tooth portion <b>52</b><i>b </i>and the eighth tooth portion <b>52</b><i>e </i>form comb electrodes. It is noted that the beam <b>51</b><i>c </i>is the same as the beam <b>52</b><i>c. </i></p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Assuming that a first drive voltage with a predetermined first frequency is applied to the first driver <b>51</b>, a polarity of electrostatic force produced between the tooth portions <b>51</b><i>b</i>, <b>51</b><i>e </i>changes at the first frequency. Due to the electrostatic force between the tooth portions <b>51</b><i>b</i>, <b>51</b><i>e</i>, the weight <b>14</b> joined to the extension <b>51</b><i>a </i>vibrates in the X-direction at the first frequency. Accordingly, the first drive frame <b>11</b> to which the weight <b>14</b> is joined vibrates in the X-direction at the first frequency.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Assuming that a second drive voltage with a predetermined second frequency is applied to the second driver <b>52</b>, a polarity of electrostatic force produced between the tooth portions <b>52</b><i>b</i>, <b>52</b><i>e </i>changes at the second frequency. Due to the electrostatic force between the tooth portions <b>52</b><i>b</i>, <b>52</b><i>e</i>, the second drive frame <b>31</b> to which the extension <b>52</b><i>a </i>is joined vibrates in the X-direction at the second frequency. Accordingly, the second movable electrode <b>34</b> that is joined to the second drive frame <b>31</b> through the fourth spring <b>33</b> vibrates in the X-direction at the second frequency.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">When the weight <b>14</b> vibrates in the X-direction, the vibration of the weight <b>14</b> is transmitted to the second drive frame <b>31</b> through the first drive frame <b>11</b> and the third spring <b>32</b>. Thus, each of the supporting members <b>31</b><i>a</i>, <b>31</b><i>b </i>vibrates in the X-direction. When the weight <b>14</b> is displaced in a first direction (i.e., left or right in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of the X-direction, the second drive frame <b>31</b> is displaced in the first direction by following the displacement of the weight <b>14</b>. Therefore, when drive voltages with opposite polarities are respectively applied to the first drivers <b>51</b>, the weights <b>14</b> vibrate in opposite phases in the X-direction so that the supporting members <b>31</b><i>a</i>, <b>31</b><i>b </i>can vibrate in opposite phases in the X-direction. In this case, the supporting members <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>11</b><i>b </i>also vibrate in opposite phases in the X-direction. In the embodiment, the drive voltages with opposite polarities are respectively applied to the first drivers <b>51</b>. In such an approach, the supporting members <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>11</b><i>b </i>vibrate in opposite phases in the X-direction so that the supporting members <b>31</b><i>a</i>, <b>31</b><i>b </i>can vibrate in opposite phases in the X-direction.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The second movable electrode <b>34</b> forming the capacitor C<b>2</b><i>a </i>and the second movable electrode <b>34</b> forming the capacitor C<b>2</b><i>b </i>vibrate in opposite phases in the X-direction. Therefore, a capacitance change of the capacitor C<b>2</b><i>a </i>due to the vibration caused by the second driver <b>52</b> becomes equal to a capacitance change of the capacitor C<b>2</b><i>b </i>due to the vibration caused by the second driver <b>52</b>. In other words, the capacitance change of the capacitor C<b>2</b><i>a </i>due to the displacement of the second movable electrode <b>34</b> in the X-direction becomes equal to the capacitance change of the capacitor C<b>2</b><i>b </i>due to the displacement of the second movable electrode <b>34</b> in the X-direction. Therefore, an output voltage of the capacitor C<b>2</b><i>a </i>can be compared with the an output voltage of the capacitor C<b>2</b><i>b </i>without taking into consideration the effect of the second driver <b>52</b>. In other words, there is no need to take into consider the capacitance change of the capacitors C<b>2</b><i>a</i>, C<b>2</b><i>b </i>due to the change in the facing area between the second movable electrode <b>34</b> and the second fixed electrode <b>35</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The sensor <b>100</b> detects an acceleration based on the following acceleration detection principle. When an acceleration is applied to the sensor <b>100</b> in the Y-direction under a condition that the supporting members <b>31</b><i>a</i>, <b>31</b><i>b </i>are caused to vibrate in opposite phases in the X-direction by the first driver <b>51</b>, the first movable electrode <b>12</b> forming the capacitor C<b>1</b><i>a </i>and the first movable electrode <b>12</b> forming the capacitor C<b>1</b><i>b </i>vibrate, along with the first movable electrode <b>12</b>, in the same phase in the Y-direction due to inertial force induced by the acceleration. As a result, the distance between the first movable electrode <b>12</b> and the first fixed electrode <b>13</b> changes so that the capacitance of the capacitors C<b>1</b><i>a</i>, C<b>1</b><i>b </i>can change. Since the amount of the capacitance change of the capacitors C<b>1</b><i>a</i>, C<b>1</b><i>b </i>is in proportion to the acceleration applied to the sensor <b>100</b>, the acceleration can be detected based on the amount of the capacitance change of the capacitors C<b>1</b><i>a</i>, C<b>1</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The sensor <b>100</b> detects an angular velocity based on the following angular velocity principle. When an acceleration is applied to the sensor <b>100</b> in a Z-direction under a condition that the supporting members <b>31</b><i>a</i>, <b>31</b><i>b </i>are caused to vibrate in opposite phases in the X-direction by the first and second drivers <b>51</b>, <b>52</b>, Coriolis force in the Y-direction acts on the supporting members <b>31</b><i>a</i>, <b>31</b><i>b</i>, and the second movable electrode <b>34</b> that is connected through the fourth spring <b>33</b> to the supporting members <b>31</b><i>a</i>, <b>31</b><i>b</i>. The Coriolis force is in proportion to the vibration speed and the angular velocity. As described above, since the second movable electrode <b>34</b> forming the capacitor C<b>2</b><i>a </i>and the second movable electrode <b>34</b> forming the capacitor C<b>2</b><i>b </i>vibrate in opposite phases in the X-direction, the Coriolis force acting on the second movable electrode <b>34</b> forming the capacitor C<b>2</b><i>a </i>is opposite to the Coriolis force acting on the second movable electrode <b>34</b> forming the capacitor C<b>2</b><i>b </i>in the Y-direction. Accordingly, the second movable electrode <b>34</b> forming the capacitor C<b>2</b><i>a </i>and the second movable electrode <b>34</b> forming the capacitor C<b>2</b><i>b </i>are displaced in opposite directions along the Y-direction. As a result, the distance between the second movable electrode <b>34</b> and the second fixed electrode <b>35</b> changes so that the capacitance of the capacitors C<b>2</b><i>a</i>, C<b>2</b><i>b </i>can change. Since the amount of the capacitance change of the capacitors C<b>2</b><i>a</i>, C<b>2</b><i>b </i>is in proportion to the angular velocity applied to the sensor <b>100</b>, the angular velocity can be detected based on the amount of the capacitance change of the capacitors C<b>2</b><i>a</i>, C<b>2</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">As described above, according to the embodiment of the present invention, the first movable electrode <b>12</b> is supported by the first pair of the supporting members <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>11</b><i>b</i>. The supporting members <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>11</b><i>b </i>are coupled together by the first spring <b>11</b><i>c </i>having elasticity in the Y-direction. Each of the supporting members <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>11</b><i>b </i>is coupled to the wall <b>71</b> of the base <b>70</b> by the second spring <b>15</b> having elasticity in both the X-direction and the Y-direction. Thus, a structural resonance of the acceleration detector <b>10</b> depends on the first spring <b>11</b><i>c </i>and the second spring <b>15</b>, each of which has elasticity in the Y-direction as a detection direction.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In contrast, the second pair of supporting members <b>31</b><i>a</i>, <b>31</b><i>b </i>are coupled to the first pair of the supporting members <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>11</b><i>b </i>by the third spring <b>32</b> having elasticity in both the X-direction and the Y-direction. Further, the second pair of the supporting members <b>31</b><i>a</i>, <b>31</b><i>b </i>is coupled to the second movable electrode <b>34</b> by the fourth spring <b>33</b> having elasticity in the Y-direction. Thus, a structural resonance of the angular velocity detector <b>30</b> depends on the third spring <b>32</b> and the fourth spring <b>33</b>, each of which has elasticity in the Y-direction.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In summary, the structural resonance of the angular velocity detector <b>30</b> and the structural resonance of the angular velocity detector <b>30</b> are separated from each other. Therefore, the structural resonance of the angular velocity detector <b>30</b> and the structural resonance of the angular velocity detector <b>30</b> can be separately determined by adjusting spring constants of the first spring <b>11</b><i>c</i>, the second spring <b>15</b>, the third spring <b>32</b>, and the fourth spring <b>33</b>. For example, increasing the spring constants of the first spring <b>11</b><i>c </i>and the spring <b>15</b><i>b </i>of the second spring <b>15</b> can prevent a reduction in sensitivity characteristics of the acceleration detector <b>10</b>, and decreasing the spring constants of the third spring <b>32</b> and the fourth spring <b>33</b> can prevent a reduction in impact resistance of the angular velocity detector <b>30</b>. Therefore, the sensor <b>100</b> can be configured in such a manner that the acceleration detector <b>10</b> has a suitable sensitivity characteristics and that the angular velocity detector <b>30</b> has a suitable impact resistance.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Specifically, it is noted that the structural resonance of the angular velocity detector <b>30</b> depends on not only the spring constants of the third and fourth springs <b>32</b>, <b>33</b> but also the spring constant of the second spring <b>15</b>. However, the structural resonance of the angular velocity detector <b>30</b> and the structural resonance of the angular velocity detector <b>30</b> can be separated from each other by adjusting the spring constants of the third and fourth springs <b>32</b>, <b>33</b>. Further, as mentioned previously, since the second spring <b>15</b> mainly distributes to the displacement of the first drive frame <b>11</b> in the Y-direction, the contribution of the second spring <b>15</b> to the displacement of the second movable electrode <b>34</b> in the Y-direction is small enough to be negligible.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">According to the embodiment, the second movable electrode <b>34</b> of the angular velocity detector <b>30</b> is joined to the wall <b>71</b> of the base <b>70</b> through the fourth spring <b>33</b>, the second drive frame <b>31</b>, the third spring <b>32</b>, the first drive frame <b>11</b>, and the second spring <b>15</b>. Thus, external stress applied to the base <b>70</b> is damped by the fourth spring <b>33</b>, the second drive frame <b>31</b>, the third spring <b>32</b>, the first drive frame <b>11</b>, and the second spring <b>15</b> before reaching the second movable electrode <b>34</b>. For this reason, in particular, regarding angular velocity, the reduction in the impact resistance can be prevented.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">According to the embodiment, the first movable electrode <b>12</b> has the first tooth portion <b>12</b><i>a</i>, and the first fixed electrode <b>13</b> has the second tooth portion <b>13</b><i>a </i>forming comb-electrodes with the first tooth portion <b>12</b><i>a</i>. Thus, the facing area between the first movable electrode <b>12</b> and the first fixed electrode <b>13</b> can be increased compared to a case where the first movable electrode <b>12</b> and the first fixed electrode <b>13</b> are plate electrodes.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">According to the embodiment, the second movable electrode <b>34</b> has the third tooth portion <b>34</b><i>b</i>, and the second fixed electrode <b>35</b> has the fourth tooth portion <b>35</b><i>b </i>forming comb-electrodes with the third tooth portion <b>34</b><i>b</i>. Thus, the facing area between the second movable electrode <b>34</b> and the second fixed electrode <b>35</b> can be increased compared to a case where the second movable electrode <b>34</b> and the second fixed electrode <b>35</b> are plate electrodes.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">(Modification)</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The embodiment described above can be modified in various ways, for example, as follows.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">In the embodiment, the second pair of supporting members <b>31</b><i>a</i>, <b>31</b><i>b </i>are arranged symmetrically with respect to the line L<b>1</b> in the Y-direction. Alternatively, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the second pair of supporting members <b>31</b><i>a</i>, <b>31</b><i>b </i>can be arranged symmetrically with respect to a line L<b>2</b> in the X-direction. The line L<b>2</b> is parallel to the Y-direction. That is, whereas the sensor <b>100</b> according to the embodiment has symmetry with respect to the line L<b>1</b>, the sensor <b>100</b> according to the modification shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> has symmetry with respect to the line L<b>2</b>. In the modification shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the second pair of supporting members <b>31</b><i>a</i>, <b>31</b><i>b </i>are coupled together by a fifth spring <b>36</b> having elasticity in the X-direction and thus can vibrate in a coupled manner in the X-direction.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In the embodiment, the first movable electrode <b>12</b> has the first tooth portion <b>12</b><i>a</i>. That is, the first movable electrode <b>12</b> has a comb-shape. Alternatively, the first movable electrode <b>12</b> can have a shape other than a comb-shape. For example, the first movable electrode <b>12</b> can have a plate-shape.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In the embodiment, the first fixed electrode <b>13</b> has the second tooth portion <b>13</b><i>a</i>. That is, the first fixed electrode <b>13</b> has a comb-shape. Alternatively, the first fixed electrode <b>13</b> can have a shape other than a comb-shape. For example, the first fixed electrode <b>13</b> can have a plate-shape.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">In the embodiment, the second movable electrode <b>34</b> has the detection frame <b>34</b><i>a </i>and the third tooth portion <b>34</b><i>b</i>. That is, the second movable electrode <b>34</b> has a comb-shape. Alternatively, the second movable electrode <b>34</b> can have a shape other than a comb-shape. For example, the second movable electrode <b>34</b> can have a plate-shape.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">In the embodiment, the second fixed electrode <b>35</b> has the extension <b>35</b><i>a </i>and the fourth tooth portion <b>35</b><i>b</i>. That is, the second fixed electrode <b>35</b> has a comb-shape. Alternatively, the second fixed electrode <b>35</b> can have a shape other than a comb-shape. For example, the second fixed electrode <b>35</b> can have a plate-shape.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">In the embodiment, the first driver <b>51</b> includes the extension <b>51</b><i>a</i>, the fifth tooth portion <b>51</b><i>b</i>, the beam <b>51</b><i>c</i>, the extension <b>51</b><i>d</i>, and the sixth tooth portion <b>51</b><i>e</i>. That is, the first driver <b>51</b> has a comb-shape. Alternatively, the first driver <b>51</b> can have a shape other than a comb-shape. For example, the first driver <b>51</b> can have a plate-shape.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">In the embodiment, the second driver <b>52</b> includes the extension <b>52</b><i>a</i>, the seventh tooth portion <b>52</b><i>b</i>, the beam <b>52</b><i>c</i>, the extension <b>52</b><i>d</i>, and the eighth tooth portion <b>52</b><i>e</i>. That is, the second driver <b>52</b> has a comb-shape. Alternatively, the second driver <b>52</b> can have a shape other than a comb-shape. For example, the second driver <b>52</b> can have a plate-shape.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In the embodiment, the first and second drivers <b>51</b>, <b>52</b> cause the first and second frames <b>11</b>, <b>31</b> to vibrate by electrostatic force. Alternatively, the first and second drivers <b>51</b>, <b>52</b> can cause the first and second frames <b>11</b>, <b>31</b> to vibrate by force other than electrostatic force. For example, the first and second drivers <b>51</b>, <b>52</b> can cause the first and second frames <b>11</b>, <b>31</b> to vibrate by electromagnetic force.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Such changes and modifications are to be understood as being within the scope of the present invention as defined by the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A sensor for detecting acceleration and angular velocity, the sensor comprising:
<claim-text>a base;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an acceleration detector including a pair of first fixed electrodes, a pair of first movable electrodes, and a pair of first supporting members configured to support the pair of first movable electrodes;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an angular velocity detector including a pair of second fixed electrodes, a pair of second movable electrodes, and a pair of second supporting members configured to support the pair of second movable electrodes;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a driver configured to cause the pair of first supporting members to vibrate in opposite phases in a first direction and configured to cause the pair of second supporting members to vibrate in opposite phases in the first direction by electrostatic force;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first spring having elasticity in the first direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second spring configured to couple the pair of first supporting members to the base, the second spring having elasticity in both the first direction and a second direction perpendicular to the first direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third spring configured to couple the pair of first supporting members to the pair of second supporting members, the third spring having elasticity in both the first direction and the second direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth spring configured to couple the pair of second supporting members to the pair of second movable electrodes, the fourth spring having elasticity in the second direction; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fifth spring configured to couple the pair of second supporting members together, the fifth spring having elasticity in the first direction, wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the pair of first supporting members are arranged in the first direction and coupled together by the first spring,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the pair of first movable electrodes is located to face the pair of first fixed electrodes in the second direction to form a first capacitor therebetween,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the pair of second supporting members is located in a region surrounded by the pair of first supporting members,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the pair of second movable electrodes is located to face the pair of second fixed electrodes in the second direction to form a second capacitor therebetween,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the acceleration detector detects the acceleration in the second direction based on a change in a capacitance of the first capacitor due to inertial force,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the angular velocity detector detects the angular velocity in a third direction perpendicular to each of the first and second directions based on a change in a capacitance of the second capacitor due to inertial force.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The sensor according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>each of the pair of first fixed electrodes and the pair of first movable electrodes has a comb-shape.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The sensor according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>each of the pair of second fixed electrodes and the pair of second movable electrodes has a comb-shape.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The sensor according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the driver includes a comb electrode.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The sensor according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the driver uses electromagnetic force to cause the pair of first supporting members to vibrate in opposite phases in the first direction and to cause the pair of second supporting members to vibrate in opposite phases in the first direction.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The sensor according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the driver includes a first driver and a second driver,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first driver causes the pair of first supporting members to vibrate in opposite phases in the first direction by electrostatic force, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second driver causes the pair of second supporting members to vibrate in opposite phases in the first direction by electrostatic force.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The sensor according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the base is a semiconductor substrate, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the acceleration detector, the angular velocity detector, and the driver are integrated on the semiconductor substrate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The sensor according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the pair of first supporting members has a rectangular C-shape.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The sensor according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the pair of second supporting members has a rectangular ring shape.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The sensor according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the pair of second supporting members is located in a region surrounded by the pair of first supporting members, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the pair of second movable electrodes is located in a region surrounded by the pair of second supporting members.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The sensor according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the pair of first supporting members are coupled together by the first spring in the first direction.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
