<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08621885-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08621885</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13199088</doc-number>
<date>20110818</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>244</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>25</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>08</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 624574</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Single beverage freezable container</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4002235</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Donnelly</name>
<date>19770100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>206219</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4163374</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Moore et al.</name>
<date>19790800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4870837</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Weins</name>
<date>19891000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 624574</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4955497</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Winden et al.</name>
<date>19900900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4974741</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Gustafson et al.</name>
<date>19901200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5390804</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Beggins</name>
<date>19950200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5605242</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hwang</name>
<date>19970200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>220  8</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6123220</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Williams</name>
<date>20000900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6398061</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Duff et al.</name>
<date>20020600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6554155</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Beggins</name>
<date>20030400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>220739</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6604649</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Campi</name>
<date>20030800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6814252</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Murakami et al.</name>
<date>20041100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>220739</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7201285</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Beggins</name>
<date>20070400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7614516</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Beggins</name>
<date>20091100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00015">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8365941</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Mayer</name>
<date>20130200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2202593</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>10</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 624571</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 624573</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 624574</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 624575</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 62371</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 62530</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>61401776</doc-number>
<date>20100819</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Niebolte</last-name>
<first-name>Eric P.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Highlands Ranch</city>
<state>CO</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Niebolte</last-name>
<first-name>Eric P.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Highlands Ranch</city>
<state>CO</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Pizarro</last-name>
<first-name>Ramon L.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Crabtree</last-name>
<first-name>Edwin H.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Jones</last-name>
<first-name>Melvin</first-name>
<department>3744</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A container for accepting and retaining bottles or cans for the purpose of insulating or bringing them to a desired temperature range is disclosed. A preferred embodiment includes a hollow upper section with an internal cylindrical portion that has an upper edge. The upper section includes an internal frusto-conical section with a slotted aperture that commences from the cylindrical portion and extends away from the cylindrical portion. The device also includes a hollow base section that is adapted for engaging the upper section. The arrangement accommodates cans as well as bottles, and allows drinking from either type of container while retaining the container.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="158.92mm" wi="156.13mm" file="US08621885-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="268.39mm" wi="196.17mm" file="US08621885-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="246.63mm" wi="166.45mm" file="US08621885-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of my provisional application having Ser. No. 61/401,776, filed Aug. 19, 2010, now abandoned.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">(a) Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">This application relates to a system and device for retaining and cooling a beverage container, and more particularly, but without limitation, to a reusable container holder that is designed to be cooled and then used to cool a beverage container retained within the device.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">(b) Discussion of Known Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The need to cool or retain a beverage container, such as a beverage bottle or can, is well recognized. However, solutions for this problem have resulted in designs that provide significant compromises. For instance, devices that are used solely to insulate the beverage container do not provide the ability to also chill or heat the contents of the beverage container, if chilling or heating is desired. Devices that provide chilling capability, such as the device disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 4,163,374 to Moore et al. lack the ability to accommodate both bottled and canned beverages, and thus provide limited versatility and utility. There is a need for a device or system that can be used to get canned or bottled beverages to a desired temperature range, and keep the beverage within the bottle or can at the desired temperature range.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Another example is disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 6,604,549 to Campi discloses a device made of foamed plastic that can accommodate cans by using a &#x201c;puck-shaped&#x201d; lid, and can then be modified to accommodate long neck bottles by replacing the puck-shaped lid with a lid that follows the shape of the top of a long-neck bottle. Immediately apparent shortcomings of this approach is that the user must carry and store different types of lids for different types of containers, depending if one will be using the device with a can or a bottle.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">An approach at alleviating the problems associated with the Moore et al. and the Campi type of devices is found in U.S. Pat. No. 6,814,252 to Murakami et al., which uses an extendible, flexible, frusto-conical section to accommodate the neck portion of a bottle. The frusto-conical section includes a pair of opposed stretch panels to accommodate various shapes of bottles.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Therefore, a review of known devices reveals that there remains a need for a container that can be used to keep bottled or canned beverages at a desired temperature range without having to modify the container to allow use of the device with a can or with a bottle, or whether it is used to hold a long-neck beer bottle or a feeding bottle for an infant.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">It has been discovered that the problems left unanswered by known art can be solved by providing a container for accepting and retaining bottles or cans for the purpose of insulating or bringing them to a desired temperature range, and which in a preferred embodiment includes:</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">A hollow upper section having an internal cylindrical portion that has an upper edge and a lower edge; the upper section also having an internal frusto-conical section that extends from the cylindrical portion, the frusto-conical section having a slotted aperture that commences from the cylindrical portion and extends away from the cylindrical portion, the cylindrical portion also having a threaded portion next to the lower edge; and</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">A hollow base section, the base section having a base threaded portion that is adapted for engaging the threaded portion of the upper section.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to a highly preferred embodiment of the invention the hollow upper section and the hollow base section are filled with a liquid or fluidized material such as a &#x201c;freezer gel&#x201d;, which is commonly hydroxyethyl cellulose, or a polymer, or silica coated with vinyl, or other similar material with a high enthalpy of fusion. Thus the hollow upper section and the hollow base section will both be hollow shells or sections that are filled with freezer gel.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">It should also be understood that while the above and other advantages and results of the present invention will become apparent to those skilled in the art from the following detailed description and accompanying drawings, showing the contemplated novel construction, combinations and elements as herein described, and more particularly defined by the appended claims, it should be clearly understood that changes in the precise embodiments of the herein disclosed invention are meant to be included within the scope of the claims, except insofar as they may be precluded by the prior art.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The accompanying drawings illustrate preferred embodiments of the present invention according to the best mode presently devised for making and using the instant invention, and in which:</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of an embodiment of the disclosed invention while retaining a canned beverage, and also illustrates the outline of the positioning of a long-necked bottle when retained within the disclosed invention.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exploded view of the components used to make the he hollow upper section and the hollow base section. The internal freezer gel material has been omitted from the view.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is section view illustrating the fitment of the components illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, and illustrating the nesting of the domed lower portion of the hollow base section and the domed recess commonly found in the bottom of bottles and cans.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EXEMPLAR EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">While the invention will be described and disclosed here in connection with certain preferred embodiments, the description is not intended to limit the invention to the specific embodiments shown and described here, but rather the invention is intended to cover all alternative embodiments and modifications that fall within the spirit and scope of the invention as defined by the claims included herein as well as any equivalents of the disclosed and claimed invention.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Attention is now directed to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> where a preferred embodiment of the disclosed freezable container holder <b>10</b>, which is designed for retaining a single beverage container <b>12</b>, such as a bottle <b>13</b> or can <b>15</b>, has been illustrated. The container holder <b>10</b> includes a hollow upper section <b>14</b> that has an internal cylindrical portion <b>16</b>. The internal cylindrical portion <b>16</b> has an upper edge <b>18</b> and a lower edge <b>14</b>. Additionally, the upper section <b>14</b> also includes an internal frusto-conical section <b>20</b>, which while preferably being frusto-conical, may also be generally conical or shaped so as to accept the shape of a longneck type bottle.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">As can be understood from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 3</figref>, the frusto-conical section <b>20</b> extends from the internal cylindrical portion <b>16</b>, and preferably includes a slotted aperture <b>22</b> that extends through the frusto-conical section <b>20</b> and commences from a location that is at or next to the cylindrical portion and extends away from the cylindrical portion. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> also makes it clear that, in a preferred embodiment of the invention, the cylindrical portion <b>16</b> includes a threaded portion <b>24</b> next to the lower edge <b>21</b>. It is important to note that while threads have been illustrated as being the preferred embodiment, it is also contemplated that slotted engagement mechanisms may also be used.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The threaded portion <b>24</b> of the hollow upper section <b>14</b> cooperates with a hollow base section <b>26</b> to capture or enclose the beverage container <b>12</b> between the two sections. The hollow base section <b>26</b> includes a base threaded portion <b>28</b> that is adapted for engaging the threaded portion <b>24</b> of the hollow upper section <b>14</b>. The use of threads adds adjustability to the disclosed system in that turning the upper section <b>14</b> relative to the hollow base section <b>26</b> allows adjustment of the overall length of the disclosed invention in order to accommodate variations in length or shapes of cans of bottles that are to be retained by the disclosed invention.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, it will be understood that the hollow base section <b>26</b> is preferably made up from a base shell section <b>29</b> that has a horizontal base portion <b>30</b> that includes a perimeter <b>32</b>, which may be a flat-ring shape or curved section, and a base domed section <b>34</b>. The base shell section <b>28</b> of the hollow base section <b>26</b> also includes a wall portion <b>36</b> that extends up from the perimeter <b>32</b> and around the base domed section <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref> also show that the hollow base section <b>26</b> also preferably includes a base inner sleeve <b>37</b>. The illustrated preferred example of the base inner sleeve <b>37</b> includes a generally domed bottom section <b>38</b> that is at a distance or spaced apart from the base domed section <b>34</b>. Additionally, the base inner sleeve <b>37</b> includes a base inner wall <b>40</b> that extends up from the generally domed bottom section <b>38</b> and ends in the base threaded portion <b>28</b>. A base sealing wall <b>42</b> that extends from the base inner wall <b>40</b> to the wall portion <b>36</b> of the base shell section <b>29</b> when the base inner sleeve <b>37</b> is inserted into the base shell section <b>29</b>. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the generally domed bottom section <b>38</b> is adapted for engaging the recess <b>44</b> commonly found on the bottom of the bottle or can, which is the single beverage container. Thus, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the base domed section <b>34</b> adapted for extending into the generally domed bottom section <b>38</b> when the base sealing wall <b>42</b> is in contact with the wall portion <b>36</b> of the base shell section <b>29</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Thus, it will be understood that the hollow upper section <b>14</b> and the hollow base section <b>26</b> may be filled with a liquid <b>44</b> or fluidized material such as a &#x201c;freezer gel&#x201d;, which is commonly hydroxyethyl cellulose, or a polymer, or silica coated with vinyl, or other similar material that may be frozen so that the disclosed invention may be used to cool the bottle <b>13</b> or can <b>15</b> retained by the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Thus it can be appreciated that the above-described embodiments are illustrative of just a few of the numerous variations of arrangements of the disclosed elements used to carry out the disclosed invention. Moreover, while the invention has been particularly shown, described and illustrated in detail with reference to preferred embodiments and modifications thereof, it should be understood that the foregoing and other modifications are exemplary only, and that equivalent changes in form and detail may be made without departing from the true spirit and scope of the invention as claimed, except as precluded by the prior art.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A single beverage container holder comprising:
<claim-text>A hollow upper section having an internal cylindrical portion that has an upper edge and a lower edge, the upper section further comprising an internal frusto-conical section that extends from the cylindrical portion, the frusto-conical section having a slotted aperture that extends through the frusto-conical section and commences from a location next to the cylindrical portion and extends away from the cylindrical portion, the cylindrical portion also having a threaded portion next to the lower edge; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>A hollow base section, the base section having a base threaded portion that is adapted for engaging the threaded portion of the upper section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A single beverage container holder according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said hollow base section comprises a base shell section having a horizontal base portion having a perimeter, and a wall portion that extends up from the perimeter; and
<claim-text>a base inner sleeve, the base inner sleeve having a generally domed bottom section and a base inner wall that extends up from the generally domed bottom section and terminating in the base threaded portion, and a base sealing wall that extends from the base inner wall to the wall portion of the base shell section, the generally domed bottom section being adapted for engaging the single beverage.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A single beverage container holder according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> wherein said horizontal base portion of the base shell section includes a shell domed section that is adapted for extending into the generally domed bottom section when the base sealing wall is in contact with the wall portion of the base shell section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A single beverage container holder according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref> wherein said hollow upper section and said hollow base section are filled with a fluid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A single beverage container holder according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref> wherein the hollow base section and the hollow upper section are filled with a liquid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A container holder for retaining a single beverage container having a domed base, the container holder comprising:
<claim-text>A hollow upper section having an internal cylindrical portion that has an upper edge and a lower edge, the upper section further comprising an internal frusto-conical section that extends from the cylindrical portion, the frusto-conical section having a slotted aperture that extends through the frusto-conical section and commences from a location next to the cylindrical portion and extends away from the cylindrical portion, the cylindrical portion also having a threaded portion next to the lower edge; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>A hollow base section, the base section having a base threaded portion that is adapted for engaging the threaded portion of the upper section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A single beverage container holder according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> wherein said hollow base section comprises a base shell section having a horizontal base portion having having a perimeter and a base domed section, and a wall portion that extends up from the perimeter and around the base domed section; and
<claim-text>a base inner sleeve, the base inner sleeve having a generally domed bottom section that is at a distance from the base domed section, and a base inner wall that extends up from the generally domed bottom section and terminating in the base threaded portion, and a base sealing wall that extends from the base inner wall to the wall portion of the base shell section, the generally domed bottom section being adapted for engaging the single beverage.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A single beverage container holder according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref> wherein said horizontal base portion of the base shell section includes a shell domed section that is adapted for extending into the generally domed bottom section when the base sealing wall is in contact with the wall portion of the base shell section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A single beverage container holder comprising:
<claim-text>a hollow upper section having an internal cylindrical portion that has an upper edge and a lower edge, the upper section further comprising an internal frusto-conical section that extends from the cylindrical portion, the frusto-conical section having a slotted aperture that extends through the frusto-conical section and commences from a location next to the cylindrical portion and extends away from the cylindrical portion, the cylindrical portion also having a threaded portion next to the lower edge; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a hollow base section, the base section having a base domed section and a base threaded portion that is adapted for engaging the threaded portion of the upper section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A single beverage container holder according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref> wherein the hollow base section and the hollow upper section are filled with a liquid. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
