<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622642-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622642</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12911926</doc-number>
<date>20101026</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>580</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>43</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>16</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>401108</main-classification>
<further-classification>401107</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">One hand lip stick</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2386417</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Apfelbaum</name>
<date>19451000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2486073</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Dann</name>
<date>19491000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2513830</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Voegeli</name>
<date>19500700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2644577</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Orenick</name>
<date>19530700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3612072</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Fukui</name>
<date>19711000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3617138</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Fukui</name>
<date>19711100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4973178</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kakuta et al.</name>
<date>19901100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5171096</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Perrotti</name>
<date>19921200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5423622</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Perrotti</name>
<date>19950600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5890826</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kim</name>
<date>19990400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5904431</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Terruzzi</name>
<date>19990500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5979468</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Blake, III</name>
<date>19991100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6056465</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kuo</name>
<date>20000500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6588959</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Kuo</name>
<date>20030700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>401108</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00015">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8152398</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kim et al.</name>
<date>20120400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>401108</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>18</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>401107</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>401108</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120099916</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120426</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Tae Jin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Middletown</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Tae Jin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Middletown</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>LRK Patent Law Firm</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Walczak</last-name>
<first-name>David</first-name>
<department>3751</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A one hand lipstick container includes: a container main body having a cylinder standing at the center of a body and a center through-hole; a container cover rotatably connected to the upper portion of the container main body and having an open inlet; a cover holder combined by a spiral with the outer side of the cylinder of the container main body and vertically moving up/down by rotational force of the container cover; a door hinged to the cover holder to open/close the upper portion of the cover holder; a lipstick housing combined by a spiral with the inner side of the center through-hole of the container main body and vertically moved up/down by rotational force of the cover holder; and a vertical guide transmitting the rotational force of the cover holder to the lipstick housing and vertically guiding the lipstick housing to move up/down.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="201.34mm" wi="180.17mm" file="US08622642-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="226.82mm" wi="190.75mm" file="US08622642-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="215.98mm" wi="132.84mm" file="US08622642-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="202.35mm" wi="131.49mm" file="US08622642-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="218.69mm" wi="162.81mm" file="US08622642-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="194.14mm" wi="151.89mm" file="US08622642-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="224.11mm" wi="137.58mm" file="US08622642-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a lipstick container, in detail, a one hand lipstick container that can be used by one hand.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In general, lipsticks are necessities that most women carry. Although most women put on a lipstick in the house to go outside, they put on a lipstick at the outside also in many cases. Therefore, lipsticks should be easy to carry and use.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Containers for the lipsticks are formed such that a container main body and a container cover are separated, such that users had to use the lipstick with one hand while holding the container cover with other hand.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The structure of existing lipstick containers known in the art is described below.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Lipstick containers are composed of a cylinder with a vertical groove standing in a container main body, a lipstick holder inserted in the container main body, an outer container surrounding the outer side of the cylinder in the container main body, and a cover have been widely known.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The lipstick containers of the related art are beautiful because there is no protrusion on the container containing the lipstick, give elegant feeling because they turn, and can make it possible to reduce the manufacturing cost and time because the number of parts is small; however, it is necessary to use both hands to open the cap and turn the lower portion of the containers.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Further, the lipstick containers in the related art have a problem in that the lipstick is mashed and cannot be used, when the cover is closed, with the lipstick not fully inserted in the container.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Researches for developing a lipstick container that can be used by one hand have been conducted to increase portability and convenience of the lipstick container.</p>
<p id="h-0002" num="0000">As a related art having the above object, there is a lipstick container that is operated by rotating the container main body, without using a cap, which is as follows.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">First, a lipstick container including a plate covering the upper portion of the container and a device opening the plate has been proposed (U.S. Pat. No. 6,056,465). However, the above relate art has a problem in that it is not good in appearance because the plate remains on the outer side of the container when the plate opens an opening.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Further, although other technologies for inserting plates in containers have been know in the related art, there are problems in that the external appearance is deteriorated by a portion of a plate protruding outside (U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,423,622, 2,386,417, 5,979,468, 2,486,073, 3,617,138, and 3,612,072), a plate is made of a flexible material, such that stability is reduced (U.S. Pat. Nos. 2,644,577, 5,890,826, and 5,904,431), it is difficult to produce and assemble in large quantities due to too many parts, or there is high probability that defective products will be made in assemblage (U.S. Pat. No. 5,171,096).</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Further, a technology that uses a protrusion for operation, such as a handle, outside the container main body (U.S. Pat. Nos. 2,513,830 and 4,973,178). Since these technologies in the related art use new methods for users, not the existing methods, there is a problem in that these may repel consumers or give them inconvenience.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In order to overcome the above problems, it is an object of the present invention to provide a one hand lipstick container that can be easily operated and used by one hand.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">It is another object of the present invention to provide a one-hand lipstick container that can be designed to have an elegant external appearance by assembling all the part in a container cover and a container main body such that the parts are not exposed to the outside.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">It is another object of the present invention to provide a one-hand lipstick container that can be used by rotating the container main body, similar to existing lipstick containers.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">It is another object of the present invention to provide a one-hand lipstick container in which the height of the container main body is optimized such that a user can take all action with the lipstick container in one hand.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">An aspect of the present invention provides a one hand lipstick container in which wherein an inner spiral guide groove and an outer spiral guide groove are formed at a cylinder of a container main body, in opposite directions, a lipstick housing is disposed to move up/down along the inner spiral guide groove when the container main body rotates, and a door is opened or closed by up-down movement in the opposite direction to the lipstick housing along the outer spiral guide groove.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Another aspect of the present invention provides a one hand lipstick container including: a container body having a cylinder standing at the center of a body and a center through-hole formed through the center of the cylinder; a container cover rotatably connected to the upper portion of the container main body and having an open inlet formed through the top; a vertical guide having a fixed end combined with the upper portion of the container cover and a pipe extending down to be rotatably fitted in the center through-hole of the container main body; a lipstick housing inserted in the pipe of the vertical guide and vertically moving up/down along a slide guide formed in the pipe; a cover holder disposed between one side of the fixed end of the vertical guide and the inner side of the container to vertically slide and vertically moving up/down along the outer spiral guide groove on the cylinder of the container main body; and a door hinged to the upper end of the cover holder and operating with the up-down movement to open/close the inlet of the container cover.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The container main body may have the outer spiral guide groove on the outer side of the cylinder such that the cover holder spirally rotates and moves up/down and the inner spiral guide groove on the inner side of the cylinder such that the lipstick housing spirally rotates and moves up/down.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Further, the container cover rotatably may be connected to the upper portion of the container cover and have the inlet open at the top and a door guide groove guiding a top close path of the door operating with up-down movement of the cover holder, in the inner side</p>
<p id="h-0004" num="0000">Further, the vertical guide may have a pipe fitted in the center through-hole of the container main body and a fixed end extending from the top of the pipe to be combined with the container cover, with the cover holder movable up/down on one side.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The pipe may have a slide groove formed vertically long at one side to guide the guide protrusion of the lipstick container.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Further, the lipstick housing may have a cylindrical housing body where a lipstick is received, and a guide protrusion may be formed on the outer side of the housing body to be spirally inserted in the inner spiral guide groove</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Further, the cover holder may have a base plate being in contact with one side of the fixed end of the vertical guide to slide up/down, a pipe-fitting portion extending in a ring shape from the lower end of the base plate to cover the outer side of the cylinder of the container main body, a door hinge portion formed at the upper end of the base plate such that the door is hinged, and an outer rotational protrusion formed on the inner side of the lower end of the base plate to be spiral-combined with the outer spiral guide groove of the cylinder.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Further, the door has one end hinged to a door hinge portion of the cover holder and the other end fitted between a door guide groove on the inner side of the container cover and a door guide groove at the vertical guide, to be guided along an open path.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Further, the inner spiral guide groove and the outer spiral guide groove may be formed in the opposite directions on the cylinder of the container main body.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Further, the pitch of an outer spiral guide groove formed on the outer side of the cylinder of the container main body may not be uniform.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The pitch of the outer spiral guide groove may be formed wide at an upper section and relatively narrow at a lower section</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Further, a cylinder member may be provided to cover the lipstick housing and move up/down before the lipstick housing moves up/down.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">A guide protrusion inserted in the inner spiral guide groove of the cylinder of the container main body may be formed at the lower end of the cylinder member and a protrusion groove where the guide protrusion of the lipstick housing is inserted may be formed under the guide protrusion</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The present invention having the configurations described above makes it possible to use the lipstick container with one hand, such that the use is simple and a good appearance is provided.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Further, since all the parts are assembled in the container cover and the container main body and the parts are not exposed to the outside, it is possible to make the external appearance of the lipstick container in an elegant design. In addition, since the lipstick container is used by turning the container main body, similar to existing lipstick containers, users can familiarly use it, without strangeness.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Further, according to the present invention, by optimizing the height of the container main body such that a user can take all action with the lipstick container in one hand, it is possible to easily rotate the container cover with fingers while gripping the container main body with the palm, such that the use is convenient.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Further, the container main body and the container cover of the lipstick container of the present invention can be made of high-strength synthetic resin, metal, or ceramic, and when it is made of metal, such as aluminum, it is possible to achieve a high-quality product due to the peculiar metallic luster and the textural expression. Further, since it is possible to reduce the thickness of the parts, it is possible to reduce the entire size of the product and implement more refined product image.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an exploded perspective view of a one hand lipstick container according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</figref> are front views of the container main body of the one hand lipstick container according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view showing the vertical guide of the one hand lipstick container according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a perspective view showing the door and the cover holder of the one hand lipstick container according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective view showing an installation structure of the cylinder member of the one hand lipstick container according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Exemplary embodiments of the present invention are described hereafter in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an exploded perspective view of a one hand lipstick container according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a one hand lipstick container according to an embodiment of the present invention includes a container main body <b>110</b>, a container cover <b>120</b>, a cover holder <b>130</b>, a door <b>140</b>, a lipstick housing <b>150</b>, and a vertical guide <b>160</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The container main body <b>110</b> is described first in detail hereafter.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In the container main body <b>110</b>, a cylinder <b>113</b> stands at the center of a body <b>111</b> and a center through-hole <b>115</b> is formed through the center of the cylinder <b>113</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The body <b>111</b> supporting the cylinder <b>113</b> may be formed in various shapes and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a cylindrical shape as an example.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Further, it is possible to improve the aesthetic appearance of the body <b>111</b> by combining a case <b>119</b> made of a specific material.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</figref> are front views of the container main body of the one hand lipstick container according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, the cylinder <b>113</b> has an outer spiral guide groove <b>114</b>, in which the outer spiral guide groove <b>114</b> guides the cover holder <b>130</b>, which is combined by a spiral, to rotate upward/downward.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>, the center through-hole <b>115</b> in the cylinder <b>113</b> is connected to the bottom of the body <b>111</b> and has an inner spiral guide groove <b>116</b>, in which the inner spiral guide groove <b>116</b> guides the lipstick housing <b>150</b> (described below) which is combined by a spiral, to rotate upward/downward.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In this configuration, the center through-hole <b>115</b> of the container main body <b>110</b> is an integral through-hole having the same inner diameter from the top of the cylinder <b>113</b> to the bottom of the body <b>111</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The container cover <b>120</b> is described in detail hereafter.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the container cover <b>120</b> is rotatably connected to the upper portion of the container main body <b>110</b> and has an open inlet <b>121</b> formed through the top.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The inlet <b>121</b> allows the lipstick in the lipstick housing <b>150</b>, which is combined with to move up/down, to protrude outside and is opened or closed by the door <b>140</b> operatively combined with the cover holder <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">A door guide groove <b>123</b> that guides the top opening/closing-path of the door <b>140</b> in accordance with the ascent/descent of the cover holder <b>130</b> is formed on the inner side of the container cover <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">In this configuration, the container cover <b>120</b> may be formed in various shapes, including a circle, a polygon, or combinations of them, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a cylindrical shape as an example.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The container cover <b>120</b> equipped with the vertical guide <b>160</b> that is rotatably fitted in the center through-hole <b>115</b> of the container main body <b>100</b> to guide the lipstick housing <b>150</b> rotating and moving up/down.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The vertical guide <b>160</b> is described in detail hereafter.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view showing the vertical guide of the one hand lipstick container according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the vertical guide <b>160</b> of the present invention transmits the rotational force of the container cover <b>120</b> to the lipstick housing <b>150</b> disposed in the center through-hole <b>115</b> and guides the lipstick housing <b>150</b> to move up/down in the opposite directions to the cover holder <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The vertical guide <b>160</b> is composed of a pipe <b>161</b> fitted in the center through-hole <b>115</b> of the container main body <b>110</b> and a fixed end <b>163</b> extending from the top of the pipe <b>161</b> to be combined with the container cover <b>120</b>, with the cover holder <b>130</b> movable up/down on one side.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The lipstick housing <b>150</b> is disposed in the pipe <b>161</b> to be movable up/down.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">A slide groove <b>165</b> is formed vertically long on one side of the pipe <b>161</b> such that the lipstick housing <b>150</b> can vertically move up/down and a guide protrusion <b>153</b> formed at the lower portion of the lipstick housing <b>150</b> is inserted in the slide groove <b>165</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The guide protrusion <b>153</b> of the lipstick housing <b>150</b> protrudes outside through the slide groove and is seated in the inner spiral guide groove <b>116</b> of the container main body <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">That is, the vertical guide <b>160</b> with the fixed end <b>163</b> in the container cover <b>120</b> rotates with the container cover <b>120</b> and transmits the rotational force of the container cover to the lipstick housing <b>150</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The lipstick housing <b>150</b> rotates with the vertical guide <b>160</b> by means of the rotational force and vertically moves up/down along the slide groove <b>165</b> of the vertical guide <b>160</b> by the guide protrusion <b>153</b> that revolves along the inner spiral guide groove <b>116</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The lipstick housing <b>150</b> is described in detail hereafter.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the lipstick housing <b>150</b> is spiral-combined with the container main body <b>110</b> by the inner spiral guide groove <b>116</b> formed on the center through-hole <b>115</b> of the container main body <b>110</b> to move up/down, and has a cylindrical housing body <b>151</b> where the lipstick is received and the guide protrusion <b>153</b> that protrudes on the outer side of the housing body <b>151</b> to be fitted in the inner spiral guide groove <b>116</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The lipstick housing <b>150</b> rotates with the cover holder <b>120</b> by the vertical guide <b>160</b> and vertically moves up/down in accordance with the rotational direction.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">The cover holder <b>130</b> that operates in the opposite direction to the lipstick housing <b>150</b>, that is, moves down with moving-up of the lipstick housing <b>150</b> and moves up with moving-down of the lipstick housing <b>150</b> is positioned between the fixed end <b>163</b> of the vertical guide <b>160</b> and the container cover <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The cover holder <b>130</b> is described first in detail hereafter.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a perspective view showing the door and the cover holder of the one hand lipstick container according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the cover holder <b>130</b> of the present invention is composed of a base plate <b>131</b> being in contact with one side of the fixed end <b>163</b> of the vertical guide <b>160</b> to slide up/down, a pipe-fitting portion <b>133</b> extending in a ring shape from the lower end of the base plate <b>131</b> to cover the outer side of the cylinder <b>113</b> of the container main body <b>110</b>, a door hinge portion <b>135</b> formed at the upper end of the base plate <b>131</b> such that the door <b>140</b> is hinged, and an outer rotational protrusion <b>137</b> formed on the inner side of the lower end of the base plate <b>131</b> to be spiral-combined with the outer spiral guide groove <b>114</b> of the cylinder <b>113</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The cover holder <b>130</b> having this configuration rotates with the vertical guide <b>160</b> when the container cover <b>120</b> rotates, in which the outer rotational protrusion <b>137</b> at the lower end of the base plate revolves along the outer spiral guide groove <b>114</b> of the cylinder <b>113</b>, thereby changing the vertical position.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The base plate <b>131</b> of the cover holder <b>130</b> is slidably fitted in a vertical guide portion <b>164</b> of the vertical guide <b>160</b> to be vertically guided up/down.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">The door <b>140</b> is hinged to the upper end of the cover holder <b>130</b> to open/close the inlet <b>121</b> of the container cover <b>120</b> by the moving-up/down of the cover holder <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The door <b>140</b> is described in detail hereafter.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> the door <b>140</b> is combined to open/close the inlet <b>121</b> of the container cover <b>120</b>, with one end hinged to the door hinge portion <b>135</b> of the cover holder <b>130</b> and the other end between a door guide groove <b>123</b> on the inner side of the container cover <b>120</b> and a door guide groove <b>162</b> at the vertical guide <b>160</b>, to be guided along an open path.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">As the cover holder <b>130</b> moves down, the end of the door <b>140</b> hinged to the cover holder <b>130</b> moves down, and at the same time, the opposite end moves along the open path of the door guide grooves <b>123</b>, <b>162</b>, such that the inlet <b>121</b> of the container cover <b>120</b> is opened.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">The door <b>140</b> is horizontally smoothly opened while the cover holder <b>130</b> moves down, and the door <b>140</b> vertically stands and stop moving down when the cover holder <b>130</b> fully moves down, that is, the inlet <b>121</b> is fully opened, which corresponds to the final lower position of the cover holder <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">On the contrary, as the cover holder <b>130</b> moves up, the door <b>140</b> moves along the close path of the door guide groove <b>123</b>, such that the inlet <b>121</b> of the container cover <b>120</b> is closed.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">The up-down movement of the cover holder <b>130</b> is made by the rotational force of the container cover <b>120</b>, in the opposite directions to the up-down movement of the lipstick housing <b>150</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">The inner spiral guide groove <b>116</b> and the outer spiral guide groove <b>114</b> of the cylinder <b>113</b> of the cover main body <b>110</b> are formed in the opposite direction to achieve the above configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">The operation of the one hand lipstick container according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention is described hereafter.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">First, a user rotates the container cover <b>120</b> with fingers, with the container body <b>110</b> in one hand.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">In this operation, the vertical guide <b>160</b> and the cover holder <b>130</b> combined with the container main body <b>110</b> are correspondingly rotated and the cover holder <b>130</b> moves down while rotating along the outer spiral guide groove <b>114</b> on the cylinder <b>113</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">In this operation, the cover holder <b>130</b> vertically moves down along the inner side of the container cover <b>120</b>, with the door <b>140</b> hinged to the cover holder <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">Further, the opposite end of the door <b>140</b> moves along the open path of the door grooves <b>123</b>, <b>162</b> and opens the inlet <b>121</b> of the container cover <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">As the inlet <b>121</b> is fully opened, the door vertically stands <b>140</b> and stop moving down.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">In this operation, the cover holder <b>130</b> moves down while the lipstick housing <b>150</b> moves up, in which since the lipstick housing <b>150</b> receives the rotational force of the container cover <b>120</b> through the vertical guide <b>160</b>, they move up/down along the inner spiral guide groove <b>116</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">The lipstick housing <b>150</b> receiving the rotational force from the vertical guide <b>160</b> moves up/down along the inner spiral guide groove <b>116</b>, in the opposite direction to the cover holder <b>130</b>, that is, vertically moves up/down along the slide groove <b>165</b> of the vertical guide <b>160</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">The lipstick in the lipstick housing <b>150</b> protrudes through the open inlet <b>121</b> of the container cover <b>120</b> and the user can make up with the lipstick.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">One of the important features of the present invention is that the lipstick housing <b>150</b> is slowly moved up after the cover holder <b>130</b> and the door <b>140</b> are opened first.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">For this operation, according to the mechanism of the present invention, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, it is possible to non-uniformly form the pitch of the outer spiral guide groove <b>114</b> on the outer side of the cylinder <b>113</b>, and for example, it is possible to make wide the pitch of the upper section in the entire section and relatively narrow the pitch of the lower section.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">As described above, the reason that the pitch of the outer spiral guide groove <b>114</b> is non-uniform is because the descent section of the cover holder <b>130</b> is relatively shorter than the ascent section of the lipstick housing <b>150</b>, which is for continuing the rotation while the lipstick housing <b>150</b> move up to the highest position, by narrowing the pitch such that the lipstick housing rapidly moves down in the upper section of the outer spiral groove <b>114</b> to open the inlet <b>121</b> of the container cover <b>120</b> and then slowly moves down in the lower section.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">Further, the present invention may be implemented by a structure opposite to the structure described above. That is, it is also possible to non-uniformly form the pitch of the inner spiral guide groove <b>116</b>, in which the pitch is set small at the lower section such that the lipstick housing move up/sown slow while waiting for the opening timing of the door <b>140</b>, and the pitch is set large after the door <b>140</b> is opened such that it can rapidly move up/down.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">Further, according to the present invention, it is possible, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, to a cylinder member <b>170</b> moves up/down before the lipstick housing <b>150</b> moves up/down, by positioning the cylinder member <b>170</b> to cover the lipstick housing <b>150</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective view showing an installation structure of the cylinder member of the one hand lipstick container according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the cylinder member <b>170</b> can be disposed to cover the lipstick housing <b>150</b>. A guide protrusion <b>171</b> inserted in the inner spiral guide groove <b>115</b> of the cylinder <b>113</b> of the container main body <b>110</b> is formed at the lower end of the cylinder member <b>170</b> and a protrusion groove <b>173</b> where the guide protrusion <b>153</b> of the lipstick housing <b>150</b> is inserted is formed under the guide protrusion <b>171</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">The cylinder member <b>170</b> is formed in a pipe shape and moves up first to the uppermost portion of the center through-hole <b>115</b> to protrude through the inlet <b>121</b> of the container cover <b>120</b> before the lipstick housing <b>150</b> moves up, and then the lipstick housing <b>150</b> moves up second over the cylinder member <b>170</b> such that the lipstick protrudes.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">This is for preventing a problem that the door <b>140</b> interferes with the lipstick.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">Although it is possible to manufacture the container main body and the container cover of the lipstick container of the present invention described above with synthetic resin, metal, or ceramic, when they are made of metal, such as aluminum, it is possible achieve a high-quality product due to the peculiar metallic luster and the textural expression.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">In particular, using metal can decrease the thickness of the product, such that it is possible to decrease the entire size of the product, which contributes to refine the image of the product.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">Further, the present invention having the configurations described above makes it possible to use the lipstick container with one hand, such that the use is simple and a good aesthetic appearance is achieved.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">Further, since all the parts are assembled in the container cover and the container main body and the parts are not exposed to the outside, elegant design can be accomplished even if the lipstick container is manufactured to have the same external appearance as existing lipstick containers. In addition, since the lipstick container is used by rotating the container main body, similar to existing lipstick containers, users can familiarly use it, without strangeness.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">Further, according to the present invention, by optimizing the height of the container main body such that a user can take all action with the lipstick container in one hand, it is possible to easily rotate the container cover with fingers while gripping the container main body with the palm, such that the use is convenient.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A one hand lipstick container,
<claim-text>wherein an inner spiral guide groove and an outer spiral guide groove are formed at a cylinder of a container main body in opposite directions, a lipstick housing is disposed to move up/down along the inner spiral guide groove when a container cover rotates, and a door is opened or closed by up-down movement in the opposite direction to the direction of movement of the lipstick housing along the outer spiral guide groove, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the door has one end hinged to a dogs hinge portion of a cover holder and another end fitted between a door guide groove on an inner side of the container cover and a door guide groove at a vertical guide, to be guided along an open path.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A one hand lipstick container comprising:
<claim-text>a container body having a cylinder standing at a center of a body and a center through-hole formed through a center of the cylinder;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a container cover rotatably connected to an upper portion of the container main body and having an open inlet formed through a top thereof;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a vertical guide having a fixed end combined with an upper portion of the container cover and a pipe extending down to be rotatably fitted in the center through-hole of the container main body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lipstick housing inserted in the pipe of the vertical guide and vertically moving up/down along a slide groove formed in the pipe;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cover holder disposed between one side of the fixed end of the vertical guide and an inner side of the container to vertically slide and vertically moving up/down along an outer spiral guide groove on the cylinder of the container main body; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a door hinged to an upper end of the cover holder and operating with the up-down movement to open/close the inlet of the container cover,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the door has one end hinged to a door hinge portion of the cover holder and another end fitted between a door guide groove on the inner side of the container cover and a door guide groove at the vertical guide, to be guided along an open path.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The one hand lipstick container according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the container cover is connected to the upper portion of the container main body and has the inlet open at the top and a door guide groove guiding the door operating with up-down movement of the cover holder, in the inner side of the container cover.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The one hand lipstick container according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the fixed end extends from a top of the pipe to be combined with the container cover, with the cover holder movable up/down on one side of the fixed end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The one hand lipstick container according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the pipe has the slide groove formed vertically long at one side to guide a guide protrusion of the lipstick housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The one hand lipstick container according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the cover holder has a base plate being in contact with one side of the fixed end of the vertical guide to slide up/down, a pipe-fitting portion extending in a ring shape from a lower end of the base plate to cover an outer side of the cylinder of the container main body, a door hinge portion formed at an upper end of the base plate such that the door is hinged, and an outer rotational protrusion formed on an inner side of the lower end of the base plate to be spiral-combined with the outer spiral guide groove of the cylinder.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The one hand lipstick container according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the container main body has the outer spiral guide groove on an outer side of the cylinder such that the cover holder spirally rotates and moves up/down and an inner spiral guide groove on an inner side of the cylinder such that the lipstick housing spirally rotates and moves up/down.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The one hand lipstick container according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein a pitch of the outer spiral guide groove formed on the outer side of the cylinder of the container main body is not uniform.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The one hand lipstick container according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the pitch of the outer spiral guide groove is formed wide at an upper section and relatively narrow at a lower section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The one hand lipstick container according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein a cylinder member is provided to cover the lipstick housing and moves up/down before the lipstick housing moves up/down.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The one hand lipstick container according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein a guide protrusion inserted in the inner spiral guide groove of the cylinder of the container main body is formed at a lower end of the cylinder member and a protrusion groove where a guide protrusion of the lipstick housing is inserted is formed under the guide protrusion inserted in the inner spiral guide groove of the cylinder.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The one hand lipstick container according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the lipstick housing has a cylindrical housing body where a lipstick is received, and a guide protrusion is formed on an outer side of the housing body to be spirally inserted in an inner spiral guide groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The one hand lipstick container according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the container main body has the outer spiral guide groove on an outer side of the cylinder such that the cover holder spirally rotates and moves up/down and the inner spiral guide groove on an inner side of the cylinder such that the lipstick housing spirally rotates and moves up/down.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The one hand lipstick container according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein a pitch of the outer spiral guide groove formed on the outer side of the cylinder of the container main body is not uniform.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The one hand lipstick container according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the pitch of the outer spiral guide groove is formed wide at an upper section and relatively narrow at a lower section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The one hand lipstick container according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein a cylinder member is provided to cover the lipstick housing and moves up/down before the lipstick housing moves up/down.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The one hand lipstick container according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein a guide protrusion inserted in the inner spiral guide groove of the cylinder of the container main body is formed at a lower end of the cylinder member and a protrusion groove where a guide protrusion of the lipstick housing is inserted is formed under the guide protrusion inserted in the inner spiral guide groove of the cylinder.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The one hand lipstick container according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the lipstick housing has a cylindrical housing body where a lipstick is received, and a guide protrusion is formed on an outer side of the housing body to be spirally inserted in the inner spiral guide groove. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
