<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623744-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623744</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13863509</doc-number>
<date>20130416</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>21</main-group>
<subgroup>301</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>21</main-group>
<subgroup>48</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>21</main-group>
<subgroup>78</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438464</main-classification>
<further-classification>438458</further-classification>
<further-classification>438460</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Die singulation method</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6777267</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Ruby et al.</name>
<date>20040800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438113</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7566634</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Beyne et al.</name>
<date>20090700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438462</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7781310</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Grivna</name>
<date>20100800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438462</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0079024</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Akram</name>
<date>20060400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438110</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>22</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438458</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438460</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438464</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>12</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12758838</doc-number>
<date>20100413</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8461023</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13863509</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Sandia Corporation</orgname>
<address>
<city>Albuquerque</city>
<state>NM</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Swiler</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas P.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Albuquerque</city>
<state>NM</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Garcia</last-name>
<first-name>Ernest J.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Albuquerque</city>
<state>NM</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Francis</last-name>
<first-name>Kathryn M.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Rio Rancho</city>
<state>NM</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Beckett</last-name>
<first-name>Michael A.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Sandia Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Albuquerque</city>
<state>NM</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Smith</last-name>
<first-name>Zandra</first-name>
<department>2822</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Perkins</last-name>
<first-name>Pamela E</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A method is disclosed for singulating die from a semiconductor substrate (e.g. a semiconductor-on-insulator substrate or a bulk silicon substrate) containing an oxide layer (e.g. silicon dioxide or a silicate glass) and one or more semiconductor layers (e.g. monocrystalline or polycrystalline silicon) located above the oxide layer. The method etches trenches through the substrate and through each semiconductor layer about the die being singulated, with the trenches being offset from each other around at least a part of the die so that the oxide layer between the trenches holds the substrate and die together. The trenches can be anisotropically etched using a Deep Reactive Ion Etching (DRIE) process. After the trenches are etched, the oxide layer between the trenches can be etched away with an HF etchant to singulate the die. A release fixture can be located near one side of the substrate to receive the singulated die.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="195.75mm" wi="349.33mm" file="US08623744-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="181.19mm" wi="144.10mm" file="US08623744-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="227.50mm" wi="169.67mm" file="US08623744-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="234.19mm" wi="177.63mm" file="US08623744-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="261.11mm" wi="180.26mm" file="US08623744-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="199.05mm" wi="171.20mm" file="US08623744-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="208.87mm" wi="190.92mm" file="US08623744-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a Continuation application of copending utility application U.S. patent application Ser. No. 12/758,838 entitled &#x201c;DIE SINGULATION METHOD&#x201d;, filed on Apr. 13, 2010, which is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?GOVINT description="Government Interest" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">GOVERNMENT RIGHTS</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This invention was made with Government support under Contract No. DE-AC04-94AL85000 awarded by the U.S. Department of Energy. The Government has certain rights in the invention.</p>
<?GOVINT description="Government Interest" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates in general to semiconductor processing, and in particular to a method for singulating die from a semiconductor substrate by etching.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A large number of semiconductor devices are typically fabricated on a common semiconductor wafer having a diameter up to 12 inches or more and then are separated (i.e. singulated) for packaging as individual devices. These semiconductor devices, which can be integrated circuits (ICs), microprocessors, microelectromechanical systems (MEMS), microfluidic devices, sensors, etc., are conventionally singulated by saw cutting. The use of saw cutting requires a spacing (i.e. a street) between adjacent devices which are being singulated with this spacing being up to 100 microns or more wide; and this spacing limits the number of devices which can be fabricated from the semiconductor wafer. Additionally, saw cutting generates debris which can contaminate the devices or become lodged in moveable members of MEMS devices or in fluid channels of microfluidic devices. Furthermore, saw cutting must be performed along straight lines in a serial fashion one cut at a time; and this limits the shape of the devices to being square or rectangular and generally all of the same size. Saw cutting is also time since each saw cut must be carefully aligned with each street separating adjacent rows of devices to singulate the devices without damaging them. For all of the above reasons, conventional saw cutting is disadvantageous so that an advance in the art is needed to improve the singulation of devices from semiconductor wafers.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The present invention provides such an improvement in the art by providing a method for singulating one or more die from a semiconductor wafer (i.e. a semiconductor substrate) which relies on etching trenches from two opposite sides of the semiconductor wafer with a portion or all of the trench on one side of the semiconductor wafer being laterally offset from the trench on the other side of the semiconductor wafer. The trenches expose an oxide layer on the semiconductor wafer so that when the oxide layer between the trenches is etched away, the die will be singulated. The method can also provide a release fixture beneath the semiconductor wafer to receive and support the singulated die once the oxide layer is etched away between the trenches on each side of the semiconductor wafer.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The method of the present invention is compatible with standard semiconductor processes and allows all of the die on the semiconductor wafer to be singulated simultaneously in a parallel process without attachment to a handle wafer. This saves time and cost and also increases yield and performance by minimizing die handling and particulates which would otherwise occur if conventional sawing were used to singulate the die. This also eliminates adhesives which would otherwise be required to attach the die and the substrate from which the die are formed to the handle wafer, and additional cleaning steps that would be required to remove these adhesives from the singulated die.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The method of the present invention can be used to singulate die of an arbitrary shape, and can be used to form die with rounded corners.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The method of the present invention can be used with silicon-on-insulator (SOI) substrates, or bulk silicon substrates having one or more oxide and polycrystalline silicon layers deposited thereon.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The method of the present invention can also be adapted to release features within one or more MEMS devices which are formed on the die. The offset between the trenches on each side of the substrate can be predetermined so that singulation of the die by etching away the oxide layer between the trenches will occur at a time shortly after release of features within the MEMS devices.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">These and other advantages of the present invention will become evident to those skilled in the art.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The present invention relates to a method for singulating one or more die from a semiconductor substrate having an oxide layer disposed on the semiconductor substrate, and a semiconductor layer disposed on the oxide layer. The method comprises the steps of etching a first trench into one of the semiconductor substrate and the semiconductor layer around the die to be singulated, with the etching of the first trench being terminated proximate to the oxide layer; etching a second trench into the other of the semiconductor substrate and the semiconductor layer, with the etching of the second trench being terminated proximate to the oxide layer, with at least a portion of the second trench being laterally offset from the first trench; and etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench and thereby singulating the die from the semiconductor substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The semiconductor substrate can comprise monocrystalline silicon, and the semiconductor layer can comprise either monocrystalline silicon (e.g. in the case of a silicon-on-insulator substrate), or polycrystalline silicon (e.g. in the case of a bulk semiconductor substrate). The oxide layer can comprise silicon dioxide or a silicate glass.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In some embodiments of the present invention, one of the steps of etching the first trench and etching the second trench can comprise etching the semiconductor layer to provide lateral dimensions of the semiconductor layer within the die to be singulated which are smaller than the lateral dimensions of the semiconductor substrate in the die. In other embodiments of the present invention, one of the steps of etching the first trench and etching the second trench can comprise etching the semiconductor layer to provide lateral dimensions of the semiconductor layer in the die to be singulated which are larger than the lateral dimensions of the semiconductor substrate in the die.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The step of etching the first trench can comprise etching the first trench using a Deep Reactive Ion Etching (DRIE) process; and the step of etching the second trench can comprise etching the second trench using the DRIE process. The step of etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench can comprise etching away the oxide layer using an etchant comprising hydrofluoric acid (HF).</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The method can further comprise the step of providing a release fixture proximate to the semiconductor substrate during the step of etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench. The release fixture can include one or more die pockets which are sized to receive the die being singulated. The release fixture can also include one or more openings therethrough, and the step of etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench can comprise providing an etchant comprising HF (also referred to herein as the HF etchant) in both the first trench and the second trench.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In some embodiments of the present invention wherein the die to be singulated include one or more MEMS devices, one of the steps of etching the first trench and etching the second trench can comprise etching moveable features of each MEMS device located on the die being singulated. In these embodiments, the step of etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench can also be used to etch away the oxide layer from beneath the moveable features of the MEMS device, thereby releasing the MEMS device. An offset distance between the first trench and the second trench can be sized to be about the same or slightly larger than a widest moveable feature in the MEMS device. When this is done, completion of the step of etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench can signal completion of releasing the MEMS device. This is advantageous since completion of the step of etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench can be easily visually observed as the die is singulated and drops away from the substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The present invention also relates to a method for singulating one or more die from a silicon-on-insulator (SOI) substrate having a monocrystalline silicon body, an oxide layer disposed on the monocrystalline silicon body and a monocrystalline silicon layer disposed on the oxide layer. The method comprises the steps of etching a first trench into one of the monocrystalline silicon body and the monocrystalline silicon layer, with the etching of the first trench being terminated proximate to the oxide layer, and with the first trench forming an outline about the die to be singulated from the SOI substrate; etching a second trench into the other of the monocrystalline silicon body and the monocrystalline silicon layer, with the etching of the second trench being terminated proximate to the oxide layer, and with a portion or all of the second trench being laterally offset from the first trench; and etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench and thereby singulating the die from the SOI substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">One of the steps of etching the first trench and etching the second trench can comprise etching the monocrystalline silicon layer in the die to be singulated to provide lateral dimensions which are smaller than the lateral dimensions of the monocrystalline silicon body in the die to be singulated. Alternately, one of the steps of etching the first trench and etching the second trench can comprise etching the monocrystalline silicon layer in the die to be singulated to provide lateral dimensions which are larger than the lateral dimensions of the monocrystalline silicon body in the die to be singulated.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The step of etching the first trench can comprise etching the first trench using a Deep Reactive Ion Etching (DRIE) process. The step of etching the second trench can also comprise etching the second trench using the DRIE process.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The step of etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench can comprise etching away the oxide layer using an etchant comprising hydrofluoric acid (HF). The method can further comprise the step of removing the die from the HF etchant within a few minutes after singulation of the die by the step of etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">One of the steps of etching the first trench and etching the second trench can comprise etching moveable features of a MEMS device into the monocrystalline silicon layer on the die to be singulated from the SOI substrate. In this case, the step of etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench can also etch away the oxide layer beneath the moveable features of the MEMS device, thereby releasing the MEMS device for movement. Completion of the step of etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench can also be used to signal completion of the step of releasing the MEMS device for movement (e.g. when an offset distance between the first trench and the second trench is substantially equal to or slightly larger than the width of a widest moveable feature in the MEMS device).</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The method can further comprise the step of providing a release fixture beneath the SOI substrate to support the die after singulating the die by the step of etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench. The release fixture can include a die pocket located beneath the die to be singulated. The release fixture can also include one or more openings through the release fixture proximate to the die to be singulated. These openings allow the step of etching away the oxide layer to etch away the oxide layer through both the first trench and the second trench.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The present invention further relates to a method for singulating a die from a semiconductor substrate having an oxide layer disposed on the semiconductor substrate, and a semiconductor layer disposed on the oxide layer. The method comprises the steps of anisotropically etching a first trench in the semiconductor substrate around the die to be singulated to expose one side of the oxide layer; anisotropically etching a second trench in the semiconductor layer around the die to be singulated to expose another side of the oxide layer, with the second trench being laterally offset from the first trench around at least a portion of the die to be singulated; providing a release fixture proximate to the semiconductor substrate, with the release fixture having a die pocket to receive the die to be singulated; etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench and thereby singulating the die from the semiconductor substrate; and catching the singulated die in the die pocket of the release fixture. The substrate can comprise, for example, a silicon-on-insulator (SOI) substrate, or a bulk semiconductor substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The step of anisotropically etching the first trench can comprise anisotropically etching the first trench by a Deep Reactive Ion Etching (DRIE) process; and the step of anisotropically etching the second trench can comprise anisotropically etching the second trench by the DRIE process. The step of etching away the oxide layer can comprise isotropically etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench using an etchant comprising hydrofluoric acid (HF).</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The steps of anisotropically etching the first trench can comprise etching a first annular trench completely around the die to be singulated; and the step of anisotropically etching the second trench can comprise etching a second annular trench completely around the die to be singulated, with the second annular trench being enclosed within an outline about the die which is defined by the annular trench.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Additional advantages and novel features of the invention will become apparent to those skilled in the art upon examination of the following detailed description thereof when considered in conjunction with the accompanying drawings. The advantages of the invention can be realized and attained by means of the instrumentalities and combinations particularly pointed out in the appended claims.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The accompanying drawings, which are incorporated into and form a part of the specification, illustrate several aspects of the present invention and, together with the description, serve to explain the principles of the invention. The drawings are only for the purpose of illustrating preferred embodiments of the invention and are not to be construed as limiting the invention. In the drawings:</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a schematic plan view of a semiconductor substrate having a plurality of die formed thereon prior to singulation of the die using the method of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates steps in the method of the present invention for singulating the die in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A-3F</figref> show schematic partial cross-section views along the section line <b>1</b>-<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> to illustrate the steps in the method of the present invention for singulating the die in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref> shows a schematic partial cross-section view similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref> but with a MEMS device being formed on each die to illustrate how an offset distance between the trenches can be predetermined so that the MEMS device is released prior to or at about the same time the die is singulated by the method of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</figref> shows a schematic partial cross-section view of the semiconductor substrate of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref> after singulating the die according to the method of the present invention, with the MEMS device being fully released for movement.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> shows a schematic partial cross-section view similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref> but with the second trench being laterally offset from the first trench so that the semiconductor layer within each die being singulated extends outside of an outline around the die formed by the first trench.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref> shows a schematic partial cross-section view of the semiconductor substrate of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> after singulation of the die, with a release fixture being located proximate to the semiconductor substrate.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a schematic plan view of a semiconductor substrate <b>10</b> having a plurality of die <b>12</b> formed thereon prior to singulation of the die <b>12</b> according to the method <b>100</b> of the present invention. Various steps in the method <b>100</b> for singulating the die <b>12</b> from the semiconductor substrate <b>10</b> are illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> and will be described hereinafter with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A-3E</figref> which show a series of schematic partial cross-section views along the section line <b>1</b>-<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The term &#x201c;die&#x201d; as used herein, which can be either singular or plural, refers to a portion of the substrate <b>10</b> wherein at least one semiconductor device such as an integrated circuit (IC), a microelectromechanical system (MEMS) device, a microfluidic device, a sensor, or a combination thereof is formed by a series of well-known semiconductor processing steps. The terms &#x201c;singulation&#x201d; and &#x201c;singulating&#x201d; as used herein refer to separating one or more of the die <b>12</b> from the semiconductor substrate <b>10</b> wherefrom the die <b>12</b> are formed.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The method <b>100</b> of the present invention can be initiated by a first step <b>102</b> wherein a semiconductor substrate <b>10</b> is provided on which one or more semiconductor devices have been formed. The semiconductor substrate <b>10</b> can comprise an oxide layer <b>14</b> disposed on the substrate <b>10</b>, and one or more semiconductor layers <b>16</b> (also termed device layers) located above the oxide layer <b>14</b>. As an example, the semiconductor substrate <b>10</b> can be a silicon-on-insulator (SOI) substrate <b>10</b> comprising a monocrystalline silicon base <b>18</b> and a monocrystalline silicon layer <b>16</b> with the oxide layer <b>14</b> (e.g. comprising silicon dioxide) sandwiched therebetween. As another example, the semiconductor substrate <b>10</b> can comprise a bulk silicon substrate <b>18</b> with an oxide layer <b>14</b> (e.g. comprising a silicate glass such as such as TEOS which can be deposited from the thermal decomposition of tetraethylorthosilicate) deposited onto the bulk silicon substrate <b>18</b>, and with one or more semiconductor layers <b>16</b> comprising polycrystalline silicon (also termed polysilicon) deposited above the oxide layer <b>14</b>. When a plurality of polysilicon layers <b>16</b> are used, additional oxide layers <b>14</b> can be used to separate adjacent polysilicon layers <b>16</b> (e.g. to build up the structure of a MEMS device). <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> schematically illustrates the semiconductor substrate <b>10</b> in a partial cross-section view taken along the section line <b>1</b>-<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The semiconductor substrate <b>10</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> can have an overall thickness of, for example, 50-1000 microns (&#x3bc;m). The semiconductor layer <b>16</b> can have a thickness, for example, in the range of 1-400 &#x3bc;m depending upon the type of semiconductor devices being formed on the die <b>12</b>. The oxide layer <b>14</b> can have a thickness, for example, of 1-10 &#x3bc;m.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In step <b>104</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a first trench <b>20</b> can be etched into the semiconductor substrate <b>10</b> from a bottom side <b>22</b> of the substrate <b>10</b>. This is schematically illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>. The first trench <b>20</b> can be can extend around the die <b>12</b> being singulated from the substrate <b>10</b> to form an outline about the die <b>12</b>. The first trench <b>20</b> can be an annular trench, or can be a plurality of straight-line, curved or zig-zag trenches which intersect as needed to form the outline around each die <b>12</b> and thereby determine the shape for each die <b>12</b> being singulated.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The die <b>12</b> being singulated according to the method <b>100</b> of the present invention can be square, rectangular, polygonal, or any arbitrary shape including a curved shape (e.g. circular or elliptical). When the die <b>12</b> being singulated are square or rectangular, the method <b>100</b> of the present invention can be used to provide rounded corners on the square or rectangular die <b>12</b>. This is not possible with conventional saw cutting. Providing rounded corners on die <b>12</b> formed according to the method <b>100</b> of the present invention can be advantageous since this can reduce the formation of particulates which can otherwise be generated by handling of die with square (i.e. 90&#xb0;) corners (i.e. the sharp 90&#xb0; corners can break off during handling of the die to generate the particulates). Such particulates can be damaging to a MEMS device formed on the die since the particulates can eventually become lodged in or between moveable elements of the MEMS device, and render the MEMS device inoperable.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The first trench <b>20</b> can be etched through the substrate <b>10</b> in step <b>104</b> by an anisotropic etching process which produces substantially vertical sidewalls for the first trench <b>20</b> which can have a width of, for example, up to 100 &#x3bc;m or more. The anisotropic etching process can comprise a so-called &#x201c;Bosch process&#x201d; which is also referred to herein as Deep Reactive Ion Etching (DRIE) and which is disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 5,501,893 to Laermer et al., which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Prior to etching the first trench <b>20</b>, an etch mask (not shown) can be provided over the bottom side <b>22</b> of the substrate <b>10</b> with an opening photolithographically defined at the location of the first trench <b>20</b> around each die <b>12</b> being singulated. The opening in the etch mask can be aligned to alignment features located on a top side <b>24</b> of the substrate <b>10</b> to precisely locate the first trench <b>20</b> about the die <b>12</b> being singulated.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Additional openings (not shown) can be photolithographically defined in the etch mask at locations within the die <b>12</b> being singulated for etching features to be formed within the die <b>12</b>. For example, when one or more microfluidic connections are to be provided through the substrate <b>10</b> to fluid channels formed on the top side <b>24</b> of the substrate <b>10</b> within each die <b>12</b>, each microfluidic connection can be etched during step <b>104</b> when the first trench <b>20</b> is etched. As another example, when a portion of the substrate <b>10</b> (e.g. the monocrystalline silicon base <b>18</b> in an SOI substrate <b>10</b>) is to form a part of a MEMS device (e.g. a proof mass in a MEMS accelerometer), this portion of the substrate <b>10</b> can be patterned by etching during the step <b>104</b> at the same time the first trench <b>20</b> is etched.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">With the etch mask in place, the DRIE etch process can be initiated in step <b>104</b> to etch the first trench <b>20</b> through the substrate <b>10</b> from the bottom side <b>22</b> thereof as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, with the etching step <b>104</b> being terminated proximate to the oxide layer <b>14</b>. The DRIE etch process uses an iterative plasma deposition and etch cycle wherein a polymer etch inhibitor is conformally deposited as a film over the bottom side <b>22</b> of the substrate <b>10</b> and in the first trench <b>20</b> being etched through the substrate <b>10</b> during a deposition cycle, and then the film and a portion of the silicon substrate material in the first trench <b>20</b> is then preferentially removed during an etching cycle. The DRIE etch process can have an aspect ratio of up to about 50:1 or more with an etch rate of up to 8 &#x3bc;m per minute or more.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In the DRIE etch process, the polymer film, which can be formed using a plasma containing a fluorocarbon such as C<sub>4</sub>F<sub>8 </sub>and an inert carrier gas such as argon, deposits conformally over a bottom surface and sidewalls of the first trench <b>20</b> being etched. During a subsequent etch cycle with a plasma formed from a fluorine-containing gas (e.g. SF<sub>6</sub>) and the inert carrier gas (e.g. Ar), the polymer film is quickly etched away from the bottom surface of the first trench <b>20</b>, while the polymer film is etched away more slowly from the sidewalls of the trench <b>20</b>. This exposes the silicon substrate material at the bottom surface of the first trench <b>20</b> to reactive fluorine atoms from the SF<sub>6</sub>/Ar-based plasma, with the fluorine atoms then being responsible for etching the exposed bottom surface while the sidewalls are protected from being etched by the remaining polymer film. Before the polymer film on the sidewalls of the first trench <b>20</b> is completely removed by action of the SF<sub>6</sub>/Ar-based plasma, the polymer deposition step using the C<sub>4</sub>FWAr-based plasma is repeated. This cycle is repeated many times, with each polymer deposition and etch cycle generally lasting about 10 seconds or less, until the etching is terminated proximate to the oxide layer <b>14</b> (e.g. when the oxide layer <b>14</b> is exposed). The oxide layer <b>14</b> acts as an etch stop for the DRIE process since the oxide layer <b>14</b> is much more resistant to etching by the C<sub>4</sub>FWAr-based plasma than the silicon substrate material. At the end of this etching step <b>104</b>, the die <b>12</b> being singulated are still attached to the substrate <b>10</b> by the oxide layer <b>14</b> and the semiconductor layer <b>16</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>. This maintains the structural integrity of the substrate <b>10</b> so that the substrate <b>10</b> can be handled.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In step <b>106</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a second trench <b>26</b> can be etched into the semiconductor layer <b>16</b> as schematically illustrated in the cross-section view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref>. The etching step <b>106</b> can be terminated upon etching through the semiconductor layer <b>16</b> to expose the underlying oxide layer <b>14</b>. In preparation for the etching step <b>106</b>, another etch mask (not shown) can be provided over the top side <b>24</b> of the substrate <b>10</b> with an opening photolithographically defined at the location of the second trench <b>26</b> around each die <b>12</b> being singulated. The etching step <b>106</b> can then be performed using the same DRIE process described above for etching the first trench <b>20</b>. Alternately, reactive ion etching (RIE) can be used to etch the second trench <b>26</b>. The second trench <b>26</b> can have a width of, for example, up to 100 &#x3bc;m or more.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">According to the method <b>100</b> of the present invention, a portion or all of the second trench <b>26</b> is laterally offset from the first trench <b>20</b> by a distance, d, which can be, for example, 50-100 &#x3bc;m (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref>). This maintains the structural integrity of the substrate <b>10</b> after the etching steps <b>104</b> and <b>106</b>, with the die <b>12</b>, which are not yet completely singulated, being held in place on the substrate <b>10</b> by a portion of the oxide layer <b>14</b> between the first and second trenches <b>20</b> and <b>26</b>. This is advantageous to allow handling of the substrate <b>10</b> after completion of the step <b>106</b>. This also avoids the need for providing any temporary holding material (e.g. epoxy or photoresist) in the first trench <b>20</b> after the etching step <b>104</b> or in the second trench <b>26</b> after the etching step <b>106</b> so that the substrate <b>10</b> can be handled without breaking, or without the die <b>12</b> prematurely falling out of the substrate <b>10</b> during handling of the substrate <b>10</b>. This also avoids the need for temporarily attaching a handle wafer (e.g. a substrate, plate, or tack tape) to one side <b>22</b> or <b>24</b> of the substrate <b>10</b> using an adhesive during singulation of the die <b>12</b>. The use of an adhesive is disadvantageous since the adhesive can contaminate the die <b>12</b> and the semiconductor devices therein, and since additional process steps are required for removing the adhesive and the handle wafer and for cleaning of the die <b>12</b> once the adhesive has been removed.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In some embodiments of the present invention, the second trench <b>26</b> can be laterally offset from the first trench <b>20</b> so that the semiconductor layer <b>16</b> in the die <b>12</b> being singulated is located completely inside of the outline around the die <b>12</b> formed by the first trench <b>20</b>. This provides lateral dimensions of the semiconductor layer <b>16</b> in the die <b>12</b> being singulated which are smaller than the lateral dimensions of the substrate <b>10</b> and is useful to prevent possible damage to the semiconductor device(s) on the die <b>12</b> during handling of the singulated die <b>12</b>. This is also advantageous to allow the die <b>12</b>, when completely singulated, to drop through the substrate <b>10</b> to an underlying release fixture <b>28</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3D-3F</figref>) which will be described hereinafter.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In other embodiments of the present invention, the lateral offset between the first trench <b>20</b> and the second trench <b>26</b> can extend around only a portion of the die <b>12</b> being singulated, with the first and second trenches <b>20</b> and <b>26</b> being superposed one above the other around a remainder of the die <b>12</b>. In this case, when the semiconductor layer <b>16</b> in the die <b>12</b> being singulated is inside of the outline formed by the first trench <b>20</b>, the die <b>12</b> upon singulation thereof can drop down through the substrate <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In yet other embodiments of the present invention, the second trench <b>26</b> can be laterally offset from the first trench <b>20</b> so that the semiconductor layer <b>16</b> in the die <b>12</b> being singulated extends outside of the outline formed by the first trench <b>20</b> around a portion or the entirety of the die <b>12</b>. This is useful to allow the die <b>12</b>, when completely singulated by removing the oxide layer <b>14</b> between the first and second trenches, <b>20</b> and <b>26</b>, to be retained within a frame <b>34</b> which is formed by the etching step <b>108</b> from a remainder of the substrate <b>10</b> not used for the die <b>12</b>. In this case, the release fixture <b>28</b> can be optionally provided on the top side <b>24</b> of the substrate <b>10</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Those skilled in the art will understand that the order of etching the first trench <b>20</b> and the second trench <b>26</b> can be reversed from that discussed above (i.e. the order in which the steps <b>104</b> and <b>106</b> are performed can be reversed, and the locations of the trenches <b>20</b> and <b>26</b> can be reversed). Thus, the terms &#x201c;first trench&#x201d; and &#x201c;second trench&#x201d; are not intended to suggest that the &#x201c;first trench&#x201d; must always be etched before the &#x201c;second trench&#x201d; is etched, or that the &#x201c;first trench&#x201d; must always be etched into the substrate <b>10</b> with the &#x201c;second trench&#x201d; being etched into the semiconductor layer <b>16</b>. The terms &#x201c;first trench&#x201d; and &#x201c;second trench&#x201d; as used herein simply indicate that there are two types of trenches <b>20</b> and <b>26</b> which are etched into opposite sides <b>22</b> and <b>24</b> of the substrate <b>10</b>. Thus, according to the present invention, the &#x201c;first trench&#x201d; can be etched into one of the semiconductor substrate <b>10</b> and the semiconductor layer <b>16</b>; and the &#x201c;second trench&#x201d; can be etched into the other of the semiconductor substrate <b>10</b> and the semiconductor layer <b>16</b>. Furthermore, those skilled in the art will understand that the term &#x201c;first trench&#x201d; as used herein can include more than one trench <b>20</b>, and that the term &#x201c;second trench&#x201d; as used herein can include more than one trench <b>26</b>. This is the case, for example, when there are a plurality of die <b>12</b> on the semiconductor substrate <b>10</b> and the &#x201c;first trench&#x201d; and the &#x201c;second trench&#x201d; are formed as isolated annular trenches around each die <b>12</b> (i.e. when each die <b>12</b> has annular trenches <b>20</b> and <b>26</b> about that die <b>12</b> which do not intersect with the annular trenches <b>20</b> and <b>26</b> formed about an adjacent die <b>12</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The method <b>100</b> of the present invention can include an optional step <b>110</b> of providing a release fixture <b>28</b> proximate to the semiconductor substrate <b>10</b> to receive the die <b>12</b> after singulation. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3D</figref> shows an example of the release fixture <b>28</b> which can be located beneath the substrate <b>10</b> to receive the singulated die <b>12</b>. In this example, the release fixture <b>28</b> includes a die pocket <b>30</b> below each die <b>12</b> being singulated, with the die pocket <b>30</b> being sized to receive the die <b>12</b> (e.g. with lateral dimensions parallel to the substrate <b>10</b> which are slightly larger than the lateral dimensions of the die <b>12</b>) so that upon singulation, the die <b>12</b> will drop into the die pocket <b>30</b> and will be caught and supported therein.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Additionally, the release fixture <b>28</b> can include one or more openings <b>32</b> through the fixture <b>28</b> to provide access for an etchant comprising hydrofluoric acid (HF) to enter the first trench <b>20</b>. This allows the oxide layer <b>14</b> to be etched away from both the first and second trenches <b>20</b> and <b>26</b> during the etching step <b>108</b>, thereby reducing the time required for etching away the oxide layer <b>14</b> between the first and second trenches <b>20</b> and <b>26</b>. The openings <b>32</b> also allow the HF etchant to be drained away from the trench <b>20</b> and the die pocket <b>30</b> when the etching step <b>108</b> is completed.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In other embodiments of the present invention, the release fixture <b>28</b> can be a screen, a flat plate, or a wafer (e.g. another silicon substrate) with lateral dimensions about the same as those of the substrate <b>10</b>, and with one or more openings <b>32</b> formed therethrough. When another silicon substrate is used to form the release fixture <b>28</b>, each die pocket <b>30</b> and opening <b>32</b> can be etched into the silicon substrate (e.g. by DRIE etching). In some cases, the frame <b>34</b> formed from a prior use of the method <b>100</b> of the present invention can be used as the release fixture <b>28</b> for a subsequent use of the method <b>100</b> of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">According to the present invention, the release fixture <b>28</b> is not attached to the semiconductor substrate <b>10</b> with an adhesive, but instead is simply located proximate to the substrate <b>10</b>. It is also not necessary that the release fixture <b>28</b> be in contact with the bottom side <b>22</b> of the substrate <b>10</b> although this can be the case. As long as the release fixture <b>28</b> is separated from the bottom side <b>22</b> of the substrate <b>10</b> by a distance which is less than the thickness of the substrate <b>10</b> when arranged as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3D</figref>, the singulated die <b>12</b> will be caught and retained between the release fixture <b>28</b> and the frame <b>34</b> formed from the substrate <b>10</b> during the etching step <b>108</b>. This is the case even if the release fixture <b>28</b> and the frame <b>34</b> were to be inverted from the position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3E</figref> during the etching step <b>108</b>, or thereafter. In other embodiments of the present invention, the release fixture <b>28</b> can be located proximate to the top side <b>24</b> of the substrate <b>10</b> or in contact therewith (e.g. when the semiconductor layer <b>16</b> of the die <b>12</b> being singulated extends outside of the outline formed by the first trench <b>20</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The semiconductor substrate <b>10</b> and the release fixture <b>28</b> can be located proximate to each other by inserting them into a wafer carrier (not shown) in preparation for the etching step <b>108</b>. As mentioned above, the HF etchant is used to remove the oxide layer <b>14</b> in the etching step <b>108</b>. The HF etchant will generally be in the form of a wet solution (e.g. hydrofluoric acid and water, or a buffered oxide etchant comprising hydrofluoric acid, ammonium fluoride and water), although, in some cases, or the HF etchant can be in vapor form. When the oxide layer <b>14</b> is etched away between the first and second trenches, <b>20</b> and <b>26</b>, the die <b>12</b> will be singulated and will be free to drop into the die pockets <b>30</b> in the release fixture <b>28</b> when the frame <b>34</b> and release fixture <b>28</b> are oriented as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3E</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The completion of the etching step <b>108</b> can be visually indicated by observing each singulated die <b>12</b> as it drops below the top side <b>24</b> of the frame <b>34</b> formed from the substrate <b>10</b> and into an underlying die pocket <b>30</b> of the release fixture <b>28</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3E</figref>. This visual indication of the die singulation upon completion of the etching step <b>108</b> is advantageous since it allows the singulated die <b>12</b> to be removed from the HF etchant shortly (e.g. within a few minutes) after singulation, thereby minimizing any etching of the oxide layer <b>14</b> beyond that which is necessary to singulate the die <b>12</b>. This minimizes the etching of the oxide layer <b>14</b> which holds the frame <b>34</b> together to maintain the integrity of the frame <b>34</b> and to allow the frame <b>34</b> to be used, if desired, as the release fixture <b>28</b> during a subsequent use of the method <b>100</b> to singulate additional die <b>12</b> from another semiconductor substrate <b>10</b>. This also minimizes the etching of the oxide layer <b>14</b> which holds the semiconductor layer <b>16</b> in place in each singulated die <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">When a MEMS device <b>40</b> is formed in the semiconductor layer <b>16</b>, the offset distance, d, between the first and second trenches, <b>20</b> and <b>26</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref>), can be predetermined so that the MEMS device <b>40</b> will be released at about the same time or prior to the singulation of the die <b>12</b> by the etching step <b>108</b>. The MEMS device <b>40</b> can include a plurality of moveable features to be released including a widest moveable feature <b>42</b> as schematically illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref> which schematically illustrates the substrate <b>10</b> and die <b>12</b> prior to the etching step <b>108</b>. These moveable features of the MEMS device <b>40</b> can be etched into the semiconductor layer <b>16</b> during the step <b>106</b> for etching the second trench <b>26</b>. By making the offset distance, d, about the same or slightly larger than the width of the widest moveable feature <b>42</b> of the MEMS device <b>40</b>, the oxide layer <b>14</b> beneath the widest moveable feature <b>42</b> can be removed by the HF etchant at about the same time or prior to the oxide layer <b>14</b> being etched away between the trenches <b>20</b> and <b>26</b> by the etching step <b>108</b> to singulate the die <b>12</b>. The singulated die <b>12</b> and the released MEMS device <b>40</b> thereon are shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</figref> after completion of the etching step <b>108</b>. Portions of the oxide layer <b>14</b> can be retained, as needed, to anchor the moveable features of the MEMS device to the underlying monocrystalline silicon base or bulk silicon substrate <b>18</b> and also to anchor the semiconductor layer <b>16</b> to the substrate <b>18</b> in the frame <b>34</b>. This can be done, for example, by encapsulating these portions of the oxide layer <b>14</b> (e.g. in a deposited layer of polysilicon or silicon nitride) so that they are not exposed to the HF etchant, or by providing one or more supports for the moveable features of the MEMS device <b>40</b> which are wider than the widest moveable features <b>42</b> therein so that the oxide layer <b>14</b> will not be completely removed beneath the supports during the etching step <b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The terms &#x201c;release,&#x201d; &#x201c;released&#x201d; and &#x201c;releasing&#x201d; used herein refer to well-known terms of art which describe a process of removing a sacrificial material (e.g. by etching away an exposed portion of one or more oxide layers <b>14</b>) after build-up of the structure of a MEMS device or a microfluidic device to free up moveable elements in the MEMS device or to open up fluid channels in the microfluidic device so that these devices can operate for their intended purpose (i.e. so that the moveable elements in the MEMS device can move in response to applied forces, or so that a fluid can be conducted through the fluid channels in the microfluidic device).</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Releasing the MEMS device <b>40</b> on each die <b>12</b> prior to or at the same time the die <b>12</b> are singulated using the step <b>108</b> is advantageous singulation of the die <b>12</b> can be easily observed visually due to the relatively large size of the die <b>12</b>; whereas releasing the MEMS device <b>40</b> is not so easy to visually observe since the widest moveable features <b>42</b> of the MEMS device <b>40</b> will be much smaller. Thus, visually observing the completion of singulating the die <b>12</b> by the etching step <b>108</b> provides a convenient indicator of the completion of releasing the MEMS device <b>40</b> on the die <b>12</b>, and can be used to avoid the need for a precise timing of the etching step <b>108</b> and can also be used to avoid over etching of the oxide layer <b>14</b> beneath the MEMS device <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The use of the release fixture <b>28</b> in step <b>110</b> as discussed previously is also advantageous since it prevents the singulated die <b>12</b> from dropping down to the bottom of a tank or chamber containing the HF etchant during the etching step <b>108</b>, and instead allows the singulated die <b>12</b> to be easily removed all at once from the HF etchant while minimizing any potential damage to the singulated die <b>12</b> from handling. The use of the release fixture <b>28</b> can also hold the singulated die <b>12</b> in place during additional processing (e.g. when the HF etchant is rinsed off of the singulated die <b>12</b>, and when the die <b>12</b> are dried).</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">After the etching step <b>108</b>, the frame <b>34</b> formed from the remainder of the substrate <b>10</b> which is not used for the die <b>12</b> can be removed to leave the singulated die <b>12</b> in place in the release fixture <b>28</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3F</figref>. The singulated die <b>12</b> can be individually removed by hand (e.g. with tweezers or a vacuum wand) or using a conventional pick-and-place apparatus. The singulated die <b>12</b> can then be placed into a container (e.g. a Gel Pack container), or in a permanent package.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> shows a partial schematic cross-section view similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref>, but with the second trench <b>26</b> being laterally offset from the first trench <b>20</b> so that the semiconductor layer <b>16</b> in the die <b>12</b> being singulated extends outside of the outline around the die <b>12</b> formed by the first trench <b>20</b>. In this case, when the oxide layer <b>14</b> is etched away between the first and second trenches <b>20</b> and <b>26</b> by the etching step <b>108</b>, the singulated die <b>12</b> can be supported by the frame <b>34</b> formed from the remainder of the substrate <b>10</b> when the frame <b>34</b> and die <b>12</b> are oriented upright as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Prior to the etching step <b>108</b>, a release fixture <b>28</b> can be optionally provided over the substrate <b>10</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>. This is useful to hold the die <b>12</b> in place at any arbitrary angle during and after the etching step <b>108</b>. The release fixture <b>28</b> can optionally include one or more die pockets <b>30</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>, with the die pockets <b>30</b> having lateral dimensions which are slightly larger than the die <b>12</b> being singulated. One or more openings <b>32</b> can also be provided in the release fixture <b>28</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref> to provide access for the HF etchant to reach the oxide layer <b>14</b> through the second trench <b>26</b> about each die <b>12</b>. The release fixture <b>28</b> can be fabricated, for example, by etching a silicon substrate or, in some cases, can comprise a frame <b>34</b> from a prior etching step <b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The matter set forth in the foregoing description and accompanying drawings is offered by way of illustration only and not as a limitation. The actual scope of the invention is intended to be defined in the following claims when viewed in their proper perspective based on the prior art.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method for singulating a die from a semiconductor substrate having an oxide layer disposed on the semiconductor substrate and a semiconductor layer disposed on the oxide layer, the method comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>etching a first trench into one of the semiconductor substrate and the semiconductor layer around the die to be singulated, with the etching of the first trench being terminated proximate to the oxide layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>etching a second trench into the other of the semiconductor substrate and the semiconductor layer around the die to be singulated, with the etching of the second trench being terminated proximate to the oxide layer, and with at least a portion of the second trench being laterally offset from the first trench;</claim-text>
<claim-text>etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench and thereby singulating the die from the semiconductor substrate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a release fixture proximate to the semiconductor substrate during the step of etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the semiconductor substrate comprises monocrystalline silicon, and the semiconductor layer comprises monocrystalline silicon or polycrystalline silicon.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the oxide layer comprises silicon dioxide or a silicate glass.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the semiconductor substrate comprises a silicon-on-insulator (SOI) substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein one of the steps of etching the first trench and etching the second trench comprises etching the semiconductor layer to provide lateral dimensions of the semiconductor layer in the die to be singulated which are smaller than the lateral dimensions of the semiconductor substrate in the die.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein one of the steps of etching the first trench and etching the second trench comprises etching the semiconductor layer to provide lateral dimensions of the semiconductor layer in the die to be singulated which are larger than the lateral dimensions of the semiconductor substrate in the die.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the step of etching the first trench comprises etching the first trench using a Deep Reactive Ion Etching (DRIE) process, and the step of etching the second trench comprises etching the second trench using the DRIE process.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref> wherein the step of etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench comprises etching away the oxide layer using an etchant comprising hydrofluoric acid (HF).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the release fixture includes at least one opening therethrough, and the step of etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench comprises providing an etchant comprising hydrofluoric acid (HF) in both the first trench and the second trench.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein one of the steps of etching the first trench and etching the second trench comprises etching moveable features of a microelectromechanical system (MEMS) device located on the die to be singulated.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref> wherein the step of etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench also etches away the oxide layer beneath the moveable features of the MEMS device, thereby releasing the MEMS device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> wherein completion of the step of etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench signals completion of releasing the MEMS device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A method for singulating a die from a silicon-on-insulator (SOI) substrate having a monocrystalline silicon body, an oxide layer disposed on the monocrystalline silicon body and a monocrystalline silicon layer disposed on the oxide layer, the method comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>etching a first trench into one of the monocrystalline silicon body and the monocrystalline silicon layer, with the etching of the first trench being terminated proximate to the oxide layer, and with the first trench forming an outline about the die to be singulated from the SOI substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>etching a second trench into the other of the monocrystalline silicon body and the monocrystalline silicon layer, with the etching of the second trench being terminated proximate to the oxide layer, and with at least a portion of the second trench being laterally offset from the first trench;</claim-text>
<claim-text>etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench and thereby singulating the die from the SOI substrate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a release fixture beneath the SOI substrate to support the die after singulating the die by the step of etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> wherein one of the steps of etching the first trench and etching the second trench comprises etching the monocrystalline silicon layer in the die to be singulated to provide lateral dimensions which are smaller than the lateral dimensions of the monocrystalline silicon body in the die to be singulated.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> wherein one of the steps of etching the first trench and etching the second trench comprises etching the monocrystalline silicon layer in the die to be singulated to provide lateral dimensions which are larger than the lateral dimensions of the monocrystalline silicon body in the die to be singulated.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> wherein the step of etching the first trench comprises etching the first trench using a Deep Reactive Ion Etching (DRIE) process, and the step of etching the second trench comprises etching the second trench using the DRIE process.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref> wherein the step of etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench comprises etching away the oxide layer using an etchant comprising hydrofluoric acid (HF).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref> further comprising the step of removing the die from the HF etchant within a few minutes after singulation of the die by the step of etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> wherein one of the steps of etching the first trench and etching the second trench comprises etching moveable features of a microelectromechanical system (MEMS) device into the monocrystalline silicon layer on the die to be singulated from the SOI substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref> wherein the step of etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench also etches away the oxide layer beneath the moveable features of the MEMS device, thereby releasing the MEMS device for movement.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref> wherein completion of the step of etching away the oxide layer between the first trench and the second trench signals completion of releasing the MEMS device for movement.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> wherein the release fixture includes an opening therethrough proximate to the die to be singulated, and the step of etching away the oxide layer comprises etching away the oxide layer through both the first trench and the second trench. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
