<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624647-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624647</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12690064</doc-number>
<date>20100119</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>664</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>017</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>327175</main-classification>
<further-classification>327172</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Duty cycle correction circuit for memory interfaces in integrated circuits</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7236028</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Choi</name>
<date>20070600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>327158</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7365583</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Shin</name>
<date>20080400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7873131</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Lin et al.</name>
<date>20110100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7940103</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Satoh et al.</name>
<date>20110500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>327175</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7990194</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Shim</name>
<date>20110800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>327158</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0164920</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Cho</name>
<date>20080700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0231006</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Jang et al.</name>
<date>20090900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>327175</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>11</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110175657</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110721</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chong</last-name>
<first-name>Yan</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Huang</last-name>
<first-name>Joseph</first-name>
<address>
<city>Morgan Hill</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nagarajan</last-name>
<first-name>Pradeep</first-name>
<address>
<city>Santa Clara</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="004" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sung</last-name>
<first-name>Chiakang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Milpitas</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chong</last-name>
<first-name>Yan</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Huang</last-name>
<first-name>Joseph</first-name>
<address>
<city>Morgan Hill</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nagarajan</last-name>
<first-name>Pradeep</first-name>
<address>
<city>Santa Clara</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="004" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sung</last-name>
<first-name>Chiakang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Milpitas</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Womble Carlyle Sandridge &#x26; Rice LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altera Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Cox</last-name>
<first-name>Cassandra</first-name>
<department>2816</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Circuits and a method for correcting duty cycle distortions in an integrated circuit (IC) are disclosed. The IC includes a splitter circuit that is coupled to receive a clock signal. The clock signal is split into two different clock signals. One of the clock signals is an inverted version of the other. A delay circuit is coupled to each of the clock signals. Each of the delay circuits generates a delayed version of the corresponding clock signal. A corrector circuit is coupled to receive both the delayed versions of the clock signals. The corrector circuit generates a clock output signal with a corrected duty cycle.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="76.12mm" wi="146.39mm" file="US08624647-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="107.61mm" wi="174.41mm" file="US08624647-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="242.49mm" wi="181.86mm" file="US08624647-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="162.81mm" wi="184.57mm" file="US08624647-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="227.50mm" wi="175.77mm" file="US08624647-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="244.52mm" wi="160.10mm" file="US08624647-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="118.53mm" wi="173.74mm" file="US08624647-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="202.35mm" wi="131.49mm" file="US08624647-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">In digital circuits, the clock signal synchronizes communication between different parts within the circuit and between different circuits. Circuits designed to operate with the clock signal may respond at the rising or falling edge of the clock signal. Single data-rate (SDR) memory interfaces normally utilize only either the rising or falling edge to transfer data. Double data-rate (DDR) memory interfaces, on the other hand, transfer data on both the rising edge and falling edge of the clock signal. Thus, the data transfer rate in a DDR memory interface is twice as fast as the transfer rate of a regular SDR memory interface.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">As data rates increase, duty cycle distortions may be problematic as the size of the window, during which valid data may be captured, may be reduced and potentially lead to the loss of data. A duty cycle is the fraction of time that the clock or system is in an &#x201c;active&#x201d; state. A substantially symmetrical duty cycle is required for most high speed applications as asymmetric duty cycles will make the synchronization of all the clocks in a system more difficult. A symmetrical duty cycle or a 50% duty cycle means each clock period has equal high and low periods. In other words, a clock signal with 50% duty cycle spends half the clock period at logic 1 and the other half at logic 0.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Various duty correction techniques are usually employed to correct duty cycle distortions. Static delay chains that can delay rising and falling edges of the clock signal are generally used. However, as duty cycle distortions normally vary from device to device, it is difficult to use one static delay setting to correct duty cycle distortions in different devices. It is also difficult to find the correct settings for devices operating under different process, voltage and temperature (PVT) conditions as duty cycle distortions also vary under different PVT conditions.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Therefore, it is desirable to have a duty cycle correction circuit that can automatically correct duty cycle distortions in different devices operating under different PVT conditions. It is within this context that the invention arises.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Embodiments of the present invention include circuits and a method for correcting duty cycle distortions in an integrated circuit (IC).</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">It should be appreciated that the present invention can be implemented in numerous ways, such as a process an apparatus, a system, a device or a method on a computer readable medium. Several inventive embodiments of the present invention are described below.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In one embodiment, an IC with a corrector circuit is disclosed. The IC includes a splitter circuit that receives a clock signal and splits the clock signal into two different clock signals. In one embodiment, one of the clock signals is an inverted version of the other. Each of the clock signals is coupled to a delay circuit. Each of the delay circuits generates a delayed version of the corresponding clock signal. A corrector circuit is coupled to both the delayed versions of the clock signals to generate a clock output signal based on the delayed versions of the clock signals. The generated clock output signal has a corrected duty cycle.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In yet another embodiment in accordance with the present invention, a duty cycle correction circuit is provided. The circuit includes a latch and pulse generator circuits. One pulse generator circuit is coupled to receive a first clock signal. A first pulse signal is generated by the pulse generator circuit based on the first clock signal. Another pulse generator circuit is coupled to receive a second clock signal. A second pulse signal is generated by the pulse generator circuit based on the second clock signal. The latch receives the two pulse signals and generates a clock output signal with a corrected duty cycle based on the two pulse signals.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In an alternative embodiment in accordance with the present invention, a method of operating an IC is provided. The method includes splitting a clock signal into two different clock signals. A delay is applied to each of the two clock signals to generate delayed versions of the two clock signals. Two pulse signals are generated based on each of the delayed versions of the two clock signals. The generated pulse signals transition from one logic level to another based on the transition of the delayed version of the corresponding clock signal. A clock output with a corrected duty cycle is generated based on the first and second pulse signals.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Other aspects of the invention will become apparent from the following detailed description, taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, illustrating by way of example the principles of the invention.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The invention may best be understood by reference to the following description taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings in which:</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows an exemplary waveform of a clock signal with an uneven duty cycle and an exemplary waveform of a clock signal with an even duty cycle.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, meant to be illustrative and not limiting, shows an exemplary circuit with duty corrector circuits for a memory interface in an IC as one embodiment in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>, meant to be illustrative and not limiting, shows a memory interface read path circuit as one embodiment in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, meant to be illustrative and not limiting, shows a more detailed representation of a leveling block as one embodiment in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, meant to be illustrative and not limiting, shows a more detailed representation of a delay chain as one embodiment in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, meant to be illustrative and not limiting, shows a more detailed representation of a corrector circuit as one embodiment in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>, meant to be illustrative and not limiting, shows a more detailed representation of a splitter circuit as one embodiment in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>, meant to be illustrative and not limiting, shows a more detailed representation of a pulse generator circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</figref>, meant to be illustrative and not limiting, shows a detailed representation of a latch as one embodiment in the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, meant to be illustrative and not limiting, shows exemplary waveforms that describe the relationship between the clock signal, the inverted version of the clock signal, the set pulse signal, the reset pulse signal and the clock output signal.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, meant to be illustrative and not limiting, is a simplified flow chart that shows a method flow for operating an IC as another embodiment in accordance with the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Embodiments of the present invention include circuits and a method for correcting duty cycle distortions in an integrated circuit (IC).</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">It will be obvious, however, to one skilled in the art, that the present invention may be practiced without some or all of these specific details. In other instances, well-known operations have not been described in detail in order not to unnecessarily obscure the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The embodiments described herein provide circuits and techniques to correct duty cycle distortions in an IC to generate a clock signal with approximately 50% duty cycle across all PVT ranges. It should be appreciated that in high speed applications, e.g., high speed memory interfaces like DDR3, a 50%, or close to 50%, duty cycle is required to ensure that the transmission window is wide enough to ensure that data is appropriately captured. In high speed applications, clock signals with an asymmetric duty cycle may make data synchronization more difficult. The disclosed embodiments provide a dynamic duty cycle correction circuit that can easily correct duty cycle distortions in clock signals within an IC device. One embodiment describes a duty cycle correction circuit in an IC that splits a clock signal into two different clock signals and uses the two clock signals to generate a symmetrical, or substantially symmetrical, output clock signal. Another embodiment describes a duty cycle correction circuit that uses two signal pulses and a latch to generate a substantially symmetrical clock signal.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows exemplary waveform <b>100</b> of an asymmetrical clock signal and waveform <b>110</b> of a symmetrical clock signal. Waveform <b>100</b> has an uneven period of high and low for each clock period. Interval T as shown on waveform <b>100</b> is the clock period of the clock signal. One skilled in the art understands that one clock period refers to the period from one rising/falling edge to the next rising/falling edge. The duty cycle parameter specifies the relative duration of the logic high output during each clock period. As shown in waveform <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, each clock period T has a relatively shorter logic high duration compared to its logic low duration. As explained before, a symmetrical clock signal has a substantially 50% duty cycle. In other words, each clock period T should have an equal, or almost equal, duration of logic high and logic low outputs. Exemplary waveform <b>110</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a symmetrical clock signal. Each clock period T on waveform <b>110</b> has an even duration of high and low outputs. As such, waveform <b>110</b> is a waveform of a symmetrical clock signal with a 50% duty cycle.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, meant to be illustrative and not limiting, shows exemplary circuit <b>200</b> with duty corrector circuits for a memory interface in an IC as one embodiment in accordance with the present invention. One skilled in the art should appreciate that the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> shows the write path of a memory interface in an IC and output pins <b>250</b>A and <b>250</b>B may be connected to an external memory module. One skilled in the art should also appreciate that output pins <b>250</b>A and <b>250</b>B may represent the data (DQ) pin and the data strobe (DQS) pin, respectively. The embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> shows leveling block <b>210</b> coupled to I/O registers <b>240</b>A and <b>240</b>B through logic block <b>230</b>. Clock signal <b>202</b> is coupled to leveling block <b>210</b>. In one embodiment, leveling block <b>210</b> includes a delay chain that is coupled to receive clock signal <b>202</b>. In an exemplary embodiment, the delay chain is a plurality of buffers connected in series that generates a plurality of delayed versions of clock signal <b>202</b>. Output <b>212</b> of delay locked-loop (DLL) <b>215</b> is coupled to leveling block <b>210</b>. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, DLL <b>215</b> is coupled to an enable input of each of the plurality of buffers in leveling block <b>210</b>, details of which will be explained in later paragraphs. In one embodiment, leveling block <b>210</b> is a current-starved delay chain. DLL <b>215</b> outputs and sends a delay setting to leveling block <b>210</b> to control the delay of each leveling stage and the delay setting is maintained across different PVT conditions. Leveling block <b>210</b> generates multiple delayed versions of clock signal <b>202</b> as outputs <b>214</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, outputs <b>214</b> are connected to corrector circuits <b>220</b>. In one embodiment, each of corrector circuits <b>220</b> includes a set/reset (SR) latch. An output of each of corrector circuits <b>220</b> is coupled to selector circuits <b>235</b>A and <b>235</b>B. Select inputs <b>234</b>A and <b>234</b>B of selector circuits <b>235</b>A and <b>235</b>B, respectively, control which of the plurality of inputs <b>231</b> is selected as an output for selector circuits <b>235</b>A and <b>235</b>B. Outputs <b>237</b>A and <b>237</b>B are coupled to I/O registers <b>240</b>A and <b>240</b>B, respectively. I/O registers <b>240</b>A and <b>240</b>B include multiple storage circuits or registers connected to various logic elements. Outputs <b>237</b>A and <b>237</b>B are connected to the clock terminals of registers <b>244</b>A-<b>244</b>H in I/O registers <b>240</b>A and <b>240</b>B, respectively. In one embodiment, I/O registers <b>244</b>A-<b>244</b>H are triggered by edges of the clock output signals from corrector circuits <b>220</b>. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, output <b>237</b>A is connected to the clock terminals of registers <b>244</b>A-<b>244</b>D, and select input <b>243</b>C of selector circuit <b>242</b>C in I/O register <b>240</b>A. Registers <b>244</b>A and <b>244</b>B, coupled to logic gate <b>246</b>A and selector circuit <b>242</b>A, control enable terminal <b>249</b>A of output buffer <b>245</b>A. Output buffer <b>245</b>A is coupled to output pin DQ <b>250</b>A. Registers <b>244</b>C and <b>244</b>D are coupled to output buffer <b>245</b>A through selector circuits <b>242</b>C and <b>242</b>B. Input terminal <b>241</b>B of register <b>244</b>B is coupled to the output of register <b>244</b>A. One skilled in the art should appreciate that input terminals <b>241</b>A, <b>241</b>C and <b>241</b>D may be connected to the core of the IC that may provide either a logic high or a logic low level. One skilled in the art should also appreciate that selector circuits <b>242</b>A and <b>242</b>B can be used to bypass registers <b>244</b>A-<b>244</b>D, logic gate <b>246</b>A and selector circuit <b>242</b>C. In one embodiment, select inputs <b>243</b>A and <b>243</b>B are connected to a static value or a configuration random access memory (CRAM) bit to control the output of selector circuits <b>242</b>A and <b>242</b>B, respectively. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, input terminals <b>247</b>A and <b>247</b>B are coupled to the core the IC. One skilled in the art should appreciate that input terminals <b>247</b>A and <b>247</b>B may be connected to registers in the core of the IC. The output of selector circuit <b>242</b>A enables and disables output buffer <b>245</b>A and the output of selector circuit <b>242</b>B carries output data from I/O register <b>240</b>A to output pin DQ <b>250</b>A through output buffer <b>245</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, I/O register <b>240</b>B shares similarities with I/O register <b>240</b>A. For the sake of brevity, elements shown in I/O register <b>240</b>A and described above, e.g., registers <b>244</b>E-<b>244</b>F, input terminals <b>241</b>E-<b>241</b>H, input terminals <b>247</b>D and <b>247</b>E, select inputs <b>243</b>D and <b>243</b>E, selector circuits <b>242</b>D-<b>242</b>F and logic gate <b>246</b>B, are not repeated or described in detail here. Selector circuit <b>235</b>B of logic block <b>230</b> selects one of the delayed versions of the clock signal from leveling block <b>210</b> as an output signal. In one embodiment, select input <b>234</b>B is coupled to a core logic block in the IC. The core logic block controls select input <b>234</b>B and selects different phases during a calibration process in order to determine a suitable phase for the clock signal <b>202</b>. In another embodiment, select input <b>234</b>A of selector circuit <b>235</b>A selects one of input signals <b>231</b> as output <b>237</b>A according to a selection of selector circuit <b>235</b>B. For example, selector circuit <b>235</b>A may select a phase shifted version of the input signal <b>231</b> that is selected as output <b>237</b>B of selector circuit <b>235</b>B. In an exemplary embodiment, outputs <b>237</b>A and <b>237</b>B are substantially 90&#xb0; out of phase alignment. Output <b>237</b>B is coupled to the clock terminals of registers <b>244</b>E-<b>244</b>H in I/O register <b>240</b>B. Outputs of selector circuits <b>242</b>D and <b>242</b>E in I/O register <b>240</b>B are connected to enable terminal <b>249</b>B and output buffer <b>245</b>B, respectively. Output buffer <b>245</b>B is connected to output pin <b>250</b>B. In one embodiment, output pins <b>250</b>A and <b>250</b>B are DQ and DQS pins, respectively, and both DQ and DQS pins are connected to an external memory module. One skilled in the art should appreciate that DQ and DQS signals are used in DDR memory interfaces. One skilled in the art should also appreciate that when a memory interface in an IC writes to a memory module, DQS is asserted when DQ pins have data to be written to the memory module.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>, meant to be illustrative and not limiting, shows circuit <b>290</b> as one embodiment in accordance with the present invention. For the sake of brevity, elements already shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> and described above, e.g., leveling block <b>210</b>, DLL block <b>215</b>, corrector circuit <b>220</b>, and selector circuits <b>235</b>A and <b>235</b>B, will not be described in detail here. One skilled in the art should appreciate that circuit <b>290</b> represents a read path of a memory interface circuit in an IC. As such, well known elements are not described in detail so as to not obscure the present invention. In one embodiment, pins <b>280</b>A and <b>280</b>B are connected to an external memory module and pins <b>280</b>A and <b>280</b>B are input pins that read data from the memory module to the IC. In one such embodiment, pin <b>280</b>A may be a DQS pin and pin <b>280</b>B may be a DQ pin. Pin <b>280</b>A is coupled to input buffer <b>265</b>A that receives signals transmitted from pin <b>280</b>A. Signals from input buffer <b>265</b>A are transmitted to delay chain <b>270</b>. In one embodiment, delay chain <b>270</b> includes several buffers connected in series to produce a delayed version, or a phase shifted version, of the input signal. Corrector circuit <b>220</b> corrects distortions in the phase shifted clock signal to produce a clock signal with a substantially 50% duty cycle. The output from delay chain <b>270</b> is connected to corrector circuit <b>220</b>. In one embodiment, the output from delay chain <b>270</b> includes a delayed version of the input signal and an inverted version of the delayed version of the same signal. Details of delay chain <b>270</b> and corrector circuit <b>220</b>, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3B and 4</figref>, respectively, will be described in later paragraphs. The output of corrector circuit <b>220</b> is coupled to one of the input terminals of logic gate <b>264</b>B and the clock terminal of register <b>262</b>C. One skilled in the art should appreciate that the clock terminal of register <b>262</b>C is an active low terminal, in one embodiment. In other words, in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>, register <b>262</b>C is triggered by the falling edges of the received clock signal.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>, register <b>262</b>C outputs a logic high signal and is connected to one of the other input terminals of logic gate <b>264</b>B. Selector circuit <b>235</b>B selects a DQS enable signal to control registers <b>262</b>A and <b>262</b>B. In one embodiment, the DQS enable signal is also known as a postamble clock signal. It should be appreciated that the postamble clock signal is a clock signal that has been calibrated to achieve correct timing for the DQS enable signal. The output of selector circuit <b>235</b>B is connected to the clock terminals of selector circuits <b>262</b>A and <b>262</b>B. Selector circuits <b>262</b>A and <b>262</b>B are coupled to logic gate <b>264</b>A to control the clear terminal of register <b>262</b>C. Register <b>262</b>C is cleared when registers <b>262</b>A and <b>262</b>B are enabled. In one embodiment, registers <b>262</b>A and <b>262</b>B, together with logic gate <b>264</b>A, are enabled only when circuit <b>290</b> is reading from a memory module in order to prevent glitches in the circuit when circuit <b>290</b> is not reading from the memory module. In another embodiment, the postamble signal from selector circuit <b>235</b>B gates pin <b>280</b>A to prevent glitches or false edges in the clock signal.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>, pin <b>280</b>B is connected to input buffer <b>265</b>B. In one embodiment, pin <b>280</b>B is a DQ pin that reads data from an external memory module and transmits that data to input register <b>285</b>. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>, input register <b>285</b> includes a few storage elements, or registers, <b>262</b>D-<b>262</b>H, that are connected to each other as illustrated. Data or signals received at pin <b>280</b>B are transmitted through input buffer <b>265</b>B to registers <b>262</b>D-<b>262</b>H. Registers <b>262</b>F, <b>262</b>G and <b>262</b>H are controlled by the corrected clock output signal from logic gate <b>264</b>B. The clock output signal may be connected to delay circuits <b>280</b>. One skilled in the art should appreciate that delay circuits <b>280</b> are simple delay chains, e.g., two inverters coupled in series, that are used to correct or reduce clock skews in the circuit. As such, delay circuits <b>280</b> may be bypassed when the skew is substantially low. It should be appreciated that circuit <b>290</b> may be connected to an external memory module that operates with a different clock domain. Therefore, in one embodiment, registers <b>262</b>D and <b>262</b>E are used to resynchronize the clock signal from the external memory module with the clock signal within the system in this embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, meant to be illustrative and not limiting, shows a more detailed representation of leveling block <b>210</b> as one embodiment in accordance with the present invention. Clock signal <b>202</b> is connected to splitter circuit <b>310</b>. Splitter circuit <b>310</b> splits clock input signal <b>202</b> to generate two different clock signals <b>312</b>A and <b>312</b>B. In one embodiment, clock signal <b>312</b>E is an inverted version of clock signal <b>312</b>A. The two clock signals, i.e., <b>312</b>A and <b>312</b>B, are coupled to leveling delay blocks <b>210</b>A and <b>210</b>B. Each of leveling delay blocks <b>210</b>A and <b>210</b>B includes multiple delay buffers <b>211</b> connected in series. Each of buffers <b>211</b> generates a delayed version of the corresponding clock signals <b>312</b>A and <b>312</b>B. The output from each of buffers <b>211</b> is connected to corrector circuit <b>220</b>. DLL block <b>215</b> is connected to each of buffers <b>211</b> in leveling delay blocks <b>210</b>A and <b>210</b>B. Each of corrector circuits <b>220</b> outputs a clock signal with a corrected duty cycle based on the corresponding delayed clock signals from leveling delay blocks <b>210</b>A and <b>210</b>B. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, the clock signal generated by each of corrector circuits <b>220</b> is coupled to selector circuit <b>235</b>A and <b>235</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, meant to be illustrative and not limiting, shows a more detailed representation of delay chain <b>270</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref> as one embodiment in accordance with the present invention. DLL block <b>215</b> is connected to each of delay chains <b>270</b>A and <b>270</b>B. Terminal DQSIN <b>305</b> is connected to input buffer <b>265</b>A of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>. Splitter circuit <b>310</b> splits the clock signal received at terminal DQSIN <b>305</b> into clock signals <b>312</b>A and <b>312</b>B. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, clock signal <b>312</b>E is an inverted version of clock signal <b>312</b>A. Each of delay chains <b>270</b>A and <b>270</b>B includes multiple buffers <b>211</b> connected in series. The output from each of the buffers <b>211</b> in delay chain <b>270</b>A and <b>270</b>B is connected to selector circuit <b>275</b>A and <b>275</b>B, respectively. The output from each of delay chains <b>270</b>A and <b>270</b>B is connected to corrector circuit <b>220</b>. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, corrector circuit <b>220</b> generates a clock signal with a corrected duty cycle based on the clock signals from delay chains <b>270</b>A and <b>270</b>B. The clock signal with the corrected duty cycle is connected to logic gate <b>264</b>B and register <b>262</b>C in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>. Even though only three buffers <b>211</b> are shown in leveling blocks <b>210</b>A and <b>210</b>B of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, and delay chains <b>270</b>A and <b>270</b>B of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, one skilled in the art should appreciate that the required number of buffers may vary across different circuits for different applications. Thus, more or fewer buffers <b>211</b> can be used in leveling blocks <b>210</b>A and <b>210</b>B and delay chains <b>270</b>A and <b>270</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, meant to be illustrative and not limiting, shows a more detailed representation of corrector circuit <b>220</b> as one embodiment in accordance with the present invention. Corrector circuit <b>220</b> includes two pulse generator circuits, <b>415</b>A and <b>415</b>B, connected to latch <b>420</b>. Clock signals <b>405</b>A and <b>405</b>B are similar to the output signals from leveling blocks <b>210</b>A, <b>210</b>B and delay chains <b>270</b>A and <b>270</b>B in the embodiments of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A and 3B</figref>. Clock signals <b>405</b>A and <b>405</b>B are connected to pulse generator circuits <b>415</b>A and <b>415</b>B, respectively. Pulse generator circuits <b>415</b>A and <b>415</b>B generate relatively small pulses based on clock signals <b>405</b>A and <b>405</b>B, respectively. Details of how the pulses are generated are discussed with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, latch <b>420</b> is an SR-latch and pulse generator <b>415</b>A is connected to the set terminal of latch <b>420</b> while pulse generator <b>415</b>B is connected to the reset terminal of latch <b>420</b>. In one embodiment, pulse generators <b>415</b>A and <b>415</b>B generate non-overlapping set and reset signals, respectively. In an exemplary embodiment, output <b>425</b> of SR-latch <b>420</b> is a clock signal with a corrected duty cycle that is generated based on the pulses from pulse generators <b>415</b>A and <b>415</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>, meant to be illustrative and not limiting, shows a more detailed representation of splitter circuit <b>310</b> as one embodiment in accordance with the present invention. Splitter circuit <b>310</b> includes pass gate <b>510</b> and inverter <b>520</b>. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>, pass gate <b>510</b> is a complementary metal-oxide-semiconductor (CMOS) pass gate. Splitter circuit <b>310</b> receives a clock signal, CLKin signal <b>505</b>, and splits the signal into CLK <b>512</b> and CLKB <b>522</b> signals. CLKin signal <b>505</b> is transmitted through pass gate <b>510</b> and inverter <b>520</b>. Inverter <b>520</b> inverts CLKin signal <b>505</b> to generate CLKB signal <b>522</b>. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>, clock signal CLKB <b>522</b> is an inverted version of clock signal CLK <b>512</b>. Each of clock signals CLK <b>512</b> and CLKB <b>522</b> may be connected to a leveling delay block or a delay chain as shown in the embodiments of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A and 3B</figref>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>, meant to be illustrative and not limiting, shows a more detailed representation of pulse generator circuit <b>415</b>. Input signal IN <b>532</b> is connected to configurable delay chain circuit <b>550</b> in pulse generator circuit <b>415</b>. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>, input signal IN <b>532</b> may be connected to either clock signal CLK <b>512</b> or clock signal CLKB <b>522</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>. Configurable delay chain circuit <b>550</b> controls the width of the pulses that are generated by pulse generator circuit <b>415</b>. The signal from configurable delay chain circuit <b>550</b> is inverted by inverter <b>520</b> and connected to logic gate <b>560</b>. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>, logic gate <b>560</b> is an AND gate that receives the inverted signal from configurable delay chain circuit <b>550</b> and input signal IN <b>532</b>. Output signal OUT <b>562</b> is generated based on a logic state of input signal IN <b>532</b> and the inverted signal from configurable delay chain circuit <b>550</b>. In an exemplary embodiment, output signal OUT <b>562</b> is a signal with relatively small pulses. Output signal OUT <b>562</b> may be connected to a latch. In the illustrative embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, output signals from pulse generators <b>415</b>A and <b>415</b>B are connected to the set and reset terminals, respectively, of latch <b>420</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</figref>, meant to be illustrative and not limiting, shows a detailed representation of latch <b>420</b> as one embodiment in the present invention. It should be appreciated that in one embodiment, latch <b>420</b> is an SR-latch and as such, well-known elements of such a latch are not described in detail so as not to obscure the present invention unnecessarily. Latch <b>420</b> includes two inverters, <b>520</b>A and <b>520</b>B, and two NAND gates, <b>570</b>A and <b>570</b>B. Pass gate <b>510</b> is coupled to the output of inverter <b>520</b>A and an input of NAND gate <b>570</b>A. In one embodiment, pass gate <b>510</b> is used to equalize the signal paths from input signal S <b>562</b>A to output OUT <b>572</b> and input signal R <b>562</b>B to output OUT <b>572</b>. Input signal S <b>562</b>A and input signal R <b>562</b>B are generated by a pulse generator circuit. In the illustrative embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, input signal S <b>562</b>A is generated by pulse generator <b>415</b>A while input signal R <b>562</b>B is generated by pulse generator <b>415</b>B. In one embodiment, output OUT <b>572</b> of latch <b>420</b> is a clock signal with a substantially 50% duty cycle that is generated based on the pulses from input signal S <b>562</b>A and input signal R <b>562</b>B. Even though a latch is used in this embodiment, one skilled in the art should appreciate that similar logic or storage elements that perform similar functions can be used in place of a latch in this context.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, meant to be illustrative and not limiting, shows exemplary waveforms <b>610</b>, <b>620</b>, <b>630</b>, <b>640</b> and <b>650</b> that describe the relationship between the clock input signal, the inverted version of the clock signal, the set pulse signal, the reset pulse signal and the clock output signal in accordance with one embodiment of the invention. Waveform <b>610</b> is an exemplary waveform of a clock input signal and waveform <b>620</b> is an exemplary waveform of the inverted version of the clock input signal. In one embodiment, the clock input signal is a phase shifted clock signal with a delay and the inverted version of the clock input signal is an inverted version of the phase shifted clock signal with the delay. In one embodiment, the clock input signal is a clock output signal from one of buffers <b>211</b> in leveling block <b>210</b>A and the inverted version of the clock output signal from one of buffers <b>211</b> in leveling block <b>210</b>B of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the clock input signal as represented by waveform <b>610</b> does not have a 50% duty cycle as each clock period, T, does not have an equal period of logic high and logic low level. In the illustrative embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the clock input signal has a substantially longer logic high period in each clock period, T. As such, it should be appreciated that the inverted version of the clock signal as represented by waveform <b>620</b> also does not have a 50% duty cycle.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, waveform <b>630</b> shows the generated set signal. In the illustrative embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the set signal as represented by waveform <b>630</b> is an active-high signal with substantially short active pulses. One skilled in the art should appreciate that an active-high signal is considered &#x201c;active&#x201d; when it is at a logic high level, i.e., logic 1. In this instance, the set signal as represented by waveform <b>630</b> is active when waveform <b>630</b> is at a logic high state. Waveform <b>640</b> shows the generated reset signal with relatively short pulses. In the illustrative embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the set signal <b>630</b> changes from a logic low level to a logic high level when the clock input signal <b>610</b> transitions from a logic low level to a logic high level. The reset signal <b>640</b> changes from a logic low level to a logic high level when the inverted version of the clock input signal <b>620</b> transitions from a logic low level to a logic high level. In an exemplary embodiment, the width, W, of pulses in the set signal and reset signal as represented by waveforms <b>630</b> and <b>640</b>, respectively, can be adjusted. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>, configurable delay chain circuit <b>550</b> is used to adjust the width, W, of each of the set <b>630</b> and reset <b>640</b> pulses. In one embodiment, the width, W, of each of the set <b>630</b> and reset <b>640</b> pulses are less than &#xbd; period, &#xbd; T, of the clock input signal <b>610</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, waveform <b>650</b> shows a generated clock output signal with a substantially 50% duty cycle, i.e., equal periods of high and low logic levels. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the clock output signal <b>650</b> is generated based on the set <b>630</b> and reset <b>640</b> signals. The clock output signal <b>650</b> changes from a logic low level to a logic high level when the set signal <b>630</b> changes from a logic low level to a logic high level. When the reset signal <b>640</b> changes from a logic low level to a logic high level, the clock output signal <b>650</b> transitions from a logic high level to a logic low level to achieve a substantially 50% duty cycle. In the illustrative embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</figref>, the set and reset pulses as represented by waveforms <b>630</b> and <b>640</b>, respectively, are used to set and reset latch <b>420</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</figref>. Output OUT <b>572</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</figref> represents the clock output signal shown in waveform <b>650</b>. Each clock period, T, of the clock output signal in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> has a substantially 50% duty cycle. In an exemplary embodiment, the clock output signal has a duty cycle that is not worse than 45/55.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, meant to be illustrative and not limiting, is a simplified flow chart that shows method flow <b>700</b> for operating an IC as another embodiment in accordance with the present invention. A first clock signal is split in operation <b>710</b> to generate second and third clock signals. In the illustrative embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, CLKin signal <b>202</b> is split into CLK signal <b>312</b>A and CLKB signal <b>312</b>B by splitter circuit <b>310</b>. The third clock signal may be an inverted version of the second clock signal, in one embodiment. A delay is applied to the second and third clock signals to generate delayed versions of the second and third clock signals in operation <b>720</b>. In an exemplary embodiment, the delayed versions of the second and third clock signals are phase shifted versions of the second and third clock signals. In the illustrative embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, the delayed version of the clock signal is generated by leveling block <b>210</b>. A pulse signal is generated based on the delayed version of the second clock signal in operation <b>730</b>. In one embodiment, the pulse signal has relatively small pulses of logic high level and the width of each of the pulses is less than half of the width of the logic high pulse of the second clock signal. A configurable delay chain circuit, e.g., configurable delay <b>550</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>, may used to adjust the width of each of the pulses. In another embodiment, the pulse signal is a set pulse signal that is used to set a latch, such as SR-latch <b>420</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</figref>. The pulse signal transitions from a logic low level to a logic high level when the second clock signal transitions from a logic low level to a logic high level. In the illustrative embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, waveform <b>630</b> shows a representation of the pulse signal.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, another pulse signal is generated in operation <b>740</b>. This pulse signal is generated based on the third clock signal. In an exemplary embodiment, the pulse signal generated in operation <b>740</b> is a reset pulse signal that transitions from a logic low level to a logic high level when the third clock signal transitions from a logic low level to a logic high level. The reset pulse signal is represented by waveform <b>640</b> in the illustrative embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. The reset pulse signal is used to reset latch <b>420</b> in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</figref>. A clock output signal is generated in operation <b>750</b>. The clock output signal, generated based on the two pulse signals generated in operations <b>730</b> and <b>740</b>, has a corrected duty cycle. In the illustrative embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the clock output signal is represented by waveform <b>650</b>. In one embodiment, the rising edges of the clock output signal occurs substantially contemporaneously with the rising edges of the pulse signal generated in operation <b>730</b> while the falling edges of the clock output signal occurs substantially contemporaneously with the rising edges of the pulse signal generated in operation <b>740</b>. In another embodiment, the clock output signal is a clock signal with a substantially symmetrical, i.e., close to 50%, duty cycle.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The embodiments, thus far, were described with respect to integrated circuits. The method and apparatus described herein may be incorporated into any suitable circuit. For example, the method and apparatus may be incorporated into numerous types of devices such as microprocessors or programmable logic devices. Exemplary programmable logic devices include programmable array logic (PAL), programmable logic array (PLA), field programmable logic array (FPLA), electrically programmable logic devices (EPLD), electrically erasable programmable logic device (EEPLD), logic cell array (LCA), field programmable gate array (FPGA), application specific standard product (ASSP), application specific integrated circuit (ASIC), just to name a few.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The programmable logic device described herein may be part of a data processing system that includes one or more of the following components; a processor; memory; I/O circuitry; and peripheral devices. The data processing system can be used in a wide variety of applications, such as computer networking, data networking, instrumentation, video processing, digital signal processing, or any suitable other application where the advantage of using programmable or re-programmable logic is desirable. The programmable logic device can be used to perform a variety of different logic functions. For example, the programmable logic device can be configured as a processor or controller that works in cooperation with a system processor. The programmable logic device may also be used as an arbiter for arbitrating access to a shared resource in the data processing system. In yet another example, the programmable logic device can be configured as an interface between a processor and one of the other components in the system. In one embodiment, the programmable logic device may be one of the devices owned by the assignee.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Although the method operations were described in a specific order, it should be understood that other operations may be performed in between described operations, described operations may be adjusted so that they occur at slightly different times or described operations may be distributed in a system which allows the occurrence of the processing operations at various intervals associated with the processing, as long as the processing of the overlay operations are performed in a desired way.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Although the foregoing invention has been described in some detail for purposes of clarity of understanding, it will be apparent that certain changes and modifications can be practiced within the scope of the appended claims. Accordingly, the present embodiments are to be considered as illustrative and not restrictive, and the invention is not to be limited to the details given herein, but may be modified within the scope and equivalents of the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An integrated circuit (IC), comprising:
<claim-text>a splitter circuit coupled to receive a first clock signal, wherein the splitter circuit generates a second clock signal and a third clock signal based on the first clock signal, and wherein the splitter comprises a pass gate coupled to receive the first clock signal, the pass gate generating the second clock signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first delay circuit coupled to receive the second clock signal, wherein the first delay circuit generates a delayed version of the second clock signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second delay circuit coupled to receive the third clock signal, wherein the second delay circuit generates a delayed version of the third clock signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a corrector circuit coupled to receive the delayed versions of the second and third clock signals, wherein the corrector circuit generates a clock output signal with a duty cycle modified relative to the first clock signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The IC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a first selector circuit coupled to receive the clock output signal from each of a plurality of the corrector circuit, wherein the first selector circuit selects and outputs a first corrected clock output signal from one of the plurality of corrector circuits; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second selector circuit coupled to receive the clock output signal from each of the plurality of the corrector circuits, wherein the second selector circuit selects and outputs a second corrected clock output signal from another of the plurality of the corrector circuits.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The IC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the second corrected clock output signal is a phase shifted version of the output first corrected clock output signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The IC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the first corrected clock output signal and the second corrected clock output signal are substantially 90 degrees out of phase alignment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The IC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of storage circuits coupled to receive the first and second corrected clock output signals, wherein the plurality of storage circuits is triggered by transitioning edges of the first and second corrected clock output signals.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The IC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the corrector circuit comprises an SR-latch.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The IC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the splitter circuit comprises:
<claim-text>an inverter coupled to receive the first clock signal, the inverter generating the third clock signal, wherein the third clock signal is an inverted version of the second clock signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The IC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second delay circuits each includes a plurality of buffers coupled in series.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A duty cycle correction circuit, comprising:
<claim-text>a first pulse generator circuit coupled to receive a first clock signal, wherein the first pulse generator circuit generates a first pulse signal based on the first clock signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pulse generator circuit coupled to receive a second clock signal, wherein the second pulse generator circuit generates a second pulse signal based on the second clock signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a latch coupled to receive the first and second pulse signals, wherein the latch generates a clock output signal having a modified duty cycle relative to a clock input signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The IC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a splitter circuit coupled to receive the clock input signal, wherein the splitter circuit splits the clock input signal into third and fourth clock signals; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a delay chain circuit coupled to receive each of the third and fourth clock signals, wherein the delay chain circuit generates a delayed version for each of the third and fourth clock signals as the first and second clock signals, respectively.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The IC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the delay circuit comprises a plurality of buffers coupled in series and a selector circuit coupled to receive an output from each of the plurality of buffers.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The IC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the second clock signal is an inverted version of the first clock signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The IC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the first pulse signal sets the latch and the second pulse signal resets the latch.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The IC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second pulse generator circuits each comprises:
<claim-text>a configurable delay chain circuit coupled to receive one of the first or second clock signals;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an inverter coupled to an output of the configurable delay chain; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a logic gate coupled to an output of the inverter and one of the first or second clock signals,</claim-text>
<claim-text>whereby each of the first and second pulse generators generate pulses having a smaller width than pulses of the clock input signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The IC of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the configurable delay chain circuit controls a width of the first and second pulse signals.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A method of operating an integrated circuit (IC), comprising:
<claim-text>splitting a first clock signal to generate second and third clock signals;</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a delay to the second and third clock signals to generate delayed versions of the second and third clock signals;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a first pulse signal based on the delayed version of the second clock signal, wherein the first pulse signal transitions from a first logic level to a second logic level according to a transition of the second clock signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a second pulse signal based on the delayed version of the third clock signal, wherein the second pulse signal transitions from the first logic level to the second logic level according to a transition of the third clock signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a clock output signal with a modified duty cycle relative to the first clock signal, wherein the clock output signal is a phase shifted version of the first clock signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein a width of the first pulse signal is less than half of a width of the second clock signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein a rising edge of the clock output signal occurs substantially contemporaneously with a rising edge of the first pulse signal and a falling edge of the output clock signal occurs substantially contemporaneously as a rising edge of the second pulse signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the third clock signal is an inverted version of the second clock signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the generating the first and second pulse signals includes setting a latch when the second clock signal transitions from the first logic level to the second logic level and resetting the latch when the third clock signal transitions from the first logic level to the second logic level. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
