<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622495-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622495</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13049031</doc-number>
<date>20110316</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-060918</doc-number>
<date>20100317</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>271</us-term-extension>
<disclaimer>
<text>This patent is subject to a terminal disclaimer.</text>
</disclaimer>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>29</main-group>
<subgroup>38</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>25</main-group>
<subgroup>308</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>2</main-group>
<subgroup>01</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347  8</main-classification>
<further-classification>347 16</further-classification>
<further-classification>347101</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e73">Paper floating detection apparatus and inkjet recording apparatus</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2012/0050373</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Korogi et al.</name>
<date>20120300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347 16</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>199 06 343</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19990900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2004-299155</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20041000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2007-76109</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20070300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2007-98650</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20070400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2008-126155</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20080600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-76872</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20100400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00008">
<othercit>US Office Action, dated Sep. 24, 2013, for U.S. Appl. No. 13/221,555.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>17</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347  4</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347  8</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 16</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 19</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347101</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>14</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>16</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110227985</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110922</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Korogi</last-name>
<first-name>Yutaka</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kanagawa-ken</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Korogi</last-name>
<first-name>Yutaka</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kanagawa-ken</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Birch, Stewart, Kolasch &#x26; Birch, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>FUJIFILM Corporation</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Uhlenhake</last-name>
<first-name>Jason</first-name>
<department>2853</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A paper floating detection apparatus which detects floating of paper conveyed along a prescribed conveyance path on a prescribed conveyance surface, includes: a paper floating detection device which includes a light emission unit and a light reception unit disposed so as to be mutually opposing across the conveyance path, and detects whether the paper floats or not according to whether a detection beam emitted parallel to the conveyance surface from the light emission unit toward the light reception unit in a position at a prescribed height from the conveyance surface is received by the light reception unit or not; a light emission parallel flat plate which is disposed in front of the light emission unit in such a manner that the detection beam emitted from the light emission unit passes through the light emission parallel flat plate, and which is provided rotatably about an axis parallel to the conveyance surface and perpendicular to the detection beam in such a manner that the height of the detection beam emitted from the light emission parallel flat plate after passing inside the light emission parallel flat plate varies according to rotation of the light emission parallel flat plate; and a light emission parallel flat plate rotation driving device which drives the rotation of the light emission parallel flat plate.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="212.68mm" wi="136.82mm" file="US08622495-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="250.53mm" wi="146.13mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622495-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="239.69mm" wi="171.11mm" file="US08622495-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="244.77mm" wi="156.97mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622495-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="242.91mm" wi="156.97mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622495-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="193.55mm" wi="124.97mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622495-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="247.99mm" wi="145.46mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622495-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="228.09mm" wi="135.89mm" file="US08622495-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="245.45mm" wi="161.46mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622495-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="239.69mm" wi="148.67mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622495-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="242.23mm" wi="165.35mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622495-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="255.02mm" wi="167.22mm" file="US08622495-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="245.45mm" wi="151.89mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622495-20140107-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="239.69mm" wi="150.62mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622495-20140107-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00014" num="00014">
<img id="EMI-D00014" he="242.91mm" wi="163.41mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622495-20140107-D00014.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a paper floating detection apparatus and to an inkjet recording apparatus, and more particularly to a paper floating detection apparatus and an inkjet recording apparatus, allowing the detection height of floating paper to be varied.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In an inkjet recording apparatus, a prescribed image is recorded on a recording surface of paper by ejecting ink droplets from an inkjet head onto paper which is conveyed along a predetermined conveyance path. In an inkjet recording apparatus of this kind, if the conveyed paper floats up from the conveyance surface, then there are possibilities that the distance from the nozzle surface of the head to the recording surface of the paper (the throw distance) changes, the recording quality declines, the paper rubs against the nozzle surface of the head and the nozzle surface becomes damaged. Consequently, in an inkjet recording apparatus, a paper floating detection apparatus is disposed in the paper conveyance path and if floating of a specified value or more is detected, then processing, such as halting conveyance, or the like, is implemented.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In general, floating up of paper has been detected by disposing a light emitting unit and a light reception unit in mutually opposing fashion across the paper conveyance path, emitting a detection beam from the light emitting unit toward the light reception unit in a position at a predetermined height from the conveyance surface, and detecting whether or not the detection beam is received. In other words, when floating of the paper occurs, the paper shields reception of the detection beam, and hence the presence or absence of floating of the paper is judged on this basis (see, for example, Japanese Patent Application Publication No. 2007-76109 and Japanese Patent Application Publication No. 2007-98650).</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Papers which are recorded by an inkjet recording apparatus include papers of various different thicknesses. Therefore, if the thickness of the paper used has changed, it is necessary to change the floating detection height in accordance with this paper thickness.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Japanese Patent Application Publication No. 2004-299155 proposes technology in which a light emitting unit and a light reception unit are provided on a member that is raised and lowered together with an inkjet head, and a floating detection height is changed in accordance with the raising or lowering of the inkjet head.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">However, in the technology described in Japanese Patent Application Publication No. 2004-299155, there is a possibility that fine adjustment is difficult due to the composition which alters the detection height by raising and lowering the inkjet head.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Furthermore, if the inkjet head is twisted, then positional displacement occurs between the light emitting unit and the light reception unit, and hence there is a possibility that the detection accuracy falls.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Moreover, in an apparatus which carries out maintenance by moving an inkjet head periodically to a maintenance unit, discrepancy may occur in the detection height each time the inkjet head is moved, and hence there is a possibility that highly accurate detection cannot be carried out in a stable fashion.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Furthermore, a light emitting unit and a light reception unit are provided below the inkjet head, and therefore when the inkjet head is withdrawn, the withdrawal amount is required to be made large and hence there is a possibility that the apparatus becomes large in size.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The present invention has been contrived in view of these circumstances, an object thereof being to provide a paper floating detection apparatus and an inkjet recording apparatus whereby the floating detection height can be adjusted with high accuracy and highly accurate detection can be performed stably.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In order to attain an object described above, one aspect of the present invention is directed to a paper floating detection apparatus which detects floating of paper conveyed along a prescribed conveyance path on a prescribed conveyance surface, the paper floating detection apparatus comprising: a paper floating detection device which includes a light emission unit and a light reception unit disposed so as to be mutually opposing across the conveyance path, and detects whether the paper floats or not according to whether a detection beam emitted parallel to the conveyance surface from the light emission unit toward the light reception unit in a position at a prescribed height from the conveyance surface is received by the light reception unit or not; a light emission parallel flat plate which is disposed in front of the light emission unit in such a manner that the detection beam emitted from the light emission unit passes through the light emission parallel flat plate, and which is provided rotatably about an axis parallel to the conveyance surface and perpendicular to the detection beam in such a manner that the height of the detection beam emitted from the light emission parallel flat plate after passing inside the light emission parallel flat plate varies according to rotation of the light emission parallel flat plate; and a light emission parallel flat plate rotation driving device which drives the rotation of the light emission parallel flat plate.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">According to this aspect of the invention, by rotating the parallel flat plate for light emission which is disposed in front of the light emission unit, it is possible to alter the height for detecting floating of paper (namely, the height of the detection beam from the conveyance surface). If the parallel flat plate for light emission is inclined with respect to the optical axis of the detection beam, then due to the effects of refraction, the emission position of the detection beam emitted from the parallel flat plate for light emission is shifted upwards or downwards. The emission position of the detection beam is displaced in accordance with the angle of incidence of the detection beam which is incident on the parallel flat plate for light emission, and the angle of incidence varies with the amount of rotation of the parallel flat plate for light emission. Therefore, by rotating the parallel flat plate for light emission, it is possible to change the emission position of the detection beam and hence to alter the height of the detection beam (the detection height for floating of the paper). By using the refraction action of a parallel flat plate for light emission in this way to shift the optical axis of a detection beam, it is possible to adjust the detection height for floating simply and accurately. Furthermore, since the detection apparatus is not dependent on other compositional elements, it is possible to achieve stable detection over a long period of time.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Desirably, the paper floating detection apparatus further comprises: a light reception parallel flat plate which is disposed in front of the light reception unit in such a manner that the detection beam having passed through the light emission parallel flat plate passes through the light reception parallel flat plate, and which is provided rotatably about an axis parallel to the conveyance surface and perpendicular to the detection beam in such a manner that the height of the detection beam emitted from the light reception parallel flat plate after passing inside the light reception parallel flat plate varies according to rotation of the light reception parallel flat plate; and a light reception parallel flat plate rotation driving device which drives the rotation of the light reception parallel flat plate.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">According to this aspect of the invention, the parallel flat plate for light reception is provided on the light reception side, allowing the height of the detection beam to be adjusted. With such a plate, more accurate detection can be accomplished.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Desirably, an aperture for light reception is disposed between the light reception unit and the light reception parallel flat plate.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">According to this aspect of the invention, an aperture (aperture for light reception) is provided between the light reception unit and the parallel flat plate for light reception. By this means, even if there is some positional discrepancy between the light emission unit and the light reception unit, the position of the optical axis of the detection beam can be specified by the aperture, and therefore it is possible to achieve a highly robust structure.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Desirably, an aperture for light emission is disposed between the light emission unit and the light emission parallel flat plate.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">According to this aspect of the invention, an aperture (aperture for light emission) is also provided between the light emission unit and the parallel flat plate for light emission. By this means, it is possible to achieve even more accurate detection of floating.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Desirably, an opening surface area of the aperture for light reception is set to be smaller than an opening surface area of the aperture for light emission.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">According to this aspect of the invention, the opening surface area of the aperture for light reception is set to be smaller than the opening surface area of the aperture for light emission. By this means, it is possible to extremely reduce the effects of the introduction of reflected light, and therefore detection of high accuracy can be performed.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Desirably, the paper floating detection apparatus further comprises a detection height adjustment device which controls driving of the light emission parallel flat plate rotation driving device according to a detection result of the paper floating detection device, so as to adjust the height of the detection beam, wherein the detection height adjustment device performs an operation of: causing the light emission parallel flat plate to rotate in a first direction in a state where the detection beam is received by the light reception unit, halting the rotation of the light emission parallel flat plate when the detection beam is no longer received by the light reception unit and employing, as a reference position, a position of the light emission parallel flat plate when the rotation of the light emission parallel flat plate is halted, and causing the light emission parallel flat plate to rotate by a prescribed amount from the reference position in a second direction which is opposite to the first direction so as to adjust the height of the detection beam.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">According to this aspect of the invention, since the height of the detection beam (the detection height for floating of paper) is set by detecting the position of the conveyance surface as a reference for positional adjustment, then it is possible to set the detection height for floating of paper with high accuracy.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Desirably, the paper floating detection apparatus further comprises a detection height adjustment device which controls driving of the light emission parallel flat plate rotation driving device and the light reception parallel flat plate rotation driving device according to a detection result of the paper floating detection device, so as to adjust the height of the detection beam, wherein the detection height adjustment device performs an operation of: causing the light emission parallel flat plate to rotate in a first direction in a state where the detection beam is received by the light reception unit, and halting the rotation of the light emission parallel flat plate when the detection beam is no longer received by the light reception unit, and rotating the light emission parallel flat plate by a prescribed amount in a second direction which is opposite to the first direction, then causing the light reception parallel flat plate to rotate in the second direction, and halting the rotation of the light reception parallel flat plate when the detection beam is no longer received by the light reception unit, and employing, as reference positions, positions of the light emission parallel flat plate and the light reception parallel flat plate when the rotation of the light reception parallel flat plate is halted, and causing the light reception parallel flat plate to rotate by a prescribed amount from the reference position in the first direction and causing the light emission parallel flat plate to rotate by a prescribed amount from the reference position in the second direction so as to adjust the height of the detection beam.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">According to this aspect of the invention, since the height of the detection beam (the detection height for floating of paper) is set by detecting the position of the conveyance surface as a reference for positional adjustment, then it is possible to set the detection height for floating of paper with high accuracy.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Desirably, the detection height adjustment device starts the operation from a prescribed start position for light emission, and the paper floating detection apparatus further comprises: a light emission reference rotation amount detection device which detects, as a light emission reference rotation amount, an amount of the rotation of the light emission parallel flat plate from the start position for light emission to the reference position; and an abnormality judgment device which compares the light emission reference rotation amount detected by the light emission reference rotation amount detection device with a threshold value so as to judge whether there is an apparatus abnormality.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">According to this aspect of the invention, the amount of rotation of the parallel flat plate for light emission from a prescribed light emission start position to a reference position is detected as a light emission reference rotation amount, and an apparatus abnormality is judged on the basis of this light emission reference rotation amount. By this means, it is possible to prevent an apparatus abnormality in advance, and stable detection can be performed.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Desirably, the detection height adjustment device starts the operation from a prescribed start position for light emission and a prescribed start position for light reception, and the paper floating detection apparatus further comprises: a light emission reference rotation amount detection device which detects, as a light emission reference rotation amount, an amount of the rotation of the light emission parallel flat plate from the start position for light emission to the reference position; a light reception reference rotation amount detection device which detects, as a light reception reference rotation amount, an amount of the rotation of the light reception parallel flat plate from the start position for light reception to the reference position; and an abnormality judgment device which compares the light emission reference rotation amount detected by the light emission reference rotation amount detection device with a threshold value and compares the light reception reference rotation amount detected by the light reception reference rotation amount detection device with a threshold value so as to judge whether or not there is an apparatus abnormality.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">According to this aspect of the invention, the amount of rotation of the parallel flat plate for light emission from a prescribed light emission start position to a reference position is detected as a light emission reference rotation amount, the amount of rotation of the parallel flat plate for light reception from a prescribed light reception start position to a reference position is detected as a light reception reference rotation amount, and an apparatus abnormality is judged on the basis of the light emission reference rotation amount and the light reception reference rotation amount. By this means, it is possible to prevent an apparatus abnormality in advance, and stable detection can be performed.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Desirably, the detection height adjustment device repeats the operation a plurality of times so as to adjust the height of the detection beam.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">According to this aspect of the invention, the height of the detection beam is adjusted by repeating an adjustment operation of the height position of the detection beam a plurality of times. By this means, it is possible to achieve even more accurate adjustment.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Desirably, the light emission unit and the light reception unit are disposed in such a manner that the detection beam emitted from the light emission unit toward the light reception unit is inclined at a prescribed angle with respect to a direction perpendicular to a conveyance direction of the paper.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">According to this aspect of the invention, the light emission unit and the light reception unit are arranged in such a manner that the detection beam emitted from the light emission unit toward the light reception unit is inclined at a prescribed angle (0.3&#xb0; to 2&#xb0; inclination) with respect to the direction perpendicular to the conveyance direction of the paper. By this means, it is also possible to detect the floating in a direction perpendicular to the conveyance direction of the paper, with good accuracy.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In order to attain an object described above, another aspect of the present invention is directed to an inkjet recording apparatus comprising: a conveyance device which conveys paper; an inkjet head which ejects droplets of ink onto a recording surface of the paper conveyed by the conveyance device to form an image; any one of the above paper floating detection apparatuses which is disposed on an upstream side of the inkjet head and detects the floating of the paper from the conveyance surface of the conveyance device; and a conveyance abnormality judgment device which judges a conveyance abnormality of the paper according to a detection result of the paper floating detection apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">According to this aspect of the invention, a paper floating detection apparatus is incorporated into an inkjet recording apparatus and floating of paper during recording is detected by the paper floating detection apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Desirably, the conveyance device is a conveyance drum which holds the paper by suction on an outer circumferential surface of the conveyance drum and conveys the paper by rotating.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">According to this aspect of the invention, floating of paper conveyed by a conveyance drum is detected.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Desirably, the inkjet head is provided movably between an image formation position where the droplets of ink are ejected onto the recording surface of the paper conveyed by the conveyance device to form the image and a withdrawn position where the inkjet head is withdrawn from the conveyance device, and the paper floating detection apparatus raises the height of the detection beam by a prescribed amount of height or halts detection, when the inkjet head is moved to the withdrawn position.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">According to this aspect of the invention, when the inkjet head is moved to a withdrawn position, the height of the detection beam produced by the paper floating detection apparatus (the detection height for floating of paper) is raised by a prescribed amount. Alternatively, detection of floating of the paper by the paper floating detection apparatus is halted. By this means, detection errors can be prevented.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Desirably, the paper floating detection apparatus raises the height of the detection beam by a prescribed amount of height or halts detection, when recording is halted.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">According to this aspect of the invention, when recording is halted, the height of the detection beam produced by the paper floating detection apparatus (the detection height for floating of paper) is raised by a prescribed amount. Alternatively, detection of floating of the paper by the paper floating detection apparatus is halted. By this means, detection errors can be prevented.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">According to the present invention, it is possible to adjust the detection height for floating with high accuracy, and highly accurate detection of the floating can be performed in a stable fashion.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">A preferred embodiment of this invention as well as other objects and benefits thereof, will be explained in the following with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which like reference characters designate the same or similar parts throughout the figures and wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic drawing showing the general composition of an inkjet recording apparatus to which an embodiment of the present invention is applied;</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram showing the general composition of a control system of an inkjet recording apparatus;</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a front view diagram of a first embodiment of a paper floating detection apparatus;</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a plan view diagram of the first embodiment of the paper floating detection apparatus;</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a graph showing the relationship between the angle of rotation (angle of inclination) of a parallel flat glass plate for light emission and the amount of displacement X in the height direction of a detection beam;</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6A to 6C</figref> are diagrams showing the relationship between the angle of rotation (angle of inclination) of a parallel flat glass plate for light emission and the amount of displacement X in the height direction of a detection beam;</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a flowchart showing steps for setting the detection height for floating of the paper;</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a front view diagram of a second embodiment of the paper floating detection apparatus;</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a front view diagram of a third embodiment of the paper floating detection apparatus;</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a plan view diagram of a third embodiment of the paper floating detection apparatus;</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a flowchart showing steps for setting the detection height for floating of the paper;</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a front view diagram of a fourth embodiment of the paper floating detection apparatus;</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a front view diagram of a further embodiment of the paper floating detection apparatus; and</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is a plan view diagram of a fifth embodiment of the paper floating detection apparatus.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="h-0005" num="0000">General Composition</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is schematic drawing showing the general composition of an inkjet recording apparatus into which a paper floating detection apparatus according to an embodiment of the present invention is incorporated.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The inkjet recording apparatus <b>10</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a recording apparatus which performs printing by an inkjet method onto cut sheet paper P, using an aqueous ink (ink including water in the solvent), and includes a paper supply unit <b>20</b> which supplies paper P, a treatment liquid deposition unit <b>30</b> which deposits a prescribed treatment liquid onto a recording surface of the paper P, an image recording unit <b>40</b> which forms a color image by ejecting droplets of ink of the respective colors of C (cyan), M (magenta), Y (yellow) and K (black) onto a recording surface of the paper P, from an inkjet head, an ink drying unit <b>50</b> which dries the ink droplets that have been ejected onto the paper P, a fixing unit <b>60</b> which fixes the image recorded on the paper P, and a recovery unit <b>70</b> which recovers paper P after printing.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Conveyance drums <b>31</b>, <b>41</b>, <b>51</b>, <b>61</b> are provided respectively as conveyance devices of the paper P, in the treatment liquid deposition unit <b>30</b>, the image recording unit <b>40</b>, the ink drying unit <b>50</b> and the fixing unit <b>60</b>. The paper P is conveyed through the treatment liquid deposition unit <b>30</b>, the image recording unit <b>40</b>, the ink drying unit <b>50</b> and the fixing unit <b>60</b>, by means of these conveyance drums <b>31</b>, <b>41</b>, <b>51</b>, <b>61</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The conveyance drums <b>31</b>, <b>41</b>, <b>51</b>, <b>61</b> are formed to correspond to the paper width and rotate by being driven by motors (not illustrated) (in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the drums rotate in the counter-clockwise direction). Grippers G are provided on the circumferential surface of each conveyance drum <b>31</b>, <b>41</b>, <b>51</b>, <b>61</b>, and the paper P is conveyed with the leading end portion thereof being gripped by a gripper G. In the present embodiment, a composition is adopted in which grippers G are provided at two positions (separated by 180&#xb0;) on the circumferential surface of each conveyance drum <b>31</b>, <b>41</b>, <b>51</b>, <b>61</b>, in such a manner that two sheets of paper can be conveyed in one revolution.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Moreover, a lot of suction holes are formed in each of the circumferential surfaces of the conveyance drums <b>31</b>, <b>41</b>, <b>51</b>, <b>61</b>, and the rear surface of the paper P is vacuum suctioned via these suction holes, thereby holding the paper P by suction on the circumferential surfaces of the conveyance drums <b>31</b>, <b>41</b>, <b>51</b>, <b>61</b>. In the present embodiment, a composition is adopted in which the paper P is vacuum suctioned and held by suction on the outer circumferential surfaces of the conveyance drums <b>31</b>, <b>41</b>, <b>51</b>, <b>61</b>, but it is also possible to adopt a composition in which the paper P is attracted electrostatically and held by attraction on the outer circumferential surfaces of the conveyance drums <b>31</b>, <b>41</b>, <b>51</b>, <b>61</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Transfer drums <b>80</b>, <b>90</b>, <b>100</b> are disposed respectively between the treatment liquid deposition unit <b>30</b> and the image recording unit <b>40</b>, between the image recording unit <b>40</b> and the ink drying unit <b>50</b>, and between the ink drying unit <b>50</b> and the fixing unit <b>60</b>. The paper P is conveyed between the respective units by means of these transfer drums <b>80</b>, <b>90</b>, <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The transfer drums <b>80</b>, <b>90</b>, <b>100</b> are composed by transfer drum main bodies <b>81</b>, <b>91</b>, <b>101</b> constituted by frames, and grippers G which are provided on the transfer drum main bodies <b>81</b>, <b>91</b>, <b>101</b>. The transfer drum main bodies <b>81</b>, <b>91</b>, <b>101</b> are formed to correspond to the paper width and rotate by being driven by motors (not illustrated) (in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the drums rotate in the clockwise direction). By this means, the grippers G rotate on the same circular path. The paper P is conveyed with the leading end portion thereof being gripped by a gripper G. In the present embodiment, a pair of grippers G is arranged at symmetrical positions about the axis of rotation, in such a manner that two sheets of paper can be conveyed in one revolution.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">Circular arc-shaped guide plates <b>83</b>, <b>93</b>, <b>103</b> are arranged along the conveyance path of the paper P, below the transfer drums <b>80</b>, <b>90</b>, <b>100</b> respectively. The paper P which is conveyed by the transfer drums <b>80</b>, <b>90</b>, <b>100</b> is conveyed while the rear surface of the paper (the surface on the opposite side to the recording surface) is guided by the guide plates <b>83</b>, <b>93</b>, <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Furthermore, driers <b>84</b>, <b>94</b>, <b>104</b> which blow a hot air flow toward the paper P conveyed by the transfer drum <b>80</b> are arranged inside the transfer drums <b>80</b>, <b>90</b>, <b>100</b>. The hot air flows blown out from the driers <b>84</b>, <b>94</b>, <b>104</b> during this conveyance process strike the recording surface of the paper P conveyed by the transfer drums <b>80</b>, <b>90</b>, <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The paper P supplied from the paper supply unit <b>20</b> is transferred to the conveyance drum <b>31</b> of the treatment liquid deposition unit <b>30</b>, and is then transferred from the conveyance drum <b>31</b> of the treatment liquid deposition unit <b>30</b> to the conveyance drum <b>41</b> of the image recording unit <b>40</b> via the transfer drum <b>80</b>. The paper P is transferred from the conveyance drum <b>41</b> of the image recording unit <b>40</b> to the conveyance drum <b>51</b> of the ink drying unit <b>50</b> via the transfer drum <b>90</b>, and is transferred from the conveyance drum <b>51</b> of the ink drying unit <b>50</b> to the conveyance drum <b>61</b> of the fixing unit <b>60</b> via the transfer drum <b>100</b>. The paper is then transferred from the conveyance drum <b>61</b> of the fixing unit <b>60</b> to the recovery unit <b>70</b>. While passing through this series of conveyance steps, required processes are carried out and an image is formed on the recording surface of the paper P.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">The paper P is conveyed in such a manner that the recording surface is facing toward the outside on the conveyance drums <b>31</b>, <b>41</b>, <b>51</b>, <b>61</b>, and the recording surface is facing toward the inside on the transfer drums <b>80</b>, <b>90</b>, <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The composition of the respective units of the inkjet recording apparatus <b>10</b> according to the present embodiment is described in detail below.</p>
<p id="h-0006" num="0000">Paper Supply Unit</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">The paper supply unit <b>20</b> includes a paper supply device <b>21</b>, a paper supply tray <b>22</b> and a transfer drum <b>23</b>, and supplies cut sheet paper P continuously, one sheet at a time, to the treatment liquid deposition unit <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">The paper supply device <b>21</b> supplies paper P stacked in a magazine (not illustrated), successively, one sheet at a time from the upper side, to the paper supply tray <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The paper supply tray <b>22</b> outputs the paper P supplied from the paper supply device <b>21</b>, to the transfer drum <b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The transfer drum <b>23</b> receives the paper P output from the paper supply tray <b>22</b>, conveys the paper along a prescribed conveyance path, and then transfers the paper to the conveyance drum <b>31</b> of the treatment liquid deposition unit <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">Versatile recording paper, which is not exclusively produced for inkjet printing, is used as the paper P.</p>
<p id="h-0007" num="0000">Treatment Liquid Deposition Unit</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The treatment liquid deposition unit <b>30</b> deposits a prescribed treatment liquid onto the recording surface of the paper P. The treatment liquid deposition unit <b>30</b> includes a conveyance drum which conveys the paper P (called &#x201c;treatment liquid deposition drum&#x201d; below) <b>31</b>, and a treatment liquid deposition apparatus <b>32</b> which deposits a prescribed treatment liquid onto the recording surface of the paper P conveyed by the treatment liquid deposition drum <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">The treatment liquid deposition drum <b>31</b> receives paper P from the transfer drum <b>23</b> of the paper supply unit <b>20</b> (by gripping the leading end of the paper P with a gripper G), and conveys the paper P by rotating.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">The treatment liquid deposition apparatus <b>32</b> deposits treatment liquid having a function of aggregating the coloring material in the ink, onto the recording surface of the paper P conveyed by the treatment liquid deposition drum <b>31</b>. In this treatment liquid deposition apparatus <b>32</b>, for example, the treatment liquid deposition apparatus <b>32</b> is constituted as a coating apparatus for applying treatment liquid by a roller which applies treatment liquid to the recording surface of the paper P by abutting and pressing a coating roller bearing treatment liquid on the circumferential surface thereof against the surface of the paper P. By previously depositing treatment liquid of this kind and then ejecting droplets of ink, it is possible to suppress feathering, bleeding, and the like, and to perform recording of high quality, even when using generic recording paper. For the treatment liquid deposition apparatus <b>32</b>, it is possible to adopt a composition which deposits a treatment liquid by using a droplet ejection head similar to the inkjet head described below, or a composition which deposits a treatment liquid by means of a spray.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">According to the treatment liquid deposition unit <b>30</b> having the composition described above, the paper P is conveyed along a prescribed conveyance path by the treatment liquid deposition drum <b>31</b>, and during this conveyance process, treatment liquid is deposited onto the recording surface from the treatment liquid deposition apparatus <b>32</b>. The paper P having treatment liquid deposited on the recording surface thereof is then transferred from the treatment liquid deposition drum <b>31</b> to the transfer drum <b>80</b> at a prescribed position.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">Here, as described above, a drier <b>84</b> is arranged inside the transfer drum <b>80</b>, and a hot air flow is blown toward the guide plate <b>83</b>. A hot air flow is blown onto the recording surface of the paper P in the course of the conveyance of the paper from the treatment liquid deposition unit <b>30</b> to the image recording unit <b>40</b> by the transfer drum <b>80</b>, thereby drying the treatment liquid which has been deposited on the recording surface (namely, evaporating off the solvent component in the treatment liquid).</p>
<p id="h-0008" num="0000">Image Recording Unit</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">The image recording unit <b>40</b> forms a color image on the recording surface of the paper P by ejecting ink droplets of the respective colors of C, M, Y, K onto the recording surface of the paper P. The image recording unit <b>40</b> includes: a conveyance drum <b>41</b> which conveys paper P (hereinafter, called &#x201c;image recording drum&#x201d;), a paper pressing roller <b>42</b> which presses against the recording surface of the paper P conveyed by the image recording drum <b>41</b>, thereby causing the rear surface of the paper P to make close contact with the circumferential surface of the image recording drum <b>41</b>, a paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b> which detects floating of the paper P having passed the paper pressing roller <b>42</b>, and inkjet heads <b>44</b>C, <b>44</b>M, <b>44</b>Y, <b>44</b>K which eject ink droplets of respective colors of C, M, Y, K onto the paper P.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">The image recording drum <b>41</b> receives paper P from the transfer drum <b>80</b> and conveys the paper P by rotating. In this step, as described above, the paper P is conveyed by being held by suction on the outer circumferential surface of the image recording drum <b>41</b>. Therefore, a circular arc-shaped surface demarcated by the outer circumferential surface of the image recording drum <b>41</b> (the region from where the paper P is received from the transfer drum <b>80</b> to where the paper P is transferred to the transfer drum <b>90</b>) is formed as a conveyance surface, and the paper P is conveyed along a conveyance path set on this conveyance surface. The conveyance path is set in accordance with the width of the paper P and passing through the center of the image recording drum <b>41</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">The paper pressing roller <b>42</b> is disposed in the vicinity of the paper receiving position of the image recording drum <b>41</b> (the position where paper P is received from the transfer drum <b>80</b>), and is abutted and pressed against the circumferential surface of the image recording drum <b>41</b> by receiving a pressing force from a pressing mechanism, which is not illustrated. The paper P transferred from the transfer drum <b>80</b> to the image recording drum <b>41</b> is nipped by passing the paper pressing roller <b>42</b> and the rear surface of the paper is thereby caused to make close contact with the outer circumferential surface of the image recording drum <b>41</b></p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">The paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b> detects floating of the paper P having passed the paper pressing roller <b>42</b> (a prescribed amount of floating or more from the outer circumferential surface of the image recording drum <b>41</b>). This paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b> detects floating of the paper P by irradiating laser light (a detection beam) across the image recording drum <b>41</b> at a position a predetermined height from the outer circumferential surface (conveyance surface) of the image recording drum <b>41</b>, and detecting the presence or absence of shielding of the light. In other words, if floating of the paper P occurs, then the laser light is shielded by the paper P, and therefore floating of the paper P is detected by detecting the presence or absence of shielding of the laser light. The composition of this paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b> is described in detail hereinafter.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">The four inkjet heads <b>44</b>C, <b>44</b>M, <b>44</b>Y, <b>44</b>K are disposed after the paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b> and are arranged at uniform intervals along the conveyance path of the paper P. The inkjet heads <b>44</b>C, <b>44</b>M, <b>44</b>Y, <b>44</b>K are each constituted by a line head corresponding to the paper width and eject ink droplets of the corresponding color toward the image recording drum <b>41</b> from a nozzle row formed on the nozzle surface.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">According to the image recording unit <b>40</b> having the composition described above, the paper P is conveyed along a prescribed conveyance path by the image recording drum <b>41</b>. The paper P transferred from the transfer drum <b>80</b> to the image recording drum <b>41</b> is firstly nipped by the paper pressing roller <b>42</b> and caused to make close contact with the outer circumferential surface of the image recording drum <b>41</b>. Thereupon, the presence or absence of floating is detected by the paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b>, whereupon ink droplets of respective colors of C, M, Y, K are ejected onto the recording surface from the inkjet heads <b>44</b>C, <b>44</b>M, <b>44</b>Y, <b>44</b>K, thereby forming a color image on the recording surface.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">Here, in the inkjet recording apparatus <b>10</b> according to the present embodiment, an aqueous ink composed by an ink in which a thermoplastic resin has been dispersed is used for each color. Even if using an aqueous ink of this kind, since a predetermined treatment liquid is deposited on the paper P, then it is possible to perform recording of high quality without giving rise to feathering, bleeding, or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">Furthermore, if floating of the paper P is detected by the paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b>, then conveyance is halted and a warning is issued.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">The paper P on which an image is formed is transferred onto the transfer drum <b>90</b>, is conveyed on a prescribed conveyance path by the transfer drum <b>90</b>, and is transferred onto the conveyance drum <b>51</b> of the ink drying unit <b>50</b>. As described above, a drier <b>94</b> is arranged inside the transfer drum <b>90</b>, and a hot air flow is blown toward the guide plate <b>93</b>. An ink drying process is carried out in an ink drying unit <b>50</b> at a later stage, but the paper P also undergoes a drying process during conveyance by the transfer drum <b>90</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">Although not shown in the drawings, a maintenance unit which performs maintenance of the inkjet heads <b>44</b>C, <b>44</b>M, <b>44</b>Y, <b>44</b>K is provided in the image recording unit <b>40</b>, and the inkjet heads <b>44</b>C, <b>44</b>M, <b>44</b>Y, <b>44</b>K are moved to the maintenance unit as and when necessary so as to be able to receive required maintenance.</p>
<p id="h-0009" num="0000">Ink Drying Unit</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">The ink drying unit <b>50</b> dries the liquid component remaining on the paper P after image recording. This ink drying unit <b>50</b> includes a conveyance drum (hereinafter, called &#x201c;ink drying drum&#x201d;) <b>51</b> which conveys the paper P, and an ink drying apparatus <b>52</b> which carries out a drying process on the paper P conveyed by the ink drying drum <b>51</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">The ink drying drum <b>51</b> receives the paper P from the transfer drum <b>90</b> and conveys the paper P by rotating.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">The ink drying apparatus <b>52</b> is constituted by a drier (in this embodiment, three dryers are provided along the conveyance path for the paper P), for example, and dries the ink (evaporates off the liquid component present on the paper) by blowing a hot air flow toward the paper P conveyed by the ink drying drum <b>51</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">In the ink drying unit <b>50</b> having the composition described above, the paper P is conveyed on the ink drying drum <b>51</b>. In the course of this conveyance, a hot air flow is blown from the ink drying apparatus <b>52</b> onto the recording surface and the ink which has been deposited on the recording surface is dried.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">The paper P which has passed through the ink drying apparatus <b>52</b> is subsequently received onto the transfer drum <b>100</b> from the ink drying drum <b>51</b> at a prescribed position. The paper P is conveyed on a prescribed conveyance path by the transfer drum <b>100</b> and is transferred to the conveyance drum <b>61</b> of the fixing unit <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">As described above, a drier <b>104</b> is disposed inside the transfer drum <b>100</b> and blows a hot air flow toward the guide plate <b>103</b>. Consequently, the paper P undergoes a drying process during the conveyance on the transfer drum <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0010" num="0000">Fixing Unit</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">The fixing unit <b>60</b> fixes the image which has been recorded on the recording surface, by applying heat and pressure to the paper P. The fixing unit <b>60</b> includes a conveyance drum which conveys paper P (hereinafter called &#x201c;fixing drum&#x201d;) <b>61</b>, heat rollers <b>62</b>, <b>63</b> which apply a heating and pressurization process to the paper P conveyed by the fixing drum <b>61</b>, and an in-line sensor <b>64</b> which determines the temperature and humidity, and the like, of the paper P after recording and which captures the recorded image.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">The fixing drum <b>61</b> receives the paper P from the transfer drum <b>100</b> and conveys the paper P by rotating.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">The heat rollers <b>62</b>, <b>63</b> heat and pressurize the ink that has been deposited onto the recording surface of the paper P, thereby melting the thermoplastic resin dispersed in the ink and causing the ink to form a film. Furthermore, deformation such as cockling, curl, and the like, which has occurred in the paper P is also corrected simultaneously with this. The heat rollers <b>62</b>, <b>63</b> are formed to substantially the same width as the fixing drum <b>61</b>, and are heated to a prescribed temperature by the heaters provided therein. Furthermore, the heat rollers <b>62</b>, <b>63</b> are abutted and pressed against the circumferential surface of the fixing drum <b>61</b> with a prescribed pressing force, by means of a pressurizing device, which is not illustrated. When the paper P passes the heat rollers <b>62</b>, <b>63</b>, the paper P is heated and pressurized by the heat rollers <b>62</b>, <b>63</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">The in-line sensor <b>64</b> includes a temperature meter, a humidity meter, and a CCD line sensor, and the like, and determines the temperature and humidity, and the like, of the paper P conveyed by the fixing drum <b>61</b>, as well as capturing the image recorded on the paper P. Apparatus abnormalities and head ejection defects, and the like, are checked on the basis of the determination results of the in-line sensor <b>64</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">According to the fixing unit <b>60</b> having the composition described above, the paper P is conveyed by the fixing drum <b>61</b>, and the heat rollers <b>62</b>, <b>63</b> are abutted and pressed against the recording surface in the course of this conveyance, thereby applying heat and pressure to the paper. By this means, the thermoplastic resin dispersed in the ink is melted and the ink forms a film. Furthermore, simultaneously with this, the deformation which has occurred in the paper P is corrected.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">The paper P which has undergone the fixing process is transferred from the fixing drum <b>61</b> to the recovery unit <b>70</b> at a prescribed position.</p>
<p id="h-0011" num="0000">Recovery Unit</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">The recovery unit <b>70</b> recovers the paper P which has undergone the series of recording processes, in a stacked fashion in a stacker <b>71</b>. The recovery unit <b>70</b> includes the stacker <b>71</b> which recovers paper P, and a paper output conveyor <b>72</b> which receives paper P that has undergone the fixing process in the fixing unit <b>60</b>, from the fixing drum <b>61</b>, conveys the paper P on a prescribed conveyance path, and outputs the paper to the stacker <b>71</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">The paper P which has undergone the fixing process in the fixing unit <b>60</b> is transferred onto the paper output conveyor <b>72</b> from the fixing drum <b>61</b>, conveyed by the paper output conveyor <b>72</b> up to the stacker <b>71</b>, and then recovered in the stacker <b>71</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0012" num="0000">Conveyance System</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram showing the approximate composition of a conveyance system of an inkjet recording apparatus <b>10</b> according to the present embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the inkjet recording apparatus <b>10</b> includes a system controller <b>200</b>, a communications unit <b>201</b>, an image memory <b>202</b>, a conveyance control unit <b>203</b>, a paper supply control unit <b>204</b>, a treatment liquid deposition control unit <b>205</b>, an image recording control unit <b>206</b>, an ink drying control unit <b>207</b>, a fixing control unit <b>208</b>, a recovery control unit <b>209</b>, an operating unit <b>210</b>, a display unit <b>211</b>, a warning unit <b>212</b> and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">The system controller <b>200</b> functions as a control device which performs overall control of the respective units of the inkjet recording apparatus <b>10</b>, and also functions as a calculation device which performs various calculation processes. This system controller <b>200</b> includes a CPU, ROM, RAM and the like, and operates in accordance with a prescribed control program. Control programs executed by the system controller <b>200</b> and various data necessary for control purposes are stored in the ROM.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">The communications unit <b>201</b> includes a prescribed communications interface, and sends and receives data between the communications interface and a host computer connected to the communications interface.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">The image memory <b>202</b> functions as a temporary storage device for various data including image data, and data is read from and written to the memory via the system controller <b>200</b>. Image data which has been read in from the host computer via the communications unit <b>201</b> is stored in the image memory <b>202</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">The conveyance control unit <b>203</b> controls the driving of the conveyance drums <b>31</b>, <b>41</b>, <b>51</b>, <b>61</b> and the transfer drums <b>80</b>, <b>90</b>, <b>100</b>, which are conveyance devices of the paper P in the treatment liquid deposition unit <b>30</b>, the image recording unit <b>40</b>, the ink drying unit <b>50</b> and the fixing unit <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111">More specifically, as well as controlling the driving of the motors which drive the conveyance drums <b>31</b>, <b>41</b>, <b>51</b>, <b>61</b>, the conveyance control unit <b>203</b> also controls the opening and closing of the grippers G which are provided on the conveyance drums <b>31</b>, <b>41</b>, <b>51</b>, <b>61</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">Similarly, the conveyance control unit <b>203</b> also controls the driving of the motors which drive the transfer drums <b>80</b>, <b>90</b>, <b>100</b>, as well as controlling the opening and closing of the grippers G which are provided in the transfer drums <b>80</b>, <b>90</b>, <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">Furthermore, since a mechanism for suctioning and holding the paper P on the circumferential surface is provided in each of the conveyance drums <b>31</b>, <b>41</b>, <b>51</b>, <b>61</b>, then the conveyance control unit <b>203</b> also controls the driving of the suctioning and holding mechanisms (in the present embodiment, since the paper P is suctioned by vacuum, then the conveyance control unit <b>203</b> controls the driving of the vacuum pump which forms a negative pressure generating device).</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">Moreover, the driers <b>84</b>, <b>94</b>, <b>104</b> are provided in the transfer drums <b>80</b>, <b>90</b>, <b>100</b>, and therefore the conveyance control unit <b>203</b> also controls the driving (amount of heating and air flow volume) of these driers.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">The driving of the conveyance drums <b>31</b>, <b>41</b>, <b>51</b>, <b>61</b> and the transfer drums <b>80</b>, <b>90</b>, <b>100</b> is controlled in accordance with instructions from the system controller <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116">The paper supply control unit <b>204</b> controls the driving of the respective units which constitute the paper supply unit <b>20</b> (the paper supply device <b>21</b>, transfer drum <b>23</b>, and the like), in accordance with instructions from the system controller <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0117">The treatment liquid deposition control unit <b>205</b> controls the driving of the respective units (for example, the treatment liquid deposition apparatus <b>32</b>) which constitute the treatment liquid deposition unit <b>30</b>, in accordance with instructions from the system controller <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0118">The image recording control unit <b>206</b> controls the driving of the respective units which constitute the image recording unit <b>40</b> (the paper pressing roller <b>42</b>, inkjet heads <b>44</b>C, <b>44</b>M, <b>44</b>Y, <b>44</b>K, and the like) in accordance with instructions from the system controller <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0119">The ink drying control unit <b>207</b> controls the driving of the respective units which constitute the ink drying unit <b>50</b> (for example, the ink drying apparatus <b>52</b>, and the like), in accordance with instructions from the system controller <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0120">The fixing control unit <b>208</b> controls the driving of the respective units which constitute the fixing unit <b>60</b> (for example, the heat rollers <b>62</b>, <b>63</b>, the in-line sensor <b>64</b>, and the like), in accordance with instructions from the system controller <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0121">The recovery control unit <b>209</b> controls the driving of the respective units (for example, the paper output conveyor <b>72</b>, and the like) which constitute the recovery unit <b>70</b>, in accordance with instructions from the system controller <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0122">The operating unit <b>210</b> includes a required operating device (for example, operating buttons and a keyboard, a touch panel, or the like), and outputs operational information input from the operating device to the system controller <b>200</b>. The system controller <b>200</b> executes various processing in accordance with the operational information input from the operating unit <b>210</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0123">The display unit <b>211</b> includes a required display apparatus (for example, an LCD panel, or the like), and causes prescribed information to be displayed on the display apparatus in accordance with instructions from the system controller <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0124">The warning unit <b>212</b> includes a warning light and a speaker, or the like, and carries out a required warning operation (flashing the warning light, issuing a warning sound from the speaker, or the like), in accordance with instructions from the system controller <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0125">As described above, a paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b> is provided in the image recording unit <b>40</b> and floating up of the paper P is detected. The detection result for floating of the paper P by the paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b> is output to the system controller <b>200</b>. When floating of the paper P is detected, the system controller <b>200</b> judges that a conveyance abnormality has occurred and instructs the conveyance control unit <b>203</b> to halt conveyance of the paper P, as well as instructing the warning unit <b>212</b> to issue a required warning operation.</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0126">As described above, image data to be recorded on the paper P is read into the inkjet recording apparatus <b>10</b> from the host computer via the communications unit <b>201</b> and is stored in the image memory <b>202</b>. The system controller <b>200</b> generates dot data by carrying out required signal processing on the image data stored in the image memory <b>202</b>, and records an image represented by this image data by controlling the driving of each inkjet head of the image recording unit <b>40</b> in accordance with the generated dot data.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0127">In general, the dot data is generated by subjecting the image data to color conversion processing and halftone processing. The color conversion processing is processing for converting image data represented by sRGB, or the like (for example, RGB 8-bit image data) into ink volume data for each color of ink used by the inkjet recording apparatus <b>10</b> (in the present embodiment, ink volume data for the respective colors of C, M, Y, K). Halftone processing is processing for converting the ink volume data of the respective colors generated by the color conversion processing into dot data of respective colors by error diffusion processing, or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0128">The system controller <b>200</b> generates dot data of the respective colors by applying color conversion processing and halftone processing to the image data. An image represented by the image data is recorded on the paper by controlling the driving of the corresponding inkjet heads in accordance with the dot data for the respective colors thus generated.</p>
<p id="h-0013" num="0000">Recording Operation</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0129">Next, a printing operation of the inkjet recording apparatus <b>10</b> described above will be explained.</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0130">When the system controller <b>200</b> outputs a paper supply instruction to the paper supply device <b>21</b>, a sheet of paper P is supplied from the paper supply device <b>21</b> to the paper supply tray <b>22</b>. The paper P supplied to the paper supply tray <b>22</b> is transferred to the treatment liquid deposition drum <b>31</b> of the treatment liquid deposition unit <b>30</b> via the transfer drum <b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0132" num="0131">The paper P transferred onto the treatment liquid deposition drum <b>31</b> is conveyed along a prescribed conveyance path by the treatment liquid deposition drum <b>31</b>, and in the course of this conveyance, the paper passes through the treatment liquid deposition apparatus <b>32</b> and treatment liquid is deposited on the recording surface of the paper P.</p>
<p id="p-0133" num="0132">The paper P on which treatment liquid has been deposited is transferred from the treatment liquid deposition drum <b>31</b> to the transfer drum <b>80</b>, conveyed on a prescribed conveyance path by the transfer drum <b>80</b>, and then transferred to the image recording drum <b>41</b> of the image recording unit <b>40</b>. In the course of conveyance by the transfer drum <b>80</b>, a hot air flow is blown onto the recording surface from the drier <b>84</b> which is disposed inside the transfer drum <b>80</b>, and the treatment liquid which has been deposited on the recording surface is dried.</p>
<p id="p-0134" num="0133">The paper P transferred from the transfer drum <b>80</b> to the image recording drum <b>41</b> is firstly nipped by the paper pressing roller <b>42</b> by passing the paper pressing roller <b>42</b>, thereby causing the paper to make close contact with the outer circumferential surface of the image recording drum <b>41</b>. Thereupon, the presence or absence of floating up of the paper P is detected by the paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b>. Here, if floating up of the paper P is detected, it is determined that a conveyance abnormality of the paper P has occurred, and the conveyance is halted and a required warning is issued. On the other hand, if floating up of the paper P is not detected, then the conveyance is continued without alteration and ink droplets of the respective colors of CMYK are ejected from the respective inkjet heads <b>44</b>C, <b>44</b>M, <b>44</b>Y, <b>44</b>K. By this means, a color image is recorded on the recording surface. The paper P on which an image has been formed is subsequently received onto the transfer drum <b>90</b> from the image recording drum <b>41</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0135" num="0134">The paper P which has been transferred to the transfer drum <b>90</b> is conveyed on a prescribed conveyance path by the transfer drum <b>90</b>, and is transferred onto the ink drying drum <b>51</b> of the ink drying unit <b>50</b>. In the course of this conveyance, a hot air flow is blown onto the recording surface from the drier <b>94</b> which is disposed inside the transfer drum <b>90</b>, and the ink which has been deposited on the recording surface is dried.</p>
<p id="p-0136" num="0135">The paper P which has been transferred to the ink drying drum <b>51</b> is conveyed along a prescribed conveyance path by the ink drying drum <b>51</b>, and in the course of this conveyance, a hot air flow is blown onto the recording surface from the ink drying apparatus <b>52</b>, thereby drying the liquid components remaining on the recording surface.</p>
<p id="p-0137" num="0136">The paper P which has undergone the drying process is transferred from the ink drying drum <b>51</b> to the transfer drum <b>100</b>, conveyed along a prescribed conveyance path, and transferred to the fixing drum <b>61</b> of the fixing unit <b>60</b>. In the course of conveyance by the transfer drum <b>100</b>, a hot air flow is blown onto the recording surface from the drier <b>104</b> which is disposed inside the transfer drum <b>100</b>, thereby further drying the ink which has been deposited on the recording surface.</p>
<p id="p-0138" num="0137">The paper P which has been transferred to the fixing drum <b>61</b> is conveyed along a prescribed conveyance path by the fixing drum <b>61</b>, and in the course of this conveyance is heated and pressurized by the heat rollers <b>62</b>, <b>63</b>, thereby fixing the image formed on the recording surface. The paper P is then transferred onto the paper output conveyor <b>72</b> of the recovery unit <b>70</b> from the fixing drum <b>61</b>, conveyed by the paper output conveyor <b>72</b> up to the stacker <b>71</b>, and then output into the stacker <b>71</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0139" num="0138">As described above, in the inkjet recording apparatus <b>10</b> according to the present embodiment, the paper P is conveyed on drums and in the course of this conveyance, respective processes of treatment liquid deposition and drying, ejection of ink droplets, drying, and fixing are carried out on the paper P, thereby recording a prescribed image on the paper P.</p>
<p id="h-0014" num="0000">Paper Floating Detection Apparatus</p>
<p id="p-0140" num="0139">Embodiments of the paper floating detection apparatus are described below.</p>
<heading id="h-0015" level="1">First Embodiment</heading>
<p id="h-0016" num="0000">Composition</p>
<p id="p-0141" num="0140">As described above, in the inkjet recording apparatus <b>10</b> according to the present embodiment, a paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b> is incorporated into the image recording unit <b>40</b>, and floating up of the paper P is detected before ejection of ink droplets.</p>
<p id="p-0142" num="0141"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref> are, respectively, a front view diagram and a plan diagram of a first embodiment of the paper floating detection apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0143" num="0142">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref>, the paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b> includes a light emission unit <b>310</b> which emits a detection beam (laser light) B, a light reception unit <b>312</b> which receives the detection beam B emitted from the light emission unit <b>310</b>, a parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> which is disposed in front of the light emission unit <b>310</b>, a light emission motor <b>316</b> which drives and rotates the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b>, and a light emission start position detection sensor <b>318</b> which detects a start position of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0144" num="0143">The light emission unit <b>310</b> and the light reception unit <b>312</b> constitute a paper floating detection device which detects floating of the paper P. The light emission unit <b>310</b> and the light reception unit <b>312</b> are arranged so as to be mutually opposing via the image recording drum <b>41</b> (namely, so as to be mutually opposing via the conveyance path of the paper P).</p>
<p id="p-0145" num="0144">The light emission unit <b>310</b> is installed on the main body frame of the inkjet recording apparatus <b>10</b> via a bracket, which is not illustrated. This light emission unit <b>310</b> includes a light emitting element and emits a detection beam B from the light emitting element toward the light reception unit <b>312</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0146" num="0145">Here, the detection beam B is emitted in parallel with the axis of rotation T of the image recording drum <b>41</b> (namely, perpendicularly with respect to the conveyance direction of the paper P), as well as being emitted so as to pass through a position at a prescribed height H from the outer circumferential surface (conveyance surface) of the image recording drum <b>41</b>. Therefore, the light emission unit <b>310</b> is arranged so as to satisfy these conditions.</p>
<p id="p-0147" num="0146">The system controller <b>200</b> controls the driving of the light emission unit <b>310</b> so as to control the emission of the detection beam B.</p>
<p id="p-0148" num="0147">The light reception unit <b>312</b> is installed on the main body frame of the inkjet recording apparatus <b>10</b> via a bracket, which is not illustrated. The light reception unit <b>312</b> includes a light receiving element (for example, a transmissive photoelectric element), and the detection beam B emitted from the light emission unit <b>310</b> is received by this light receiving element. The light receiving element is provided so as to oppose the light emitting element of the light emission unit <b>310</b> and receives the detection beam B which is emitted from the light emitting element in parallel with the axis of rotation T of the image recording drum <b>41</b> and in a position at a prescribed height H from the outer circumferential surface of the image recording drum <b>41</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0149" num="0148">The light reception information (amount of light received) of the detection beam B obtained by the light reception unit <b>312</b> is output to the system controller <b>200</b>. The system controller <b>200</b> judges the presence or absence of floating of the paper P on the basis of the light reception information of the detection beam B obtained by the light reception unit <b>312</b>. More specifically, the amount of light received is compared with a previously specified threshold value, and if the amount of light received is equal to or lower than the threshold value, then it is judged that the detection beam B has been shielded by the paper P and hence it is judged that floating of the paper P has occurred.</p>
<p id="p-0150" num="0149">The parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> is constituted by a rectangle-shaped transparent glass plate having an incident face <b>314</b><i>a </i>and an emission face <b>314</b><i>b</i>, these faces being mutually parallel. This parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> is arranged in front of the light emission unit <b>310</b> (between the light emission unit <b>310</b> and the image recording drum <b>41</b>), and is provided rotatably about a rotational axle <b>315</b> disposed on a side face of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> on the upstream side in terms of the direction of conveyance of the paper P. The rotational axle <b>315</b> of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> is arranged so as to lie in parallel with the conveyance surface of the paper P (here, in parallel with the direction of the tangent to the image recording drum <b>41</b> at the point of passage of the detection beam B), as well as being perpendicular to the detection beam B which is emitted from the light emission unit <b>310</b>. Furthermore, the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> is arranged in such a manner that the detection beam B emitted from the light emission unit <b>310</b> is incident approximately in the center of the incident face <b>314</b><i>a </i>thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0151" num="0150">The detection beam B emitted from the light emission unit <b>310</b> passes through the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> and is received by the light reception unit <b>312</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0152" num="0151">Here, when the incident face <b>314</b><i>a </i>of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> is perpendicular to the detection beam B, then the detection beam B incident on the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> proceeds straight without alternation and exits from the emission face <b>314</b><i>b</i>. On the other hand, if the incident face <b>314</b><i>a </i>of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> is inclined with respect to the detection beam B, then the light axis is shifted upward or downward by refraction (by an amount corresponding to the refractive index) and exits from the emission face <b>314</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0153" num="0152">More specifically, by altering the angle of inclination of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b>, it is possible to alter the height h of the detection beam B which passes above the image recording drum. Furthermore, the angle of inclination of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> can be altered by rotating the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0154" num="0153"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a graph showing the relationship between the angle of rotation (angle of inclination) of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> and the amount X of displacement in the height direction of the detection beam.</p>
<p id="p-0155" num="0154">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the attitude which is perpendicular to the detection beam B is 0&#xb0;, an angle of rotation in the counter-clockwise direction is positive (+) and an angle of rotation in the clockwise direction is negative (&#x2212;).</p>
<p id="p-0156" num="0155">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the position of the detection beam B is displaced upwards and downwards in accordance with the angle of rotation (angle of inclination) of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0157" num="0156">Therefore, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6A</figref>, <b>6</b>B and <b>6</b>C, by adjusting the angle of rotation (angle of inclination) &#x3b8; of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b>, it is possible to adjust the height h of the detection beam B which passes above the image recording drum <b>41</b> (namely, the position of the detection beam B which is emitted from the emission face <b>314</b><i>b</i>). This height adjustment enables fine adjustment, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> (has high resolution), and therefore highly accurate height adjustment can be performed.</p>
<p id="p-0158" num="0157">The light emission motor <b>316</b> drives rotation of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b>. This light emission motor <b>316</b> is constituted by a pulse motor which is capable of forward and reverse rotations, for example, and is installed on the main body frame of the inkjet recording apparatus <b>10</b> via a bracket, which is not illustrated. The parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> is disposed in a prescribed position by being installed on the output shaft of the light emission motor <b>316</b>. Therefore, by driving this light emission motor <b>316</b>, it is possible to rotate the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> (in the forward direction or reverse direction).</p>
<p id="p-0159" num="0158">The system controller <b>200</b> controls the driving of the light emission motor <b>316</b> so as to control the angle of rotation (angle of inclination) of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> and hence the height h of the detection beam B.</p>
<p id="p-0160" num="0159">A light emission start position detection sensor <b>318</b> detects that the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> is situated in a start position. In other words, this sensor <b>318</b> detects that the angle of inclination of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> is 0&#xb0; (that the incident face <b>314</b><i>a </i>of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> is not inclined with respect to the detection beam B emitted from the light emission unit <b>310</b>). The light emission start position detection sensor <b>318</b> is constituted by a proximity sensor (magnetic sensor, or the like), for example, and is arranged directly below the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> when the angle of inclination is 0&#xb0;. A detection object (not illustrated) is installed on the lower surface portion of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b>, and by detecting this detection object by means of the light emission start position detection sensor <b>318</b>, it is detected that the angle of inclination of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> is 0&#xb0;. The output from the light emission start position detection sensor <b>318</b> is sent to the system controller <b>200</b>, and the system controller <b>200</b> detects that the angle of inclination of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> is 0&#xb0;, on the basis of the output from the light emission start position detection sensor <b>318</b>. In other words, the system controller <b>200</b> detects that the plate <b>314</b> is situated in a start position.</p>
<p id="p-0161" num="0160">The composition of the light emission start position detection sensor <b>318</b> is not limited to this and it is also possible to use another composition. Furthermore, in the example described above, a composition is adopted in which detection is made in a non-contact fashion by using a proximity sensor, but it is also possible to adopt a composition in which detection is made using a contact type sensor.</p>
<p id="h-0017" num="0000">Action</p>
<p id="p-0162" num="0161">Next, the action of the paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b> according to the present embodiment having the composition described above will be explained.</p>
<p id="p-0163" num="0162">Floating of paper P is detected by emitting a detection beam B at a prescribed height from the conveyance surface of the paper P (namely, in the present embodiment, the outer circumferential surface of the image recording drum <b>41</b>) and detecting whether or not the light is shielded by the paper P. The presence or absence of shielding by the paper P is judged on the basis of whether or not the detection beam B is received by the light reception unit <b>312</b>. More specifically, if the detection beam B is shielded by the paper P, then the detection beam B ceases to be received by the light reception unit <b>312</b> and therefore, on this basis, it is detected that floating of the paper P has occurred.</p>
<p id="p-0164" num="0163">Firstly, the detection height h<b>0</b> for floating of the paper P is set. The detection height h<b>0</b> for floating of the paper P is set to the sum of the thickness t of the paper P plus a predetermined floating tolerance value &#x3b1; (for example, assigned tolerance), (t+&#x3b1;).</p>
<p id="p-0165" num="0164">The detection height h<b>0</b> for floating of the paper P is set by setting the height of the detection beam which has passed through the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> (the detection beam having passed above the image recording drum <b>41</b>) B to a position at a height of h<b>0</b>(=t+&#x3b1;) from the conveyance surface (the outer circumferential surface of the image recording drum <b>41</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0166" num="0165"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a flowchart showing steps for setting the detection height for floating of the paper.</p>
<p id="p-0167" num="0166">Firstly, the system controller <b>200</b> situates the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> at a start position.</p>
<p id="p-0168" num="0167">This process is carried out by driving the light emission motor <b>316</b> to rotate the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> in one direction (the clockwise direction: CW), and detecting that the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> is situated in the start position by means of the light emission start position detection sensor <b>318</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0169" num="0168">Consequently, firstly, the system controller <b>200</b> drives the light emission motor <b>316</b> to turn the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> in the clockwise direction (CW) (step S<b>10</b>). The system controller <b>200</b> judges whether or not the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> has arrived at the start position on the basis of the output from the light emission start position detection sensor <b>318</b> (step S<b>11</b>). If it is judged that the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> has arrived at the start position, then the driving of the light emission motor <b>316</b> is halted, thereby halting the rotation of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> (step S<b>12</b>). By this means, the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> is located in the start position.</p>
<p id="p-0170" num="0169">Next, the system controller <b>200</b> causes the light emission unit <b>310</b> to emit a detection beam B (step S<b>13</b>). The detection beam B emitted from the light emission unit <b>310</b> passes through a position at a prescribed height H from the conveyance surface and is received by the light reception unit <b>312</b>. In this state, the system controller <b>200</b> performs processing for detecting the conveyance surface, in other words, processing for locating the detection beam B in a reference position.</p>
<p id="p-0171" num="0170">Firstly, the light emission motor <b>316</b> is driven and the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> is rotated in the clockwise direction (CW) (rotated in a direction whereby the detection beam B approaches the conveyance surface) (step S<b>14</b>). By this means, the height of the detection beam B is gradually reduced and at a certain point, the beam ceases to be received by the light reception unit <b>312</b>. The system controller <b>200</b> judges whether or not the conveyance surface has been detected, and judges whether or not the detection beam B is located in the reference position, on the basis of the output from the light reception unit <b>312</b> (step S<b>15</b>). More specifically, when the detection beam B reaches the height of the conveyance surface, the detection beam B is shielded by the conveyance surface (in the present embodiment, shielded by the image recording drum <b>41</b>), and therefore the system controller <b>200</b> judges whether or not the detection beam B is situated in the reference position (the position of the conveyance surface) by judging whether or not the detection beam B is received by the light reception unit <b>312</b>. If it is judged that the detection beam B is positioned at the reference position, then the rotation of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> is halted (step S<b>16</b>). By this means, the detection beam B is situated on the conveyance surface.</p>
<p id="p-0172" num="0171">Next, the system controller <b>200</b> situates the detection beam B in a position at a detection height h<b>0</b> from the reference position (the position of the conveyance surface). This process is carried out by driving the light emission motor <b>316</b> to rotate the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> by a specified amount in the counter-clockwise direction (CCW) (namely, to rotate the detection beam B by a specified amount in a direction away from the conveyance surface) (step S<b>17</b>). In other words, since the amount of rotation of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> and the amount of displacement of the detection beam B are already known (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>), the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> is rotated (in the counter-clockwise direction) by an amount whereby the detection beam B is situated in a position at a detection height h<b>0</b> from the conveyance surface. By this means, the detection beam B is situated in a position at a detection height h<b>0</b> from the conveyance surface.</p>
<p id="p-0173" num="0172">By the series of steps described above, the setting of the detection height h<b>0</b> for floating of the paper P is completed. Thereupon, detection can be performed.</p>
<p id="p-0174" num="0173">As described above, floating of the paper P is detected on the basis of whether or not the detection beam B is received by the light reception unit <b>312</b>. More specifically, if floating of the paper P occurs, then the detection beam B is shielded by the floating paper P, and therefore the detection beam B ceases to be received by the light reception unit <b>312</b> (the amount of received light becomes equal to or lower than a threshold value). The system controller <b>200</b> judges that floating of the paper P has occurred on the basis of the fact that the detection beam B has ceased to be received by the light reception unit <b>312</b>, and implements a prescribed warning operation (flashing of a warning lamp, issuing of a warning sound from the speaker, or the like). Furthermore, the conveyance of paper P is halted simultaneously with this.</p>
<p id="p-0175" num="0174">In this way, in the paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b> according to the present embodiment, it is possible to alter the height of the detection beam B by rotating the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b>. By this means, it is possible to change the detection height h<b>0</b> for floating of the paper P, in a simple fashion.</p>
<p id="p-0176" num="0175">Furthermore, since a composition is adopted in which the detection beam B is displaced by an amount corresponding to the refractive index by rotating the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b>, then the height can be adjusted with high resolution and highly accurate height setting can be performed. By this means, it is possible to achieve highly accurate detection of floating.</p>
<p id="p-0177" num="0176">Moreover, when setting the detection height h<b>0</b>, it is possible to adjust the height by detecting the conveyance surface, and therefore the detection height h<b>0</b> can be set with good accuracy. Furthermore, it is also possible to achieve stable detection which is resistant to temporal change.</p>
<p id="p-0178" num="0177">In the example described above, when setting the detection height h<b>0</b> for floating of the paper P, the process of detecting the reference position is carried out only once, but desirably, this process is repeated a plurality of times. In other words, desirably, the process in steps S<b>14</b> to S<b>17</b> described above is repeated a plurality of times. By this means, it is possible to set the height with even higher accuracy.</p>
<heading id="h-0018" level="1">Second Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0179" num="0178"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a front view diagram of a second embodiment of the paper floating detection apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0180" num="0179">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, in the paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b>A according to the present embodiment, a light reception aperture <b>320</b> having a prescribed opening is disposed in front of the light reception unit <b>312</b> (between the light reception unit <b>312</b> and the image recording drum <b>41</b>). This light reception aperture <b>320</b> is fixed to a main body frame of the inkjet recording apparatus <b>10</b> via a bracket, which is not illustrated.</p>
<p id="p-0181" num="0180">By disposing a light reception aperture <b>320</b> of this kind in front of the light reception unit <b>312</b>, then even if a certain amount of discrepancy occurs between the positioning of the light emission unit <b>310</b> and the light reception unit <b>312</b>, the position of the optical axis of the detection beam B can still be specified by the light reception aperture <b>320</b>, and a highly robust structure can be achieved.</p>
<p id="p-0182" num="0181">In the present example, an aperture is provided only on the light reception side, but desirably, an aperture is disposed in a similar fashion on the light emission side (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>). In other words, desirably, a light emission aperture is arranged in front of the light emission unit <b>310</b> (between the light emission unit <b>310</b> and the image recording drum <b>41</b>). In this case, desirably, the opening surface area of the light reception aperture is smaller than the opening surface area of the light emission aperture. By this means, it is possible to extremely reduce the effects of the introduction of reflected light, and therefore detection of even higher accuracy can be performed.</p>
<heading id="h-0019" level="1">Third Embodiment</heading>
<p id="h-0020" num="0000">Composition</p>
<p id="p-0183" num="0182"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</figref> are, respectively, a front view diagram and a plan diagram of a third embodiment of the paper floating detection apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0184" num="0183">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</figref>, the paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b>B according to the present embodiment includes a parallel flat glass plate provided on the light reception side. Consequently, it is possible to adjust the position of the optical axis of the detection beam B on the light reception side as well.</p>
<p id="p-0185" num="0184">The composition on the light emission side is the same as the composition of the first embodiment described above, and therefore only the composition on the light reception side is described here.</p>
<p id="p-0186" num="0185">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</figref>, a parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b>, a light reception motor <b>336</b> which drives the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> to rotate, and a light reception start position detection sensor <b>338</b> which detects the start position of the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> are provided in front of the light reception unit <b>312</b> (between the light reception unit <b>312</b> and the image recording drum <b>41</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0187" num="0186">The parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b>, similarly to the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b>, is constituted by a rectangle-shaped transparent glass plate having an incident face <b>334</b><i>a </i>and an emission face <b>334</b><i>b</i>, these faces being mutually parallel. This parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> is arranged in front of the light reception unit <b>312</b> (between the light reception unit <b>312</b> and the image recording drum <b>41</b>), and is provided rotatably about a rotational axle <b>335</b> disposed on a side face of the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> to the upstream side in terms of the direction of conveyance of the paper P. The rotational axle <b>335</b> of the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> is arranged so as to lie in parallel with the conveyance surface of the paper P (here, in parallel with the direction of a tangent to the image recording drum <b>41</b> at the point of passage of the detection beam B), as well as being perpendicular to the detection beam B which is emitted from the light emission unit <b>310</b>. Furthermore, the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> is also arranged in such a manner that the center of the emission surface <b>334</b><i>b </i>coincides substantially with the center of the light receiving surface of the light reception unit <b>312</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0188" num="0187">The detection beam B which has passed through the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> subsequently passes through the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> and is received by the light reception unit <b>312</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0189" num="0188">Here, when the incident face <b>334</b><i>a </i>of the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> is perpendicular to the detection beam B, then the detection beam B incident on the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> proceeds straight without alternation and exits from the emission face <b>334</b><i>b</i>. On the other hand, if the incident face <b>334</b><i>a </i>of the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> is inclined with respect to the detection beam B, then the light axis is shifted upward or downward by refraction (by an amount corresponding to the refractive index) and exits from the emission face <b>334</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0190" num="0189">More specifically, by changing the angle of inclination of the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b>, it is possible to alter the height position of the detection beam B which is received by the light reception unit <b>312</b>. Furthermore, the angle of inclination of the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> can be altered by rotating the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0191" num="0190">The light reception motor <b>336</b> drives rotation of the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b>. This light reception motor <b>336</b> is constituted by a pulse motor capable of forward and reverse rotations, for example, and is installed on the main body frame of the inkjet recording apparatus <b>10</b> via a bracket, which is not illustrated. The parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> is disposed in a prescribed position by being installed on the output shaft of the light reception motor <b>336</b>. Therefore, by driving this light reception motor <b>336</b>, it is possible to rotate the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> (in the forward direction or reverse direction).</p>
<p id="p-0192" num="0191">The system controller <b>200</b> controls the driving of the light reception motor <b>336</b> so as to control the angle of rotation (angle of inclination) of the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> and hence the height position of the detection beam B that enters the light reception unit <b>312</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0193" num="0192">The light reception start position determination sensor <b>338</b> determines that the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> is situated in a start position. In other words, this sensor <b>338</b> determines that the angle of inclination of the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> is 0&#xb0; (that the incident face <b>334</b><i>a </i>of the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> is not inclined with respect to the detection beam B). The light reception start position determination sensor <b>338</b> is constituted by a proximity sensor (magnetic sensor, or the like), for example, and is arranged directly below the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> when the angle of inclination is 0&#xb0;. A detection object (not illustrated) is installed on the lower surface portion of the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b>, and by detecting this detection object by means of the light reception start position determination sensor <b>338</b>, it is determined that the angle of inclination of the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> is 0&#xb0;. The output from the light reception start position determination sensor <b>338</b> is sent to the system controller <b>200</b>, and the system controller <b>200</b> determines that the angle of inclination of the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> is 0&#xb0;, on the basis of the output from the light reception start position determination sensor <b>338</b>. In other words, the system controller <b>200</b> detects that the plate <b>334</b> is situated in a start position.</p>
<p id="p-0194" num="0193">The composition of the light reception start position detection sensor <b>338</b> is not limited to this and it is also possible to use another composition. Furthermore, in the example described above, a composition is adopted in which detection is made in a non-contact fashion by using a proximity sensor, but it is also possible to adopt a composition in which detection is made using a contact type sensor.</p>
<p id="h-0021" num="0000">Action</p>
<p id="p-0195" num="0194">Next, the action of the paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b>B according to the present embodiment having the composition described above will be explained.</p>
<p id="p-0196" num="0195">The method of detecting floating of the paper P is the same as in the paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b> according to the first embodiment described above (namely, determining whether or not the detection beam B is shielded by the floating of paper P), and therefore the method of setting the detection height for floating of the paper P is described here.</p>
<p id="p-0197" num="0196">Similarly to the paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b> of the first embodiment described above, the detection height h<b>0</b> for floating of the paper P is set to the sum of the thickness t of the paper P plus a predetermined floating tolerance value a (for example, assigned tolerance), (t+&#x3b1;).</p>
<p id="p-0198" num="0197"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a flowchart showing steps for setting the detection height for floating of the paper.</p>
<p id="p-0199" num="0198">Firstly, the system controller <b>200</b> situates the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> and the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> respectively at start positions.</p>
<p id="p-0200" num="0199">Firstly, the system controller <b>200</b> drives the light emission motor <b>316</b> to turn the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> in the clockwise direction (CW) (step S<b>20</b>). The system controller <b>200</b> judges whether or not the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> has arrived at the start position on the basis of the output from the light emission start position detection sensor <b>318</b> (step S<b>21</b>). If it is judged that the plate <b>314</b> has arrived at the start position, then the driving of the light emission motor <b>316</b> is halted, thereby halting the rotation of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> (step S<b>22</b>). By this means, the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> is located in the start position.</p>
<p id="p-0201" num="0200">Thereupon, the system controller <b>200</b> drives the light reception motor <b>336</b> to turn the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> in the counter-clockwise direction (CCW) (step S<b>23</b>). The system controller <b>200</b> judges whether or not the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> has arrived at the start position on the basis of the output from the light reception start position detection sensor <b>338</b> (step S<b>24</b>). If it is judged that the plate <b>334</b> has arrived at the start position, then the driving of the light reception motor <b>336</b> is halted, thereby halting the rotation of the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> (step S<b>25</b>). By this means, the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> is located in the start position.</p>
<p id="p-0202" num="0201">Next, the system controller <b>200</b> causes the light emission unit <b>310</b> to emit a detection beam B (step S<b>26</b>). The detection beam B emitted from the light emission unit <b>310</b> passes through a position at a prescribed height H from the conveyance surface and is received by the light reception unit <b>312</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0203" num="0202">Thereupon, the system controller <b>200</b> drives the light emission motor <b>316</b> to rotate the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> in the clockwise direction (CW) (in a direction whereby the detection beam B approaches the conveyance surface) (step S<b>27</b>). By this means, the height of the detection beam B is gradually reduced and at a certain point, the beam ceases to be received by the light reception unit <b>312</b>. The system controller <b>200</b> judges whether or not the detection beam B has ceased to be received by the light reception unit <b>312</b>, on the basis of the output from the light reception unit <b>312</b> (step S<b>28</b>). If it is judged that the detection beam B has ceased to be received by the light reception unit <b>312</b>, then the rotation of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> is halted (step S<b>29</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0204" num="0203">Thereupon, the system controller <b>200</b> drives the light emission motor <b>316</b> and rotates the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> by a prescribed amount in the counter-clockwise direction (CCW) (by a prescribed distance in a direction whereby the detection beam B moves away from the conveyance surface) so that the detection beam B is received at the light reception unit <b>312</b> (step S<b>30</b>). By this means, the detection beam B is received again by the light reception unit <b>312</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0205" num="0204">Thereupon, the system controller <b>200</b> drives the light reception motor <b>336</b> to turn the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> in the counter-clockwise direction (CCW) (step S<b>31</b>). By this means, at a certain point, the detection beam B again ceases to be received by the light reception unit <b>312</b>. The system controller <b>200</b> judges whether or not the detection beam B is received, on the basis of the output from the light reception unit <b>312</b> (step S<b>32</b>). If it is judged that the detection beam B has ceased to be received by the light reception unit <b>312</b>, then the rotation of the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> is halted (step S<b>33</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0206" num="0205">The system controller <b>200</b>, taking the position where the detection beam B ceases to be received as a reference position (the position of the conveyance surface), rotates the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> by a specified amount in the counter-clockwise direction (CCW) (step S<b>34</b>) and also rotates the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b> by a specified amount in the clockwise direction (CW) (step S<b>35</b>) so as to situate the detection beam B in a position at a prescribed detection height h<b>0</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0207" num="0206">By the series of steps described above, the setting of the detection height h<b>0</b> for floating of the paper P is completed. Thereupon, detection can be performed.</p>
<p id="p-0208" num="0207">In this way, by arranging a parallel flat glass plate on the light receiving side as well and enabling adjustment of the height of the detection beam B, it is possible to detect floating of the paper P with even higher accuracy.</p>
<p id="p-0209" num="0208">In the example described above, the process of detecting a reference position is performed only once, but desirably, this process is carried out a plurality of times. In other words, desirably, the process in steps S<b>27</b> to S<b>35</b> described above is repeated a plurality of times. By this means, it is possible to set the height with even higher accuracy.</p>
<heading id="h-0022" level="1">Fourth Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0210" num="0209"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a front view diagram of a fourth embodiment of the paper floating detection apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0211" num="0210">According to the paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b>C according to the present embodiment as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, a light receiving aperture <b>320</b> is further provided in front of the light reception unit <b>312</b> (between the light reception unit <b>312</b> and the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b>) in the paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b>B according to the third embodiment. This light reception aperture <b>320</b> is fixed to a main body frame of the inkjet recording apparatus <b>10</b> via a bracket, which is not illustrated.</p>
<p id="p-0212" num="0211">By disposing a light reception aperture <b>320</b> of this kind in front of the light reception unit <b>312</b>, then even if a certain amount of discrepancy occurs between the positioning of the light emission unit <b>310</b> and the light reception unit <b>312</b>, the position of the optical axis of the detection beam B can still be specified by the light reception aperture <b>320</b>, and a highly robust structure can be achieved.</p>
<p id="p-0213" num="0212">In the present example, an aperture is provided only on the light reception side, but desirably, an aperture is disposed in a similar fashion on the light emission side (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>). In other words, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, a light emission aperture <b>322</b> is arranged in front of the light emission unit <b>310</b> (between the light emission unit <b>310</b> and the image recording drum <b>41</b>). In this case, desirably, the opening surface area S<b>2</b> of the light reception aperture <b>320</b> is smaller than the opening surface area S<b>1</b> of the light emission aperture <b>322</b>. By this means, it is possible to extremely reduce the effects of the introduction of reflected light, and therefore detection of even higher accuracy can be performed.</p>
<heading id="h-0023" level="1">Fifth Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0214" num="0213"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is a plan view diagram of a paper floating detection apparatus according to a fifth embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0215" num="0214">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref>, according to the paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b>D according to the present embodiment, a detection beam B is emitted at a prescribed angle of inclination (an inclination of 0.3&#xb0; to 2&#xb0;) with respect to a direction perpendicular to the conveyance direction of the paper P (namely, with respect to the axial direction of the image recording drum <b>41</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0216" num="0215">By inclining the detection beam B at a prescribed angle with respect to the direction perpendicular to the conveyance direction of the paper P in this way, it is possible to accurately detect the floating in the direction perpendicular to the conveyance direction of the paper P.</p>
<p id="p-0217" num="0216">In this way, in the paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b>D according to the present embodiment, since the detection beam B is inclined at a prescribed angle with respect to the direction perpendicular to the conveyance direction of the paper P, then the light emission unit and the light reception unit, and the like, are disposed so as to be inclined at a prescribed angle with respect to the direction perpendicular to the conveyance direction of the paper P.</p>
<p id="p-0218" num="0217">In the present embodiment, a composition is adopted in which the detection beam B is inclined in the composition of the paper floating detection apparatus <b>300</b>B according to the third embodiment described above, but it is also possible to adopt a composition in which the detection beam B is inclined with respect to the direction perpendicular to the conveyance direction of the paper P in a paper floating detection apparatus according to another embodiment. In such a case, similar beneficial effects can be obtained.</p>
<heading id="h-0024" level="1">Sixth Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0219" num="0218">As described above, in a paper floating detection apparatus according to a sixth embodiment, when setting the detection height for floating of paper P, a reference position (the position of the conveyance surface) is detected and the detection height for floating of the paper P is set by displacing the height of the detection beam B to a desired height position from the detected reference position. When detecting the reference position, the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> (and the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b>) are rotated in one direction from prescribed start positions, so as to detect the reference positions.</p>
<p id="p-0220" num="0219">When the apparatus has been used for a long period of time, the assembly precision, or the like, declines, and there is a change in the amount of rotation (number of pulses) of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> (and the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b>) that is required from the start position until the reference position is detected. Furthermore, when an abnormality has occurred in the apparatus, in a similar fashion, the assembly precision, or the like, declines, and there is a change in the amount of rotation (number of pulses) of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> (and the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b>) that is required from the start position until the reference position is detected.</p>
<p id="p-0221" num="0220">Therefore, the amount of rotation (number of pulses) of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> (and the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b>) required from the start position until detection of the reference position is detected as a reference amount of rotation for light emission (and a reference amount of rotation for light reception), and this amount is compared with a threshold value (a previously established reference amount of rotation (reference number of pulses)), an abnormality being judged to have occurred in the apparatus if the reference amount of rotation for light emission (or the reference amount of rotation for light reception) exceeds the threshold value.</p>
<p id="p-0222" num="0221">By this means, it is possible to detect an abnormality in the apparatus at an early stage and floating of the paper P can be detected in a stable fashion. If an apparatus abnormality is judged to have occurred, the system controller <b>200</b> implements a required warning operation. In response to this, an operator performs maintenance, cleaning, or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0223" num="0222">In order to implement this composition, desirably, the light emission motor <b>316</b> (and the light reception motor <b>336</b>) include a device for measuring the amount of rotation (in the case of a pulse motor, a device which counts the number of pulses). The system controller <b>200</b> detects the amount of rotation (number of pulses) of the parallel flat glass plate for light emission <b>314</b> (and the parallel flat glass plate for light reception <b>334</b>) required from the start position until the reference position is detected, on the basis of the measurement results of the device for measuring the amount of rotation of the light emission motor <b>316</b> (and the light reception motor <b>336</b>), and compares this amount of rotation with a threshold value (a previously established reference amount of rotation (number of reference pulses)) and judges that an apparatus abnormality has occurred if the detection amount of rotation exceeds the threshold value.</p>
<heading id="h-0025" level="1">Seventh Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0224" num="0223">In the embodiments described above, a paper floating detection apparatus according to an embodiment of the present invention is incorporated into an image recording unit <b>40</b> of an inkjet recording apparatus <b>10</b> and detects floating of the paper P conveyed by an image recording drum <b>41</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0225" num="0224">The image recording drum <b>41</b> has a large thermal capacity and if the detection beam B is projected in the vicinity of this drum, and if air with a different temperature from outside, etc., passes through the optical axis of the detection beam B, then the optical axis of the detection beam B is deflected, and therefore the beam can no longer be detected or detection errors can occur.</p>
<p id="p-0226" num="0225">Therefore, the system controller <b>200</b> either raises the detection height h<b>0</b> for floating of the paper P or halts detection of floating of the paper P when the detection of floating of the paper P is not required, such as when the inkjet heads <b>44</b>C, <b>44</b>M, <b>44</b>Y,d <b>44</b>K are not situated over the image recording drum <b>41</b> (for example, when the inkjet heads <b>44</b>C, <b>44</b>M, <b>44</b>Y, <b>44</b>K have been withdrawn to a maintenance unit) or when paper P is not passing (for example, during maintenance of the inkjet heads <b>44</b>C, <b>44</b>M, <b>44</b>Y, <b>44</b>K). By this means, detection errors, and the like, are prevented and the inkjet recording apparatus can be operated in a stable fashion.</p>
<heading id="h-0026" level="1">Further Embodiments</heading>
<p id="p-0227" num="0226">In the embodiments described above, examples are described in which a paper floating detection apparatus relating to an embodiment of the present invention is incorporated into an inkjet recording apparatus, but the application of the paper floating detection apparatus according to embodiments of the present invention is not limited to this. Embodiments of the present invention can also be applied to other recording apparatuses to incorporate a paper floating detection apparatus, and furthermore, can also be applied to apparatuses other than recording apparatuses.</p>
<p id="p-0228" num="0227">Moreover, in the embodiments described above, an example is given in which floating of paper conveyed by a conveyance drum is detected, but the application of the present invention is not limited to this. The present invention can also be applied similarly to a case where paper is conveyed by another conveyance device. For example, the invention can also be applied similarly to a case of detecting floating of paper conveyed by a conveyance belt. Furthermore, the invention can also be applied similarly to a case where paper is conveyed by sliding over a prescribed conveyance surface, and not only cases where paper is conveyed while being held by suction or the like. For example, the invention can be applied to cases of detecting floating of paper conveyed over a platen.</p>
<p id="p-0229" num="0228">In the embodiments described above, glass plates are used as the parallel flat plate for light emission and the parallel flat plate for light reception, but the material constituting the parallel flat plates is not limited to this. It is also possible to use parallel flat plates made from another material.</p>
<p id="p-0230" num="0229">It should be understood that there is no intention to limit the invention to the specific forms disclosed, but on the contrary, the invention is to cover all modifications, alternate constructions and equivalents falling within the spirit and scope of the invention as expressed in the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A paper floating detection apparatus which detects floating of paper conveyed along a prescribed conveyance path on a prescribed conveyance surface, the paper floating detection apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a paper floating detection device which includes a light emission unit and a light reception unit disposed so as to be mutually opposing across the conveyance path, and detects whether the paper floats or not according to whether a detection beam emitted parallel to the conveyance surface from the light emission unit toward the light reception unit in a position at a prescribed height from the conveyance surface is received by the light reception unit or not;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light emission parallel flat plate which is disposed in front of the light emission unit in such a manner that the detection beam emitted from the light emission unit passes through the light emission parallel flat plate, and which is provided rotatably about an axis parallel to the conveyance surface and perpendicular to the detection beam in such a manner that the height of the detection beam emitted from the light emission parallel flat plate after passing inside the light emission parallel flat plate varies according to rotation of the light emission parallel flat plate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light emission parallel flat plate rotation driving device which drives the rotation of the light emission parallel flat plate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The paper floating detection apparatus as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a light reception parallel flat plate which is disposed in front of the light reception unit in such a manner that the detection beam having passed through the light emission parallel flat plate passes through the light reception parallel flat plate, and which is provided rotatably about an axis parallel to the conveyance surface and perpendicular to the detection beam in such a manner that the height of the detection beam emitted from the light reception parallel flat plate after passing inside the light reception parallel flat plate varies according to rotation of the light reception parallel flat plate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light reception parallel flat plate rotation driving device which drives the rotation of the light reception parallel flat plate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The paper floating detection apparatus as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein an aperture for light reception is disposed between the light reception unit and the light reception parallel flat plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The paper floating detection apparatus as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein an aperture for light emission is disposed between the light emission unit and the light emission parallel flat plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The paper floating detection apparatus as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein an opening surface area of the aperture for light reception is set to be smaller than an opening surface area of the aperture for light emission.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The paper floating detection apparatus as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, further comprising a detection height adjustment device which controls driving of the light emission parallel flat plate rotation driving device and the light reception parallel flat plate rotation driving device according to a detection result of the paper floating detection device, so as to adjust the height of the detection beam,
<claim-text>wherein the detection height adjustment device performs an operation of:
<claim-text>causing the light emission parallel flat plate to rotate in a first direction in a state where the detection beam is received by the light reception unit, and halting the rotation of the light emission parallel flat plate when the detection beam is no longer received by the light reception unit, and rotating the light emission parallel flat plate by a prescribed amount in a second direction which is opposite to the first direction,</claim-text>
<claim-text>then causing the light reception parallel flat plate to rotate in the second direction, and halting the rotation of the light reception parallel flat plate when the detection beam is no longer received by the light reception unit, and employing, as reference positions, positions of the light emission parallel flat plate and the light reception parallel flat plate when the rotation of the light reception parallel flat plate is halted, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>causing the light reception parallel flat plate to rotate by a prescribed amount from the reference position in the first direction and causing the light emission parallel flat plate to rotate by a prescribed amount from the reference position in the second direction so as to adjust the height of the detection beam.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The paper floating detection apparatus as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the detection height adjustment device starts the operation from a prescribed start position for light emission, and
<claim-text>the paper floating detection apparatus further comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light emission reference rotation amount detection device which detects, as a light emission reference rotation amount, an amount of the rotation of the light emission parallel flat plate from the start position for light emission to the reference position; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an abnormality judgment device which compares the light emission reference rotation amount detected by the light emission reference rotation amount detection device with a threshold value so as to judge whether or not there is an apparatus abnormality.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The paper floating detection apparatus as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the detection height adjustment device starts the operation from a prescribed start position for light emission and a prescribed start position for light reception, and
<claim-text>the paper floating detection apparatus further comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light emission reference rotation amount detection device which detects, as a light emission reference rotation amount, an amount of the rotation of the light emission parallel flat plate from the start position for light emission to the reference position;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light reception reference rotation amount detection device which detects, as a light reception reference rotation amount, an amount of the rotation of the light reception parallel flat plate from the start position for light reception to the reference position; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an abnormality judgment device which compares the light emission reference rotation amount detected by the light emission reference rotation amount detection device with a threshold value and compares the light reception reference rotation amount detected by the light reception reference rotation amount detection device with a threshold value so as to judge whether or not there is an apparatus abnormality.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The paper floating detection apparatus as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the detection height adjustment device repeats the operation a plurality of times so as to adjust the height of the detection beam.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The paper floating detection apparatus as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a detection height adjustment device which controls driving of the light emission parallel flat plate rotation driving device according to a detection result of the paper floating detection device, so as to adjust the height of the detection beam,
<claim-text>wherein the detection height adjustment device performs an operation of:
<claim-text>causing the light emission parallel flat plate to rotate in a first direction in a state where the detection beam is received by the light reception unit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>halting the rotation of the light emission parallel flat plate when the detection beam is no longer received by the light reception unit and employing, as a reference position, a position of the light emission parallel flat plate when the rotation of the light emission parallel flat plate is halted, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>causing the light emission parallel flat plate to rotate by a prescribed amount from the reference position in a second direction which is opposite to the first direction so as to adjust the height of the detection beam.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The paper floating detection apparatus as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the detection height adjustment device starts the operation from a prescribed start position for light emission, and
<claim-text>the paper floating detection apparatus further comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light emission reference rotation amount detection device which detects, as a light emission reference rotation amount, an amount of the rotation of the light emission parallel flat plate from the start position for light emission to the reference position; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an abnormality judgment device which compares the light emission reference rotation amount detected by the light emission reference rotation amount detection device with a threshold value so as to judge whether there is an apparatus abnormality.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The paper floating detection apparatus as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the detection height adjustment device repeats the operation a plurality of times so as to adjust the height of the detection beam.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The paper floating detection apparatus as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the light emission unit and the light reception unit are disposed in such a manner that the detection beam emitted from the light emission unit toward the light reception unit is inclined at a prescribed angle with respect to a direction perpendicular to a conveyance direction of the paper.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. An inkjet recording apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a conveyance device which conveys paper;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an inkjet head which ejects droplets of ink onto a recording surface of the paper conveyed by the conveyance device to form an image;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the paper floating detection apparatus as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> which is disposed on an upstream side of the inkjet head and detects the floating of the paper from the conveyance surface of the conveyance device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a conveyance abnormality judgment device which judges a conveyance abnormality of the paper according to a detection result of the paper floating detection apparatus.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The inkjet recording apparatus as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the conveyance device is a conveyance drum which holds the paper by suction on an outer circumferential surface of the conveyance drum and conveys the paper by rotating.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The inkjet recording apparatus as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the inkjet head is provided movably between an image formation position where the droplets of ink are ejected onto the recording surface of the paper conveyed by the conveyance device to form the image and a withdrawn position where the inkjet head is withdrawn from the conveyance device, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the paper floating detection apparatus raises the height of the detection beam by a prescribed amount of height or halts detection, when the inkjet head is moved to the withdrawn position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The inkjet recording apparatus as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the paper floating detection apparatus raises the height of the detection beam by a prescribed amount of height or halts detection, when recording is halted. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
