<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625060-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625060</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13106968</doc-number>
<date>20110513</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>99133322 A</doc-number>
<date>20100930</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>153</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>1335</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>349113</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Reflective display apparatus</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0280635</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hinata</name>
<date>20051200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>345173</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>1713212</doc-number>
<date>20051200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>200604949</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20060200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>200745637</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20071200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>200837408</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20080900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>201013241</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20100400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00007">
<othercit>Taiwan Patent Office, &#x201c;Office Action&#x201d;, Aug. 15, 2013.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00008">
<othercit>China Patent Office, &#x201c;Office Action&#x201d;, Jul. 2, 2013.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>9</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>349113</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>1</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>1</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120081650</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120405</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wang</last-name>
<first-name>Yi-Ching</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsinchu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tsai</last-name>
<first-name>Yuan-Chih</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsinchu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wang</last-name>
<first-name>Yi-Ching</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsinchu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tsai</last-name>
<first-name>Yuan-Chih</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hsinchu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>WAPT, PC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>King</last-name>
<first-name>Justin</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>E Ink Holdings Inc.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Hsinchu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Vu</last-name>
<first-name>Phu</first-name>
<department>2871</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A reflective display apparatus includes a transparent substrate, a reflective substrate, a display layer and a transparent gluing layer. The transparent gluing layer is disposed between the transparent substrate and the display layer and the refractive indices of the transparent gluing layer and of the transparent substrate are substantially the same. Therefore, the energy loss of light can be reduced at the interface between the transparent gluing layer and the transparent substrate, so the brightness of the image displayed by the reflective display apparatus may be increased.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="126.49mm" wi="200.24mm" file="US08625060-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="199.22mm" wi="125.48mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625060-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to a reflective display apparatus, and more particularly to a reflective display apparatus with excellent light exitance rate.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">As compared to conventional display apparatus, reflective display apparatus is of energy saving due to it is capable of utilizing environment light as light source to display image.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The quality of the image displayed by the reflective display apparatus is greatly influenced by brightness of the light reflected by the reflective display apparatus. If the environment light is brighter and the light utilization rate of the reflective display apparatus is greater, the image displayed by the reflective display apparatus may be clearer. However, when the light enters a medium from another medium, the energy loss (Fresnel Loss) will be generated at the interface between the mediums because of light refraction. For example, when the light enters glass from air, the refractive indices at the interface is in the range about 7-8%. Therefore, how to reduce the energy loss rate of the light inside the reflective display apparatus to optimize the utilization rate of incident light is concerned by industry participants.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The present invention provides a reflective display apparatus with low energy loss and excellent light exitance rate.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In order to achieve the above-mentioned advantages, the present invention provides a reflective display apparatus includes a reflective substrate, a transparent substrate, a display layer and a transparent gluing layer. The display layer is disposed on the reflective substrate. The transparent substrate is disposed on the display layer. The transparent gluing layer is disposed between the transparent substrate and the display layer and the refractive indices of the transparent gluing layer and that of the transparent substrate are substantially the same.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In one embodiment of the present invention, the display layer is a liquid crystal layer, an electrowetting display layer or an electrophoretic display layer, such as a microcapsule electrophoretic display layer, a microcup electrophoretic display layer, or microgroove electrophoretic display layer.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In one embodiment of the present invention, the reflective display apparatus further includes a plurality of color filter films formed on the transparent substrate and located between the transparent substrate and the display layer.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In one embodiment of the present invention, the refractive index of the transparent gluing layer is no less than 1.4 and no more than 1.7.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In one embodiment of the present invention, material of the transparent gluing layer is epoxy, acrylic or silicone.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In one embodiment of the present invention, the transparent substrate is a touch panel.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In the reflective display apparatus of the present invention, the transparent gluing layer with substantially the same refractive index as the transparent substrate is disposed between the transparent substrate and the display layer. Therefore, the energy loss of light can be reduced when light exits from the reflective display apparatus, so the brightness of the image displayed by the reflective display apparatus may be increased.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The above objects and advantages of the present invention will become more readily apparent to those ordinarily skilled in the art after reviewing the following detailed description and accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic, cross sectional view of a reflective display apparatus according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The present invention will now be described more specifically with reference to the following embodiments. It is to be noted that the following descriptions of preferred embodiments of this invention are presented herein for purpose of illustration and description only. It is not intended to be exhaustive or to be limited to the precise form disclosed.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a reflective display apparatus <b>100</b> according to an embodiment of the present invention includes a transparent substrate <b>110</b>, a reflective substrate <b>120</b>, a display layer <b>130</b> and a transparent gluing layer <b>140</b>. The display layer <b>130</b> is disposed on the reflective substrate <b>120</b>. The transparent substrate <b>110</b> is disposed on the display layer <b>130</b>. The transparent gluing layer <b>140</b> is disposed between the transparent substrate <b>110</b> and the display layer <b>130</b>. More concretely, the reflective substrate <b>120</b> includes, for example, a plurality of pixel units (not shown), and each of the pixel units has a reflective surface <b>122</b>, the display layer <b>130</b> is disposed on and covers the reflective surface <b>122</b>. In this embodiment, the display layer <b>130</b> may be, but not limited to, a liquid crystal layer. In other embodiments, the display layer <b>130</b> may be an electrophoretic display layer, such as a microcup electrophoretic display layer, a microcapsule electrophoretic display layer, or a microgroove electrophoretic display layer. Alternatively, the display layer <b>130</b> may be an electrowetting display layer.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">More specially, the refractive indices of the transparent gluing layer <b>140</b> and that of the transparent substrate <b>110</b> are substantially the same. Therefore, the energy loss of the light L reflected by the reflective substrate <b>120</b> can be reduced at the interface between the transparent gluing layer <b>110</b> and the transparent substrate <b>140</b>. In this embodiment, the refractive index of the transparent gluing layer <b>140</b> is in the range of about 1.4 to 1.7, and 1.5 is preferred. Material of the transparent gluing layer <b>140</b> may be epoxy, acrylic or silicone. More concretely, the transparent gluing layer <b>140</b> may be a sheet or be formed by curing liquid material.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Also referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, in this embodiment, the transparent substrate <b>110</b> includes, for example, a plurality of color filter films <b>114</b> thereon. More concretely, the color filter films <b>114</b> may be red filter films, blue filer films and green filter films. That is to say, the display layer <b>130</b> is configured with a color filter <b>150</b> thereon, and the color filter <b>150</b> is composed of the color filter films <b>114</b> and the transparent substrate <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In other embodiments, the transparent substrate <b>110</b> may be, but not limited to, a touch panel.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">As mentioned above, in the reflective display apparatus of the present invention, the transparent gluing layer <b>140</b> with substantially the same refractive index as the transparent substrate <b>110</b> is disposed between the transparent substrate <b>110</b> and the display layer <b>130</b>. Therefore, the energy loss of the light can be reduced when light exits from the reflective display apparatus, so the brightness of the image displayed by the reflective display apparatus may be increased.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">While the invention has been described in terms of what is presently considered to be the most practical and preferred embodiments, it is to be understood that the invention needs not be limited to the disclosed embodiment. On the contrary, it is intended to cover various modifications and similar arrangements included within the spirit and scope of the appended claims which are to be accorded with the broadest interpretation so as to encompass all such modifications and similar structures.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A reflective display apparatus, comprising:
<claim-text>a reflective substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a display layer disposed on the reflective substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least a transparent substrate disposed on the display layer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transparent gluing layer disposed between the transparent substrate and the display layer, and the transparent gluing layer being contacted to the display layer directly, wherein a refractive index of the transparent gluing layer and a refractive index of the transparent substrate are substantially the same.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The reflective display apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the display layer is a liquid crystal layer, an electrowetting display layer or an electrophoretic display layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The reflective display apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the electrophoretic display layer includes a microcapsule electrophoretic display layer, a microcup electrophoretic display layer, or a microgroove electrophoretic display layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The reflective display apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising a plurality of color filter films formed on the transparent substrate and located between the transparent substrate and the display layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The reflective display apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the refractive index of the transparent gluing layer is no less than 1.4 and no more than 1.7.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The reflective display apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein material of the transparent gluing layer is epoxy, acrylic or silicone.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The reflective display apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the transparent substrate is a touch panel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The reflective display apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the transparent gluing layer is contacted to the color filter films.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The reflective display apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the reflective substrate comprises a plurality of pixel units, and each of the pixel units has a reflective surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
