<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="USH0002288-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>H0002288</doc-number>
<kind>H1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<us-sir-flag sir-text="A statutory invention registration is not a patent. It has the defensive attributes of a patent but does not have the enforceable attributes of a patent. No article or advertisement or the like may use the term patent, or any term suggestive of a patent, when referring to a statutory invention registration. For more specific information on the rights associated with a statutory invention registration see 35 U.S.C.157."/>
<application-reference appl-type="sir">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13836322</doc-number>
<date>20130315</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>29</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>47</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>425113</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e47">Uniform shear valve for an extrusion machine</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3253300</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Gove et al.</name>
<date>19660500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>165 64</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4367190</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Beach</name>
<date>19830100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>26417119</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>5</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>425113</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Davis-Standard, LLC</orgname>
<address>
<city>Pawcatuck</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Montalbano</last-name>
<first-name>John A.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Constantia</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Michaud-Kinney Group LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Davis-Standard, LLC</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Pawcatuck</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Pihulic</last-name>
<first-name>Daniel</first-name>
<department>3645</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A uniform shear valve for an extruder machine includes a body having a generally annular wall that defines an interior area extending along a longitudinal axis thereof. The interior area extends between an inlet proximate a first end of the body and a second end of the body. The second end is opposite the first end. The body has a first bore extending through the wall along a traverse axis substantially perpendicular to the longitudinal axis at a first position and second position. A flow control member is sealingly and slidingly positioned partially in the first bore at the first position and extends out of the body. The flow control member defines a first seat on an end thereof. An outlet is located in the first bore at the second position. A second seat is positioned proximate the outlet and is concentric with the first seat along the traverse axis. A uniform flow area is defined by a gap between the first seat and the second seat.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="174.58mm" wi="241.64mm" file="USH0002288-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="249.85mm" wi="171.28mm" orientation="landscape" file="USH0002288-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="193.29mm" wi="178.82mm" orientation="landscape" file="USH0002288-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="224.11mm" wi="188.47mm" orientation="landscape" file="USH0002288-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="245.36mm" wi="179.92mm" orientation="landscape" file="USH0002288-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="166.54mm" wi="169.76mm" orientation="landscape" file="USH0002288-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="214.88mm" wi="181.78mm" orientation="landscape" file="USH0002288-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to the field of control of the flow of polymer materials discharged from an extrusion machine and in particular to a valve which creates uniform shear flow of the polymer through the valve to eliminate melt fracture and melt memory effects in a polymer flowing therethough.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Extrusion devices are used to melt, blend, and form materials, such as plastics and polymers, into a desired shape. Typical extrusion devices include a rotating screw housed coaxially within a heated, cylindrically-shaped feed throat and barrel. A portion of the feed throat is cut away forming an opening for admission of materials. A hopper is coupled to the extrusion device for feeding the material through the opening, into the feed throat and subsequently into the barrel. The screw rotates within the feed throat and barrel and drives the material therethrough. The extrusion material is forced through a flanged discharge port at a discharge end of the barrel and into a downstream into a die or aperture.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">One of the basic problems that has plagued polymer industry is that when the polymer exits too fast from an extruder or through flow restrictions, such as in valves, a surface of the extruded polymer starts to exhibit undulations or irregularities. The undulations become progressively stronger as the flowrate increases. At even higher flow rates, the distortions can become so severe that they cause the extrudate to break, which is referred to as melt fracture. Melt memory relates to the elasticity of the melted polymer and can also affect the quality of the extruded polymer.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the prior art extrusion machine <b>10</b>, includes a valve <b>100</b> mounted on a discharge flange <b>11</b> of the extrusion machine <b>10</b> via a coupling <b>113</b>. The valve <b>100</b> includes a body <b>110</b> having an inlet <b>112</b> and an outlet <b>114</b>. The outlet <b>114</b> is positioned proximate an opposing end <b>116</b> of the inlet <b>112</b> and is oriented at an angle of about ninety (90) degrees from the inlet <b>112</b>. The opposing end <b>116</b> has an opening <b>118</b> therein and that is coaxial with the inlet <b>112</b> relative to a longitudinal axis L. A generally cylindrical plug <b>120</b> having a bore <b>121</b> extending therethrough is positioned in the opening <b>118</b>. The plug <b>120</b> defines a flange <b>122</b> formed on a distal end thereof. The flange <b>122</b> is secured to the opposing end <b>116</b> of the valve <b>100</b> with suitable fasteners <b>123</b>. The plug <b>120</b> also defines a body portion <b>124</b> that extends partially into an interior area <b>100</b>A defined by the valve <b>100</b>. The body portion <b>124</b> defines a radially inward tapered surface <b>126</b> that extends from one end <b>124</b>A of the body portion <b>124</b> towards the flange <b>120</b> and terminates therebetween by transitioning into a constant diameter D defined by the bore <b>121</b>. A screen pack <b>133</b> is positioned in the interior area <b>100</b>A between the inlet <b>112</b> and the end <b>124</b>A of the plug <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a flow control member <b>130</b> extends into the bore <b>121</b> concentrically with the longitudinal axis L. The flow control member <b>130</b> defines a tapered end <b>132</b> that is positioned in the bore <b>121</b>. The flow control member <b>130</b> translates along the longitudinal axis L in the bore <b>121</b> and a through packing gland <b>140</b>. The flow control member <b>130</b> controls the flow of high pressure polymer material discharged from the extrusion machine <b>10</b>, as described below. The flow control member <b>130</b> can be moved by a suitable operator, such as a hand-wheel. The packing gland <b>140</b> includes packing <b>142</b> which is compressed between walls of the bore <b>121</b> and an exterior surface <b>130</b>E of the of the flow control member <b>130</b>. The packing <b>142</b> is compressed by a packing follower <b>144</b> that is moveably secured to the end <b>116</b> of the valve <b>100</b> by suitable fasteners <b>145</b>, for example packing gland bolts.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, the outlet <b>114</b> defines a first opening <b>151</b> and a radially inward and axially outward tapered surface <b>152</b>. The tapered surface <b>152</b> extends between the first opening <b>151</b> and a transition point <b>153</b> of constant diameter of an outlet port <b>154</b>. There is a non-uniform flow area <b>160</b> defined at an intersection of the flow control member <b>130</b> and the general area defined by the outlet <b>114</b>, for example, proximate the first opening <b>151</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">During operation of the extrusion machine <b>10</b> and prior art valve <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, high pressure extruded polymer is discharged into the inlet <b>112</b> at a high pressure (e.g., 2200 psi). The flow control device <b>130</b> is selectively positioned in the bore <b>121</b> and over the outlet <b>114</b> to control the flow of the polymer into the outlet <b>114</b> thereby reducing the pressure of the polymer to about 250 psi. As the polymer flows through the non-uniform flow area <b>160</b> creating areas of high local shear <b>160</b>A, <b>160</b>B, <b>160</b>C and <b>160</b>D. The areas of high local shear <b>160</b>A, <b>160</b>B, <b>160</b>C and <b>160</b>D can create melt fracture and melt memory effects which cause profile disturbances in the polymer.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In addition, movement of the control member <b>130</b> is difficult because of the high pressure in the interior area <b>100</b>A which the flow control member <b>130</b> acts against.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to aspects illustrated herein, there is provided a uniform shear valve for an extruder machine. The uniform shear valve includes a body having a generally annular wall that defines an interior area extending along a longitudinal axis thereof. The interior area extends between an inlet proximate a first end of the body and a second end of the body. The second end is opposite the first end. The body has a first bore extending through the wall along a traverse axis substantially perpendicular to the longitudinal axis at a first position and second position. A flow control member is sealingly and slidingly positioned partially in the first bore at the first position and extends out of the body. The flow control member defines a first seat on an end thereof. An outlet is located in the first bore at the second position. A second seat is positioned proximate the outlet and is concentric with the first seat along the traverse axis. A uniform flow area is defined by a gap between the first seat and the second seat.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to another aspect illustrated herein, the uniform flow area is configured to eliminate melt fracture and melt memory effects in a fluid flowing therethough.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a cross sectional view of a prior art valve shown mounted on a discharge flange of an extruder;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is top view of a portion of the prior art valve taken across the line <b>2</b>-<b>2</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view of an extruder:</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cross sectional view of uniform shear valve of the present invention shown mounted on a discharge flange of the extruder of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a top view of a portion of the uniform shear valve of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> taken across the line <b>4</b>-<b>4</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a cross sectional view of uniform shear valve of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> with the plug removed.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, an extrusion machine is generally designated by the numeral <b>210</b>. The extrusion machine <b>210</b> includes a drive section <b>202</b>, a feed section <b>204</b> and an extrusion section <b>206</b> with the feed section <b>204</b> disposed between the drive section <b>202</b> and the extrusion section <b>206</b>. An extruder screw <b>288</b> as shown in cross section view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, has one end supported by and connected to a drive shaft (not shown) disposed within the drive section <b>202</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. The drive section <b>202</b> includes a gear box <b>202</b>A that is driven by a suitable driver (not shown) (e.g., a hydraulic drive system or a motor) that rotates gears (not shown) in the gear box <b>202</b>A, the shaft and the screw <b>288</b>. The screw <b>288</b> is also supported in the extrusion section <b>206</b> by a suitable bearing (not shown) such as a journal bearing. The extrusion machine <b>210</b> defines a discharge flange <b>211</b> for discharging high pressure (e.g., 2200 psi) extruded polymer therethrough and into a uniform shear valve <b>200</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the extrusion machine <b>210</b>, includes a uniform shear valve <b>200</b> mounted on a discharge flange <b>211</b> of the extrusion machine <b>210</b> via coupling <b>213</b>. The valve <b>200</b> includes a body <b>210</b> having an inlet <b>212</b> and an outlet <b>214</b>. The outlet <b>214</b> is positioned proximate an opposing end <b>216</b> of the inlet <b>212</b> and is oriented at an angle of about ninety (90) degrees from the inlet <b>212</b>. The opposing end <b>216</b> has an opening <b>218</b> therein and that is coaxial with the inlet <b>212</b> relative to a longitudinal axis L. A generally cylindrical plug <b>220</b> having a bore <b>221</b> extending partially therethrough is positioned in the opening <b>218</b>. The plug <b>220</b> defines a closed end flange <b>222</b> formed on a distal end thereof. The bore <b>221</b> terminates at the closed end flange <b>222</b>. The closed end flange <b>222</b> is secured to the opposing end <b>216</b> of the uniform shear valve <b>200</b> with suitable fasteners <b>223</b>. The plug <b>220</b> also defines a body portion <b>224</b> that extends partially into an interior area <b>200</b>A defined by the uniform shear valve <b>200</b>. The body portion <b>224</b> defines a radially inward tapered surface <b>226</b> that extends from one end <b>224</b>A of the body portion <b>224</b> towards the flange <b>220</b> and terminates therebetween by transitioning into a constant diameter D defined by the bore <b>221</b>. A screen pack <b>233</b> is positioned in the interior area <b>200</b>A between the inlet <b>212</b> and the end <b>224</b>A of the plug <b>220</b>. While the body <b>210</b> is described as having the opening <b>218</b> with the plug positioned therein, the present invention is not limited in this regard as the body <b>210</b> may be formed with the second end <b>218</b> closed and the plug <b>220</b> formed integrally with the body.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a flow control member <b>230</b> extends traversely into the bore <b>121</b> through a side bore <b>266</b> along an axis P that is substantially perpendicular to the longitudinal axis L. The flow control member <b>230</b> and the side bore <b>266</b> are aligned coaxially with the outlet <b>214</b>. The flow control member <b>230</b> defines a tapered end <b>232</b>, for example a seat that traverses across the bore <b>221</b> and into an opening <b>251</b> defined by the body portion <b>224</b> of the plug <b>220</b>. The flow control member <b>230</b> translates along the longitudinal axis P in the side bore <b>266</b> and a through packing gland <b>240</b>. The flow control member <b>230</b> controls the flow of high pressure polymer material discharged from the extrusion machine <b>210</b>, as described below. The flow control member <b>230</b> is selectively positionable, for example, is moved by a suitable operator, such as a hand-wheel or motor operated actuator. The packing gland <b>240</b> includes packing <b>242</b> which is compressed between walls of the side bore <b>266</b> and an exterior surface <b>230</b>E of the of the flow control member <b>230</b>. The packing <b>242</b> is compressed by a packing follower <b>244</b> that is moveably secured to a portion of the body <b>210</b> of the uniform shear valve <b>200</b> proximate the side bore <b>266</b>, by suitable fasteners <b>245</b>, for example packing gland bolts.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, the outlet <b>214</b> defines the first opening <b>251</b> and a radially inward and axially outward tapered surface <b>252</b>, for example a seat. The tapered surface <b>252</b> extends between the first opening <b>251</b> and a transition point <b>253</b> of constant diameter of an outlet port <b>254</b>. There is a uniform flow area <b>260</b>A defined between the exterior surface <b>230</b>E of the flow control member <b>230</b> and the first opening <b>251</b>. The uniform flow area <b>260</b>A defines annular gap between the exterior surface <b>230</b>E of the flow control member <b>230</b> and the first opening <b>251</b> having a radially measured width of U1. The uniform flow area <b>160</b> is decreased in magnitude, but maintains its uniformity, as the flow control member <b>230</b> is inserted further towards the outlet port <b>254</b>, thereby establishing other uniform flow areas. For example, a uniform flow area <b>260</b>B is defined between the outer surface <b>230</b>E of the flow control member <b>230</b> and the transition point <b>253</b> of constant diameter of an outlet port <b>254</b>. The uniform flow area <b>260</b>B defines annular gap between the outer surface <b>230</b>E of the flow control member <b>230</b> and the transition point <b>253</b> of constant diameter of an outlet port <b>254</b> having a radially measured width of U2. In addition, a uniform flow area and annular gap of constant a radially measured width are defined between: 1) a circumferential section of the tapered end <b>232</b> and the tapered surface <b>252</b>; 2) a circumferential section of the tapered end <b>232</b> and the opening <b>251</b>; and 3) a circumferential section of the tapered end <b>232</b> and the transition point <b>253</b> of constant diameter of an outlet port <b>254</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">During operation of the extrusion machine <b>210</b> and uniform shear valve <b>200</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4-6</figref>, high pressure extruded polymer is discharged into the inlet <b>212</b> at a high pressure (e.g., 2200 psi). The flow control member <b>230</b> is selectively positioned along the axis P and the flow control member <b>230</b> and the tapered end <b>232</b> are caused to traverse the bore <b>221</b> and move towards or away from the outlet <b>214</b>. Thus the flow control member <b>230</b> and the tapered end <b>232</b> control the flow of the polymer into the outlet <b>214</b> thereby reducing the pressure of the polymer to about 250 psi. As the polymer flows through the -uniform flow areas <b>260</b>A, <b>260</b>B uniform shear of the polymer is created. The uniform shear eliminates any melt fracture and melt memory effects which typically cause profile disturbances in the polymer. In addition, movement of the control member <b>230</b> is requires less force to operate compared to the prior art valve <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> because of the pressure acting on the flow control member <b>230</b> is the downstream reduced pressure (e.g., 250 psi) rather than the high pressure (e.g., 2200 psi) from the extrusion device <b>210</b> discharge. Thus the position of the flow control member <b>230</b> is controllable via an automated controller and actuator such as a computer processor that controls a motor operator which is in communication with and controls the position of the flow control member <b>230</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> the uniform shear valve <b>200</b> is shown with the plug <b>220</b> removed. During maintenance, the plug <b>220</b> can be removed more easily than the plug <b>120</b> of the prior art valve <b>100</b>, because there is no flow control member <b>230</b> positioned in the plug <b>220</b>. In addition, the screen pack <b>233</b> and the extruder screw <b>288</b> can also be easily removed and/or replaced for maintenance, through the opening <b>218</b> in the direction shown by the arrow X.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Although the present invention has been disclosed and described with reference to certain embodiments thereof, it should be noted that other variations and modifications may be made, and it is intended that the following claims cover the variations and modifications within the true scope of the invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A uniform shear valve for an extruder machine comprising:
<claim-text>a body having a generally annular wall that defines an interior area extending along a longitudinal axis thereof, between an inlet proximate a first end of the body and a second end of the body, the second end being opposite the first end, the body having a first bore extending through the wall along a traverse axis substantially perpendicular to the longitudinal axis at a first position and second position,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a flow control member sealingly and slidingly positioned partially in the first bore at the first position and extending out of the body, the flow control member defining a first seat on an end thereof;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an outlet located in the first bore at the second position;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second seat positioned proximate the outlet and being concentric with the first seat along the traverse axis; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a uniform flow area defined by a gap between the first seat and the second seat.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The uniform shear valve of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising an opening in the body at the second end and a plug positioned in and sealing the opening, the plug defining a second bore therethrough that is concentric with the traverse axis, the seat being formed in the second bore.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The uniform shear valve of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the plug defines a third bore aligned with a longitudinal axis of the body, the third bore comprising a tapered surface extending from an inlet of the third bore.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The uniform shear valve of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the flow control member is selectively positionable to vary a magnitude of the uniform flow area.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The uniform shear valve of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the uniform flow area is configured to eliminate melt fracture and melt memory effects in a fluid flowing therethough.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
