<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622571-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622571</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13051411</doc-number>
<date>20110318</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>FI</country>
<doc-number>20105279</doc-number>
<date>20100319</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>235</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>21</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>25</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362221</main-classification>
<further-classification>36224903</further-classification>
<further-classification>362555</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">LED tube and a lighting fixture arrangement having a safety unit</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7611260</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Lin et al.</name>
<date>20091100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8147091</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Hsia et al.</name>
<date>20120400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362221</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0133202</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Huang et al.</name>
<date>20070600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0183156</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Shan</name>
<date>20070800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0223225</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Eiich et al.</name>
<date>20070900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362260</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0290334</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ivey et al.</name>
<date>20091100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0002439</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lin et al.</name>
<date>20100100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0260614</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hartikka et al.</name>
<date>20111000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>315 51</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0260622</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hartikka et al.</name>
<date>20111000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>315113</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2012/0299494</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hartikka</name>
<date>20121100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>315201</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>AU</country>
<doc-number>101044</doc-number>
<kind>A4</kind>
<date>20091100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1 852 648</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20071100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>GB</country>
<doc-number>2465966</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20100600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO 2009067074</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20090500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00015">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO 2009/131340</doc-number>
<kind>A2</kind>
<date>20091000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00016">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO 2010/069983</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20100600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>14</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362221</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362294</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362551</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36224903</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362555</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>11</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110228526</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110922</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hartikka</last-name>
<first-name>Yrj&#xf6;</first-name>
<address>
<city>Pennala</city>
<country>FI</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>FI</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kuisma</last-name>
<first-name>Jouko</first-name>
<address>
<city>Lahti</city>
<country>FI</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>FI</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hartikka</last-name>
<first-name>Yrj&#xf6;</first-name>
<address>
<city>Pennala</city>
<country>FI</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kuisma</last-name>
<first-name>Jouko</first-name>
<address>
<city>Lahti</city>
<country>FI</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Leydig, Voit &#x26; Mayer, Ltd.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Teknoware Oy</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Lahti</city>
<country>FI</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Green</last-name>
<first-name>Tracie Y</first-name>
<department>2879</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A LED tube (<b>41</b>) comprises one or more LED components (<b>34</b>) and a current control unit (<b>33</b>) installed therein. Both ends of the LED tube (<b>41</b>) are provided with a contact pin pair (<b>37, 38, 39, 40</b>) for connecting the LED tube mechanically and electrically to tube holders of a fluorescent tube lighting fixture. The LED tube includes a safety unit (<b>42, 43</b>, S<b>1</b>) arranged to prevent a voltage from passing through the LED tube (<b>41</b>) from its one end to the other end thereof until at both ends of the LED tube, a voltage (U<b>1</b>, U<b>2</b>) fed from the corresponding tube holder of the lighting fixture to the contact pin pair (<b>37, 38, 39, 40</b>) has been detected separately.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="91.86mm" wi="167.13mm" file="US08622571-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="253.32mm" wi="179.83mm" file="US08622571-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="249.26mm" wi="182.54mm" file="US08622571-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="250.61mm" wi="175.01mm" file="US08622571-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="193.04mm" wi="166.96mm" file="US08622571-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The invention relates to lamps, and particularly to LED tubes having one or more LEDs as a light source and enabling a fluorescence tube to be replaced.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Fluorescent lamps are widely used in various environments, such as homes, offices, industry. Fluorescent lamps have longer life, they are more economic and more efficient than incandescent lamps wherein most of the electric power generates heat rather than light. In a conventional fluorescent lamp, the body consists of a straight tube whose length is 15 to 60 times that of the diameter of the tube. The tube may also be bent, in which case the tube may have almost any shape. Fluorescent tubes are low-pressure mercury discharge lamps wherein the inner surface of the tube is coated with a fluorescent material. The structure of a fluorescent tube is very simple; this is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>. The lamp consists of an airtight glass tube <b>4</b> containing a small amount of mercury, an inert gas, a fluorescent coating (luminophore), such as phosphorus, as well as electrodes <b>2</b> and <b>3</b> (filaments). Both ends of the fluorescent tube are provided with a cap <b>5</b> or <b>6</b> having two symmetrically placed contact pins <b>7</b> and <b>8</b> or <b>9</b> and <b>10</b> to which the electrode <b>2</b> or <b>3</b> is connected. The current supply to the fluorescent tube is provided via these contact pins <b>7</b> and <b>8</b>, <b>9</b> and <b>10</b>. When the lamp is in operation, the temperature of the electrodes <b>2</b> and <b>3</b> has to be sufficiently high in order to enable electrons to be released therefrom. At a normal operating voltage, the fluorescent lamp does not ignite without preheating. It is typical of fluorescent tubes (EN 60081) that their cathodes are heated by separate preheat circuits or arrangements. On the other hand, after ignition, a discharging current passing through the tube has to be limited in order for the tube not to become destroyed. Therefore, all fluorescent tubes need a ballast. Conventionally, the ballast has been a ballast-starter combination, which is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref>. When a mains voltage (e.g. 230 VAC) is connected to the lamp, the resistance through the tube is very high, and electric current passes via a ballast L, the electrode <b>3</b>, a closed starter <b>11</b>, and the electrode <b>2</b>. When the electric current passes through the electrodes <b>2</b> and <b>3</b>, it heats the electrodes, causing them to emit electrons which ionize the gas inside the tube. The ionized gas forms a current path through the tube. The current passing through the ballast L generates a magnetic field therein. When, after a while, the starter <b>11</b> opens, the magnetic field of the ballast L generates a high voltage between the electrodes <b>2</b> and <b>3</b>, which ignites the lamp.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Today, also electronic ballasts are used. An electronic ballast is also responsible for igniting the lamp, so no separate starter is necessary. The preheating arrangement is implemented either by separate preheating windings or a starter capacitor. This is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</figref>. An electronic ballast <b>12</b> connected to the mains voltage (e.g. 230 VAC) provides a continuous electric current through each electrode <b>2</b> and <b>3</b>. These electric currents are configured so that a voltage difference is formed between the electrodes <b>2</b> and <b>3</b>. When the mains voltage is connected to the ballast <b>12</b>, the electric current passing through the electrodes heats them quickly, and the emitted electrons ionize the gas contained in the tube. After the gas has become ionized, the voltage difference between the electrodes starts a gas discharge.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A common aim is to replace fluorescent tubes by LED tubes having the same length and values. Their physical dimensions are the same as those of straight fluorescent tubes (e.g. T8 having a 26 mm diameter and being e.g. 60 or 120 cm in length), enabling a LED tube to directly replace a fluorescent tube in an existing fluorescent lamp. Examples of such LED tube lamps are set forth in EP1852648, US2007/0183156, US2010/0002439, and WO2009/131340. The goal is to achieve a long life for the light source and a better luminous efficiency (quantity of light/electric power). In practice, the aim is only to replace a fluorescent tube by a LED tube without changing the structures of the lamp. Some LED tubes work directly with a fluorescent tube ballast, in which case only the starter is to be removed from use. In such a case, the LED tube replacement may take place easily and without any professional assistance.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">This causes some problems, the most important one being the danger of an electric shock while installing the LED tube. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates in a simplified manner a fluorescent tube lighting fixture <b>20</b> comprising a body <b>24</b> containing the necessary electronic structures, such as a ballast <b>12</b> and a starter <b>11</b>, which is usually necessary only in connection with a ballast. The ends of the lighting fixture are provided with tube holders <b>21</b> and <b>22</b> provided with contact sockets <b>23</b> into which contact pins of the ends <b>26</b> and <b>27</b> of the tube <b>25</b> are inserted in order to achieve a mechanical and electrical connection. According to safety regulations in the field, lighting fixtures are to be built such that it is impossible for a user to come into contact with any parts at the mains voltage while replacing a fluorescent tube even if the lamp were connected to the mains voltage. This requirement is met even if the fluorescent tube were replaced such that only one end <b>27</b> of the tube <b>25</b> is in contact with the contacts <b>23</b> of the tube holder <b>22</b> while the other end <b>26</b> of the tube may freely come into contact with a person carrying out the replacement. This requirement is met since no current flows through the gas-filled fluorescent tube until the gas in the tube is ionized by a starting pulse. Thus, the gas per se in the fluorescent tube serves as an insulating material. The electrical structure of the lighting fixture, again, is such that the generation of a starting pulse requires that both ends of the tube be connected to the contacts of the tube holder. This enables the risk of an electric shock in connection with a fluorescent tube to be prevented while replacing the tube.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In connection with LED tubes, this electrical safety condition is not met. Inside the LED tubes there is provided a printed circuit board or a corresponding structure where the LEDs and their necessary electronic current supply components are installed. The purpose of these components is to convert the supply network alternating voltage into direct voltage and regulate the direct current required by the LEDs. In practice, current flows through these components as soon as voltage is applied thereto, in other words the LED tube is in a conductive state without any separate starting pulse. Therefore, in a use situation, when the LED tube <b>25</b> is being installed in the fluorescent tube lighting fixture <b>20</b>, the contact pins <b>27</b> of one end of the LED tube <b>25</b> may come into contact with the contacts <b>23</b> of the tube holder <b>22</b> and the other end <b>26</b> of the tube be left outside the lighting fixture such that the person installing or replacing the tube may come into contact therewith, putting him or her at the risk of an electric shock.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">An object of the invention is thus to provide a LED tube and a lighting fixture arrangement so as to enable the aforementioned electrical safety problem to be solved. The object of the invention is achieved by a LED tube and an arrangement which are characterized by what is stated in the independent claims. Preferred embodiments of the invention are disclosed in the dependent claims.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">An aspect of the invention is a LED tube comprising a substantially fluorescent-tube-shaped and fluorescent-tube-sized translucent or fluorescent tube having one or more LED components and a current control unit installed therein, both ends of the LED tube being provided with at least one contact pin for connecting the LED tube mechanically and electrically to tube holders of a fluorescent tube lighting fixture. The LED tube includes a safety unit arranged to prevent a voltage from passing through the LED tube from its one end to the other end thereof until at both ends of the LED tube, a voltage fed from the corresponding tube holder of the lighting fixture to said at least one contact pin is detected separately.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to an embodiment, the safety unit comprises switching means on a current path between the contact pins provided at different ends of the LED tube, the switching means being arranged to be open and break the current path when no voltage has been detected from said at least one contact pin of one or either of the ends of the LED tube, and arranged to be closed and connect the current path only when a voltage has been detected from said at least one contact pin of both ends of the LED tube.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to an embodiment, the safety unit comprises switching means in series on a current path at least between said at least one contact pin of one end of the LED tube and the current control unit, the switching means being arranged to be open and break the current path when no voltage has been detected from said at least one contact pin of one or either of the ends of the LED tube, and arranged to be closed and connect the current path only when a voltage has been detected from said at least one contact pin of both ends of the LED tube.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to an embodiment, the LED tube comprises two contact pins at both ends of the LED tube, the safety unit being arranged to detect a voltage between these two contact pins at both ends of the LED tube.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to an embodiment, the safety unit is arranged to detect a preheating voltage received from a socket of a fluorescent tube lighting fixture at the contact pins at both ends of the LED tube.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to an embodiment, the LED tube comprises, at both ends of the LED tube, two contact pins between which a resistive, inductive and/or capacitive measuring component is connected to form a current path between the contact pins. The safety unit is arranged to detect a low voltage across the measuring component at both ends of the LED tube, the low voltage resulting from a current passing through the measuring component and being generated in the ballast-starter type fluorescent tube lighting fixture by a high-resistance component connected in place of or in parallel with a starter.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">According to some embodiments, the high-resistance component is a resistor, a capacitor, an inductance or a combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">According to an embodiment, the measuring components and the high-resistance component of the LED tube are dimensioned such that the current flowing therein is very substantially lower than a heating current of a fluorescent tube would be.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">According to an embodiment, the LED tube comprises user-operable means for connecting or disconnecting the measuring components between the contact pins, according to the lighting fixture.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">According to an embodiment, the switching means are arranged to break the current path bipolarly.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">According to an embodiment, the detected voltages, heating voltages or low voltages are connected directly to be control voltages of the switching means, e.g. control voltages of a relay or relays.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">According to an embodiment, the LED tube comprises means for keeping the switching means closed after the LED tube has ignited even if one or more of the detected voltages becomes lower or non-existent but the main voltage remains.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In an embodiment, a cold cathode type fluorescent tube whose both ends are provided with only one contact pin is replaced, in which case the safety unit is arranged to detect the voltage of the ends of the LED tube.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Another aspect of the invention is a lighting fixture arrangement, comprising a lighting fixture which is meant for a fluorescent tube and in which a LED tube according to an embodiment of the invention is installed.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">According to an embodiment, the lighting fixture arrangement includes a ballast-starter type device wherein in place of or in parallel with the starter, a high-resistance component is connected in order to generate a low current for the measuring components of the LED tube.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In a lighting fixture arrangement according to an embodiment, the high-resistance component is a resistor, a capacitor, an inductance or a combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">By means of the embodiments of the invention, a situation is shown wherein only one end of the LED tube is connected to an energized lighting fixture and a person installing the LED tube is at the risk of receiving an electrical shock through the LED tube from an uninstalled end thereof.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE FIGURES</heading>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The invention is now described in closer detail in connection with exemplary embodiments and with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> shows a simplified example of a mechanical structure of a fluorescent tube;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> shows an example of an electrical circuitry of a fluorescent tube when a ballast is implemented by a ballast-starter combination;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</figref> shows an example of an electrical circuitry of a fluorescent tube when an electronic ballast is used;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a simplified example of a structure of a fluorescent tube lighting fixture;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> shows a simplified example of a mechanical structure of a LED tube;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref> is a simplified circuit diagram showing an example of a LED circuit of the LED tube of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> and current supply thereof;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> schematically shows a LED tube according to an exemplary embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> schematically shows a LED tube and circuit arrangement according to another exemplary embodiment of the invention when installed in a fluorescent tube lighting fixture provided with a ballast-starter combination;</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref> shows an example of dimensioning of resistors R<b>1</b>, R<b>2</b>, and R<b>3</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> schematically shows a LED tube according to another exemplary embodiment of the invention, wherein a circuit-breaking switch is implemented by two relays that are directly controlled by heating voltages; and</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> schematically shows a LED illuminating tube according to yet another exemplary embodiment of the invention, wherein a circuit-breaking switch is kept closed after ignition of the LED tube even if heating voltages become lower or non-existent.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF EXEMPLARY EMBODIMENTS OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The field of application of the invention comprises all lamps, particularly tube lamps, having one or more LEDs as a light source and enabling a fluorescent tube lighting fixture or the like to be replaced.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> illustrates a simplified example of a possible structure of a LED tube. The lamp <b>31</b> consists of a straight (or bent) tube <b>30</b> made from a suitable translucent material, such as glass or plastic, or possibly a fluorescent material. The tube <b>30</b> does not have to be airtight. On the contrary, it may be provided with openings, holes and/or gaps for providing air circulation and cooling.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Inside the tube <b>30</b> there is provided a printed circuit board <b>32</b> or a corresponding structure wherein LED (Light Emitting Diode) components <b>34</b> and electronic current supply components <b>33</b> necessitated thereby are installed. The purpose of these components <b>33</b> is to convert the alternating voltage (e.g. 230 VAC) of the mains supply network into direct voltage (dc) and regulate the dc current required by the LEDs <b>34</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref> shows an example of a possible LED circuit of the LED tube of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> and the current supply thereof. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, the alternating voltage (L) of the supply network and neutral (N) are connected to a rectifier circuit <b>33</b>&#x2032;, which generates a dc voltage. To the dc voltage, a LED chain having N LEDs in series, where N=1, 2 . . . , is connected via a series resistor R limiting the current. The series resistor R shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref> may be replaced e.g. by an electronic (preferably low-loss) switched mode solution.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Both ends of the tube <b>30</b> are closed with a cap <b>35</b> or <b>36</b> provided with two symmetrically placed contact pins <b>37</b> and <b>38</b> or <b>39</b> and <b>40</b>. Current supply to the current supply components <b>33</b> on the circuit board <b>32</b> is carried out via these contact pins <b>37</b> and <b>38</b>, <b>39</b> and <b>40</b>. It is to be noted that the internal structure and electrical implementation of the LED tube are irrelevant to the invention but the safety solution according to embodiments of the invention may be applied in connection with implementations of various types. The mechanical dimensions, at least the length, and the number, location and dimensions of contact pins are preferably the same as those of a fluorescent tube to be replaced, so that it is possible to directly replace the fluorescent tube by a LED tube in an existing fluorescent tube lighting fixture. The dimensions of the LED tube <b>31</b> may be compatible e.g. with a T8 tube lamp, whose diameter is about 26 mm and length e.g. 60 or 120 cm. According to an embodiment of the invention, the LED tube is meant to replace a fluorescent tube whose both ends are provided with only one contact pin (single pin tube). Such a tube may be e.g. a cold cathode fluorescent tube having no electrode preheating.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">As explained above, if e.g. the LED tube <b>31</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> is installed e.g. in the lighting fixture <b>20</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the contact pins <b>39</b> and <b>40</b> of the LED tube <b>31</b> may be inserted into the contact socket <b>23</b> of the tube holder <b>22</b>, which carries a mains voltage. On the other hand, the contact pins <b>37</b> and <b>38</b> of an opposite end of the LED tube <b>31</b> may still be outside the lighting fixture <b>20</b> and able to become into contact with an installer. A dangerous voltage may pass from the contact pins <b>39</b> and <b>40</b> via the structures inside the tube <b>35</b>, such as the circuit board <b>32</b>, the LEDs <b>34</b> and/or the current supply components <b>33</b>, to the contact pins <b>37</b> and <b>38</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> schematically shows a LED tube <b>41</b> according to an exemplary embodiment of the invention. The mechanical and electrical structures of the LED tube <b>41</b> may be similar to those of the LED tube <b>31</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, for instance, except that the LED tube <b>41</b> is further provided with a safety circuit according to an embodiment of the invention in order to remove the risk of an electric shock posed to the installer. Preferably, the components of the safety circuit may be placed on the same printed circuit board <b>32</b> or a corresponding structure as where the LEDs <b>34</b> and other current supply components <b>33</b> are placed.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">As explained above in connection with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</figref>, the electronic ballast <b>12</b> feeds the heating voltage of the electrodes by two conductors directly to both ends of the fluorescent tube <b>1</b>, more precisely to the contact pins <b>7</b>, <b>8</b>, <b>9</b>, and <b>10</b> therein. The operating voltage of the fluorescent tube <b>1</b> is generated between these heating voltages, in which case the heating voltages are in a different potential. If the lighting fixture <b>20</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> contains such an electronic ballast (in which case it contains no starter <b>11</b>), these heating voltages are also available at the contact sockets <b>23</b> of the tube holders <b>21</b> and <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In some embodiments of the invention, these directly fed, low heating voltages are utilized as detection voltages of a safety circuit. In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, voltage detectors (DET<b>1</b>) <b>42</b> and (DET<b>2</b>) <b>43</b> are arranged inside the LED tube <b>41</b>. The voltage detector <b>42</b> is connected to detect (measure) a heating voltage U<b>1</b> between the contact pins <b>37</b> and <b>38</b> provided at a first end of the LED tube <b>41</b>. The voltage detector <b>42</b> activates a control signal CTL<b>1</b> when the heating voltage U<b>1</b> is being detected. Similarly, the voltage detector <b>43</b> is connected to measure a heating voltage U<b>2</b> between the contact pins <b>39</b> and <b>40</b> provided at a second end of the LED tube <b>41</b>. The voltage detector <b>43</b> activates a control signal CTL<b>2</b> when the heating voltage U<b>2</b> is being detected. Furthermore, at least one circuit-breaking switch S<b>1</b> is further provided in connection with the current supply circuit of the LED tube <b>41</b> such that the circuit-breaking switch S<b>1</b>, controlled by the control signals CTL<b>1</b> and CTL<b>2</b>, opens (breaks) or closes (connects) the current circuit of the LED tube and thereby prevents a dangerous voltage from passing through the LED tube from its one end to the other end thereof, or allows this. The circuit-breaking switch S<b>1</b> is open when the LED tube <b>41</b> has not been installed in the lighting fixture, in other words when neither of the voltage detectors <b>42</b> and <b>43</b> detects a heating voltage U<b>1</b> and U<b>2</b>, respectively. The circuit-breaking switch S<b>1</b> is also open when only one end of the LED tube <b>41</b> is installed in the contact socket of the lighting fixture, in other words when only one of the voltage detectors <b>42</b> and <b>43</b> detects the heating voltage U<b>1</b> or U<b>2</b>, respectively. The circuit-breaking switch S<b>1</b> closes only if both ends of the LED tube <b>41</b> are installed correctly in the tube holders of the lighting fixture and both voltage detectors <b>42</b> and <b>43</b> detect the heating voltage U<b>1</b> or U<b>2</b>, respectively, coming from the lighting fixture. This enables a situation to be prevented wherein only one end of the LED tube <b>41</b> is connected to the energized parts of the lighting fixture and a person installing the LED tube may receive an electric shock through the LED tube.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Conventional ballast-starter circuits contain no separate heating voltages but the preheating of a fluorescent tube is carried out by a temporary current pulse from a ballast-starter circuit, as was explained in connection with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref>. In a fluorescent tube lighting fixture provided with such a ballast-starter circuit, no separate heating voltages are thus available for the contact pins <b>37</b>, <b>38</b>, <b>39</b>, and <b>40</b> of both ends of the LED tube <b>41</b>, but to the contact pins <b>37</b>, <b>38</b>, <b>39</b>, and <b>40</b> of both ends, the supply voltage of the lighting fixture comes through the ballast <b>12</b>. In such a lighting fixture, the detection circuits <b>42</b> and <b>43</b> of the LED tube <b>41</b> of the type shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> should detect (measure) high-ohmically the mains voltage or another supply voltage at the contact pins of different ends of the LED tube. This, again, results in a possible risk of an electric shock via the detection circuit when one end of the LED tube <b>41</b> is connected to the contact socket <b>23</b> of the lighting fixture but the other end is uninstalled. This is the case irrespective of the fact that in the LED tube according to the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the circuit-breaking switch S<b>1</b> of the safety circuit is opened and no supply voltage is fed to the circuit board <b>32</b> therethrough.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> schematically shows a LED tube <b>51</b> and circuit arrangement according to another exemplary embodiment of the invention when installed in a fluorescent tube lighting fixture provided with a ballast-starter combination, e.g. in the lighting fixture <b>20</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The mechanical and electrical structures of the LED tube <b>51</b> may be similar to those of e.g. the LED tube <b>31</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, except that the LED tube <b>51</b> is further provided with a safety circuit according to an embodiment of the invention in order to remove the risk of an electric shock posed to the installer. Preferably, the components of the safety circuit may be placed on the same printed circuit board <b>32</b> or a corresponding structure as where the LEDs <b>34</b> and other current supply components <b>33</b> are placed. It is to be noted that <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> shows the contact pins (<b>37</b>, <b>38</b>, <b>39</b>, and <b>40</b>) and the related conductors of the lighting fixture schematically. In practice, the conductors are connected to the contact pins of the LED tube via the contacts <b>23</b> according to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> that are provided in the tube holders <b>21</b> and <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The LED tube <b>51</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> may be substantially similar to the LED tube <b>41</b> of another exemplary embodiment, except that in the LED tube <b>51</b>, a component R<b>1</b> which replaces a heating filament of an electrode of a fluorescent tube and through which current I is allowed to pass is connected between the contact pins <b>37</b> and <b>38</b>. Similarly, at the other end of the LED tube <b>51</b>, a component R<b>2</b> which replaces a heating filament of an electrode of a fluorescent tube and through which current I is allowed to pass is connected between the contact pins <b>39</b> and <b>40</b>. The components R<b>1</b> and R are e.g. resistors, capacitors, inductances or other corresponding components or combinations thereof. In the circuit arrangement, the starter of the lighting fixture <b>20</b> has been removed and replaced by a component R<b>3</b> having a high resistance, in which case a low current I caused by the network voltage passes therethrough. Alternatively, the component R<b>3</b> may be placed in parallel with the starter, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>. The component R<b>3</b> may be e.g. a resistor, a capacitor, an inductance or another corresponding component or a combination thereof. The component R<b>3</b> may be implemented by means of a housing and connectors whose physical dimensions correspond with those of the starter <b>11</b> in order to enable the component R<b>3</b> to be inserted into the socket of the starter <b>11</b> in the lighting fixture <b>20</b>. Preferably, the values of these components R<b>1</b>, R<b>2</b>, and R<b>3</b> are dimensioned to be high-ohmic such that the current I passing therein is very substantially lower than a heating current of a fluorescent tube would be. By means of an example, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref> illustrates the dimensioning of the components R<b>1</b>, R<b>2</b>, and R<b>3</b> when they are resistors. The resistors R<b>1</b>, R<b>2</b>, and R<b>3</b> are connected in series between a supply voltage Uin (as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> between the phase voltage L<b>1</b> and neutral N). A voltage U<b>1</b> (also measured in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>) is generated across the resistor R<b>1</b> and a voltage U<b>2</b> (also measured in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>) is generated across the resistor R<b>2</b>. A voltage U<b>3</b> is generated across the resistor R<b>3</b>. The values of the voltages U<b>1</b> and U<b>2</b> may be determined by means of equations of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>. The resistances of the resistors R<b>1</b>, R<b>2</b>, and R<b>3</b> may be selected so that the desired voltages U<b>1</b> and U<b>2</b> are obtained at a certain supply voltage Uin. As is obvious to one skilled in the art, the R<b>1</b>, R<b>2</b>, and R<b>3</b> shown in the equations may be replaced by symbols Z<b>1</b>, Z<b>2</b>, and Z<b>3</b> when in place of or in addition to resistance, the components include inductance and/or capacitance.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">This arrangement enables a situation to be provided wherein between the contacts <b>37</b> and <b>38</b> as well as <b>39</b> and <b>40</b>, respectively, (across the components R<b>1</b> and R<b>2</b>, respectively) of both ends of the LED tube <b>51</b>, a low voltage U<b>1</b> and U<b>2</b>, respectively, is generated that may be used as a detection voltage. The voltage detectors <b>42</b> and <b>43</b> detect the voltages U<b>1</b> and U<b>2</b> in a manner similar to that used in detecting the heating voltages, and by the control signals CTL<b>1</b> and CTL<b>2</b> control the circuit-breaking switch S<b>1</b> e.g. in a manner similar to that shown in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. This enables the LED tube <b>41</b> to be kept completely open (non-conductive) until the voltage detectors <b>42</b> and <b>43</b> have verified from the voltages U<b>1</b> and U<b>2</b> that the tube <b>41</b> has been installed reliably in its tube holders <b>21</b> and <b>22</b> in the lighting fixture <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The LED tube <b>51</b>, which includes the components R<b>1</b> and R<b>2</b>, is suitable for use also in connection with an electronic ballast, which generates directly the heating voltages. The high-resistance component R<b>1</b> or R<b>2</b> causes no significant waste current from the low heating voltage. In some embodiments of the invention, the components R<b>1</b> and R<b>2</b> are both in series with at least one switch enabling the components R<b>1</b> and R<b>2</b> to be connected and disconnected between the contact pins, in which case the LED tube, according to the installation, may be placed to conform with the tube <b>51</b> or the tube <b>41</b>. The user may choose the positions of the switches by actuators provided in the caps <b>35</b> and <b>36</b>, for instance.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In yet another embodiments of the invention, the LED tube is meant to replace a fluorescent tube whose both ends are provided with only one contact pin (single pin tube). This may be e.g. a cold cathode fluorescent tube having no electrode preheating. For example, a single pin version of the LED tube of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> could only be provided with contact pins <b>37</b> and <b>38</b>. The safety unit according to the invention may also be applied to such a single pin LED tube. In such a case, the contact pins <b>38</b> and <b>40</b> and the corresponding connections may be omitted from the LED tube of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, for instance. The voltage detectors <b>42</b> and <b>43</b> may monitor the voltages of the contact pins <b>37</b> and <b>39</b> and close the circuit-breaking switch S<b>1</b> only if both of them detect a voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The at least one circuit-breaking switch S<b>1</b> mentioned in all embodiments of the invention may be implemented by any switch structure or switch component capable of breaking (disconnecting) a supply-voltage circuit. Preferably, the circuit-breaking takes place bipolarly, as illustrated in the examples of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>. Examples of suitable circuit-breaking switches include electromechanical switches, such as relays, and semiconductor switches, such as transistors. In the examples of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, the circuit-breaking switch S<b>1</b> is connected between the contact pins <b>37</b>, <b>38</b> and the rest of the LED circuitry <b>32</b> provided on the circuit board <b>32</b>, in which case it naturally efficiently prevents a dangerous voltage from passing from one end of the LED tube <b>41</b> or <b>51</b> to the other end thereof. However, alternatively the circuit-breaking switch S<b>1</b> may be located at any point of the LED circuitry, as long as it breaks the current path in a way which prevents a dangerous voltage from passing from one end of the LED tube <b>41</b> or <b>51</b> to the other end thereof. In an embodiment of the invention, both ends of the LED tube <b>41</b> or <b>51</b> are provided with a circuit-breaking switch S<b>1</b> of their own, which may be controlled by both voltage detectors <b>42</b> and <b>43</b> or by a voltage detector detecting the heating voltage U<b>1</b> or U<b>2</b> of the end in question only. However, increasing the number of circuit-breaking switches increases costs, so it is advantageous to minimize the number of switches.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The voltage detector <b>42</b> or <b>43</b> may be implemented by any circuit solution which, when a sufficient heating voltage U<b>1</b> or U<b>2</b>, respectively, occurs, generates a control signal CTL<b>1</b> or CTL<b>2</b>, respectively, e.g. a control voltage. The voltage detector <b>42</b> or <b>43</b> may be e.g. a relay or a voltage comparator which derives also its operating voltage from the heating voltage U<b>1</b> or U<b>2</b>. It may thus also be a part of the switch S<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> schematically shows a LED tube <b>61</b> according to another exemplary embodiment of the invention, wherein the circuit-breaking switch S<b>1</b> according to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5A</figref> is formed by two successively connected relays S<b>1</b>A and S<b>1</b>B that derive their operating voltage from the heating circuits of different ends of the LED tube <b>61</b>. In other words, the heating voltage U<b>1</b> between the contact pins <b>37</b> and <b>38</b> is connected in parallel with a control coil M<b>1</b>A of the relay S<b>1</b>A and, correspondingly, the heating voltage U<b>2</b> between the contact pins <b>39</b> and <b>40</b> is connected in parallel with a control coil M<b>1</b>B of the relay S<b>1</b>B. In such a case, the control coils M<b>1</b>A and M<b>1</b>B of the relays directly form the voltage detectors <b>42</b> and <b>43</b> according to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5A</figref>. When there is a heating voltage U<b>1</b> between the contact pins <b>37</b> and <b>38</b>, the control coil M<b>1</b>A pulls the contacts of the relay S<b>1</b>A from an open position in to a closed position. Similarly, when there is a heating voltage U<b>2</b> between the contact pins <b>39</b> and <b>40</b>, the control coil M<b>1</b>B pulls the contacts of the relay S<b>1</b>B from the open position in to the closed position. Both relays S<b>1</b>A and S<b>1</b>B close (the current path is connected) only if both ends of the LED tube <b>61</b> have been installed correctly in the tube holders of the lamp and both control coils M<b>1</b>A and M<b>1</b>B receive the heating voltage U<b>1</b> and U<b>2</b>, respectively, from the lighting fixture. This enables a situation to be prevented wherein only one end of the LED tube <b>61</b> is connected to the energized parts of the lighting fixture and the person installing the LED tube may receive an electric shock through the LED tube. This embodiment is particularly suitable for electronic ballasts with separate heating voltage feeds. It is to be noted that instead of two relays S<b>1</b>A and S<b>1</b>B, also one relay having a compound coil for control may be used, in which case it takes both heating voltage feeds to close the relay. More generally, this embodiment may be applied by using, instead of a relay or relays, any circuit-breaking switch, e.g. a semiconductor relay, for which the detected voltages, heating voltages or low voltages are connected directly as control voltages. Direct connecting may also include the use of a driver circuit or circuits of a switch.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> schematically shows a LED tube <b>71</b> according to yet another exemplary embodiment of the invention, wherein the circuit-breaking switch S<b>1</b> according to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5A</figref> is a relay having a control coil M<b>1</b> and a control amplifier <b>72</b>. The voltage detectors <b>42</b> and <b>43</b> detect the voltages U<b>1</b> and U<b>2</b>, respectively, received at the contact pins <b>37</b>, <b>38</b>, <b>39</b>, and <b>40</b> and, by means of the amplifier <b>72</b>, control the control coil M<b>1</b> of the switch S<b>1</b>. When the pins of both ends of the tube <b>71</b> carry the heating voltages U<b>1</b> and U<b>2</b>, the voltage detectors generate control signals CTL<b>1</b> and CTL<b>2</b> to be fed as inputs to the amplifier <b>72</b>. Upon receiving both control signals CTL<b>1</b> and CTL<b>2</b>, the amplifier <b>72</b> generates at its control output a voltage or current, as a consequence of which the control coil M<b>1</b> pulls the contacts of the relay S<b>1</b> from the open position to the closed position, whereby the current path closes and the LED light unit is lit up. When the switch S<b>1</b> is closed, the amplifier <b>72</b> also receives an indication HOLD of the state of the switch S<b>1</b>, in the form of voltage (tube voltage, arc voltage) received at the different ends of the tube. If now the heating voltage U<b>1</b> or U<b>2</b> received at the contact pins <b>37</b>, <b>38</b>, <b>39</b>, and <b>40</b> becomes lower or non-existent, the amplifier <b>72</b> continues to keep the switch S<b>1</b> closed, if the hold control HOLD, such as tube voltage, is still supplied to the amplifier via the switch S<b>1</b>. If the tube voltage becomes non-existent at the contact pins <b>37</b> and <b>39</b>, e.g. upon detaching the tube <b>71</b> from the lighting fixture or when the lighting fixture is turned off, also the hold control HOLD disappears and the amplifier <b>72</b> controls the switch S<b>1</b> to open. In such a case, the state of the LED tube <b>71</b> returns to its original state. Reclosing the switch S<b>1</b> again requires heating voltages at both ends of the tube <b>71</b>. This exemplary embodiment is particularly suitable for electronic ballasts provided with an advanced heating circuit, such as preheating, and possibly lowering or disconnection of heating voltages after an ignition process. In this exemplary embodiment, it is ensured that even if the operation of the electronic ballast is such that the heating voltage is disconnected after the tube has ignited, however, the operation continues until the actual supply voltage is connected to the tube <b>71</b>. It is to be noted that the holding circuit or &#x201c;holding memory&#x201d; of the relay S<b>1</b> may also be implemented in a manner other than via the contacts of the relay S<b>1</b>. More generally this embodiment may be applied by using, instead of a relay, any circuit-breaking switch provided with a holding circuit or &#x201c;holding memory&#x201d; for keeping the circuit-breaking switch closed after the LED tube has lit up, even if one or more of the detected voltages U<b>1</b> and U<b>2</b> become lower or non-existent but the main voltage (e.g. mains voltage) of the LED tube remains.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">It is apparent to one skilled in the art that as technology advances, the basic idea of the invention may be implemented in many different ways. The invention and its embodiments are thus not restricted to the above-described examples but may vary within the scope of the claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A LED tube, comprising a substantially fluorescent-tube-shaped and fluorescent-tube-sized translucent or fluorescent tube having at least one LED component and a current control unit installed therein, both ends of the LED tube being provided with two contact pins for connecting the LED tube mechanically and electrically to tube holders of a fluorescent tube lighting fixture, at both ends of the LED tube, a resistive, inductive and/or capacitive measuring component is connected between these two contact pins to form a current path between the contact pins, wherein the LED tube includes a safety unit arranged to prevent a voltage from passing through the LED tube from its one end to the other end thereof until at both ends of the LED tube, a voltage fed from the corresponding tube holder of the lighting fixture to said two contact pins has been detected separately, the safety unit being arranged to detect a low voltage across the measuring component at both ends of the LED tube, the low voltage resulting from a current passing through the measuring component and being generated in the ballast-starter circuit in the fluorescent tube lighting fixture by a high-resistance component connected in place of or in parallel with a starter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The LED tube as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the safety unit comprises switching means on a current path between the contact pins provided at different ends of the LED tube, the switching means being arranged to be open and break the current path when no voltage has been detected from said two contact pins of at least one of the ends of the LED tube, and arranged to be closed and connect the current path only when a voltage has been detected from said two contact pins of both ends of the LED tube.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The LED tube as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the safety unit comprises switching means in series on a current path at least between said two contact pins of one end of the LED tube and the current control unit, the switching means being arranged to be open and break the current path when no voltage has been detected from said two contact pins of at least one of the ends of the LED tube, and arranged to be closed and connect the current path only when a voltage has been detected from said two contact pins of both ends of the LED tube.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The LED tube as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the safety unit is arranged to detect a voltage between the contact pins of the two contact pins at both ends of the LED tube.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The LED tube as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the safety unit is arranged to detect a heating voltage received from the tube holder of the fluorescent tube lighting fixture at the contact pins at both ends of the LED tube.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The LED tube as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the high-resistance component is a resistor, a capacitor, an inductance or a combination thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The LED tube as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the measuring components of the LED tube and the high-resistance component are dimensioned such that the current flowing therein is very substantially lower than a heating current of a fluorescent tube would be.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The LED tube as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the LED tube comprises user-operable means for selectively connecting the measuring components between the contact pins, according to the type of the lighting fixture.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The LED tube as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the switching means are arranged to break the current path bipolarly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The LED tube as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the detected voltages, heating voltages or low voltages are connected directly to be control voltages of the switching means.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The LED tube as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the LED tube comprises means for keeping the switching means closed after the LED tube has ignited even if at least one of the detected voltages become lower or non-existent but the main voltage remains.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. A lighting fixture arrangement, comprising a lamp which is de-signed for a fluorescent tube and in which a LED tube is installed, the LED tube comprising a substantially fluorescent-tube-shaped and fluorescent-tube-sized translucent or fluorescent tube having at least one LED component and a current control unit installed therein, both ends of the LED tube being provided with two contact pins for connecting the LED tube mechanically and electrically to tube holders of a fluorescent tube lighting fixture, at both ends of the LED tube, a resistive, inductive and/or capacitive measuring component is connected between these two contact pins to form a current path between the contact pins, wherein the LED tube includes a safety unit arranged to prevent a voltage from passing through the LED tube from its one end to the other end thereof until at both ends of the LED tube, a voltage fed from the corresponding tube holder of the lighting fixture to said two contact pins has been detected separately, the safety unit being arranged to detect a low voltage across the measuring component at both ends of the LED tube, the low voltage resulting from a current passing through the measuring component and being generated in the ballast-starter circuit in the fluorescent tube lighting fixture by a high-resistance component connected in place of or in parallel with a starter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The lighting fixture arrangement as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, comprising a ballast-starter assembly, wherein a high-resistance component is connected in place of or in parallel with a starter in order to generate a low current for measuring components of the LED tube.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The lighting fixture arrangement as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the high-resistance component is a resistor, a capacitor, an inductance or a combination thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
