<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624581-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624581</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13165864</doc-number>
<date>20110622</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2011 1 0134958</doc-number>
<date>20110524</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>435</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>19</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>324123R</main-classification>
<further-classification>324 731</further-classification>
<further-classification>710301</further-classification>
<further-classification>714805</further-classification>
<further-classification>365 63</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Input power measuring device</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6467053</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Connolly et al.</name>
<date>20021000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>714 39</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0256281</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Fahr et al.</name>
<date>20081000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>710305</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0231209</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ahmed et al.</name>
<date>20100900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>324239</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>3</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>32476201-7621</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>32475401-7543</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>32475501-7551</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>324 731</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>324123 R</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257 48</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438 14- 18</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>365 63</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>710301</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>714805</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120299582</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121129</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bai</last-name>
<first-name>Yun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yang</last-name>
<first-name>Fu-Sen</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tong</last-name>
<first-name>Song-Lin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bai</last-name>
<first-name>Yun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yang</last-name>
<first-name>Fu-Sen</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tong</last-name>
<first-name>Song-Lin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hong Fu Jin Precision Industry (ShenZhen) Co., Ltd</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Vazquez</last-name>
<first-name>Arleen M</first-name>
<department>2868</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Le</last-name>
<first-name>Son</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An input power measuring device includes a board with an edge connector, a first dual inline memory modules (DIMM) socket, a resistor, a differential amplifier circuit, a voltage dividing circuit, a display screen, and a controller. When the edge connector is inserted into a second DIMM socket of a motherboard and the motherboard is powered on, the resistor samples first current, and converts the first current into a first voltage. The differential amplifier circuit amplifiers the first current to a second current. The voltage dividing circuit divides the first voltage, and outputs a second voltage. The controller converts the second current into a third current, converts the second voltage into a third voltage, and calculates a power according to the third current and the third voltage.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="131.74mm" wi="337.31mm" file="US08624581-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="203.88mm" wi="155.19mm" file="US08624581-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="176.53mm" wi="180.34mm" file="US08624581-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="172.64mm" wi="174.75mm" file="US08624581-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to an input power measuring device.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">With the development of flash memories (e.g., NAND memories), some attempts have been made to use these flash memories as data storage devices. One form of the data storage devices using NAND flash memories is referred as solid state drives (SSDs). In order to ensure reliability of the SSDs, a measurement for the input power of the SSDs is required. However, it is difficult to measure the input power of an SSD inserted into a dual inline memory module (DIMM) socket in a motherboard. Therefore, there is room for improvement in the art.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Many aspects of the present embodiments can be better understood with reference to the following drawings. The components in the drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the present embodiments. Moreover, in the drawing, all the views are schematic, and like reference numerals designate corresponding parts throughout the several views.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view of an embodiment of an input power measuring device, the input power measuring device includes a measuring circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram of the measuring circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> connected between an alternating current power and a motherboard.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic view of the input power measuring device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> testing an input power of a solid state drive.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The disclosure, including the accompanying drawings in which like references indicate similar elements, is illustrated by way of example and not by way of limitation. It should be noted that references to &#x201c;an&#x201d; or &#x201c;one&#x201d; embodiment in this disclosure are not necessarily to the same embodiment, and such references mean at least one.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Referring to the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref>, an embodiment of an input power measuring device <b>100</b> is used to measure an input power of a solid state drive (SSD) <b>200</b>. The input power measuring device <b>100</b> includes a board <b>10</b>, a dual inline memory modules (DIMM) socket <b>20</b> mounted on a top side of the board <b>10</b>, and a measuring circuit <b>30</b> arranged on the board <b>10</b>. Two latching slots <b>14</b> are defined in two opposite ends of the board <b>10</b>. The latching slots <b>14</b> are used to engage with two latching blocks of a DIMM socket <b>320</b> mounted on a motherboard <b>300</b>, thereby fixing the input power measuring device <b>100</b> to the DIMM socket <b>320</b>. An edge connector <b>12</b> is formed on a bottom side of the board <b>10</b>, to be inserted into the DIMM socket <b>320</b> of the motherboard <b>300</b>. The DIMM socket <b>20</b> is used to engage with the SSD <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The measuring circuit <b>30</b> includes a resistor <b>31</b>, a differential amplifier circuit <b>32</b>, a voltage dividing circuit <b>33</b>, a controller <b>34</b>, and a display screen <b>35</b>. A first terminal of the resistor <b>31</b> is connected to a first power pin <b>122</b> of the edge connector <b>12</b>. A second terminal of the resistor <b>31</b> is connected to a second power pin <b>22</b> of the DIMM socket <b>20</b> and the voltage dividing circuit <b>33</b>. The differential amplifier circuit <b>32</b> is connected to the resistor <b>31</b> in parallel. The controller <b>34</b> is connected to the voltage dividing circuit <b>33</b>, the differential amplifier circuit <b>32</b>, and the display screen <b>35</b>. The display screen <b>35</b> is mounted on a surface of the board <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In use, the SSD <b>200</b> is inserted into the DIMM socket <b>20</b>. The edge connector <b>12</b> of the input power measuring device <b>100</b> is inserted into the DIMM socket <b>320</b> of the motherboard <b>300</b>. A data interface <b>220</b> of the SSD <b>200</b> is connected to a data interface <b>340</b> of the motherboard <b>300</b> through a data cable <b>400</b>. When the motherboard <b>300</b> is powered on, a voltage from the motherboard <b>300</b> is supplied to the SSD <b>200</b> through the DIMM socket <b>320</b>, the first power pin <b>122</b> of the edge connector <b>12</b>, the resistor <b>31</b>, the second power pin <b>22</b> of the DIMM socket <b>20</b>. The SSD <b>200</b> communicates with the motherboard <b>300</b> through the data interfaces <b>220</b> and <b>340</b>. The resistor <b>31</b> samples a first current outputted from the DIMM connector <b>320</b> of the motherboard <b>300</b>, and converts the first current into a first voltage. The voltage dividing circuit <b>33</b> divides the first voltage, and outputs a second voltage to the controller <b>34</b>. The differential amplifier circuit <b>32</b> amplifies the sampled first current to a second current, and output the second current to the controller <b>34</b>. The controller <b>34</b> converts the second current into a third current, and converts the third current into a third voltage. The controller <b>34</b> calculates a power according to the third current and the third voltage, that is, the power is equal to a product of the third current and the third voltage. The third current is the input current of the SSD <b>200</b>. The third voltage is the input voltage of the SSD <b>200</b>. The power is the input power of the SSD <b>200</b>. The controller <b>34</b> controls the display screen <b>35</b> to display the input current, input voltage and the input power of the SSD.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">It is to be understood, however, that even though numerous characteristics and advantages of the embodiments have been set forth in the foregoing description, together with details of the structure and function of the embodiments, the disclosure is illustrative only, and changes may be made in details, especially in matters of shape, size, and arrangement of parts within the principles of the embodiments to the full extent indicated by the broad general meaning of the terms in which the appended claims are expressed.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An input power measuring device to measure an input power of a solid state drive (SSD), the input power measuring device comprising:
<claim-text>a board comprising an edge connector formed on a bottom side of the board;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first dual inline memory modules (DIMM) socket mounted on the board to engage with the SSD; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a measuring circuit arranged on the board, the measuring circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a resistor comprising a first terminal connected to a first power pin of the edge connector and a second terminal connected to a second power pin of the first DIMM socket, wherein when the edge connector is inserted into a second DIMM socket of a motherboard and the motherboard is powered on, the first power pin of the edge connector is connected to a third power pin of the second DIMM socket to receive first current from the motherboard, the resistor samples first current from the first power pin, and converts the first current into a first voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a differential amplifier circuit connected between the first and second terminals of the resistor amplifies the first current to second current, and output the second current;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a voltage dividing circuit connected to the second terminal of the resistor divide the first voltage, and output a second voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a controller connected to the voltage dividing circuit, the differential amplifier circuit, and the display screen, convert the second current into third current, convert the second voltage into a third voltage, and calculate a power according to the third current and the third voltage; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a display screen mounted on the board display the power.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The input power measuring device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first DIMM socket is mounted on a top side of the board.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The input power measuring device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein two latching slots are defined in two opposite ends of the board to engage with the second DIMM socket, thereby fixing the board in the second DIMM socket. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
