<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623016-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623016</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11631042</doc-number>
<date>20050525</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10 2004 031 141</doc-number>
<date>20040628</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>1306</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>18</main-group>
<subgroup>18</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>606 51</main-classification>
<further-classification>606 50</further-classification>
<further-classification>606 52</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Electrosurgical instrument</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5891142</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Eggers et al.</name>
<date>19990400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5954720</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Wilson et al.</name>
<date>19990900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6273887</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Yamauchi et al.</name>
<date>20010800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6364879</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Chen et al.</name>
<date>20020400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6679882</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Kornerup</name>
<date>20040100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>606 51</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6736813</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Yamauchi et al.</name>
<date>20040500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2001/0037109</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yamauchi et al.</name>
<date>20011100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>606 48</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0109876</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yamauchi</name>
<date>20030600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>606 48</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>1976642</doc-number>
<date>20070600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>EP 0 797 959</doc-number>
<date>20030300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>0986990</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20000300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2000-102545</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20000400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2002-078717</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20020300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2003-116669</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20030400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00015">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2004-516043</doc-number>
<date>20040600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00016">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO-02/07627</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20020100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00017">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO 2004032777</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20040400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-cpc-text>A61B 18/14</classification-cpc-text>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>10</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>606 48</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>606 51</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>606 52</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>606 46</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080045944</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20080221</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Fischer</last-name>
<first-name>Klaus</first-name>
<address>
<city>Nagold</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Fischer</last-name>
<first-name>Klaus</first-name>
<address>
<city>Nagold</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Dickstein Shapiro LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Erbe Elektromedizin GmbH</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>T&#xfc;bingen</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Dvorak</last-name>
<first-name>Linda</first-name>
<department>3739</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Della</last-name>
<first-name>Jaymi</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/EP2005/005680</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20050525</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20061228</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2006/000280</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20060105</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The invention concerns an electrosurgical instrument comprising two articulated branches, which can be actuated in the manner of a squeezing tool. The instrument further comprises electrode parts at the distal ends of the branches for grasping tissue and for conducting a coagulating current through the tissue in order to cause it to coagulate as well as current-supplying devices for supplying the coagulating current to the electrode parts from an HF generator. At least one device for preventing a short circuit is arranged and configured on the electrode parts in such a way that the electrode parts are unable to touch.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="75.52mm" wi="62.91mm" file="US08623016-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="187.37mm" wi="169.93mm" file="US08623016-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="231.99mm" wi="153.25mm" file="US08623016-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="91.10mm" wi="161.29mm" file="US08623016-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="168.15mm" wi="150.20mm" file="US08623016-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is related to and claims priority from German Patent Application No. DE 10 2004 031 141.2, filed on Jun. 28, 2004, the entirety of which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">STATEMENT REGARDING FEDERALLY SPONSORED RESEARCH OR DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Not applicable.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">REFERENCE TO MICROFICHE APPENDIX</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Not applicable.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The invention concerns an electrosurgical instrument.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Electrosurgical instruments have been used for many years in high-frequency surgery to coagulate or cut biological tissue. With coagulation, a high-frequency current is passed through the tissue being treated, causing it to alter due to protein coagulation and dehydration. Here, the tissue constricts in such a way that the vessels occlude and bleeding is staunched. A high current density is required for a cutting procedure, the effect being that explosive vaporisation of the tissue fluid and tearing of the cellular membranes completely cut the tissue in two.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The use of bipolar instruments is gaining in importance more and more, since lower current strengths than with monopolar instruments are required. It is particularly advantageous that the direction of current between the electrode parts of bipolar instruments can be calculated and does not proceed any distance through the body of the patient.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Bipolar instruments have two articulated squeezing parts and gripping devices are provided at their proximal ends for handling the squeezing parts. At the distal ends of the squeezing parts, there are electrode parts for grasping tissue and for conducting a coagulating current through the tissue. A voltage produced by a HF generator, and the HF current which this provides, is conducted via current-supplying devices to the electrode parts of the bipolar instrument. To prevent a short circuit upon contact of the two electrode parts, the known instruments have a device for preventing a short circuit accommodated on the branches, whereby the electrode parts are always spaced apart when the instrument is closed.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The problem with the known devices for preventing a short circuit is that they only indirectly define the space between the electrode parts, because they are accommodated away from the electrode parts. Thus, the aspect ratios of the branches, for example, need to be taken into account to determine the appropriate space. This makes the adjustment of space and required HF voltage considerably difficult.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">It is therefore the object of the invention to further construct an electrosurgical instrument of the type specified at the start so that it is possible to adjust the space between the electrode parts to the required HF voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to the invention there is provided an electrosurgical instrument comprising consisting of two articulated branches, which are actuated in the manner of a squeezing tool. The instrument further comprises electrode parts at the distal ends of the branches for grasping tissue and for conducting a coagulating current through the tissue to cause it to coagulate as well as current-supplying devices for supplying the coagulating current to the electrode parts from a HF generator. At least one device for preventing a short circuit is arranged and configured on the electrode parts in such a way that the electrode parts are unable to touch.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Hence, in the present invention the device for preventing a short circuit is now arranged directly at the place where the effective space must be, that is, between the electrode parts. At the same time, coagulation is not prevented, because the tissue is also able to coagulate at a point of contact between tissue and device due to thermal conduction. To this extent, any sparking between the electrode parts can be reliably avoided with a coagulating procedure.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In one preferred embodiment, the device for preventing a short circuit has a distance element provided as an insulating section on at least one electrode part. Thus the short circuit between the electrode parts is prevented by the distance element, should these touch.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In another preferred embodiment, adjoining the insulating section, at least one initial cutting section is arranged on at least one of the electrode parts, in particular configured with a reduced space from the opposite electrode relative to the coagulating electrodes, in such a way that an arc for cutting through the tissue is produced from the initial cutting section with any increase in the voltage of the coagulating current. The cutting section is preferably arranged on the electrode part as an area that tapers in relation to the electrode part and protrudes from this. The electrode part will then have an explicit coagulating section beside the cutting section. The electrode part forming the coagulating section and the cutting section may, during a coagulating procedure, operate as a coagulating electrode over its entire surface area, i.e. both over the surface area of the coagulating section and over the surface area of the cutting section, whereas the tapered cutting section is available solely for a subsequent cutting procedure.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The cutting section guarantees that the arc is only produced here, whereas a disruptive discharge to the opposite electrode cannot occur on the rest of the electrode section as a result of too great a space between the electrode parts. Thus one and the same instrument can be used to both coagulate and cut, and a change of instrument can be avoided to the benefit of an uninterrupted operation.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The distance element may be configured as both linear in shape and punctiform. The distance element that is linear in shape will then extend, for example, in the direction of the branch progression, concentrically arranged on the electrode part, over the entire electrode part and accordingly form an edge. Advantageously, in this way the steady formation of an arc is made possible and an even cut is guaranteed. A punctiform distance element is easy to manufacture, reliably prevents a short circuit occurring between the electrode parts and, as a result of thermal conduction, also guarantees safe coagulation at the point of contact between tissue and distance element. Several punctiform distance elements arranged on the corresponding electrode part, e.g. at the respective ends of the electrode part, reliably prevent a short circuit and affect neither the coagulating nor the cutting procedure.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Preferably, a second cutting section will be configured on the electrode part facing the electrode part with the insulating section. This is particularly advantageous if the insulating section facing the second cutting section is arranged directly on the electrode part so that the electrode part does not have an explicit initial cutting section. In this embodiment, the insulating section is preferably smaller than the opposite cutting section, with the result that an arc can be formed around peripheral areas of the insulating section toward the opposite cutting section. This enables a precise cut to be achieved.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Alternatively, it is possible to configure the cutting section on both opposing electrode parts. Thus the area for the arc formation and the cutting progression are extremely precisely defined.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Preferably, the device for preventing a short circuit has at least one insulating section which is formed within an electrode part. A distance element provided as a cutting section is then configured on the electrode part facing the insulating section. The cutting section is arranged in such a way that it only comes into contact with the insulating section when the branches are brought together. Advantageously, a precise cut is also provided for here since the arc is formed between the incorporated section and the cutting section. The insulating section with this embodiment is protected from jolts or similar mechanical strains and essentially from the arc also.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The insulating section in this embodiment may be configured so as to be flush with an electrode surface of the electrode part that has the insulating section. This allows the electrode part to be cleaned simply and safely after treatment.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Alternatively, it is possible to arrange the insulating section so that it is sunk in the corresponding electrode part, with the result that the electrode part has a recess. The cutting section configured on the opposite electrode part can thus be at least partially lowered into the recess so that an arc can form inside the recess toward the cutting section during the cutting procedure. Surrounding tissue is thus protected from burning, while at the same time a precise cutting line can be defined.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In one preferred embodiment, the insulating section is symmetrically arranged toward the initial cutting section and/or second cutting section on the respective electrode parts. A symmetrical arrangement of the cooperating sections guarantees a uniformly developing arc on peripheral areas of the distance element, making for an even cutting progression.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">One possible embodiment provides for the distance element being configured in such a way that mechanical cutting can be carried out. Preferably, the distance element will then have a cutting edge which lends itself to mechanical cutting. With appropriate exertion on the part of the surgeon, the tissue can then be cut through completely following a coagulating procedure and without having to change instrument. This allows an especially soft treatment of the tissue to be achieved.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In one preferred embodiment the cutting section is configured as an edge with an essentially triangular cross-section on at least one electrode part. A triangular cross-section allows for the successive transition from one large surface area of the electrode part to its edge-shaped tapering. The smooth transition is especially suited to using the entire electrode part as a coagulating electrode where there is sufficient tissue thickness, because the entire surface area and the tissue can be brought into contact with each other.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Advantageously, the cutting section is configured as an edge with an essentially rounded or circular cross-section on at least one electrode part, as is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, for example. On one transition between the explicit coagulating section and the cutting section, the preference is to configure the cutting section in a truncated manner so that a secure anchorage of the cutting section to the corresponding electrode part is guaranteed. With this embodiment there is a relatively large electrode surface available for the coagulating procedure, whereas the cutting section configured as an edge is hardly of any consequence where there is sufficient tissue thickness. At an advanced stage of an operation, on the other hand, and with sufficient proximity of the opposite electrode parts of the electrosurgical instrument, the edge-shaped configuration of the cutting section allows the current density to be increased in such a way that a cutting procedure is possible.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Preferably, the insulating section is constructed from material that is resistant to arc erosion. Thus, reliable resistance to abrasion from the arc is provided.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In one preferred embodiment the insulating section consists of a ceramic material. Advantageously, ceramics have a high degree of resistance to corrosion and a high degree of resistance to abrasion from the arc and also to mechanical strain.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Embodiments of the invention will now be described by way of examples with reference to the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>a </i>is a cross-section of a schematically represented electrode arrangement in a first embodiment during a coagulation phase;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>b </i>shows the electrode arrangement shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>a </i>at the end of the coagulation phase;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>c </i>shows the electrode arrangement shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>a </i>during a cutting phase;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross-section of a schematically represented electrode arrangement in a second embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a cross-section of a schematically represented electrode arrangement in a third embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cross-section of a schematically represented electrode arrangement in a fourth embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross-section of a schematically represented electrode arrangement in a fifth embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a cross-section of a schematically represented electrode arrangement in a sixth embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a side elevation of a schematically represented electrosurgical instrument with an electrode arrangement according to the invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a cross-section of a schematically represented electrode arrangement in a further embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In the following description, the same reference numerals are used for the same and similarly working parts.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>a </i>depicts a front elevation as a cross-section of an electrode arrangement during a coagulation phase in a first embodiment. Represented here are two opposite electrode parts <b>18</b>, <b>19</b>, wherein one electrode part <b>18</b> has a cutting section or a cutting portion <b>18</b><i>a </i>and an insulating section or an insulating portion <b>21</b> configured as a distance element. In this embodiment, the distance element forms a device <b>20</b> for preventing a short circuit. Treated tissue <b>30</b> is clamped between the electrodes.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The insulating section <b>21</b> prevents an unwanted short circuit between the electrode parts <b>18</b>, <b>19</b> when the branches <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> are brought together and may be configured as both linear in shape and punctiform. The distance element that is linear in shape will then extend, for example, in the direction of the branch progression, concentrically arranged on the electrode part, over the entire electrode part and accordingly form an edge. Advantageously, the steady formation of an arc is thus made possible and an even cut is guaranteed. A punctiform distance element is easy to manufacture, reliably prevents a short circuit occurring between the electrode parts and, as a result of thermal conduction, also guarantees safe coagulation at the point of contact between tissue and distance element. Several punctiform distance elements arranged on the corresponding electrode part, e.g. at the respective ends of the electrode part, reliably prevent a short circuit and affect neither the coagulating nor the cutting procedure. The cutting section <b>18</b><i>a </i>is in any event configured as linear in shape.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Besides preventing a short circuit, the section <b>21</b> defines a thickness of the tissue <b>30</b> that remains after the coagulation phase, because it prevents an arc forming prematurely with any pre-set coagulating voltage due to too small a space between the electrode parts <b>18</b>, <b>19</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>b </i>depicts the electrode arrangement according to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>a</i>, although here the end of the coagulation is represented. According to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref><i>a </i>and <b>1</b><i>b </i>a coagulating current flows over an entire surface of the electrode parts <b>18</b>, <b>18</b><i>a</i>, <b>19</b>, with the effect that the interposed tissue <b>30</b> is coagulated. As a result of thermal conduction the tissue <b>30</b> is coagulated under the insulating section <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>c </i>depicts the electrode arrangement described above during a cutting phase. At the end of the coagulation phase, a HF voltage required for the electrosurgical treatment is slightly increased, with the result that between the cutting section <b>18</b><i>a </i>and the opposite electrode part <b>19</b> the arc <b>23</b> is formed, which now cuts through the already coagulated tissue <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The cutting section <b>18</b><i>a </i>is preferably arranged on the electrode part <b>18</b> as an area that tapers in relation to the electrode part <b>18</b> and protrudes from this. The electrode part <b>18</b> will then consist of an explicit coagulating section beside the cutting section <b>18</b><i>a</i>. The electrode part <b>18</b> forming the coagulating section and the cutting section <b>18</b><i>a </i>may, during a coagulating procedure, operate as a coagulating electrode over its entire surface area, i.e. both over the surface area of the coagulating section and over the surface area of the cutting section <b>18</b><i>a</i>, whereas the tapered cutting section <b>18</b><i>a </i>is available solely for a subsequent cutting procedure.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The height of the insulating section <b>21</b> and thus the space from the cutting section <b>18</b><i>a </i>and opposite electrode part <b>19</b> and the HF voltage required for cutting are adjusted to each other. The formation of the arc <b>23</b> outside the cutting section <b>18</b><i>a</i>, that is, on the remaining areas of the electrode part <b>18</b>, is thus avoided.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Because of the electrode arrangement just described, one and the same instrument can be used to both coagulate and cut, and a change of instrument can be avoided to the benefit of an uninterrupted operation.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> a front elevation as a cross-section of an electrode arrangement is represented in a second embodiment. Tissue clamped between the electrode parts during a treatment is not represented in this embodiment for the benefit of better clarity. The same applies, moreover, to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3 to 6</figref>. The arrangement differs from the one represented in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>a </i>to <b>1</b><i>c </i>in that a cutting section <b>18</b><i>a </i>is configured as an edge with a triangular cross-section. Because of the successive transition from one large surface area of the electrode part <b>18</b> to its edge-shaped tapering, this embodiment is especially suited to using the entire electrode part <b>18</b> as a coagulating electrode where there is sufficient tissue thickness, because the entire surface area and the tissue can be brought into contact with each other. With a suitable HF voltage, an arc <b>23</b> is formed between the cutting section <b>18</b><i>a </i>and an opposed electrode part <b>19</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The insulating section <b>21</b> has in this instance a tapered shape to also facilitate mechanical cutting where necessary, that is, the distance element has an explicit cutting edge <b>22</b>. With appropriate exertion on the part of the surgeon, the tissue can then be cut through completely following a coagulating procedure and without having to change instrument. This makes for an especially gentle treatment of the tissue without the use of an arc.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> depicts a front elevation as a cross-section of an electrode arrangement in a third embodiment. Here both a cutting section <b>18</b><i>a </i>is configured on an electrode part <b>18</b> and a cutting section <b>19</b><i>a </i>is configured on an electrode part <b>19</b>. An insulating section <b>21</b> is arranged directly below the cutting section <b>18</b><i>a </i>and symmetrically to the cutting sections <b>18</b><i>a</i>, <b>19</b><i>a</i>. A symmetric arrangement of the cooperating sections <b>18</b><i>a</i>, <b>21</b>, <b>19</b><i>a </i>guarantees a uniformly developing arc <b>23</b> on peripheral areas of the insulating section <b>21</b>, making for an even cutting progression. The insulating section <b>21</b> functioning as a distance element is smaller than the cutting sections <b>18</b><i>a</i>, <b>19</b><i>a</i>, so as not to prevent the arc <b>23</b> from forming. Because of the narrow cutting sections <b>18</b><i>a</i>, <b>19</b><i>a </i>accommodated on the electrode parts <b>18</b>, <b>19</b>, the cutting progression can be extremely precisely defined.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">An extremely simple embodiment of an electrode arrangement is depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. Here an electrode part <b>19</b> only has one cutting section <b>19</b><i>a</i>, whereas on an electrode part <b>18</b> facing the electrode part <b>19</b> there is only an insulating section <b>21</b> configured. Because the arc <b>23</b> forms in the direction of the cutting section <b>19</b><i>a</i>, this embodiment allows an exact cutting line to be defined in an especially easy way.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> depicts a front elevation as a cross-section of an electrode arrangement where an electrode part <b>18</b> has an insulating section <b>21</b> configured within the electrode part <b>18</b>, wherein the insulating section <b>21</b> terminates flush with an electrode surface <b>18</b><i>b</i>. A second cutting section <b>19</b><i>a </i>is provided as a distance element on an opposing electrode part <b>19</b>. The insulating section <b>21</b> and the cutting section <b>19</b><i>a </i>operate in this embodiment as a device <b>20</b> for preventing a short circuit. Advantageously, a precise cut is also provided for here since the arc <b>23</b> is formed between the incorporated section <b>21</b> and the cutting section <b>19</b><i>a</i>. The insulating section <b>21</b> with this embodiment is protected from jolts or similar mechanical strains and essentially from the arc <b>23</b> also.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> depicts a similar configuration of an electrode arrangement as represented in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. An insulating section <b>21</b> is configured here, however, to be sunk in a corresponding electrode part <b>18</b>, so that a recess <b>18</b><i>c </i>is formed on the electrode part <b>18</b>. A cutting section <b>19</b><i>a </i>configured on an opposing electrode part <b>19</b> can be at least partially lowered into the recess <b>18</b><i>c</i>, so that an arc <b>23</b> can form inside the recess <b>18</b><i>c </i>toward the cutting section <b>19</b><i>a </i>during the cutting procedure. Surrounding tissue is thus protected from burning, while at the same time a precise cutting line can be defined.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In this embodiment, too, the cutting section <b>19</b><i>a </i>may be configured with an explicit cutting edge, allowing the tissue to be cut through mechanically.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> depicts a fully illustrated electrosurgical instrument <b>10</b> with an electrode arrangement according to the invention. In the illustration the reference numerals <b>11</b> and <b>12</b> identify two branches of the electrosurgical instrument <b>10</b>. These branches <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> have ends <b>13</b>, <b>14</b> fitted with electrode parts <b>18</b>, <b>19</b>, wherein the electrode parts <b>18</b>, <b>19</b> face each other. With the aid of the electrode parts <b>18</b>, <b>19</b>, it is possible to grasp a vessel, for example, and to coagulate or cut this by supplying a high-frequency current. In addition, gripping parts <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>12</b><i>a </i>are provided which are attached to respective proximal ends <b>15</b>, <b>16</b> of the branches <b>11</b>, <b>12</b>. The proximal ends <b>15</b>, <b>16</b> of the squeezing parts <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> end in a connecting element <b>17</b><i>a </i>of current-supplying devices <b>17</b>. The current-supplying devices <b>17</b> serve to connect the electrosurgical instrument <b>10</b> to a HF generator (not represented), which produces a HF voltage, so that a HF current may be supplied to the electrode parts <b>18</b>, <b>19</b> by, for example, electrical leads (not depicted) running through the instrument <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">An edge-shaped cutting section <b>18</b><i>a </i>is configured on the electrode part <b>18</b>. This has two insulating sections <b>21</b>, <b>21</b>&#x2032; configured as two punctiform distance elements. The distance elements arranged at the respective ends of the electrode part <b>18</b> or on the cutting section <b>18</b><i>a </i>reliably prevent a short circuit and affect neither the coagulating nor the cutting procedure.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">To achieve a high degree of resistance of the insulating section to an arc, the section is preferably constructed from material that is resistant to arc erosion. A high degree of resistance to abrasion is provided in particular by the use of ceramic materials.</p>
<heading id="h-0009" level="1">LIST OF REFERENCE NUMERALS</heading>
<p id="p-0058" num="0000">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0057"><b>10</b> Electrosurgical instrument</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0002" num="0058"><b>11</b> Squeezing part, branch</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0003" num="0059"><b>11</b><i>a </i>Gripping part</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0004" num="0060"><b>12</b> Squeezing part, branch</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0005" num="0061"><b>12</b><i>a </i>Gripping part</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0006" num="0062"><b>13</b> Distal end</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0007" num="0063"><b>14</b> Distal end</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0008" num="0064"><b>15</b> Proximal end</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0009" num="0065"><b>16</b> Proximal end</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0010" num="0066"><b>17</b> Current-supplying devices</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0011" num="0067"><b>17</b><i>a </i>Connecting element</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0012" num="0068"><b>18</b> Electrode part</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0013" num="0069"><b>18</b><i>a </i>Cutting section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0014" num="0070"><b>18</b><i>b </i>Electrode surface</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0015" num="0071"><b>18</b><i>c </i>Recess</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0016" num="0072"><b>19</b> Electrode part</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0017" num="0073"><b>19</b><i>a </i>Cutting section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0018" num="0074"><b>20</b> Device for preventing a short circuit</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0019" num="0075"><b>21</b>, <b>21</b>&#x2032; Insulating section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0020" num="0076"><b>22</b> Cutting edge</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0021" num="0077"><b>23</b> Arc</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0022" num="0078"><b>30</b> Tissue</li>
</ul>
</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An electrosurgical instrument comprising:
<claim-text>two articulated branches, each with a distal end, which are actuated in the manner of a squeezing tool;</claim-text>
<claim-text>electrode parts comprising a first electrode part and an opposing electrode part, the first electrode part being at the distal end of one of the two articulated branches and the opposing electrode part being at the distal end of the other of the two articulated branches, the electrode parts being adapted to grasp tissue and to conduct a coagulation current through the tissue in order to cause it to coagulate or a cutting current in order to cause it to cut the tissue;</claim-text>
<claim-text>current-supplying devices adapted to supply said coagulation and cutting currents to the first electrode part and the opposing electrode part from a high-frequency (HF) generator; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one device for preventing a short circuit which is configured on said electrode parts and arranged such that the first electrode part and the opposing electrode part are unable to touch one another, wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the at least one device for preventing a short circuit comprises at least one insulating region forming part of a first distance element, and wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first electrode part or the opposing electrode part comprises a coagulation section and a cutting section protruding from the coagulation section, each of the coagulation section and the cutting section forming a surface area, wherein the surface areas of the coagulation section and the cutting section serve as a coagulating electrode, whereas the surface area of the cutting section but not the surface area of the coagulation section is available for a cutting procedure in such a way that an arc for cutting through the tissue is produced from the cutting section, and wherein the cutting section defines an edge having a substantially trapezoidal cross-section on at least one of the first electrode part or the opposing electrode part;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the at least one insulating region is arranged in a projecting manner on the cutting section such that the at least one insulating region is arranged between the cutting section and the opposing electrode part if the two articulated branches are brought together, wherein said cutting section is symmetrical about said at least one insulating region, and wherein the at least one insulating region is smaller than the cutting section so as not to prevent the arc from forming, and wherein a height of the first distance element determines a distance between the cutting section and the opposing electrode part when the two articulated branches are in a closed position;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the at least one device for preventing a short circuit comprises the at least one insulating region, which is arranged on one of the electrode parts, and a second distance element adapted as a second cutting section, which is configured on the opposing electrode part facing the at least one insulating region and which is adapted such that, when the two articulated branches are squeezed together, the second cutting section only touches the at least one insulating region.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. An electrosurgical instrument according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the cutting section includes an initial cutting section that adjoins the at least one insulating region and is arranged such that, with any increase in a voltage of the coagulation or cutting currents, the arc for cutting through the tissue is produced from the initial cutting section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. An electrosurgical instrument according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said at least one insulating region is arranged symmetrically to at least one of said cutting section on the first electrode part and said second cutting section on the opposing electrode part.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. An electrosurgical instrument according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said first distance element is adapted to enable mechanical cutting to be carried out.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. Electrosurgical instrument according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein said cutting section defines an edge with a rounded profile on at least one of said electrode parts.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. An electrosurgical instrument according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said at least one insulating region is comprised of a material resistant to arc erosion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. An electrosurgical instrument according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said at least one insulating region is comprised of a ceramic material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. An electrosurgical instrument according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said second cutting section is symmetrical about said at least one insulating region when said second cutting section touches said at least one insulating region.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. An electrosurgical instrument according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said first and second distance elements are adapted to enable mechanical cutting to be carried out.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. Electrosurgical instrument according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said cutting section defines an edge with a rounded profile on at least one of said electrode parts.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
