<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625258-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625258</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12955927</doc-number>
<date>20101130</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>605</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36167901</main-classification>
<further-classification>181207</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Mounting apparatus for expansion card</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4066058</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Anderkay</name>
<date>19780100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>123198 E</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6786298</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Chang et al.</name>
<date>20040900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>181207</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2001/0037911</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Stanienda</name>
<date>20011100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>181207</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0242322</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Tsai</name>
<date>20091000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>181207</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0228451</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Chiu</name>
<date>20110900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36167901</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0304960</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lu</name>
<date>20111200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36167901</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>16</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36167901</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>181207</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110317342</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20111229</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Li</last-name>
<first-name>Zhan-Yang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Li</last-name>
<first-name>Zhan-Yang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hong Fu Jin Precision Industry (ShenZhen) Co., Ltd</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Phillips</last-name>
<first-name>Forrest M</first-name>
<department>2837</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A mounting apparatus includes a mounting bracket and a securing element. The mounting bracket is configured to mount an expansion card. The mounting bracket is mounted in a chassis. The securing element includes a positioning member mounted to the mounting bracket, a mounting member mounted in the positioning member, and an elastic member surrounding the mounting member. The positioning member includes a first stopping portion. The mounting member includes a contact portion and a threaded portion engaging the chassis. The elastic member is resiliently compressed between the first stopping portion and the contact portion. The elastic member is configured to bias the threaded portion away from the chassis.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="207.01mm" wi="104.48mm" file="US08625258-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="248.67mm" wi="183.90mm" file="US08625258-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="243.50mm" wi="125.90mm" file="US08625258-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="205.06mm" wi="162.14mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625258-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="204.39mm" wi="150.54mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625258-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="210.48mm" wi="146.47mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625258-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to mounting apparatuses, and particularly to a mounting apparatus for securing expansion cards in an electronic device.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A computer system usually includes expansion cards, such as sound cards, video cards, graphics cards and so on, for enhancing capabilities of the computer system. Often, an expansion card is coupled to a riser card, and one end of the expansion card is secured to a rear wall of the computer system enclosure. However, some expansion cards are longer than others. If the longer expansion cards are secured to the computer enclosure as described, they will be unstable.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Many aspects of the embodiments can be better understood with references to the following drawings. The components in the drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the embodiments. Moreover, in the drawings, like reference numerals designate corresponding parts throughout the several views.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an exploded, isometric view of a mounting apparatus for an expansion card in accordance with an embodiment, the mounting apparatus including a securing element.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exploded, isometric view of the securing element of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a pre-assembly view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cross section of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, taken along line IV-IV.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross section of the mounting apparatus being assembled.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The disclosure is illustrated by way of example and not by way of limitation in the figures of the accompanying drawings in which like references indicate similar elements. It should be noted that references to &#x201c;an&#x201d; or &#x201c;one&#x201d; embodiment in this disclosure are not necessarily to the same embodiment, and such references mean at least one.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 3</figref>, a mounting apparatus includes a chassis <b>10</b>, a mounting bracket <b>21</b> of an expansion card module <b>20</b>, and a securing element <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The chassis <b>10</b> includes a bottom plate <b>11</b>, a rear plate <b>13</b> extending perpendicularly from the bottom plate <b>11</b>, and a side plate <b>15</b> extending perpendicularly from the bottom plate <b>11</b>. The bottom plate <b>11</b> is configured to mount a printed circuit board <b>40</b>. The bottom plate <b>11</b> includes a securing portion <b>111</b>. A securing hole <b>112</b> is defined in the securing portion <b>111</b>. A mounting opening <b>131</b> is defined in the rear plate <b>13</b>. A first mounting hole <b>133</b> and a slot <b>135</b> are defined in two opposite sides of the mounting opening <b>131</b>. An inserting slot <b>41</b> and a through hole <b>42</b> are defined in the printed circuit board <b>40</b>. The through hole <b>42</b> corresponds to the securing hole <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The expansion card module <b>20</b> includes a plurality of expansion cards <b>22</b> mounted in the mounting bracket <b>21</b>. The mounting bracket <b>21</b> includes a rear panel <b>211</b> and a side panel <b>213</b>. A converter card <b>23</b> is mounted on the side panel <b>213</b>. The converter card <b>23</b> includes an inserting terminal <b>231</b> corresponding to the inserting slot <b>41</b> of the printed circuit board <b>40</b>. A second mounting hole <b>2111</b> is defined in the rear panel <b>211</b> corresponding to the first mounting hole <b>133</b> of the rear plate <b>13</b> of the chassis <b>10</b>. The rear panel <b>211</b> includes a protrusion <b>2112</b> corresponding to the slot <b>135</b> of the rear plate <b>13</b>. The side panel <b>213</b> includes mounting portion <b>2131</b>. A plurality of third mounting holes <b>2132</b> is defined in the mounting portion <b>2131</b>. The mounting portion <b>2131</b> includes a bent tab <b>2133</b>, and a through hole <b>2134</b> is defined in the bent tab <b>2133</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The securing element <b>30</b> includes a positioning member <b>31</b>, an elastic member <b>32</b>, and a mounting member <b>33</b>. A through hole <b>311</b> is defined in the positioning member <b>31</b>. The positioning member <b>31</b> includes a main body <b>310</b>, a first stopping portion <b>312</b> and a second stopping portion <b>313</b> in an inner side of the main body <b>310</b>. The main body <b>310</b> is U-shaped. The positioning member <b>31</b> also includes a plurality of mounting protrusions <b>314</b> extending from the main body <b>310</b>. In one embodiment, the elastic member <b>32</b> is a spring. The mounting member <b>33</b> includes a handling portion <b>331</b>, a threaded portion <b>332</b>, and a contact portion <b>333</b>. The contact portion <b>333</b> is disposed between the threaded portion <b>332</b> and the handling portion <b>331</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 5</figref>, during assembly of the securing element <b>30</b> to the mounting bracket <b>21</b>, the elastic member <b>32</b> surrounds the mounting member <b>33</b>. The elastic member <b>32</b> is disposed between the contact portion <b>333</b> and the first stopping portion <b>312</b>. The contact portion <b>333</b> abuts the second stopping portion <b>313</b> of the positioning member <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In assembly of the mounting apparatus, the expansion cards <b>22</b> are received in the mounting bracket <b>21</b>. The expansion card module <b>20</b> is aligned with the mounting opening <b>131</b> of the rear plate <b>13</b>. The protrusion <b>2112</b> is disposed in the slot <b>135</b> of the rear plate <b>13</b>. The first mounting hole <b>133</b> is aligned with the second mounting hole <b>2111</b> of the rear panel <b>211</b>. A fastener <b>50</b> extends into the first and second mounting holes <b>133</b>, <b>2111</b> to secure the mounting bracket <b>21</b> to the rear plate <b>13</b>. The threaded portion <b>332</b> of the mounting member <b>33</b> is aligned with the through hole <b>42</b> of the printed circuit board <b>40</b> and the securing hole <b>112</b> of the bottom plate <b>11</b>. When the threaded portion <b>332</b> of the mounting member <b>33</b> reaches the securing hole <b>112</b> of the bottom plate <b>11</b>, the handling portion <b>331</b> of the mounting member <b>33</b> is rotated to enable the threaded portion <b>332</b> to extend into the securing hole <b>112</b>, thereby securing the mounting bracket <b>21</b> to the bottom plate <b>11</b>. At this time, the elastic member <b>32</b> is resiliently compressed between the first stopping portion <b>312</b> and the contact portion <b>333</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">During disassembly, the fastener <b>50</b> is removed from the first mounting hole <b>133</b> to enable the mounting bracket <b>21</b> to separate from the rear plate <b>13</b>. The threaded portion <b>332</b> of the mounting member <b>33</b> is separated from the securing hole <b>112</b> to enable the mounting bracket <b>21</b> to separate from the bottom plate <b>11</b>. At this time, the elastic member <b>32</b> is released to enable the contact portion <b>333</b> to block the second stopping portion <b>313</b>. The expansion card module <b>20</b> is moved upward to be separated from the chassis <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">It is to be understood, however, that even though numerous characteristics and advantages have been set forth in the foregoing description of embodiments, together with details of the structures and functions of the embodiments, the disclosure is illustrative only and changes may be made in detail, especially in matters of shape, size, and arrangement of parts within the principles of the disclosure to the full extent indicated by the broad general meaning of the terms in which the appended claims are expressed.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A mounting apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a mounting bracket configured to mount an expansion card, the mounting bracket configured to be mounted in a chassis; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a securing element, the securing element comprising a positioning member mounted to a mounting bracket, a mounting member mounted in the positioning member, and an elastic member surrounding the mounting member; the positioning member comprising a main body, a first stopping portion and a second stopping portion; the first stopping portion and the second stopping portion extending from an inner side of the main body; the mounting member comprising a contact portion and a threaded portion configured to engage the chassis; the contact portion resisting the second stopping portion and located between the first stopping portion and the second stopping portion; the elastic member resiliently compressed between the first stopping portion and the contact portion; and the elastic member configured to bias the threaded portion away from the chassis.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The securing element of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the main body is U-shaped.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The mounting apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a through hole is defined in the mounting bracket, the through hole corresponds to the threaded portion, and the threaded portion is configured to extend through the through hole to engage the chassis.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The mounting apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the mounting member comprises a handling portion; and the handling portion is configured to be rotated to enable the threaded portion to engage the chassis.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The mounting apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the positioning member comprises a mounting protrusion, and a mounting hole is defined in the mounting bracket corresponding to the mounting protrusion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. An electronic device, comprising:
<claim-text>a chassis, the chassis comprising a bottom plate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mounting bracket, the mounting bracket configured to mount an expansion card and the mounting bracket mounted on the bottom plate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a securing element; the securing element comprising a positioning member mounted to the mounting bracket, a mounting member mounted in the positioning member, and an elastic member surrounding the mounting member; the positioning member comprising a main body, a first stopping portion, and a second stopping portion; the mounting member comprising a contact portion, and the mounting member engages the bottom plate; the first stopping portion and the second stopping portion extending from an inner side of the main body; the contact portion located between the first stopping portion and the second stopping portion; the elastic member is resiliently compressed between the first stopping portion and the contact portion; and the elastic member configured to bias the mounting member away from the bottom plate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The electronic device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the mounting member further comprises a threaded portion, and a securing hole, defined in the bottom plate, engages the threaded portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The electronic device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein a through hole is defined in the mounting bracket, the through hole corresponds to the securing hole, and the threaded portion extends through the through hole to engage the securing hole.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The electronic device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the mounting member comprises a handling portion; and the handling portion is configured to be rotated to enable the threaded portion to engage the securing hole.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The electronic device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, further comprising a printed circuit board, wherein the expansion card is connected to the printed circuit board; and a through hole is defined in the printed circuit board, and the threaded portion extends through the through hole to engage the securing hole.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The securing element of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the main body is U-shaped.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The electronic device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the positioning member comprises a mounting protrusion, and a mounting hole is defined in the mounting bracket corresponding to the mounting protrusion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The electronic device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the chassis further comprises a rear plate substantially perpendicular to the bottom plate, and a fastener securing the mounting bracket to the rear plate along a direction substantially perpendicular to the rear plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A securing element, comprising:
<claim-text>a positioning member configured to be mounted to a mounting bracket, the positioning member comprising a main body, a first stopping portion, and a second stopping portion; and the first stopping portion and the second stopping portion extending from an inner side of the main body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mounting member mounted in the positioning member, the mounting member comprising a contact portion and a threaded portion configured to engage a chassis to secure the mounting bracket to the chassis, and the contact portion contacting the second stopping portion and located between the first stopping portion and the second stopping portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an elastic member surrounding the mounting member; the elastic member resiliently compressed between the first stopping portion and the contact portion; and the elastic member configured to bias the threaded portion away from the chassis.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The securing element of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the mounting member comprises a handling portion; and the handling portion is configured to be rotated to enable the threaded portion to engage the chassis.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The securing element of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the main body is U-shaped.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
