<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624415-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624415</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13450979</doc-number>
<date>20120419</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>78</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>16</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>290 52</main-classification>
<further-classification>310114</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Multi-rotor generator</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5376827</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hines</name>
<date>19941200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>290 52</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6794781</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Razzell et al.</name>
<date>20040900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>310114</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7573176</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Shibukawa</name>
<date>20090800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>310268</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7880355</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Qu et al.</name>
<date>20110200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>310103</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8063527</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Qu et al.</name>
<date>20111100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>310112</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8222784</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Serra et al.</name>
<date>20120700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>310114</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0184245</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Arimitsu</name>
<date>20031000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>318268</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>290 52</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>310112</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>310114</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>2</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130277976</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20131024</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Koenig</last-name>
<first-name>Andreas C.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Machesney Park</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Koenig</last-name>
<first-name>Andreas C.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Machesney Park</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Kinney &#x26; Lange, P.A.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hamilton Sundstrand Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Windsor Locks</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Waks</last-name>
<first-name>Joseph</first-name>
<department>2833</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A generator system comprises an inner generator rotor, an outer generator rotor, and a stator. The inner rotor is mounted on the first shaft rotating at a first speed, while the outer rotor is mounted on a second shaft coaxial with the first shaft, and rotating at a second speed different from the first speed. The outer rotor is mounted coaxially with and radially outward of the inner rotor, and the stator is mounted coaxially with and radially outward of the outer rotor.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="131.40mm" wi="206.93mm" file="US08624415-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="220.30mm" wi="171.28mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624415-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="210.14mm" wi="141.48mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624415-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates generally to electrical machines, and more particularly to a multi-rotor generator for use in aircraft.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Most modern aircraft are primarily powered by gas turbine engines. Gas turbine engines are Brayton cycle engines comprising a compressor, a combustor, and a turbine. The compressor pressurizes environmental air, typically via multiple stages of rotary blades and stationary vanes. The combustor injects fuel into the high-pressure air stream provided by the compressor, and combusts the resulting fuel-air mixture. The turbine extracts energy from the resulting high-pressure, high-temperature airflow. This extracted energy is used to drive the compressor, and to power other systems. Many aircraft gas turbine engines are connected to rotary generators via mechanical gearboxes to supply electrical power to aircraft systems. The power and propulsion demands of commercial aircraft continue to increase.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Most modern commercial aircraft use multi-stage gas turbine engines with separate high and low pressure spools. High pressure turbines operate at high speeds, extracting energy from gas leaving the combustor to drive high pressure compressor stages immediately upstream of the combustor via a high pressure shaft. Low pressure turbines operate at much lower speeds but considerably more variable speed range, and extract energy from gas leaving the high pressure turbine. Low pressure turbines are connected via low pressure shafts which drive low pressure compressors. Gearboxes for electrical generators are conventionally attached to the high pressure shaft, and extract energy from the high pressure spool. Gearboxes can add considerable weight and mechanical complexity to turbine/generator systems.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Many generator systems for aircraft use generation systems with three rotating machines on a common shaft: a main generator, an exciter, and the permanent magnet generator (PMG). The largest of these is the main generator, commonly of a wound rotor synchronous type. The rotor of a generator of this type has a field winding that is provided with DC current to create a magnetic field that spins in synchronism with the rotor. The exciter commonly consists of a stationary field winding with a rotating armature winding. The alternating current from the rotating armature winding is rectified to a direct current using a rotating rectifier and is fed to the wound rotor of the main generator. The current in the field winding of the exciter is controlled by a generator control unit (GCU) to provide the required output from the main generator. The GCU may be designed such that it can be powered by either the main generator or the permanent magnet generator (in the event that the main generator is not yet providing electricity). The permanent magnet generators comprise permanent magnet rotors with wound stators connected to the GCU.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Turbofans are often classified by bypass ratio, the ratio of bypass airflow (i.e. airflow through a fan which bypasses the compressor, combustor, and turbine) to compressor airflow. The trend in recent engines is for higher bypass ratios, with the result that less power is available from the high pressure spool for electrical power generation.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The present invention is directed toward a generator system with an inner generator rotor, an outer generator rotor, and a stator. The inner rotor is mounted on the first shaft rotating at a first speed, while the outer rotor is mounted on a second shaft coaxial with the first shaft, and rotating at a second speed different from the first speed. The outer rotor is mounted coaxially with and radially outward of the inner rotor, and the stator is mounted coaxially with and radially outward of the outer rotor.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic cross-sectional view of an aircraft turbine/generator system according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic cross-sectional view of a multi-rotor generator of the aircraft turbine/generator system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic cross-sectional view of turbine/generator system <b>10</b>. Turbine/generator system <b>10</b> is depicted as a turbofan system, although other forms of aircraft propulsion gas turbine systems could equivalently be used. Turbine/generator system <b>10</b> is a two spool aircraft power and propulsion system comprising low pressure spool <b>12</b>, high pressure spool <b>14</b>, combustor <b>16</b>, and generator <b>18</b>. Low pressure spool <b>12</b> comprises low pressure shaft <b>20</b>, fan <b>22</b>, low pressure compressor <b>24</b>, and low pressure turbine <b>26</b>. High-pressure spool <b>14</b> comprises high pressure shaft <b>28</b>, high pressure compressor <b>30</b>, and high pressure turbine <b>32</b>. Generator <b>18</b> comprises inner rotor <b>34</b>, outer rotor <b>36</b>, and stator <b>38</b>. Air flows through turbine/generator system <b>10</b> substantially in flow direction F.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Low pressure spool <b>12</b> and high pressure spool <b>14</b> are separately rotating spools of turbine/generator system <b>10</b>. Fan <b>22</b> and low pressure compressor <b>24</b> are driven by low pressure shaft <b>20</b>, and pressurize environmental air, driving it into high pressure compressor <b>30</b>. High pressure compressor <b>30</b> is driven by high pressure spool <b>20</b>, and further compresses pressurized air received from low pressure compressor <b>24</b>. Pressurized air from high pressure compressor <b>30</b> is mixed with fuel (supplied by a fuel system not depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) in combustor <b>16</b>, where this fuel-air mixture is ignited. High pressure turbine <b>32</b> extracts energy from the resulting high-temperature, high-pressure gas in the form of torque on high pressure shaft <b>28</b>, and low pressure turbine <b>26</b> similarly extracts energy from gas exiting high pressure turbine <b>32</b> in the form of torque on low pressure shaft <b>20</b>. High pressure shaft <b>28</b> and low pressure shaft <b>20</b> drive high pressure combustor <b>30</b> and low pressure combustor <b>24</b>, respectively. All elements of low pressure spool <b>12</b> rotate at one shared speed, while all elements of high pressure spool <b>14</b> rotate at another. In some embodiments of turbine/generator system <b>10</b>, blades and vanes of high pressure compressor <b>30</b>, low pressure compressor <b>24</b>, high pressure turbine <b>32</b>, and high pressure turbine <b>26</b> may be configured such that high pressure spool <b>14</b> and low pressure spool <b>12</b> rotate in opposite directions. Operational speeds of high pressure spool <b>14</b> exceed operational speeds of low pressure spool <b>12</b>, but vary less. The ratio of upper to lower bounds of rotational speeds of high pressure spool <b>14</b> may, for instance, be on the order of 2:1, as contrasted with a ratio of 5:1 for low pressure spool <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Generator <b>18</b> is a multi-rotor electrical generator which produces electrical power from relative rotation of low pressure shaft <b>28</b> and high pressure shaft <b>20</b>, as described in greater detail below with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. In alternative embodiments inner rotor <b>34</b> may be a wound field or permanent magnet rotor. Outer rotor <b>34</b> is a wound induction type rotor, while stator <b>38</b> is a wound stator which extracts electricity from changes in magnetic flux. Electricity from generator <b>18</b> may power a variety of aircraft systems, including navigation systems, cabin lighting and air circulation, and mechanical actuators for aircraft wings and wheels.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">As noted above, bypass ratios have been increasing in recent aircraft, leaving less power available for extraction from high pressure spool <b>14</b> for electrical applications. Generator <b>18</b> alleviates this limitation by drawing power both from high pressure spool <b>14</b> and from low pressure spool <b>12</b>. In addition, turbine/generator system <b>10</b> dispenses with the large, heavy gearbox found in conventional aircraft generator systems. By mounting inner rotor <b>34</b> and outer rotor <b>36</b> directly on low pressure shaft <b>20</b> and high pressure shaft <b>28</b>, respectively, turbine/generator <b>10</b> allows generator <b>18</b> to be embedded near low pressure compressor <b>24</b> and high pressure compressor <b>30</b>, thereby lowering the overall weight and size of turbine/generator system <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic cross-sectional view of generator <b>18</b>, comprising low pressure shaft <b>20</b>, high pressure shaft <b>28</b>, inner rotor <b>34</b>, outer rotor <b>36</b>, stator <b>38</b>, outer rotor windings <b>40</b>, stator windings <b>42</b>, and power converter <b>44</b>. As discussed above with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, low pressure shaft <b>20</b> and high pressure shaft <b>28</b> are co-axial torque shafts which carry torque from low pressure turbine <b>26</b> and high pressure turbine <b>32</b>, respectively. High pressure shaft <b>28</b> drives outer rotor <b>36</b>, and low pressure shaft <b>20</b> drives inner rotor <b>34</b>. High pressure shaft <b>28</b> and low pressure shaft <b>20</b> rotate at different speeds, and in some embodiments may rotate in opposite directions. Inner rotor <b>34</b> may be a permanent magnet rotor or a wound field rotor, and outer rotor <b>40</b> may be a squirrel cage or wound induction rotor. Stator <b>38</b> is a wound stator with a plurality of conductive stator windings <b>42</b> through which changing magnetic flux from outer rotor <b>36</b> induces current.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Inner rotor <b>34</b> produces a magnetic field which rotates during operation of generator <b>18</b>. This rotating magnetic field has a field rotation frequency at outer rotor <b>36</b> equal to the difference in rotational speed (in RPM) between high pressure shaft <b>28</b> and low pressure shaft <b>20</b>. In embodiments of turbine/generator system <b>10</b> wherein high pressure shaft <b>28</b> and low pressure shaft <b>20</b> are configured to rotate in opposite directions, this field rotation frequency will be especially large. Depending on shaft speed ranges, the ratio of maximum to minimum field rotation frequency at outer rotor <b>36</b> can be significantly reduced relative to the ratio of maximum to minimum speeds of low pressure shaft <b>20</b>, promoting substantially constant or narrower range variable frequency power output.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Outer rotor <b>36</b> may be a wound rotor comprising a rigid support structure and a plurality of outer rotor windings <b>40</b> comprising coils of conductive wire. Alternatively, outer rotor <b>36</b> may be a squirrel cage. In either case, inner rotor <b>34</b> produces a magnetic field that induces currents in outer rotor <b>36</b>. These currents in turn produce a field that couples to stator <b>38</b>. Power converter <b>44</b> receives and conditions electrical power from stator <b>38</b> for use by aircraft systems. Power converter <b>44</b> may, for instance, include a three-phase inverter/rectifier bridge to stator <b>38</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In a first embodiment, inner rotor <b>34</b> is a wound rotor fed by a secondary current source, such as a secondary generator or an energy storage device connected by a brush contact. In this first embodiment, inner rotor <b>34</b> produces a strong magnetic field that induces currents in outer rotor <b>36</b> based on relative motion of inner rotor <b>34</b> and outer rotor <b>36</b>. By coupling these induced currents to stator <b>38</b>, generator <b>18</b> allows large amounts of energy to be extracted from both inner low-pressure shaft <b>20</b> and high-pressure shaft <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In a second embodiment, inner rotor <b>34</b> is a permanent magnet rotor. In this second embodiment, inner rotor <b>34</b> comprises a plurality of circumferentially spaced permanent magnets which produce a relatively weak magnetic field at outer rotor <b>36</b> that varies as inner rotor <b>34</b> rotates with respect to outer rotor <b>36</b>. As in the first embodiment, this magnetic field at outer rotor <b>36</b> induces a current coupled to stator <b>38</b>. The field produced by inner rotor <b>34</b> is selected to be relatively weak, so that generator <b>18</b> can be readily deactivated during fault conditions, to avoid damaging outer rotor windings <b>40</b> or stator windings <b>42</b>. Higher magnetic field strengths could be utilized (for instance using more or stronger permanent magnets), but would necessitate additional mechanisms to electrically or mechanically de-energize inner rotor <b>34</b> during fault conditions. Low field strengths from inner rotor <b>34</b> allow less power to be drawn from low pressure shaft <b>20</b>, but allow generator <b>18</b> to be &#x201c;bootstrapped&#x201d; when secondary starting power is unavailable. This second embodiment allows generator <b>18</b> to eschew secondary starter generators or energy storage devices, reducing total generator mass and bulk.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In a third embodiment, inner rotor <b>34</b> could comprise both fed conductive windings and permanent magnets. The inclusion of permanent magnets would enable rotor <b>34</b> to be used to bootstrap generator <b>18</b> during starting conditions, while conductive windings could subsequently be fed to allow greater power to be extracted from low pressure shaft <b>20</b>. This third embodiment would utilize significantly more complex wiring, but would combine the advantages of the first and second embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">All embodiments of turbine/generator system <b>10</b> allow generator <b>18</b> to be mounted in a relatively cool region of an aircraft gas turbine engine, such as between low pressure compressor <b>24</b> and high pressure compressor <b>30</b>. By directly coupling generator <b>18</b> to low pressure shaft <b>20</b> and high pressure shaft <b>28</b>, turbine/generator system <b>10</b> dispenses with heavy, bulky gearboxes.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">All embodiments of generator <b>18</b> further allow at least some power to be extracted from low pressure shaft <b>20</b>, unlike conventional systems wherein power generation systems are driven exclusively by high pressure shaft <b>28</b>. These embodiments can reduce the overall speed range of the generator, promoting constant or relatively narrow variable frequency output. Generator <b>18</b> may be made still more compact for embodiments of turbine/generator system <b>10</b> wherein low pressure spool <b>12</b> and high pressure spool <b>14</b> counter rotate. Generator <b>18</b> may also be used to transfer power from low pressure shaft <b>20</b> of low pressure spool <b>12</b> to high pressure shaft <b>28</b> of high pressure spool <b>14</b>, or vice versa, to modify engine dynamics to the benefit of the thermal cycle of turbine/generator system <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The first and third embodiments disclosed above allow greater energy to be extracted from low pressure shaft <b>20</b>. The second and third embodiments disclosed above allow turbine/generator system <b>10</b> to dispense with additional starter hardware (e.g. permanent magnet stator and exciter), saving space and weight.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">While the invention has been described with reference to an exemplary embodiment(s), it will be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes may be made and equivalents may be substituted for elements thereof without departing from the scope of the invention. In addition, many modifications may be made to adapt a particular situation or material to the teachings of the invention without departing from the essential scope thereof. Therefore, it is intended that the invention not be limited to the particular embodiment(s) disclosed, but that the invention will include all embodiments falling within the scope of the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A turbine/generator system comprising:
<claim-text>a multispool gas turbine having a high pressure shaft and a low pressure shaft;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an inner rotor mounted on the low pressure shaft;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an outer induction rotor mounted on the high pressure shaft coaxially with and radially outward of the inner rotor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a stator mounted coaxially with and radially outward of the outer induction rotor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The turbine/generator system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the inner rotor comprises a plurality of permanent magnets configured to induce current on the outer induction rotor during operation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The turbine/generator system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the inner rotor is a fed wound rotor, and further comprising a starter power source connected to the fed wound rotor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The turbine/generator system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the inner rotor is fed by a secondary current source.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The turbine/generator system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the outer induction rotor is a wound induction rotor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The turbine/generator system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the outer induction rotor comprises a squirrel cage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The turbine/generator system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, and further comprising a power converter w/ an inverter/rectifier bridge to the stator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The turbine/generator system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the multispool gas turbine is an aircraft propulsion turbofan engine.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The turbine/generator system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the inner rotor comprises both permanent magnets and windings fed from the stator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The turbine/generator system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the inner rotor, the outer induction rotor, and the stator are situated in a cool region of the multispool gas turbine engine.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The turbine/generator system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the high pressure shaft and the low pressure shaft are configured to rotate in opposite directions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. A multi-rotor generator comprising:
<claim-text>an inner rotor mounted on a first rotating shaft configured to rotate at a first speed range;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an outer rotor mounted concentric with and radially outward of the inner rotor, on a second rotating shaft concentric with the first rotating shaft and configured to rotate at a second speed range not equal to the first speed range;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a stator mounted concentric with and radially outward of the outer rotor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The multi-rotor generator of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the inner rotor is a wound rotor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The multi-rotor generator of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further comprising a starter power source coupled to the wound rotor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The multi-rotor generator of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the inner rotor comprises a plurality of circumferentially spaced permanent magnets.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The multi-rotor generator of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the inner rotor further comprises a plurality of windings fed by the stator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The multi-rotor generator of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the outer rotor is an induction rotor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The multi-rotor generator of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the induction rotor is a squirrel cage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The multi-rotor generator of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the induction rotor is a wound induction rotor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The multi-rotor generator of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein multi-rotor generator is embedded in a cool region of the gas turbine. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
