<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624753-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624753</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12907880</doc-number>
<date>20101019</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>606</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>08</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>3406911</main-classification>
<further-classification>345156</further-classification>
<further-classification>345173</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Event sensor including printed electronic circuit</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5270711</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Knapp</name>
<date>19931200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>341 34</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6118426</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Albert et al.</name>
<date>20000900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>345107</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7570231</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Itokawa et al.</name>
<date>20090800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>345 68</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8184107</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Lee et al.</name>
<date>20120500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>345174</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8432370</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Park et al.</name>
<date>20130400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>345173</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>3406911</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>3406916</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>3408154</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>341 34</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>345156</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>345173</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>345174</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>10</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>11</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120092181</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120419</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Daniel</last-name>
<first-name>Jurgen H.</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Francisco</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ng</last-name>
<first-name>Tse Nga</first-name>
<address>
<city>Mountain View</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Daniel</last-name>
<first-name>Jurgen H.</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Francisco</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ng</last-name>
<first-name>Tse Nga</first-name>
<address>
<city>Mountain View</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Small</last-name>
<first-name>Jonathan A.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Palo Alto Research Center Incorporated</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Palo Alto</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Swarthout</last-name>
<first-name>Brent</first-name>
<department>2689</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An event sensor device comprises a detector and circuitry, connected thereto, produced by printed electronics processes. This circuitry may be comprised of fixed characteristic devices, such as a series resistive chain, or variable characteristic devices such as thin film transistors (TFTs) and the like. A pulse is input to the printed electronic circuitry. The printed electronic circuitry divides the pulse across the various devices comprising the circuitry according to pulse amplitude and pulse width. The circuitry provides an output signal which is provided to a plurality of display elements, which are capable of indicating the division performed at the printed electronic circuitry. In one embodiment, each display element is an electrophoretic display which changes contrast as a function of the applied voltage. Not only the pulse amplitude and pulse width, but the number of pulses applied to the printed circuitry (i.e., sensed by the detector) may be indicated.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="153.25mm" wi="139.45mm" file="US08624753-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="191.26mm" wi="163.75mm" file="US08624753-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="208.03mm" wi="157.31mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624753-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="180.26mm" wi="130.13mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624753-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="209.89mm" wi="163.15mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624753-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="202.27mm" wi="160.36mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624753-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="202.86mm" wi="163.15mm" file="US08624753-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="117.60mm" wi="119.80mm" file="US08624753-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="221.23mm" wi="168.66mm" file="US08624753-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="152.15mm" wi="146.98mm" file="US08624753-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="182.12mm" wi="166.54mm" file="US08624753-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED FILINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present disclosure is related to and claims priority from U.S. patent application titled &#x201c;Method For Event Sensing Employing A Printed Event Sensor&#x201d;, Ser. No. 12/907,891, filed on the same filing date and assigned to the same assignee as the present application, and further which, in its entirety, is hereby incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure is related to sensing circuitry, and more specifically to an electronic device formed by printing in which a shock, inertial movement, pressure force, presence of light, chemicals, biologics, etc. results in generation of an electric pulse which is indicated on a dedicated display.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">There are today a relatively large number of different techniques for producing electronic devices. One family of such techniques, of interest herein, is commonly referred to as printed electronics. Various methods fall within the definition of printed electronics. Screen printing, traditional and digital lithography, flexography, gravure and jet-printing are a number of the more common of such methods. In each case, a material, conductive, semi-conductive or insulating, is deposited over a substrate to form interconnected passive and and/or active electronic components. Printing processes typically deposit materials in form of a solution, a slurry or in form of a powder. However, also transfer processes such as thermal transfer or laser transfer processes may be used to print structures. In a thermal transfer process, a layer such as a metal film may be transferred from a carrier substrate to another substrate. Known printed electronic processes can utilize a wide variety of materials for these components, and are not limited to organic materials.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Printed electronic processes take advantage of known, relatively simple printing techniques, and are thus typically less expensive and often less environmentally hazardous than traditional lithography and deposition techniques. Certain materials and processes used for printed electronics permit printing on non-crystalline substrates, such as paper, plastic, fabric, etc. Such processes may permit printing on flexible substrates, which is not easily done with conventional electronic device fabrication techniques. Furthermore, printing processes have been developed for non-planar surfaces, which is also a challenge for conventional electronic device fabrication techniques. However, in order to maintain a low cost and/or substrate flexibility, the components produced by printed electronic processes are relatively large, and the circuits relatively simple. For this reason, and others, printed event sensor devices are not generally available today.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">An event sensor, as used herein, is a device for detecting and indicating the occurrence, duration, and extent of an event or a series of events. Sensed events include acceleration, pressure force, exposure to light or other radiation, sound, and so forth. A relatively common event sensor is the accelerometer. Conventional accelerometers are typically based on mechanical or electromechanical components. For example, when a &#x201c;proof&#x201d; mass within the sensor is displaced, such as by acceleration or deceleration, often referred to as shock, that displacement is measured, and a signal issued in accordance therewith. More compact devices rely on strain gauges, in which current through a member is a function of the strain it experiences, micro-electro-mechanical (MEMs) devices, which are often very small proof masses, interleaved combs, and the like, and piezoelectric materials, in which strain results in generation of a charge within the material. The sensing signals issuing from these devices are commonly processed by additional electronic circuits for amplification, processing, display, and so on.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The applications for event sensors vary widely. However, a common requirement for many applications is low cost. There is a further common requirement for many applications that the sensor and even the display mechanism be flexible, for example permitting it to be applied over a non-planar structure, such as a medicine bottle, shipping package, etc. Still further, in some applications it is desirable to provide a sensor without a separate voltage source (e.g., without a battery).</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Present event sensors are not capable of meeting these requirements. The majority of known systems do not provide both a low cost sensor and a low cost display in a single circuit. Furthermore, most low cost shock sensing systems are configured to indicate whether a threshold level of shock has been exceeded. Still further, common shock sensing systems do not provide field replaceable elements such as display portions and the like. And common electronic shock sensors require a battery or similar separate voltage source.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Accordingly, the present disclosure is directed to systems for providing simple, low-cost sensors with displays. A device according to the present disclosure comprises a sensor and circuitry, connected thereto, produced by printed electronics processes. This circuitry may be comprised of fixed characteristic devices, such as a series resistive chain, or variable characteristic devices such as thin film transistors (TFTs) and the like. A pulse is input to the printed electronic circuitry. The printed electronic circuitry divides the pulse across the various devices comprising the circuitry according to pulse amplitude and pulse width. The circuitry provides an output signal which is provided to a plurality of display elements, which are capable of indicating the division performed at the printed electronic circuitry. In one embodiment, each display element is an electrophoretic display which changes contrast as a function of the applied voltage. Not only the pulse amplitude and pulse width, but the number of pulses applied to the printed circuitry (i.e., sensed by the detector) may be indicated. Accordingly, the sensor, circuitry, and display of the present disclosure also operates as an event counter, for example providing a visual indication of the cumulative number of events detected.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">One or more elements of the system may be fabricated by printed electronics processes. In one embodiment, the circuitry is fabricated by printed electronics processes. In another embodiment, the detector and circuitry are fabricated by printed electronics processes. In still another embodiment at least a portion of the display elements, the detector, and the circuitry are fabricated by printed electronics processes.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The display elements are driven by a display voltage which may be provided by a voltage source, modulated for example by the detector providing a pulse in response to a detected event. Alternatively, the voltage source and detector may be integrated together as one in the same element (such as a piezoelectric beam or the like), with the display voltage provided directly as a part of the pulse from a sensed event (such as physical strain due to acceleration, pressure or shock).</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Event detectors according to the present disclosure may be integrated into packaging (e.g., for determining whether a package has experienced shock above a certain threshold, such as when dropped, or when attached to the cap of a medicine package, to indicate whether the package has been tampered), applied to a body (e.g., for counting movement such as steps), part of a dedicated sensor apparatus (e.g., sensing the presence of a certain chemical or biological agent in a sample), etc.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Accordingly, an event sensor device is disclosed herein, comprising a pulse generator that responds to the detection of an event by generating a voltage pulse having a pulse amplitude and pulse width; a printed electronic circuit that receives said voltage pulse and generates, responsive to said pulse amplitude and said pulse width, a display driving signal; and a graduated-scale display responsive to said display driving signal which produces a display indicative of said detection of an event by way of said display driving signal. As an alternative to a display, the circuit may be configured such that the display driving signal is provided to other signal processing elements prior to display.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The above is a summary of a number of the unique aspects, features, and advantages of the present disclosure. However, this summary is not exhaustive. Thus, these and other aspects, features, and advantages of the present disclosure will become more apparent from the following detailed description and the appended drawings, when considered in light of the claims provided herein.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In the drawings appended hereto like reference numerals denote like elements between the various drawings. While illustrative, the drawings are not drawn to scale. In the drawings:</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic illustration of a pulse generator (event detector and voltage source) and display including a series resistive chain printed voltage dividing circuit according to one embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic illustration of a pulse generator (event detector and voltage source) and display including a variable characteristic printed voltage dividing circuit, where the variable characteristic is variable resistance, according to another embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> is a representative schematic illustration of a variable resistance voltage divider stage according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref> is an example of a circuit for realizing the variable resistance voltage divider stage according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic illustration of a pulse generator (event detector and voltage source) and display including a variable characteristic printed voltage dividing circuit, where the variable characteristic is variable capacitance, according to yet another embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a schematic illustration of a pulse generator (event detector and voltage source) and display including a variable characteristic printed voltage dividing circuit, where the variable characteristic is variable capacitance, according to still another embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a schematic illustration of an event detector, voltage source, and display including a variable characteristic printed voltage dividing circuit, where the variable characteristic is variable resistance, according to another embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is an example of a circuit for realizing the variable resistance voltage divider stage according to another embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a schematic illustration of a pulse generator (event detector and voltage source) and display including a variable characteristic printed voltage dividing circuit, where the variable characteristic is memristance, according to still another embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a microphotograph of a memristor circuit comprised of cross-bar junctions which may be employed in an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a graph of current against voltage for memristors with different dielectric thicknesses.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">We initially point out that descriptions of well known starting materials, processing techniques, components, equipment and other well known details are merely summarized or are omitted so as not to unnecessarily obscure the details of the present disclosure. Thus, where details are otherwise well known, we leave it to the application of the present disclosure to suggest or dictate choices relating to those details.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, there is shown an event sensor device <b>10</b> according an embodiment of the present disclosure. Event sensor device <b>10</b> comprises a detector <b>12</b> for detecting an occurrence of an event of interest. A wide variety of detectors for detecting a wide variety of events are contemplated by the present disclosure. For example, detector <b>12</b> may comprise a piezoelectric material formed and configured for detecting an inertial shock such as acceleration or deceleration. The piezoelectric material may be in the form of a deflecting membrane, and have associated therewith a proof mass to assist with such detection. The piezoelectric material may also be formed and configured for detecting pressure change, temperature change, and so on. Detector <b>12</b> may be a radiation sensor, such as for sensing light, for example which changes conductivity when radiation of a selected wavelength is incident thereon. Still further, detector <b>12</b> may be a material for detecting presence or absence of a chemical, molecule, compound or the like, for example which changes conductivity in the presence or absence of the chemical, molecule, compound or the like. It will be understood that the operation of detector <b>12</b>, and the event which it detects, does not form a limitation on the scope of the present disclosure or claims hereof.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In event sensor device <b>10</b>, detector <b>12</b> modulates the application of a voltage pulse provide by voltage source <b>14</b>, such as a battery. Together detector <b>12</b> and voltage source <b>14</b> form a pulse generator <b>16</b>. In certain embodiments, detector <b>12</b> and voltage source <b>14</b> are a single element, and in other embodiments detector <b>12</b> and voltage source <b>14</b> may be separate elements of pulse generator <b>16</b>. The voltage pulse provided will have a pulse amplitude (height) and pulse width which may depend on the magnitude and duration of the event detected.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The voltage pulse is provided to a printed voltage dividing circuit <b>18</b> responsive to the amplitude and width of the pulse. Printed voltage dividing circuit <b>18</b> in turn provides a driving signal for driving a processing circuit <b>20</b>, such as a graduated display. In the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, printed voltage dividing circuit <b>18</b> comprises a resistor chain comprised of a plurality of resistors <b>22</b><i>a</i>, <b>22</b><i>b</i>, <b>22</b><i>c</i>. It will be appreciated that a voltage dividing function can also be provided by other elements such as transistors, capacitors, diodes, etc. as will be appreciated by one skilled in the art. Elements <b>26</b><i>a</i>, <b>26</b><i>b</i>, <b>26</b><i>c </i>may each be of the same design and material, or one or more may be different. The resistors are arranged such that the chain provides ascending resistance. While three resistors <b>22</b><i>a</i>, <b>22</b><i>b</i>, <b>22</b><i>c </i>are shown and described to comprise printed voltage dividing circuit <b>18</b>, other numbers of resistors, such as two or more, may be provided. Furthermore, while resistors are shown in this example, a wide range of other elements may be assembled to form voltage dividing chains, as will be appreciated by one skilled in the art. Each resistor <b>22</b><i>a</i>, <b>22</b><i>b</i>, <b>22</b><i>c </i>is connected to a node <b>24</b><i>a</i>, <b>24</b><i>b</i>, <b>24</b><i>c</i>, respectively, at which a voltage pulse is provided. At node <b>24</b><i>a</i>, the pulse (amplitude and width) is that provided at the output of pulse generator <b>16</b>. At node <b>24</b><i>b </i>the amplitude of the pulse has been reduced by resistor <b>22</b><i>a</i>. At node <b>24</b><i>c </i>the amplitude of the pulse has been further reduced by the series combination of resistors <b>22</b><i>a </i>and <b>22</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Circuit <b>18</b> is preferably produced by way of a printed electronics process. We define &#x201c;printed electronic process&#x201d; for the purposes of this disclosure to exclude traditional photoresist-based process involving depositing, masking, exposing, etching, and further depositing (e.g., vacuum-based electronic fabrication techniques often referred to generally as photolithography). Examples of printed electronic process within the scope of this definition include screen-printing; traditional lithography; digital lithography; flexography; gravure; and inkjet-printing. In particular printed electronic processes may include additive deposition processes where all the layers of the circuit are patterned by selectively depositing materials where required without removing substantial amounts of other materials. Processes may include laser and heat transfer printing, nanoimprinting, pad printing, aerosol printing as well as continuous coating processes such as dip coating, spray coating, extrusion coating, slot coating, doctorblading and lamination. A printing process may include materials removal processes such as for trimming purposes or for patterning of via interconnects. Such processes may include laser ablation, die cutting or printing of solvents. Other processes not listed may also be within this definition. A circuit produced by a printed electronic process is referred to herein as a &#x201c;printed electronic circuit.&#x201d;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Printed voltage dividing circuit <b>18</b> is an example of such a printed electronic circuit. The precise variant of the printed electronics process is not a critical component in most embodiments of the present disclosure. Rather, the selected process must be consistent with the substrate on which the electronics are being formed (e.g., paper, plastic, fabric, etc.), be of low cost, and be able to produce a large quantity of devices. Likewise, the materials used by the process are not a critical component in most embodiments of the present disclosure. Rather, the selected materials must be consistent with the selected process, and again enable low cost, high volume production. In one example, circuit <b>18</b> is printed by screen printing a resistive ink such as carbon based Electrical Resistor Ink (product #104-18) from Creative Materials, Inc. of Tyngsboro, Mass. The resistive elements are then connected to each other and to other circuit elements by screen printing silver Electrically Conductive Ink (product #101-42) from Creative Materials, Inc.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Nodes <b>22</b><i>a</i>, <b>22</b><i>b</i>, <b>22</b><i>c </i>are connected to display elements <b>26</b><i>a</i>, <b>26</b><i>b</i>, <b>26</b><i>c</i>, respectively, of processing circuit <b>20</b>. In the case of electrostatic displays such as electrophoretic displays, display elements <b>26</b><i>a</i>, <b>26</b><i>b</i>, <b>26</b><i>c </i>are effectively capacitors able to provide an indication of the field applied thereto. In one embodiment, that indication is visual, such as a grayscale display. In other embodiments, the indication may be audible, thermal, haptic (tactile), etc. Display elements <b>26</b><i>a</i>, <b>26</b><i>b</i>, <b>26</b><i>c </i>may be produced in whole or in part by printed electronics processes. Elements <b>26</b><i>a</i>, <b>26</b><i>b</i>, <b>26</b><i>c </i>may each be of the same design and material, or one or more may be different. While three elements <b>26</b><i>a</i>, <b>26</b><i>b</i>, <b>26</b><i>c </i>are shown and described, other than three such elements can be provided (more than two), in count corresponding the number of resistors in circuit <b>18</b>, as described above. A greater number of such elements (and corresponding resistors) can, for example, provide a finer gradation between indicated sensed pulse levels.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, elements <b>26</b><i>a</i>, <b>26</b><i>b</i>, <b>26</b><i>c </i>are electrophoretic. These elements contain small, mobile particles that migrate in the presence of an electric field. The amount of particle movement, and hence the visible contrast or change in color or tone with the application an electric field, is a function of the duration and magnitude of the field. Thus, the greater the amplitude and/or width of the pulse at node <b>24</b><i>a</i>, <b>24</b><i>b</i>, <b>24</b><i>c</i>, the greater the visual contrast of the corresponding element <b>26</b><i>a</i>, <b>26</b><i>b</i>, <b>26</b><i>c</i>. As element <b>26</b><i>a </i>sees essentially the signal issued by pulse generator <b>16</b>, its contrast will change if the pulse height/width from pulse generator <b>16</b> are sufficiently large. Element <b>26</b><i>b </i>sees a smaller pulse height/width at node <b>24</b><i>b</i>, and hence will show visibly less contrast change than element <b>26</b><i>a </i>for a given pulse from pulse generator <b>16</b>. Likewise, element <b>26</b><i>c </i>sees an even smaller pulse height at node <b>24</b><i>c</i>, and hence will show still less visible contrast change than elements <b>26</b><i>a</i>, <b>26</b><i>b </i>for a given pulse from pulse generator <b>16</b>. By providing a calibration reference in association with the graduated display of processing circuit <b>20</b>, the number of elements <b>26</b><i>a</i>, <b>26</b><i>b</i>, <b>26</b><i>c </i>showing contrast change, and the extent of that change for each element can indicate the number of events that have been sensed. In one example, the bottom electrode pads for the electrophoretic elements <b>26</b><i>a</i>-<i>c </i>may be screen printed, e.g., with conductive silver ink. The electrophoretic medium, such as Vizplex film from E-ink Corporation, may be laminated onto the electrode. The top electrode of the electrophoretic film may be connected to printed lines on the substrate by electrically conductive adhesive such as b-stageable, electrically conductive epoxy adhesive (product #118-06) from Creative Materials, Inc.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">While electrophoretic display elements have been described above, other display types may similarly be employed. For example, liquid crystal, electrochromic, electrowetting, light emitting (e.g., organic LED), electrochemical, and other forms of displays may be used. In some of these cases, the voltage may operate switching circuits, such as thin film transistors (TFT) used to regulate the application of an appropriate driving current representative of the voltage at the various nodes <b>24</b><i>a</i>, <b>24</b><i>b</i>, <b>24</b><i>c. </i></p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Detector <b>12</b> may detect a number of individual events, which may result in a single cumulative pulse by way of an integrator or the like (not shown). Similarly, pulse generator <b>16</b> may provide a number of discrete voltage pulses modulated by detector <b>12</b>, and a single cumulative pulse provided by way of an integrator or the like. Alternatively, for certain electrophoretic display, the particle migration may be cumulative for the application of several sequential field applications. Thus, the &#x201c;number&#x201d; of pulses sensed and indicated may correspond to the degree of a sensed event, such as acceleration, or shock. The display can therefore provide an indication of the degree of shock to which the sensor has been subjected. When the sensor is applied to a shipping container, for example, the amount of shock that the container has been subjected to can be indicated. Or the number of times a package has been dropped can be indicated.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In the description of the embodiment above it has initially been assumed that printed voltage dividing circuit <b>18</b> is fabricated by an appropriate printed electronics process. While in certain embodiments only printed voltage dividing circuit <b>18</b> is fabricated by a printed electronics process, in other embodiments other elements of event sensor device <b>10</b> are also fabricated by a printed electronics process. For example, portions or all of pulse generator <b>16</b> may be formed in the same process used to form printed voltage dividing circuit <b>18</b>. Furthermore, portions or all of processing circuit <b>20</b> may similarly be fabricated by a printed electronics process. In one embodiment of a method for fabricating event sensor device <b>10</b>, all elements of the circuit are fabricated by a single, common printed electronics process in order to simplify manufacturing and reduce cost.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Furthermore, in the description of the embodiment above pulse generator <b>16</b> was described as comprised of a separate detector <b>12</b> and voltage source <b>14</b>. However, according to an embodiment of the present disclosure, pulse generator <b>16</b> may be comprised of a single, combined detector <b>12</b> and voltage source <b>14</b>. Unlike the embodiment in which detector <b>12</b> serves as a switch or modulator for a voltage supplied by voltage source <b>14</b>, a single element produces a pulse which can be output from pulse generator <b>16</b>. For example, pulse generator <b>16</b> may be a piezoelectric material that generates a voltage in response to physical strain within its structure. An example of a material that may be employed in this embodiment is piezoelectric (or pyroelectric) polyvinylidene fluoride (PVDF). The PVDF may be a film, with or without a proof mass. When strained (e.g., by deflection), polarized PVDF will produce a net charge. That charge may appear as a pulse at nodes <b>24</b><i>a</i>, <b>24</b><i>b</i>, <b>24</b><i>c </i>which may be displayed via the graduated display described above. In this way, no separate voltage is required&#x2014;the detector itself provides the pulse for sensing.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The PVDF film may be laminated to the substrate. The PVDF film may previously have been metalized on both sides such as the PVDF films available from Measurement Specialties, Inc. In this case, the bottom electrode of the PVDF film may be bonded onto a printed electrode pad on the substrate with conductive epoxy ink. The connection to the top electrode of the PVDF material may be made by printing a conductive line between the top electrode and the connecting circuit. Alternatively, a PVDF copolymer such as PVDF-TrFE(trifluoroethylene) may be used. PVDF copolymers can be deposited from a solution and therefore are printable. Similar to PVDF, they need to be polarized by corona charging or electrical poling by directly applying a voltage in order to give them piezoelectric properties. In either case, the bottom and top electrodes of the piezoelectric material may be printed, e.g. screen printed. Of course, other known piezoelectric materials may also be used.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">PVDF may also be used in appropriate embodiments to provide single-element temperature sensing in a manner similar to that described above. Other known pyroelectric materials may also be employed. Known optoelectric materials such as a blend of organic n- and p-type semiconductors, such as Phenyl-C61-buryric acid methyl ester (PCBM, a bucky ball derivative) and poly(3-hexylthiophene), respectively can provide similar functionality when sensing optical radiation. Magnetoelectric structures, such as a printed spiral inductor coil, may also provide similar functionality for sensing the presence or absence of a magnetic field. The coil will generate a voltage pulse when a magnetic material is swiped past it. A magnetic core may be attached to the coil in order to increase the inductance of the coil. Bioelectric (e.g., changing conductivity in the presence of a selected biological agent) and chemoelectric (e.g., changing conductivity in the presence of a selected chemical element or compound agent) materials can further provide similar functionality. Piezoresistive materials such as elastomers with embedded conducting particles in which the percolation path changes upon pressure may be used to sense pressure. Combinations of these difference-sensing materials may also form embodiments of event sensor device <b>10</b> as contemplated by the present disclosure. While not shown, it is contemplated that the output of pulse generator <b>16</b> may also be amplified or otherwise processed prior to application to circuit <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">A number of additional circuit designs are possible given the basic concepts presented above. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates one such additional circuit design <b>30</b> in which each voltage pulse causes a change in an electronic component. Circuit <b>30</b> comprises a plurality of input nodes <b>32</b><i>a</i>, <b>32</b><i>b</i>, <b>32</b><i>c </i>each communicatively connected to receive a pulse from pulse generator <b>16</b>. Nodes <b>32</b><i>a</i>, <b>32</b><i>b</i>, <b>32</b><i>c </i>are each communicatively connected to a printed voltage dividing circuit <b>28</b>, which itself comprises a plurality of variable characteristic devices which are in this embodiment voltage divider stages <b>34</b><i>a</i>, <b>34</b><i>b</i>, <b>34</b><i>c</i>, respectively, described further below. Each voltage divider stage <b>34</b><i>a</i>, <b>34</b><i>b</i>, <b>34</b><i>c </i>is communicatively connected to an output node <b>36</b><i>a</i>, <b>36</b><i>b</i>, <b>36</b><i>c</i>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> is a representative schematic illustration of a variable resistance voltage divider stage. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref> is an example of a circuit for realizing the variable resistance voltage divider stage. With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, a sample voltage divider stage <b>34</b><i>a </i>is illustrated (voltage divider stages <b>34</b><i>b</i>, <b>34</b><i>c </i>may be of similar design, or one or more may differ from the others). Voltage divider stage <b>34</b><i>a </i>comprises a threshold resistor R<sub>a</sub>, a transistor element T<sub>a</sub>, and a reference resistor R<sub>L</sub>. In operation, the electric field associated with the voltage pulse from pulse generator <b>16</b> causes a threshold voltage shift in the transistor, making the channel of the transistor more resistive or more conductive. (Threshold voltage shift of the transistor may be caused by various effects such as ion movement, charge trapping or charge injection.) The amount of threshold voltage shift (and the direction) due to a pulse may be varied by choice of semiconductor materials, by varying the material for the gate dielectric or by adjusting the thickness of the gate dielectric. The more pulses transistor T<sub>a </sub>sees, the greater the change of its conductivity. This change will then alter the voltage at nodes <b>36</b><i>a</i>, <b>36</b><i>b</i>, <b>36</b><i>c</i>, and ultimately at display elements <b>26</b><i>a</i>, <b>26</b><i>b</i>, <b>26</b><i>c</i>. While the variable characteristic devices are described above as based on the channel conductivity of a TFT, other types of variable characteristic devices are within the scope of this disclosure, as discussed further below.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Returning to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the voltage pulse from pulse generator <b>16</b> is seen by the series of voltage divider stages <b>34</b><i>a</i>, <b>34</b><i>b</i>, <b>34</b><i>c</i>. These voltage dividers may represent a high impedance input for the signal. The voltage pulse is divided across voltage divider stages <b>34</b><i>a</i>, <b>34</b><i>b</i>, <b>34</b><i>c </i>according to their resistance values. The resistance in the voltage dividers increases or decreases when a voltage pulse is applied&#x2014;the degree of change is different for each of voltage divider stages <b>34</b><i>a</i>, <b>34</b><i>b</i>, <b>34</b><i>c </i>based on the values of R<sub>a</sub>, R<sub>b</sub>, and R<sub>c </sub>(<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>). In this example, the resistance of voltage divider stage <b>34</b><i>a </i>may change slowest (requiring a relatively large number of pulses, pulse amplitude, and/or pulse width) and that of voltage divider stage <b>34</b><i>c </i>may change the fastest (requiring the least number of pulses, pulse amplitude, and/or pulse width). The attached display elements may then change contrast, for example, to a greater degree with increasing voltage. It should be noted that a grayscale can be achieved from display elements <b>26</b><i>a</i>, <b>26</b><i>b</i>, <b>26</b><i>c </i>by providing voltage dividers <b>34</b><i>a</i>, <b>34</b><i>b</i>, <b>34</b><i>c </i>with fixed values of decreasing ratio from <b>34</b><i>a </i>to <b>34</b><i>b </i>to <b>34</b><i>c</i>. In this case, the display element that experiences the lower voltage levels requires more pulses to change, e.g., from black to white. However, if the ratio of the voltage dividers <b>34</b><i>a</i>, <b>34</b><i>b</i>, <b>34</b><i>c </i>changes with the number of pulses, the voltage level of the pulses seen by the display elements may initially be below a threshold and gradually the voltage level becomes higher, exceeding that threshold. If the display elements <b>26</b><i>a</i>, <b>26</b><i>b</i>, <b>26</b><i>c </i>have a switching threshold (a minimum required voltage to cause any change at all) then the variable nature of elements <b>34</b> can cause the voltage pulse on the display to increase from below threshold to above threshold. This non-linearity is useful for displaying the number of events or the extent of an event more accurately. When the display elements <b>26</b><i>a</i>, <b>26</b><i>b</i>, <b>26</b><i>c </i>are electrophoretic, the above-described display of the relative level of node voltages is provided, which may be calibrated against a reference to indicate the number of events (or extent of an event) detected.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">While <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a circuit based on a variable resistance circuit, other circuit elements may also or alternatively be employed. For example, TFT T<sub>a </sub>may be replaced by a capacitor such that a change in its properties (e.g., change in capacitance, breakdown voltage, etc.) results in voltage at nodes <b>36</b><i>a</i>, <b>36</b><i>b</i>, <b>36</b><i>c</i>. Other changes in properties by alternative devices may also be employed.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates another additional circuit design <b>40</b> in which each voltage pulse causes a change in an electronic component. Circuit <b>40</b> comprises a printed voltage dividing circuit <b>38</b>, which itself comprises a plurality of variable characteristic devices, which in this embodiment are variable capacitance circuits <b>42</b><i>a</i>, <b>42</b><i>b</i>, <b>42</b><i>c </i>each communicatively connected via nodes <b>32</b><i>a</i>, <b>32</b><i>b</i>, <b>32</b><i>c </i>to receive a pulse from pulse generator <b>16</b>. Each variable capacitance circuit <b>42</b><i>a</i>, <b>42</b><i>b</i>, <b>42</b><i>c </i>is communicatively connected to an output node <b>36</b><i>a</i>, <b>36</b><i>b</i>, <b>36</b><i>c</i>, respectively. The capacitance of each variable capacitance circuits <b>42</b><i>a</i>, <b>42</b><i>b</i>, <b>42</b><i>c </i>changes (e.g., due to ion movement within the capacitor caused by an applied electric field) with the pulse amplitude, pulse width, and number of pulses from pulse generator <b>16</b> such that the RC constant of each of the variable capacitance circuits changes. Thus, with decreasing capacitance as between variable capacitance circuits <b>42</b><i>a</i>, <b>42</b><i>b</i>, <b>42</b><i>c</i>, the voltage level on the display elements to which each variable capacitance circuit is connected increases. The attached display elements may then change contrast, for example, to a greater degree with increasing voltage. When the display elements <b>26</b><i>a</i>, <b>26</b><i>b</i>, <b>26</b><i>c </i>are electrophoretic, the above-described display of the relative level of node voltages is provided, which may be calibrated against a reference to indicate the number of events (or extend of an event) detected. The capacitors may be printed by printing the electrodes using metal ink such as ink made of silver nanoparticles. The dielectric layer between the capacitor plates may be a polymer such as PVA (polyvinylalcohol) and it may be also printed (e.g., using inkjet or flexographic printing).</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates yet another circuit design <b>50</b> in which each voltage pulse causes a change in an electronic component. Circuit <b>50</b> comprises a printed voltage dividing circuit <b>48</b>, which itself comprises plurality of variable characteristic devices, which in this embodiment are plurality of variable capacitance circuits <b>52</b><i>a</i>, <b>52</b><i>b</i>, <b>52</b><i>c </i>each communicatively connected via nodes <b>32</b><i>a</i>, <b>32</b><i>b</i>, <b>32</b><i>c </i>to receive a pulse from pulse generator <b>16</b>. Each variable capacitance circuits <b>52</b><i>a</i>, <b>52</b><i>b</i>, <b>52</b><i>c </i>is communicatively connected to an output node <b>36</b><i>a</i>, <b>36</b><i>b</i>, <b>36</b><i>c</i>, respectively. In this embodiment, resistors such as <b>44</b><i>a</i>, <b>44</b><i>b</i>, <b>44</b><i>c </i>of the circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> are replaced with capacitors such as <b>54</b><i>a</i>, <b>54</b><i>b</i>, <b>54</b><i>c</i>. Again, the capacitance of each variable capacitance circuit <b>52</b><i>a</i>, <b>52</b><i>b</i>, <b>52</b><i>c </i>changes with the pulse amplitude, pulse width, and number of pulses from pulse generator <b>16</b>. Display elements <b>26</b><i>a</i>, <b>26</b><i>b</i>, <b>26</b><i>c </i>may change contrast, for example, to a greater degree with increasing voltage at nodes <b>36</b><i>a</i>, <b>36</b><i>b</i>, <b>36</b><i>c</i>. This contrast level may be calibrated against a reference to indicate the number of events (or extent of an event) detected.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In certain embodiments it may be desirable to operate the printed circuitry driving the display by way of a display voltage, switched by a separate sensor. Such a circuit <b>60</b> is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. According to this embodiment, voltage source <b>14</b> is connected through switch <b>70</b> to provide a display voltage to each of input nodes <b>62</b><i>a</i>, <b>62</b><i>b</i>, <b>62</b><i>c</i>. Voltage source <b>14</b> may be a battery, an AC supply source, a piezo element, etc. Printed voltage dividing circuit <b>58</b> comprises a plurality of variable characteristic devices, which in this embodiment are a plurality of variable resistance voltage dividers <b>64</b><i>a</i>, <b>64</b><i>b</i>, <b>64</b><i>c </i>provided between input nodes <b>62</b><i>a</i>, <b>62</b><i>b</i>, <b>62</b><i>c </i>and output nodes <b>66</b><i>a</i>, <b>66</b><i>b</i>, <b>66</b><i>c</i>. A voltage pulse is provided by detector <b>12</b> to each of divider nodes <b>64</b><i>a</i>, <b>64</b><i>b</i>, <b>64</b><i>c</i>, which controls the voltage from voltage source <b>14</b> flowing to display elements <b>26</b><i>a</i>, <b>26</b><i>b</i>, <b>26</b><i>c. </i></p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, an example of a specific variable resistance voltage divider is shown. In this embodiment, a voltage pulse provided at divider node <b>72</b><i>a </i>controls the conductivity of the channel of TFT T<sub>a</sub>. This conductivity controls the current between input node <b>62</b><i>a </i>and ground, which in turn controls the voltage at node <b>66</b><i>a </i>that may be presented to a display element (not shown). Returning to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, each of the variable resistance voltage dividers <b>64</b><i>a</i>, <b>64</b><i>b</i>, <b>64</b><i>c </i>may be of a similar construction to that illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, with the values of R<sub>L </sub>and/or R<sub>a </sub>adjusted such that each divider <b>64</b><i>a</i>, <b>64</b><i>b</i>, <b>64</b><i>c </i>requires a successively higher voltage pulse (greater pulse amplitude, pulse width, and/or number of pulses) in order to provide a certain voltage at nodes <b>66</b><i>a</i>, <b>66</b><i>b</i>, <b>66</b><i>c</i>, respectively. This arrangement of separate detector <b>12</b> and voltage source <b>14</b> permits the display driving voltage to be lower than the sensor pulse voltage, or vice-versa. In one example, the low drive voltage may be sufficient to drive a display such as an OLED display, an electrochemical display or electrochromic display and the drive voltage can be applied for a relatively long time. The simple pulse drive described earlier requires a bistable display medium such as an electrophoretic display medium. Non-bistable displays such as many liquid crystal displays, OLED displays or electrochromic displays require an applied voltage for the display state to be maintained (i.e., during the time when a message is displayed). Also, some of these displays require relatively high currents (current driven displays). In such a case, the simple pulse may not be sufficient. The separate power source <b>14</b> may be able to provide sufficient current to drive a display, such as an OLED display, and the message may be read out as long as the switch <b>70</b> is closed. An additional benefit of this concept may be that the message or display pattern can be read out only when desired, but it may otherwise be invisible, such as beforehand during the recording time. This may be of advantage for keeping the information secure. In a specific example, power source <b>14</b> may be a printed battery such as a printed Zinc Manganese battery. Power source <b>14</b> may also consist of an inductor coil with rectifier and the power may be supplied by electromagnetic induction. In particular, the coil and or the rectifier may be printed. The switch <b>70</b> may also be printed and may consist of a conductive carbon layer which is brought into press contact with two conductive traces on the substrate, thereby establishing electrical connection between the traces.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">As an alternative to the above-described embodiment, one or more of the dividers <b>64</b><i>a</i>, <b>64</b><i>b</i>, <b>64</b><i>c </i>may be of a different construction, but provide the same stepped increase in required pulse voltage from detector <b>12</b> to produce a set display element response. For example, in place of TFT Ta, a variable capacitance or resistance can be employed, with the separate voltage source and sensor circuit described above. Accordingly, an event sensor device is provided such that, for example, a grayscale indication at display elements <b>26</b><i>a</i>, <b>26</b><i>b</i>, <b>26</b><i>c </i>can be compared to a calibrated reference and a quantitative indication of event level, e.g., magnitude of shock, can be obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> illustrates yet another circuit <b>70</b> in which each voltage pulse causes a change in an electronic component. Circuit <b>70</b> comprises a printed voltage dividing circuit <b>72</b>, which itself comprises plurality of variable characteristic devices, which in this embodiment are memristive circuits <b>74</b><i>a</i>, <b>74</b><i>b</i>, <b>74</b><i>c </i>each communicatively connected via nodes <b>76</b><i>a</i>, <b>76</b><i>b</i>, <b>76</b><i>c </i>to receive a pulse from pulse generator <b>16</b>. Each memristive circuit <b>74</b><i>a</i>, <b>74</b><i>b</i>, <b>74</b><i>c </i>is communicatively connected to an output node <b>78</b><i>a</i>, <b>78</b><i>b</i>, <b>78</b><i>c</i>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Each memristive circuit <b>74</b><i>a</i>, <b>74</b><i>b</i>, <b>74</b><i>c </i>comprises one or more memristive devices connected to a fixed reference resistance. For example, memristive circuit <b>74</b><i>a </i>comprises a fixed reference resistance <b>80</b><i>a </i>and a single memristor <b>82</b><i>a</i>. Memristive circuits <b>74</b><i>a</i>, <b>74</b><i>b</i>, <b>74</b><i>c </i>present an increasing resistance to a pulse from pulse generator <b>16</b>. Thus, memristive circuit <b>74</b><i>b </i>comprises a fixed reference resistance <b>80</b><i>b </i>and memristors <b>82</b><i>b</i>, <b>84</b><i>b</i>, and memristive circuit <b>74</b><i>c </i>comprises a fixed reference resistance <b>80</b><i>c </i>and memristors <b>82</b><i>c</i>, <b>84</b><i>c</i>, <b>86</b><i>c</i>. Typically, the reference resistances will be equal (i.e., <b>80</b><i>a</i>=<b>80</b><i>b</i>=<b>80</b><i>c</i>), but such need not necessarily be the case. A three stage printed voltage dividing circuit <b>72</b> is shown, although a different number of stages may also be employed depending on the applications of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The resistance M(q) of a memristor is dependent on past input charge with the relationship I*M(q)=V, where I is current and V is voltage. In one embodiment, memristors are simple cross-bar junctions, illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, with a dielectric layer sandwiched between metal electrodes. In one embodiment, the dielectric layer is solution-processed titanium dioxide and the metal is printed from silver (Ag) solution. The thickness of the memristor layer, the area of the cross-bar junctions, and the number of memristors can be adjusted, to allow designing for a wide range of dector characteristics (e.g., sensitivity, threshold, etc.) needed for different applications. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a graph of current against voltage for memristors with different dielectric thicknesses.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Returning to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, as a pulse passes through a memristor, its resistance decreases due to charge movement. This change remains when the pulse is removed (hence, memresistance). As another pulse passes through the memristor, its resistance may decrease further. In the memristive voltage dividing circuit <b>72</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, if a pulse at nodes <b>76</b><i>a</i>, <b>76</b><i>b</i>, <b>76</b><i>c </i>is of sufficient pulse amplitude or pulse width, memristive circuits <b>74</b><i>a</i>, <b>74</b><i>b</i>, <b>74</b><i>c </i>may present a voltage at nodes <b>78</b><i>a</i>, <b>78</b><i>b</i>, <b>78</b><i>c </i>dependent on the resistance of each memristive circuit <b>74</b><i>a</i>, <b>74</b><i>b</i>, <b>74</b><i>c</i>. By providing additional memristors from stage to stage (e.g., one memristor at memristive circuit <b>74</b><i>a</i>, two memristors at memristive circuit <b>74</b><i>b</i>, and three memristors at memristive circuit <b>74</b><i>c</i>), for a pulse having a given pulse amplitude and pulse width the voltage presented at nodes <b>78</b><i>a</i>, <b>78</b><i>b</i>, <b>78</b><i>c </i>decreases from nodes <b>78</b><i>a </i>to <b>78</b><i>b</i>, and from nodes <b>78</b><i>b </i>to <b>78</b><i>c</i>. The attached display elements <b>26</b><i>a</i>, <b>26</b><i>b</i>, <b>26</b><i>c </i>may then change contrast, for example, to a greater degree with increasing voltage as between nodes <b>78</b><i>a</i>, <b>78</b><i>b</i>, <b>78</b><i>c</i>. When the display elements <b>26</b><i>a</i>, <b>26</b><i>b</i>, <b>26</b><i>c </i>are electrophoretic, the above-described display of the relative level of node voltages is provided, which may be calibrated against a reference to indicate the number of events (or extend of an event) detected.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> and described above can be generalized to a threshold detection circuit. The conductance of the memristive circuit &#x201c;jumps&#x201d; up when a sufficient input flux has been reached. Changes to the memristance can be obtained by accumulating pulses or by spending a certain time period at a fixed voltage, such as when used in a timer application. Such applications rely on the non-linear rise in memristor conductance, and the increase in current may be on the order of 100-times after even relatively short voltage application times. The required switching time can be adjusted by varying the applied voltage, the memristor dielectric thickness, or the number of junctions placed in series.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The physics of modern electrical devices and the methods of their production are not absolutes, but rather statistical efforts to produce a desired device and/or result. Even with the utmost of attention being paid to repeatability of processes, variations and imperfections result. Accordingly, no limitation in the description of the present disclosure or its claims can or should be read as absolute. Each of the above examples are provided to illustrate various facets of the present disclosure. The limitations of the claims, not the examples in this description section, are intended to define the boundaries of the present disclosure, up to and including those limitations. To further highlight this, the term &#x201c;substantially&#x201d; may occasionally be used herein in association with a claim limitation (although consideration for variations and imperfections is not restricted to only those limitations used with that term). While as difficult to precisely define as the limitations of the present disclosure themselves, we intend that this term be interpreted as &#x201c;to a large extent&#x201d;, &#x201c;as nearly as practicable&#x201d;, &#x201c;within technical limitations&#x201d;, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Furthermore, while a plurality of preferred exemplary embodiments have been presented in the foregoing detailed description, it should be understood that a vast number of variations exist, and these preferred exemplary embodiments are merely representative examples, and are not intended to limit the scope, applicability or configuration of the disclosure in any way. For example, the output of the voltage dividing circuits described herein may be to processing elements, as opposed to display element as shown, for various forms of signal processing. Various of the above-disclosed and other features and functions, or alternative thereof, may be desirably combined into many other different systems or applications. Various presently unforeseen or unanticipated alternatives, modifications variations, or improvements therein or thereon may be subsequently made by those skilled in the art which are also intended to be encompassed by the claims, below.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Therefore, the foregoing description provides those of ordinary skill in the art with a convenient guide for implementation of the disclosure, and contemplates that various changes in the functions and arrangements of the described embodiments may be made without departing from the spirit and scope of the disclosure defined by the claims thereto.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An event sensor device, comprising:
<claim-text>a pulse generator that responds to detection of an event by generating a voltage pulse having a pulse amplitude and pulse width;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a printed voltage dividing circuit that receives said voltage pulse and generates, responsive to said pulse amplitude and said pulse width, a display driving signal, said printed voltage dividing circuit comprising a plurality of individual threshold devices; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a graduated-scale display responsive to said display driving signal which produces an indication of said detection of an event by way of said display driving signal, said graduated-scale display comprising a plurality of individually addressable display elements;</claim-text>
<claim-text>each said threshold device connected to a unique one of said individually addressable display elements for driving said connected individually addressable display element in response to said detection of an event by way of said display driving signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The event sensor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said pulse generator comprises an integrated detector and voltage source.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The event sensor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein said pulse generator comprises a structure selected from group consisting of: piezoelectric structures, pyroelectric structures, optoelectric structures, magnetoelectric structures, bioelectric structures, and chemoelectric structures.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The event sensor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein said pulse generator is formed by a printed electronic process and comprises a portion of said printed voltage dividing circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The event sensor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said pulse generator comprises a separate event detector and a voltage source.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The event sensor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein said event detector comprises a structure selected from group consisting of: piezoelectric structures, pyroelectric structures, optoelectric structures, magnetoelectric structures, bioelectric structures, and chemoelectric structures.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The event sensor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein said event detector is formed by a printed electronic process and comprises a portion of said printed voltage dividing circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The event sensor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said plurality of individually addressable visual display elements comprise a grey-scale display.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The event sensor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each said individual threshold device comprises a printed electronic resistive device, and further wherein each said printed electronic resistive device is connected together in series to said pulse generator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The event sensor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each said individual threshold device comprises a printed electronic variable resistive circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The event sensor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each said individual threshold device comprises a printed electronic variable capacitance circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The event sensor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each said individual threshold device comprises a printed thin-film transistor (TFT) circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The event sensor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each said individual threshold device comprises:
<claim-text>a variable characteristic device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said variable characteristic device connected in parallel with the variable characteristic device of each other individual threshold device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said pulse generator is connected to each said threshold device such that a single pulse issued by said pulse generator changes the variable characteristic of at least two of said of connected variable characteristic devices by a different amount.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The event sensor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein said variable characteristic device is selected from the group comprising: a printed thin film transistor voltage dividing circuit, a printed variable resistance voltage dividing circuit, a printed variable capacitance voltage dividing circuit, and a printed variable memristive voltage dividing circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The event sensor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein said pulse generator comprises a separate event detector and a voltage source.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The event sensor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein a voltage from said voltage source is provided at a first node connected to one of said display elements, and a voltage pulse is provided by said event detector at a second node connected to said variable characteristic device such that said voltage pulse changes the variable characteristic of said variable characteristic device and thereby modulates the voltage provided by said voltage source to said display element connected to said first node.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. An event sensor device, comprising:
<claim-text>a pulse generator comprising:
<claim-text>a printed detector; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a voltage source that responds to the detection of an event by generating a voltage pulse having a pulse amplitude and pulse width;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a printed voltage dividing circuit comprising a plurality of individual threshold devices that receive said voltage pulse and generate, responsive to said pulse amplitude and said pulse width, a display driving signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a graduated-scale display comprising a plurality of individually addressable display elements, each said individually addressable display element connected to a unique one of said threshold devices, each said individually addressable display element further responsive to said display driving signal to produce a visual display indicative of said detection of an event by way of said display driving signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The event sensor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein said detector comprises a structure selected from group consisting of: piezoelectric structures, pyroelectric structures, optoelectric structures, magnetoelectric structures, bioelectric structures, and chemoelectric structures.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The event sensor device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>each said individual threshold device comprises:
<claim-text>a variable characteristic device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said variable characteristic device connected in parallel with the variable characteristic device of each other individual threshold device; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>said pulse generator is connected to each said threshold device such that a single pulse issued by said pulse generator changes the variable characteristic of at least two of said of connected variable characteristic devices by a different amount;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said pulse generator comprises a separate event detector and a voltage source; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a voltage from said voltage source is provided at a first node connected to one of said display elements, and a voltage pulse is provided by said event detector at a second node connected to said variable characteristic device such that said voltage pulse changes the variable characteristic of said variable characteristic device and thereby modulates the voltage provided by said voltage source to said display element connected to said first node.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. A printed electronic event sensor device, comprising:
<claim-text>a pulse generator comprising a printed piezoelectric detector that responds to physical strain by generating a voltage pulse having a pulse amplitude and pulse width;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a printed voltage dividing circuit comprising a plurality of individual printed electronic resistors connected in series to said pulse generator to thereby receive said voltage pulse and generate, responsive to said pulse amplitude and said pulse width, a display driving signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a printed electronic graduated-scale display comprising a plurality of individually addressable display elements, each said individually addressable display element connected to a unique one of said printed electronic resistors, each said individually addressable display element further responsive to said display driving signal to produce a visual display indicative of detection of said physical strain.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
