<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622767-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622767</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13540921</doc-number>
<date>20120703</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2011-149008</doc-number>
<date>20110705</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>1</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>62</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439499</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Connector</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4712848</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Edgley</name>
<date>19871200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439327</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6089905</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Shimmyo et al.</name>
<date>20000700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439495</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7044773</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Suzuki et al.</name>
<date>20060500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439495</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7494366</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Suzuki et al.</name>
<date>20090200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439495</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8292648</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kiryu et al.</name>
<date>20121000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439328</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>09161895</doc-number>
<date>19970600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2008053246</doc-number>
<date>20080300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2009070758</doc-number>
<date>20090400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2009266457</doc-number>
<date>20091100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>8</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439260</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439325</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439327</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439328</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439495</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439499</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439630</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>17</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130012071</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130110</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nakazura</last-name>
<first-name>Kazumi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kanagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Satoh</last-name>
<first-name>Tomoyuki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kanagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nakazura</last-name>
<first-name>Kazumi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kanagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Satoh</last-name>
<first-name>Tomoyuki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kanagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>McCornick, Paulding &#x26; Huber, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Kyocera Connector Products Corporation</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Kanagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Nguyen</last-name>
<first-name>Khiem</first-name>
<department>2833</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A connector includes an insulator, into which a thin plate-like object is removably insertable, including contact insertion grooves and partition walls positioned therebetween and contacts inserted into the contact insertion grooves, each of the contacts including first and second contact portions spaced from each other to allow the thin plate-like object to be inserted therebetween, and including a connecting portion connecting the first and second contact portions. At least one of the first and second contact portions contacts the thin plate-like object when inserted into the insulator. A hollow portion having a greater width than the contact insertion grooves is formed in each partition wall to superimpose part of each contact as viewed in a contact arranging direction, and the partition walls prevent each hollow portion from being communicatively connected with the contact insertion grooves.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="94.49mm" wi="153.92mm" file="US08622767-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="235.63mm" wi="144.27mm" file="US08622767-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="249.60mm" wi="128.02mm" file="US08622767-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="252.14mm" wi="134.03mm" file="US08622767-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="243.33mm" wi="107.61mm" file="US08622767-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="151.38mm" wi="141.90mm" file="US08622767-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="204.72mm" wi="155.45mm" file="US08622767-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="246.38mm" wi="184.32mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622767-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="191.35mm" wi="172.72mm" file="US08622767-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention is related to and claims priority of the following co-pending application, namely, Japanese Patent Application No. 2011-149008 filed on Jul. 5, 2011.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to a connector to which a thin plate-like connecting object such as an FPC or FFC, etc., is to be connected.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">A connector via which a circuit board (rigid board) and a thin plate-like (thin sheet or thin plate) connecting object (e.g., an FPC or FFC, etc.) are electrically connected is usually provided with an insulator and a plurality of contacts. The insulator is provided with a groove into which the connecting object is insertable, and from which the connecting object is removable, and a plurality of contact insertion grooves which are elongated in the connecting object insertion/removal direction and arranged in a direction orthogonal to the connecting object insertion/removal direction, and the plurality of contacts are inserted into the plurality of contact insertion grooves of the insulator, respectively. The plurality of contacts are connected to conductor traces of a circuit pattern formed on a surface of the circuit board. Upon the connecting object being inserted into the aforementioned groove of the insulator, the connecting object comes into contact with each of the aforementioned plurality of contacts, so that the circuit board and the connecting object are electrically connected to each other via the plurality of contacts.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Such a conventional connector is disclosed in Japanese Patent Publication No. 4,413,961.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">To improve the high frequency property of an electrical signal fed to this type of connector (the contacts thereof), it is required to make the impedance (value) of the connector as close to the impedance (value) of the circuit board and the connecting object as possible.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">However, the insulator is provided with partition walls which are formed between the plurality of contact insertion grooves so that each partition wall separates the adjacent contact insertion grooves from each other, and the relative permittivity of the synthetic resin which forms the insulator is usually high (e.g., approximately three to four). Accordingly, such a conventional type of connector has a structure in which the coupling capacitance between adjacent contacts easily increases, and the impedance (value) of the connector tends to decrease largely as compared with the impedance (value) of the circuit board and the connecting object.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The present invention provides a connector in which a plurality of contacts are arranged on an insulator and supported thereby, and which is configured to be capable of improving the high frequency property of the connector.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to an aspect of the present invention, a connector is provided, including an insulator, into which a thin plate-like object to be connected to the connector is removably insertable, including a plurality of contact insertion grooves and a plurality of partition walls that are positioned between the contact insertion grooves to separate the contact insertion grooves from one another, the contact insertion grooves being elongated in an insertion/removal direction of the thin plate-like object and arranged in a direction orthogonal to the insertion/removal direction; and a plurality of contacts which are inserted into the contact insertion grooves, respectively, each of the contacts including a first contact portion and a second contact portion that are spaced from each other in a direction of thickness of the thin plate-like object to allow the thin plate-like object to be inserted in between the first contact portion and the second contact portion, and further including a connecting portion which connects the first contact portion and the second contact portion to each other, wherein at least one of the first contact portion and the second contact portion comes in contact with the thin plate-like object when the thin plate-like object is inserted into the insulator. A hollow portion having a greater width than each of the contact insertion grooves is formed in each of the partition walls of the insulator in a manner such that the hollow portion superimposes part of each contact of the contacts as viewed in a contact arranging direction in which the contacts are arranged, and in a manner such that each of the plurality of partition walls prevents each corresponding the hollow portion from being communicatively connected with the contact insertion grooves in the contact arranging direction.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">It is desirable for the hollow portion to be greater in dimension in the direction of thickness of the thin plate-like object than each of the contact insertion grooves.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">It is desirable for the hollow portion to be formed in the insulator so as to superimpose part of the connecting portions of the plurality of contacts as viewed in the contact arranging direction.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">It is desirable for the first contact portion to be fixed to a bottom wall of the insulator, and for the hollow portion to be formed in the insulator so as to superimpose both the first contact portion and a portion of the second contact portion extending from the connecting portion and along the second contact portion the insertion/removal direction as viewed from a lateral side of the insulator.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">It is desirable for a recess to be formed on a surface of the first contact portion which faces the bottom wall of the insulator.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">It is desirable for the hollow portion to be formed in the insulator so as to superimpose the recess as viewed in the contact arranging direction.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">It is desirable for the thin plate-like object to include an FPC including at least one circuit trace which extends along an elongated direction of the thin plate-like object; and an insulating cover layer which covers both sides of the FPC except both ends of the circuit trace. The circuit trace includes a land which is positioned outside the insulating cover layer and comes into contact with at least one of the first contact portion and the second contact portion, an end of the land adjacent to an edge of the insulating cover layer being formed to decrease in width gradually in a direction toward the edge of the insulating cover layer; and a connecting portion which is smaller in width than the land, except the end of the land, and extends linearly from the end of the land to the edge of the insulating cover layer.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">It is desirable for the FPC to include at least one ground trace which extends along the elongated direction of the thin plate-like object.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In the present invention, a hollow portion having a greater width than each contact insertion groove is formed in each partition wall of the insulator in such a manner as to superimpose part of each contact as viewed in a contact arranging direction in which the plurality of contacts are arranged, and in such a manner as to be prevented from being communicatively-connected with the plurality of contact insertion grooves in the contact arranging direction by the plurality of partition walls. The relative permittivity of this hollow portion (air space) is 1, thus being lower than the relative permittivity of a typical insulator (partition wall). Accordingly, in the connector according to the present invention, the coupling capacitance between adjacent contacts does not easily increase, so that the impedance (value) of the connector can be brought closer to the impedance (value) of the circuit board and the connecting object as compared with a conventional connector having no hollow portion (corresponding to the hollow portion provided in the present invention). Therefore, the high frequency property of an electrical signal fed to the connector (the contacts thereof) can be improved.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The present invention will be discussed below in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a front perspective view of an embodiment of a connector according to the present invention, showing a state where the rotational actuator of the connector is in the unlocked position;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exploded rear perspective view of the connector;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a front elevational view of the connector with the rotational actuator in the unlocked position;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a bottom view of the connector with the rotational actuator in the unlocked position;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross sectional view taken along the line V-V shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, viewed in the direction of the appended arrows;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a cross sectional view taken along the line VI-VI shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, viewed in the direction of the appended arrows;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a cross sectional view taken along the line VII-VII shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, viewed in the direction of the appended arrows;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a cross sectional view taken along the line VIII-VIII shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, viewed in the direction of the appended arrows;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is an enlarged view of a portion of the connector indicated by the one-dot chain line IX shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a front perspective view of the connector and an insertion end of an FPC inserted into the connector with the rotational actuator in the locked position;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a cross sectional view similar to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, showing the connector and the</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">FPC in the same state as that shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is an enlarged plan view of part of the insertion end of the FPC;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a cross sectional view taken along the line XIII-XIII shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, viewed in the direction of the appended arrows;</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is a cross sectional view taken along the line XIV-XIV shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, viewed in the direction of the appended arrows;</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is a graph illustrating the impedance when an electrical signal is supplied from a circuit board, to the connector and to the FPC;</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref> is a view similar to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, of an modified embodiment of the FPC; and</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</figref> is a view similar to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref>, of the FPC shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">An embodiment of a connector according to the present invention will be hereinafter discussed with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 15</figref>. In the following descriptions, forward and rearward directions, leftward and rightward directions, and upward and downward directions of the connector <b>10</b> are determined with reference to the directions of the double-headed arrows shown in the drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The connector <b>10</b> is a so-called back flip lock connector and can accommodate differential transmission for seven circuits. The connector <b>10</b> is provided with an insulator <b>15</b>, a total of twenty-two contacts consisting of eight ground contacts <b>25</b>A and fourteen signal contacts <b>25</b>B, two fastening clips <b>35</b> and a rotational actuator <b>45</b>, which constitute major components of the connector <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The insulator <b>15</b> is formed from electrical-insulative and heat-resistant synthetic resin by injection molding. The insulator <b>15</b> is provided, on the front thereof except the left and right ends, with an FPC insertion groove <b>16</b> which is recessed rearward to a middle part of the insulator <b>15</b>. The insulator <b>15</b> is provided, on the rear side thereof except the left and right ends, with an actuator receiving recess <b>17</b>. The insulator <b>15</b> is provided, on the rear surfaces thereof in the vicinity of the left and right sides of the insulator <b>15</b>, with a pair of bearing recesses <b>18</b>, respectively, which are communicatively connected to the rotational actuator receiving recess <b>17</b>. The insulator <b>15</b> is provided, at the front thereof in the vicinity of the left and right ends of the insulator <b>15</b>, with a left and right pair of fastening-clip installation grooves <b>19</b>, respectively, which are linearly formed to elongate in the rearward direction. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, each fastening-clip installation groove <b>19</b> is substantially (lowercase) h-shaped in a side view (resembling a reversed lowercase h lying on its side). In addition, the insulator <b>15</b> is provided, at the front thereof between the left and right pair of fastening-clip installation grooves <b>19</b>, with a total of twenty-two contact insertion grooves <b>20</b> which are linearly formed to elongate in the rearward direction and are arranged at predetermined intervals (at intervals of 0.5 mm) in the leftward/rightward direction. As shown in the drawings, each contact insertion groove <b>20</b> is open at both ends in the forward/rearward direction and is substantially (lowercase) h-shaped in a side view (resembling a reversed lowercase h lying on its side). The insulator <b>15</b> is provided between the twenty-two contact insertion grooves <b>20</b> with a total of twenty-one partition walls <b>21</b> which respectively separate corresponding adjacent pairs of the twenty-two contact insertion grooves <b>20</b> from one another. Each partition wall <b>21</b> is substantially (lowercase) h-shaped in a side view (resembling a reversed lowercase h lying on its side). The insulator <b>15</b> is provided in different portions thereof (specifically, portions of the twenty-one partition walls <b>21</b>, a portion of the insulator <b>15</b> between the leftmost contact insertion groove <b>20</b> and the left fastening-clip installation groove <b>19</b> and a portion of the insulator <b>15</b> between the rightmost contact insertion groove <b>20</b> and the right fastening-clip installation groove <b>19</b>), with a total of twenty-three hollow portions <b>22</b>, respectively, which are arranged in the leftward/rightward direction. Each hollow portion <b>22</b> is substantially (lowercase) h-shaped in a side view (resembling a reversed lowercase h lying on its side) (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>). As shown in the drawings, both sides (left and right sides) of each hollow portion <b>22</b> that is respectively formed in the partition walls <b>21</b> are closed by the partition walls <b>21</b>, respectively. In addition, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, each hollow portion <b>22</b> is greater in width than each contact insertion groove <b>20</b> (specifically, the width of each hollow portion <b>22</b> is 0.2 mm and the width of each contact insertion groove <b>20</b> is 0.13 mm in this particular embodiment) and also greater in dimension in the vertical direction than each contact insertion groove <b>20</b>. Additionally, the left side of the leftmost hollow portion <b>22</b> is closed by part of the insulator <b>15</b> and the right side of the rightmost hollow portion <b>22</b> is closed by another part of the insulator <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The total of twenty-two contacts (the eight ground contacts <b>25</b>A and the fourteen signal contacts <b>25</b>B) are each formed from a thin base material made of a resilient copper alloy (e.g., phosphor bronze, beryllium copper or titanium copper) or a resilient Corson-copper alloy and formed into the shape shown in the drawings (by stamping), and is firstly coated with nickel (Ni) plating as base plating and subsequently with gold (Au) plating as finish plating. The thickness (dimension in the leftward/rightward direction) of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B is 0.1 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">As shown in the drawings, the eight ground contacts <b>25</b>A and the fourteen signal contacts <b>25</b>B are each substantially H-shaped in a side view and is provided with a fixed contact portion (first contact portion) <b>26</b>, a movable contact portion (second contact portion) <b>27</b> and a deformable connecting portion (connecting portion) <b>28</b>. The fixed contact portion <b>26</b> is elongated substantially in the forward/rearward direction. The movable contact portion <b>27</b> is elongated substantially in the forward/rearward direction and is shorter than the fixed contact portion <b>26</b>. The deformable connecting portion <b>28</b> is resiliently deformable and connects middle portions of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> and the movable contact portion <b>27</b> to each other. The fixed contact portion <b>26</b> is provided, on the bottom surface thereof in the vicinity of the rear end of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b>, with a recess <b>25</b><i>a</i>. The recess <b>25</b><i>a </i>has a trapezoidal shape in a side view and is recessed over the entire width of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> in the leftward/rearward direction. The fixed contact portion <b>26</b> is provided at the rear bottom end thereof with a hook-shaped engaging portion (tail portion) <b>29</b> which projects downward and forward. The fixed contact portion <b>26</b> is provided on the top and at the front end thereof with a contacting projection (lower contacting projection) <b>30</b>. The fixed contact portion <b>26</b> is also provided on the top thereof at the rear end of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> with a hook <b>31</b> which curves so as to project upward and forward. The movable contact portion <b>27</b> is provided at the front end thereof with a contacting projection (upper contacting projection) <b>32</b> which projects downward, and is further provided, on a lower surface of the movable contact portion <b>27</b> in the vicinity of the rear end thereof, with a locking recess (pressure-receiving portion) <b>33</b> which is recessed upward.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The eight ground contacts <b>25</b>A and the fourteen signal contacts <b>25</b>B are inserted into the twenty-two contact insertion grooves <b>20</b>, respectively, from the rear of the insulator <b>15</b>. More specifically, the ground contacts <b>25</b>A are inserted into two left and right end contact insertion grooves <b>20</b> and six contact insertion grooves <b>20</b> provided therebetween at regular intervals (one ground contact <b>25</b>A per every three contact insertion grooves), and two signal contacts <b>25</b>B are respectively inserted into two contact insertion grooves <b>20</b> that are positioned between two adjacent ground contacts <b>25</b>A. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 11</figref>, upon each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B being inserted into the associated contact insertion groove <b>20</b>, a lower surface of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B comes in contact with the bottom surface of the associated contact insertion groove <b>20</b>, the upper surface of the movable contact portion <b>27</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B is spaced downward from the top surface of the associated contact insertion groove <b>20</b>, and the hook-shaped engaging portion <b>29</b> of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B is engaged with the rear edge of a bottom wall <b>20</b><i>a </i>of the insulator <b>15</b>. In addition, an engaging projection (not shown) formed on a side of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B digs into (cuts into) a side surface in the associated contact insertion groove <b>20</b> (not shown), and accordingly, the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B is fixed to the bottom of the associated contact insertion groove <b>20</b> (the bottom wall <b>20</b><i>a </i>of the insulator <b>15</b>). In addition, the entire lower surface of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B except the portion thereof on which the recess <b>25</b><i>a </i>is formed is in contact with the bottom of the associated contact insertion groove <b>20</b> (the bottom wall <b>20</b><i>a </i>of the insulator <b>15</b>), and accordingly, both a portion of the lower surface of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> immediately in front of the recess <b>25</b><i>a </i>and another portion of the lower surface of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> immediately behind the recess <b>25</b><i>a </i>(this portion is positioned immediately above the front end of the associated hook-shaped engaging portion <b>29</b>) are in contact with the bottom of the associated contact insertion groove <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The left and right fastening clips <b>35</b> are press-formed products that are formed out of sheet metal. Each fastening clip <b>35</b> is provided with a fixed portion <b>36</b>, a movable portion <b>37</b> and a deformable connecting portion <b>38</b>. The fixed portion <b>36</b> is elongated substantially in the forward/rearward direction. The movable portion <b>37</b> is elongated substantially in the forward/rearward direction and is shorter than the fixed portion <b>36</b>. The deformable connecting portion <b>38</b> is resiliently deformable and connects middle portions of the fixed portion <b>36</b> and the movable portion <b>37</b> to each other. The fixed portion <b>36</b> is provided, on the bottom surface in the vicinity of the front end thereof, with a hook-shaped engaging portion <b>39</b> which projects downward and rearward. The fixed portion <b>36</b> is provided, on front and rear portions of the top surface thereof, with an engaging projections <b>40</b> and a lock-engaging projection <b>41</b>, respectively. The movable portion <b>37</b> is provided at the front end thereof with an engaging projection <b>42</b> which projects downward, and is further provided, on a lower surface of the movable portion <b>37</b> in the vicinity of the rear end thereof, with a locking recess <b>43</b> which is recessed upward.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The left and right fastening clips <b>35</b> are inserted into the left and right pair of fastening-clip installation grooves <b>19</b>, respectively, from the front of the insulator <b>15</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, upon each fastening clip <b>35</b> being inserted into the associated fastening-clip installation groove <b>19</b>, a lower surface of the fixed portion <b>36</b> of each fastening clip <b>35</b> comes in contact with the bottom surface of the associated fastening-clip installation groove <b>19</b>, the upper surface of the movable portion <b>37</b> of each fastening clip <b>35</b> is spaced downward from the top surface of the associated fastening-clip installation groove <b>19</b>, and the hook-shaped engaging portion <b>39</b> of the fixed portion <b>36</b> of each fastening clip <b>35</b> is engaged with the front edge of the bottom wall <b>20</b><i>a </i>of the insulator <b>15</b>. In addition, the lock-engaging projection <b>41</b>, which is projected from the rear of the fixed portion <b>36</b> that is inserted into a rear end <b>19</b><i>a </i>of the associated fastening-clip installation groove <b>19</b>, digs into (cuts into) an upper surface in the rear end <b>19</b><i>a </i>of the associated fastening-clip installation groove <b>19</b>, and accordingly, the fixed portion <b>36</b> of each fastening clip <b>35</b> is fixed to the bottom of the associated fastening-clip installation groove <b>19</b> (the bottom wall <b>20</b><i>a </i>of the insulator <b>15</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The rotational actuator <b>45</b> is a tabular shaped member elongated in the leftward/rightward direction and molded out of a heat-resistant synthetic resin by injection molding using a metal mold. The rotational actuator <b>45</b> is provided, at lower ends of the left and right side surfaces thereof, with a pair of (left and right) pivots <b>46</b>, respectively, which project in opposite directions away from each other in the leftward/rightward direction to be coaxial with each other. The rotational actuator <b>45</b> is provided, on a surface thereof (front surface with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 5</figref> or upper surface with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 and 11</figref>) in the vicinity of the lower end of this surface, with a total of forty five recesses <b>47</b> which are arranged in the leftward/rightward direction. The rotational actuator <b>45</b> is provided, at the lower end (pivoted end) thereof except both ends of this lower end in the leftward/rightward direction, with a cam portion (pressing portion) <b>48</b> which extends in the leftward/rightward direction. In addition, the rotational actuator <b>45</b> is provided in the rear surface thereof (rear surface with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 5</figref> or lower surface with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 and 11</figref>) with a total of twenty-two retaining recesses <b>49</b> arranged in the leftward/rightward direction.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The rotational actuator <b>45</b> is mounted on the insulator <b>15</b> to be rotatable about the left and right pivots <b>46</b> with the lower end (except the left and right pivots <b>46</b>) of the rotational actuator <b>45</b> being positioned in the rotational actuator receiving recess <b>17</b> and with the left and right pivots <b>46</b> being rotatably engaged into the left and right bearing recesses <b>18</b> of the insulator <b>15</b>, respectively. The rotational actuator <b>45</b> is rotatable between an unlocked position (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>3</b> and <b>5</b> through <b>7</b>), in which the rotational actuator <b>45</b> extends substantially orthogonal (vertical) to the insulator <b>15</b>, and a locked position (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 and 11</figref>), in which the rotational actuator <b>45</b> lies substantially horizontal.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">When the rotational actuator <b>45</b> is in the unlocked position as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 5</figref>, the rear end of the movable contact portion <b>27</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B is loosely engaged in the associated recess <b>47</b> of the rotational actuator <b>45</b>, so that the cam portion <b>48</b> does not press the locking recess <b>33</b> of the movable contact portion <b>27</b>. In addition, an inner-edge surface of each retaining recess <b>49</b> of the rotational actuator <b>45</b> contacts the lower surface of the front-end projecting portion of the hook <b>31</b>. Additionally, the rear end of the movable contact portion <b>37</b> of each fastening clip <b>35</b> is loosely engaged in the associated recess <b>47</b> of the rotational actuator <b>45</b>, so that the cam portion <b>48</b> does not press the locking recess <b>43</b> of the movable portion <b>37</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">On the other hand, rotating the rotational actuator <b>45</b> to the locked position as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 and 11</figref> causes the cam portion <b>48</b> of the rotational actuator <b>45</b> to press the locking recess <b>33</b> of the movable contact portion <b>27</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B upward, thus causing the front end of the movable contact portion <b>27</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B to rotate downward about the associated deformable connecting portion <b>28</b> while resiliently deforming this deformable connecting portion <b>28</b>. In addition, this rotation of the rotational actuator <b>45</b> to the locked position causes the hook <b>31</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B to be engaged in the base portion of the associated retaining recess <b>49</b>. In addition, since the cam portion <b>48</b> of the rotational actuator <b>45</b> presses the locking recess <b>43</b> of the movable portion <b>37</b> of each fastening clip <b>35</b> upward (though this action is not shown in the drawings), this pressing operation causes the front end of the movable portion <b>37</b> of each fastening clip <b>35</b> to rotate downward about the associated deformable connecting portion <b>38</b> while resiliently deforming this deformable connecting portion <b>38</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The connector <b>10</b> that has the above described structure is mounted onto a top surface of a circuit board CB (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) by soldering the hook-shaped engaging portion <b>29</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B to an associated conductor trace of a circuit pattern (not shown) formed on the top surface of the circuit board CB and by soldering the hook-shaped engaging portion <b>39</b> of each fastening clip <b>35</b> to an associated conductor trace of a ground pattern (not shown) formed on the top surface of the circuit board CB.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">When the rotational actuator <b>45</b> is in the unlocked position, an FPC (flexible printed circuit) <b>50</b> that constitutes a connecting object (object to be connected to the connector <b>10</b>) can be inserted into the FPC insertion groove <b>16</b> of the insulator <b>15</b> from the front side.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The FPC <b>50</b> is a long and thin plate-like member, and the thickness of the FPC <b>50</b> is smaller than the distance between the upper contacting projection <b>32</b> and the lower contacting projection <b>30</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B when the contacts <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B are in a free state and also smaller than the distance between the upper engaging projection <b>42</b> and the lower engaging projection <b>40</b> of each fastening clip <b>35</b> when the fastening clips <b>35</b> are in a free state. The FPC <b>50</b> has a multi-layered structure made up of a plurality of thin films which are bonded together and includes a total of eight ground traces (conductor traces) <b>51</b>, a total of fourteen circuit traces (conductor traces) <b>52</b>, a cover lay (insulating cover layer) <b>53</b>, a reinforcing plate <b>54</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 10</figref>) and other members. The eight ground traces <b>51</b> linearly extend along the elongated direction of the FPC <b>50</b>. The fourteen circuit traces <b>52</b> are arranged such that two circuit traces <b>52</b> are positioned between any two adjacent ground traces <b>51</b>. The cover lay <b>53</b> covers both sides of the FPC <b>50</b> except both ends of each ground trace <b>51</b> and both ends of each circuit trace <b>52</b>. The reinforcing plate <b>54</b> is fixed to one side (the underside with respect to the drawings) of each end of the FPC <b>50</b>, with respect to the elongated direction thereof, and has greater rigidity than the remaining part of the FPC <b>50</b>. Additionally, the FPC <b>50</b> is provided at each end of the FPC <b>50</b>, with respect to the elongated direction thereof, with a pair of engaging recesses <b>55</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13 and 14</figref> each show a detailed cross section structure of the FPC <b>50</b>. The material and thickness of each component of the FPC <b>50</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13 and 14</figref> are as follows (the unit of the dimension of each component shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>. is &#x3bc;m):</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00001" num="00001">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="4">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="35pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="56pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="77pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>THICKNESS</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>STRUCTURE</entry>
<entry>MATERIAL</entry>
<entry>(&#x3bc;m)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="4">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="56pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="77pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="49pt" align="char" char="."/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;1&#x3e;</entry>
<entry>Cover Lay</entry>
<entry>Polyimide</entry>
<entry>25</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;2&#x3e;</entry>
<entry>Adhesive Layer</entry>
<entry>Thermosetting Adhesive</entry>
<entry>25</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>i.</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;3&#x3e;</entry>
<entry>Plating</entry>
<entry>Copper Through-Hole</entry>
<entry>15</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;4&#x3e;</entry>
<entry>Copper Leaf</entry>
<entry>Electrolytic Copper</entry>
<entry>18</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;5&#x3e;</entry>
<entry>Substrate</entry>
<entry>Liquid Crystal</entry>
<entry>50</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>Polymer (LCP)</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;6&#x3e;</entry>
<entry>Copper Leaf</entry>
<entry>Electrolytic Copper</entry>
<entry>18</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;7&#x3e;</entry>
<entry>Plating</entry>
<entry>Copper Through-Hole</entry>
<entry>15</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;8&#x3e;</entry>
<entry>Adhesive Layer</entry>
<entry>Thermosetting Adhesive</entry>
<entry>25</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;9&#x3e;</entry>
<entry>Cover Lay</entry>
<entry>Polyimide</entry>
<entry>25</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;10&#x3e;&#x2002;</entry>
<entry>Adhesive Layer</entry>
<entry>Thermosetting Adhesive</entry>
<entry>50</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;11&#x3e;&#x2002;</entry>
<entry>Reinforcing Plate</entry>
<entry>Polyimide</entry>
<entry>125</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> (the unit of the dimension of each component shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is mm), the portion of each ground trace <b>51</b> which is covered by the cover lay <b>53</b> except a portion of the aforementioned covered portion in the close vicinity of an edge <b>53</b><i>a </i>(see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12 and 14</figref>) of the cover lay <b>53</b> is constant in width and gradually decreases in width in a direction toward the edge <b>53</b><i>a </i>of the cover lay <b>53</b> at each end of the FPC <b>50</b>, with respect to the elongated direction thereof. At each end of the FPC <b>50</b>, with respect to the elongated direction thereof, a land <b>51</b><i>a </i>of each ground trace <b>51</b> that is formed in the close vicinity of the end of this ground trace <b>51</b> (and that is positioned outside the cover lay <b>53</b>, extending linearly from the edge <b>53</b><i>a</i>) has a constant width from the edge <b>53</b><i>a </i>to a point immediately behind the end of the FPC <b>50</b>, with respect to the elongated direction thereof, and an end portion of each ground trace <b>51</b> which is closer to the end of the FPC <b>50</b>, with respect to the elongated direction thereof, than the land <b>51</b><i>a </i>is smaller in width than the land <b>51</b><i>a</i>. On the other hand, the portion of each circuit trace <b>52</b> which is covered by the cover lay <b>53</b> except a portion of the aforementioned covered portion in the close vicinity of the edge <b>53</b><i>a </i>of the cover lay <b>53</b> is formed as a constant-width portion <b>52</b><i>c</i>, and a bent portion <b>52</b><i>d </i>of each circuit trace <b>52</b> which extends from the end of the constant-width portion <b>52</b><i>c </i>to the edge <b>53</b><i>a </i>of the cover lay <b>53</b> is slightly greater in width than the constant-width portion <b>52</b><i>c</i>. At each end of the FPC <b>50</b>, with respect to the elongated direction thereof, an adjacent end portion (connecting portion) <b>52</b><i>e </i>(which is provided near the end of the FPC <b>50</b>) of each circuit trace <b>52</b> (which is positioned outside the cover lay <b>53</b>, extending linearly from the edge <b>53</b><i>a </i>to a midpoint position of the reinforcing plate <b>54</b> in the elongated direction of the FPC <b>50</b>) is identical in width to the bent portion <b>52</b><i>c </i>up until the midpoint position of the reinforcing plate <b>54</b> in the elongated direction of the FPC <b>50</b>, a land <b>52</b><i>a </i>of each circuit trace <b>52</b> which extends from the aforementioned mid-position to a position in the close vicinity of the end of the FPC <b>50</b> in the elongated direction thereof is greater in width than the adjacent end portion <b>52</b><i>e</i>, and an end portion <b>52</b><i>f </i>of each circuit trace <b>52</b> which extends from the land <b>52</b><i>a </i>to the end of the FPC <b>50</b> in the elongated direction thereof is smaller in width than the land <b>52</b><i>a </i>(identical in width to the adjacent end portion <b>52</b><i>e</i>). By chamfering the four corners of the land <b>52</b><i>a </i>of each circuit trace <b>52</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> (i.e., by forming the same four corners into round corners in a plan view), rather than forming the same four corners into square corners, the widths of both ends <b>52</b><i>b </i>of the land <b>52</b><i>a </i>of each circuit trace <b>52</b> in the elongated direction of the FPC <b>50</b> gradually vary in the elongated direction of the FPC <b>50</b> to thereby reduce the area of the land <b>52</b><i>a</i>, which achieves a reduction in stub of the land <b>52</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Upon one end (insertion end; the right end with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the FPC <b>50</b> being inserted into the FPC insertion groove <b>16</b> (the insertion/removal direction of the FPC <b>50</b> with respect to the FPC insertion groove <b>16</b> corresponds to the forward/rearward direction of the connector <b>10</b>), this insertion end of the FPC <b>50</b> is positioned in each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B between a front half of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> and a front half of the movable contact portion <b>27</b>. In addition, the lower engaging projections <b>40</b> of the left and right fastening clips <b>35</b> are engaged in the left and right pair of engaging recesses <b>55</b> from below, respectively, though this state of engagement is not shown in the drawings. In this state, rotating the rotational actuator <b>45</b> to the locked position causes the front end of the movable contact portion <b>27</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B to rotate downward as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, thus causing the contacting projection <b>32</b> of each ground contact <b>25</b>A to be pressed hard against the land <b>51</b><i>a </i>of the associated ground trace <b>51</b> of the FPC <b>50</b>, causing the contacting projection <b>32</b> of each signal contact <b>25</b>B to be pressed hard against the land <b>52</b><i>a </i>of the associated circuit trace <b>52</b> of the FPC <b>50</b> (a black solid circle marked on the land <b>52</b><i>a </i>of each circuit trace <b>52</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> designates a contact point with which the contacting projection <b>32</b> of the associated signal contact <b>25</b>B comes into contact) and causing the contacting projection <b>30</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B to be pressed hard against a lower surface of the insertion end of the FPC <b>50</b>. Consequently, the circuit traces <b>52</b> of the FPC <b>50</b> and associated conductor traces of the aforementioned circuit pattern (not shown) of the circuit board CB are electrically connected via the fourteen signal contacts <b>25</b>B, while the ground traces <b>51</b> of the FPC <b>50</b> and associated conductor traces of the aforementioned ground pattern (not shown) of the circuit board CB are electrically connected via the eight ground contacts <b>25</b>A. In addition, the rotation of the rotational actuator <b>45</b> to the locked position causes the upper engaging projections <b>42</b> of the left and right fastening clips <b>35</b> to be engaged in the left and right pair of engaging recesses <b>55</b> from above, respectively (though this state of engagement is not shown in the drawings), to thereby prevent the FPC <b>50</b> from being withdrawn from the FPC insertion groove <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">On the other hand, if the contact pressure exerted on the FPC <b>50</b> from each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B is released while the upper engaging projections <b>42</b> of the left and right fastening clips <b>35</b> are respectively disengaged upward from the left and right pair of engaging recesses <b>55</b> by returning the rotational actuator <b>45</b> to the unlocked position, the FPC <b>50</b> can be forwardly withdrawn from the FPC insertion groove <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is a graph illustrating the relationship between time and the impedance (value) when an electrical signal is supplied to an SMA (Sub-Miniature version A) connector (connector for coaxial cable; not shown) connected to the circuit board CB. In the horizontal axis indicating time, the time when an electrical signal enters the SMA connector is defined as a reference time (zero). Since the electrical signal travels toward the FPC <b>50</b> as time passes, the horizontal axis practically shows positions of the signal paths of a signal which passes through the SMA connector, the circuit board CB, the connector <b>10</b> (the ground contacts <b>25</b>A and the signal contacts <b>25</b>B) and the FPC <b>50</b> (note that the section from 0 [ns] to approximately 0.2 [ns] corresponds to the SMA connector; the section from approximately 0.2 [ns] to approximately 0.5 [ns] corresponds to the circuit board CB; the section from approximately 0.5 [ns] to approximately 0.7 [ns] corresponds to the connector <b>10</b>; and the section from approximately 0.7 [ns] onwards (rightward with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref>) corresponds to the FPC <b>50</b>). An analysis was carried out using a vector network analyzer (E5071C) produced by Agilent Technologies in conditions in which the Tr (rise time) was 50 ps and the contact pitch was 0.5 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref>, a total of two line graphs are shown. Out of these two line graphs, the line graph that is represented by a fine line is a graph obtained when a connector similar in structure to the connector <b>10</b>, in which the hollow portions <b>22</b> of the present invention are omitted (namely, a connector having a conventional configuration), is connected to the FPC <b>50</b> and the circuit board CB. As can be clearly understood from this line graph, in this case the impedances of the circuit board CB and the FPC <b>50</b> are approximately 100 ohms and approximately 90 ohms, respectively; however, the minimum impedance of the connector (contacts) is approximately 63 ohms, and accordingly, there is a large difference between this minimum impedance of the connector and the impedance of the circuit board CB and the FPC <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">On the other hand, the line graph that is represented by a thick line in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is a graph obtained when the present embodiment of the connector <b>10</b> is connected to the FPC <b>50</b> and the circuit board CB. As can be understood from this graph, in this case, the impedances of the circuit board CB and the FPC <b>50</b> are approximately 100 ohms and approximately 86 ohms. However, the minimum impedance of the connector <b>10</b> (the signal contacts <b>25</b>B) is approximately 84 ohms, so that it can be understood that the difference between this minimum impedance of the connector <b>10</b> and the impedance of the circuit board CB and the FPC <b>50</b> has become significantly smaller. This result is due to the formation of the hollow portions <b>22</b> in the insulator <b>15</b> that are formed in such a manner as to superimpose the deformable connecting portion <b>28</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B, superimpose the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B, and superimpose approximately half (&#xbd;) of the movable contact portion <b>27</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B (i.e., a portion of the movable contact portion <b>27</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B which is positioned extending from the deformable connecting portion <b>28</b> forward), as viewed from a lateral side (the left or right side) of the insulator <b>15</b>; and also due to the partition walls <b>21</b> preventing the hollow portions <b>22</b> from being communicatively connected with the contact insertion grooves <b>20</b> in the leftward/rightward direction; and also due to the hollow portions <b>22</b> being greater in width than the contact insertion grooves <b>20</b> and also being greater in dimension in the vertical direction than the contact insertion grooves <b>20</b>. The relative permittivity of each hollow portion <b>22</b> (air space) is 1, thus being far lower than the relative permittivity of the synthetic resin from which the insulator <b>15</b> is made (which is approximately 3 to 4). Accordingly, the coupling capacitance between two adjacent contacts <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B, between which one hollow portion <b>22</b> is formed, does not easily increase, and hence the impedance (value) of the connector <b>10</b> is higher than that of a connector configured to have no hollow portions corresponding to the hollow portions <b>22</b>. Therefore, when the connector <b>10</b> is connected to the circuit board CB and the FPC <b>50</b>, the high frequency property of an electrical signal supplied to the connector <b>10</b> is improved compared with the case where a connector having a conventional structure is connected to the circuit board CB and the FPC <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">In addition, the formation of the recess <b>25</b><i>a </i>on the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B reduces the surface area of the laterally-opposed surfaces of the fixed contact portions <b>26</b> adjacent to each other (the surface area of the laterally-opposed portions of the fixed contact portions <b>26</b> adjacent to each other if the partition walls <b>21</b> were omitted); and moreover, a hollow portion (spacing) is formed between the recess <b>25</b><i>a </i>of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B and the bottom of the associated contact insertion groove <b>20</b>, which makes it possible to improve the high frequency property of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In addition, each hollow portion <b>22</b> that is formed on the insulator <b>15</b> is substantially (lowercase) h-shaped in a side view (resembling a reversed lowercase h lying on its side). At least a part of the rear end <b>19</b><i>a </i>of each hollow portion <b>22</b> superimposes the recess <b>25</b><i>a </i>of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> as viewed from a lateral side of the insulator <b>15</b>, which consequently increases the area of a portion of each hollow portion <b>22</b> which superimposes the associated contact insertion groove <b>20</b> (the associated contact <b>25</b>A or <b>25</b>B), thus making the coupling capacitance between any two adjacent contacts <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B far more difficult to increase, so that the impedance (value) of the connector <b>10</b> becomes higher than that in the case where neither the recess <b>25</b><i>a </i>nor the rear end portion <b>19</b><i>a </i>is formed.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Moreover, although the cam portion <b>48</b> of the rotational actuator <b>45</b> exerts a downward force on a portion of the upper surface of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B immediately above the recess <b>25</b><i>a </i>of the associated contact <b>25</b>A or <b>25</b>B (i.e., on a portion of the upper surface of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B in the vicinity of the rear end thereof) when the rotational actuator <b>45</b> is rotated, such a downward force that is exerted on the portion of the upper surface of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B in the vicinity of the rear end thereof from the cam portion <b>48</b> of the rotational actuator <b>45</b> is securely received by the bottom surface <b>20</b><i>a </i>of the insulator <b>15</b> because both the front and rear lower surfaces of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B that are positioned on the opposite sides of the recess <b>25</b><i>a </i>in the forward/rearward direction are in contact with the bottom of the associated contact insertion groove <b>20</b>. Therefore, the portion of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B in the vicinity of the rear end thereof does not flex by a large amount, and accordingly, the transmission characteristics can be improved without impairing either the rotational operability of the rotational actuator <b>45</b> or the stability of the position of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B (i.e., the firmness of the fixing force of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B relative to the bottom wall <b>20</b><i>a </i>of the insulator <b>15</b>), which are fundamental requirements (capabilities) for cable connectors.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Additionally, if each circuit trace <b>52</b> of the FPC <b>50</b> is structured so that the land <b>52</b><i>a </i>is directly connected to the end of the constant-width portion <b>52</b><i>c </i>(i.e., if the distance between the edge <b>53</b><i>a </i>of the cover lay <b>53</b> and the land <b>52</b><i>a </i>of each circuit trace <b>52</b> is reduced), the impedance sharply drops at the connection between the constant-width portion <b>52</b><i>c </i>and the land <b>52</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">However, in each circuit trace <b>52</b> of the present embodiment of the FPC <b>50</b>, forming the adjacent end portion <b>52</b><i>e </i>which is smaller in width than the land <b>52</b><i>a</i>, extends linearly and is positioned on the outer side of the edge <b>53</b><i>a </i>of the cover lay <b>53</b>, increases the distance from the edge <b>53</b><i>a </i>of the cover lay <b>53</b> to the aforementioned contact point (the position of each black solid circle shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>) on the land <b>52</b><i>a </i>(i.e., makes the length of the land <b>52</b><i>a </i>shorter than a conventional land), while the width of each end <b>52</b><i>b </i>of the land <b>52</b><i>a </i>is made to vary gradually. By forming each circuit trace <b>52</b> in this manner, the width of most of the area from the edge <b>53</b><i>a </i>of the cover lay <b>53</b> to the aforementioned contact point (the position of each black solid circle shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>) on the land <b>52</b><i>a </i>is made to be substantially constant, which prevents the impedance from dropping sharply.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">Moreover, in each circuit trace <b>52</b> of the present embodiment of the FPC <b>50</b>, since the land <b>52</b><i>a</i>, with which the upper contacting projection <b>32</b> of the movable contact portion <b>27</b> of the associated signal contact <b>25</b>B comes into contact, is the greatest in width than any other part of the circuit tract <b>52</b>, the upper contacting projection <b>32</b> and the land <b>52</b><i>a </i>can be made to come into contact with each other with reliability.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Although the present invention has been described based on the above illustrated embodiment of the connector <b>10</b>, the present invention is not limited solely to this particular embodiment; making various modifications to the above illustrated embodiment of the connector <b>10</b> is possible.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">For instance, an FPC <b>50</b>&#x2032; which has the structure shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 16 and 17</figref> can be used instead of the FPC <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">The FPC <b>50</b>&#x2032; has a multi-layered structure made up of a plurality of thin films which are bonded together and includes a total of eight ground traces (conductor traces) <b>51</b>, a total of fourteen circuit traces (conductor traces) <b>52</b> that are arranged such that two circuit traces <b>52</b> are positioned between any two adjacent ground trace <b>51</b>, a cover lay <b>53</b>, a reinforcing plate <b>54</b> and other members. Additionally, the FPC <b>50</b>&#x2032; is provided, on both side edges of each end of the FPC <b>50</b>&#x2032; in the elongated direction thereof, with a pair of engaging recesses <b>55</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The material and thickness of each component of the FPC <b>50</b>&#x2032; shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 16 and 17</figref> are as follows (the unit of the dimension of each component shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref> is &#x3bc;m):</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00002" num="00002">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="4">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="35pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="56pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="77pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>THICKNESS</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>STRUCTURE</entry>
<entry>MATERIAL</entry>
<entry>(&#x3bc;m)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="4">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="56pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="77pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="49pt" align="char" char="."/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;1&#x3e;</entry>
<entry>Cover Lay</entry>
<entry>Polyimide</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;2&#x3e;</entry>
<entry>Adhesive Layer</entry>
<entry>Thermosetting Adhesive</entry>
<entry>25</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;3&#x3e;</entry>
<entry>Plating</entry>
<entry>Copper Through-Hole</entry>
<entry>15</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;4&#x3e;</entry>
<entry>Copper Leaf</entry>
<entry>Electrolytic Copper</entry>
<entry>18</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;5&#x3e;</entry>
<entry>Adhesive Layer</entry>
<entry>Thermosetting Adhesive</entry>
<entry>10</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;6&#x3e;</entry>
<entry>Substrate</entry>
<entry>Polyimide</entry>
<entry>25</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;7&#x3e;</entry>
<entry>Adhesive Layer</entry>
<entry>Thermosetting Adhesive</entry>
<entry>10</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;8&#x3e;</entry>
<entry>Copper Leaf</entry>
<entry>Electrolytic Copper</entry>
<entry>18</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;9&#x3e;</entry>
<entry>Plating</entry>
<entry>Copper Through-Hole</entry>
<entry>15</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;10&#x3e;&#x2002;</entry>
<entry>Adhesive Layer</entry>
<entry>Thermosetting Adhesive</entry>
<entry>25</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;11&#x3e;&#x2002;</entry>
<entry>Cover Lay</entry>
<entry>Polyimide</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;12&#x3e;&#x2002;</entry>
<entry>Adhesive Layer</entry>
<entry>Thermosetting Adhesive</entry>
<entry>50</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&#x3c;13&#x3e;&#x2002;</entry>
<entry>Reinforcing Plate</entry>
<entry>Polyimide</entry>
<entry>125</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">Also in this case where the FPC <b>50</b>&#x2032; is connected to the connector <b>10</b>, the high frequency property of an electrical signal supplied to the connector <b>10</b> is improved compared with the case where a connector having a conventional structure is connected to the circuit board CB and the FPC <b>50</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">In addition, if the hollow portions <b>22</b>, which are formed in the partition walls <b>21</b> of the insulator <b>15</b>, superimpose at least part of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B as viewed from a lateral side of the insulator <b>15</b>, the shape (setting range) can be modified. For instance, it is possible to omit from the hollow portions <b>22</b> in the above described embodiment of the connector <b>10</b>: (1) portions of the hollow portions <b>22</b> which superimpose the fixed contact portions <b>26</b>, (2) portions of the hollow portions <b>22</b> which superimpose the movable contact portions <b>27</b>, or (3) portions of the hollow portions <b>22</b> which superimpose the fixed contact portions <b>26</b> and the movable contact portions <b>27</b> (so that the hollow portions <b>22</b> include only portions thereof for superimposing the deformable connecting portions <b>28</b>) as viewed from a lateral side of the insulator <b>15</b>. Even in the case where any of these modifications are made to the connector <b>10</b>, the impedance of the connector <b>10</b> is greater than that in the case where the hollow portions <b>22</b> are not formed in the insulator <b>15</b>. According to experimental study carried out by the applicant of the present invention, portions of the hollow portions <b>22</b> which superimpose the deformable connecting portions <b>28</b>, as viewed from a lateral side of the insulator <b>15</b>, display a maximum effect (effect of preventing the coupling capacitance between any two adjacent contacts <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B from increasing), and accordingly, it is desirable that the hollow portions <b>22</b> be shaped so that each hollow portion <b>22</b> includes a portion superimposing the deformable connecting portions <b>28</b> as viewed from a lateral side of the insulator <b>15</b>, regardless of the type of shape into which the hollow portions are formed.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The ground contacts <b>25</b>A and the signal contacts <b>25</b>B can be alternately arranged and inserted into the contact insertion grooves <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">The thin plate-like connecting object can be a cable other than an FPC, e.g., an FFC (flexible flat cable).</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">Additionally, the positions of the lower contacting projection <b>30</b> and the upper contact projection <b>32</b> of each ground contact <b>25</b>A can be relatively shifted (displaced) in the forward/rearward direction. Similarly, the positions of the lower contacting projection <b>30</b> and the upper contact projection <b>32</b> of each signal contact <b>25</b>B can be relatively shifted (displaced) in the forward/rearward direction.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">In addition, the connector <b>10</b> can be made as a connector for single-end transmission (all the contacts of the connector <b>10</b> can be made as signal contacts <b>25</b>B) while all the conductor traces of the circuit board CB, the FPC <b>50</b> and the FPC <b>50</b>&#x2032; can be made as circuit traces.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">It is possible to make circuit traces of the connecting object come in contact with the lower contacting portions <b>30</b> of the signal contacts <b>25</b>B by inserting the connecting object into the insulator <b>15</b> with the connecting object upside down, or it is possible to form circuit traces on both sides of the connecting object so that these circuit traces (upper and lower contact traces) on both sides of the connecting object come in contact with the upper contacting portions <b>32</b> and the lower contacting portions <b>30</b> of the signal contacts <b>25</b>B, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">Additionally, a hook-shaped engaging portion (tail portion) corresponding to the hook-shaped engaging portion <b>29</b> can be formed at the front end of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">Additionally, each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B can be substantially (lowercase) h-shaped in a side view (resembling a reversed lowercase h lying on its side) from which a rear half of the movable contact portion <b>27</b> (i.e., a portion thereof which is positioned rearward from the portion of the movable contact portion <b>27</b> which is connected to the deformable connecting portion <b>28</b>) is omitted, or substantially U-shaped in a side view from which both a rear halves of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> (i.e., a portion thereof which is positioned rearward from the portion of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b> which is connected to the deformable connecting portion <b>28</b>) and the aforementioned rear half of the movable contact portion <b>27</b> are omitted (in this case, a hook-shaped engaging portion (tail portion) is formed at the front or rear end of the fixed contact portion <b>26</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">Even if each contact is in the shape of a letter &#x201c;H&#x201d;, &#x201c;h&#x201d; (reversed and on its side) or &#x201c;U&#x201d;, the connector can be made as a so-called front-lock type by making the rotational actuator supported by a front half of the insulator to be rotatable between an unlocked position, in which the rotational actuator oriented substantially orthogonal to the insulator <b>15</b>, and a locked position, in which the rotational actuator lies substantially horizontal (i.e., the rotational actuator has been tilted forwardly down). In this case, a cam portion (pressing portion) formed on part of the rotational actuator is positioned between the fixed contact portions <b>26</b> and the movable contact portions <b>27</b> of the contacts <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B while the connecting object that is inserted into the insulator is positioned immediately below the cam portion. When this rotational actuator is in the unlocked position, the pressing portion that is positioned immediately above the connecting object does not press the connecting object downward. On the other hand, when this rotational actuator is in the locked position, the pressing portion presses the connecting object downward to make conductor traces of a circuit pattern (not shown) that are formed on the lower surface of the connecting object come in contact with the lower contacting projections <b>30</b> of the contacts <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">Additionally, in the case where each contact is shaped into a substantially letter &#x201c;h&#x201d; (reversed and on its side) or &#x201c;U&#x201d;, a recess corresponding to the recess <b>25</b><i>a </i>can be formed in a lower surface (which faces the bottom wall <b>20</b><i>a</i>) of the fixed contact portion of each contact. In this case also, it is desirable that both the front and rear lower surfaces of the fixed contact portion of each contact <b>25</b>A and <b>25</b>B that are positioned on the opposite sides of the recess in the forward/rearward direction be in contact with the bottom of the associated contact insertion groove <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">Obvious changes may be made in the specific embodiments of the present invention described herein, such modifications being within the spirit and scope of the invention claimed. It is indicated that all matter contained herein is illustrative and does not limit the scope of the present invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A connector comprising:
<claim-text>an insulator, into which a thin plate-like object to be connected to said connector is removably insertable, including a plurality of contact insertion grooves and a plurality of partition walls that are positioned between said contact insertion grooves to separate said contact insertion grooves from one another, said contact insertion grooves being elongated in an insertion/removal direction of said thin plate-like object and arranged in a direction orthogonal to said insertion/removal direction; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of contacts which are inserted into said contact insertion grooves, respectively, each of said contacts including a first contact portion and a second contact portion that are spaced from each other in a direction of thickness of said thin plate-like object to allow said thin plate-like object to be inserted in between said first contact portion and said second contact portion, and further including a connecting portion which connects said first contact portion and said second contact portion to each other, wherein at least one of said first contact portion and said second contact portion comes in contact with said thin plate-like object when said thin plate-like object is inserted into said insulator,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a hollow portion having a greater width than each of said contact insertion grooves is formed in each of said partition walls of said insulator in a manner such that said hollow portion superimposes part of each contact of said contacts as viewed in a contact arranging direction in which said contacts are arranged, and in a manner such that each of said plurality of partition walls prevents each corresponding said hollow portion from being communicatively connected with said contact insertion grooves in said contact arranging direction.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The connector according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said hollow portion is greater in dimension in said direction of thickness of said thin plate-like object than each of said contact insertion grooves.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The connector according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said hollow portion is formed in said insulator so as to superimpose part of said connecting portions of said plurality of contacts as viewed in said contact arranging direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The connector according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein said first contact portion is fixed to a bottom wall of said insulator, and wherein said hollow portion is formed in said insulator so as to superimpose both said first contact portion and a portion of said second contact portion extending from said connecting portion and along said second contact portion said insertion/removal direction as viewed from a lateral side of said insulator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The connector according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a recess is formed on a surface of said first contact portion which faces said bottom wall of said insulator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The connector according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein said hollow portion is formed in said insulator so as to superimpose said recess as viewed in said contact arranging direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The connector according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said thin plate-like object comprises an FPC including at least one circuit trace which extends along an elongated direction of said thin plate-like object; and an insulating cover layer which covers both sides of said FPC except both ends of said circuit trace, and
<claim-text>wherein said circuit trace comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a land which is positioned outside said insulating cover layer and comes into contact with at least one of said first contact portion and said second contact portion, an end of said land adjacent to an edge of said insulating cover layer being formed to decrease in width gradually in a direction toward said edge of said insulating cover layer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a connecting portion which is smaller in width than said land, except said end of said land, and extends linearly from said end of said land to said edge of said insulating cover layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The connector according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein said FPC further includes at least one ground trace which extends along said elongated direction of said thin plate-like object. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
