<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622526-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622526</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13431812</doc-number>
<date>20120327</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2011-071872</doc-number>
<date>20110329</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>38</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>2</main-group>
<subgroup>045</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 68</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Liquid ejecting head and liquid ejecting apparatus</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6494566</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Kishino et al.</name>
<date>20021200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7919904</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Sugahara et al.</name>
<date>20110400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>310331</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8047635</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Okubo</name>
<date>20111100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347 68</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8454133</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Mizukami et al.</name>
<date>20130600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347 70</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>10-286956</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19981000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>10-305574</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19981100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>6</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 67</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 68</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 69</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 70- 72</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120249682</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121004</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Munakata</last-name>
<first-name>Manabu</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Munakata</last-name>
<first-name>Manabu</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Kilpatrick Townsend &#x26; Stockton LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Seiko Epson Corporation</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Nguyen</last-name>
<first-name>Lamson</first-name>
<department>2861</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A nozzle plate made of conductive ceramics is grounded. Therefore, electric charges do not easily accumulate on the nozzle plate. The migration of electric charges from nozzle orifices to a diaphragm plate through ink filled in pressure generation chambers is unlikely to occur or significantly less likely to occur. Thus, it is possible to prevent the dielectric breakdown of the diaphragm plate caused conventionally by accumulated electric charges and to provide an ink-jet recording head that is substantially free from the damage of a driving circuit.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="194.14mm" wi="270.09mm" file="US08622526-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="191.85mm" wi="139.70mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622526-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="218.78mm" wi="169.67mm" file="US08622526-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="210.74mm" wi="156.46mm" file="US08622526-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="215.90mm" wi="277.20mm" file="US08622526-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a liquid ejecting head and a liquid ejecting apparatus using the liquid ejecting head.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A liquid ejecting head that ejects liquid through nozzle orifices is used in various kinds of liquid ejecting apparatuses. Examples of them are: an image recording apparatus such as a printer, a liquid ejecting apparatus used in the production of a color filter for a liquid crystal display device, etc. A certain type of a liquid ejecting head ejects liquid in the form of droplets when voltage is applied to piezoelectric elements provided on a surface of a diaphragm plate. The voltage is applied thereto so as to cause the piezoelectric elements to get deformed in accordance with driving signals supplied from a driving circuit. Such a liquid ejecting head is provided with a head unit that includes the diaphragm plate, pressure generation chambers, nozzle orifices, and a manifold. The diaphragm plate constitutes a ceiling part of each of the pressure generation chambers. The diaphragm plate, a flow passage formation substrate, a nozzle plate, which is a plate through which the nozzle orifices are formed, are laid one on another for manufacturing the head unit. For example, an ink-jet recording head manufactured by co-firing plate members made of ceramics is known as an example of such a liquid ejecting head as disclosed in JP-A-10-286956.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">If insulating ceramics is used as the material of each of a diaphragm plate, a flow passage formation substrate, and a nozzle plate, and if these insulating ceramic plate members are co-fired, the insulating ceramics will be charged due to piezoelectric-element electrification or due to static electricity. Therefore, there is a risk that the dielectric breakdown of the diaphragm plate might occur, or a driving circuit may get damaged through the electrodes of the piezoelectric elements.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">To solve the above problems without any limitation thereto, the invention provides, as various aspects thereof, a liquid ejecting head and a liquid ejecting apparatus having features stated in Application Examples below or described as an exemplary mode.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">APPLICATION EXAMPLE 1</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">A liquid ejecting head according to an aspect of the invention includes: a flow passage formation substrate in which pressure generation chambers and liquid flow passages demarcated by partition walls are formed, the flow passage formation substrate being made of ceramics; a diaphragm plate that is provided on one surface of the flow passage formation substrate to constitute a part of each of the pressure generation chambers and each of the liquid flow passages, the diaphragm plate being made of insulating ceramics; piezoelectric elements that are provided on one surface of the diaphragm plate each at a position where the piezoelectric element overlaps the corresponding pressure generation chamber with the diaphragm plate interposed therebetween, the piezoelectric element including a pair of electrodes; a driving circuit that is connected to the electrodes; and a nozzle plate in which nozzle orifices that are in communication with the pressure generation chambers are formed, the nozzle plate being made of conductive ceramics.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The above application example offers the following advantage. The nozzle plate is made of conductive ceramics. The nozzle plate is grounded. Therefore, electric charges do not easily accumulate on the nozzle plate. The migration of electric charges from the nozzle orifices to the diaphragm plate through liquid filled in the pressure generation chambers is unlikely to occur or significantly less likely to occur. Thus, it is possible to prevent the dielectric breakdown of the diaphragm plate caused conventionally by accumulated electric charges and to provide a liquid ejecting head that is substantially free from the damage of a driving circuit due to the inflow of electric charge.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">APPLICATION EXAMPLE 2</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The liquid ejecting head further includes a conductive cover case for encasing the nozzle plate, wherein the nozzle plate is grounded via the cover case.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The nozzle plate is grounded via the conductive cover case. Therefore, with the above application example, besides the advantageous effect described above, the liquid ejecting head offers a structure for protecting the nozzle plate.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">APPLICATION EXAMPLE 3</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In the liquid ejecting head, the flow passage formation substrate, the diaphragm plate, and the nozzle plate are co-fired.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The flow passage formation substrate, the diaphragm plate, and the nozzle plate, each of which is made of ceramics, are co-fired. Therefore, with the above application example, it is possible to reduce the displacement of the flow passage formation substrate, the diaphragm plate, and the nozzle plate relative to one another due to thermal contraction and to provide a liquid ejecting head that can be assembled easily.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">APPLICATION EXAMPLE 4</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">A liquid ejecting apparatus is provided with the liquid ejecting head described above.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">With the above application example, it is possible to provide a liquid ejecting apparatus that can produce the advantageous effects described above.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The invention will be described with reference to the accompanying drawings, wherein like numbers reference like elements.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view that schematically illustrates an example of the structure of a printer according to an exemplary embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exploded perspective view that schematically illustrates an example of the structure of an ink-jet recording head.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an exploded perspective view that schematically illustrates an example of the structure of a head unit.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a sectional view for explaining an essential part of the head unit and a cover case.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF EXEMPLARY EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">With reference to the accompanying drawings, an exemplary embodiment of the present invention will now be explained in detail. In order to make it easier to understand the concept of the embodiment, the configuration is partially omitted or shown in an exaggerated manner in the drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In the following description, a configuration in which an ink-jet recording head <b>100</b> is mounted on a printer <b>1000</b> functioning as an image recording apparatus is taken as an example. The ink-jet recording head <b>100</b> is an example of a liquid ejecting head. The printer <b>1000</b> is an example of a liquid ejecting apparatus. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram that schematically illustrates an example of the structure of the printer <b>1000</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, X denotes a main scan direction, which is a direction in which a carriage <b>104</b> travels. Y denotes sub scan direction, which is a direction in which a recording target medium P is transported. Z denotes a direction that is orthogonal to the X and Y directions.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the printer <b>1000</b> is provided with the ink-jet recording head <b>100</b>, the carriage <b>104</b>, a carriage movement mechanism <b>105</b>, a platen roller <b>106</b>, and ink cartridges <b>107</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The ink-jet recording head <b>100</b> is mounted on a recording-target-medium-side surface (that is, the surface closer to the recording target medium P; the lower surface in the Z direction in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of the carriage <b>104</b>. The ink-jet recording head <b>100</b> ejects ink in the form of droplets onto the surface of the recording target medium P. The carriage movement mechanism <b>105</b> includes a timing belt <b>108</b>, a driving pulley <b>111</b>, a driven pulley <b>112</b>, and a motor <b>109</b>. The carriage <b>104</b> is attached to the timing belt <b>108</b>. The timing belt <b>108</b> is stretched between the driving pulley <b>111</b> and the driven pulley <b>112</b>. The driving pulley <b>111</b> is connected to the output shaft of the motor <b>109</b>. Therefore, as the motor <b>109</b> operates, the carriage <b>104</b> reciprocates in the X direction, that is, the main scan direction, while being guided along a guide rod <b>110</b> supported inside the casing of the printer <b>1000</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Driven by a motor <b>103</b>, the platen roller <b>106</b> rotates to transport the recording target medium P in the Y direction, that is, the sub scan direction. The ink cartridges <b>107</b>, which contain ink, are detachably attached to the carriage <b>104</b>. Ink is supplied from the ink cartridges <b>107</b> to the ink-jet recording head <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The printer <b>1000</b> having the structure described above can print an image, etc. on the recording target medium P such as recording paper by ejecting ink in the form of droplets from the ink-jet recording head <b>100</b> mounted on the carriage <b>104</b> while moving the carriage <b>104</b> in the X direction in a reciprocating manner by means of the carriage movement mechanism <b>105</b> and transporting the recording target medium P in the Y direction by means of the platen roller <b>106</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exploded perspective view that schematically illustrates an example of the structure of the ink-jet recording head <b>100</b>. The main scan direction X, the sub scan direction Y, and the direction Z orthogonal to these directions X and Y are shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the ink-jet recording head <b>100</b> includes a mounting plate <b>10</b>, a case head <b>20</b>, a head unit <b>30</b>, and a cover case <b>40</b>. The head unit <b>30</b> is provided on the bottom of the case head <b>20</b>. The head unit <b>30</b> is encased in the cover case <b>40</b>. Though/ a single head unit <b>30</b> and a single cover case <b>40</b> are shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a plurality of combined components may be adopted as a substitute for the illustrated single component.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The mounting plate <b>10</b> includes needles <b>11</b> functioning as inlet members through which ink flows in from the ink cartridges <b>107</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. In addition, the mounting plate <b>10</b> includes ink filters <b>12</b>. The case head <b>20</b> includes a case-head-side substrate <b>13</b> for connection to a flexible printed circuit board <b>37</b> described later.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an exploded perspective view that schematically illustrates an example of the structure of the head unit <b>30</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a sectional view for explaining an essential part of the head unit <b>30</b> and the cover case <b>40</b>. The main scan direction X, the sub scan direction Y, and the direction Z orthogonal to these directions X and Y are shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref>, too. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref>, the head unit <b>30</b> includes a nozzle plate <b>31</b>, which is provided at a position where the nozzle plate <b>31</b> faces the recording target medium P illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. Nozzle orifices <b>310</b> through which ink is ejected are formed in the nozzle plate <b>31</b>. The nozzle orifices <b>310</b> are formed at a pitch corresponding to dot-forming density. A flow passage formation substrate <b>32</b>, a diaphragm plate <b>33</b>, a reservoir plate <b>34</b>, and a compliance plate <b>35</b> are provided in layers over the nozzle plate <b>31</b>. The flow passage formation substrate <b>32</b> is a plate member having passages through which ink is supplied to the nozzle plate <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, passage holes functioning as pressure generation chambers <b>320</b>, ink supply passages <b>321</b> that are in communication with the pressure generation chambers <b>320</b>, and a communication portion <b>322</b> are formed in the flow passage formation substrate <b>32</b>. The pressure generation chamber <b>320</b> has a rectangular cross-sectional shape as viewed in the width direction of the ink-jet recording head <b>100</b>, that is, the X direction, which is orthogonal to the length direction of the ink-jet recording head <b>100</b>, that is, the Y direction. The pressure generation chamber <b>320</b> is elongated in the width direction X of the ink-jet recording head <b>100</b>. This direction is defined as the length direction of the pressure generation chamber <b>320</b>. The cross-sectional shape is not limited to a rectangle. For example, it may be a trapezoid.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The communication portion <b>322</b> is formed at an area outside the pressure generation chambers <b>320</b> in the flow passage formation substrate <b>32</b> as viewed in the length direction of the pressure generation chamber <b>320</b>. The communication portion <b>322</b> is in communication with each of the pressure generation chambers <b>320</b> through the corresponding ink supply passage <b>321</b> formed for the pressure generation chamber <b>320</b>. The ink supply passage <b>321</b> is an example of a liquid supply passage. The width of the ink supply passage <b>321</b> is smaller than that of the pressure generation chamber <b>320</b>. Having such a narrower structure, the ink supply passage <b>321</b> keeps the flow passage resistance of ink that flows from the communication portion <b>322</b> into the pressure generation chamber <b>320</b> therethrough at a constant level.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The diaphragm plate <b>33</b>, which is provided on the flow passage formation substrate <b>32</b>, constitutes a ceiling part of the pressure generation chamber <b>320</b>. Piezoelectric elements <b>36</b> are provided on the diaphragm plate <b>33</b>. The piezoelectric element <b>36</b> vibrates due to flexural oscillation when a voltage is applied thereto. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the piezoelectric element <b>36</b> includes a lower electrode <b>360</b>, a piezoelectric substance <b>361</b>, and an upper electrode <b>362</b>. The lower electrode <b>360</b> is a grounded common electrode. The upper electrode <b>362</b> is an individual electrode. The plurality of piezoelectric elements <b>36</b>, each of which is provided for the corresponding one of the plurality of pressure generation chambers <b>320</b>, are arranged in a line in the direction in which a line of nozzles is formed. The piezoelectric elements <b>36</b> are provided on one surface of the diaphragm plate <b>33</b> opposite to the other surface that is closer to the pressure generation chambers <b>320</b>. The piezoelectric elements <b>36</b> are arranged in such a way as to cover the pressure generation chambers <b>320</b> respectively with the diaphragm plate <b>33</b> interposed therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">For example, metal such as platinum or iridium or, alternatively, metal oxide such as lanthanum nickelate (LNO) or strontium ruthenate (SrRuO) can be used as a material for forming the lower electrode <b>360</b>. For example, metal such as platinum or iridium can be used as a material for forming the upper electrode <b>362</b>. A sputtering method, a vapor deposition method, or the like can be used for forming these electrodes.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Lead zirconate titanate can be used as the material of the piezoelectric substance <b>361</b>. A so-called sol-gel method can be used as a method for manufacturing the film of the piezoelectric substance <b>361</b>. Specifically, in the sol-gel method, so-called sol obtained by either dissolving or dispersing a metal organic matter into a catalyst is applied and dried to form it into gel. Then, it is fired at a high temperature to obtain the film of the piezoelectric substance <b>361</b> that is made of metal oxide. Note that the method for manufacturing the film of the piezoelectric substance <b>361</b> is not limited to the sol-gel method. For example, an MOD (Metal-Organic Decomposition) method may be used. Moreover, the method for manufacturing the film of the piezoelectric substance <b>361</b> is not limited to these liquid-phase methods. For example, a sputter deposition method may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Each of the nozzle plate <b>31</b>, the flow passage formation substrate <b>32</b>, and the diaphragm plate <b>33</b> is made of a ceramic plate using alumina, zirconia, or the like. These plate members are co-fired for connection to each other. In the present embodiment of the invention, conductive ceramics is used as the material of the nozzle plate <b>31</b>, whereas insulating ceramics is used as the material of each of the flow passage formation substrate <b>32</b> and the diaphragm plate <b>33</b>. The nozzle plate <b>31</b> is encased in the cover case <b>40</b>. The nozzle plate <b>31</b> is grounded via the ink-jet recording head <b>100</b> and the printer <b>1000</b>. A ceramic substance obtained by dispersing conductive particles in insulating ceramics such as alumina or zirconia can be used as the conductive ceramics. An example of the conductive particles is silicon particles.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The following method can be used for co-firing. For example, necessary passage holes, etc. are formed in a green sheet (sheet material that has not been fired yet) by drilling, punching, or the like to form a sheet-type precursor for each of the nozzle plate <b>31</b>, the flow passage formation substrate <b>32</b>, and the diaphragm plate <b>33</b>. Next, the sheet-type precursors are laid one on another and then fired. As a result, the sheet-type precursors form into a single ceramic sheet. Since the sheet-type precursors are co-fired to form into a single sheet, no special bonding processing is necessary. In addition, it is possible to obtain high sealing property on the adhesion surface of each of the sheet-type precursors.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a piezoelectric element housing portion <b>340</b> for protecting the piezoelectric elements <b>36</b> and a passage hole functioning as a reservoir portion <b>341</b> are formed in the reservoir plate <b>34</b>. The reservoir portion <b>341</b> is in communication with the communication portion <b>322</b>. The reservoir plate <b>34</b> is bonded to the diaphragm plate <b>33</b>. The communication portion <b>322</b> and the reservoir portion <b>341</b> are collectively called as manifold. The compliance plate <b>35</b> is bonded to one surface of the reservoir plate <b>34</b> opposite to the other surface that is bonded to the diaphragm plate <b>33</b>. A region of the compliance plate <b>35</b> that corresponds to the reservoir portion <b>341</b> is made of a flexible film <b>352</b>. The flexible film <b>352</b> absorbs pressure fluctuation occurring in the manifold.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the flexible printed circuit board <b>37</b> is inserted through the reservoir plate <b>34</b> and the compliance plate <b>35</b>. The flexible printed circuit board <b>37</b> is connected to the lower electrode <b>360</b> and the upper electrodes <b>362</b> of the piezoelectric elements <b>36</b>. A COF (Chip On Film) substrate can be used as the material of the flexible printed circuit board <b>37</b>. The flexible printed circuit board <b>37</b> is connected to the case-head-side substrate <b>13</b> provided on the body of the case head <b>20</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. Power is supplied from the case-head-side substrate <b>13</b> to the flexible printed circuit board <b>37</b>. A driving circuit <b>370</b> is mounted on the flexible printed circuit board <b>37</b>. The driving circuit <b>370</b> performs control processing for supplying driving signals from the case-head-side substrate <b>13</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> to the piezoelectric elements <b>36</b> on a selective basis.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">When a voltage is applied to a piezoelectric vibrator, the piezoelectric element <b>36</b> vibrates due to flexural oscillation. As a result of the vibration, ink is ejected from the nozzle orifice <b>310</b> of the nozzle plate <b>31</b>. The ink-jet recording head <b>100</b> is configured to eject ink in this way.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The embodiment described above produces the following advantageous effects.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">(1) The nozzle plate <b>31</b> is made of conductive ceramics. The nozzle plate <b>31</b> is grounded. Therefore, electric charges do not easily accumulate on the nozzle plate <b>31</b>. The migration of electric charges from the nozzle orifices <b>310</b> to the diaphragm plate <b>33</b> through ink filled in the pressure generation chambers <b>320</b> is unlikely to occur or significantly less likely to occur. Thus, it is possible to prevent the dielectric breakdown of the diaphragm plate <b>33</b> caused conventionally by accumulated electric charges and to provide the ink-jet recording head <b>100</b> that is substantially free from the damage of the driving circuit <b>370</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">(2) The nozzle plate <b>31</b> is encased in the grounded conductive cover case <b>40</b>. Therefore, besides the advantageous effect described above, the ink-jet recording head <b>100</b> offers a structure for protecting the nozzle plate <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">(3) The flow passage formation substrate <b>32</b>, the diaphragm plate <b>33</b>, and the nozzle plate <b>31</b>, each of which is made of ceramics, are co-fired. Therefore, it is possible to reduce the displacement of the flow passage formation substrate <b>32</b>, the diaphragm plate <b>33</b>, and the nozzle plate <b>31</b> relative to one another due to thermal contraction and to provide the ink-jet recording head <b>100</b> that can be assembled easily.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">(4) It is possible to provide the printer <b>1000</b> that can produce the advantageous effects described above.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The scope of the invention is not limited to the embodiment described above. It can be modified in various ways.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">For example, the flow passage formation substrate <b>32</b> may be made of conductive ceramics.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In the foregoing description, the ink-jet recording head <b>100</b> is taken as an example of a liquid ejecting head. However, a liquid ejecting head according to various aspects of the invention is not limited thereto. The invention can be applied to various types of a liquid ejecting head including but not limited to: a color material ejection head that is used in the production of a color filter for a liquid crystal display device or the like; an electrode material ejection head that is used for the electrode formation of an organic electroluminescence (EL) display device, a surface/plane emission display device (FED), and the like; and a living organic material ejection head that is used for production of biochips.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Though the printer <b>1000</b> is taken as an example of a liquid ejecting apparatus according to various aspects of the invention, the liquid ejecting apparatus may be used for industrial applications. Various kinds of functional materials that are dissolved in a solvent or dispersed in a dispersion medium to have moderate viscosity can be used as liquid (a liquid material) to be discharged. Besides an image recording apparatus such as a printer described above, the invention can be applied to various types of a liquid ejecting apparatus including but not limited to: a color material ejection apparatus that is used in the production of a color filter for a liquid crystal display device or the like; a liquid material ejection apparatus that is used for the electrode formation or color-filter production of an organic EL display device, an FED, and the like; and a living organic material ejection apparatus that is used for production of biochips.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The entire disclosure of Japanese Patent Application No. 2011-071872, filed Mar. 29, 2011 is incorporated by reference herein.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A liquid ejecting head comprising:
<claim-text>a flow passage formation substrate in which pressure generation chambers and liquid flow passages demarcated by partition walls are formed, the flow passage formation substrate being made of ceramics;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a diaphragm plate that is provided on one surface of the flow passage formation substrate to constitute a part of each of the pressure generation chambers and each of the liquid flow passages, the diaphragm plate being made of insulating ceramics;</claim-text>
<claim-text>piezoelectric elements that are provided on one surface of the diaphragm plate each at a position where the piezoelectric element overlaps the corresponding pressure generation chamber with the diaphragm plate interposed therebetween, the piezoelectric element including a pair of electrodes;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a driving circuit that is connected to the electrodes; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a nozzle plate in which nozzle orifices that are in communication with the pressure generation chambers are formed, the nozzle plate being made of conductive ceramics.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The liquid ejecting head according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a conductive cover case for encasing the nozzle plate, wherein the nozzle plate is grounded via the cover case.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The liquid ejecting head according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the flow passage formation substrate, the diaphragm plate, and the nozzle plate are co-fired.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A liquid ejecting apparatus that is provided with the liquid ejecting head according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A liquid ejecting apparatus that is provided with the liquid ejecting head according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A liquid ejecting apparatus that is provided with the liquid ejecting head according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
