<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623719-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623719</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13687240</doc-number>
<date>20121128</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>21</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438164</main-classification>
<further-classification>257E29264</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Method for forming and structure of a recessed source/drain strap for a MUGFET</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6855990</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Hu et al.</name>
<date>20050200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7172943</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Yeo et al.</name>
<date>20070200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7180134</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Yang et al.</name>
<date>20070200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7262086</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Yeo et al.</name>
<date>20070800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438149</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7268024</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Yeo et al.</name>
<date>20070900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7301206</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Yeo et al.</name>
<date>20071100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7425740</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Liu et al.</name>
<date>20080900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0275006</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Tang</name>
<date>20051200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0052027</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ke et al.</name>
<date>20070300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0287256</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Chang et al.</name>
<date>20071200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00011">
<othercit>U.S. Patent Office Communication, U.S. Appl. No. 12/876,343, Dated Aug. 16, 2012, pp. 1-7.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00012">
<othercit>U.S. Patent Office Communication, U.S. Appl. No. 12/876,343, Dated Oct. 9, 2012, pp. 1-7.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257288</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257347</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257298</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E29264</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E21411</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E29255</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438164</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12876343</doc-number>
<date>20100907</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8378394</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13687240</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130122668</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130516</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>International Business Machines Corporation</orgname>
<address>
<city>Armonk</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Anderson</last-name>
<first-name>Brent A.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Jericho</city>
<state>VT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bryant</last-name>
<first-name>Andres</first-name>
<address>
<city>Burlington</city>
<state>VT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nowak</last-name>
<first-name>Edward J.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Essex Junction</city>
<state>VT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="004" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Rankin</last-name>
<first-name>Jed H.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Richmond</city>
<state>VT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Gibb &#x26; Riley, LLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kotulak, Esq.</last-name>
<first-name>Richard M.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>International Business Machines Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Armonk</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Ahmed</last-name>
<first-name>Selim</first-name>
<department>2826</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A method and semiconductor structure includes an insulator layer on a substrate, a plurality of parallel fins above the insulator layer. Each of the fins has a central semiconductor portion and conductive end portions. At least one conductive strap is positioned within the insulator layer below the fins. The conductive strap can be perpendicular to the fins and contact the fins. The conductive strap includes recessed portions disposed within the insulator layer, below the plurality of fins, and between each of the plurality of fins, and projected portions disposed above the insulator layer, collinear with each of the plurality of fins. The conductive strap is disposed in at least one of a source region and a drain region of the semiconductor structure. A gate insulator contacts and covers the central semiconductor portion of the fins, and a gate conductor covers and contacts the gate insulator.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="140.21mm" wi="244.01mm" file="US08623719-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="248.07mm" wi="192.11mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623719-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="240.20mm" wi="197.36mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623719-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="243.50mm" wi="175.60mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623719-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="239.86mm" wi="132.42mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623719-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="210.57mm" wi="173.31mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623719-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a divisional of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 12/876,343, filed Sep. 7, 2010, the complete disclosure of which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention generally relates to spacers for FETs (Field Effect Transistors) and more particularly to the formation of a recessed source/drain strap for a MUGFET (Multi-Gate FET).</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">As the end of linear scaling of planar complementary metal oxide semiconductors (CMOS) approaches, alternative device structures are being evaluated. One of the primary candidates is FINFET (Fin Field Effect Transistor) technology, where a thin fin, or pillar of silicon is created using sub-lithographic techniques, thereby allowing placement of the gate on sides of the fin, which in the &#x201c;on&#x201d; state, fully depletes the silicon in the fin, making it a high performance device.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The term FINFET generally refers to a nonplanar, double-gate transistor. Integrated circuits that include INFETs may be fabricated on a bulk silicon substrate or, more commonly, on a silicon-on-insulator (SOI) wafer that includes an active SOI layer of a single crystal semiconductor, such as silicon, a substrate, and a buried insulator layer, e.g., a buried oxide layer that separates and electrically isolates the substrate from the semiconductor layer. Each FINFET generally includes a narrow vertical fin body of single crystal semiconductor material with vertically-projecting sidewalls. A gate contact or electrode intersects a channel region of the fin body and is isolated electrically from the fin body by a thin gate dielectric layer. At opposite ends of the fin body are heavily-doped source/drain regions.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">A multi-gate device or Multi-gate Field Effect Transistor (MUGFET) refers to a MOSFET that incorporates more than one gate into a single device. The multiple gates may be controlled by a single gate electrode, wherein the multiple gate surfaces act electrically as a single gate, or by independent gate electrodes.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In a multi-gate device, the channel is surrounded by several gates on multiple surfaces, allowing more effective suppression of &#x201c;off-state&#x201d; leakage current. Multiple gates also allow enhanced current in the &#x201c;on&#x201d; state, also known as drive current. These advantages translate to lower power consumption and enhanced device performance. Nonplanar devices are also more compact than conventional planar transistors, enabling higher transistor density, which translates to smaller overall microelectronics.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In a conventional fabrication process of a MUGFET, it is desirable to provide for electrical connection to one or more fins from a wiring level to the transistor. In particular, such connections are prone to the introduction of added (series) resistances to source and drain as well as added parasitic capacitance from gate to source and gate to drain. It is, therefore, further desirable to provide electrical connections to one or more fins in a manner that introduces minimal added series resistance and minimal added gate-to-source and gate-to-drain capacitances. A large contact area of metal silicide to highly doped regions (source and drain) of the fins is needed to attain low resistance; prior-art structures introduced to add such area have also added significantly to the capacitance between the gate and the low-resistance structures.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The purpose of the strap is to form a conductive region between the FINFETs that is both low in resistance and low in capacitance. A conductive strap recessed below the surface plane of the FINFETs limits the capacitance between the conductive strap and the gate at very low levels. A conductive strap that is planar with the fins (that shorts the ends together) has a very high capacitance to the gate region. This gate to strap capacitance results in a switching speed delay and higher power.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">An exemplary aspect of an embodiment herein includes a semiconductor structure that includes an insulator layer on a substrate, and a plurality of parallel fins above the insulator layer, relative to a bottom of the structure. Each of the fins comprises a central semiconductor portion and conductive end portions. At least one conductive strap may be positioned within the insulator layer below the fins, relative to the bottom of the structure. The conductive strap can be perpendicular to the fins and contact the fins. The conductive strap further includes recessed portions disposed within the insulator layer, below the plurality of fins, relative to the bottom of the structure, and between each of the plurality of fins, and projected portions disposed above the insulator layer, collinear with each of the plurality of fins, relative to the bottom of the structure. The conductive strap is disposed in at least one of a source and a drain region of the semiconductor structure. A gate insulator contacts and covers the central semiconductor portion of the fins, and a gate conductor covers and contacts the gate insulator.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Another exemplary aspect of an embodiment of herein includes a semiconductor structure includes an insulator layer on a substrate, and a plurality of parallel fins above the insulator layer, relative to a bottom of the semiconductor structure. Each of the fins includes a central semiconductor portion and conductive end portion, at least one conductive strap positioned within the insulator layer below the fins, relative to the bottom of the structure, the conductive strap being perpendicular to the fins and electrically connects and contacts the fins. The conductive strap produces physical strain within the central semiconductor portion of the fins, the at least one conductive strap includes recessed portions disposed within the insulator layer, below the plurality of parallel fins, relative to the bottom of the structure, and between each of the plurality of parallel fins. Projected portions extend into the fins, collinear with each of the plurality of parallel fins, relative to the bottom of the structure. A gate dielectric contacts and covers the central semiconductor portion of the fins, and a gate conductor covers and contacts the gate dielectric, wherein the at least one conductive strap electrically connects and contacts the fins. The at least one conductive strap produces a physical strain within the central semiconductor portion of the plurality of parallel fins, and the conductive strap is disposed in at least one of a source and a drain region of the semiconductor structure.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Another exemplary aspect of an embodiment of herein includes a method for creating a semiconductor structure by providing an insulator layer on a substrate, patterning the insulator layer to form at least one recess in the insulator layer, forming at least one conductive strap within the recess in the insulator layer, and patterning a plurality of parallel fins above the insulator layer, relative to a bottom of the structure. Each of the fins including a central semiconductor portion and conductive end portions, where the conductive strap is positioned within the insulator layer below the fins, relative to the bottom of the structure, and is perpendicular to the fins and contacts the fins. The conductive strap includes projected portions extending into the fins, collinear with each of the plurality of fins, relative to the bottom of the structure, forming a gate dielectric contacting and covering the central semiconductor portion of the fins. A gate conductor is formed covering and contacting the gate dielectric, wherein the conductive strap is disposed in at least one of a source and a drain region of the semiconductor structure.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Another exemplary aspect of an embodiment of herein includes a method for creating a semiconductor structure by providing an insulator layer on a substrate, patterning the insulator layer to form at least one recess in the insulator layer, forming at least one conductive strap within the recess in the insulator layer, and patterning a plurality of parallel fins above the insulator layer, relative to a bottom of the structure. Each of the fins including a central semiconductor portion and conductive end portions, the conductive strap being positioned within the insulator layer below the fins, relative to the bottom of the structure. The conductive strap is perpendicular to the fins and contacting the fins, and the conductive strap includes projected portions extending into the fins, collinear with each of the plurality of fins, relative to the bottom of the structure. A gate dielectric is formed contacting and covering the central semiconductor portion of the fins, and forming a gate conductor covering and contacting the gate dielectric. The conductive strap is disposed in at least one of a source and a drain region of the semiconductor structure, wherein the one conductive strap produces a physical strain within the central semiconductor portion of the plurality of parallel fins. The conductive strap is disposed in at least one of a source and a drain region of the semiconductor structure.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">With these features, the embodiments herein provide a source/drain strap that allows for a low capacitance connection between semiconductor fins, and the strap also provides for a large amount of silicide to contact area.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The foregoing and other exemplary purposes, aspects and advantages will be better understood from the following detailed description of an exemplary embodiment herein with reference to the drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a side-view schematic diagram that shows a fabrication process for forming a first semiconductor structure, in accordance with embodiments herein;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a side-view schematic diagram that shows a fabrication process for forming a first semiconductor structure, in accordance with embodiments herein;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a side-view schematic diagram that shows a fabrication process for forming a first semiconductor structure, in accordance with embodiments herein;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a side-view schematic diagram that shows a fabrication process for forming a first semiconductor structure, in accordance with embodiments herein;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> is a side-view schematic diagram that shows a fabrication process for forming a first semiconductor structure, in accordance with embodiments herein;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref> is a side-view schematic diagram that shows an alternative view of the fabrication process of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> for forming a first semiconductor structure, in accordance with embodiments herein;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a perspective-view schematic diagram that shows an alternative perspective view of the fabrication process of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> for forming a first semiconductor structure, in accordance with embodiments herein;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a side-view schematic diagram that shows a fabrication process for forming a first semiconductor structure, in accordance with embodiments herein; and</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a logic flowchart diagram for forming a first semiconductor structure, in accordance with embodiments herein.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Referring now to the drawings, and more particularly to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-8</figref>, there are shown exemplary embodiments of the method and structures herein.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates an embodiment herein having a starting silicon-on-insulator structure that includes a Si layer <b>12</b> formed on an insulator layer <b>11</b> on a BOX <b>10</b> (buried oxide) substrate. A nitride hardmask <b>14</b> is formed over the Si layer <b>12</b>. The Si layer <b>12</b> and nitride hardmask <b>14</b> are formed in conventional processes. For example, a Si layer <b>12</b> may be bonded to insulator layer <b>11</b>, and the nitride hardmask <b>14</b> may be deposited on the Si layer <b>12</b>, respectively. The nitride hardmask <b>14</b> may then be patterned, and etched using RIE (reactive ion etch) processes to form the nitride hardmask <b>14</b> having a mask opening <b>16</b>, which is subsequently used to form a trench <b>18</b> in the Si layer <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates an embodiment of the invention immediately after an etching process where the mask opening <b>16</b> enables an etchant to form a trench <b>18</b> through the Si layer <b>12</b> and into insulator layer <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates an embodiment of the invention where polysilicon material is deposited into the trench <b>18</b> to form a conductive polysilicon strap <b>20</b>, and after forming the polysilicon material in the trench <b>18</b>, a planarization step removes the material deposited on the top to be planar with the rest of the surface of the Si layer <b>12</b>. Additionally, the nitride hardmask <b>14</b> is removed through a planarization step so that the Si layer <b>12</b> remains. In one embodiment of the invention, the conductive polysilicon strap <b>20</b> provide a compressive or tensile strain into the channel based on the type of material deposited and/or the method of depositing the material into the trench <b>18</b>. Another embodiment of the invention may grow selective silicon on the conductive polysilicon strap <b>20</b>, or in another embodiment, the conductive polysilicon strap <b>20</b> may be silicided.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates an embodiment of invention where a second mask layer <b>22</b> is applied to the upper surface of the Si layer <b>12</b> and the upper surface of the conductive polysilicon strap <b>20</b>. The second mask layer <b>22</b> includes polysilicon strap mask patterns <b>22</b>A that allow an etchant to edge selected portions of the conductive polysilicon strap <b>20</b> below the upper surface of the Si layer <b>12</b> and into the insulator layer <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A</figref>, <b>5</b>B, and <b>6</b> illustrate an embodiment herein where semiconductor fins <b>28</b> may be etched simultaneously, or independently of the masking and etching process of the conductive polysilicon strap <b>20</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> illustrates the conductive polysilicon strap <b>20</b> having strap recesses <b>24</b> formed below an upper surface of the insulator layer <b>11</b> at a depth &#x201c;D&#x201d;, and an upper portion <b>26</b> of the conductive polysilicon strap <b>20</b> forming teeth like protrusions that extend into the semiconductor fins <b>28</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A and 5B</figref> illustrate the semiconductor fins <b>28</b> formed by a second mask layer <b>22</b> or an additional mask layer (not shown) that include a central semiconductor portion <b>28</b>A, and distal conductive end portions <b>28</b>B opposite this central semiconductor portion <b>28</b>A. The conductive polysilicon strap <b>20</b> thereby forms an electrical connection between the aligned semiconductor fins <b>28</b>. The conductive polysilicon strap <b>20</b> actually makes up a portion of the semiconductor fins <b>28</b> and, therefore, may induce a compressive or tensile stress on the semiconductor fins <b>28</b> depending on the type of material and process of formation of the conductive polysilicon strap <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> also illustrates a Source/Drain region of the semiconductor located at the distal end portions <b>28</b>B of the semiconductor fins <b>28</b>. This region is where the conductive polysilicon strap <b>20</b> is located underneath the semiconductor fins <b>28</b>. A silicide (not shown) may be formed on the Source/Drain regions of the semiconductor fins <b>28</b>, which may extend onto the conductive polysilicon strap(s) <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates an embodiment herein where a gate dielectric material <b>29</b> is deposited to cover the semiconductor fins <b>28</b> to a thickness between <b>10</b> to <b>30</b> angstroms, formed through thermal or chemical deposition. A gate conductor <b>30</b> is formed through masking, depositing the gate conductor material and etching the same, such that the gate conductor <b>30</b> is formed over the gate dielectric material <b>29</b> and the central semiconductor portions <b>28</b>A of semiconductors fins <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> illustrates a logic flow diagram of a method of fabrication of one embodiment herein. The process provides an insulator layer on a substrate <b>800</b>, and subsequently patterns and etches the insulator layer to form at least one recess in the insulator layer <b>802</b>. Material is then deposited forming at least one conductive strap within the recess in the insulator layer <b>804</b>. At <b>806</b>, a plurality of parallel fins is patterned above the insulator layer, relative to the bottom of the structure, wherein each of the fins comprises a central semiconductor portion and conductive end portions. The conductive strap may be positioned within the insulator layer below the fins, relative to the bottom of the structure; the conductive strap is perpendicular to the fins and contacts the fins. The conductive strap is disposed in the source and/or drain region of the semiconductor structure. A gate dielectric may be formed <b>808</b> contacting and covering the central semiconductor portion of the fins. Thereafter, a gate conductor is formed <b>810</b> covering and contacting the gate dielectric.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">With its features, one or more embodiments herein provide a source/drain strap that allows a low capacitance connection between semiconductor fins, wherein the strap also provides for a large amount of silicide to contact area.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The method as described above is used in the fabrication of integrated circuit chips. The resulting integrated circuit chips can be distributed by the fabricator in raw wafer form (that is, as a single wafer that has multiple unpackaged chips), as a bare die, or in a packaged form. In the latter case the chip is mounted in a single chip package (such as a plastic carrier, with leads that are affixed to a motherboard or other higher level carrier) or in a multichip package (such as a ceramic carrier that has either or both surface interconnections or buried interconnections). In any case, the chip is then integrated with other chips, discrete circuit elements, and/or other signal processing devices as part of either (a) an intermediate product, such as a motherboard, or (b) an end product. The end product can be any product that includes integrated circuit chips, ranging from toys and other low-end applications to advanced computer products having a display, a keyboard or other input device, and a central processor.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The terminology used herein is for the purpose of describing particular embodiments only and is not intended to be limiting of any embodiments herein. As used herein, the singular forms &#x2018;a&#x2019;, &#x2018;an&#x2019;, and &#x2018;the&#x2019; are intended to include the plural forms as well, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise. It will be further understood that the terms &#x2018;comprises&#x2019; and/or &#x2018;comprising,&#x2019; when used in this specification, specify the presence of stated features, integers, steps, operations, elements, and/or components, but do not preclude the presence or addition of one or more other features, integers, steps, operations, elements, components, and/or groups thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The corresponding structures, materials, acts, and equivalents of all means or step plus function elements in the claims below are intended to include any structure, material, or act for performing the function in combination with other claimed elements as specifically claimed. The description of the embodiments herein has been presented for purposes of illustration and description, but is not intended to be exhaustive or limited to the embodiments herein in the form disclosed. Many modifications and variations will be apparent to those of ordinary skill in the art without departing from the scope and spirit of the embodiments herein. The embodiment was chosen and described in order to best explain the principles of the embodiments herein and the practical application, and to enable others of ordinary skill in the art to understand the embodiments herein for various embodiments with various modifications as are suited to the particular use contemplated.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method of creating a semiconductor structure comprising:
<claim-text>providing an insulator layer on a substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>patterning said insulator layer to form at least one recess in said insulator layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming at least one conductive strap within said at least one recess in said insulator layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>patterning a plurality of fins above said insulator layer, relative to a bottom of said semiconductor structure, each of said fins comprising a central semiconductor portion and conductive end portions, said at least one conductive strap being positioned within said insulator layer below said plurality of fins, relative to said bottom of said semiconductor structure, said plurality of fins being parallel to each other, and said at least one conductive strap being perpendicular to said fins and contacting said fins, and said at least one conductive strap comprising projected portions extending into said fins, collinear with each of said plurality of fins, relative to said bottom of said semiconductor structure;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a gate dielectric contacting and covering said central semiconductor portion of said plurality of fins; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a gate conductor contacting and covering said gate dielectric,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said at least one conductive strap being disposed in at least one of a source region and a drain region of said semiconductor structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of creating a semiconductor structure according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, said forming said at least one conductive strap comprising depositing in said recess one of a silicon component and a metal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of creating a semiconductor structure according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising siliciding at least a portion of said at least one conductive strap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of creating a semiconductor structure according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, each of said plurality of fins having a height, width, and length, said patterning said plurality of fins comprising forming said height to be greater than said width and said length to be greater than said height.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of creating a semiconductor structure according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, said conductive end portions of said fins comprising said source regions and said drain regions of said fins.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A method of creating a semiconductor structure comprising:
<claim-text>providing an insulator layer on a substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>patterning said insulator layer to form at least one recess in said insulator layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming at least one conductive strap within said at least one recess in said insulator layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>patterning a plurality of fins above said insulator layer, relative to a bottom of said semiconductor structure, each of said fins comprising a central semiconductor portion and conductive end portions,
<claim-text>said at least one conductive strap being positioned within said insulator layer below said fins, relative to said bottom of said semiconductor structure,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said plurality of fins being parallel to each other and said at least one conductive strap being perpendicular to said fins and contacting said fins, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said at least one conductive strap comprising projected portions extending into said fins, collinear with each of said plurality of fins, relative to said bottom of said semiconductor structure;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a gate dielectric contacting and covering said central semiconductor portion of said plurality of fins; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a gate conductor contacting and covering said gate dielectric,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said at least one conductive strap electrically contacting and connecting said fins,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said at least one conductive strap producing a physical strain within said central semiconductor portion of said plurality of fins, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said at least one conductive strap being disposed in at least one of a source region and a drain region of said semiconductor structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of creating a semiconductor structure according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, said forming said at least one conductive strap comprising depositing in said recess one of a silicon component and a metal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method of creating a semiconductor structure according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, further comprising siliciding at least a portion of said at least one conductive strap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of creating a semiconductor structure according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, each of said plurality of fins having a height, width, and length, said patterning said plurality of fins comprising forming said height to be greater than said width and said length to be greater than said height.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of creating a semiconductor structure according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, said conductive end portions of said fins comprising said source regions and said drain regions of said fins.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A method comprising:
<claim-text>providing a silicon-on-insulator (SOI) structure comprising a silicon layer formed on an insulator layer formed on a buried oxide substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>patterning said SOI structure to form at least one recess through said silicon layer and at least partially into said insulator layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a conductive strap within said at least one recess;</claim-text>
<claim-text>patterning a plurality of fins above said SOI structure, relative to a bottom of said SOI structure, each of said fins comprising a central semiconductor portion and conductive end portions,
<claim-text>said conductive strap being positioned within said insulator layer below said plurality of fins, relative to said bottom of said SOI structure,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said plurality of fins being parallel to each other, and said conductive strap being perpendicular to said fins and contacting said fins, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said conductive strap comprising projected portions extending into said fins, collinear with each of said plurality of fins, relative to said bottom of said SOI structure;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a gate dielectric on at least a portion of said plurality of fins, said gate dielectric contacting and covering said central semiconductor portion of said plurality of fins; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a gate conductor on said gate dielectric, said gate conductor contacting and covering said gate dielectric,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said conductive strap being disposed in at least one of a source region and a drain region of said SOI structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, said forming of said conductive strap comprising depositing in said recess one of a silicon component and a metal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further comprising siliciding at least a portion of said conductive strap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, each of said plurality of fins having a height, width, and length, said patterning said plurality of fins comprising forming said height to be greater than said width and said length to be greater than said height.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, said conductive end portions of said fins comprising source regions and drain regions of a field effect transistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A method comprising:
<claim-text>providing a silicon-on-insulator (SOI) structure comprising a silicon layer formed on an insulator layer formed on a buried oxide substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>patterning said SOI structure to form at least one recess through said silicon layer and at least partially into said insulator layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a conductive strap within said at least one recess;</claim-text>
<claim-text>patterning a plurality of fins above said SOI structure, relative to a bottom of said SOI structure, each of said fins comprising a central semiconductor portion and conductive end portions,
<claim-text>said conductive strap being positioned within said insulator layer below said plurality of fins, relative to said bottom of said SOI structure,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said plurality of fins being parallel to each other, and said conductive strap being perpendicular to said fins and contacting said fins, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said conductive strap comprising projected portions extending into said fins, collinear with each of said plurality of fins, relative to said bottom of said SOI structure;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a gate dielectric on at least a portion of said plurality of fins, said gate dielectric contacting and covering said central semiconductor portion of said plurality of fins; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a gate conductor on said gate dielectric, said gate conductor contacting and covering said gate dielectric,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said conductive strap electrically contacting and connecting said fins,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said conductive strap producing a physical strain within said central semiconductor portion of said plurality of fins, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said conductive strap being disposed in at least one of a source region and a drain region of said SOI structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, said forming of said conductive strap comprising depositing in said recess one of a silicon component and a metal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, further comprising siliciding at least a portion of said conductive strap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, each of said plurality of fins having a height, width, and length, said patterning said plurality of fins comprising forming said height to be greater than said width and said length to be greater than said height.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, said conductive end portions of said fins comprising source regions and drain regions of a field effect transistor. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
