<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624291-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624291</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13091581</doc-number>
<date>20110421</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2011-016085</doc-number>
<date>20110128</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>280</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20100101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>33</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257103</main-classification>
<further-classification>257E33024</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Crystalline aluminum carbide thin film, semiconductor substrate having the aluminum carbide thin film formed thereon and method of fabricating the same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5632827</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Fujita et al.</name>
<date>19970500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>148688</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0171102</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ro et al.</name>
<date>20060800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>361516</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0080352</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Wu et al.</name>
<date>20070400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257 79</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>52061475</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19770500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00005">
<othercit>&#x201c;Composition and Mechanical Properties of AlC, AlN and AlCN thin films obtained by r.f. magnetron sputtering&#x201d; by L. Yate et al., Surface and Coatings Technology, 203, 1904-1907 (2009).</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>8</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257 76</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257103</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E29003</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E33024</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>9</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>18</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120193640</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120802</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sakai</last-name>
<first-name>Shiro</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tokushima</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sakai</last-name>
<first-name>Shiro</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tokushima</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>H.C. Park &#x26; Associates, PLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Seoul Opto Device Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Ansan-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Tran</last-name>
<first-name>Minh-Loan T</first-name>
<department>2826</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Embodiments of the invention provide a crystalline aluminum carbide thin film, a semiconductor substrate having the crystalline aluminum carbide thin film formed thereon, and a method of fabricating the same. Further, the method of fabricating the AlC thin film includes supplying a carbon containing gas and an aluminum containing gas to a furnace, to growing AlC crystals on a substrate.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="53.17mm" wi="157.90mm" file="US08624291-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="52.07mm" wi="160.61mm" file="US08624291-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="224.96mm" wi="161.80mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624291-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="242.32mm" wi="140.80mm" file="US08624291-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="180.42mm" wi="131.74mm" file="US08624291-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="157.56mm" wi="156.80mm" file="US08624291-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="218.78mm" wi="172.13mm" file="US08624291-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="216.83mm" wi="146.90mm" file="US08624291-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="231.56mm" wi="154.26mm" file="US08624291-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="124.54mm" wi="172.13mm" file="US08624291-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority from and the benefit of Japanese Patent Application No. JP2011-016085, filed on Jan. 28, 2011, which is hereby incorporated by reference for all purposes as if fully set forth herein.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Exemplary embodiments of the present invention relate to a crystalline aluminum carbide thin film, a semiconductor substrate having a crystalline aluminum carbide thin film formed thereon, and a method of fabricating the same.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Discussion of the Background</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">A light emitting diode (LED) including a gallium nitride (GaN) based semiconductor may be used for various applications, such as signal devices, backlight units for liquid crystal panels, and the like. Since AlGaInN-based LEDs have a wavelength band of 260&#x2dc;290 nm or 360&#x2dc;600 nm, an AlGaN-based active layer may be included to produce a shorter wavelength band (300&#x2dc;340 nm). As such, Al<sub>x</sub>Ga<sub>1-x</sub>N-based semiconductor materials have been continuously developed. At a wavelength of 280 nm, it is possible to obtain a light extraction efficiency of 10% or more.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">However, since AlGaN is liable to be split and has higher dislocation density, an AlGaN material used in a wavelength band from 300 nm to 360 nm has not yet been developed. Current reports say that LEDs exhibit a light extraction efficiency of at most 8%, in a wavelength band of 300&#x2dc;350 nm.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Generally, elements located at an upper part of the periodic table emit light at shorter wavelengths. Although BN or C have the shortest wavelengths, these components are not suited for general light emitting materials, since the growth of these materials requires high temperatures of 2500&#xb0; C. or more. AlN may be used instead of these materials. Namely, investigations have been made to develop a material that emits light at a short wavelength (&#x3bb;=210 nm) using AlN. However, AlGaN has a low light extraction efficiency, as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Meanwhile, aluminum carbide Al<sub>4</sub>C<sub>3 </sub>(hereinafter, &#x201c;AlC&#x201d;) is an important compound in aluminum technology, due to its high electric resistance and high thermal conductivity at room temperature. Since AlCN, which is an aluminum compound similar to AlC, can be used in various applications, such as microelectronics, photonic technology, and the like, is due to its wide band gap, high chemical stability, and high hardness, AlC is also anticipated to have the same capabilities as AlCN. AlC is a III-IV group-based material and is generally known as a nano-processing material.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In order to use AlC for a semiconductor substrate, particularly, for LEDs, it is necessary to provide a thin film exhibiting excellent crystallinity. However, crystalline thin films formed using AlC has not yet been developed. Currently, only a non-crystalline thin film of AlC is reported by L. Yate et al., Surface and Coatings Technology, 203, 1904 (2009).</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Exemplary embodiments of the invention provide a crystalline aluminum carbide thin film, a semiconductor substrate having the crystalline aluminum carbide thin film formed thereon, and a method of fabricating the same.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Additional features of the invention will be set forth in the description which follows, and in part will be apparent from the description, or may be learned by practice of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">An exemplary embodiment of the invention provides a crystalline aluminum carbide (AlC) thin film. The AlC thin film may emit light at a wavelength in the range of 310 nm to 413 nm in cathode luminescence (CL) measurement. The AlC thin film may have a band gap from 3.4 eV to 4.3 eV in a transmittance measurement. The AlC thin film may be formed on a sapphire substrate or a silicon carbide substrate. The AlC thin film may be formed on a c-plane of the sapphire substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">An exemplary embodiment of the invention provides a semiconductor substrate having a crystalline AlC thin film.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">An exemplary embodiment of the invention provides a method of fabricating an AlC thin film. The method includes supplying a carbon-containing gas and an aluminum-containing gas to form an AlC thin film, by growing AlC crystals on a substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">An exemplary embodiment of the invention provides a method of fabricating a semiconductor substrate having an AlC thin film formed thereon. The method includes supplying a carbon-containing gas and an aluminum containing gas to form an AlC thin film, by growing a AlC crystals on a substrate.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The accompanying drawings, which are included to provide a further understanding of the invention and are incorporated in and constitute a part of this specification, illustrate embodiments of the invention, and together with the description serve to explain the principles of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a view of a semiconductor substrate, in accordance with an exemplary embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a graph depicting conditions for fabricating an AlC thin film on the semiconductor substrate, in accordance with an exemplary embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3(</figref><i>a</i>) shows a relationship between a growth temperature and a growth rate of an AlC thin film, in accordance with an exemplary embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3(</figref><i>b</i>) shows a relationship between a flow rate of TMA and a growth rate of the AlC thin film.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3(</figref><i>c</i>) shows a relationship between a IV/III ratio and the growth rate of the AlC thin film.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>a</i>) is a scanning electron microscope (SEM) image of an AlC thin film formed at 700&#xb0; C.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>b</i>) is a (SEM) image of an AlC thin film formed at 1150&#xb0; C.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>c</i>) is a scanning electron microscope (SEM) image of an AlC thin film formed at 1200&#xb0; C.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5(</figref><i>a</i>) is an SEM image of a side section of a semiconductor substrate having an AlC film formed at 1150&#xb0; C.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5(</figref><i>b</i>) is an SEM image of a side section of a semiconductor substrate having an AlC film formed at 1200&#xb0; C.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a graph of an XRD measurement of the semiconductor substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7(</figref><i>a</i>) is an SEM image of a side section of the semiconductor substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7(</figref><i>b</i>) shows an energy dispersive X-ray spectrometer (EDX) result for aluminum detection.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7(</figref><i>c</i>) shows an EXD result for carbon detection.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7(</figref><i>d</i>) shows an EXD result for oxygen detection.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8(</figref><i>a</i>) shows a CL measurement of an AlC thin film formed at 700&#xb0; C.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8(</figref><i>b</i>) shows a CL measurement of an AlC thin film formed at 1200&#xb0; C.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a graph depicting a result of transmittance measurement for the semiconductor substrate having the AlC thin film.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE ILLUSTRATED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The invention is described more fully hereinafter with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which exemplary embodiments of the invention are shown. This invention may, however, be embodied in many different forms and should not be construed as limited to the embodiments set forth herein. Rather, these exemplary embodiments are provided so that this disclosure is thorough, and will fully convey the scope of the invention to those skilled in the art. In the drawings, the sizes and relative sizes of layers and regions may be exaggerated for clarity. Like elements will be denoted by like reference numerals and repeated descriptions thereof will be omitted herein.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">It will be understood that when an element or layer is referred to as being &#x201c;on&#x201d; or &#x201c;connected to&#x201d; another element or layer, it can be directly on or directly connected to the other element or layer, or intervening elements or layers may be present. In contrast, when an element is referred to as being &#x201c;directly on&#x201d; or &#x201c;directly connected to&#x201d; another element or layer, there are no intervening elements or layers present.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The inventors of the invention investigated materials, fabrication conditions, and the like to obtain a crystalline aluminum carbide thin film (hereinafter, referred to as an &#x201c;AlC thin film&#x201d;) and finally developed a crystalline AlC thin film on a c-plane of the sapphire substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">An AlC thin film, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure, may be evaluated using a scanning electron microscope (SEM), X-ray diffraction (XRD), an energy dispersive x-ray spectrometer (EDX), cathode luminescence (CL), and/or a transmittance measurement. Since Al<sub>4</sub>C<sub>3 </sub>generally has a yellow color, when the AlC thin film is formed on a substrate formed of a different material than the AlC thin film, AlC thin film can be observed with the naked eye or an optical microscope, in that the substrate appears to have a yellow color. Further, it can be seen through SEM observation that crystals are grown on the substrate. Through an SEM image of a side section of the substrate, the AlC thin film is shown to be formed on the substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The AlC thin film has a peak near 35&#xb0; in 2&#x3b8;-&#x3c9; mode of XRD, which is caused by Al<sub>4</sub>C<sub>3 </sub>crystals. Further, when the AlC thin film is formed on a substrate having a different crystal structure from the Al<sub>4</sub>C<sub>3 </sub>crystals, peaks caused by the crystals of the substrate are also detected. For example, when the AlC thin film is formed on a c-plane of a sapphire substrate, peaks near 38&#xb0; and 42&#xb0; are detected, which are caused by the sapphire substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">An EDX image shows the presence of aluminum and carbon in the AlC thin film. In the EDX image showing the presence of aluminum and carbon, since the AlC thin film has crystallinity, aluminum and carbon are detected in a dispersed state. The aluminum and carbon may be uniformly dispersed in the AlC thin film.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In a CL measurement, the AlC thin film emits light in a wavelength range of from 310 nm to 413 nm, which is caused by the Al<sub>4</sub>C<sub>3 </sub>crystals. The AlC thin film has a peak near 340 nm and exhibits light extraction in a wavelength band of 300&#x2dc;350 nm, when used in an LED.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In a transmittance measurement, the AlC thin film has a band gap of from 3.4 eV to 4.3 eV. Further, the AlC thin film has a direct transition in the region of the band gap, that is, in a luminescence energy region. Here, the direct transition refers to a state in which the square of the transmittance ratio is proportional to energy, in a plot of values obtained by dividing the transmittance ratio of the Al<sub>4</sub>C<sub>3</sub>/substrate by the transmittance ratio of the substrate, with respect to the energy. Further, the AlC thin film may be adjusted to have an indirect band gap, by adjusting a fabrication temperature thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">As described above, although only a non-crystalline AlC thin film has been reported in the art, the present crystalline AlC thin film may be applied to a crystalline semiconductor layer, which demonstrates the characteristics described above. Further, when used in an LED, the AlC thin film exhibits light extraction in the wavelength band of 300&#x2dc;350 nm.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a view of a semiconductor substrate <b>100</b>, in accordance with an exemplary embodiment of the invention. The semiconductor substrate <b>100</b> includes an AlC thin film <b>10</b> formed on an upper surface of a substrate <b>20</b>. Here, the substrate <b>20</b> may be any type of substrate that can be used for AlC crystal growth in the field of semiconductors, particularly, in the field of LEDs. For example, the substrate <b>20</b> may be a sapphire substrate or a silicon carbide substrate. When the sapphire substrate is used as the substrate <b>20</b>, the AlC thin film <b>10</b> may be formed on a c-plane of the sapphire substrate <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The semiconductor substrate <b>100</b> may be evaluated using a scanning electron microscope (SEM), X-ray diffraction (XRD), energy dispersive x-ray spectroscopy (EDX), cathode luminescence (CL), and transmittance measurements.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">When observed with the naked eye or an optical microscope, the AlC thin film <b>10</b> formed on the substrate <b>20</b> can be observed to impart a yellow color to the substrate. Further, using a SEM, it can be seen that crystals are grown on the substrate <b>20</b>. Through an SEM image of a side section of the substrate, the AlC thin film <b>10</b> is shown to be formed on the substrate <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The AlC thin film <b>10</b> has a peak near 35&#xb0; in 2&#x3b8;-&#x3c9; w mode of XRD, which is caused by Al<sub>4</sub>C<sub>3 </sub>crystals. Further, peaks caused by the crystal of the substrate <b>20</b> are detected, in addition to the peaks caused by the Al<sub>4</sub>C<sub>3 </sub>crystals. For example, when the AlC thin film <b>10</b> is formed on a c-plane of the sapphire substrate <b>20</b>, peaks near 38&#xb0; and 42&#xb0; are detected, which are caused by the sapphire substrate <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">An EDX image shows the presence of aluminum and carbon in the semiconductor substrate <b>100</b>. In the EDX image showing the presence of aluminum and carbon, since the AlC thin film <b>10</b> is crystalline, aluminum and carbon are detected in a dispersed state. In this embodiment, aluminum and carbon may be uniformly dispersed in the AlC thin film <b>10</b>. Further, when a sapphire substrate is used as the substrate <b>20</b>, aluminum is also detected in the sapphire substrate, whereas carbon is detected in the AlC thin film <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In a CL measurement, the semiconductor substrate <b>100</b> emits light in the wavelength range of from 310 nm to 413 nm, as a result of the Al<sub>4</sub>C<sub>3 </sub>crystals. The semiconductor substrate <b>100</b> has a peak near 340 nm and exhibits light extraction in a wavelength band of 300&#x2dc;350 nm, when used in an LED.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In transmittance measurement, the semiconductor substrate <b>100</b> has a band gap of from 3.4 eV to 4.3 eV. Further, the semiconductor substrate <b>100</b> has a direct transition in the region of the band gap, that is, in a luminescence energy region. Further, the semiconductor substrate <b>100</b> may be adjusted to have an indirect band gap, by controlling the fabrication temperature thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">As described above, although an AlC thin film only for a non-crystalline thin film has been reported in the art, the semiconductor substrate <b>100</b> may allow a crystalline AlC thin film to be formed. Accordingly, the semiconductor substrate <b>100</b> demonstrates the characteristics described above. Further, when used in an LED, the semiconductor substrate <b>100</b> exhibits light extraction in the wavelength band of 300&#x2dc;350 nm.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Metal organic vapor deposition (MOCVD) may be used to fabricate the crystalline AlC thin <b>10</b> film and the semiconductor substrate <b>100</b>. In this embodiment, the crystalline AlC thin film <b>10</b> is grown on an upper surface of the substrate <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Raw materials for the AlC thin film <b>10</b> include a carbon-containing gas and an aluminum-containing gas. The carbon-containing gas may be methane (CH<sub>4</sub>) and the aluminum-containing gas may be tri-methyl aluminum ((CH<sub>3</sub>)<sub>3</sub>Al; hereinafter &#x201c;TMA&#x201d;). Further, hydrogen (H<sub>2</sub>) may be used as a carrier gas. The respective raw materials may be commercial materials used in the field of semiconductors, particularly, in the field of LEDs.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The TMA may be may be supplied at flow rates of from 33 &#x3bc;mol/min to 66 &#x3bc;mol/min, and the methane may be supplied at flow rates of 13 mmol/min to 27 mmol/min, to grow the AlC crystals. Further, the AlC crystals are grown at a temperature of 700&#xb0; C. or more, or at a temperature of 1100&#xb0; C. or more. Although time for growing the AlC crystals depends on the flow rate of raw materials and/or the thickness of the AlC thin film <b>10</b>, the time for growing the AlC crystals may be in the range of, for example, 60&#x2dc;120 minutes. The substrate <b>20</b> may be annealed, by supplying hydrogen gas before growing the AlC crystals. Annealing may be performed at 1150&#xb0; C. for 10 minutes, for example, when the flow rate of hydrogen gas is 10 slm.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">By the method described above, it is possible to form a crystalline AlC thin film on a semiconductor substrate. Accordingly, the semiconductor substrate demonstrates the characteristics described above. Further, when used in an LED, the semiconductor substrate exhibits light extraction in the wavelength band of 300&#x2dc;350 nm.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a graph depicting conditions for fabricating the AlC thin film <b>10</b> formed on the semiconductor substrate <b>100</b>, in accordance with an exemplary embodiment of the invention. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, &#x201c;Car(III)&#x201d; indicates the flow rate of hydrogen supplied as the carrier gas of TMA, &#x201c;Car(IV)&#x201d; indicates the flow rate of hydrogen supplied as the carrier gas of CH<sub>4</sub>, &#x201c;Sub&#x201d; indicates the flow rate of hydrogen for re-dilution of Car(III) and Car(IV), and &#x201c;Counter&#x201d; indicates the flow rate of nitrogen towards an upper side of a furnace that faces the substrate <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3(</figref><i>a</i>) shows a relationship between the growth temperature and the growth rate of the AlC thin film <b>10</b>. Although the AlC thin film <b>10</b> could be grown at a temperature of 700&#xb0; C., the growth rate was slow at this temperature. A meaningful growth rate could be measured beginning at a temperature of 1100&#xb0; C. Further, a furnace used for this example was operated at a temperature of 1200&#xb0; C.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4(</figref><i>a</i>), <b>4</b>(<i>b</i>), and <b>4</b>(<i>c</i>) are SEM images of AlC thin films formed at 700&#xb0; C., 1150&#xb0; C., and 1200&#xb0; C., respectively. Each of the figures is obtained by observing the semiconductor substrate <b>100</b> including the AlC thin film <b>10</b>, from an upper side of the substrate <b>100</b>. In this example, a SM6499 (Nippon Electronic Corporation) was used as the SEM. At a growth temperature of 1150&#xb0; C. or more, AlC crystals were observed.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5(</figref><i>a</i>) and <b>5</b>(<i>b</i>) are SEM images of side sections of semiconductor substrates <b>100</b> having AlC thin films formed at 1150&#xb0; C. and 1200&#xb0; C., respectively. At 1150&#xb0; C. and 1200&#xb0; C., it was observed that AlC thin films <b>10</b> were formed on the upper surface of the substrates <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3(</figref><i>b</i>) shows the relationship between the flow rates of TMA and the growth rates of AlC thin films. In this example, the growth temperature was set to 1150&#xb0; C. and the flow rate of methane was set to 13.4 mmol/min. The flow rate of TMA was set to 5.1 &#x3bc;mol/min, 6.6 &#x3bc;mol/min, 33 &#x3bc;mol/min, and 66 &#x3bc;mol/min. As the flow rate of TMA increased, the growth rate of the AlC thin film increased.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3(</figref><i>c</i>) shows a relationship between the IV/III ratio and the growth rate of the AlC thin films. In this example, the growth temperature was set to 1150&#xb0; C. The IV/III ratio was set to 203, 406, 812, 4032, and 5261. At a IV/III ratio of 406, the highest growth rate was achieved.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows XRD measurement results. In this example, an X&#x2032;pert MRD (Philips Co., Ltd.) was used as the XRD apparatus. The peaks caused by sapphire used for the substrate were observed near 38&#xb0; and 42&#xb0;. For the AlC thin films formed at 1100&#xb0; C. and 1150&#xb0; C., a peak caused by the Al<sub>4</sub>C<sub>3 </sub>crystals was detected near 35&#xb0;, in addition to the peaks caused by sapphire. The AlC thin film formed even at a growth temperature of 700&#xb0; C. had low growth efficiency. As a result, when the thin film was grown for 60 minutes in this example, the Al<sub>4</sub>C<sub>3 </sub>crystal peak was not detected.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Next, the semiconductor substrate <b>100</b> having the AlC thin film <b>10</b> formed thereon was examined by EDX. In this example, a Link ISIS (Oxford Co., Ltd.) was used as the EDX. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7(</figref><i>a</i>) is a SEM image of a side section of the semiconductor substrate <b>100</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7(</figref><i>b</i>) shows a result of aluminum detection, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7(</figref><i>c</i>) shows a result of carbon detection, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7(</figref><i>d</i>) shows a result of oxygen detection. Aluminum was detected in both the AlC thin film <b>10</b> and the sapphire substrate <b>20</b>. Carbon was detected in the AlC thin film <b>10</b>, and oxygen was detected in the sapphire substrate <b>20</b>. From these results, it can be seen that the AlC thin film <b>10</b> is formed on the upper surface of the sapphire substrate <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Next, a CL measurement was performed with respect to the semiconductor substrate <b>100</b> having the AlC thin film <b>10</b> formed thereon. In this example, a MONO CL2 (Oxford Co., Ltd.) was used as the CL testing apparatus. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8(</figref><i>a</i>) shows a result of CL measurement for the AlC thin film <b>10</b> formed at 700&#xb0; C., and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8(</figref><i>b</i>) shows a result of CL measurement for the AlC thin film <b>10</b> formed at 1200&#xb0; C. In the AlC thin film <b>10</b> formed at 1200&#xb0; C., light emission was detected in the wavelength range of 310 nm to 413 nm, typically near a wavelength of 340 nm, and the half width at half maximum was 50 nm. On the other hand, in CL measurement of the AlC thin film <b>10</b> formed at 700&#xb0; C., a wide peak including a wavelength longer than 340 nm was detected. From these results, it can be assumed that the AlC thin film <b>10</b> formed at 1200&#xb0; C. had good film quality.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Last, transmittance measurement was performed with respect to the semiconductor substrate <b>100</b> having the AlC thin film <b>10</b> formed thereon. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a graph depicting a result of the transmittance measurement for the semiconductor substrate <b>100</b> having the AlC thin film <b>10</b> formed at 1200&#xb0; C. In the graph of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the band gap of the AlC thin film <b>10</b> was typically about 3.4 eV and exhibited a direct transition. In other conditions, the AlC thin film <b>10</b> had a band gap of 3.4 eV to 4.3 eV.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">As such, the exemplary embodiments of the invention provide a crystalline aluminum carbide thin film, a semiconductor substrate having the crystalline aluminum carbide thin film formed thereon, and a method of fabricating the same.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">It will be apparent to those skilled in the art that various modifications and variation can be made in the present invention without departing from the spirit or scope of the invention. Thus, it is intended that the present invention cover the modifications and variations of this invention provided they come within the scope of the appended claims and their equivalents.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A crystalline aluminum carbide (AlC) thin film configured to emit light at a wavelength in the range of 310 nm to 413 nm, in a cathode luminescence (CL) measurement.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The AlC thin film of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the AlC thin film is formed on a c-plane of a sapphire substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A crystalline aluminum carbide (AlC) thin film having a band gap of from 3.4 eV to 4.3 eV, in a transmittance measurement.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A crystalline aluminum carbide (AlC) thin film disposed on a sapphire substrate or a silicon carbide substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A semiconductor substrate comprising a crystalline AlC thin film disposed on a sapphire substrate or a silicon carbide substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The semiconductor substrate of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the AlC thin film is formed on a c-plane of a sapphire substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The semiconductor substrate of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the AlC thin film emits light at a wavelength in the range of 310 nm to 413 nm, in a cathode luminescence (CL) measurement.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The semiconductor substrate of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claims 5</claim-ref>, wherein the AlC thin film has a band gap from 3.4 eV to 4.3 eV, in a transmittance measurement. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
