<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622035-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622035</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13136759</doc-number>
<date>20110810</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10 2009 008 422</doc-number>
<date>20090211</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>239</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>9</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123 9011</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Valve drive control device</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5544628</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Voigt</name>
<date>19960800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>123 9016</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6967550</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Elendt et al.</name>
<date>20051100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>335229</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7409938</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Dengler</name>
<date>20080800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>123 9018</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>200680025863</doc-number>
<date>20080700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>201 14 466</doc-number>
<date>20020200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10 20063 015 233</doc-number>
<date>20071000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10 2006 051 809</doc-number>
<date>20080500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10 2006 059188</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20080600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>11</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123 9016</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123 9011</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>25112901</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>25112915</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>25112916</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation-in-part>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>PCT/EP2010/000429</doc-number>
<date>20100126</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13136759</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation-in-part>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120037102</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120216</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Meintschel</last-name>
<first-name>Jens</first-name>
<address>
<city>Bernsdorf</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Stolk</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kirchheim</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>von Gaisberg-Helfenberg</last-name>
<first-name>Alexander</first-name>
<address>
<city>Beilstein</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Meintschel</last-name>
<first-name>Jens</first-name>
<address>
<city>Bernsdorf</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Stolk</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kirchheim</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>von Gaisberg-Helfenberg</last-name>
<first-name>Alexander</first-name>
<address>
<city>Beilstein</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bach</last-name>
<first-name>Kraus J.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Daimler AG</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Stuttgart</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Chang</last-name>
<first-name>Ching</first-name>
<department>3748</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">In a valve drive control device, in particular for an internal combustion engine, for controlling the position of a cam element on a camshaft, the valve drive comprises at least one control armature element and a control element connected to the control armature element for engagement with a control gate of the cam element for controlling axial positioning of the cam element on the camshaft. The valve drive control device has a coupling unit which is provided to couple the control armature element and the control element movably to each other with at least one degree of freedom.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="116.42mm" wi="258.40mm" file="US08622035-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="170.86mm" wi="145.12mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622035-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="201.59mm" wi="169.93mm" file="US08622035-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="143.17mm" wi="140.29mm" file="US08622035-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="130.39mm" wi="138.60mm" file="US08622035-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="145.20mm" wi="146.81mm" file="US08622035-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="144.86mm" wi="144.86mm" file="US08622035-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This is a Continuation-In-Part application of pending international patent application PCT/EP2010/000429 filed Jan. 26, 2010 and claiming the priority of German patent application 10 2009 008 422.3 filed Feb. 11, 2009.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The invention relates to a valve drive control device for controlling a valve drive in particular of an internal combustion engine, with an armature element having a control element for coupling the armature element to a cam element for controlling axial positioning of the cam element.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">DE 10 2006 051 809 A1 discloses a valve drive control device, particularly for an internal combustion engine, for controlling a valve drive with at least one control armature element provided for a control movement, and with a control element provided for a engagement in a control gate of a cam element, wherein the control armature element and the control element can be moved relative to each other in a longitudinal direction.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">From DE 10 2006 015 233 A1a valve drive control device, particularly for controlling a valve drive in an internal combustion engine, is known. The valve drive control device comprises at least one control armature element which is provided for a control movement, and a control element, which is provided for a coupling to a control gate of a cam element, wherein the control armature element and the control element are coupled to each other.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In DE 10 2006 059 188 A1a valve drive control device, particularly for controlling a valve drive in an internal combustion engine, is described, which has at least one control armature element provided for a control movement, and a control element provided for a coupling to a control gate of a cam element, wherein a coupling of the control armature element and the control element is provided.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">It is the principal object of the invention to optimize a control process triggered by the valve drive control device.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In a valve drive control device, in particular for an internal combustion engine, for controlling the position of a cam element on a camshaft, the valve drive comprises at least one control armature element and a control element for engagement with a control gate of the cam element for controlling axial positioning of the cam element on the camshaft. The valve drive control device has a coupling unit which is provided to couple the control armature element and the control element movably to each other with at least one degree of freedom.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">It is suggested that the valve drive control device has a coupling unit which is provided for coupling the control armature element and the control element movably to each other with at least one degree of freedom. An advantageous guidance of the control element can be achieved thereby, whereby a control process implemented by means of the valve control device can be optimized in a particularly simple manner. A &#x201c;degree of freedom&#x201d; is particularly meant to be a movement parameter of a system, which is independent of further parameters, as for example a linear movement and/or a rotational movement. The coupling unit preferably has at least two degrees of freedom and particularly preferred at least three degrees of freedom.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The control element is preferably formed at least partially as a slide shoe. The control element can thereby be coupled to the control gate in a particular advantageous manner.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">It is further suggested that the control armature element is formed at least partially as, or provided with, a control pin. The control element can thereby be coupled to the control movement of the control armature in a particularly simple manner.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">It is further suggested that the coupling unit is provided for at least one degree of freedom in the form of a rotational movement. A particularly simple and advantageous coupling between the control element and the control armature element can be achieved thereby.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">It is further suggested that the at least one degree of freedom is formed as a rotational movement around a rotational axis extending along the direction of a main extension of the control armature element. The control element can thereby advantageously adapt to the course of a gate path and the course of a displacement curve of the gate path in its orientation in a particularly simple manner. The rotational movement is preferably formed as a free rotational movement, where a possible angle of the rotational movement is 360&#xb0; and a free rotational movement is thus possible. The rotational movement can basically also be restricted.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">It is further suggested that the at least one degree of freedom is formed as a rotational movement around a rotational axis along a main direction of extension of the control element. A lateral tilting of the control element can thereby be compensated in an effective manner. This rotational movement is advantageously formed as a restricted rotational movement, that is, a rotational movement, whose possible angle is restricted to an angle smaller than 360&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">It is further suggested that the at least one degree of freedom is formed as a rotational movement around a rotational axis vertical to a main extension direction of the control armature element and/or vertical to a main direction of extension of the control element. A height course of the gate path can thereby be compensated in a particular advantageous manner. This rotational movement is preferably also formed as a restricted rotational movement.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">It is further suggested that the coupling unit comprises a ball head and a recess corresponding to the ball head. The coupling unit can thereby be constructively designed in a particularly simple manner. A coupling unit can thereby particularly be provided, which only has degrees of freedom in the form of rotational movements.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">It is further suggested that the ball head is arranged at one end of the control armature element. A particularly simple forming of the coupling unit can be achieved thereby.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">It is further suggested that the recess is formed at least partially within the control element. A guide of the control element can thereby be provided in a particularly simple manner. Furthermore, an additional constructions space can be saved by the design of the recess formed for receiving the ball head within the control element. &#x201c;Within the control element&#x201d; is thereby particularly meant to be spatially between functional surfaces of the control element.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The coupling unit is preferably provided for a form-fit coupling. A coupling between the control armature element and the control element can thereby be provided, which can be assembled in a particularly simple manner and which has a high load capacity.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">It is further suggested that the control element is formed in a rotation-symmetrical manner. An advantageous guide of the control element by means of the control gate can be achieved thereby. &#x201c;Rotation symmetrical&#x201d; shall thereby particularly mean at least partially ellipsoidal.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">It is further suggested that the control element has a slot, which is provided as a spring means for a form-fit connection between the control armature element and the control element. Thereby, a particularly simple spring element for establishing an assembly-friendly form-fit connection can be provided, as the coupling unit for a snap connection can be provided thereby. Other spring means for producing a snap connection between the control element and the control armature element are basically also conceivable. A sleeve inserted into the control element can for example also be provided for providing a spring means.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">It is additionally suggested that the control element has a side surface, which is formed at least partially as at least one functional surface and which is provided to correspond to at least one flank of a gate path of the control gate. A moving contact point between the functional surface and the flank of the gate path can be realized thereby, whereby a tolerance with regard to angle errors of components of the valve drive control device can be increased. Particularly, a wear of the control element and the gate path can thereby be reduced effectively and constructively. A &#x201c;functional surface&#x201d; is particularly meant to be a region at the side surface of the control element for the functional coupling to the control gate. As &#x201c;corresponding&#x201d; is particularly meant that a curvature of the functional surface is adapted to a curvature of the flank of the gate path.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The invention will become more readily apparent from the following description of an embodiment of the invention on the basis of the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a top view of a valve drive control device with axially displaceable cam elements,</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows an actuating actuator of the valve drive control device,</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a control armature element and a control element of the actuating actuator in a disassembled state,</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> the control armature element and the control element in an assembled state, and</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows the control armature element and the control element and</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows the control element in a controlled state.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF A PARTICULAR EMBODIMENT OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a valve drive control device for an internal combustion engine. The valve drive control element has at least one cam element <b>13</b>, which is disposed on a base shaft <b>30</b> in an axially slidable but rotationally fixed manner. The valve drive control device further has an actuation device <b>31</b>, by means of which a control force for displacing the at least one cam element <b>13</b> is provided.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The actuation device <b>31</b> has a control unit <b>32</b> with at least one actuating actuator <b>33</b> and with a control gate <b>12</b> with at least one gate path <b>29</b>. The actuating actuator <b>33</b> comprises a control armature element <b>10</b> and a control element <b>11</b>. In a control position, in which the control armature element <b>10</b> is extended, the control element <b>11</b> engages the control gate <b>12</b>, so that, by a rotational movement of the cam element <b>13</b>, an axially acting control force is provided. In a neutral position, the control element <b>11</b> is retracted from the control gate <b>12</b>. A second actuating actuator, not designated in detail, for engagement with a second gate path is designed in an analogous manner.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The actuating actuator <b>33</b> has an electromagnetic unit <b>34</b> with a stator unit <b>35</b> and an armature unit <b>36</b>. The stator unit <b>35</b> comprises a solenoid <b>37</b> and a solenoid core <b>38</b>, by means of which a solenoid magnetic field that can be generated by the solenoid <b>37</b> can be strengthened. The armature unit <b>36</b> comprises a permanent magnet <b>39</b>, which is rigidly connected to the control armature element <b>10</b>. By means of the solenoid <b>37</b> and the permanent magnet <b>39</b>, an actuation force for controlling the control armature element <b>10</b> is provided, which acts along a main extension direction <b>15</b> of the control armature element <b>10</b>. The control armature element <b>10</b> is mounted in a movable manner along its main extension direction <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The control armature element <b>10</b> of the actuating actuator <b>33</b> is partially formed as a control pin <b>40</b>. The control element <b>11</b> of the actuating actuator <b>33</b> in the form of a slide shoe (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). The control element <b>11</b> is formed in one piece and engages the gate path <b>29</b> in the control position. The control pin <b>40</b> is mounted in an actuator housing <b>41</b> of the actuating actuator <b>33</b> and extends through the actuator housing <b>41</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">If the solenoid <b>37</b> is de-energized, the permanent magnet <b>39</b> interacts with the surrounding material. In the neutral position, the permanent magnet <b>39</b> particularly interacts with the solenoid core <b>38</b> of the electromagnetic unit <b>34</b>, which consists of a magnetizable material. In the control position, the permanent magnet <b>39</b> particularly interacts with the actuator housing <b>41</b> of the actuating actuator <b>33</b>. In an operating state without current, the permanent magnet <b>64</b><i>a </i>retains the control element <b>11</b> in the control position or the neutral position. The actuating actuator <b>33</b> is designed as a bistable system, which is held either in the control position or the neutral position in a de-energized state of the solenoid.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In an operating state, in which the electromagnetic unit <b>34</b> is energized, the permanent magnetic field of the permanent magnet <b>39</b> interacts with the magnetic field of the solenoid <b>37</b>. An attracting force and a repelling force can thereby be realized in dependence on a polarization of the permanent magnet <b>39</b> and the electromagnetic unit <b>34</b>. A polarization of the electromagnetic unit <b>34</b> can be adjusted by means of the direction of the current, with which the solenoid <b>37</b> is supplied. In order to move the switch element <b>10</b> from its neutral retracted position to the extended switch position, the electromagnetic unit <b>37</b> is energized with a current in the current direction, which results in a repellent force between the electromagnetic unit <b>34</b> and the permanent magnet <b>39</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">For providing the axially acting control force, the gate path <b>29</b> has an axial and a radial directional component. If the actuating actuator <b>33</b> is in the control position, a rotational movement of the cam element <b>13</b> the axially acting force is generated by the axial direction component of the gate path <b>29</b>, by means of which force the cam element <b>13</b> is displaced. In order to move the actuating actuator <b>33</b> into its neutral position after a displacement of the cam element, the gate path has a disengagement element <b>42</b>, which is formed by a groove base <b>43</b> of the gate path <b>29</b> rising up to a base circle level. By means of the disengagement element <b>42</b>, a force acts on the actuating actuator <b>33</b>, which returns the control armature element <b>10</b> back into its neutral position.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Upon movement of the control armature element <b>10</b> from its control position into the retracted neutral position by the disengagement element <b>42</b>, the control armature element <b>10</b> is held in a first phase in the control position as a result of an interaction between the permanent magnet <b>39</b> and the actuator housing <b>41</b>. In a second phase, the control armature element <b>10</b> releases from the groove base <b>43</b> and aims for the neutral position by the interaction between the permanent magnet <b>39</b> and the solenoid core <b>38</b>. The control armature element <b>10</b> is moved to its neutral position by the interaction between the permanent magnet <b>39</b> and the solenoid core <b>38</b> in the second phase independently of the rotational movement of the cam element <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The control armature element <b>10</b> and the control element <b>11</b> are coupled to each other in a movable manner by means of a coupling unit <b>14</b>. The coupling unit <b>14</b> comprises a ball head <b>19</b> arranged at one end <b>21</b> of the control armature element <b>10</b> and a recess <b>20</b> corresponding to the ball head <b>19</b>, which recess is arranged in the control element <b>11</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>). The control armature element <b>10</b> and the ball head <b>19</b> are designed in one piece. In an assembled state, the control armature element <b>10</b> and the control element <b>11</b> are connected to each other in a form-fit manner by means of the ball head <b>19</b> and the corresponding recess <b>20</b>. The recess <b>20</b> of the control element <b>11</b> receives the ball head <b>19</b> therein. The control armature element <b>10</b> and the control element <b>11</b> are coupled to each other in three degrees of freedom in a movable manner by means of the coupling unit <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The three degrees of freedom are rotational movements between the control armature element <b>10</b> and the control element <b>11</b> independent of each other. Rotational axes <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>, <b>44</b> for all three degrees of freedom are defined by means of the ball head <b>19</b> and the recess <b>20</b> The three rotational axes <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>, <b>44</b> have a common intersection <b>45</b>. The three rotational axes <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>, <b>44</b> are aligned vertically to each other (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The rotational axis <b>16</b> for the rotational movement of the first degree of freedom extends along the longitudinal axis <b>15</b> of the control armature element <b>10</b>. The control element <b>11</b> can rotate freely around the longitudinal axis direction <b>15</b> of the control armature element <b>10</b> which also forms the rotational axis <b>16</b> by an angle of 360&#xb0;. The rotational movement of the first degree of freedom can basically be restricted to a defined angle region by means of a guide element, for example an angle region adapted to the gate path. The rotational axis <b>18</b> for the rotational movement of the second degree of freedom extends along a main extension direction <b>17</b> of the control element <b>11</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>). The rotational movement around the rotational axis <b>18</b> is restricted. The rotational axis <b>44</b> for the rotational movement of the third degree of freedom extends vertically to the main extension direction <b>17</b> of the control element and vertically to the main extension direction <b>15</b> of the control armature element <b>10</b>. The rotational movement around the rotational axis <b>44</b> is also restricted.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">For an assembly of the actuating actuator <b>33</b>, the coupling unit <b>14</b> has a spring means <b>23</b>, by means of which the recess <b>20</b> corresponding to the ball head <b>19</b> can be widened, in order to introduce the ball head <b>19</b> into the recess <b>20</b>. The spring means <b>23</b> is formed in one piece with the control element <b>11</b>. In order to form the spring element <b>23</b>, the control element <b>11</b> has a slot <b>22</b> applied along the main extension direction <b>17</b> of the control element <b>11</b>. The slot <b>22</b> is introduced centrally into the control element <b>11</b>. It passes through the control element <b>11</b> to an essential part. In a rear region <b>46</b>, two halves <b>47</b>, <b>48</b> of the control element <b>11</b> are separated from each other by the slot <b>22</b>. In a front region <b>49</b>, the two halves <b>47</b>, <b>48</b> are connected to each other by the one-piece formation of the control element <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">With an assembly of the coupling unit <b>14</b>, the slot <b>22</b> widens for a short period, while the ball head <b>19</b> is pressed into the recess <b>20</b>. By means of the force of the retracting ball head <b>19</b>, the slot <b>22</b> and therewith the halves <b>47</b>, <b>48</b> of the control element <b>11</b> formed as a slide shoe are pressed apart and the ball head <b>19</b> engages the recess <b>20</b>. As soon as the ball head <b>19</b> is in the recess <b>20</b>, the halves <b>47</b>, <b>48</b> of the control element <b>11</b> snap back into their starting position. A sliding out of the ball head <b>19</b> from the recess <b>20</b> is prevented by the spring means <b>23</b>, which is formed by means of the slot <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The control element <b>11</b>, formed as a slide shoe, has a rotation-symmetrical basic form <b>50</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>). The rotation-symmetrical basic form <b>50</b> of the control element <b>11</b> formed as a slide shoe has two functional surfaces <b>25</b>, <b>26</b>, which are formed as parts of a side surface <b>24</b> of the control element <b>11</b>. The functional surfaces <b>25</b>, <b>26</b> are provided for engagement with the gate path <b>29</b>. The functional surfaces <b>25</b>, <b>26</b> are formed as contact surfaces between the control element <b>11</b> and flanks <b>27</b>, <b>28</b> of the gate path <b>29</b>. The functional surfaces <b>25</b>, <b>26</b> correspond to the flanks <b>27</b>, <b>28</b> of the gate path <b>29</b>. A curvature of the functional surfaces <b>25</b>, <b>26</b> is larger than a maximum curvature of the gate path <b>29</b>. When displacing the cam element <b>13</b> during a control process, a coherent part at least of the corresponding functional surface <b>25</b>, <b>26</b> is always in contact with the associated flank <b>27</b>, <b>28</b> of the gate path <b>29</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">By means of the rotation-symmetric basic form <b>50</b> and the free rotatability of the control element <b>11</b> formed as a slide shoe, a contact point <b>51</b> wanders in contact with the corresponding flank <b>27</b> of the gate path, which is defined by the contact between the functional surfaces <b>25</b>, <b>26</b> with the associated flank <b>27</b>, <b>28</b>. Depending on an angle degree of the gate path <b>29</b>, a relative position of the contact point <b>51</b> wanders with regard to the control element <b>11</b> or to the functional surfaces <b>25</b>, <b>26</b> of the control element <b>11</b>.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A valve drive control device for a camshaft of an internal combustion engine, for controlling operation of a valve drive, the device comprising at least one control armature element (<b>10</b>), and a slide control element (<b>11</b>) connected to the control armature element (<b>10</b>) provided for a coupling to a control gate (<b>12</b>) of a cam element (<b>13</b>) for controlling the axial position of the cam element (<b>13</b>) on the camshaft, and a coupling unit (<b>14</b>) arranged at one end (<b>21</b>) of the control armature element (<b>10</b>) for coupling the control armature element (<b>10</b>) and the slide control element (<b>11</b>) movably to each other with at least one degree of freedom the slide control element (<b>11</b>) the form of an elongated slide shoe pivotally joined to the control armature element (<b>10</b>) by the coupling unit (<b>14</b>).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The valve drive control device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the control armature element (<b>10</b>) is formed at least partially as a control pin (<b>40</b>).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The valve drive control device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the coupling unit (<b>14</b>) is provided for at least one degree of freedom formed as rotational movement.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The valve drive control device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one degree of freedom is formed as a rotational movement around a rotational axis (<b>16</b>) extending along to a main extension direction (<b>15</b>) of the control armature element (<b>11</b>).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The valve drive control device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one degree of freedom is formed as a rotational movement around a rotational axis (<b>44</b>) extending vertically to a main extension direction (<b>15</b>) of the control armature element (<b>10</b>) and vertically to a main extension direction (<b>17</b>) of the slide control element (<b>11</b>).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The valve drive control device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the coupling unit (<b>14</b>) comprises a ball head (<b>19</b>) and a recess (<b>20</b>) formed in the slide shoe (<b>11</b>) and accommodating the ball head (<b>19</b>).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The valve drive control device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the recess (<b>20</b>) is formed at least partially within the slide control element (<b>11</b>).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The valve drive control device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the coupling unit (<b>14</b>) is a form-fit coupling.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The valve drive control device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the slide control element (<b>11</b>) is formed in a rotation-symmetrical manner.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The valve drive control device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the slide control element (<b>11</b>) has a slot (<b>22</b>), which is provided to form a spring means (<b>23</b>) for a form-fit connection between the control armature element (<b>10</b>) and the slide control element (<b>11</b>).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The valve drive control device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the slide control element (<b>11</b>) has a side surface (<b>24</b>), which is formed at least partially as a functional surface (<b>25</b>, <b>26</b>) and which is provided to correspond with at least one flank (<b>27</b>, <b>28</b>) of a gate path (<b>29</b>) of the control gate (<b>12</b>). </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
