<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08627068-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08627068</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11118158</doc-number>
<date>20050429</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>2820</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>29</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>713164</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Selecting access authorities</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6047312</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Brooks et al.</name>
<date>20000400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6289462</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>McNabb et al.</name>
<date>20010900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6629109</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Koshisaka</name>
<date>20030900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7231640</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Evans et al.</name>
<date>20070600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7275264</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Cuenod et al.</name>
<date>20070900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0061504</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Sprigg et al.</name>
<date>20030300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>713200</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00007">
<othercit>Stiegler, M. et al., &#x201c;A Capability Based Client: The DarpaBrowser&#x201d;, Combex Inc., Jun. 26, 2002.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>30</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>713164</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>713165</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>713166</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Miller</last-name>
<first-name>Mark S.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Baltimore</city>
<state>MD</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Stiegler</last-name>
<first-name>Marc D.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kingman</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Miller</last-name>
<first-name>Mark S.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Baltimore</city>
<state>MD</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Stiegler</last-name>
<first-name>Marc D.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kingman</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hewlett-Packard Development Company, L. P.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Houston</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Tran</last-name>
<first-name>Ellen</first-name>
<department>2433</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Group access authorities for a restricted user account group in a directory system are selected to include directory traverse authority. A restricted user account is included in the restricted user account group such that the restricted user account inherits group access authorities. The directory system is configured to allow directory traversing without performing directory traverse checking. An application is confined to run within the restricted user account so that access authorities of the application include group access authorities.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="225.89mm" wi="147.66mm" file="US08627068-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="232.75mm" wi="149.61mm" file="US08627068-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="212.17mm" wi="167.30mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627068-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="171.20mm" wi="166.96mm" file="US08627068-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="201.68mm" wi="151.38mm" file="US08627068-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="232.33mm" wi="142.58mm" file="US08627068-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="264.92mm" wi="159.34mm" file="US08627068-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="202.95mm" wi="155.70mm" file="US08627068-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="244.77mm" wi="165.18mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627068-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">In the past few years, computer viruses have caused damage to computer systems throughout the world. A computer virus is a program capable of operation on a computer system, such as a personal computer, that is self-replicating and that can &#x201c;infect&#x201d; other programs by modifying them or their environment such that a call to an infected program results in an action that the user may not like.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Computer systems today typically run operating systems having user accounts for users of the systems. A user logs into the computer system under a user account and has authorities to add, edit, delete or use most of the resources available in the computer system. Additionally, applications running in the user's account have the same authorities as the user. This arrangement presents a computer virus with a doorway to most of the resources in the computer system. For instance, if an application is infected by a virus, the virus is able to spread to any resource that the application may access including other files located on the computer system. Conventional virus detection software may be unable to stop the spread of these viruses before they do irreparable damage.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">According to an example, a method includes selecting group access authorities for a restricted user account group in a directory system include directory traverse authority. A restricted user account is included in the restricted user account group such that the restricted user account inherits group access authorities. The directory system is configured to allow directory traversing without performing directory traverse checking. An application is confined to run within the restricted user account so that access authorities of the application include group access authorities.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Embodiments of the invention are illustrated by way of example and without limitation in the accompanying figures in which like numeral references refer to like elements, and wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a block diagram of a system for setting access authorities in accordance with an example of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a block diagram of a directory system with access authorities in accordance with an example of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a Venn diagram of user accounts in accordance with an example of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a table of access authorities for accounts in accordance with an example of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows a flow diagram of an operational mode of a system for selecting access authorities in accordance with an example of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows a flow diagram of an operational mode of a system for selecting access authorities in accordance with another example of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows a flow diagram of an operational mode of a system for selecting access authorities in accordance with another example of the invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> shows a schematic diagram of a computer system in which examples of the invention may be implemented.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">For simplicity and illustrative purposes, the principles are shown by way of examples of systems and methods described. In the following description, numerous specific details are set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding of the examples. It will be apparent however, to one of ordinary skill in the art, that the examples may be practiced without limitation to these specific details. In other instances, well known methods and structures have not been described in detail so as not to unnecessarily obscure the examples.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Throughout the present disclosure, reference is made to access authorities. The access authorities may be defined as rights to access resources in a computer system. The resource may be a file in a directory of a computer system. The access authorities may control the rights of accounts, for instance a user account, to access data in a variety of manners. For example, the access authorities may provide the user account with read-only and/or execute access to an executable file for running an application. In addition, the access authorities may provide the user account with access to a data file used by the application. The term &#x201c;access,&#x201d; when unqualified, includes at least read and write access authorities to a file.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Reference is also made to a restricted user account. The restricted user account may be defined as an account provided access authorities (referred to as individual access authorities) to fewer resources than the user's login account. A software application, to be confined, runs within the restricted user account. The restricted user account may have the individual access authorities to access an executable file for the application and any other file necessary to complete a task for the application. For example, the restricted user account, and likewise the application, may have read-only and/or execute access to an executable file which started the application and read/write access to support files or directories containing the support files used by the application.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Reference is also made to a restricted user account group. The restricted user account group may be defined as an account group having predetermined access authorities (referred to as group access authorities). The restricted user account group may be used to select the individual access authorities for the restricted user account by including the restricted user account in the restricted user account group. The individual access authorities of the restricted user account may correspond to the group access authorities of the restricted user account group. In another example, the individual access authorities may include additional access authorities as compared to the group access authorities either increasing or decreasing a number of resources available to the restricted user account. For instance, the group access authorities inherited by the restricted user account may include read-only or execute access to a directory while the individual access authorities may further include write access to the directory. The access authorities may include both the individual access authorities and/or the group access authorities. It should be understood, however, that the access authorities may be grouped, defined, categorized, and/or labeled in a variety of manners without changing the scope of examples shown herein. It should also be understood that the concept of the restricted user account group may be implemented by simply explicitly detailing individually for each restricted account all the rights conceptually assigned to the group.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Viral vulnerabilities of a computer system may be reduced by controlling an application's access authorities to resources within the computer system. Reducing or controlling the scope of access authorities of an application may also reduce potential damage done to the computer system by a virus. For instance, a word processor application may have read-only access authorities to the executable file that started the word processor. Therefore, a virus attacking the word processor application may not alter the executable file. This reduces virus spreading.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In one example, access authorities of an application are reduced by confining the application to run within a restricted user account. This may be accomplished by selecting group access authorities for a restricted user account group. The restricted user account is included in the restricted user account group such that the restricted user account inherits the group access authorities. In this manner, the access authorities of the application include the group access authorities.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In some examples, the group access authorities may be selected to include read-only or execute access to files within a program files directory. The program files directory may be defined as any directory having executable files for applications. The group access authorities may also be selected to include read-only and/or execute access to files within an operating system directory. The operating system directory may be defined as any directory having files for supporting functioning of the operating system. The group access authorities may also be selected to exclude access to files within a root directory of a directory system. In other examples, a directory system may be configured to allow directory traversing by an application without performing directory traverse checking.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Individual access authorities for the restricted user account may be selected to extend the access authorities of the application. This may allow the application to access files within a data directory for reading and writing. For instance, selecting individual access authorities for the restricted user account may allow a word processing application confined therein to write data to a text file.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">With reference first to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, there is shown a block diagram of a system <b>100</b> for selecting access authorities. The system <b>100</b> includes an application <b>102</b>, a restricted user account <b>104</b>, a set-up program <b>106</b>, a polarizer <b>108</b>, a polalauncher <b>110</b>, a powerbox <b>112</b>, a restricted user account group <b>114</b>, a list of resources <b>116</b>, and a directory traverse checker <b>118</b>. The application <b>102</b> may be confined to run within the restricted user account <b>104</b> by the polarizer <b>108</b>. The set-up program <b>106</b> designates group access authorities <b>120</b>, individual access authorities <b>122</b>, and application information <b>124</b> providing these to the polarizer <b>108</b>. The set-up program <b>106</b> may also configure the directory traverse checker <b>118</b> to allow directory traversing without performing directory traverse checking.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The polarizer <b>108</b> accepts as inputs the individual access authorities <b>122</b>, the group access authorities <b>120</b>, and the application information <b>124</b>. The individual access authorities <b>122</b> may be input by a user selecting a resource or resources that will available to the application <b>102</b> through the restricted user account <b>104</b>. The application information <b>124</b> may include the name and/or path of an executable file for the application <b>102</b>. The polarizer <b>108</b> accepts the individual access authorities <b>122</b> and application information <b>124</b> and may create a polalauncher <b>110</b> for the application <b>102</b>. The polalauncher <b>110</b> may be configured to ensure that the application <b>102</b> runs within the restricted user account <b>104</b>, that is, the application <b>102</b> is confined to run within the restricted user account <b>104</b>. Examples of creating and using the polalauncher <b>110</b> may be found in co-pending and commonly assigned U.S. patent application Ser. No. 11/047,015 filed Jan. 31, 2005, and entitled &#x201c;Launching An Application In A Restricted User Account,&#x201d; the disclosure of which is hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In one example, the polarizer <b>108</b> may modify the list of resources <b>116</b> to include the individual access authorities <b>122</b> for the restricted user account <b>104</b>. In another example, the polarizer <b>108</b> may provide the individual access authorities <b>122</b> (or instructions to modify the predetermined set of authorities in the powerbox <b>112</b>) to the polalauncher <b>110</b>. The polalauncher <b>110</b> includes this information when sending the request to the powerbox <b>112</b> that then modifies the list of resources <b>116</b> for the restricted user account <b>104</b> upon request.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The list of resources <b>116</b> may be accessible to the polarizer <b>108</b> and/or the powerbox <b>112</b> and includes a listing of resources available to accounts and account groups within an operating system. The list of resources <b>116</b> may be stored in a table, database or any data structure and used to modify or edit an access control list attached to a particular resource. The access control list is a list attached to a single resource that lists the accounts or groups that can access the single resource. The access control list may be populated or edited using a list of resources <b>116</b>. One of ordinary skill in the art would recognize that the list of resources may be stored in a variety of manners.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In one example, the powerbox <b>112</b> receives a request from the polalauncher <b>110</b> and runs the application <b>102</b> within the restricted user account <b>104</b>, which is created or was previously created and provided with the group access authorities <b>120</b>. The powerbox <b>112</b> may also be configured to receive a request from a user of the application <b>102</b> to access other computer resources and modify the access authorities through the list of resources <b>116</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, there is shown a block diagram of a directory system <b>200</b> with access authorities. The directory system <b>200</b> may include a plurality of directories including but not limited to a root directory <b>202</b>, a program files directory <b>204</b>, an operating system directory <b>206</b>, a user account directory <b>208</b>, a data directory <b>210</b>, an application 1 directory <b>212</b>, and an application 2 directory <b>214</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The root directory <b>202</b>, for instance, may include the group access authorities <b>120</b> and directory traverse authority. Both the program files directory <b>204</b> and the operating system directory <b>206</b> may also include group access authorities <b>120</b>. In this manner, the group access authorities <b>120</b> provide the restricted user account group <b>114</b> and thus the restricted user account <b>104</b> and the application <b>102</b> with access authorities to run executable files located in the application 1 directory <b>212</b> and the application 2 directory <b>214</b> and supporting files located in the operating system directory <b>206</b>. The individual access authorities <b>122</b> may extend the access authorities of application <b>102</b> to include access to a file within the data directory <b>210</b> and the application 1 directory <b>212</b> if needed. In another instance, the individual access authorities <b>122</b> may extend the access authorities of the application <b>102</b> to include access to a file or subdirectory within the program files directory <b>204</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, there is shown a Venn diagram <b>300</b> of a user account and restricted user accounts in accordance with an example of a computer system. An administrative account <b>302</b> may have access to all resources available in a computer system while a user account <b>304</b> may have access to all resources available to that particular user. User accounts, such as user account <b>304</b>, typically have access to fewer resources than the administrative account <b>302</b>. However, many user accounts may have access to all resources available in a computer system thus increasing the need for additional protections. The Venn diagram <b>300</b> also includes four smaller circles representing four restricted user accounts <b>306</b>-<b>312</b> having access to a predetermined set of resources. The first restricted user account <b>306</b> has access to the fewest number of resources. For example, the first restricted user account <b>306</b> may have access to a single executable file or application. The second restricted user account <b>308</b> has access to more resources while the third restricted user account <b>310</b> has access to even more resources. In the Venn diagram <b>300</b>, the forth restricted user account <b>312</b> has access to the most systems resources although access is limited to a subset of the resources available to the user which itself is a subset of resources available in the computer system.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The system resources may be designated by the administrator of the system. For example, the administrator may determine that a particular user needs access to all text files in certain folders but should not have access to any files containing financial information while an administrator of a company should have access to any file containing financial information but not have access to any file containing confidential client information. The administrator may designate authorities to user accounts accordingly.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">One of ordinary skill in the art would recognize that the any number of restricted user accounts may be created having a plurality of possible permission settings. Additionally, multiple restricted user accounts may be designated for multiple instances of the same application. That is multiple instances of one application may be simultaneously running on the same computer system. For example, a first instance may be started by a user double-clicking on an icon for the application, and while the first instance is running, the user may double-click on the icon again which starts a second instance of the application. Each instance runs in its own restricted user account which can limit the spread of viruses within a computer system.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In one example, the restricted user accounts <b>306</b>-<b>312</b> may be accounts for the same user of the user account <b>304</b>. However, the restricted user accounts <b>306</b>-<b>312</b> were created to run the applications described above in an environment where the applications have access to limited resources instead of all the resources of the user account <b>304</b>. Thus, a virus infecting any of the applications is substantially confined to the resources available to the infected application.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a table <b>400</b> of user account authorities in accordance with the Venn, diagram of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. The administrative account <b>302</b> has access to all systems resources, shown in entry <b>402</b>, in the computer system. The user account <b>304</b>, or the user's login account, has access to several system resources, shown in entry <b>404</b>. The system resources may be designated by the administrator of the system. For example, the administrator may determine that a particular user needs access to all text files in certain folders but should not have access to any files containing financial information while an administrator of a company should have access to any file containing financial information but not have access to any file containing confidential client information. The administrator may designate authorities to user accounts accordingly.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The first restricted user account <b>406</b> has access to a single application, shown in entry <b>406</b>. The first restricted user account <b>306</b> may have been created to run a single executable file, such as, a game, calculator or any other program that runs as a single application. The second restricted user account <b>308</b> has access to a single application and contact information, including an e-mail address, shown in entry <b>408</b>. The second restricted user account <b>308</b> may have been created to run a word processor and notify an alert computer if attacked by a virus that propagates by way of e-mail. The third restricted user account <b>310</b> has access to a single application and contact information, including a network address, shown in entry <b>410</b>. The third restricted user account <b>310</b> may have been created to run a spread sheet program and notify an alert computer if attacked by a virus that collects and transmits a user's information to another computer system. The fourth restricted user account <b>312</b> has access to a single application and contact information, including an e-mail address and a network address, shown in entry <b>412</b>. The fourth restricted user account <b>312</b> may have been created to run the application <b>102</b>. The description of the restricted user accounts above are for illustrative purposes only. One of ordinary skill in the art would recognize that the any number of restricted user accounts may be created having a plurality of possible permission settings.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">One of the possible permission settings may include allowing or disallowing an account to change permission settings. If an account where given permission to change write or execute permissions or to change permissions to access other applications, the restrictions placed on the account may become moot. Therefore, the restrictions placed on the account may include no permissions to add or modify permissions even to the resources over which the account has write authority.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows a flow diagram of an operational mode <b>500</b> of an example of a system for selecting access authorities. The following description of the operational mode <b>500</b> is made with reference to the system <b>100</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, and thus makes reference to the elements cited therein. The following description of the operational mode <b>500</b> is one manner in which the system <b>100</b> may be implemented. In this respect, it is to be understood that the following description of the operational mode <b>500</b> is but one manner of a variety of different manners in which such a system may be operated.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In the operational mode <b>500</b>, the set-up program <b>106</b> selects group access authorities <b>120</b> for a restricted user account group <b>114</b> at step <b>502</b>. The set-up program <b>106</b> includes the restricted user account <b>104</b> in the restricted user account group <b>114</b> such that the restricted user account <b>104</b> inherits the group access authorities <b>120</b> at step <b>504</b>. The set-up program <b>106</b> configures the directory system <b>200</b> to allow directory traversing without performing directory traverse checking at step <b>506</b>. The application <b>102</b> is confined to run within the restricted user account <b>104</b> such that the access authorities of the application <b>102</b> include the group access authorities <b>120</b> at step <b>508</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows a flow diagram of an operational mode <b>600</b> of another example of a system for selecting access authorities. The following description of the operational mode <b>600</b> is made with reference to the system <b>100</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and the directory system illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, and thus makes reference to the elements cited therein. The following description of the operational mode <b>600</b> is one manner in which the system <b>100</b> may be implemented. In this respect, it is to be understood that the following description of the operational mode <b>600</b> is but one manner of a variety of different manners in which such a system may be operated.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In the operational mode <b>600</b>, the set-up program <b>106</b> selects group access authorities <b>120</b> for a restricted user account group <b>114</b> at step <b>602</b>. The set-up program <b>106</b> selects the group access authorities <b>120</b> to include read-only and/or execute access to files within the program files directory <b>204</b> at step <b>604</b>. The set-up program <b>106</b> selects the group access authorities <b>120</b> to include read-only and/or execute access to files within the operating system directory <b>206</b> at step <b>606</b>. The set-up program <b>106</b> selects the group access authorities <b>120</b> to exclude access to files within the root directory <b>208</b> at step <b>608</b>. The set-up program <b>106</b> may also configure the directory traverse checker <b>118</b> to allow directory traversing without performing directory traverse checking at step <b>610</b>. The set-up program <b>106</b> includes the restricted user account <b>104</b> in the restricted user account group <b>114</b> such that the restricted user account <b>104</b> inherits the group access authorities <b>120</b> at step <b>612</b>. The application <b>102</b> is confined to run within the restricted user account <b>104</b> such that the access authorities of the application <b>102</b> include the group access authorities <b>120</b> at step <b>614</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows a flow diagram of an operational mode <b>700</b> of another example of a system for selecting access authorities. The following description of the operational mode <b>700</b> is made with reference to the system <b>100</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and the directory system <b>200</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, and thus makes reference to the elements cited therein. The following description of the operational mode <b>700</b> is one manner in which the system <b>100</b> may be implemented. In this respect, it is to be understood that the following description of the operational mode <b>700</b> is but one manner of a variety of different manners in which such a system may be operated.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In the operational mode <b>700</b>, the polarizer <b>108</b> selects the individual access authorities <b>122</b> for a restricted user account <b>104</b> at step <b>702</b>. The polarizer <b>108</b> selects the individual access authorities <b>122</b> to include access to files within the data directory <b>210</b> at step <b>704</b>. The polarizer <b>108</b> selects the individual access authorities <b>122</b> to include access to files within a directory having an executable for the application <b>102</b> at step <b>704</b>. This directory may be a subdirectory within the program files directory <b>204</b>. In order to function properly, some legacy programs write to a file or files within the program files directory <b>204</b> or a subdirectory thereof. This inclusion may allow legacy programs to operate in the system <b>100</b>. The polarizer <b>108</b> selects the individual access authorities <b>122</b> to exclude authority to grant access authorities at step <b>708</b>. This exclusion protects against virus spreading by thwarting a virus's attempt to grant itself access authorities and thus spread to other files and directories in the directory system <b>202</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Some of the steps illustrated in the operational modes <b>500</b>, <b>600</b>, and <b>700</b> may be contained as a utility, program, subprogram, in any desired computer accessible medium. In addition, the operational modes <b>500</b>, <b>600</b> and <b>700</b> may be embodied by a computer program or a plurality of computer programs, which may exist in a variety of forms both active and inactive in a single computer system or across multiple computer systems. For example, they may exist as software program(s) comprised of program instructions in source code, object code, executable code or other formats for performing some of the steps. Any of the above may be embodied on a computer readable medium, which include storage devices and signals, in compressed or uncompressed form.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Examples of suitable computer readable storage devices include conventional computer system RAM (random access memory), ROM (read only memory), EPROM (erasable, programmable ROM), EEPROM (electrically erasable, programmable ROM), and magnetic or optical disks or tapes. Examples of computer readable signals, whether modulated using a carrier or not, are signals that a computer system hosting or running the computer program may be configured to access, including signals downloaded through the Internet or other networks. Concrete examples of the foregoing include distribution of the programs on a CD ROM or via Internet download. In a sense, the Internet itself, as an abstract entity, is a computer readable medium. The same is true of computer networks in general. It is therefore to be understood that those functions enumerated below may be performed by any electronic device capable of executing the above-described functions.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> illustrates an exemplary block diagram of a computer system <b>800</b> that may run the application <b>102</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The computer system <b>800</b> includes one or more processors, such as processor <b>802</b>, providing an execution platform for executing software, such as the application <b>102</b>, the set-up program <b>106</b>, the polarizer <b>108</b>, the polalauncher <b>110</b>, and the powerbox <b>112</b>. The processor <b>802</b> may also execute an operating system (not shown) for executing the software in addition to performing operating system tasks.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Commands and data from the processor <b>802</b> are communicated over a communication bus <b>804</b>. The computer system <b>800</b> also includes a main memory <b>806</b>, such as a Random Access Memory (RAM), where software may be executed during runtime, and a secondary memory <b>808</b>. The secondary memory <b>808</b> includes, for example, a hard disk drive <b>810</b> and/or a removable storage drive <b>812</b>, representing a floppy diskette drive, a magnetic tape drive, a compact disk drive, etc., or a nonvolatile memory where a copy of the software may be stored. Applications and some resources, such as files, may be stored in the secondary memory <b>808</b> and transferred to the main memory <b>806</b> during run time. The secondary memory <b>808</b> may also include ROM (read only memory), EPROM (erasable, programmable ROM), EEPROM (electrically erasable, programmable ROM).</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">A user interfaces with the computer system <b>800</b> with one or more input devices <b>818</b>, such as a keyboard, a mouse, a stylus, and the like. The display adaptor <b>822</b> interfaces with the communication bus <b>804</b> and the display <b>820</b> and receives display data from the processor <b>802</b> and converts the display data into display commands for the display <b>820</b>. The user interacts with the application <b>102</b> through the use of the input devices <b>818</b> and display <b>820</b>. A network interface <b>830</b> is provided for communicating with other nodes.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">What has been described and illustrated herein are examples of the systems and methods described herein along with some of their variations. The terms, descriptions and figures used herein are set forth by way of illustration only and are not meant as limitations. Those skilled in the art will recognize that many variations are possible within the spirit and scope of these examples, which intended to be defined by the following claims and their equivalents in which all terms are meant in their broadest reasonable sense unless otherwise indicated.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method of selecting access authorities in a directory system, the method comprising:
<claim-text>selecting group access authorities for a restricted user account group, the group access authorities including directory traverse authority;</claim-text>
<claim-text>including a restricted user account in the restricted user account group such that the restricted user account inherits the group access authorities;</claim-text>
<claim-text>configuring the directory system to allow directory traversing without performing directory traverse checking; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>confining an application to run within the restricted user account wherein the access authorities of the application include the group access authorities.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein selecting the group access authorities further comprises selecting the group access authorities including at least one of read-only and execute access to program files.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein selecting the group access authorities further comprises selecting the group access authorities including at least one of read-only and execute access to operating system files.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein selecting the group access authorities further comprises selecting the group access authorities excluding access to files within a root directory.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>selecting individual access authorities for the restricted user account such that the access authorities for the application includes the group access authorities and the individual access authorities.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> wherein selecting the individual access authorities further comprises selecting the individual access authorities including access to data files.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> wherein selecting the individual access authorities further comprises selecting the individual access authorities including access to an executable file for the application.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref> wherein selecting the individual access authorities further comprises selecting the individual access authorities excluding access permission grant authority.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A method of selecting access authorities, the method comprising:
<claim-text>using a set-up program to select group access authorities for a restricted user account group and to configure a directory traverse checker to allow directory traversing without performing directory traverse checking;</claim-text>
<claim-text>including directory traverse authority in the group access authorities;</claim-text>
<claim-text>including a restricted user account in the restricted user account group such that the restricted user account inherits the group access authorities including the directory traverse authority; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>confining an application to run within the restricted user account wherein the access authorities of the application include the group access authorities.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>including in the group access authorities at least one of read-only and execute access to program files.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>including in the group access authorities at least one of read-only and execute access to operating system files.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>excluding in the group access authorities access to files within a root directory.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>using a polarizer to select individual access authorities for the restricted user account such that the access authorities for the application includes the group access authorities and the individual access authorities.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>including in the individual access authorities access to data files.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>including in the individual access authorities access to an executable file for the application.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>excluding in the individual access authorities access permission grant authority.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. A computer readable medium on which is embedded one or more computer programs, said one or more computer programs implementing a method for selecting access authorities, said one or more computer programs comprising a set of instructions for:
<claim-text>selecting group access authorities for a restricted user account group, the group access authorities including directory traverse authority;</claim-text>
<claim-text>turning off a directory traverse checker for a directory system in which the group access authorities are used;</claim-text>
<claim-text>including a restricted user account in the restricted user account group such that the restricted user account inherits the group access authorities;</claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting individual access authorities for the restricted user account; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>confining an application to run within the restricted user account such that the access authorities for the application includes the group access authorities and the individual access authorities.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The computer readable medium according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, the one or more computer programs further comprising a set of instructions for:
<claim-text>including in the group access authorities at least one of read-only and execute access to files within an operating system directory and to program files.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The computer readable medium according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, the one or more computer programs further comprising a set of instructions for:
<claim-text>excluding in the group access authorities access to files within a root directory.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The computer readable medium according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, the one or more computer programs further comprising a set of instructions for:
<claim-text>including in the individual access authorities access to data files.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. A computer system comprising:
<claim-text>a data storage device to store computer program instructions; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one processor to execute the computer program instructions to:</claim-text>
<claim-text>create a restricted user account group having group access authorities, the group access authorities including directory traverse authority;</claim-text>
<claim-text>configure a directory system to allow directory traversing without performing directory traverse checking;</claim-text>
<claim-text>include a restricted user account in the restricted user account group; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>confine an application to run within the restricted user account.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The computer system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein the computer program instructions are executed by the at least one processor to create the restricted user account.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. The computer system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, wherein the computer program instructions ructions are executed by the at least one processor to select individual access authorities for the restricted user account.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. A computer system comprising:
<claim-text>at least one data storage device to store computer program instructions; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one processor to execute the computer program instructions to:</claim-text>
<claim-text>select a restricted user account group having group access authorities, the group access authorities including directory traverse authority;</claim-text>
<claim-text>configure a directory traverse checker to allow directory traversing without performing traverse checking; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>inherit the group access authorities in a restricted user account.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text>25. The computer system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00024">claim 24</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one data storage device stores a program files directory having an executable file and wherein the group access authorities includes at least one of read-only and execute access to program files.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text>26. The computer system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00024">claim 24</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one data storage device stores an operating system directory having a support file and wherein the group access authorities includes at least one of read-only and execute access to operating system files.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text>27. The computer system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00024">claim 24</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one data storage device stores a root directory having a file and wherein the group access authorities excludes access to files within the root directory.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text>28. The computer system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00024">claim 24</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one data storage device stores a polarizer to select individual access authorities for the restricted user account.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029" num="00029">
<claim-text>29. The computer system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00028">claim 28</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one data storage device stores a data directory having a file and wherein the individual access authorities includes access to the file within the data directory.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030" num="00030">
<claim-text>30. The computer system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00029">claim 29</claim-ref>, wherein the individual access authorities excludes permission to grant access authorities.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
