<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622710-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622710</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13492555</doc-number>
<date>20120608</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10 2011 105 228</doc-number>
<date>20110610</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>416230</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e61">Wind turbine component having an electrical line embedded in a laminate and method for making the same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4079903</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Ashton et al.</name>
<date>19780300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2441235</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7494324</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Hibbard</name>
<date>20090200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0183888</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Gunneskov et al.</name>
<date>20070800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>415146</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0257881</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ostergaard Kristensen et al.</name>
<date>20091000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0260612</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Vasudeva et al.</name>
<date>20101000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>416227 R</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>15</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>416224</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>416230</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>416229 R</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>416 39</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120315147</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121213</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Rindt</last-name>
<first-name>Philipp</first-name>
<address>
<city>Rostock</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Austinat</last-name>
<first-name>Dirk</first-name>
<address>
<city>Jarmen</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Rindt</last-name>
<first-name>Philipp</first-name>
<address>
<city>Rostock</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Austinat</last-name>
<first-name>Dirk</first-name>
<address>
<city>Jarmen</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ottesen P.A.</last-name>
<first-name>Walter</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Nordex Energy GmbH</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Hamburg</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Edgar</last-name>
<first-name>Richard</first-name>
<department>3745</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A wind turbine component has a laminate of fibrous material and plastic and an electrical line embedded in the laminate, wherein a profile is arranged on a lateral surface of the electrical line, the profile counteracting the formation of a hollow space or plastic nest between the lateral surface and a fibrous material layer which covers an upper side of the electrical line during the manufacture of the laminate.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="92.79mm" wi="150.96mm" file="US08622710-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="166.88mm" wi="148.34mm" file="US08622710-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="192.62mm" wi="152.15mm" file="US08622710-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="181.86mm" wi="166.71mm" file="US08622710-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority of German patent application no. 10 2011 105 228.7, filed Jun. 10, 2011, the entire content of which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The invention relates to a wind turbine component having a laminate of fibrous material and plastic and an electrical line embedded in the laminate. The wind turbine component can, for example, be a rotor blade or a part of a rotor blade. Such components are often manufactured from fiber reinforced plastic and typically have very large dimensions. Furthermore, during operation they are subject to very high and constantly changing loads. For this reason, electrical lines which are to be connected to such a component must be permanently and securely fixed to the component. This is often done over a great length, for example a lightning protection cable which extends from the blade tip to the blade root of a rotor blade.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">United States patent application publication 2009/0257881 discloses a rotor blade for a wind turbine having an integrated lightning protection cable. The lightning protection cable is a flat cable with a rectangular cross-section which is embedded in the laminate during manufacture of the rotor blade. For this, a vacuum injection process is used, with which the liquid plastic material is introduced between two different layers of the fibrous material after the arrangement of the lightning protection cable.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">U.S. Pat. No. 7,494,324 B2 discloses a component for equalizing potential between electric conducting components of a wind turbine rotor blade. As a result of the potential equalization, an electric flashover between the components is avoided, especially in the case of a lightning strike. The component for the potential equalization includes a contact facilitating layer on which a metallic conductor is arranged. A cover layer of electric conducting fibrous material, which can be permeated with resin, is arranged over the metallic conductor. A hollow space can form between the cover layer and a lateral surface of the metallic conductor. In this patent, the suggestion is made to fill the hollow space with resin.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">On the basis thereof, it is an object of the invention to provide a wind turbine component having a laminate of fibrous material and plastic and an electrical line embedded in the laminate, in which electrical lines of any cross-section can be securely and permanently fixed with a simple and/or less error-prone manufacturing process, and also a manufacturing process for such a wind turbine component.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The wind turbine component of the invention includes a laminate of fibrous material and plastic and an electrical line embedded in the laminate, wherein a profile is arranged on a lateral surface of the electrical line, said profile, during the manufacture of the laminate, counteracting the formation of a hollow space or a plastic nest between the lateral surface and a fibrous material layer which covers the upper side of the electrical line.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The invention is based on the knowledge that, in the manufacturing process described at the beginning, infusion errors can occur in the region of an embedded electrical line, and these infusion errors would require expensive reworking. In particular, hollow spaces or plastic nests can form on a lateral surface of the electrical line when a fibrous material layer which covers the electrical line cannot fully follow the cross-sectional geometry of the cable. In this case a free space, which is either completely filled with plastic and thus forms a plastic nest or is not entirely filled by the injection of the plastic so that a hollow space with an air pocket remains after the plastic has cured, is created between the lateral surface of the electrical line and the fibrous material layer which covers the electrical line. Neither of these is optimal for a permanent fixation of the line. In particular, air filled hollow spaces are critical because layers adjacent to the hollow space can form cracks under dynamic loads, and these cracks can endanger the stability of the component and the fixation of the line. For this reason, corresponding defects in the embedding of the cable must be repaired manually with a great amount of effort after the resin has cured, if this is even still possible with the often limited accessibility of the corresponding regions of the wind turbine component. A different manufacturing defect can occur when a layer of fibrous material which covers the electrical line ends up entirely or partially below the line. This can happen both during the insertion of the corresponding fiber layers into a mold and as during the evacuation of the mold during the plastic injection. A fold or a wave forms in the fibrous material, and this can also lead to problems.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In the present invention the electrical line is embedded in a laminate. Embedded means that the electrical line is cross-sectionally enclosed by the laminate on all sides. Included are arrangements in which other components of the wind turbine, in addition to the cable, for example made of balsa wood or another filling material, are also embedded in the laminate. In these cases, the electrical line can, for example, rest on such other material and be embedded in the laminate together therewith.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The fibrous material has fibers which are arranged in layers. The arrangement of the fibers within the individual layers is arbitrary. It can be, for example, unidirectional, bidirectional or unsorted. Glass fibers are often used. The use of carbon fiber is also known. The use of other plastic fibers is also conceivable. The laminate further has a plastic in which the fibers are embedded. The plastic can, for example, be polyester resin or epoxy resin or another plastic material which cures in a suitable manner.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The electrical line can be, for example, a lighting protection line, a supply line or a signal line. It can have any desired cross-section and can have shielding and/or insulation. The electrical line can have, for example, a diameter of 6 mm, 8 mm, 10 mm, 15 mm or more. It can also have a rectangular cross-section, for example with a height of 6 mm, 8 mm, 10 mm or more. The electrical line has a lateral surface. The lateral surface can be planar or curved. For example, the lateral surface can be a planar lateral surface which is formed by a short side of a rectangle or a line having a rectangular cross-section. The lateral surface can also be curved, for example in the case of a circular cable, wherein a section of the circumference forms the lateral surface. The electrical line also has an upper side which can also be planar or curved. The upper side can be formed by a section of the surface of the electrical line which is adjacent to the lateral surface.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">A profile is arranged on the lateral surface of the electrical line. The profile has a defined cross-section and extends over a large length in comparison to the dimensions of the cross-section, especially corresponding to the entire length of the electrical line which is embedded in the laminate or a majority thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">During manufacture of the laminate, the profile counteracts the formation of a hollow space or plastic nest between the lateral surface and a fibrous material layer which covers an upper side of the electrical line. For this, the cross-section of the profile can be dimensioned such that it &#x201c;conforms&#x201d; directly to the electrical line in the region of the lateral surface. It can, however, also be at a distance from the lateral surface, wherein a remaining free space between the profile and the lateral surface is so small that it can generally be filled with the plastic without problems. The cross-section of the profile is matched to the cross-section of the electrical line in such a manner that at most a small free space remains between the two. Small, here, means that the free space has a cross-sectional area which is smaller than the cross-sectional area of the electrical line. It can, for example, be 20%, 10%, 5% or less of the cross-sectional area of the cable. The cross-section of the profile can be selected so that it fills, essentially fills or at least partially fills a free space between the lateral surface of the electrical line and material layer located below the electrical line.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The cross-section of the profile can be selected such that a fibrous material layer which covers the upper side of the electrical line rests against the upper side of the electrical line and against the profile. The layer of fibrous material which covers the upper side of the electrical line can also lie against a material layer which is located below the electrical line, specifically to the side of the profile. Through appropriate selection of the cross-section of the profile, all this is possible without the fibrous material layer which covers the electrical line having to have a curvature which this fibrous material layer cannot readily assume during the manufacturing of the laminate.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The upper side of the electrical line can be covered by a single- or multi-layer fibrous material. A single-layer fibrous material above the electrical line can be sufficient for permanent and secure fixation.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The invention prevents a hollow space or resin nest being created on the lateral surface of the electrical line during the manufacture of the laminate. As a result, proper and error-free embedding of the electrical lines in the laminate is ensured. As a result, the manufacturing process is more reliable and expensive reworking can be omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In one embodiment, the electrical line has a lower side which rests against an essentially planar material layer in the area surrounding the electrical line. The planar material layer can be, in particular, a layer of fibrous material. The planar material layer can also be another part of the wind turbine component, such as a filling material of balsa wood or a foamed material which has an essentially planar surface. The lower side of the electrical line can lie opposite the upper side of the electrical line. The area surrounding the electrical line can extend from a middle of the electrical line in the direction of the planar material layer to the lateral surface of the electrical line and beyond. The surrounding area can have, for example, a width which corresponds to twice the diameter of the electrical line or more. In this embodiment, the profile can rest by way of a lower side against the essentially planar material layer and extend from a distance from the electrical line to the lateral surface of the electrical line. Thus, the profile counteracts the formation of the hollow space or plastic nest in the desired manner when the electrical line rests against a planar surface. In this arrangement, the danger of the formation of a hollow space or plastic nest, in particular in connection with an electrical line having a circular cross-section, is especially great.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In one embodiment, the profile has a wedge-shaped or ramp-shaped cross-section. The wedge or the ramp is formed by two surfaces, which can be planar and which abut at a sharp angle. A bottom one of these two surfaces can rest against a material layer against which a lower side of the electrical line also rests. The other of these surfaces forms a surface which slopes up toward the electrical line. It can be covered by the fibrous material layer which covers the upper side of the electrical line. In particular, this fibrous material layer can rest against this surface.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In one embodiment, the profile is made of a flexible material. In principle, the profile can also be made of a relatively stiff material, such as wood in the form of a profile strip. A flexible material can on the one hand simplify the handling even of longer profiles because these can, for example, be rolled up. On the other hand, flexibility or elasticity of the material promotes &#x201c;conformation&#x201d; of the profile to the lateral surface of the electrical line.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In one embodiment, the profile is made of a foamed material. In particular, it can be made of a foamed plastic material, for example a closed-pore foam. Such profiles have a low weight. Furthermore, they are not saturated by the plastic during the injection thereof, thereby further contributing to the low weight of the wind turbine component. Furthermore, they have a high elasticity and compressibility which is particularly suitable for the filling of free spaces between the electrical line and adjacent material layers.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In one embodiment, the profile has a height of 50% or more of the height of the electrical line. For example, the profile extends from a planar material layer on which the electrical line rests with its lower side, up to a height of 50%, 75%, 90% or more of the height of the electrical line. The profile can also extend exactly or at least to a height at which the electrical line has its greatest width. In the case of a circular electrical line, the profile can extend to the height of the center of the electrical line or beyond. As a result of the mentioned heights of the profile, the formation of hollow spaces or plastic nests at the lateral surfaces of the electrical line is already sufficiently counteracted in many instances.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In one embodiment, the electrical line has a circular cross-section and the cross-section of the profile has a concave section which abuts the lateral surface of the electrical line and the curvature radius of which corresponds to the radius of the electrical line. The concave section can lie opposite a tip of a wedge which forms the remainder of the cross-section or of a ramp which forms the remainder of the cross-section. The concave section can rest against the lateral surface of the electrical line. As a result, the formation of a hollow space or a plastic nest, in particular between the concave section of the profile and the electrical line, can be reliably prevented.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In one embodiment, the electrical line has a rectangular cross-section and the profile is triangular in cross-section. A lateral surface of the profile can abut a lateral surface of the electrical line. A further lateral surface of the profile can rest against a planar material layer against which a lower side of the electrical line also rests. A right angle can be formed between the two mentioned sides of the profile, and so the profile has the cross-section of a right-angled triangle.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In one embodiment, a further profile is arranged on a further lateral surface, which is opposite the lateral surface, of the electrical line, said further profile counteracting the formation of a hollow space or plastic nest between the further lateral surface and the fibrous material layer which covers the upper side during the manufacture of the laminate. Thus, profiles are arranged on two opposite lateral surfaces of the electrical line, said profiles having the above-described effect. In the case of multiple adjacently arranged electrical lines, the further lateral surface can also be a lateral surface of a further electrical line which is arranged on that side of the electrical line which is opposite the lateral surface. In this embodiment, in each case the formation of a hollow space or a plastic nest is counteracted on both sides of an electrical line or on both sides of a group of adjacent electrical lines.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In one embodiment, in addition to the electrical line, at least one further electrical line is embedded in the laminate, wherein a further profile is arranged between two of the electrical lines, said further profile counteracting the formation of hollow spaces or plastic nests between these electrical lines and/or between one of these lines and a fibrous material layer which covers the upper side during the manufacture of the laminate. Thus, a hollow space or a plastic nest otherwise possibly arising between two adjacent electrical lines is avoided.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In one embodiment, the further profile arranged between the two electrical lines has two opposite, concavely curved side edges in its cross-section. The profile can have a rectangular basic form, wherein two sides of the rectangle are formed by the two opposite, concavely curved side edges. In connection with circular electrical lines, the curvature radii of the concavely curved side edges can be matched to the radii of the electrical lines, such that the profile rests optimally against the two adjacent lateral surfaces of the electrical lines. Thus, the formation of a hollow space or plastic nest between the two adjacent lines is optimally counteracted.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In one embodiment, the wind turbine component is a rotor blade or a part of a rotor blade. For example, it can also be an upper shell or lower shell of a rotor blade made of two half shells or a strut extending between these half shells in the longitudinal direction of the rotor blade. In both cases, these are components to which an electrical line must be secured, possibly over a great length, and which are constructed of fiber reinforced plastic. Therefore, they are particularly suitable for the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The object indicated above is also achieved by the method of the invention. The method of the invention is for making a wind turbine component and has the following steps:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0002-0001" num="0028">inserting a number of bottom fibrous material layers into a mold,</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0002" num="0029">placing an electrical line onto a material layer,</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0003" num="0030">applying a further material layer which covers an upper side of the electrical line,</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0004" num="0031">injecting a plastic in a vacuum-injection process,</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0005" num="0032">curing the plastic,</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0006" num="0033">removing the wind turbine component from the mold, wherein</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0007" num="0034">prior to the application of the further fibrous material layer which covers the upper side of the electrical line and prior to the injection of the plastic, a profile is placed onto the material layer next to a lateral surface of the electrical line, the profile counteracting the formation of a hollow space or a plastic nest between the lateral surface and the further layer of fibrous material during the injection and curing of the plastic.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0035">For a further description of the features of the method, reference is made to the preceding description of the wind turbine component which can be manufactured by way of the method. The explanation of the materials used and other features, and also the particular advantages of the wind turbine component apply in a corresponding manner to the method.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0036">Vacuum-injection processes are understood as meaning processes in which fibrous materials which have not yet been saturated with the plastic are introduced into a mold. As a rule, the mold corresponds to the outer contour of the component to be manufactured. After the arrangement of the fibrous material, the electrical line and optionally other constituents to be embedded in the laminate, it is closed in an airtight manner, for example by applying a film which is fastened in a sealing manner to the edges of the mold. The liquid plastic material passes through channels and optionally further flow assistants in order to generate a vacuum or a strong negative pressure within the mold in the interior of the mold and in the process is distributed ideally in a bubble-free manner and completely, such that the fibrous material is completely saturated and any hollow spaces are filled completely with resin. In the invention, a profile is placed onto the material layer next to a lateral surface of the electrical line, thereby counteracting the formation of a hollow space or a plastic nest in the above-described manner. For this, and also for the properties of the profile and its precise arrangement in relation to the electrical line and/or the different layers of the fibrous material, reference is made to the above explanations. The material layer may be, in particular, one of the lower fibrous material layers.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0031" num="0037">The invention will now be described with reference to the drawings wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a simplified plan view of a wind turbine rotor blade according to the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a schematic, simplified illustration of a cross-section through the rotor blade from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> along a line designated A-A;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a schematic, simplified cross-sectional illustration of an electrical line embedded according to the invention in a laminate;</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a schematic, simplified cross-sectional illustration of three electrical lines embedded according to the invention in a laminate;</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows a schematic, simplified cross-sectional illustration of an electrical line, having a rectangular cross-section, embedded according to the invention in a laminate; and,</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows a laminate having an embedded electrical line according to the prior art.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0038" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows, as an example of a wind turbine component, a rotor blade <b>10</b> having a blade tip <b>12</b> and a blade root <b>14</b>. The rotor blade has an aerodynamic profile, which is illustrated in cross-section in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0045">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, it can be seen that the rotor blade from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is assembled from an upper shell <b>16</b> and a lower shell <b>18</b>. The upper shell <b>16</b> and the lower shell <b>18</b> are each produced in a vacuum-injection process and subsequently adhesively bonded together along their nose and rear edges.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0046">A supporting structure for this construction has two shear webs (<b>20</b>, <b>22</b>) that extend in the longitudinal direction of the rotor blade <b>10</b>. The shear web <b>20</b> is arranged further forward, toward the profile leading edge <b>24</b>. The shear web <b>22</b> is located further back, as seen in the direction of flow, closer to the profile trailing edge <b>26</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0047">The upper shell <b>16</b> and the lower shell <b>18</b> consist essentially, just like the shear webs <b>20</b> and <b>22</b>, of a laminate which has a multiplicity of layers of fibrous material, which are embedded in a plastic. For the shear webs (<b>20</b>, <b>22</b>), this structure of the laminate is indicated by a plurality of adjacent lines. An electrical line <b>28</b> is embedded in the laminate of the rearward shear web <b>22</b>, as is illustrated in an enlarged manner in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0048">The detail that can be seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a part of the shear web <b>22</b> having an electrical line <b>28</b> in cross-section. In the detail shown, the shear web <b>22</b> has a number of lower fibrous material layers <b>30</b>, which rest against one another. The material layer <b>32</b>, which is the topmost of the fibrous material layers <b>30</b>, is essentially planar in an area surrounding the electrical line <b>28</b> and the electrical line <b>28</b> rests against the material layer <b>32</b> by way of a lower side <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0049">The electrical line <b>28</b> is a lightning protection cable having a circular cross-section. The diameter is about 16 mm. The electrical line <b>28</b> has two opposite lateral surfaces <b>36</b> and <b>38</b> and also an upper side <b>40</b>. On account of the circular cross-section, both the lateral surfaces (<b>36</b>, <b>38</b>) and the lower side <b>34</b> and upper side <b>40</b> of the electrical line <b>28</b> are curved. They form in each case an elongate partial surface of a circular-cylinder jacket.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0050">Arranged on the lateral surface <b>36</b> is a profile <b>42</b>. The latter counteracts the formation of a hollow space or plastic nest between the lateral surface <b>36</b> and a fibrous material layer <b>44</b> which covers the upper side <b>40</b> of the electrical line <b>28</b>. For this, the profile <b>42</b> has a wedge- or ramp-shaped cross-section having a lower, planar surface <b>46</b> which rests against the material layer <b>32</b>, and an upper planar surface <b>48</b> which is arranged at an acute angle thereto. The fibrous material layer <b>44</b> which covers the upper side <b>40</b> of the electrical line <b>28</b> rests against this upper surface <b>48</b> and extends laterally beyond the profile <b>42</b>, where the fibrous material layer <b>44</b> rests against the material layer <b>32</b>. The electrical line <b>28</b> is thus completely enclosed by the material layer <b>32</b> and the fibrous material layer <b>44</b> which covers the upper side <b>40</b> of the electrical line <b>28</b>, and is embedded in the laminate. The same applies to the profile <b>42</b> arranged on the lateral surface <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0051">In cross-section, the profile <b>42</b> has a concave section <b>45</b>, which is adjacent to the lateral surface <b>36</b> of the electrical line <b>28</b> and the curvature radius of which corresponds to the radius of the electrical line <b>28</b>. The further profile <b>50</b> correspondingly has in cross-section a concave section <b>56</b> which is adjacent to the further lateral surface <b>38</b> of the electrical line <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0052">Arranged on the lateral surface <b>38</b> opposite the lateral surface <b>36</b> of the electrical line <b>28</b> is a further profile <b>50</b> which is constructed in a mirror-symmetrical manner in cross-section to the profile <b>42</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0053">The profile <b>42</b> has a height (a), which in the example is measured perpendicularly to the plane of the material layer <b>32</b>. The height (a) is less than the height (h), corresponding to the diameter of the electrical line <b>28</b>, of the electrical line <b>28</b>, but greater than 50% of this height (h). The width (b) of the profile <b>42</b>, measured in the direction of the material layer <b>32</b> and perpendicularly to the longitudinal direction of the electrical line <b>28</b> and of the profile <b>42</b> is approximately twice the height (a) of the profile <b>42</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0054">The entire arrangement illustrated has been saturated with a plastic in a vacuum-injection process, wherein no hollow spaces that endanger the stability of the arrangement remain between the components illustrated in detail.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0055"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates a further exemplary embodiment, wherein the same reference signs as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> are used for corresponding components, as is the case also in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. The exemplary embodiment in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> differs from that in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> in that two further electrical lines <b>52</b> and <b>54</b> are arranged next to the electrical line <b>28</b>. A profile <b>42</b> is arranged on the lateral surface <b>36</b> of the electrical line <b>28</b> in the manner already described. On that side of the electrical line <b>28</b> that is opposite the lateral surface <b>36</b>, there are two further electrical lines (<b>52</b>, <b>54</b>). Between the electrical line <b>28</b> and the further electrical line <b>52</b> there is a further profile <b>58</b> which has a rectangular basic form in cross-section, wherein two opposite sides of the rectangle which are adjacent to the lateral surfaces <b>38</b> and <b>62</b> of the electrical lines <b>28</b> and <b>52</b>, respectively, are formed by concavely curved surfaces (<b>64</b>, <b>66</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0056">Between the further electrical lines (<b>52</b>, <b>54</b>) there is arranged a further profile <b>60</b>, which has the same cross-section as the profile <b>58</b>. It is adjacent to a further lateral surface <b>68</b> of the electrical line <b>52</b> and a lateral surface <b>70</b> of the further electrical line <b>54</b>. On a further lateral surface <b>72</b> of the electrical line <b>54</b> there is arranged a further profile <b>50</b> which is formed in a manner corresponding to the further profile <b>50</b> from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0057">The entire arrangement of the electrical lines (<b>28</b>, <b>52</b>, <b>54</b>) and the profiles (<b>42</b>, <b>58</b>, <b>60</b>, <b>50</b>) is covered by a layer of fibrous material <b>44</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0058"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows, as a further exemplary embodiment, a laminate in which an electrical line <b>74</b> having a rectangular cross-section is embedded. In this case, the electrical line <b>74</b> has a planar lateral surface <b>76</b> on which a profile <b>78</b> is arranged. The profile <b>78</b> has the cross-section of a right-angled triangle. On a further lateral surface <b>80</b>, opposite the lateral surface <b>76</b> of the electrical line <b>74</b>, there is arranged a further profile <b>82</b>. The arrangement of the electrical line <b>74</b> and the two profiles (<b>78</b>, <b>82</b>) rests on a topmost, planar material layer <b>32</b> of the fibrous material layers <b>30</b> and is covered by a layer of fibrous material <b>44</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0059"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates the problem that exists in the prior art. Illustrated is an electrical line <b>84</b> having a rectangular cross-section, said electrical line <b>84</b> being embedded in a laminate. It rests on a number of fibrous material layers <b>86</b>. Furthermore, it is covered by a further fibrous material layer <b>88</b>. Between the lateral surfaces (<b>90</b>, <b>92</b>) of the electrical line <b>84</b> and the fibrous material layer <b>88</b> covering the electrical line <b>84</b>, hollow spaces <b>94</b> have formed during the manufacture of the laminate.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0060">It is understood that the foregoing description is that of the preferred embodiments of the invention and that various changes and modifications may be made thereto without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention as defined in the appended claims.</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">LIST OF REFERENCE SIGNS</heading>
<p id="p-0055" num="0000">
<ul id="ul0003" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0003-0001" num="0061"><b>10</b> Rotor blade</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0002" num="0062"><b>12</b> Blade tip</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0003" num="0063"><b>14</b> Blade root</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0004" num="0064"><b>16</b> Upper shell</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0005" num="0065"><b>18</b> Lower shell</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0006" num="0066"><b>20</b> Forward shear web</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0007" num="0067"><b>22</b> Rearward shear web</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0008" num="0068"><b>24</b> Profile leading edge</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0009" num="0069"><b>26</b> Profile trailing edge</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0010" num="0070"><b>28</b> Electrical line</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0011" num="0071"><b>30</b> Lower fibrous material layers</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0012" num="0072"><b>32</b> Material layer</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0013" num="0073"><b>34</b> Lower side of the electrical line <b>28</b></li>
    <li id="ul0003-0014" num="0074"><b>36</b> Lateral surface of the electrical line <b>28</b></li>
    <li id="ul0003-0015" num="0075"><b>38</b> Further lateral surface of the electrical line <b>28</b></li>
    <li id="ul0003-0016" num="0076"><b>40</b> Upper side of the electrical line <b>28</b></li>
    <li id="ul0003-0017" num="0077"><b>42</b> Profile</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0018" num="0078"><b>44</b> Covering fibrous material layer</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0019" num="0079"><b>45</b> Concave section of the profile <b>42</b></li>
    <li id="ul0003-0020" num="0080"><b>46</b> Lower surface of the profile <b>42</b></li>
    <li id="ul0003-0021" num="0081"><b>48</b> Upper surface of the profile <b>42</b></li>
    <li id="ul0003-0022" num="0082"><b>50</b> Further profile</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0023" num="0083"><b>52</b> Further electrical line</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0024" num="0084"><b>54</b> Further electrical line</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0025" num="0085"><b>56</b> Concave section of the further profile <b>50</b></li>
    <li id="ul0003-0026" num="0086"><b>58</b> Further profile</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0027" num="0087"><b>60</b> Further profile</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0028" num="0088"><b>62</b> Lateral surface of the further electrical line <b>52</b></li>
    <li id="ul0003-0029" num="0089"><b>64</b> Concave surface of the profile <b>58</b></li>
    <li id="ul0003-0030" num="0090"><b>66</b> Further concave surface of the profile <b>58</b></li>
    <li id="ul0003-0031" num="0091"><b>68</b> Further lateral surface of the electrical line <b>52</b></li>
    <li id="ul0003-0032" num="0092"><b>70</b> Lateral surface of the electrical line <b>54</b></li>
    <li id="ul0003-0033" num="0093"><b>72</b> Further lateral surface of the electrical line <b>54</b></li>
    <li id="ul0003-0034" num="0094"><b>74</b> Electrical line</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0035" num="0095"><b>76</b> Lateral surface of the electrical line <b>74</b></li>
    <li id="ul0003-0036" num="0096"><b>78</b> Profile</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0037" num="0097"><b>80</b> Further lateral surface of the electrical line <b>74</b></li>
    <li id="ul0003-0038" num="0098"><b>82</b> Further profile</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0039" num="0099"><b>84</b> Electrical line</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0040" num="0100"><b>86</b> Lower fibrous material layers</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0041" num="0101"><b>88</b> Covering fibrous material layer</li>
    <li id="ul0003-0042" num="0102"><b>90</b> Lateral surface of the electrical line <b>84</b></li>
    <li id="ul0003-0043" num="0103"><b>92</b> Further lateral surface of the electrical line <b>84</b></li>
    <li id="ul0003-0044" num="0104"><b>94</b> Hollow space or resin nest</li>
</ul>
</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A wind turbine component comprising:
<claim-text>a laminate of fibrous material and plastic;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an electrical cable having a lateral surface, an upper side and a lower side and being embedded in said laminate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said laminate including a fibrous material cover layer and a plurality of lower fibrous material layers;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said plurality of lower fibrous material layers including a topmost lower fibrous material layer disposed beneath said cover layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said lower side of the electrical cable resting on the topmost lower fibrous material layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said cover layer being arranged so as to cover said upper side of said electrical cable; and,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a profile arranged on said lateral surface and configured to counteract a formation of a hollow space or a plastic nest between said lateral surface and said fibrous material cover layer during the manufacture of said laminate; and,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said cover layer extending laterally beyond said profile and resting against said topmost lower fibrous material layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The wind turbine component of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said topmost lower fibrous material layer is an essentially planar material layer in an area of said electrical cable; and,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said electrical cable has a lower side which rests against said essentially planar material layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The wind turbine component of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said profile has a cross-section which is wedge-shaped.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The wind turbine component of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said profile has a cross-section which is ramp-shaped.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The wind turbine component of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said profile is made of a flexible material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The wind turbine component of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said profile is made of a foamed material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The wind turbine component of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said electrical cable has a height (h);</claim-text>
<claim-text>said profile has a height (a); and,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said height (a) of said profile is at least 50% of said height (h) of said electrical cable.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The wind turbine component of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said electrical cable has a circular cross-section and a first curvature radius;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said profile has a cross-section having a concave section with a second curvature radius;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said concave section of said profile is arranged so as to border on said lateral surface of said electrical cable and,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said second curvature radius of said concave section of said profile corresponds to said first curvature radius of said electrical cable.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The wind turbine component of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said electrical cable has a rectangular cross-section; and,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said profile has a triangular cross-section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The wind turbine component of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said electrical cable has a further lateral surface arranged adjacent to said lateral surface, said wind turbine component further comprising:
<claim-text>a further profile arranged on said further lateral surface; and,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said further profile being configured to counteract a formation of a hollow space or a plastic nest between said further lateral surface and said fibrous material cover layer during the manufacture of said laminate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The wind turbine component of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said electrical cable is a first electrical cable and said profile is a first profile, said wind turbine component further comprising:
<claim-text>at least a second electrical cable;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said second profile arranged between said first electrical cable and said second electrical cable; and,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said second profile being configured to, during the manufacture of said laminate, counteract a formation of a hollow space or plastic nest between said first electrical cable and said second electrical cable and/or between one of said first and second electrical cables and said fibrous material cover layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The wind turbine component of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein said second profile has a cross-section having two concavely curved side edges lying opposite one another.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The wind turbine component of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said wind turbine component is one of a rotor blade and a part of a rotor blade.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The wind turbine component of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said wind turbine component was manufactured in a vacuum injection process.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A method for making a wind turbine component comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>inserting a plurality of fibrous material layers including a topmost lower fibrous material layer into a mold;</claim-text>
<claim-text>placing an electrical cable having a lateral surface onto the topmost lower fibrous material layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>placing a profile next to the lateral surface of the electrical cable on the topmost lower fibrous material layer on which the electrical cable was placed to counteract a formation of a hollow space or a plastic nest between said lateral surface and said topmost lower fibrous material layer during the manufacture of said laminate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a cover fibrous material layer which covers an upper side of the electrical cable and which extends laterally beyond said profile and rests against said topmost lower fibrous material layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>injecting a plastic in a vacuum injection process;</claim-text>
<claim-text>curing the plastic; and,</claim-text>
<claim-text>removing the wind turbine component from the mold.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
