<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625494-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625494</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13216578</doc-number>
<date>20110824</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>100108884 A</doc-number>
<date>20110316</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>196</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20090101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>W</subclass>
<main-group>4</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>370328</main-classification>
<further-classification>370401</further-classification>
<further-classification>370466</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Portable router and power saving control method thereof</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7778230</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Fulknier et al.</name>
<date>20100800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>370338</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0013173</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Rinne et al.</name>
<date>20060100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>370338</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0204072</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Doan et al.</name>
<date>20070800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>710 19</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0123575</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Jaakkola</name>
<date>20080500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>370311</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0040990</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Xhafa et al.</name>
<date>20090200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>370338</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0239024</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hsieh et al.</name>
<date>20110900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>713323</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>17</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>370328</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>370400-401</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>370466</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120236770</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120920</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yeh</last-name>
<first-name>Hung-Yao</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yeh</last-name>
<first-name>Hung-Yao</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Thomas | Horstemeyer, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Tran</last-name>
<first-name>Phuc</first-name>
<department>2471</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The invention discloses a portable router and a power saving control method thereof. The portable router is capable of routing a signal among the network end and at least one electronic device. Each of the at least one electronic device has a wireless data transmitting function. The portable router comprises a first network module, a second network module, a sensing module and a data processing module. The first network module and the second network module can be switched on or off independently, the first network module is capable of exchanging signal to the network end by the first format, the second module is capable of exchanging the signal to the at least one electronic device by the second format. The sensing module is electronically connected with the network end for generating a status signal in accordance with the pre-determined state. The data processing module is capable of determining and processing a pre-determined function in accordance with the status signal and the pre-determined order.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="143.26mm" wi="183.30mm" file="US08625494-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="163.83mm" wi="186.01mm" file="US08625494-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="228.77mm" wi="187.62mm" file="US08625494-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="227.92mm" wi="161.46mm" file="US08625494-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="226.40mm" wi="189.15mm" file="US08625494-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="254.08mm" wi="161.46mm" file="US08625494-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority to Taiwan Patent Application entitled &#x201c;PORTABLE ROUTER AND POWER SAVING CONTROL METHOD THEREOF&#x201d; having serial number 100108887, filed on Mar. 16, 2011, which is incorporated by reference in its entirety.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention discloses a portable router which is capable of adjusting the power supplying status of the modules of the portable router respectively in accordance with the loading of the portable routing device</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Prior Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Router is a computer network device, capable of transmitting packages to a receiving end via the network, the said process is called as routing.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The well-known portable router of the prior art is only a simple combination of the wireless network routing device and cellular data interface. However, since most of the portable devices are capable of obtaining electricity directly from the grid-connected electricity network or dedicated battery, therefore, the problem of power saving of the portable router is not been focused by the one skilled in the art. However, since the latest version of the portable router is now able to be integrated into the smart phone, providing the smart phone the capability of routing so as to provide the electronic device having wireless transmission function to get access to the network via the smart phone having routing function. Since the power that can be provided by the battery of the smart phone is limited, therefore, the power consumption rate of the portable router become one of the main features to distinguish the quality of the portable router.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In the prior art, disregarding the loading of the portable routing device, the portable router maintains the connection with the portable routing device by consistently exchanging data with the electronic devices, resulting in the unnecessary power consumption. In order to overcome the said problem, the prior art utilized a switch on/switch off function to allow the user to switch off the routing function while the routing function is not in use. However, while the routing function is turned off, the user has to turn on the routing function manually before the electronic device is able to get access to the network via the portable routing device.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Therefore, a need exists, for a portable routing device that is capable of decreasing the power consumption rate by adjusting the power supplying status of the modules disposed therein respectively in accordance with the loading of the portable routing device.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In one aspect of the invention, a portable router is provided. The portable router is utilized to establish a connection between a network end and at least one electronic device. The portable router also has a wireless data transmitting function. The portable router previously described comprises a first network module, a second network module, a sensing module and a data processing module. The first network module, utilized to communicate with the network end with the first format, is capable of being switched on or off independently. The second network module, utilized to communicate with the electronic device with the second format, capable of being switched on or off independently. The sensing module, electronically connected with the network end, utilized to generate a condition signal in accordance with a pre-determined condition. The data processing module utilized to execute a pre-determined function in accordance with the condition signal or a pre-determined command, wherein the pre-determined command is defined by a user.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In actual practice, the first format is Wireless Wide-area Data Network such as GPRS, EDGE, WCDMA, EVDO, TD-SCDMA, HS(D/U)PA, HSPA+, LTE or WiMAX, the second format is Wireless Local Area Network.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Furthermore, the present invention can further comprises a third network module, which is utilized to exchange data with electronic device, the third network module can be switched on or off independently, wherein the electronic devices support a Wireless Person Area Network.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Furthermore, the present invention can further comprise an interface module, electronically connected with the data processing module, for providing a user interface to display the condition of the portable router to the user or to obtain the pre-determined command from the user.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Meanwhile, the pre-determined function previously described comprises a timing control function, the timing control function is capable of controlling the first network module or the second network module to switch on or off the first network module or the second network module individually or simultaneously, or setting the data processing module to a power saving mode or an active mode at an indicated time or a time period.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Nevertheless, the pre-determined function can further comprises an electronic device summoning function, the electronic device summoning function is capable of sending a signal to an electronic device to switch on the electronic device, determining a routing order of the electronic device or transmitting data to the electronic device. Furthermore, the pre-determined condition is that a signal is received by the sensing module or the first network module from the network end.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Another aspect of the invention generally provides a controlling method of a portable router for saving power, the portable router comprising a first network module, a second network module, a sensing module and a data processing module, the portable router is utilized to establish a connection between a network end and distributing the signal from the network end to the electronic device. The electronic device has a wireless data transmitting function. The controlling method of the invention comprises the steps of step S<b>1</b>, step S<b>2</b> and S<b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Step S<b>1</b> is to execute an initialization process to obtain a first condition from a user and set the data processing module to a power saving mode. Step S<b>2</b> is to determine if the portable router matches the first condition, if yes, execute the first process to switch on or off the first network module or the second network module individually or simultaneously, or set the data processing module to a power saving mode or an active mode. And the step S<b>3</b> is to determine if the portable router matches the second condition, if yes, execute a second process to switch on or off the first network module or the second network module individually or simultaneously, or set the data processing module to a power saving mode or an active mode, if no, execute a third process.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Meanwhile, in the actual practice, the initialization process comprises the Step S<b>11</b> to Step S<b>15</b>. The step S<b>11</b> is to obtain the first condition from the user; the step S<b>12</b> is to establish a connecting between the portable router and the electronic device. The step S<b>13</b> is to create an electronic device list; the step S<b>14</b> is to count the time length of the data processing module in the active mode; and the step S<b>15</b> is to determine if the time length of the data processing module in the active mode reaches the first timing threshold, if yes, set the data processing module to the power saving mode. Meanwhile, the first timing threshold is an indicate time or an indicate time period</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Furthermore, in actual practice, the first condition is that the first network module switched off and the time length that the data processing module at the power saving mode reaches the second time threshold, the first process is corresponding to the first condition. The first process comprises the steps of the step S<b>22</b>, the step S<b>24</b>, the step S<b>26</b> and the Step S<b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">However, the first condition can also be that the first network module is switched on and a signal or a user data is received by the first network module from the network end, the first process corresponding to the first condition comprises the step S<b>22</b>, step S<b>24</b> and the step S<b>28</b>. The step S<b>22</b> is to determine if the portable router matching with the first condition, if yes, execute the step S<b>24</b> and step <b>28</b>. The step S<b>24</b> is to set the data processing module to an active mode. The step <b>28</b> is to establish an internet connection to the network end via the first network module.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Meanwhile, the first condition can also be that the sensing module of the portable router accepts a signal from the network end, the first process corresponding to the first condition comprises the step S<b>22</b>, step S<b>24</b>, step S<b>26</b> and step S<b>28</b>. The step S<b>22</b> is to determine if the portable router matching with the first condition, if yes, execute the step S<b>24</b>, step S<b>26</b> and step <b>28</b>. The step <b>24</b> is to set the data processing module to an active mode. The step <b>26</b> is to switch on the first network module. The step <b>28</b> is to establish an internet connection to the network end via the first network module.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In actual practice, the second condition is that a signal or a user data is detected from the network end, the second process corresponding to the second condition comprises the step of S<b>32</b>. The step <b>32</b> is to determine if the at least one electronic device matches the routing order, if yes, switch on or switching off the first network module, the second network module or switching the data processing module among the active mode or the power saving mode; if no, save the user data or alerting the user for updates. Furthermore, the step S<b>32</b> comprises the following sub-steps of step S<b>322</b>, step S<b>324</b>, step S<b>326</b> and step S<b>328</b>. Step S<b>322</b> is to determine if the at least one electronic device <b>3</b> matches a routing order, if yes, execute step S<b>324</b>, step S<b>326</b> and step S<b>329</b>; if not, execute step S<b>328</b> and step S<b>38</b>. The step S<b>324</b> is to switch on the second network module <b>12</b>. The step S<b>326</b> is to transmit the data of the user to the at least one electronic device <b>3</b> via the network module. The step S<b>328</b> is to save the user data or alert the user for update. The step S<b>38</b> is to set the data processing module to the power saving mode. The step S<b>329</b> is to set the data processing module to the power saving mode under a predetermined condition. The pre-determined condition may refer to the condition that no user data transmission within a pre-determined period.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Meanwhile, the second condition can also be the electronic device match a routing order, the second process corresponding to the second condition comprises the step of S<b>324</b>, step S<b>326</b> and the step S<b>329</b>. The step S<b>324</b> is to switch on the second network module. The step S<b>326</b> is to transmit the data of the user to the at least one electronic device via the network module. The step S<b>329</b> is to set the data processing module to the power saving mode.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In actual practice, the third process comprises the following steps of step S<b>36</b> and step S<b>38</b>. The step S<b>36</b> is to switch off the first network module and reset the time length of the data processing module to be in the active mode respectively; and the step S<b>38</b> is to set the data processing module to the power saving mode.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The third process may also comprise the steps of S<b>328</b> and the step S<b>38</b>. The step S<b>328</b> is to save the user data or alerting the user for update; and the step S<b>38</b> is to set the data processing module to the power saving mode.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Another aspect of the invention generally provides a controlling method of a portable router for saving power, the portable router comprises a first network module, a second network module and a data processing module. The portable router is utilized to establish a connection between a network end and distribute the signal from the network end to the electronic device. The electronic device has a wireless data transmitting function. The controlling method comprises the following steps of step S<b>1</b>, step S<b>2</b> and the step S<b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The step S<b>1</b> is to execute an initialization process to obtain a first condition from a user and set the data processing module to a power saving mode. The step S<b>2</b> is to determine if the portable router matches the first condition, if yes, execute the first process to switch on or off the first network module or the second network module individually or simultaneously, or set the data processing module to power saving mode or an active mode. The step S<b>3</b> is to determine if the portable router matches the second condition, if yes, execute a second process to switch on or off the first network module or the second network module individually or simultaneously, or set the data processing module to a power saving mode or an active mode, if no, execute a third process.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE APPENDED DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The teachings of the present invention can be readily understood by considering the following detailed description in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> depicts a function block diagram of one of the embodiment of the portable router <b>1</b> of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> depicts a flow chart diagram of the embodiment of the controlling method for saving power of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> depicts a flow chart diagram of the embodiment of the initialization process of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> depicts a flow chart diagram of the another embodiment of the initialization process of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> depicts a flow chart diagram of the another embodiment of the initialization process of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The present invention generally provides a portable router <b>1</b> and the power saving control method thereof. Please refer to the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> depicts a function block diagram of one of the preferred embodiment of the portable router of the present invention. The present invention discloses a portable router <b>1</b>, utilized to establish a connection between a network end <b>2</b> and at least one electronic devices <b>3</b>. Each of the electronic device <b>3</b> has a wireless data transmitting function. In the present embodiment, the amount of the electronic device <b>3</b> that the portable router <b>1</b> is able to support is larger than <b>2</b>. Furthermore, the portable router <b>1</b> of the present invention comprises a first network module <b>11</b>, a second network module <b>12</b>, a third network module <b>13</b>, a sensing module <b>14</b>, an interface module <b>15</b>, a power supplying module <b>16</b>, a storage module <b>17</b> and a data processing module <b>18</b>. However, depend on the requirement of the user, the modules consisted in the portable router <b>1</b> can be modified accordingly. For example, the third network module <b>13</b> or second network module <b>12</b> in the portable router <b>1</b> can be optionally removed in accordance with the demand of the user.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The network end <b>2</b> of the present invention generally refers to a network provider which the portable router <b>1</b> is capable of sending, accepting or exchanging data or signal therewith. The network end <b>2</b> may be a wireless form network source or a wire connected network source. Furthermore, in the present embodiment, the network end <b>2</b> refers to an internet source utilizing LTE format.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Furthermore, the electronic device <b>3</b> of the present invention generally refers to an electronic device <b>3</b> having a wireless data transmitting function. In the present embodiment, the electronic device <b>3</b> can be, but not limited to be a laptop computer. The electronic device <b>3</b> can also be a digital camera, an electronic book, pad shaped or desktop computer, smart phone or any other electronic device <b>3</b> having the wireless data transmitting function. Furthermore, the present invention of portable router <b>1</b> is capable of connecting a plurality of electronic devices <b>3</b> with the network end <b>2</b> simultaneously.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The first network module <b>11</b> is utilized to communicate with the network end <b>2</b> with a first format for exchanging data or signal therewith. Different from the prior art, the first network <b>11</b> of the present invention can be switched on or switched off independently in accordance with the setting configured by the user via the interface module <b>15</b> during an initialization process. In the present embodiment, the first network module <b>11</b> of the present invention is a wireless network adapter, which the corresponding first format is a LTE. However, the first network module <b>11</b> of the present invention is not limited to the wireless network adapter, according to the requirement of the user, the first network module <b>11</b> can also be a traditional network adapter utilizing cable to connect therewith. Furthermore, the first format is not limited to LTE, the first format can also be GPRS, EDGE, WCDMA, EVDO, TD-SCDMA, HS(D/U)PA, HSPA+, WIMAX, any other related Wireless Wide Area Network format or the composition thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Nevertheless, the first network module <b>11</b> can also be switched on or off in accordance with the conditions of the other modules of the portable router <b>1</b> to maximize the electricity efficiency thereof. The said conditions of the modules generally refer to the power supplying status, the timing of being switched on or off, the time length of the modules which is turned on, turned off, in the active mode or in the inactive mode. The condition of the module may also refer to the status that the module receives signal or data.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The second network module <b>12</b> is utilized to communicate with the electronic device <b>3</b> with a second format for exchanging data or signal therewith. The second network module <b>12</b> can be switched on or switched off independently. The second network module <b>12</b> can also be capable of conferring a local IP address to each of the said electronic devices <b>3</b> for tracking or maintaining the connection with the electronic device <b>3</b>, then, the said local IP addresses can be stored in a storing module <b>17</b> connected with the second network module <b>12</b> by a form of address mapping table. The second network module <b>12</b> is utilized to construct a wireless LAN, WLAN, using no conducting or transmitting cable but micro-wave as the transmission mean. Accordingly, the electronic devices <b>3</b> are able to get access to the network end <b>2</b> via the WLAN constructed by the portable router <b>1</b> of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Similar to the first network module <b>11</b>, the second network module <b>12</b> of the present invention can be switched on or switched off independently in accordance with the setting configured by the user via the interface module <b>15</b> during an initialization process. Nevertheless, the second network module <b>12</b> can also be switched on or switched off in accordance with the conditions of the other modules of the portable router <b>1</b> in order to maximize the electricity efficiency thereof. The definition of the condition of the other modules will be omitted herein for the clarity of the specification since it has already been described previously.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The third network module <b>13</b>, supporting a Wireless Person Area Network, is utilized to establish a connection between a cellular network and the electronic device <b>3</b> for allowing the electronic device <b>3</b> which supporting WPAN to communicate or to exchange signal or data therewith. Similar to the first network module <b>11</b>, the third network module <b>13</b> can also be switched on or off independently.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In the present embodiment, the third network module <b>13</b> can be, but not limited to, a blue-teeth transmitting module, the third network module <b>13</b> can also be any other wireless transmission means which support WPAN, such as infra-red, magnetic wave or light wave.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In the present embodiment, the sensing module <b>14</b> is electronically connected with the network end <b>2</b> to maintain switched on and sense the condition of the network end <b>2</b> and generate a condition signal to the data processing module <b>18</b> in accordance with a pre-determined condition.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Since the sensing module <b>14</b> is utilized to sense the condition of the network end <b>2</b> so as to transmit a corresponding signal to the data processing module <b>18</b>, the sensing module <b>14</b> does not share the main function of the first network module <b>11</b>, the second network module <b>12</b> and the third network module <b>13</b>, therefore, the sensing module <b>14</b> has a relatively low power consumption rate.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In order to decrease the power consumption rate of the portable router <b>1</b> of the present invention, the first network module <b>11</b>, second network module <b>12</b> and the third network module <b>13</b> will be switch off while the portable router <b>1</b> is not in used. Meanwhile, the sensing module <b>14</b> keep monitoring the network end <b>2</b>. The sensing module <b>14</b> shall generate a condition signal in accordance with the status of the network end <b>2</b> and send the condition signal to the data processing module <b>18</b>. With the condition signal, the data processing module <b>18</b> is capable of activating the first network module <b>11</b>, the second network module <b>12</b> or the third network module <b>13</b> individually or simultaneously in accordance with the condition signal or pre-determined command to decrease the power consumption rate.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In the present embodiment, the data processing module <b>18</b> refer to a central processing unit, which is electronically connected to the other modules or components of the portable router <b>1</b> of the present invention. The data processing module <b>18</b> is capable of switching on, switching off the modules in accordance with the signal or data received from the other modules of the portable router <b>1</b>. Furthermore, the data processing module <b>18</b> is also capable of controlling the said modules in the portable router <b>1</b> to transmit or encode data therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The data processing module <b>18</b> is also capable of processing an indicate function in accordance with the condition signal or a predetermined command, wherein the said indicate function comprises a timing control function and an electronic devices summoning function.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The timing control function is generally indicated to a function that is capable of controlling the first network module <b>11</b>, the second network module <b>12</b> and the third network module <b>13</b> to be switched on or switched off individually or simultaneously in accordance with the setting of the initialization process configured by the user, wherein the setting may comprises a parameter of an indicate time, an indicate time period, a relative time or a relative time period. Furthermore, the timing control function can also be capable of switching the data processing module <b>18</b> among the power saving mode and active mode.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The indicate time or indicate time period refers to an explicit time or an explicit time period, for example, the explicit time period may represent the time period of 12 o'clock at noon to the 2 pm of everyday. The relative time period may refer to the time length after finishing the initialization process.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Furthermore, the power saving mode and the active mode of the data processing module <b>18</b> are a relative concept which is defined by the power consumption rate thereof. While the data processing module <b>18</b> is in the power saving mode, the power consumption rate is lower than the active mode, meanwhile the processing capability thereof may also be decreased correspondingly in order to save the power consumed while the power consumption requirement of the system is relatively low. The data processing module <b>18</b> may react in accordance with the condition signal. Nevertheless, the condition signal previously described refers to a signal generated by the sensing module <b>14</b> while a pre-determined condition is achieved thereby.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The power supplying module <b>16</b> is electronically connected with the other modules of the portable router <b>1</b>. The power supplying module <b>16</b> is capable of selectively providing the power to the indicate module to let the indicate module to be switched on or switched off in accordance with the signal sent by the data processing module <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The interface module <b>15</b>, electronically connected with the data processing module <b>18</b>, is for providing a user interface to display a status of portable router <b>1</b> to the user so as to let the user input a pre-determined command. In the present embodiment, the interface module <b>15</b> comprises, but not limited to, a display monitor and a keypad. However, the interface module <b>15</b> can also be a touch pad, a module having voice identifying function, a module having gesture recognition function or any other forms of inputting or outputting means in accordance with the requirement of the user.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Please refer the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> depicts a flow chart diagram of the embodiment of the controlling method of a portable router for saving power. In the present embodiment, the portable router <b>1</b> comprises a first network module <b>11</b>, a second network module <b>12</b>, a third network module <b>13</b>, a sensing module <b>14</b>, an interface module <b>15</b>, a power supplying module <b>16</b> and a data processing module <b>18</b>. The portable router <b>1</b> is utilized to establish a connection among a network end <b>2</b> and the electronic devices <b>3</b>, so as to distribute the signal from the network end <b>2</b> to the electronic devices <b>3</b>. The electronic devices <b>3</b> has a wireless data transmitting function. The controlling method for saving power of the present invention comprises step S<b>1</b>, Step S<b>2</b> and Step S<b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The step S<b>1</b> is to execute an initialization process to obtain a first condition from a user and set the data processing module <b>18</b> to a power saving mode. The said initialization process comprises a plurality of sub-steps, which comprises step S<b>11</b>, step S<b>12</b>, step S<b>13</b>, step S<b>14</b> and step S<b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The step S<b>11</b> is to obtain the first condition from the user, the user may know the status of the portable router <b>1</b> via the interface module <b>15</b> and set the first condition accordingly thereby. In the present embodiment, the first condition is that the first network module <b>11</b> is switched off and the time length that the data processing module <b>18</b> at the power saving mode reaches the second time threshold. In summary, the first condition is that the first network module <b>11</b> is switched off and the indicate time or time length of the data processing module <b>18</b> is in the power saving mode. However, the first condition is not limited to the said example, the first condition can also be fulfilled while the first network module <b>11</b> is switched on and the first network module <b>11</b> of the portable receives a user data or signal from the network end <b>2</b>. The first condition may also be that the sensing module <b>14</b> accepts a signal from the network end <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The step S<b>12</b> is to establish a connecting between the portable router <b>1</b> and the electronic device <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The step S<b>13</b> is to create an electronic device <b>3</b> list, wherein the electronic device <b>3</b> list is an Internal Router or Address Mapping Table. The electronic device <b>3</b> list is utilized to authorize an IP address to the electronic devices <b>3</b> respectively to identify the path of data transmission.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The step S<b>14</b> is to count the time length of the data processing module <b>18</b> in the active mode for obtaining the time length that the portable router <b>1</b> in the active mode and without data transmission.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The step S<b>15</b> is to determine if the time length of the data processing module <b>18</b> in the active mode reaches the first timing threshold, if yes, set the data processing module <b>18</b> to the power saving mode; if no, then repeat the step S<b>15</b> after a pre-determined period of time. Furthermore, the first timing threshold can be configured by the user, wherein the first timing threshold may comprise a parameter of indicate time, an indicate time period, a relative time or a relative time period, since the definition of the time related terms are described previously, it will be omitted herein for the clarity of the specification.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Please refer to the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, after finishing the initiation process, the step S<b>2</b> is then executed. The step S<b>2</b> is to determine if the portable router <b>1</b> matches to the first condition, if yes, execute the first process to switch on or switch off the first network module <b>11</b> or the second network module <b>12</b> individually or simultaneously, or set the data processing module <b>18</b> to a power saving mode or an active mode.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">In the present embodiment, the said first condition refers to the condition that the first network module <b>11</b> is switched off and the time length that the data processing module <b>18</b> at the power saving mode reaches the second time threshold, the first process is corresponding to the first condition. Furthermore, the second timing threshold can be configured by the user, wherein the second timing threshold may be a parameter of an indicate time, an indicate time period, a relative time or a relative time period. The definition of the time related terms will be omitted herein for the clarity of the specification since it has been described previously.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">In the present embodiment, the step S<b>2</b> further comprises a plurality of sub-steps, which is the step S<b>22</b>, the step S<b>24</b>, the step S<b>26</b> and the step S<b>28</b>. The step S<b>22</b> is to determine if the portable router <b>1</b> matches with the first condition, if yes, execute the step S<b>24</b>, step S<b>26</b> and step S<b>28</b> correspondingly. The step S<b>24</b> is to set the data processing module <b>18</b> to an active mode. The step S<b>26</b> is to switch on the first network module <b>11</b>. The step S<b>28</b> is to establish an internet connection to the network end <b>2</b> via the first network module <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">After finishing the step S<b>2</b>, then execute step S<b>3</b>. The Step S<b>3</b> of the present invention is to determine if the portable router <b>1</b> matches the second condition, if yes, execute a second process to switch on or off the first network module <b>11</b> or the second network module <b>12</b> individually or simultaneously, or set the data processing module <b>18</b> to a power saving mode or an active mode, if no, execute a third process.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">In the present embodiment, the second condition is that a signal or a user data is detected from the network end <b>2</b>. Correspondingly, the second process corresponding to the second condition comprises the step S<b>32</b>, step S<b>32</b> is to determine if the at least one electronic device <b>3</b> matches the routing order, if yes, switch on or switching off the first network module <b>11</b>, the second network module <b>12</b> or switching the data processing module <b>18</b> among the active mode or the power saving mode; if no, save the user data or alerting the user for update.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The step S<b>32</b> comprises step <b>322</b>, step <b>324</b>, step <b>326</b>, step <b>328</b>, step <b>38</b> and step <b>329</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The step S<b>322</b> is to determine if the at least one electronic device <b>3</b> matches with a routing order, if yes, execute step S<b>324</b>, step S<b>326</b> and step S<b>329</b>; if not, execute step S<b>328</b> and step S<b>38</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The step S<b>324</b> is to switch on the second network module <b>12</b>. The step S<b>326</b> is to transmit the data of the user to the at least one electronic device <b>3</b> via the network module. The step S<b>328</b> is to save the user data or alert the user for updating. The step S<b>38</b> is to set the data processing module <b>18</b> to the power saving mode. The step S<b>329</b> is to set the data processing module <b>18</b> to the power saving mode, more specifically, the step S<b>38</b> is to set the data processing module <b>18</b> to the power saving mode instantly. The step S<b>329</b> is to set the data processing module <b>18</b> to the power saving mode under a pre-determined condition. The pre-determined condition may refer to the condition that no user data transmission within a pre-determined time period.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Furthermore, please refer to the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> depicts a flow chart diagram of another embodiment of the initialization process of the present invention. Some of the descriptions of the steps are omitted herein for the clarity since the descriptions of the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is similar to the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">Please refer to the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the step S<b>1</b> of the present embodiment is the same as the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. However, the step S<b>2</b> of the present invention is different from the previous embodiment since the first condition is that the first network module <b>11</b> is switched on and a signal or a user data is received by the first network module <b>11</b> from the network end <b>2</b>. Furthermore, the first process corresponding to the first condition comprises the step S<b>22</b>, the step S<b>24</b> and the step S<b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">The step S<b>22</b> is to determine if the portable router <b>1</b> matching with the first condition, if yes, execute the step S<b>24</b> and step <b>28</b>. The step S<b>24</b> is to set the data processing module <b>18</b> to an active mode. The step S<b>28</b> is to establish an internet connection to the network end <b>2</b> via the first network module <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">Furthermore, in the present embodiment, the second condition of the step S<b>3</b> and the corresponding second process is different from the embodiment present in the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. In the present embodiment, the second condition is that the electronic device <b>3</b> matches a routing order.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">The second process corresponding to the second condition comprising the step S<b>324</b>, step S<b>326</b> and step S<b>329</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">The step S<b>324</b> is to switch on the second network module <b>12</b>; the step S<b>326</b> is to transmit the data of the user to the at least one electronic device <b>3</b> via the network module; the step S<b>329</b> is to set the data processing module <b>18</b> to the power saving mode. More specifically, the step S<b>329</b> is to set the data processing module <b>18</b> to the power saving mode under a pre-determined condition. The pre-determined condition may refer to no user data transmission within a pre-determined time period.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">Furthermore, the third process corresponding to the present embodiment further comprises step S<b>328</b> and step S<b>38</b>. The step S<b>328</b> is to save the user data or alert the user for update. The step S<b>38</b> is to set the data processing module <b>18</b> to the power saving mode. More specifically, the step S<b>38</b> is to set the data processing module <b>18</b> to the power saving mode instantly, wherein the said alerting refer to the means that utilized to remind the user. The said means may be online communicating software, email, SMS, visual warning, vibrating, sound effect or any other related means.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">Please refer to the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> depicts a flow chart diagram of another embodiment of the initialization process of the present invention. Since the step S<b>1</b> and the step S<b>3</b> is the same as the embodiment of the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, some of the descriptions of the steps are omitted herein for the clarity. In the present embodiment, the first condition refers to the condition that the first network module <b>11</b> is switched off and the time length that the data processing module <b>18</b> at the power saving mode reaches the second time threshold, the first process is corresponding to the first condition. Accordingly, the corresponding first process comprises step S<b>22</b>, step S<b>24</b>, step S<b>26</b> and step S<b>28</b>. The step S<b>22</b> is to determine if the portable router <b>1</b> matches with the first condition, if yes, execute the step S<b>24</b>, step S<b>26</b> and step <b>28</b>. The step S<b>24</b> is to set the data processing module <b>18</b> as an active mode; the step S<b>26</b> is to switch on the first network module <b>11</b>, and the step S<b>28</b> is to establish an internet connection to the network end <b>2</b> via the first network module <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">In summary, the portable router <b>1</b> of the present invention and the controlling method for saving power thereof are able to saving the power by adjusting the power distribution among the module in the portable router <b>1</b> without affecting the using experience of the user, so as to solve the problem of high power consumption and inconvenience of the prior art.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">With the example and explanations above, the features and spirits of the invention will be hopefully well described. Those skilled in the art will readily observe that numerous modifications and alterations of the device may be made while retaining the teaching of the invention. Accordingly, the above disclosure should be construed as limited only by the metes and bounds of the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A portable router, utilized to establish a connection between a network end and at least one electronic device, the electronic device having a wireless data transmitting function, the portable router comprising:
<claim-text>a first network module, utilized to communicate with the network end with a first format, wherein the first network module is capable of being switched on or off independently;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second network module, utilized to communicate with the electronic device with a second format, wherein the second network module is capable of being switched on or off independently;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensing module, electronically connected with the network end for generating a condition signal in accordance with a pre-determined condition;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a data processing module, utilized to execute a pre-determined function in accordance with the condition signal or a pre-determined command; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an interface module, the interface module electronically connected with the data processing module, for providing a user interface to display the condition of the portable router to a user or to obtain the pre-determined command from the user.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The portable router of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first format is Mobile Wide Area Data Network, the second format is Wireless Local Area Network.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The portable router of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a third network module, the third network module utilized to exchange data with electronic device, wherein the third network module can be switched on or off independently, the electronic devices support a Wireless Person Area Network.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The portable router of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the pre-determined function comprises a timing control function, the timing control function is capable of controlling the first network module or the second network module to switch on or off the first network module or the second network module individually or simultaneously, or setting the data processing module to a power saving mode or an active mode at an indicate time or an indicate time period.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The portable router of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the pre-determined function comprises an electronic devices summoning function, the electronic devices summoning function is capable of sending a signal to an electronic device to switch on the electronic device, determining a routing order of the electronic device or transmitting data to the electronic device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The portable router of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the pre-determined command is defined by a user.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The portable router of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the pre-determined condition is that a signal is received by the sensing module or the first network module from the network end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A controlling method of a portable router for saving power, the portable router comprising a first network module, a second network module, a sensing module and a data processing module, the portable router utilized to establish a connection between a network end and distributing a signal from the network end to the electronic device, the electronic device having a wireless data transmitting function, the controlling method comprising the following steps:
<claim-text>S<b>1</b>: executing an initialization process to obtain a first condition from a user and set the data processing module to a power saving mode, the initialization process comprising the following steps of:
<claim-text>S<b>11</b>: obtaining the first condition from the user;</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>12</b>: establishing a connection between the portable router and the electronic device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>13</b>: creating an electronic device list;</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>14</b>: counting a time length of the data processing module in an active mode; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>15</b>: determining if the time length of the data processing module in the active mode reaches a first timing threshold; if yes, set the data processing module to the power saving mode;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>2</b>: determining if the portable router matches the first condition; if yes, execute the first process to switch on or off the first network module or the second network module individually or simultaneously, or set the data processing module to the power saving mode or the active mode; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>3</b>: determining if the portable router matches the second condition; if yes, execute a second process to switch on or off the first network module or the second network module individually or simultaneously, or set the data processing module to the power saving mode or the active mode if no, execute a third process.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The controlling method of the <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the first timing threshold is an indicated time or an indicated time period.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The controlling method of the <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the first condition is that the first network module is switched off and the time length is that the data processing module at the power saving mode reaches the second time threshold, the first process is corresponding to the first condition, the first process comprises the following steps:
<claim-text>S<b>22</b>: determining if the portable router matches with the first condition; if yes, execute the step S<b>24</b>, step S<b>26</b> and step <b>28</b>;</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>24</b>: setting the data processing module to the active mode;</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>26</b>: switching on the first network module; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>28</b>: establishing an internet connection to the network end via the first network module.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The controlling method of the <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the first condition is that the first network module is switched on and a signal or a user data is received by the first network module from the network end, the first process corresponding to the first condition comprises the following steps:
<claim-text>S<b>22</b>: determining if the portable router matches with the first condition; if yes, execute the step S<b>24</b> and step <b>28</b>;</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>24</b>: setting the data processing module to the active mode; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>28</b>: establishing an internet connection to the network end via the first network module.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The controlling method of the <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the first condition is that the sensing module of the portable router accepts a signal from the network end, the first process corresponding to the first condition comprises the following steps:
<claim-text>S<b>22</b>: determining if the portable router matches with the first condition; if yes, execute the step S<b>24</b>, step S<b>26</b> and step <b>28</b>;</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>24</b>: setting the data processing module to the active mode;</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>26</b>: switching on the first network module; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>28</b>: establishing an internet connection to the network end via the first network module.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The controlling method of the <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the second condition is that a signal or a user data is detected from the network end, the second process corresponding to the second condition comprises the following steps:
<claim-text>S<b>32</b>: determining if the at least one electronic device matches the routing order; if yes, switch on or switch off the first network module, the second network module or switch the data processing module among the active mode or the power saving mode; if no, save the user data or alert the user for update.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The controlling method of the <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the step S<b>32</b> comprises the following steps:
<claim-text>S<b>322</b>: determining if the at least one electronic device matches a routing order; if yes, execute step S<b>324</b>, step S<b>326</b> and step S<b>329</b>; if not, execute step S<b>328</b> and step S<b>38</b>;</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>324</b>: switching on the second network module;</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>326</b>: transmitting the data of the user to the at least one electronic device via the network module;</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>328</b>: saving the user data or alerting the user for updating;</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>38</b>: setting the data processing module to the power saving mode; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>329</b>: setting the data processing module to the power saving mode.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The controlling method of the <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the second condition is that the electronic device matches a routing order, the second process corresponding to the second condition comprises the following steps:
<claim-text>S<b>324</b>: switching on the second network module;</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>326</b>: transmitting the data of the user to the at least one electronic device via the network module; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>329</b>: setting the data processing module to the power saving mode.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The controlling method of the <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the third process comprises the following steps:
<claim-text>S<b>36</b>: switching off the first network module and resetting the time length of the data processing module to be in the active mode respectively; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>38</b>: setting the data processing module to the power saving mode.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The controlling method of the <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the third process comprises the following steps:
<claim-text>S<b>328</b>: saving the user data or alerting the user for updating; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>S<b>38</b>: setting the data processing module to the power saving mode. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
