<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623298-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623298</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12679056</doc-number>
<date>20080919</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>20 2007 013 096 U</doc-number>
<date>20070919</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>762</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>22</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>35</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>422524</main-classification>
<further-classification>422512</further-classification>
<further-classification> 7386332</further-classification>
<further-classification> 73864</further-classification>
<further-classification> 7386487</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Syringe with exchangeable needle</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4490142</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Silvern</name>
<date>19841200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>604241</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4740205</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Seltzer et al.</name>
<date>19880400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>604192</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5195985</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hall</name>
<date>19930300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>604195</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0027232</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Walsh et al.</name>
<date>20070200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>523218</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>2004047895</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20040600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>2006096901</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20060900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>29</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>422512</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>422524</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20100312194</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20101209</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Leckebusch</last-name>
<first-name>Klaus</first-name>
<address>
<city>Masein</city>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CH</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Leckebusch</last-name>
<first-name>Klaus</first-name>
<address>
<city>Masein</city>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Rothwell, Figg, Ernst &#x26; Manbeck, P.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hamilton Bonaduz AG</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Bonaduz</city>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Warden</last-name>
<first-name>Jill</first-name>
<department>1773</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Fisher</last-name>
<first-name>Brittany</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/EP2008/007911</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20080919</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20100625</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2009/036994</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20090326</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A syringe comprises a syringe body (<b>12</b>) having an axial inner recess (<b>14</b>) extending in the direction of a longitudinal axis of the syringe body (L), a piston (<b>16</b>) being guided in an axially moveable manner in said inner recess and contributing to the delimitation of a fluid-receiving volume together with a section of a wall (<b>14</b><i>a</i>) radially delimiting the inner recess (<b>14</b>), and having a needle (<b>24</b>) that can be or is connected to a longitudinal end (<b>12</b><i>a</i>) of the syringe body (<b>12</b>), wherein the needle (<b>24</b>) has a coupling geometry (<b>28</b>) at the longitudinal end (<b>24</b><i>a</i>) thereof that is closer to the syringe body, wherein the needle (<b>24</b>) can be connected by said coupling geometry to a counter coupling geometry (<b>30</b>) of the syringe body (<b>12</b>), wherein the geometry composed of the coupling geometry (<b>28</b>) and counter coupling geometry (<b>30</b>) comprises an insertion section (<b>32</b>), which in the assembled state of the syringe (<b>10</b>) is received in a coupling recess (<b>34</b>) of the respectively other geometry, and wherein furthermore safety means (<b>46</b>) are provided, preventing a retraction movement of the insertion section (<b>32</b>) from the coupling recess (<b>34</b>) in the assembled state of the syringe (<b>10</b>).</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="71.37mm" wi="91.10mm" file="US08623298-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="226.74mm" wi="70.95mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623298-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="236.22mm" wi="111.00mm" file="US08623298-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a 35 U.S.C. 371 National Phase Entry Application from PCT/EP2008/07911, filed Sep. 19, 2008, which claims the benefit of German Patent Application No. 20 2007 013 096.1 filed on Sep. 19, 2007, the disclosures of which are incorporated herein in their entirety by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a syringe, as is used for instance for sample processing in chromatography and the like. Such a syringe comprises a syringe body, which comprises an axial internal recess extending in the direction of a longitudinal axis of the syringe body, in which recess a piston is guided in an axially mobile manner. Together with a portion of a wall radially defining the internal recess, this piston contributes to the delimitation of a fluid receiving volume. The longitudinal axis of the syringe body here basically defines the axial direction. A direction orthogonal thereto is a radial direction for the purposes of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Furthermore, such a syringe comprises a needle, which may be or is connected to a longitudinal end of the syringe body.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Syringes are known in principle from the field of medicine in which a needle comprises a coupling geometry at its longitudinal end adjacent the syringe body, by which the needle may be connected to a mating coupling geometry of the syringe body. In the case of the medical syringes known from the prior art the mating coupling geometry comprises an insertion portion, which is accommodated in a coupling recess of the coupling geometry when the syringe is in the assembled state.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The needle/syringe body couplings known from medicine are not sufficient for laboratory applications. They do not fulfil the necessary requirements for strength and above all tightness, such that the purity of a fluid to be received and discharged by the syringe is not satisfactorily ensured.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">It is therefore the object of the present invention further to develop syringes known from the prior art in such a way that the above-stated disadvantages are overcome.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">According to the present invention this object is achieved by a syringe of the above-mentioned type, for which securing means are provided which prevent a withdrawal movement of the insertion portion out of the coupling recess when the syringe is in the assembled state.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">As a result of the securing means provided, the needle can no longer be removed from the syringe body, such that the needle is reliably coupled together with the syringe body.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Securing of the needle to and detachment thereof from the syringe body and a particularly preferred sealing of the needle/syringe body coupling may be achieved in that the securing means comprise an axial adjustment component, which may be displaced by actuation in the axial direction, such that the axial adjustment component may exert axial pressure on the insertion portion introduced into the coupling recess.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The advantageous sealing of the needle/syringe body coupling may be increased still further in that the securing means comprise a clamping geometry which, when the syringe is in the assembled state, is in engagement with a mating clamping geometry associated with the needle.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The clamping geometry and the mating clamping geometry may be brought particularly simply and reliably into sealing engagement with one another when a geometry consisting of clamping geometry and mating clamping geometry comprises a first tapered portion, which tapers towards the free longitudinal end of the geometry bearing it and which, when the syringe is in the assembled state, is introduced at least in portions into a receiving recess of the in each case other geometry, and the receiving recess comprises a first widened portion, which widens towards the free longitudinal end of the geometry bearing it, the taper profile of the first tapered portion in the axial direction and the widening profile of the first widened portion in the axial direction preferably corresponding substantially in such a way that, when the syringe is in the assembled state, the tapered portion rests in linear manner at least along a circumferential line around the syringe body longitudinal axis, particularly preferably rests extensively against the widened portion along a circumferential contact surface.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Constructionally, provision may here be made for the first tapered portion to comprise a cone portion and for the receiving recess preferably to comprise a conical recess. Particularly preferably, the cone portion and the conical recess have the same cone opening angle.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">To reduce the number of components required for producing the syringe, provision may be made for the clamping geometry to be formed integrally on the axial adjustment component.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">On the other hand, assembly of the syringe components with one another may be effected particularly gently with regard to said components if the clamping geometry is formed on a clamping component provided separately from the axial adjustment component, which clamping component may be displaced axially by the axial adjustment component. In this case relative motion may be brought about purposefully at non-critical points and be reduced between syringe components at critical points, so reducing the risk of damage to components.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Particularly good sealing of the needle relative to the syringe body and the surrounding environment, with simultaneous correct positioning of the needle relative to the syringe body, may be ensured according to a first further development of the present invention in that a component displaying the clamping geometry is configured for joint movement with the needle. According to an alternative second further development of the present invention, at least correct positioning of the needle relative to the syringe body may also be ensured in that the axial adjustment component is configured for joint movement with the needle.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Configuration of a component &#x201c;for joint movement&#x201d; with the needle may be achieved either by one-piece construction of the component with the needle or by rigid connection of the component with the needle.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">For advantageous, maximally exact positioning of the axial adjustment component, provision may be made for the latter to be guided for axial movement on a guide component.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">From a structural standpoint, the guide component may comprise a sleeve, which is provided on the syringe body, in particular at the longitudinal end thereof nearer the needle.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">For particularly secure connection of the guide component to the syringe body, it is conceivable for the guide component, in particular the sleeve, to be connected to the syringe body by pressing and/or adhesive bonding.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Particularly simple, secure and at the same time precise positioning of the axial adjustment component relative to the guide component may be achieved in that the guide component, in particular the sleeve, comprises a thread, preferably an internal thread, and in that the axial adjustment component comprises a screw, which comprises a mating thread, preferably an external thread, in or capable of being brought into engagement with said thread. Positioning accuracy here depends on the selected pitch of the thread and mating thread.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Preferably, the thread of the guide component is an internal thread, such that the axial adjustment component may be screwed thereinto. This avoids the syringe being excessively large radially.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">To achieve a modular syringe construction, which is advantageous because it can be adapted in each case to the respective instance of use, the coupling geometry may be provided on a separate coupling component.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">For defined positioning of the coupling component in the axial direction and thus to ensure a coupling and sealing action as good as possible, it is feasible for the coupling component to comprise a projection, preferably a radial projection, for resting on a mating contact face of the syringe body.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The sealing action which may be achieved with the coupling component may be further increased in that said component is made from a resilient material. In this case the insertion portion, if provided on the coupling component, may comprise a cylindrical portion, for simplifying insertion into the coupling recess, optionally with an insertion bevel, the cylindrical portion of the insertion portion then being inserted into the coupling recess and coming to lie sealingly against an associated wall of the coupling recess by clamping by means of the above-stated clamping geometry.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">It is likewise feasible to configure the insertion portion with a bulging external shape, such that radial pretensioning may be achieved purely on the basis of resilient material deformation on insertion of the insertion portion into the coupling recess. However, gaps at the point at which the coupling component is coupled to the syringe body should be avoided, since materials may accumulate here which may contaminate the fluid accommodated in the fluid receiving volume therein in the case of a plurality of successive filling operations.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">It is likewise feasible to make the coupling component from a rigid material and to bring the rigid coupling component to rest sealingly against a likewise rigid mating coupling geometry on the syringe body.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Both in the case of the insertion portion and the coupling recess being made from rigid materials and in the case of at least one of the constructions being made from a resilient material, such as for instance polytetrafluoroethylene, a good sealing action of the coupling point between coupling geometry and mating coupling geometry may be achieved in that the insertion portion comprises a second tapered portion, which tapers towards the free longitudinal end of the geometry bearing it and which is inserted at least in portions into the coupling recess of the in each case other geometry when the syringe is in the assembled state, and in that the coupling recess comprises a second widened portion, which widens towards the free longitudinal end of the geometry bearing it, the taper profile of the second tapered portion in the axial direction and the widening profile of the second widened portion in the axial direction preferably corresponding substantially in such a way that, when the syringe is in the assembled state, the second tapered portion rests in linear manner at least along a circumferential line around the syringe body longitudinal axis, particularly preferably rests extensively against the second widened portion along a circumferential contact surface. In this case even small taper or widening angles may lead to the desired coupling and sealing results.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">From a manufacturing standpoint, the insertion portion particularly simply and therefore preferably comprises a cone portion and the coupling recess preferably comprises a conical recess.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The sealing action of the coupling point may be still further increased in that the insertion portion comprises an end face with radial extension component, which rests sealingly against a mating face of the syringe body when the syringe is in the assembled state. However, it is also recommendable, to avoid undesirable double fits, for at least one of the geometries participating in coupling to be made from a resilient material.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Particularly when the syringe described here is used in a laboratory, in particular in chromatography, it is very important to avoid contamination of the fluid drawn up in the syringe. To this end provision may be made for at least some of the surfaces, preferably all the surfaces of the syringe, which during use thereof come into contact with a fluid to be received and/or discharged by the syringe, to be provided with a coating. This coating may be a quartz or glass coating, these providing a particularly smooth surface which is inert relative to a large number of fluids and at the same time transparent. The coating may be applied by &#x201c;nano technology&#x201d; on the inside and/or outside of the needle. The coating may be applied in a manner known per se by a sol-gel process to the walls or wall portions in question of the syringe.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The present invention is described in greater detail below with reference to the attached drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a partially sectional view of a first embodiment of a syringe according to the invention,</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a longitudinally sectional detail view of the needle/syringe body coupling of the first embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>,</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a second embodiment of a needle/syringe body coupling and</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a third embodiment of a needle/syringe body coupling.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a first embodiment of a syringe according to the invention, designated overall as <b>10</b>. The syringe <b>10</b> comprises a syringe body <b>12</b> with an internal recess <b>14</b> extending in the direction of the longitudinal axis L of a syringe body, in which recess a piston <b>16</b> is accommodated so as to be movable in the direction of the longitudinal axis L of the syringe body, i.e. in an axial direction.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The piston <b>16</b> is movable by a piston rod <b>18</b> connected rigidly to the piston <b>16</b>, which piston rod <b>18</b> may be pull- and push-actuated by means of an actuating end member <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">A piston face <b>16</b><i>a </i>directed towards the longitudinal end <b>12</b><i>a </i>of the syringe body <b>12</b> nearer to the needle contributes, together with a portion <b>14</b><i>a </i>of a circumferential wall defining the internal recess <b>14</b> in the radial direction, to delimitation of a fluid receiving volume <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The syringe <b>10</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> further comprises a needle <b>24</b>, with a needle cannula <b>26</b>. In the assembled state, the needle <b>24</b> comprises a coupling geometry <b>28</b> at its longitudinal end <b>24</b><i>a </i>nearer to the syringe body which is in engagement with a mating coupling geometry <b>30</b> at the longitudinal end <b>12</b><i>a </i>of the syringe body <b>12</b> nearer to the needle to couple the needle <b>24</b> to the syringe body <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The detailed configuration of the coupling of the needle <b>24</b> to the syringe body <b>12</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows the detail encircled in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and labelled &#x201c;II&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In the first exemplary embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> the coupling geometry <b>28</b> comprises a substantially cylindrical insertion portion <b>32</b>, which has been introduced into a coupling recess <b>34</b> in the mating coupling geometry <b>30</b>. To simplify insertion of the insertion portion <b>32</b> into the coupling recess <b>34</b>, the insertion portion <b>32</b> is provided at its longitudinal end introduced into the coupling recess <b>34</b> with an insertion bevel or a circumferential insertion chamfer.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The insertion portion <b>32</b> is an integral part of a coupling component <b>36</b> made from resilient plastics, in the present example polytetrafluoroethylene.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">This component <b>36</b> comprises a mating clamping geometry <b>38</b> in the form of a clamping cone at its opposite longitudinal end from the insertion portion <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">A radial projection <b>40</b> is formed axially on the coupling component <b>36</b>, encircling the latter in the circumferential direction, between the mating clamping geometry <b>38</b> and the insertion portion <b>32</b>, said radial projection resting against a mating contact face <b>42</b> of the syringe body <b>12</b> when the syringe <b>10</b> is in the assembled state. If the radial projection <b>40</b> comes to rest against the mating contact face <b>42</b>, correct seating of the coupling component <b>36</b> is ensured.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The needle cannula <b>26</b> is inserted into a central through-recess <b>44</b> of the coupling component <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In principle, the needle cannula <b>26</b> may be connected to the coupling component <b>36</b> by adhesive bonding or the like. Preferably, to prevent undesired contamination of a fluid accommodated in the fluid receiving chamber <b>22</b> with constituents of the adhesive, the needle cannula <b>26</b> is retained merely by non-positive or frictional engagement in the coupling component <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">A sleeve-type guide component <b>46</b> is connected to the syringe body <b>12</b> by being pressed and adhesively bonded onto a radial shoulder at the longitudinal end <b>12</b><i>a </i>of the syringe body <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The guide component <b>46</b> comprises an internal thread <b>48</b>, into which an axial adjustment component in the form of a clamping screw <b>50</b> with an external thread <b>52</b> is screwed in axially movable manner along the longitudinal axis L of the syringe body.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The needle cannula <b>26</b> is fed through a central recess <b>54</b>, the diameter of the central recess <b>54</b> being greater than the external diameter of the needle cannula <b>26</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In a cup-shaped recess <b>56</b> in the clamping screw <b>50</b> there is accommodated a clamping component <b>58</b>, which is adhesively bonded, welded or otherwise connected to the needle cannula <b>26</b> for joint movement.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The clamping component <b>58</b> comprises a clamping geometry in the form of a conical receiving recess <b>60</b>, into which the conical mating clamping geometry <b>38</b> of the coupling component <b>36</b> protrudes in the axial direction.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">By turning the clamping screw <b>50</b> by means of a into the tool engagement recesses <b>62</b> at the end face of the clamping screw <b>50</b> remote from the syringe body towards the syringe body <b>12</b>, the resilient coupling component <b>36</b> may be purposefully resiliently deformed, such that it rests sealingly without a gap against the coupling component <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In the first exemplary embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> the coupling recess <b>34</b> develops continuously into the internal recess <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows an alternative second exemplary embodiment. Components which are the same as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> are provided with the same reference numerals but increased by the number <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is described hereinafter only to the extent that it differs from the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, to the description of which express reference is made.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The second embodiment, which is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, is suitable for syringes with an extremely small syringe volume, i.e. with an internal recess <b>114</b> with a very small diameter.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">It is apparent that the coupling recess <b>134</b> has a larger diameter than the internal recess <b>114</b> in the syringe body <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The coupling recess <b>134</b> therefore develops into the internal recess <b>114</b>, forming a radial step. An end face <b>164</b> of the insertion portion <b>132</b> may thus come to rest sealingly against a mating face <b>166</b> of the syringe body <b>112</b>, if sufficient deformation pressure is exerted on the coupling component <b>136</b> by means of the clamping screw <b>150</b> and the clamping component <b>158</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a third embodiment of a syringe according to the invention with a needle/syringe body coupling.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Components which are the same as in the embodiments of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 3</figref> are provided in the third embodiment according to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> with the same reference numerals, but increased by the number <b>200</b> or <b>100</b> respectively. The third embodiment is only described insofar as it differs from the first two embodiments, to the description of which express reference is otherwise made.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">In the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> the insertion portion <b>232</b> is provided on the mating coupling geometry <b>230</b> of the syringe body <b>212</b>, while the coupling recess <b>234</b> is formed in the coupling geometry <b>228</b> of the needle <b>224</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Unlike in the previous embodiments, the radial projection <b>240</b> of the coupling component <b>236</b> extends radially inwards at the longitudinal end of the coupling component <b>236</b> remote from the syringe body.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Also in contrast to the preceding embodiments, the clamping component <b>258</b> is supported axially against the sleeve-type guide component <b>264</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The clamping screw <b>250</b> is connected for joint rotation with the needle cannula <b>226</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The mating clamping geometry <b>238</b> of the coupling component <b>236</b> surrounds the insertion portion <b>234</b> of the syringe body <b>212</b> radially on the outside in the circumferential direction and rests against the conical receiving recess <b>260</b> of the clamping component <b>258</b>.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A syringe comprising:
<claim-text>a syringe body having a longitudinal axis, wherein the syringe body comprises
<claim-text>an axial internal recess extending in the direction of the longitudinal axis of the syringe body, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a piston, positioned in the axial internal recess, which is guided in an axially mobile manner, wherein the piston, together with a portion of a wall radially defining the axial internal recess, contributes to the delimitation of a fluid receiving volume,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a syringe body mating coupling geometry located at a longitudinal end of the syringe body,</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a needle having a longitudinal end,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a needle coupling geometry, located at the longitudinal end of the needle towards the syringe body, which mates the needle to the syringe body mating coupling geometry, and wherein the needle coupling geometry comprises
<claim-text>an insertion portion, wherein, when the syringe is in an assembled state, the insertion portion is accommodated in a coupling recess, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a securing means which prevents a withdrawal movement of the insertion portion out of the coupling recess when the syringe is in the assembled state, wherein the securing means prevents removal of the needle from the syringe body when the syringe is in the assembled state, and wherein the securing means comprises a clamping geometry such that when the syringe is in the assembled state, the clamping geometry is in engagement with a mating clamping geometry which is configured to contact the needle.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the securing means comprises an axial adjustment component, which is displaced by actuation in the axial direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the mating clamping geometry comprises a first tapered portion, which tapers away from the syringe body and which, when the syringe is in the assembled state, is introduced, at least in portions, into a receiving recess of the clamping geometry, wherein the receiving recess comprises a first widened portion, which widens towards the syringe body, and wherein the taper profile of the first tapered portion in the axial direction and the widening profile of the first widened portion of the receiving recess in the axial direction substantially correspond such that, when the syringe is in the assembled state, the first tapered portion rests in a linear manner at least along a circumferential line around the syringe body longitudinal axis against the first widened portion of the receiving recess along a circumferential contact surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the first tapered portion comprises a cone portion and the receiving recess comprises a conical recess.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the clamping geometry is formed integrally on the axial adjustment component.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the clamping geometry is formed on a clamping component provided separately from the axial adjustment component, wherein the clamping component is displaceable axially by the axial adjustment component.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein a clamping component comprising the clamping geometry is configured for joint movement with the needle.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the axial adjustment component is configured for joint movement with the needle.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the axial adjustment component is configured to be guided on a guide component for axial movement.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the guide component comprises a sleeve, which is provided on the longitudinal end of the syringe body towards the needle.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the guide component is connected to the syringe body by pressing and/or adhesive bonding.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the guide component comprises a thread, and wherein the axial adjustment component comprises a screw, and wherein the screw comprises a mating thread, capable of being brought into engagement with the thread of the guide component.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the needle coupling geometry is a separate coupling component.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the coupling component comprises a projection, for resting against a mating contact face of the syringe body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the coupling component is made from a resilient material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the insertion portion comprises a tapered portion, which tapers towards the syringe body and which is inserted, at least in portions, into the coupling recess when the syringe is in the assembled state, and wherein the coupling recess comprises a widened portion, which widens away from the syringe body, and wherein the taper profile of the tapered portion in the axial direction and the widening profile of the widened portion of the coupling recess in the axial direction substantially correspond such that, when the syringe is in the assembled state, the tapered portion rests in a linear manner at least along a circumferential line around the syringe body longitudinal axis against the widened portion of the coupling recess along a circumferential contact surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the insertion portion comprises a cone portion and the coupling recess comprises a conical recess.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the insertion portion comprises an end face with a radial extension component, which rests sealingly against a mating face of the syringe body when the syringe is in the assembled state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of the surfaces of the syringe, which during use thereof come into contact with a fluid to be received and/or discharged by the syringe, are provided with a coating.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the coating is a quartz or glass coating.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein a surface of the needle, is provided with a coating applied by a nano technology process.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the guide component comprises an internal thread.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the screw comprises an external mating thread.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the coupling component comprises a radial projection, for resting against a mating contact face of the syringe body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text>25. A syringe comprising:
<claim-text>a syringe body having a longitudinal axis, wherein the syringe body comprises
<claim-text>an axial internal recess extending in the direction of the longitudinal axis of the syringe body, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a piston, positioned in the axial internal recess, which is guided in an axially mobile manner, wherein the piston, together with a portion of a wall radially defining the axial internal recess, contributes to the delimitation of a fluid receiving volume,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a syringe body mating coupling geometry located at a longitudinal end of the syringe body,</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a needle having a longitudinal end,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a needle coupling geometry, located at the longitudinal end of the needle towards the syringe body, which mates the needle to the syringe body mating coupling geometry, and wherein the needle coupling geometry comprises
<claim-text>an insertion portion, wherein, when the syringe is in an assembled state, the insertion portion is accommodated in a coupling recess, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a securing means which prevents a withdrawal movement of the insertion portion out of the coupling recess when the syringe is in the assembled state, wherein the securing means prevents removal of the needle from the syringe body when the syringe is in the assembled state, and wherein the securing means comprises an axial adjustment component, which is displaced by actuation in the axial direction,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the axial adjustment component is configured to be guided on a guide component for axial movement, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the guide component comprises a sleeve, which is provided on the longitudinal end of the syringe body towards the needle.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text>26. A syringe comprising:
<claim-text>a syringe body having a longitudinal axis, wherein the syringe body comprises
<claim-text>an axial internal recess extending in the direction of the longitudinal axis of the syringe body, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a piston, positioned in the axial internal recess, which is guided in an axially mobile manner, wherein the piston, together with a portion of a wall radially defining the axial internal recess, contributes to the delimitation of a fluid receiving volume,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a syringe body mating coupling geometry located at a longitudinal end of the syringe body,</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a needle having a longitudinal end,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a needle coupling geometry, located at the longitudinal end of the needle towards the syringe body, which mates the needle to the syringe body mating coupling geometry, and wherein the needle coupling geometry comprises
<claim-text>an insertion portion, wherein, when the syringe is in an assembled state, the insertion portion is accommodated in a coupling recess, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a securing means which prevents a withdrawal movement of the insertion portion out of the coupling recess when the syringe is in the assembled state, wherein the securing means prevents removal of the needle from the syringe body when the syringe is in the assembled state, and wherein the securing means comprises an axial adjustment component, which is displaced by actuation in the axial direction,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the axial adjustment component is configured to be guided on a guide component for axial movement, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the guide component is connected to the syringe body by pressing and/or adhesive bonding.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text>27. A syringe comprising:
<claim-text>a syringe body having a longitudinal axis, wherein the syringe body comprises
<claim-text>an axial internal recess extending in the direction of the longitudinal axis of the syringe body, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a piston, positioned in the axial internal recess, which is guided in an axially mobile manner, wherein the piston, together with a portion of a wall radially defining the axial internal recess, contributes to the delimitation of a fluid receiving volume,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a syringe body mating coupling geometry located at a longitudinal end of the syringe body,</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a needle having a longitudinal end,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a needle coupling geometry, located at the longitudinal end of the needle towards the syringe body, which mates the needle to the syringe body mating coupling geometry, and wherein the needle coupling geometry comprises
<claim-text>an insertion portion, wherein, when the syringe is in an assembled state, the insertion portion is accommodated in a coupling recess, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a securing means which prevents a withdrawal movement of the insertion portion out of the coupling recess when the syringe is in the assembled state, wherein the securing means prevents removal of the needle from the syringe body when the syringe is in the assembled state, and wherein the securing means comprises an axial adjustment component, which is displaced by actuation in the axial direction,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the axial adjustment component is configured to be guided on a guide component for axial movement, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the guide component comprises a thread, and wherein the axial adjustment component comprises a screw, and wherein the screw comprises a mating thread, capable of being brought into engagement with the thread of the guide component.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text>28. A syringe comprising:
<claim-text>a syringe body having a longitudinal axis, wherein the syringe body comprises
<claim-text>an axial internal recess extending in the direction of the longitudinal axis of the syringe body, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a piston, positioned in the axial internal recess, which is guided in an axially mobile manner, wherein the piston, together with a portion of a wall radially defining the axial internal recess, contributes to the delimitation of a fluid receiving volume,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a syringe body mating coupling geometry located at a longitudinal end of the syringe body,</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a needle having a longitudinal end,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a needle coupling geometry, located at the longitudinal end of the needle towards the syringe body, which mates the needle to the syringe body mating coupling geometry, and wherein the needle coupling geometry comprises
<claim-text>an insertion portion, wherein, when the syringe is in an assembled state, the insertion portion is accommodated in a coupling recess, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a securing means which prevents a withdrawal movement of the insertion portion out of the coupling recess when the syringe is in the assembled state, wherein the securing means prevents removal of the needle from the syringe body when the syringe is in the assembled state,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the insertion portion comprises a tapered portion, which tapers towards the syringe body and which is inserted, at least in portions, into the coupling recess when the syringe is in the assembled state, and wherein the coupling recess comprises a widened portion, which widens away from the syringe body, and wherein the taper profile of the tapered portion in the axial direction and the widening profile of the widened portion of the coupling recess in the axial direction substantially correspond such that, when the syringe is in the assembled state, the tapered portion rests in a linear manner at least along a circumferential line around the syringe body longitudinal axis against the widened portion of the coupling recess along a circumferential contact surface.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029" num="00029">
<claim-text>29. A syringe according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00028">claim 28</claim-ref>, wherein the insertion portion comprises a cone portion and the coupling recess comprises a conical recess. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
