<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624111-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624111</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13165299</doc-number>
<date>20110621</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>350</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>174 50</main-classification>
<further-classification>174524</further-classification>
<further-classification>4555758</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Multilayer portable device case and method therefor</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8268426</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Antonini</name>
<date>20120900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>428 401</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8383216</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Hynecek</name>
<date>20130200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>428 357</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8509864</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Diebel</name>
<date>20130800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4555758</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8509865</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>LaColla et al.</name>
<date>20130800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4555758</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8552292</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Qin et al.</name>
<date>20131000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>174 50</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2012/0322517</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Valdez</name>
<date>20121200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4555758</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2013/0273944</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Wilson et al.</name>
<date>20131000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>455457</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>19</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>174 50</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>174524</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>174560</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4555758</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120327565</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121227</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tages</last-name>
<first-name>Fernando</first-name>
<address>
<city>Coral Springs</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Acero</last-name>
<first-name>Daniel</first-name>
<address>
<city>Miramar</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tages</last-name>
<first-name>Fernando</first-name>
<address>
<city>Coral Springs</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Acero</last-name>
<first-name>Daniel</first-name>
<address>
<city>Miramar</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Christopher &#x26; Weisberg, P.A.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>A.G. Findings &#x26; Mfg. Co.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Fort Lauderdale</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Ngo</last-name>
<first-name>Hung</first-name>
<department>2846</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A mobile device case including a housing sized to receive a mobile device; at least a portion of the housing including a first layer, a second layer, and a third layer of material, the second layer of material being disposed between the first and third layers of material and having a material with a higher durometer than the first and third layers of material.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="186.94mm" wi="192.11mm" file="US08624111-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="211.16mm" wi="190.75mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624111-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="207.77mm" wi="141.73mm" file="US08624111-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="224.11mm" wi="193.46mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624111-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="247.31mm" wi="187.37mm" file="US08624111-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="194.14mm" wi="194.14mm" file="US08624111-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="233.68mm" wi="195.50mm" file="US08624111-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="228.85mm" wi="197.53mm" file="US08624111-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">n/a</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">STATEMENT REGARDING FEDERALLY SPONSORED RESEARCH OR DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">n/a</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to mobile device cases, and in particular, to a multi-layer protective case for mobile devices.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">As mobile phones and other mobile electronic devices become more technologically advanced and include more features, the cost to purchase these mobile devices increases, as does the cost to replace them should they break. To prophylactically protect such devices from damage or breakage, protective cases have been devised to reduce the risk that a mobile device breaks should it be dropped or otherwise exposed to an impact force.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In particular, two types of materials have generally been employed to reduce the impact force on a mobile device, namely, elastic and resilient materials that absorb impact forces (&#x201c;soft cases&#x201d;), and fracture-resistant plastics (&#x201c;hard cases&#x201d;). Mobile device cases typically include one or the other of these materials, or include a softer resilient case surrounding a harder plastic case. The resultant device cases often suffer from protection limitations and a low quality user experience. For example, cases exclusively composed of high durometer plastics, or similarly hard materials, often include jagged or sharp corners providing an uncomfortable feeling in the user's hand. Further, high durometer plastic cases, while lending overall durability to the case, often rupture at connection points on two-piece clam shelled cases owing to a lack of resiliency, potentially exposing the mobile device to an impact force.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Conversely, soft resilient cases such as those made from rubber or other elastomeric materials, while providing impact protection, are often large and unwieldy, which mitigates the benefits of having a slim profile mobile device. Further, rubber and other elastomeric materials have high coefficients of friction with a user's hand, and with many surfaces on which the mobile device would be placed, for example, clothing, a hand-bag, or a desk, reducing the mobility of the device as elastomeric materials tend to stick to a surface. As a result, mobile device cases composed of rubber or elastomers, while providing impact protection, may not be aesthetically desirable to consumers, and users often remove the elastomeric case leaving the mobile device either unprotected or vulnerable in plastic cases with minimal impact resistance.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">It is therefore desirable to have a mobile device case that incorporates or integrates both impact resistant features of a soft case and the durability features of a hard case into a single easy to use and durable case. It is also desirable to provide for the ability of the user to attach and remove a softer impact absorbing outer case to a harder inner case such that a mobile device is protected and the case remains durable and resilient whether or not the outer case is attached.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In accordance with one aspect, the present invention provides a mobile device case including a housing. At least a portion of the housing includes a first layer, a second layer, and a third layer of material. The second layer of material is molded between the first and third layers of material and has a higher durometer than the first and third layers of material.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In another aspect, the present invention provides a mobile device case having a housing. The housing includes a first portion matable with a second portion. The first portion and the second portion at least partially defines an enclosed volume therein when coupled together. At least one of the first portion and the second portion includes a first layer, a second layer, and a third layer of material. The second layer of material is disposed between the first and third layers of material and has a material with a higher durometer than the first and third layers of material. A fourth layer of material surrounding at least portion of the housing has a lower durometer than the first and third layer of material.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In accordance yet another aspect, the present invention provides a method of manufacturing a mobile device case. A first layer, a second layer and a third layer of material are molded to form a mobile device case housing. The first and third layers are molded onto the second layer of material. The second layer of material is disposed between the first and third layers of material and has a higher durometer than the first and third layers of material.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">A more complete understanding of the present invention, and the attendant advantages and features thereof, will be more readily understood by reference to the following detailed description when considered in conjunction with the accompanying drawings wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is front view of the first portion and the second portion of a mobile device case in accordance with the principles of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a back view of the first portion shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is back view of the first portion shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> without the first and third layers of material;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cross-sectional view taken through section A-A in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a disassembled view of the back portions of the first portion and the second portion shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is an assembled view of the first portion and second portion shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a back perspective view of a fourth layer of material partially enclosing the device case shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is back perspective of the device case shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> disposed within a holster.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Now referring to the drawings in which like reference designators refer to like elements, there is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> a mobile device case constructed in accordance with the principles of the present invention and designated generally as &#x201c;<b>10</b>.&#x201d; The case <b>10</b> may include a housing <b>12</b> sized to receive and retain a mobile device. The housing <b>12</b> may include a first portion <b>14</b> sized to receive the mobile device. For example, the dimensions of the first portion <b>14</b> may be prefabricated to contour a specific mobile device, for example an IPHONE, iPAD or other mobile phone or tablet computer, and thus may vary depending on the size of the mobile device.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The first portion <b>14</b> may further include a side wall <b>16</b> defining a first perimeter <b>18</b>. The side wall <b>16</b> surrounds the first portion <b>14</b> and may define a height substantially commensurate with a height of the mobile device housed within the first portion <b>14</b>, or any height. The first portion <b>14</b> may further define curved or substantially right-angled corners <b>20</b> depending on the corresponding corners of the mobile device to be retained within the first portion <b>14</b>. The corners <b>20</b> may further define a recess <b>22</b> spaced a distance from the side wall <b>16</b>, such that a space is defined between the corners <b>20</b> and the mobile device disposed within the first portion <b>14</b>. The recess <b>22</b> allows the side wall <b>16</b> to flex inward the event of impact considerably reducing the impact force transferred to the mobile device.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The first portion <b>14</b> of the housing <b>12</b> may include and be partially composed of a first layer of material <b>24</b>. The first layer of material <b>24</b> may be composed of a substantially resilient material, for example, thermoplastic polyurethane (TPU) or a material with a similar durometer. In an exemplary configuration, 80% of the first layer of material <b>24</b> has a Shore A durometer of substantially 60A and 20% of the first layer of material <b>24</b> has a Shore A durometer of substantially 75A. It is further contemplated that a material with a durometer lower than 60A may be used as the first layer of material <b>24</b>. The first layer of material <b>24</b> may define a substantially closed loop about an inner periphery of a first major side <b>26</b> of the first portion <b>14</b> and/or may be disposed on a portion or all of the first side <b>26</b>. The first layer of material <b>24</b> may operate to cushion the mobile device when disposed within the first portion <b>14</b>. A pattern may be defined by the first layer of material <b>24</b> on the first side <b>26</b>, for example, a stippled pattern or other patterns that reduce the amount of material used and/or the coefficient of friction of the first layer of material <b>24</b> with other surfaces. For example, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a plurality of slits is defined by the first layer of material <b>24</b> at substantially the centerline of the substantially closed loop. The slits may operate to form a support structure in the second material layer <b>24</b> such that all three layers of material may be co-molded together, i.e., without having to remove the first portion <b>14</b> from the mold prior to depositing the first and third layers of material <b>24</b> and <b>28</b>, respectively, onto the second layer of material <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The first layer of material <b>24</b> may be co-molded with or otherwise disposed on top of the second layer of material <b>28</b>, which forms the frame of the housing <b>12</b> including the side wall <b>16</b>. In particular, the second layer of material <b>28</b> may be composed of a substantially rigid plastic, for example, polycarbonate (PC), polycarboxylic acid (PCA), or other material with a similar durometer. The second layer of material <b>28</b> may have a higher durometer than that of the first layer of material <b>24</b>, which may lend structural support to the housing <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Disposed or otherwise molded onto the surface of the second layer of material <b>28</b> may be a third layer of material <b>30</b>. The third layer of material <b>30</b> may have the same, or substantially the same, durometer as the first layer of material <b>24</b>. For example, the third layer of material <b>30</b> may also be composed of TPU or a material with as similar hardness and durometer. The side wall <b>16</b> of the first portion <b>14</b> may include alternating segments of the second layer of material <b>28</b> and third layer of material <b>30</b> around the outer surface of the side wall <b>16</b>. For example, the second layer of material <b>28</b> and the third layer of material <b>30</b> are disposed adjacent to each other along at least a portion of the side wall <b>16</b>. In particular, the third layer of material <b>30</b> may protrude a distance away from the side wall <b>16</b> and be adjacent a flat, or substantially flat, second layer of material <b>28</b>. For example, the side wall <b>16</b> includes a plurality of first segments <b>32</b> of the third layer of material <b>30</b>, on both sides of the side wall <b>16</b> and substantially along the entire outer perimeter <b>18</b> of the first portion <b>14</b>. The protruding first segments <b>32</b> of the third layer of material <b>30</b> provide impact protection should the housing <b>12</b> be exposed to an impact force. The protruding first segments <b>32</b> may span the height of the side wall <b>16</b> and may be substantially rectangular in shape, or any shape or size sufficient to perform the functions described herein. The corners <b>20</b> may also include the third layer of material <b>30</b> disposed on its surface. For example, each of the four corners <b>20</b> may include a first segment <b>32</b> of the third layer of material <b>30</b> molded to the outer surface of the corners <b>20</b> which may protrude a larger or varying distance away from the side wall <b>16</b>. These raised first segments <b>32</b> may operate to absorb an impact force should the housing <b>12</b> land on one of the corners <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Continuing to refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the housing <b>12</b> may further include a second portion <b>34</b> removeably couplable to the first portion <b>14</b>. The second portion <b>34</b> may be at least partially composed of the same, or substantially the same material as that of the second layer of material <b>28</b>, for example, PC. One or more layers of TPU, or material with a similar durometer or composition as the first layer of material <b>24</b>, may be co-molded with the second layer of material <b>28</b>. For example, the layer of PC material may be disposed between a layer of TPU above and a layer of TPU below, similar to the layering of materials in the first portion <b>14</b>. In particular, the layer of TPU molded on top of the layer of PCA may define second segments <b>36</b> composed of TPU or similar durometer material that correspond to first segments <b>32</b> of the first portion <b>14</b>. For example, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the second segments <b>36</b> are substantially positioned and aligned with the first segments <b>32</b> when the first portion <b>14</b> is mated with the second portion <b>34</b> and extend around the periphery of the second portion <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the first portion <b>14</b> includes a second major side <b>38</b> opposite the first side <b>26</b> having the third layer of material <b>30</b> deposited on a substantial portion of the second side <b>38</b>. For example, the third layer of material <b>30</b> may be deposited on substantially the entire second side <b>38</b> to provide resiliency to the housing <b>12</b> should an impact occur. A pattern of alternating portions of the second layer of material <b>28</b> and the third layer of material <b>30</b> may be disposed on the second side <b>38</b> and/or the side wall <b>16</b>. For example, the second layer of material <b>28</b> may define a perimeter about the third layer of material <b>30</b> on the second side <b>38</b> such that the third layer of material <b>30</b> protrudes a distance from the second side <b>38</b>. Further, the third layer of material <b>30</b> may define a textured surface, for example, a stippling pattern, on the second side <b>38</b> which may reduce the coefficient of friction with the third layer of material <b>30</b> and the user's hand or other surfaces. The stippling pattern may be formed by the creation of plurality of indentations <b>38</b> on the third layer of material <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the second layer of material <b>28</b> may further define a plurality of openings <b>40</b> extending from the first side <b>26</b> through a second side <b>38</b> of the first portion <b>14</b>. The openings <b>40</b> may be prefabricated such that the first layer of material <b>24</b> may be injected through the openings <b>40</b> in a fluid state and deposited at desired positions on the first portion <b>14</b> where it hardens. For example, the openings <b>40</b> may be fabricated such that the first layer of material <b>24</b> may be deposited on the surface of the second layer of material <b>28</b> in a particular pattern, for example, the substantially closed loop pattern discussed above, or any desired pattern. The second layer of material <b>28</b> may further define the dimensions of the side wall <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Although not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the second portion <b>34</b> may also define a plurality of openings <b>40</b> such that the first, second, and third layers of material can be co-molded together on the second portion <b>34</b> in accordance with the configurations discussed above with respect to the first portion <b>14</b>. For example, the second portion <b>34</b> may define a plurality of openings <b>40</b> along its periphery through which TPU may be injected to form the three layers of material configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref>, in a configuration, TPU may be injected in liquid form through the openings <b>40</b> to form both the first layer of material <b>24</b> and the third layer of material <b>30</b> such that the second layer of material <b>28</b> is sandwiched or otherwise disposed between the first layer of material <b>24</b> and the third layer of material <b>30</b> in portions of the first portion <b>14</b> when the material hardens. In particular, the first layer of material <b>24</b> and the third layer of material <b>30</b> may be contiguously connected to each other through the openings <b>40</b> such that they are co-molded together. The resulting properties of the first portion <b>14</b> therefore may include both the durable features of the second layer of material <b>28</b> and the impact absorbing resilient features of the first layer of material <b>24</b> and the third layer of material <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the second portion <b>34</b> may further define an opening and include a substantially transparent or entirely transparent flexible membrane <b>42</b> sized to cover the opening. In operation, the flexible membrane <b>42</b> covers a touch-screen of a mobile device when the mobile device is disposed within the housing <b>12</b>. The flexible membrane <b>42</b> may operate to prevent the touch-screen from being scratched while maintaining the operation of the touch-screen through the flexible membrane <b>42</b>. The flexible membrane <b>42</b> may also operate to prevent liquids or other debris from entering the housing <b>12</b> while maintaining the operation of the touch-screen through the flexible membrane <b>42</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The second portion <b>34</b> may further define portions composed solely of TPU, for example, portions covering actuable buttons, and the location of such portions may vary depending on the device to be enclosed by the housing <b>12</b>. The first portion <b>14</b> may further define a plurality of apertures <b>44</b> defined along the side wall <b>16</b> and/or the second side <b>32</b> sized to receive and/or provide access to one or more controls of the mobile device. For example, the first portion <b>14</b> may define an aperture <b>44</b> sized to provide access to one or more plug ports in the mobile device, a camera and flash, volume controls, headphones, and the like. Further, the third layer of material <b>30</b> may disposed over one or more of the apertures <b>44</b> along the side wall <b>16</b>, first side <b>26</b>, and/or second side <b>38</b>. The third layer of material <b>30</b> may be fabricated to contour and cover one or more of the apertures <b>44</b> that covers one or more of the volume controls or on/off switches of the mobile device. This contoured third layer of material <b>30</b> may provide a resiliently pressable surface to allow operation of the volume controls on the mobile device while providing a flexible layer of protection.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The second portion <b>34</b> may further define a plurality of grooves <b>46</b> along a second perimeter <b>48</b> defined by the second portion <b>34</b>. The second perimeter <b>48</b> may define a lip <b>50</b> extending substantially orthogonally from the second perimeter <b>48</b> which may define the grooves <b>46</b>. The grooves <b>46</b> may be removeably matable with corresponding tabs <b>52</b> protruding from the inner portion of the side wall <b>16</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>), such that when the second portion <b>34</b> mates with the first portion <b>14</b>, a substantially enclosed volume is defined therein substantially commensurate with the size of the mobile device to be retained within the volume. The second portion <b>34</b> may define a height such that the height of the second portion <b>34</b> plus the height of the first portion <b>14</b> is substantially the same as the height of the mobile device.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Optionally, a removably insertable camera module <b>54</b> may be included sized to fit within the aperture <b>44</b> and provide access to a mobile device camera and flash. The camera module <b>54</b> may be at least partially composed of the same or similar durometer material as the third layer of material <b>30</b> and may include a transparent membrane to protect the camera from scratching or other unwanted debris. The camera module <b>54</b> may further define a shape and size such that when the camera is in operation, the camera flash does not interfere with the image capture process. For example, a septum may be defined by the camera module disposed between the aperture <b>38</b> for the camera and the aperture <b>44</b> for the flash. The septum may operate to minimize interference from the flash on the lens of the camera during image capture.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref>, surrounding the housing <b>12</b> may be a fourth layer of material <b>56</b> sized to surround and contour a portion the housing <b>12</b>. For example, the fourth layer of material <b>56</b> may surround the second side <b>32</b> and side wall <b>16</b> of the second portion as well as the layer of TPU, or other similar hardness material, disposed around the second perimeter <b>48</b> of the second portion <b>34</b>. The fourth layer of material <b>56</b> may include an opening defined such that the touch-screen of the mobile device is accessible and operable when the fourth layer of material <b>56</b> is attached to the housing. The fourth layer of material <b>56</b> may be an elastomer, for example, silicone or rubber, and may have a durometer less than the durometer of the first layer of material <b>24</b> and the third layer of material <b>30</b>, for example approximately 60A on the Shore A hardness scale.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The fourth layer of material <b>56</b> may be removeably attached around the housing <b>12</b> such that the housing <b>12</b> may provide protection to the mobile device disposed within without the fourth layer of material <b>56</b>. For example, the fourth layer of material <b>56</b> may be a silicon cover sized to contour and receive the first segments <b>32</b> and second segments <b>36</b> when the second portion <b>34</b> is mated with the first portion <b>14</b>. In particular, the fourth layer of material <b>56</b> may define recessed portions within its interior corresponding in size to the protruded distance of the first segments <b>32</b> and the second segments <b>36</b> such that fourth layer of material <b>56</b> contours and fits to the housing <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The fourth layer of material <b>56</b> may further define apertures <b>60</b> similar in size and position of apertures <b>44</b> on the housing <b>12</b>. In particular, when the fourth layer of material <b>56</b> is disposed on the housing <b>12</b>, the apertures <b>44</b> and <b>60</b> may be substantially aligned to provide access to the various controls and features of the mobile device. Flaps <b>62</b> may be included on the fourth layer of material <b>56</b>, the flaps <b>62</b> being sized to removeably insertable within one or more apertures <b>44</b> and within one or more apertures defined by the mobile device. For example, one flap <b>62</b> may be sized fit within a plug port on the mobile device. The flaps <b>62</b> may be movable, flexible, and substantially waterproof, such that fluids are prevented from entering the openings in the mobile device. It is further contemplated that the flaps <b>62</b> may be composed of TPU or material with similar hardness, and may be movably coupled to the housing <b>12</b> directly, for example, on the first portion <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the housing <b>12</b>, whether alone or with the fourth layer of material <b>56</b> attached around it may be removeably insertable within a holster <b>64</b>. The holster <b>64</b> may include a latch <b>66</b> sized to engage and couple to a latch receiving element <b>68</b> (Seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>) defined by the first portion <b>14</b>. The holster <b>64</b> may further be sized to accommodate a mobile device having all four layers of material discussed above disposed around it or the housing <b>12</b> alone. This is so because the latch <b>66</b> may engage the latch receiving element <b>68</b> whether or not the fourth layer of material <b>56</b> is disposed around the housing <b>12</b>. The holster may further include a fixed rotating clip (not shown) such as disclosed and described in U.S. application Ser. No. 12/701,029 entitled FIXED ROTATING CLIP AND METHOD THEREOF, the entirety of which is incorporated herein by reference, which removeably affixes the holster <b>64</b> a user belt or hand bag.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">It will be appreciated by persons skilled in the art that the present invention is not limited to what has been particularly shown and described herein above. In addition, unless mention was made above to the contrary, it should be noted that all of the accompanying drawings are not to scale. A variety of modifications and variations are possible in light of the above teachings without departing from the scope and spirit of the invention, which is limited only by the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A mobile device case, comprising:
<claim-text>a housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least a portion of the housing including a first layer of material, a second layer of material, and a third layer of material, the second layer of material being molded between the first and third layers of material and having a higher durometer than the first and third layers of material.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the housing further includes a first portion removeably couplable to a second portion, the first portion and the second portion at least partially defining an enclosed volume therein when coupled together.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the second portion includes the second and third layers of material, and wherein the third layer of material defines a lip around the periphery of the second portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the first portion includes the first, second, and third layers of material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the first portion includes a first major side and a second major side opposite the first major side, and wherein the first layer of material defines a substantially closed loop on the first side.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The mobile device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the first portion includes a side wall defined by the second layer of material, the side wall having an inner surface and an outer surface opposite the inner surface, and wherein the third layer of material is disposed in segments along at least a portion of the outer surface of the side wall.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The mobile device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the segments of the third layer of material are spaced a predetermined distance from each other.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first layer of material and the third layer of material have substantially the same durometer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further including a fourth layer of material at least partially surrounding the first, second, and third layers of material and wherein the fourth layer of material has a lower durometer than the first and third layers of material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first portion defines a plurality of openings, and wherein the first layer of material and third layer of material are contiguous with each other through at least a portion of the plurality of openings in the second layer of material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first and third layers are in contact with each other.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. A mobile device case, comprising:
<claim-text>a housing, the housing including a first portion couplable with a second portion, the first portion and the second portion at least partially defining an enclosed volume therein when coupled together;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one of the first portion and the second portion including a first layer of material, a second layer of material, and a third layer of material, the second layer of material being disposed between the first and third layers of material and having a higher durometer than the first and third layers of material; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth layer of material surrounding at least portion of the housing, the fourth layer having a lower durometer than the first and third layer of material.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the first and third layers are in contact with each other.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the first portion includes a side wall defined by the second layer of material, the side wall having an inner surface and an outer surface opposite the inner surface, and wherein the third layer of material is disposed in segments along at least a portion of the outer surface of the side wall.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the second portion includes the second and third layers of material, and wherein the third layer of material defines a lip around the periphery of the second portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the first portion defines a plurality of openings, and wherein the first layer of material and third layer of material are contiguous with each other through at least a portion of the plurality of openings in the second layer of material of the first portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the first portion defines at least one aperture covered by at least one of the first and third layer of material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of the covered apertures substantially contours and facilitates the actuation of one or more controls of the mobile device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein first portion includes the first, second and third layers of material. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
