<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622464-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622464</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13216395</doc-number>
<date>20110824</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-188255</doc-number>
<date>20100825</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>30</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>62</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>25</main-group>
<subgroup>14</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>29619302</main-classification>
<further-classification>296 72</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Steering support member structure</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5868426</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Edwards et al.</name>
<date>19990200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>280779</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6155631</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Yoshinaka et al.</name>
<date>20001200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>29619302</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6250678</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Yoshinaka et al.</name>
<date>20010600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>280752</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6554352</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Nagy</name>
<date>20030400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>29620302</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8342599</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Atsumi et al.</name>
<date>20130100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0054682</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ellison et al.</name>
<date>20080300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>29619302</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0039668</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Baudart</name>
<date>20090200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>296 72</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>102011111643</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>10-129501</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19980500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006-327397</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20061200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00011">
<othercit>German Office Action for Application No. 10 2011 111 644.7 dated Nov. 28, 2012.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>6</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>296 30</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>296 70</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>296 72</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>29618703</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>29618705</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>29618712</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>29619301</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>29619302</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>180 90</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>280752</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120049573</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120301</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Atsumi</last-name>
<first-name>Ryo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shizuoka-ken</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Atsumi</last-name>
<first-name>Ryo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shizuoka-ken</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Lerner, David, Littenberg, Krumholz &#x26; Mentlik, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Suzuki Motor Corporation</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Dayoan</last-name>
<first-name>Glenn</first-name>
<department>3612</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Daniels</last-name>
<first-name>Jason S</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A structure of a steering support member, which enables the reduction of vehicle interior noise and steering vibration by suppressing the fore-and-aft vibration of the steering support member by means of a C-shaped or U-shaped brace and by increasing the rigidity of the steering support member in the front of the driver seat side, and enables the setting of a vibration mode in accordance with vehicle types by fine adjusting the positions of the brace and a steering bracket and by selecting the rigidity of the brace.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="126.07mm" wi="163.07mm" file="US08622464-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="260.86mm" wi="176.19mm" file="US08622464-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="242.23mm" wi="177.55mm" file="US08622464-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present application claims the benefit of Japanese Patent Application No. 2010-188255, filed Aug. 25, 2010, the disclosure of which is hereby incorporated by reference herein.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to the structure of a steering support member which is constructed across the width of a vehicle body within an instrument panel of a motor vehicle to support the steering column, etc.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF RELATED ART</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Conventionally, inside an instrument panel of a motor vehicle, a steering support member, which is a rigid member for supporting the steering column etc., is constructed across the width of the vehicle body. The steering support member is attached at both ends in the vehicle-body width direction to left and right dash side panels (pillars), and supports the steering column via a steering bracket on the driver seat side, and an instrument panel is mounted thereon, with heavy components such as meters and audio equipment of the instrument panel being suspended therefrom.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">If the peripheral portions of such a steering support member have low rigidity, there is a concern that vibrations from the body suspension, particularly vibrations from the engine during idling may be transferred to the steering, and such vibrations may give discomfort such as by propagating to the driver or causing vehicle interior noise, as well as that vibrations of equipment may cause squeaking. Moreover, when a load is applied from the front of vehicle body, the upper part of the dash panel and the cowl panel may deform, intruding into the vehicle interior, and thereby the steering support member may deform toward the rear of the vehicle body, resulting in a problem of the retreat of the steering wheel.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">For this reason, the rigidity of the steering support member itself is required to be raised and the connecting strength with the vehicle body is required to be increased, thereby improving vibration characteristics and reducing the deformation due to the load from the front of the vehicle body. Particularly problematic are a fore-and-aft (from diagonally to the upper front to diagonally to the lower rear) vibration mode in which the antinode of vibration curve is located at the middle in vehicle-body width direction of the steering support member, and a fore-and-aft vibration mode in which the node of vibration curve is located at both ends and the middle of the steering support member.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Thus, as disclosed by JP 10-129501 A, there are some conventional motor vehicles in which the vibration and the deformation of a steering support member are reduced by combining the steering support member with a cowl panel or dash panel in the front of the vehicle body, or the steering support member with the lower part of the dash panel or a floor panel in the lower part of the vehicle body, and a brace having a U-shaped cross section is used to achieve high rigidity of the brace.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Moreover, as disclosed in JP 4485992 B, there is a case in which the steering support member is made up of two pipes with the diameter of the pipe on the vehicle-body front side being configured to be larger than the diameter of the pipe on the vehicle-body rear side, in order to increase the rigidity of the steering support member on the driver seat side.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Nevertheless, there is a strict demand for reduction of vehicle interior noise and steering vibration in recent years, and it is necessary to achieve the reduction effect not only in vibration of a single frequency but also in vibrations in a wide frequency range.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Here, the vibration modes of the steering support member of concern are as follows:</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">1) a vibration mode in which vibrations having an antinode at the middle (and nodes at both ends) and the same phase near the brace in the fore-and-aft motion of the entire steering support member are combined (mode 1); and</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">2) a vibration mode in which vibrations having nodes at both ends and the middle, and opposite phases near the brace in the fore-and-aft motion of the entire steering support member are combined (mode 2).</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Since these vibration modes inevitably take place in a long rod-like member, it is difficult to reduce vibration. Moreover, although the vibration can be reduced by adding a large number of members, such a measure is not suitable because it will result in an increase in the number of parts and the cost, and there is a concern about the decline of fuel efficiency due to the increase of weight.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">For this reason, there is a need for a steering support member and a structure surrounding the member, to which an effective vibration reduction method is applied, and which is less likely to have vibration peaks, and allows the adjustment of the vibration characteristics in accordance with the type of vehicle.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Nevertheless, in the structure of the conventional steering support member disclosed in JP 10-129501 A, since load transfer to the cowl panel, the dash panel, and the floor panel cannot be sufficiently achieved, it is not possible to cope with the above-described strict demands for the reduction of vehicle interior noise as well as steering vibration. Moreover, the structure of the conventional steering support member disclosed in JP 4485992 B has a problem in that since the diameter of the pipe of the vehicle-body rear side, which significantly contributes to the vibration performance of the steering, is small and besides, since the pipe of the vehicle-body rear side is constructed along the vehicle-body width direction, an excess increase of weight is caused and the performance of suppressing the vibration will decrease.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The present invention has been made in view of such circumstances, and has as an object to provide a structure of a steering support member, which enables the reduction of vehicle interior noise and steering vibration by suppressing the fore-and-aft vibration of the steering support member by means of a C-shaped or U-shaped brace and by increasing the rigidity of the steering support member in the front of the driver seat side, and enables the setting of a vibration mode in accordance with vehicle types by fine adjusting the positions of the brace and a steering bracket and by selecting the rigidity of the brace.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In order to solve the above-described problems, the present invention is a structure of a steering support member which is constructed across a width of a vehicle body and attached to left and right sides of the vehicle body at both ends in a vehicle-body width direction via an end-part-connection bracket, in which the steering support member is made up of two support members which are disposed side by side in parallel, a first support member being disposed across the entire width of the vehicle body and a second support member being disposed in a corresponding location on a driver seat side, wherein an end part on vehicle body side of the second support member is attached, along with the first support member, to the vehicle body via the end-part-connection bracket, and an end part opposite the vehicle body of the second support member is attached to the first support member via an intermediate-part-connection bracket, wherein a C-shaped or U-shaped brace which extends in a vehicle body front-rear direction and straddles the first and second support members in the vehicle body front-rear direction, and a steering bracket which is C-shaped or made up of two parallel members and which extends in the vehicle body front-rear direction, are disposed in the middle in the vehicle-body width direction of the second support member, in which one edge part of the brace which connects to either or both of the first and second support members, and one member of the steering bracket which connects to the first and second support members are disposed so as to be overlapped at the middle in the vehicle-body width direction of the second support member, and another edge part of the brace which connects to either or both of the first and second support members, and the other member of the steering bracket which connects to the first and second support members are disposed so as to be overlapped at a position at &#xbc; of the total length of the second support member from the middle in the vehicle-body width direction of the second support member towards the intermediate-part-connection bracket, and wherein a C-shaped or U-shaped base part of the brace is connected to an upper part of a cowl panel or dash panel in the front of the vehicle body.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Moreover, in the present invention, there is constructed between the opposing edge parts of the C-shaped or U-shaped brace, a pipe member which is disposed in parallel with the first support member, and connects to the opposing edge parts at an intermediate position in the front-rear direction between the first support member and the base part of the brace.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Furthermore, in the present invention, the pipe member is a sheet metal which is flat in the horizontal direction.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Furthermore, in the present invention, the pipe member is formed of a resin material.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">As described above, the structure of the steering support member relating to the present invention is one which is constructed across a width of a vehicle body and attached to left and right sides of the vehicle body at both ends in a vehicle-body width direction via an end-part-connection bracket, in which the steering support member is made up of two support members which are disposed side by side in parallel, a first support member being disposed across the entire width of the vehicle body and a second support member being disposed in the region of a corresponding location on a driver seat side, in which an end part on vehicle body side of the second support member is attached, along with the first support member, to the vehicle body via the end-part-connection bracket, and the end part opposite the vehicle body of the second support member is attached to the first support member via an intermediate-part-connection bracket, in which a C-shaped or U-shaped brace which extends in the vehicle body front-rear direction and straddles the first and second support members in the vehicle body front-rear direction, and a steering bracket which is C-shaped or made up of two parallel members and which extends in the vehicle body front-rear direction, are disposed in the middle in the vehicle-body width direction of the second support member, wherein one edge part of the brace which connects to either or both of the first and second support members, and one member of the steering bracket which connects to the first and second support members are disposed so as to be overlapped at the middle in the vehicle-body width direction of the second support member, and another edge part of the brace which connects to either or both of the first and second support members, and the other member of the steering bracket which connects to the first and second support members are disposed so as to be overlapped at a position at &#xbc; of the total length of the second support member from the middle in the vehicle-body width direction of the second support member towards the intermediate-part-connection bracket, and wherein a C-shaped or U-shaped base part of the brace is connected to an upper part of a cowl panel or dash panel in the front of the vehicle body.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Thus, in the structure of the present invention, two edge parts of the brace and two members of the steering bracket are overlappingly assembled into a lattice form for two support members: the first and second support members, so that the opposing both edge parts of the C-shaped or U-Shaped brace serve to suppress the vibration against the fore-and-aft vibration of the steering support member in the above-described vibration mode 1, and particularly the edge part on the middle side of the brace is close to the antinode of vibration and therefore is effective in suppressing the motion. Moreover, in the structure of the present invention, the opposing both edge parts of the C-shaped or U-shape brace serve to suppress the vibration against the fore-and-aft vibration of the steering support member in the above-described vibration mode 2, as well as have a reduction effect on the rotational component in the horizontal surface around the middle node. The amplitude near the C-shaped or U-shaped brace is reduced in motion, since vibrations of the nodes at both ends and the middle have opposite phases for the fore-and-aft motion of the whole structure, and thus the two amplitudes are neutralized in the vicinity of the outer edge part. Furthermore, the structure of the present invention allows the rigidity of the entire steering support member to be increased by the brace and the steering bracket which are disposed so as to be partially overlapped. Moreover, when the vibration mode is different between the first and second support members, since it becomes possible to suppress the antinode of the vibration by fine adjusting the position of the brace and the steering bracket, or selecting the rigidity of the brace, it is possible to set an optimal vibration mode in accordance with vehicle types.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Moreover, in the structure of the present invention, since there is constructed between the opposing edge parts of the C-shaped or U-shaped brace, a pipe member which is disposed in parallel with the first support member, and connects with the opposing edge parts at an intermediate position in the front-rear direction between the first support member and the base part of the brace, the pipe member acts like a &#x201c;prop or drawbar&#x201d; thereby allowing the suppression of various deformation of the brace even when the C-shape or the U-shape exhibits deformation such as &#x201c;opening and narrowing&#x201d; leading to deformation of &#x201c;twisting in a horizontal plane&#x201d; or &#x201c;leaning&#x201d; of the brace in the above described vibration mode 2 due to the fore-and-aft motion of the entire steering support member in the above-described vibration modes 1 and 2. This makes it possible to reduce the fore-and-aft motion of the steering support member thereby allowing the vibration of the steering support member to be further reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Furthermore, in the structure of the present invention, since the pipe member is a sheet metal which is flat in the horizontal direction, the pipe member can be reduced in weight while exhibiting the above-described function. That is, since the effect of the pipe member in the present invention can be achieved sufficiently provided it has rigidity in the horizontal plane in the brace, similar effects can be obtained even if the pipe member is replaced with a flat plate. Furthermore, since the pipe member allows the adjustment of the vibration pattern of the steering support member by selecting the magnitude of the rigidity thereof as an add-on part, it is possible to modify the steering support member into a vibration pattern which is needed for each vehicle type.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Furthermore, in the structure of the present invention, since the pipe member is formed of a resin material, the pipe member can be further reduced in weight while exhibiting the above-described functions. That is, since the effect of the pipe member in the present invention can be sufficiently achieved provided it has a level of rigidity to enable the maintenance of the distance between opposing both edge parts of the C-shaped or U-shaped brace, similar effects can be obtained even if the material of the pipe member is replaced by a resin material. Furthermore, since the pipe member allows the adjustment of the vibration pattern of the steering support member by selecting the magnitude of the rigidity thereof as an add-on part as with the above described invention, it is possible to modify the steering support member into a vibration pattern which is needed for each vehicle type.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view to show a state in which a steering support member having a structure relating to an embodiment of the present invention is attached to the vehicle body in the vehicle interior of a motor vehicle;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a plan view to show the steering support member of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view to show the structure of the steering support member relating to the embodiment of the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a plan view to show the structure of the steering support member of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Hereafter, the present invention will be described in detail based on the illustrated embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of the vehicle interior of a motor vehicle to which the structure of a steering support member relating to an embodiment of the present invention is applied; <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a plan view of the vehicle interior of the motor vehicle of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>; <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view of the structure of the steering support member of the present embodiment; and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a plan view of the structure of the steering support member of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">A steering support member <b>1</b> which is a rigid member extending in the vehicle-body width direction is arranged in the upper part of the front side of the vehicle interior of a motor vehicle as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>. This steering support member <b>1</b> is disposed inside an instrument panel (not shown), which is a large scale resin molded component, and in which various pieces of equipment are installed and support the instrument panel and the steering column (not shown) etc.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The vehicle body of the upper and lower parts of the front side in the vehicle interior of motor vehicle is made up of a cowl panel <b>2</b> and a dash panel <b>3</b>; the vehicle body of both left and right sides in the vehicle-body width direction is made up of dash side panels <b>4</b><i>a </i>and <b>4</b><i>b</i>; a floor panel <b>5</b> and a side sill <b>6</b> are arranged on the vehicle-body rear side of the lower part of the dash panel <b>3</b>. A convex floor tunnel <b>5</b><i>a </i>which extends in the vehicle body front-rear direction is provided in the middle part in the vehicle-body width direction of the floor panel <b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The steering support member <b>1</b> is constructed across the width of vehicle body as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 4</figref>, and is attached to dash side panels <b>4</b><i>a </i>and <b>4</b><i>b</i>, which are left and right vehicle body side walls, via end-part-connection brackets <b>7</b> and <b>8</b> of both left and right sides at both ends in vehicle-body width direction.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Furthermore, the steering support member <b>1</b> of the present embodiment is made up of a short and long, first and second support members <b>9</b> and <b>10</b> which are made up of two pipe members disposed side by side in parallel at a fixed spacing in the vehicle body front-rear direction, where the first support member <b>9</b> is disposed across the width of vehicle body and the second support member <b>10</b> is disposed in a region of corresponding portion at a front position on the driver seat side. Of the first and second support members <b>9</b> and <b>10</b>, the first support member <b>9</b> is disposed on the vehicle-body front side and the second support member <b>10</b> is disposed on vehicle-body rear side. The diameter of the second support member <b>10</b> is specified to be greater than that of the first support member <b>9</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The end part on vehicle body side of the second support member <b>10</b> is attached, along with the first support member <b>9</b>, to the dash side panel <b>4</b><i>b </i>via the end-part-connection bracket <b>8</b>. Moreover, the end part opposite the vehicle body of the second support member <b>10</b> is attached to the first support member <b>9</b> via an intermediate-part-connection bracket <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The intermediate-part-connection bracket <b>11</b> is connected to a floor panel <b>5</b> via a first brace <b>12</b> extending in the vehicle body upward and downward direction. For this reason, an upper end part <b>12</b><i>a </i>of the first brace <b>12</b> is integrally formed into the intermediate-part-connection bracket <b>11</b>, and a lower end part <b>12</b><i>b </i>of the first brace <b>12</b> is connected to the side surface of a floor tunnel <b>5</b><i>a</i>. It is noted that in the present embodiment, although the intermediate-part-connection bracket <b>11</b> and the first brace <b>12</b> are integrally formed, both members may be separate bodies.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Moreover, there are disposed at the middle in vehicle-body width direction of the second support member <b>10</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 4</figref>, a C-shaped (or U-shaped) second brace <b>13</b>, which extends in the vehicle body front-rear direction and straddles the first and second support members <b>9</b> and <b>10</b> in the vehicle body front-rear direction, and a steering bracket <b>14</b> which is formed into a C-shape in a plan view, and which extends in the vehicle body front-rear direction and has an opening on the vehicle-body rear side.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The second brace <b>13</b> includes a base part <b>13</b><i>a </i>of which the vehicle-body front side is closed, and a pair of left and right edge parts <b>13</b><i>b </i>and <b>13</b><i>c </i>which are oppositely disposed by being extended in parallel from the base part <b>13</b><i>a </i>toward the rear of the vehicle while being spaced apart in the vehicle-body width direction, and is formed into a C-shape in plan view which has an opening on the vehicle-body rear side. The base part <b>13</b><i>a </i>of the second brace <b>13</b> is connected to the cowl panel in the front of the vehicle body. On the other hand, the steering bracket <b>14</b> includes support strips (members) <b>14</b><i>a </i>and <b>14</b><i>b</i>, which extend in the vehicle body front-rear direction while being spaced apart in the vehicle-body width direction, and the support strips <b>14</b><i>a </i>and <b>14</b><i>b </i>are disposed in parallel to straddle over the first and second support members <b>9</b> and <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Moreover, at the middle in the vehicle-body width direction of the second support member <b>10</b>, one edge part <b>13</b><i>c </i>located on the right hand side (vehicle body side) of the second brace <b>13</b> is connected to both the first and second support members <b>9</b> and <b>10</b>, and one support strip <b>14</b><i>b </i>located on the right hand side (vehicle-body side) of the steering bracket <b>14</b> is connected to both the first and second support members <b>9</b> and <b>10</b>, so that the edge part <b>13</b><i>c </i>of the second brace <b>13</b> and the support strip <b>14</b><i>b </i>of the steering bracket <b>14</b> are disposed so as to be overlapped in the vehicle-body width direction.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Furthermore, at a position of &#xbc; of the total length of the second support member <b>10</b> from the middle in the vehicle-body width direction of the second support member <b>10</b> towards the intermediate-part-connection bracket <b>11</b>, the other edge part <b>13</b><i>b </i>located on the left hand side (opposite side of vehicle body) of the second brace <b>13</b> is connected to both the first and second support members <b>9</b> and <b>10</b>, and the other support strip <b>14</b><i>a </i>located on the left hand side (opposite side of vehicle-body) of the steering bracket <b>14</b> is connected to both the first and second support members <b>9</b> and <b>10</b>, so that the edge part <b>13</b><i>b </i>of the second brace <b>13</b> and the support strip <b>14</b><i>a </i>of the steering bracket <b>14</b> are disposed so as to be overlapped in the vehicle-body width direction.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">It is noted that in the present embodiment, although the edge parts <b>13</b><i>b </i>and <b>13</b><i>c </i>of the second brace are connected to both the first and second support members <b>9</b> and <b>10</b>, they may be connected to the first support member <b>9</b> alone.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Such positional relationship between the edge parts <b>13</b><i>b </i>and <b>13</b><i>c </i>of the second brace <b>13</b> and the support strips <b>14</b><i>a </i>and <b>14</b><i>b </i>of the steering bracket <b>14</b> can be represented, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, by a length with reference to the intermediate-part-connection bracket <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">That is, letting the total length of the second support member <b>10</b> be L<b>1</b>, the length up to the middle in vehicle-body width direction of the second support member <b>10</b> be L<b>2</b>, and the half-length to the middle in vehicle-body width direction of the second support member <b>10</b> be L<b>3</b>, the relationship: L<b>1</b>=2&#xd7;L<b>2</b>=4&#xd7;L<b>3</b> holds.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">On the other hand, there are constructed between the opposing edge parts <b>13</b><i>b </i>and <b>13</b><i>c </i>of the second brace <b>13</b> relating to the present embodiment a pipe member <b>15</b> that connects to the edge parts <b>13</b><i>b </i>and <b>13</b><i>c </i>in such a way as to pass therethrough. The pipe member <b>15</b> is provided as a rod-like body which serves to suppress deformation of the second brace <b>13</b>, in which the C-shape is widened to open or narrowed to contract due to the fore-and-aft motion of the entire steering support member <b>1</b> in a particular vibration mode, thereby suppressing a twisting deformation and a leaning deformation in the horizontal plane of the second brace <b>13</b>; the pipe member <b>15</b> being disposed in parallel with the first support member <b>9</b> at an intermediate position in the front-rear direction closer to the front of vehicle-body, between first support member <b>9</b> and the base part <b>13</b><i>a </i>of the second brace <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Such pipe member <b>15</b> may be a sheet metal which is flat in the horizontal direction and allows weight reduction, or may be formed of resin material, provided that it has rigidity in the horizontal plane in the second brace <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">It is noted that the end-part-connection brackets <b>7</b> and of both left and right sides of the present embodiment are formed of a substantially flat plate-like body respectively as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, and in one end-part-connection bracket <b>8</b> of the right side, the first support member <b>9</b> is connected to a portion <b>8</b><i>a </i>of the vehicle-body front side, and the second support member <b>10</b> is connected to a portion <b>8</b><i>b </i>of the vehicle-body rear side. Moreover, at the left-side end-part-connection bracket <b>7</b> of the other hand, the first support member <b>9</b> is connected to a portion <b>7</b><i>a </i>of the vehicle-body front side. For this reason, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the front and rear portions <b>7</b><i>a</i>, <b>7</b><i>b</i>, <b>8</b><i>a</i>, and <b>8</b><i>b </i>of the end-part-connection brackets <b>7</b> and <b>8</b> are drilled with insertion holes <b>16</b> and <b>17</b> through which the end parts of the first and second support members <b>9</b> and <b>10</b> are inserted, and the first and second support members <b>9</b> and <b>10</b> are fixed by welding in a state of being inserted into the insertion holes <b>16</b> and <b>17</b>. It is noted that insertion holes <b>16</b> and <b>17</b> into which the first and second support members <b>9</b> and <b>10</b> are inserted are drilled in the front and rear of the intermediate-part-connection bracket <b>11</b> as with the end-part-connection brackets <b>7</b> and <b>8</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Thus, the steering support member <b>1</b> having a structure relating to an embodiment of the present invention includes a first support member <b>9</b> which is disposed across the width of the vehicle body on the vehicle-body front side, and a second support member <b>10</b> which is disposed in a region of a corresponding location of the driver seat side and on the vehicle-body rear side, in which in the first and second support members <b>9</b> and <b>10</b>, the end part on the vehicle body side is attached, along with the first support member <b>9</b>, to the dash side panel <b>4</b><i>b </i>via the end-part-connection bracket <b>8</b>, and the end part opposite the vehicle body of the second support member <b>10</b> is attached to the first support member <b>9</b> via the intermediate-part-connection bracket <b>11</b>. Moreover, in the middle in the vehicle-body width direction of the second support member <b>10</b>, one edge part <b>13</b><i>c </i>of the second brace <b>13</b> which is formed into a C-shape and connects to both the first and second support members <b>9</b> and <b>10</b>, and the support strip <b>14</b><i>b </i>of the steering bracket <b>14</b> which is formed into a C-shape and connects to the first and second support members <b>9</b> and <b>10</b>, are disposed so as to be overlapped in the vehicle-body width direction. At a position at a length L<b>3</b> of &#xbc; of the total length L<b>1</b> of the second support member <b>10</b> from the middle in the vehicle-body width direction of the second support member <b>10</b> towards the intermediate-part-connection bracket <b>11</b>, the other edge part <b>13</b><i>b </i>of the second brace <b>13</b> which connects to both the first and second support members <b>9</b> and <b>10</b>, and the other support strip <b>14</b><i>a </i>of the steering bracket <b>14</b> which connects to the first and second support members <b>9</b> and <b>10</b> are disposed so as to be overlapped, and the base part <b>13</b><i>a </i>of the second brace <b>13</b> is connected to a cowl panel <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">For this reason, it is possible to securely attach not only both ends of the first support member <b>9</b> making up the steering support member <b>1</b>, but also both ends of the second support member <b>10</b> to the dash side panel <b>4</b><i>b </i>and the first support member <b>9</b>, and to improve the rigidity of the entire steering support member <b>1</b>. Moreover, since the opposing two edge parts <b>13</b><i>b </i>and <b>13</b><i>c </i>of the C-shaped second brace <b>13</b> serves to suppress the vibration, particularly the edge part <b>13</b><i>b </i>on the middle side of the second brace <b>13</b> is close to the antinode of vibration and is effective in suppressing the motion, and also effective in reducing the rotational component in the horizontal plane around the node at the middle, the vibrations of the nodes at both ends and the middle come to have opposite phases in amplitude near the second brace <b>13</b> for the fore-and-aft motion of the whole structure so that two amplitudes are neutralized in the vicinity of the outer edge part, thereby reducing vibration and further increasing the rigidity of the entire steering support member <b>1</b>. Furthermore, when the vibration modes of the first and second support members <b>9</b> and <b>10</b> are different, it is possible to suppress the antinode of vibration by finely adjusting the position of the second brace <b>13</b> or the steering bracket <b>14</b>, or selecting the rigidity of the second brace <b>13</b>, thus allowing the setting of an optimal vibration mode in accordance with vehicle models.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Moreover, since there is disposed between the opposing edge parts <b>13</b><i>b </i>and <b>13</b><i>c </i>formed into a C-shape of the second brace relating to an embodiment of the present invention, a pipe member <b>15</b> which connects the edge parts <b>13</b><i>b </i>and <b>13</b><i>c</i>, in parallel with the first support member <b>9</b> at an intermediate position in the front-rear direction between the first support member <b>9</b> and the base part <b>13</b><i>a </i>of the second brace <b>13</b>, it is possible to suppress the deformation of the second brace <b>13</b> by the action of the pipe member <b>15</b> even when the C-shape of the second brace <b>13</b> is caused to produce various deformation described above by the fore-and-aft motion of the entire steering support member <b>1</b> in a specific vibration mode, thereby effectively reducing the fore-and-aft motion of the steering support member <b>1</b>, and more efficiently reducing the vibration of the steering support member <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Although embodiments of the present invention have been described so far, the present invention may be subjected to, without being limited to the embodiments described above, various variations and modifications based on the technical concepts of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">For example, although in the embodiment described above, the lower end part <b>12</b><i>b </i>of the first brace <b>12</b> is connected to the floor panel <b>5</b>, it may be connected to a lower part of the dash panel <b>3</b> depending on the type of the vehicle to which the invention is applied. Moreover, although in the embodiments described above, the base part <b>13</b><i>a </i>of the second brace <b>13</b> is connected to the cowl panel <b>2</b>, it may be connected to the upper part of the dash panel <b>3</b> depending on the type of the vehicle to which the invention is applied. Furthermore, although the steering bracket <b>14</b> is formed into a C-shape in the embodiment described above, it may be made up of two parallel members extending in the vehicle body front-rear direction depending on the type of vehicle to which the invention is applied.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A steering support member structure which is constructed across a width of a vehicle body and is attached to left and right sides of the vehicle body at both ends in a vehicle-body width direction via an end-part-connection bracket,
<claim-text>wherein the steering support member comprises two support members disposed side by side in parallel, a first support member being disposed across the entire width of the vehicle body and a second support member being disposed in a corresponding location on a driver seat side,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein an end part on the vehicle body side of the second support member is attached, along with the first support member, to the vehicle body via the end-part-connection bracket, and an end part opposite the vehicle body of the second support member is attached to the first support member via an intermediate-part-connection bracket,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a C-shaped or U-shaped brace which extends in a vehicle body front-rear direction and straddles the first and second support members in the vehicle body front-rear direction, and a steering bracket which is C-shaped or made up of two parallel members and which extends in the vehicle body front-rear direction, are disposed in the middle in the vehicle-body width direction of the second support member,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein one edge part of the brace which connects to at least one of the first and second support members, and one member of the steering bracket which connects to the first and second support members are disposed so as to be overlapped at the middle in the vehicle-body width direction of the second support member, and another edge part of the brace which connects to either or both of the first and second support members, and the other member of the steering bracket which connects to the first and second support members are disposed so as to be overlapped at a position at &#xbc; of the total length of the second support member from the middle in the vehicle-body width direction of the second support member towards the intermediate-part-connection bracket,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a C-shaped or U-shaped base part of the brace, of which the vehicle-body front side is closed, and which is disposed on the vehicle-body front side spaced apart from the first and second support members, is connected to an upper part of a cowl panel or dash panel in the front of the vehicle body, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein there is constructed between the opposing edge parts of the C-shaped or U-shaped brace a pipe member which is disposed in parallel with the first support member, and connects to the opposing edge parts at an intermediate position in the front-rear direction between the first support member and the base part of the brace.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The structure of a steering support member according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the pipe member is formed of a resin material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The structure of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the C-shaped or U-shaped base part of the brace suppresses vibration against a fore-and-aft vibration of the steering support member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The structure of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a length in the vehicle-body width direction of the base part of the brace is made smaller than the space between the opposing edge parts in which the pipe member is constructed therebetween, and the front of the U-shaped brace is made smaller in the front of the vehicle body with respect to the pipe member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The structure of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the opposing edge parts of the brace extend in the vehicle body front-rear direction in at location at which the two support members are disposed side by side in parallel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The structure of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the edge parts of the brace are not directly connected with each other at any location rear of the pipe member in the front-rear direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
