<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622533-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622533</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13753481</doc-number>
<date>20130129</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2012-017754</doc-number>
<date>20120131</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>2</main-group>
<subgroup>175</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 89</main-classification>
<further-classification>347 85</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e61">Inkjet recording apparatus and method for removing air bubbles in inkjet recording apparatus</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5231424</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kaneko et al.</name>
<date>19930700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347 29</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6443560</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Okano et al.</name>
<date>20020900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347 55</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7252361</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Nishikawa et al.</name>
<date>20070800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347 22</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7399075</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Nomura et al.</name>
<date>20080700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347 89</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8042902</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Katada</name>
<date>20111000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347 17</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2007-216442</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20070800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2011-079251</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20110400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>17</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347  7</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 65- 67</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 84- 87</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 89</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 92</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>13</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>13</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130194361</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130801</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Kyocera Document Solution Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Osaka</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Takahashi</last-name>
<first-name>So</first-name>
<address>
<city>Osaka</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bentolila</last-name>
<first-name>Ariel S.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Bay Area IP Group, LLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Vo</last-name>
<first-name>Anh T. N.</first-name>
<department>2861</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An inkjet recording apparatus is capable of an operation of removing air bubbles in a recording head that includes the ink supply step, the ink ejection step, and the refilling step. The ink supply step supplies ink to a common flow-passage in the state in which movement of the ink inside a second ink-flow passage is tolerated with an inflow side valve, and movement of the ink inside a third ink-flow passage is restricted with an outflow side valve. The ink ejection step ejects the ink together with the air bubbles inside the common flow-passage from an outflow port into the third ink-flow passage by tolerating movement of the ink inside the third ink-flow passage with the outflow side valve. The refilling step refills the ink in the state in which movement of the ink inside the second ink-flow passage is restricted with the inflow side valve.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="135.21mm" wi="194.65mm" file="US08622533-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="131.49mm" wi="209.80mm" file="US08622533-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="174.41mm" wi="186.01mm" file="US08622533-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="146.47mm" wi="207.09mm" file="US08622533-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="104.22mm" wi="202.69mm" file="US08622533-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="286.77mm" wi="147.83mm" file="US08622533-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="283.38mm" wi="122.60mm" file="US08622533-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="164.17mm" wi="197.61mm" file="US08622533-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="158.07mm" wi="199.56mm" file="US08622533-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="148.93mm" wi="192.96mm" file="US08622533-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="167.56mm" wi="199.56mm" file="US08622533-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="258.15mm" wi="113.79mm" file="US08622533-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="294.30mm" wi="123.27mm" file="US08622533-20140107-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="145.71mm" wi="209.30mm" file="US08622533-20140107-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">INCORPORATION BY REFERENCE</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is based upon and claims the benefit of priority from Japanese Unexamined Patent Application Publication No. 2012-017754, filed Jan. 31, 2012, the entire contents of which are incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">Field</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to an inkjet recording apparatus which, in a piece of recording equipment, such as a facsimile, a copying machine, or a printer, performs recording by discharging ink onto a record medium, such as a paper sheet, and particularly relates to recovery of a recording head, which discharges ink.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Recording apparatuses, such as facsimiles, copying machines, and printers, are configured to record an image on a record medium, such as a paper, cloth, or OHP sheet, and according to method of recording, they can be classified into inkjet type, wire dot type, thermal type, etc. Further, the inkjet recording method is available as, for example, a serial type and a line head type. With the inkjet recording method of serial type, recording is performed while the recording head scans the record medium, for example. With the inkjet recording method of line head type, recording is performed by, for example, the single pass method (one pass method). In the inkjet recording apparatus using the inkjet recording method of line head type, recording heads in the form of a line are for example, fixed in, the apparatus main body.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">For example, with the inkjet recording apparatus of line head type, a feeding means, such as a feeding belt provided in the apparatus main body feeds the record medium, such as a paper sheet, while the respective nozzles in the line heads having a recording width larger than the width of the record medium discharge the ink, thereby an image being formed on the record medium. Thus, printing at high speed can be accomplished, as compared to the serial type inkjet recording apparatus, in which the recording head makes a reciprocating operation along the direction of width of the record medium.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">With such an inkjet recording apparatus, if an air bubble is generated in the ink-flow passage, and the generated air bubble is introduced into a nozzle in the recording head, discharging ink from the nozzle is made impossible, thereby the printing operation cannot be performed.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Then, as the method for removing air bubbles in the ink, an ink supply apparatus is known which performs an operation of circulating the ink by, prior to supplying the ink from the main tank to the sub-tank, sucking up the ink from the bottom portion of the main tank to circulate the ink back to the main tank through the sub-tank.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Further, a droplet discharge head is known which includes a plurality of droplet discharge portions; a common supply passage for supplying the liquid to the supply passage of the respective droplet discharge portions; and a common recovery passage for recovering the liquid from the recovery passage of the respective droplet discharge portions in which a dead water region is formed, a reserving portion for reserving the air bubbles being provided in the dead water region, whereby a pressure fluctuation generated in the pressure chamber in the droplet discharge portion can be more easily propagated to the common recovery passage.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">An inkjet recording apparatus in accordance with one aspect of the present invention includes a recording head, an ink tank, a pump mechanism, a circulation flow passage, an inflow side valve, an outflow side valve, and a damper portion. The recording head has a common flow-passage having an inflow port at one end and an outflow port at the other end, and a plurality of nozzles communicating with the common flow-passage and discharging ink onto a record medium. The ink tank reserves the ink to be discharged onto the record medium. The pump mechanism sucks the ink inside the ink tank, and supplies the ink to the recording head. The circulation flow passage has a first ink-flow passage connecting between the pump mechanism and the ink tank, a second ink-flow passage connecting between the pump mechanism and the inflow port of the recording head, and a third ink-flow passage connecting between the outflow port of the recording head and the ink tank. The inflow side valve is provided in the second ink-flow passage. The outflow side valve is provided in the third ink-flow passage. The damper portion is formed in the ink-flow passage from the inflow side valve to the outflow side valve, buffering a change in internal pressure caused by an operation of the pump mechanism. And, the inkjet recording apparatus is capable of implementing an operation of removing air bubbles in the recording head, which includes: the ink supply step of supplying the ink to the common flow-passage by using the pump mechanism for pressurizing the ink in the state in which movement of the ink inside the second ink-flow passage is tolerated with the inflow side valve, and movement of the ink inside the third ink-flow passage is restricted with the outflow side valve; the ink ejection step of ejecting, after start of the ink supply step, the ink together with the air bubbles inside the common flow-passage from the outflow port into the third ink-flow passage by tolerating movement of the ink inside the third ink-flow passage with the outflow side valve; and the refilling step of, after termination of the ink ejection step, refilling the ink into the pump mechanism from the ink tank through the first ink-flow passage in the state in which movement of the ink inside the second ink-flow passage is restricted with the inflow side valve.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">A method for removing air bubbles in an inkjet recording apparatus in accordance with another aspect of the present invention provides the ink supply step, the ink ejection step, and the refilling step for an inkjet recording apparatus including a recording head, an ink tank, a pump mechanism, a circulation flow passage, an inflow side valve, and an outflow side valve. The recording head has a common flow-passage having an inflow port at one end and an outflow port at the other end, and a plurality of nozzles communicating with the common flow-passage. The pump mechanism supplies ink inside the ink tank to the recording head. The circulation flow passage has a first ink-flow passage connecting between the pump mechanism and the ink tank, a second ink-flow passage connecting between the pump mechanism and the inflow port of the recording head, and a third ink-flow passage connecting between the outflow port of the recording head and the ink tank. The inflow side valve is provided in the second ink-flow passage. The outflow side valve is provided in the third ink-flow passage. The ink supply step supplies the ink to the common flow-passage by using the pump mechanism for pressurizing the ink in the state in which movement of the ink inside the second ink-flow passage is tolerated with the inflow side valve, and movement of the ink inside the third ink-flow passage is restricted with the outflow side valve. The ink ejection step ejects, after start of the ink supply step, the ink inside the common flow-passage together with the air bubbles from the outflow port into the third ink-flow passage by tolerating movement of the ink inside the third ink-flow passage with the outflow side valve. The refilling step refills, after termination of the ink ejection step, the ink from the ink tank into the pump mechanism through the first ink-flow passage in the state in which movement of the ink inside the second ink-flow passage is restricted with the inflow side valve.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">An inkjet recording apparatus in accordance with another aspect of the present invention includes a recording head, an ink tank, a pump mechanism, a circulation flow passage, an inflow side valve, and an outflow side valve. The recording head has a common flow-passage having an inflow port at one end and an outflow port at the other end, and a plurality of nozzles communicating with the common flow-passage. The pump mechanism supplies ink inside the ink tank to the recording head. The circulation flow passage has a first ink-flow passage connecting between the pump mechanism and the ink tank, a second ink-flow passage connecting between the pump mechanism and the inflow port of the recording head, and a third ink-flow passage connecting between the outflow port of the recording head and the ink tank. The inflow side valve is provided in the second ink-flow passage. The outflow side valve is provided in the third ink-flow passage. And, the ink supply step of supplying the ink to the common flow-passage by using the pump mechanism for pressurizing the ink in the state in which movement of the ink inside the second ink-flow passage is tolerated with the inflow side valve, and movement of the ink inside the third ink-flow passage is restricted with the outflow side valve, the ink ejection step ejects, after start of the ink supply step, the ink inside the common flow-passage together with the air bubbles from the outflow port into the third ink-flow passage by tolerating movement of the ink inside of the third ink-flow passage with the outflow side valve, and the refilling step of refilling, after termination of the ink ejection step, the ink from the ink tank into the pump mechanism through the first ink-flow passage in the state in which movement of the ink inside the second ink-flow passage is restricted with the inflow side valve can be implemented.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a side view schematically showing the structure of an inkjet recording apparatus <b>100</b> according to one embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a plan view of a first conveyance unit <b>5</b> and a recording unit <b>9</b> of the inkjet recording apparatus <b>100</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> when viewed from the top;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a drawing schematically showing an ink-flow passage of the inkjet recording apparatus <b>100</b> of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a drawing schematically showing the internal structure of a recording head <b>17</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a drawing schematically showing a syringe pump <b>23</b> and a driving apparatus <b>70</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flowchart illustrating a first sequence of steps of operation of removing air bubbles in the recording head <b>17</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a drawing showing the state in which air bubbles are generated in a common flow-passage <b>29</b> of the recording head <b>17</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a drawing showing the state in which a damper portion <b>30</b> of the recording head <b>17</b> is inflated by supplying ink from the syringe pump <b>23</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a drawing showing the state in which the ink reserved in the damper portion <b>30</b> is ejected together with the air bubbles B from an outflow port <b>27</b><i>b </i>with an outflow side valve <b>33</b> being opened.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a drawing showing the state in which the syringe pump <b>23</b> is refilled with the ink and an inflow side valve <b>25</b> is switched over such that a sub-tank <b>21</b> and the recording head <b>17</b> are communicated with each other;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a flowchart illustrating a second sequence of steps of operation of removing air bubbles in the recording head <b>17</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a flowchart illustrating a third sequence of steps of operation of removing air bubbles in the recording head <b>17</b>; and</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a drawing schematically showing another example of configuration of the ink-flow passage of the inkjet recording apparatus <b>100</b> of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Hereinbelow, an embodiment of the present invention will be explained with reference to the drawings. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a side view schematically showing the structure of an inkjet recording apparatus <b>100</b> in accordance with the present invention, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a plan view of a first conveyance unit <b>5</b> and a recording unit <b>9</b> of the inkjet recording apparatus <b>100</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> when viewed from the top.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, in the left side portion of the inkjet recording apparatus <b>100</b>, a pick-up tray <b>2</b> for accommodating paper sheets P (record media) is provided. At one end of this pick-up tray <b>2</b>, there are provided a pick-up roller <b>3</b> for picking up the accommodated paper sheets P one by one sequentially from the top-positioned paper sheet P and feeding it to a first conveyance unit <b>5</b> later described, and a driven roller <b>4</b> which is butted against the pick-up roller <b>3</b> and driven thereby to be rotated.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">On the downstream side (the right side in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of the pick-up roller <b>3</b> and driven roller <b>4</b> in the paper sheet conveyance direction, the first conveyance unit <b>5</b> and the recording unit <b>9</b> are disposed. The first conveyance unit <b>5</b> includes a first driving roller <b>6</b> which is disposed on the downstream side in the paper sheet conveyance direction, a first driven roller <b>7</b> which is disposed on the upstream side in the paper sheet conveyance direction, and a first feeding belt <b>8</b> which is installed on the first driving roller <b>6</b> and the first driven roller <b>7</b>. With the first driving roller <b>6</b> being driven to be rotated in a clockwise direction, the paper sheet P held by the first feeding belt <b>8</b> is fed in the paper sheet conveyance direction.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Note that the first driving roller <b>6</b> is disposed on the downstream side in the paper sheet conveyance direction, thereby the feeding surface (the upper surface in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of the first feeding belt <b>8</b> being pulled by the first driving roller <b>6</b>, which allows the tension of the feeding surface of the first feeding belt <b>8</b> to be increased, and thus stable feeding of the paper sheet P to be made. As the first feeding belt <b>8</b>, a sheet made of a dielectric resin may be used, and mainly a belt having no seams (a seamless belt) may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The recording unit <b>9</b> includes a head housing <b>10</b>, and line heads <b>11</b>C, <b>11</b>M, <b>11</b>Y, and <b>11</b>K which are held by the head housing <b>10</b>. These line heads <b>11</b>C to <b>11</b>K are supported at a level where a predetermined spacing (for example, 1 mm) with respect to the feeding surface of the first feeding belt <b>8</b> is given, and as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a plurality of (herein three) recording heads <b>17</b><i>a </i>to <b>17</b><i>c </i>are arranged zigzag along the paper sheet width direction (in a vertical direction in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) which is orthogonal to the paper sheet conveyance direction. The line heads <b>11</b>C to <b>11</b>K have a width larger than the width of the paper sheet P fed, and can discharge the ink from a nozzle <b>18</b> corresponding to a printing position onto the paper sheet P which is fed on the first feeding belt <b>8</b>. Further, the respective recording heads <b>17</b><i>a </i>to <b>17</b><i>c </i>are disposed such that a part of the nozzles <b>18</b> provided in each of them are duplicated in the feeding direction.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The recording heads <b>17</b><i>a </i>to <b>17</b><i>c </i>constituting the respective line heads <b>11</b>C to <b>11</b>K are supplied with ink having a color specified for the respective line heads <b>11</b>C to <b>11</b>K from one of the tanks (not shown) of inks having four different colors (cyan, magenta, yellow and black).</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The respective recording heads <b>17</b><i>a </i>to <b>17</b><i>c </i>discharge the ink from the nozzle <b>18</b> onto the paper sheet P which is fed, being adsorbed to the feeding surface of the first feeding belt <b>8</b> to be held thereby, according to image data received from an external computer, or the like. Thereby, on the paper sheet P on the first feeding belt <b>8</b>, there is formed a color image in which the inks of the four colors of cyan, magenta, yellow, and black are superposed one upon another.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Further, at the time of starting the printing following the downtime over a long period of time, the purging operation, which discharges the ink having an increased viscosity from the nozzle <b>18</b>, is executed for the nozzles <b>18</b> in all the recording heads <b>17</b><i>a </i>to <b>17</b><i>c</i>, and at an interval between printing operations, the purging operation is made for any nozzles <b>18</b> in the recording heads <b>17</b><i>a </i>to <b>17</b><i>c </i>with which the amount of ink discharge has been lowered below a predetermined value, thereby the recording heads <b>17</b><i>a </i>to <b>17</b><i>c </i>being prepared for the subsequent printing operation. Thus, poor discharge of the ink due to, for example, drying or clogging of the recording heads <b>17</b><i>a </i>to <b>17</b><i>c </i>can be suppressed.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">On the downstream side (the right side in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of the first conveyance unit <b>5</b> in the paper sheet conveyance direction, a second conveyance unit <b>12</b> is disposed. The second conveyance unit <b>12</b> is configured to include a second driving roller <b>13</b> which is disposed on the downstream side in the paper sheet conveyance direction, a second driven roller <b>14</b> which is disposed on the upstream side in the paper sheet conveyance direction, and a second feeding belt <b>15</b> which is installed on the second driving roller <b>13</b> and the second driven roller <b>14</b>, and with the second driving roller <b>13</b> being driven to be rotated in a clockwise direction, the paper sheet P held by the second feeding belt <b>15</b> is fed in the paper sheet conveyance direction.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The paper sheet P on which an ink image is recorded by the recording unit <b>9</b> is fed to the second conveyance unit <b>12</b>, and while being passed through the second conveyance unit <b>12</b>, the inks discharged on the surface of the paper sheet P are dried. Further, under the second conveyance unit <b>12</b>, a maintenance unit <b>19</b> is disposed. The maintenance unit <b>19</b> is moved to under the recording unit <b>9</b> when the above-mentioned purging operation is executed, and wipes off the inks discharged from the nozzles <b>18</b> in the recording heads <b>17</b> to recover the inks.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">On the downstream side of the second conveyance unit <b>12</b> in the paper sheet conveyance direction, there is provided a delivery roller pair <b>16</b> for delivering the paper sheet P on which the image is recorded, to the outside of the apparatus main body, and on the downstream side of the delivery roller pair <b>16</b>, there is provided a delivery tray (not shown) on which the paper sheets P delivered to the outside of the apparatus main body are stacked.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a drawing schematically showing an ink-flow passage of the inkjet recording apparatus <b>100</b> according to the embodiment of the present invention, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a sectional view schematically showing the internal structure of the recording head <b>17</b>. Between the main tank <b>20</b> for the respective colors and the recording head <b>17</b>, the ink-flow passage shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is provided, respectively, however, the ink-flow passage for a particular color will be explained here. In addition, the recording heads <b>17</b><i>a </i>to <b>17</b><i>c </i>are expressed as the recording head <b>17</b>, the symbols <b>17</b><i>a </i>to <b>17</b><i>c </i>being abbreviated to <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, between the main tank <b>20</b> and the recording head <b>17</b>, a sub-tank <b>21</b> and a syringe pump <b>23</b> are disposed, and the sub-tank <b>21</b> and the syringe pump <b>23</b> are connected to each other by a first ink-flow passage <b>22</b> formed of a tubing member. An inflow port <b>27</b><i>a </i>of the recording head <b>17</b> and the syringe pump <b>23</b> are connected to each other by a second ink-flow passage <b>24</b> formed of a tubing member, and the second ink-flow passage <b>24</b> is connected to the first ink-flow passage <b>22</b> through an inflow side valve <b>25</b> constituted by a three-way valve.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">On the other hand, an outflow port <b>27</b><i>b </i>of the recording head <b>17</b> and the sub-tank <b>21</b> are connected to each other by a third ink-flow passage <b>32</b> formed of a tubing member, and in the third ink-flow passage <b>32</b>, an outflow side valve <b>33</b> constituted by a three-way valve is provided. In addition, to the third ink-flow passage <b>32</b>, a waste fluid tank <b>35</b> is connected through the outflow side valve <b>33</b>. The first ink-flow passage <b>22</b>, the second ink-flow passage <b>24</b>, and the third ink-flow passage <b>32</b> form a circulation flow passage which connects the recording head <b>17</b>, the sub-tank <b>21</b>, and the syringe pump <b>23</b> to one another.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, in the recording head <b>17</b>, a common flow-passage <b>29</b> ranging from the inflow port <b>27</b><i>a </i>to the outflow port <b>27</b><i>b </i>is provided, and in the portion of the common flow-passage <b>29</b> that is closer to the inflow port <b>27</b><i>a</i>, a damper portion <b>30</b> is formed. With the damper portion <b>30</b>, a part of the inner wall of the common flow-passage <b>29</b> is formed of a flexible film, and when the internal pressure of the common flow-passage <b>29</b> is raised, the damper portion <b>30</b> is inflated outward, while, when the internal pressure is lowered, the damper portion <b>30</b> becomes dented, thereby an abrupt change in internal pressure of the common flow-passage <b>29</b> can be buffered. In the present embodiment, the damper portion <b>30</b> is provided between the inflow port <b>27</b><i>a </i>and the outflow port <b>27</b><i>b </i>of the recording head <b>17</b>, however, the damper portion <b>30</b> may be disposed outside of the recording head <b>17</b>, provided that it is placed between the inflow side valve <b>25</b> and the outflow side valve <b>33</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Further, a branch passage <b>31</b> is provided which is branched downward from the common flow-passage <b>29</b>, being led to the respective nozzles <b>18</b>. For example, in a case where the recording head <b>17</b> is a piezoelectric inkjet head which transmits a pressure change caused by a deformation of a piezoelectric element (not shown) to the ink in the nozzle <b>18</b> to fluctuate the meniscus, thereby generating an ink drop, a voltage having a predetermined driving waveform is applied to the piezoelectric element to thereby discharge a predetermined amount of ink from the nozzle <b>18</b> corresponding to printing data.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a drawing schematically showing the syringe pump <b>23</b> and a driving apparatus <b>70</b> for the syringe pump <b>23</b> which are used in the present embodiment. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the syringe pump <b>23</b> includes a cylinder <b>63</b> and a piston <b>65</b>. The piston <b>65</b> has a piston portion <b>65</b><i>a</i>, which is formed at the lower end of a piston rod <b>65</b><i>b</i>. Further, the upper end of the piston rod <b>65</b><i>b </i>is extended to above the top wall of the cylinder <b>63</b>, and in the extended end portion of the piston rod <b>65</b><i>b</i>, a flange portion <b>65</b><i>c </i>is formed.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Further, there is protruded downward from the lower end face of the cylinder <b>63</b> a supply/ejection portion <b>67</b>, which is hollow cylindrical, being communicated with the cylinder <b>63</b>. The supply/ejection portion <b>67</b> is connected with the first ink-flow passage <b>22</b>, and the ink inside the sub-tank <b>21</b> (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) is caused to flow into the cylinder <b>63</b> through the supply/ejection portion <b>67</b>, while the ink inside the cylinder <b>63</b> is ejected through the supply/ejection portion <b>67</b>, the ejected ink being supplied to the recording head <b>17</b> (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) through the second ink-flow passage <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">On the other hand, the piston <b>65</b> of the syringe pump <b>23</b> can be vertically moved by the driving apparatus <b>70</b>. The driving apparatus <b>70</b> has a ball screw <b>71</b>, a nut portion <b>77</b>, and a drive motor <b>79</b>. The ball screw <b>71</b> is disposed substantially in parallel with the cylinder <b>63</b> (in a vertical direction) in the vicinity of the flange portion <b>65</b><i>c </i>of the piston <b>65</b>. The lower end portion and the upper end portion of the ball screw <b>71</b> are rotatably supported by ball screw supporting members <b>73</b><i>a </i>and <b>73</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Further, the upper end portion of the ball screw <b>71</b> is extended to above the ball screw supporting member <b>73</b><i>b</i>, the extended end portion being provided with a coupling <b>75</b>. The coupling <b>75</b> is connected with a rotating shaft <b>79</b><i>a </i>of the drive motor <b>79</b> such that the ball screw <b>71</b> is rotated with the drive motor <b>79</b> being run. Further, the drive motor <b>79</b> can be run either forward or backward. The ball screw <b>71</b> is operatively engaged with the nut portion <b>77</b>, and with the ball screw <b>71</b> being rotated, the nut portion <b>77</b> is moved upward or downward depending upon the direction of rotation.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Further, in the nut portion <b>77</b>, there is formed a fixing portion <b>77</b><i>a </i>which includes two plate-like members, being protruded toward the piston <b>65</b>, and the fixing portion <b>77</b><i>a </i>sandwiches the flange portion <b>65</b><i>c </i>of the piston <b>65</b>, thereby being connected to the flange portion <b>65</b><i>c</i>. Thus, with the drive motor <b>79</b> being run, the piston <b>65</b> is moved upward or downward together with the nut portion <b>77</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The relationship between the direction of running of the drive motor <b>79</b> and the direction of movement of the piston <b>65</b> is not specifically limited, and for example, it can be set such that, if the drive motor <b>79</b> is run in a clockwise direction when viewed from the top in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the piston <b>65</b> is moved downward (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>), while if the drive motor <b>79</b> is run in a counterclockwise direction when viewed from the top in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the piston <b>65</b> is moved upward (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The cylinder <b>63</b> is partitioned into a first containing chamber <b>63</b><i>a </i>on the supply/ejection portion <b>67</b> side and a second containing chamber <b>63</b><i>b </i>on the piston rod <b>65</b><i>b </i>side by the piston portion <b>65</b><i>a</i>. Further, the ink supplied from the sub-tank <b>21</b> is contained in the first containing chamber <b>63</b><i>a</i>. On the periphery of the piston portion <b>65</b><i>a</i>, a packing (not shown), such as an O-ring, is loaded in order to prevent the ink from being leaked from the first containing chamber <b>63</b><i>a </i>to the second containing chamber <b>63</b><i>b</i>, and permit the piston portion <b>65</b><i>a </i>to be smoothly slid on the inner wall of the cylinder <b>63</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">When the drive motor <b>79</b> is run to move the piston portion <b>65</b><i>a </i>upward (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>), a negative pressure is generated in the first containing chamber <b>63</b><i>a </i>of the cylinder <b>63</b>. Such negative pressure causes the ink in the sub-tank <b>21</b> to be sucked into the cylinder <b>63</b> through the inflow side valve <b>25</b>, thereby a substantially predetermined quantity of ink being introduced into the first containing chamber <b>63</b><i>a </i>through the supply/ejection portion <b>67</b>. On the other hand, when the drive motor <b>79</b> is run in a direction reverse to that of the above-mentioned motor running, thereby the piston portion <b>65</b><i>a </i>being moved downward, a positive pressure is generated in the first containing chamber <b>63</b><i>a</i>, and such positive pressure causes the ink to be ejected from the supply/ejection portion <b>67</b>, thereby a substantially fixed quantity of ink being supplied to the recording head <b>17</b> through the inflow side valve <b>25</b> (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Next, the operation of removing air bubbles in the recording head <b>17</b> will be explained. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flowchart illustrating a first sequence of steps of operation of removing air bubbles in the recording head <b>17</b>, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> are drawings schematically showing the respective steps to be taken in an operation of removing air bubbles in the recording head <b>17</b>. With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, and as required, to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the procedure for performing an operation of removing air bubbles in the recording head <b>17</b> will be explained along the flow of the steps in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">At a normal time (a printing waiting time), as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the sub-tank <b>21</b> side of the inflow side valve <b>25</b> and the recording head <b>17</b> side thereof are communicated with each other, and a negative pressure is applied to the damper portion <b>30</b>, resulting from a difference in water head between the sub-tank <b>21</b> and the recording head <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, in the event where air bubbles B are generated inside the common flow-passage <b>29</b> of the recording head <b>17</b>, the inflow side valve <b>25</b> is first switched over such that the syringe pump <b>23</b> side and the recording head <b>17</b> side are communicated with each other (step S<b>1</b>). Next, the piston <b>65</b> in the syringe pump <b>23</b> is pressed down to pressurize the ink in the syringe pump <b>23</b> for supplying the ink from the inflow port <b>27</b><i>a </i>of the recording head <b>17</b> to the inside of the common flow-passage <b>29</b> (step S<b>2</b>). And, as the ink is supplied from the inflow port <b>27</b><i>a</i>, an ink flow directed toward the outflow port <b>27</b><i>b </i>is generated inside the common flow-passage <b>29</b>, the air bubbles B being moved toward the outflow port <b>27</b><i>b </i>by the ink flow generated.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">At this time, the outflow side valve <b>33</b> is closed, the outflow of the ink from the outflow port <b>27</b><i>b </i>being restricted, and therefore inside the common flow-passage <b>29</b>, a positive pressure is generated, however, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the damper portion <b>30</b> is inflated to thereby buffer an abrupt increase in internal pressure inside the common flow-passage <b>29</b> due to the ink supply from the syringe pump <b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Next, when the pressurization of the ink by the syringe pump <b>23</b> has been terminated (step S<b>3</b>), the outflow side valve <b>33</b> is opened (step S<b>4</b>). With this, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the pressure inside the common flow-passage <b>29</b> is released, the ink kept in the damper portion <b>30</b> being ejected from the outflow port <b>27</b><i>b </i>together with the air bubbles B. Next, the outflow side valve <b>33</b> is again closed (step S<b>5</b>), and the inflow side valve <b>25</b> is switched over such that the syringe pump <b>23</b> side and the sub-tank <b>21</b> side are communicated with each other (step S<b>6</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Thereafter, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, the piston <b>65</b> in the syringe pump <b>23</b> is pulled up to refill the syringe pump <b>23</b> with the ink (step S<b>7</b>), and the inflow side valve <b>25</b> is switched over such that the sub-tank <b>21</b> side and the recording head <b>17</b> side are communicated with each other (step S<b>8</b>), thereby the operation of removing air bubbles being completed, and the initial state shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> being restored.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Note that, if, before the outflow side valve <b>33</b> is again closed after the ink supply by the syringe pump <b>23</b> having been terminated, the inflow side valve <b>25</b> were switched over such that the syringe pump <b>23</b> side and the sub-tank side are communicated with each other, a reverse flow of the ink would be generated from the inflow port <b>27</b><i>a </i>toward the syringe pump <b>23</b> side, the ink kept in the damper portion <b>30</b> being ejected into the common flow-passage <b>29</b> with the pressure inside the common flow-passage <b>29</b> being released and the damper portion <b>30</b> being contracted. And, as a result of this, the air bubbles B which could not have been carried away from the outflow port <b>27</b><i>b </i>would also flow upstream from the inflow port <b>27</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Accordingly, by taking the above procedure for performing an operation of removing air bubbles in the recording head <b>17</b>, there will occur no reverse flow of the ink from the inflow port <b>27</b><i>a </i>toward the syringe pump <b>23</b> side. Thus, the air bubbles B inside the common flow-passage <b>29</b> can be reliably carried away from the outflow port <b>27</b><i>b</i>. The ink which has been carried away together with the air bubbles B from the outflow port <b>27</b><i>b </i>are returned to the sub-tank <b>21</b> through the third ink-flow passage <b>32</b>. While the ink is being reserved in the sub-tank <b>21</b>, the air bubbles B in the ink get out of the liquid surface, and therefore, there is no possibility that the ink including air bubbles is supplied to the recording head <b>17</b> from the sub-tank <b>21</b> through the syringe pump <b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Further, since, after the ink inside the common flow-passage <b>29</b> has been ejected from the outflow port <b>27</b><i>b </i>into the third ink-flow passage <b>32</b> together with the air bubbles B, the outflow side valve <b>33</b> is closed before the inflow side valve <b>25</b> is switched over such that the syringe pump <b>23</b> side and the sub-tank <b>21</b> side are communicated with each other, reverse flowing of the ink inside the third ink-flow passage <b>32</b> into the common flow-passage <b>29</b> at the time of the inflow side valve <b>25</b> being switched over can be suppressed.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">As the timing when the outflow side valve <b>33</b> is to be opened, it may be any time after the ink supply by the syringe pump <b>23</b> is terminated and before the inflow side valve <b>25</b> is switched over, and the outflow side valve <b>33</b> can be opened immediately (in a few seconds) after the pressurization of the ink by the syringe pump <b>23</b> having been terminated. Alternatively, for example, like a second sequence of steps illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, the outflow side valve <b>33</b> can be opened simultaneously with the termination of the pressurization of the ink by the syringe pump <b>23</b> (step S<b>3</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a flowchart illustrating a third sequence of steps of operation of removing air bubbles in the recording head <b>17</b>. In the procedure illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, after the ink supply by the pressurization of the ink by the syringe pump <b>23</b> having been started (step S<b>2</b>), the outflow side valve <b>33</b> is opened (step S<b>3</b>) before the pressurization by the syringe pump <b>23</b> is terminated (step S<b>4</b>). Since the other controls are the same as those in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> or <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, explanation thereof will be omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">By using the above procedure for making an operation of removing air bubbles in the recording head <b>17</b>, the outflow side valve <b>33</b> can be positively opened before the ink supply by the syringe pump <b>23</b> is terminated, even if the time period from the start of the opening operation of the outflow side valve <b>33</b> to the termination thereof involves a time lag, and therefore, the control of the opening timing for the outflow side valve <b>33</b> can be easily performed. Further, since the outflow side valve <b>33</b> is opened for ejection of the ink before the pressurization of the ink by the syringe pump <b>23</b> is terminated, the time required for operation of removing air bubbles can be shortened.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a drawing schematically showing another example of configuration of the ink-flow passage of the inkjet recording apparatus <b>100</b> of the present invention. In the present embodiment, the first ink-flow passage <b>22</b> and the second ink-flow passage <b>24</b> are provided independently of each other, and a first inflow side valve <b>25</b><i>a </i>comprised of a two-way valve is disposed in the second ink-flow passage <b>24</b>, while a second inflow side valve <b>25</b><i>b </i>comprised of a two-way valve is disposed in the first ink-flow passage <b>22</b>. The configuration of the other part is the same as that of the ink-flow passage shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, and therefore, explanation thereof will be omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Also in the configuration shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, by making an operation of removing air bubbles with the same sequence of steps as that in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, or <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, occurrence of a reverse flow of the ink from the inflow port <b>27</b><i>a </i>toward the syringe pump <b>23</b> side is prevented, whereby the air bubbles B inside the common flow-passage <b>29</b> can be reliably carried away from the outflow port <b>27</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The operation of removing air bubbles as described above can be performed simultaneously with an operation of recovering (purging) the recording head <b>17</b> by forcedly discharging the viscosity-increased ink, foreign matters, air bubbles, and the like in the nozzles <b>18</b> with the syringe pump <b>23</b> being used to pressurize the ink in the recording head <b>17</b> from the inflow port <b>27</b><i>a </i>side.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">However, in a case where the air bubble removing operation is performed simultaneously with the purging operation, generation of air bubbles always involves a certain quantity of ink being discharged from the nozzles <b>18</b>, and therefore a problem has been presented that the ink consumption in an operation other than the printing operation is increased. In addition, the ink in which air bubbles have been merely generated can be used for printing with substantially no problem if the air bubbles are removed, and therefore it is not always required to make a purging. Then, the air bubble removing mode in which only the air bubbles inside the common flow-passage <b>29</b> are removed without the ink being discharged from the nozzle <b>18</b> can be implemented separately of the purging operation.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Further, when the outflow side valve <b>33</b> is opened at step S<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, and at step S<b>3</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, the outflow side valve <b>33</b> is switched over such that, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the outflow port <b>27</b><i>b </i>of the recording head <b>17</b> and the sub-tank <b>21</b> are communicated with each other, whereby the ink carried away from the outflow port <b>27</b><i>b </i>together with the air bubbles can be reused, however, instead of this scheme, the outflow side valve <b>33</b> may be switched over such that the outflow port <b>27</b><i>b </i>and the waste fluid tank <b>35</b> are communicated with each other.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">For example, in a case where the air bubble removing operation is performed simultaneously with the purging operation, communicating the outflow port <b>27</b><i>b </i>with the waste fluid tank <b>35</b> causes the ink inside the common flow-passage <b>29</b> to be recovered into the waste fluid tank <b>35</b>, thereby the possibility being eliminated that the ink containing a viscosity-increased ink, foreign matters, and the like are reused. Accordingly, whether the outflow side valve <b>33</b> is switched over to the sub-tank <b>21</b> side, or to the waste fluid tank <b>35</b> side may be determined depending upon the condition of the ink in the common flow-passage <b>29</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">Thus, the present invention is not limited to the above-stated embodiment, and may be variously modified within the scope of the spirit of the present invention. For example, the above-stated embodiment is configured such that the syringe pump <b>23</b> is used to supply the ink to the recording head <b>17</b>, however, the method for supplying the ink at the time of printing is not specifically limited, provided that the ink is suppliable from the sub-tank <b>21</b> to the recording head <b>17</b>. For example, an ink supply passage which connects between the sub-tank <b>21</b> and the recording head <b>17</b> not through the syringe pump <b>23</b> may be provided for supplying the ink from the sub-tank <b>21</b> to the recording head <b>17</b>. In addition, a pump mechanism different from the syringe pump <b>23</b> may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">In addition, the main tank <b>20</b> and the waste fluid tank <b>35</b> are not indispensable components, and for example, with a small-sized inkjet recording apparatus, the sub-tank <b>21</b> may be replaced with another one when the ink in the sub-tank <b>21</b> is used up, the main tank <b>20</b> being not provided. In addition, instead of the waste fluid tank <b>35</b>, a recovery tray for recovering the viscosity-increased ink or the ink including foreign matters that has been discharged from the nozzle <b>18</b> by the purging operation may be provided.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">In addition, the number of nozzles <b>18</b> in the recording head <b>17</b>, the nozzle-to-nozzle spacing, and the like, may be set as appropriate in accordance with the specifications for the inkjet recording apparatus <b>100</b>. In addition, the number of recording heads <b>17</b> is not particularly limited, and for example, a single recording head <b>17</b> may be disposed for each of the line heads <b>11</b>C to <b>11</b>K.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">The present invention is applicable to inkjet recording apparatuses which perform recording by discharging the ink from the recording head. By utilizing the present invention, the time required for recovering the recording head can be shortened, whereby there can be obtained an inkjet recording apparatus with which the user waiting time is shorter, and the usability is more excellent. In addition, an inkjet recording apparatus can be obtained which can suppress clogging of the ink discharge nozzle and poor printing due to sucking back a viscosity-increased ink or foreign matters discharged from the ink discharge nozzle.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An inkjet recording apparatus, comprising:
<claim-text>a recording head having a common flow-passage possessing an inflow port at one end and an outflow port at the other end, and a plurality of nozzles communicating with the common flow-passage and discharging ink onto a record medium;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an ink tank for reserving the ink to be discharged onto the record medium;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pump mechanism for sucking the ink inside the ink tank and supplying the ink introduced by suction to the recording head;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a circulation flow passage having a first ink-flow passage connecting between the pump mechanism and the ink tank, a second ink-flow passage connecting between the pump mechanism and the inflow port of the recording head, and a third ink-flow passage connecting between the outflow port of the recording head and the ink tank;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an inflow side valve provided in the second ink-flow passage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an outflow side valve provided in the third common flow passage; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a damper portion formed in the ink-flow passage from the inflow side valve to the outflow side valve for buffering a change in internal pressure caused by an operation of the pump mechanism,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the inkjet recording apparatus being capable of implementing an operation of removing air bubbles in the recording head, the operation including:</claim-text>
<claim-text>the ink supply step of supplying the ink to the common flow-passage by using the pump mechanism for pressurizing the ink in the state in which movement of the ink inside the second ink-flow passage is tolerated with the inflow side valve, and movement of the ink inside the third ink-flow passage is restricted with the outflow side valve;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the ink ejection step of ejecting, after start of the ink supply step, the ink together with the air bubbles inside the common flow-passage from the outflow port into the third ink-flow passage by tolerating movement of the ink inside the third ink-flow passage with the outflow side valve; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the refilling step of, after termination of the ink ejection step, refilling the ink into the pump mechanism from the ink tank through the first ink-flow passage in the state in which movement of the ink inside the second ink-flow passage is restricted with the inflow side valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The inkjet recording apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the ink ejection step is started before the ink supply step is terminated.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The inkjet recording apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein, after termination of the ink ejection step, movement of the ink inside the third ink-flow passage is restricted with the outflow side valve before the refilling step is started.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The inkjet recording apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein an operation of removing air bubbles in the recording head is performed separately of an operation of recovering the recording head by forcedly discharging the ink from the plurality of nozzles.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The inkjet recording apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein an operation of removing air bubbles in the recording head is performed together with an operation of recovering the recording head by forcedly discharging the ink from the plurality of nozzles.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The inkjet recording apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the outflow side valve is a three-way valve, and a waste fluid tank is connected to the third ink-flow passage through the outflow valve.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The inkjet recording apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the inflow side valve is a three-way valve, and the second ink-flow passage is connected to the first ink-flow passage through the inflow side valve.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A method for removing air bubbles in an inkjet recording apparatus, the inkjet recording apparatus including:
<claim-text>a recording head having a common flow-passage possessing an inflow port at one end and an outflow port at the other end, and a plurality of nozzles communicating with the common flow-passage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an ink tank;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pump mechanism for supplying ink inside the ink tank to the recording head;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a circulation flow passage having a first ink-flow passage connecting between the pump mechanism and the ink tank, a second ink-flow passage connecting between the pump mechanism and the inflow port of the recording head, and a third ink-flow passage connecting between the outflow port of the recording head and the ink tank;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an inflow side valve provided in the second ink-flow passage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an outflow side valve provided in the third ink-flow passage; and a damper portion formed in the common flow-passage from the inflow side valve to the outflow side valve for buffering a change in internal pressure caused by an operation of the pump mechanism,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the method comprising:</claim-text>
<claim-text>the ink supply step of supplying the ink to the common flow-passage by using the pump mechanism for pressurizing the ink in the state in which movement of the ink inside the second ink-flow passage is tolerated with the inflow side valve, and movement of the ink inside the third ink-flow passage is restricted with the outflow side valve;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the ink ejection step of ejecting, after start of the ink supply step, the ink together with the air bubbles inside the common flow-passage from the outflow port into the third ink-flow passage by tolerating movement of the ink inside the third ink-flow passage with the outflow side valve; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the refilling step of, after termination of the ink ejection step, refilling the ink into the pump mechanism from the ink tank through the first ink-flow passage in the state in which movement of the ink inside the second ink-flow passage is restricted with the inflow side valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method for removing air bubbles in an inkjet recording apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the ink ejection step is started before the ink supply step is terminated.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method for removing air bubbles in an inkjet recording apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein, after termination of the ink ejection step, movement of the ink inside the third ink-flow passage is restricted with the outflow side valve before the refilling step is started.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method for removing air bubbles in an inkjet recording apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein an operation of removing air bubbles in the recording head is performed separately of an operation of recovering the recording head by forcedly discharging the ink from the plurality of nozzles.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method for removing air bubbles in an inkjet recording apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein an operation of removing air bubbles in the recording head is performed together with an operation of recovering the recording head by forcedly discharging the ink from the plurality of nozzles.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. An inkjet recording apparatus, comprising:
<claim-text>a recording head having a common flow-passage possessing an inflow port at one end and an outflow port at the other end, and a plurality of nozzles communicating with the common flow-passage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an ink tank;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pump mechanism for supplying ink inside the ink tank to the recording head;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a circulation flow passage having a first ink-flow passage connecting between the pump mechanism and the ink tank, a second ink-flow passage connecting between the pump mechanism and the inflow port of the recording head, and a third ink-flow passage connecting between the outflow port of the recording head and the ink tank;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an inflow side valve provided in the second ink-flow passage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an outflow side valve provided in the third ink-flow passage; and a damper portion formed in the common flow-passage from the inflow side valve to the outflow side valve for buffering a change in internal pressure caused by an operation of the pump mechanism,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the inkjet recording apparatus being capable of implementing:</claim-text>
<claim-text>the ink supply step of supplying the ink to the common flow-passage by using the pump mechanism for pressurizing the ink in the state in which movement of the ink inside the second ink-flow passage is tolerated with the inflow side valve, and movement of the ink inside the third ink-flow passage is restricted with the outflow side valve;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the ink ejection step of ejecting, after start of the ink supply step, the ink together with air bubbles inside the common flow-passage from the outflow port into the third ink-flow passage by tolerating movement of the ink inside the third ink-flow passage with the outflow side valve; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the refilling step of, after termination of the ink ejection step, refilling the ink into the pump mechanism from the ink tank through the first ink-flow passage in the state in which movement of the ink inside the second ink-flow passage is restricted with the inflow side valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The inkjet recording apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the ink ejection step is started before the ink supply step is terminated.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The inkjet recording apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein, after termination of the ink ejection step, movement of the ink inside the third ink-flow passage is restricted with the outflow side valve before the refilling step is started.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The inkjet recording apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein an operation of removing air bubbles in the recording head is performed separately of an operation of recovering the recording head by forcedly discharging the ink from the plurality of nozzles.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The inkjet recording apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein an operation of removing air bubbles in the recording head is performed together with an operation of recovering the recording head by forcedly discharging the ink from the plurality of nozzles. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
