<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624112-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624112</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13298408</doc-number>
<date>20111117</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2011 1 0215786</doc-number>
<date>20110729</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>25</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>174 50</main-classification>
<further-classification>439135</further-classification>
<further-classification>36167902</further-classification>
<further-classification>36167901</further-classification>
<further-classification>3122231</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Shell assembly and assembly method thereof</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7530822</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Liao</name>
<date>20090500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439135</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8023264</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Shen et al.</name>
<date>20110900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36167958</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>10</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>174 50</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439135</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36167901</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>3122231</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130025902</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130131</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yang</last-name>
<first-name>Nai-Lin</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Zhou</last-name>
<first-name>Xiao-Meng</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gong</last-name>
<first-name>Wei</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yang</last-name>
<first-name>Nai-Lin</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Zhou</last-name>
<first-name>Xiao-Meng</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gong</last-name>
<first-name>Wei</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Shenzhen Futaihong Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>FIH (Hong Kong) Limited</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Kowloon</city>
<country>HK</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Patel</last-name>
<first-name>Dhirubhai R</first-name>
<department>2848</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A shell assembly includes a first shell having a plurality of elastic sheets mounted, and a second shell defining a plurality of securing grooves. The elastic sheets are capable of deforming and latching in the securing grooves, detachably latching the first shell and the second shell. An assembly method for assembling the shell assembly is also disclosed.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="72.05mm" wi="159.68mm" file="US08624112-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="229.79mm" wi="145.37mm" file="US08624112-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="171.20mm" wi="127.08mm" file="US08624112-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="180.09mm" wi="150.79mm" file="US08624112-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="172.04mm" wi="158.58mm" file="US08624112-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to a shell assembly and an assembly method thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Portable electronic devices such as mobile phones usually include two shells assembled together to secure a display screen between the shells. The two shells may be fixed with each other by heating a thermal bonding film positioned therebetween. However, heating the thermal bonding film makes the assembly process more complex. Furthermore, if the display screen needs to be replaced, one of the two shells will have to be damaged to remove the display screen.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Therefore, there is room for improvement within the art.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Many aspects of the present shell assembly and assembly method thereof can be better understood with reference to the following drawings. The components in the drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the present shell assembly and assembly method thereof. Moreover, in the drawings, like reference numerals designate corresponding parts throughout the several views.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an exploded view of a shell assembly according to an exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an enlarge view of an elastic sheet shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an assembled view of the shell assembly shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a partial cross-sectional view of the shell assembly shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> along line IV-IV.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>3</b> and <b>4</b> show an exemplary shell assembly <b>10</b> for use in portable electronic device <b>100</b> such as a mobile phone. The shell assembly <b>10</b> includes a first shell <b>12</b> and a second shell <b>14</b> mounted with the first shell <b>12</b>. Adhesive members <b>16</b> (such as double-faced adhesive tapes) are provided to adhere the first shell <b>12</b> to the second shell <b>14</b>. A display screen can be mounted between the first shell <b>12</b> and the second shell <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The first shell <b>12</b> includes a shell body <b>122</b> and six elastic sheets <b>124</b>. The shell body <b>122</b> and the elastic sheets <b>124</b> can be made of metal materials such as stainless steel. The elastic sheets <b>124</b> can be fixed to the shell body <b>122</b> by welding. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> further shows each elastic sheet <b>124</b> including a securing section <b>1242</b>, two opposite connecting sections <b>1244</b>, and two opposite latching sections <b>1246</b>. The securing section <b>1242</b> is used for securing the elastic sheet <b>124</b> to the shell body <b>122</b>. The two connecting sections <b>1244</b> curvedly extending at a substantially right angle from two opposite ends of the securing section <b>1242</b>, respectively. Each latching section <b>1246</b> extends from the end of the respective connecting section <b>1244</b> distal to the securing section <b>1242</b>. The latching section <b>1246</b> is used for latching with the second shell <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the second shell <b>14</b> defines securing grooves <b>142</b> corresponding to the elastic sheets <b>124</b>. Each securing groove <b>142</b> is enclosed by a bottom wall <b>1422</b> and a peripheral wall <b>1424</b> connecting to the bottom wall <b>1422</b>. The peripheral wall <b>1424</b> has two opposite latching portions <b>1426</b> protruding for latching with the latching sections <b>1246</b>, and thus defines two latching slots <b>1428</b> between the latching portions <b>1426</b> and the bottom wall <b>1422</b>. When the elastic sheet <b>124</b> is latched on the second shell <b>14</b>, the latching sections <b>1246</b> are latched by the latching portions <b>1426</b> and into the latching slots <b>1428</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">During assembly of the shell assembly <b>10</b>, the securing section <b>1242</b> can be welded to the shell body <b>122</b>, fixing each elastic sheet <b>124</b> to the shell body <b>122</b>. The elastic sheets <b>124</b> are spaced from each other. The adhesive members <b>16</b> are attached between each two adjacent sheets <b>124</b> and onto the shell body <b>122</b>. The first shell <b>12</b> is aligned with the second shell <b>14</b> with the elastic sheets <b>124</b> aligned to face the securing grooves <b>142</b>. The first shell <b>12</b> is pressed to fit with the second shell <b>14</b>, urging the elastic sheets <b>124</b> to be deformed by resisting of the latching portions <b>1426</b> and secured into the securing grooves <b>142</b>. At this time, the elastic sheets <b>124</b> and the first shell <b>12</b> are latched to the second shell <b>14</b> by the latching between the latching sections <b>1246</b> and the latching portions <b>1426</b>. The first shell <b>12</b> can be fixed to the second shell <b>14</b> by pressing the shell body <b>122</b> against the second shell <b>14</b>, until the adhesive members <b>16</b> adhere the two shells <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> together. The assembly of the shell assembly <b>10</b> is completed.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">It is to be understood that even though numerous characteristics and advantages of the present embodiments have been set forth in the foregoing description, together with details of assemblies and functions of various embodiments, the disclosure is illustrative only, and changes may be made in detail, especially in matters of shape, size, and arrangement of parts within the principles of the present disclosure to the full extent indicated by the broad general meaning of the terms in which the appended claims are expressed.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A shell assembly, comprising:
<claim-text>a first shell having a shell body and a plurality of elastic sheets, each of said elastic sheets including a securing section, two opposite connecting sections extending at a substantially right angle from the securing section, and two opposite latching sections extending from ends of the two connecting sections distal to the securing section, the securing section of each of said elastic sheets welded to the shell body; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second shell defining a plurality of securing grooves, each of the securing grooves enclosed by a bottom wall and a peripheral wall connecting to the bottom wall, the peripheral wall having two opposite latching portions protruding from the peripheral wall, the latching sections of the elastic sheets capable of deforming and latching with the latching portions, thereby detachably latching the first shell and the second shell.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The shell assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the shell assembly further comprises adhesive members, the adhesive members are attached on the first shell and adhered between the second shell and the first shell.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The shell assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the elastic sheets are welded to the first shell.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The shell assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first shell and the elastic sheet are made of metal materials.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The shell assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the peripheral wall defines two latching slots between the latching portions and the bottom wall; when the elastic sheets are latched on the second shell, the latching sections are latched by the latching portions and into the latching slots.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. An assembly method for assembling a shell assembly, comprising:
<claim-text>providing a first shell and a plurality of elastic sheets, the first shell having a shell body, each of said elastic sheets including a securing section, two opposite connecting sections extending at a substantially right angle from the securing section, and two opposite latching sections extending from ends of the two connecting sections distal to the securing section;</claim-text>
<claim-text>welding the securing section of each of the elastic sheets to the first shell;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a second shell defining a plurality of securing grooves corresponding to the elastic sheets, each of the securing grooves enclosed by a bottom wall and a peripheral wall connecting to the bottom wall, the peripheral wall having two opposite latching portions protruding from the peripheral wall;</claim-text>
<claim-text>pressing the first shell and the second shell towards with each other, latching the latching sections of the elastic sheets into the securing grooves to latch with the latching portions.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The assembly method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>providing adhesive members;</claim-text>
<claim-text>attaching each adhesive member between each two adjacent sheets and onto the first shell before pressing the first shell and the second shell;</claim-text>
<claim-text>after latching the elastic sheets into the securing grooves, further pressing the first shell against the second shell, until the adhesive members adhere the first and second shells as a whole.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The assembly method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, further comprising welding the elastic sheet to the first shell.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The assembly method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the first shell and the elastic sheets are made of metal materials.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The assembly method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the peripheral wall defines two latching slots between the latching portions and the bottom wall; when the elastic sheets are latched on the second shell, the latching sections are latched by the latching portions and into the latching slots. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
