<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625235-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625235</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13929181</doc-number>
<date>20130627</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>11</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>31</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36012515</main-classification>
<further-classification>36012514</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Perpendicular magnetic recording write head with milling defined track width</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7251878</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Le et al.</name>
<date>20070800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7337530</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Stoev et al.</name>
<date>20080300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7394621</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Li et al.</name>
<date>20080700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7672079</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Li et al.</name>
<date>20100300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0277832</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Bai et al.</name>
<date>20101100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36012503</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>8</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>3601251</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36012511</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36012514</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36012515</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>20</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12799927</doc-number>
<date>20100505</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8477453</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13929181</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130286508</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20131031</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Headway Technologies, Inc</orgname>
<address>
<city>Milpitas</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Takano</last-name>
<first-name>Kenichi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Nagano</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Zhou</last-name>
<first-name>Yuchen</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Li</last-name>
<first-name>Min</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fremont</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="004" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Smyth</last-name>
<first-name>Joe</first-name>
<address>
<city>Aptos</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Saile Ackerman LLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ackerman</last-name>
<first-name>Stephen B.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Headway Technologies, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Milpitas</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Renner</last-name>
<first-name>Craig A.</first-name>
<department>2688</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A main pole layer having at least a leading taper and trimmed pole tip portion is described. The leading taper increases head field up to &#x2267;15000 Oe even for narrow track widths approaching 50 nm. For MAMR applications, a STO and trailing shield are sequentially formed on a trailing pole tip side. Furthermore, full side shields may be added to reduce fringing field. A preferred embodiment includes both of a leading taper and trailing taper at the pole tip where leading taper angle is between 20&#xb0; and 60&#xb0; and trailing taper angle is from 10&#xb0; to 45&#xb0;. A method is provided for forming various embodiments of the present invention. A key feature is that milling depth at an effective neck height distance is greater than or equal to the pole tip thickness. A self aligned STO may be formed by the same ion milling step that defines track width.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="90.17mm" wi="197.95mm" file="US08625235-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="247.99mm" wi="128.10mm" file="US08625235-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="257.22mm" wi="189.99mm" file="US08625235-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="253.83mm" wi="114.22mm" file="US08625235-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="231.65mm" wi="156.38mm" file="US08625235-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="234.87mm" wi="137.84mm" file="US08625235-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="235.46mm" wi="117.35mm" file="US08625235-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="196.60mm" wi="125.39mm" file="US08625235-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="207.18mm" wi="129.96mm" file="US08625235-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This is a Divisional application of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 12/799,927, filed on May 5, 2010, which is herein incorporated by reference in its entirety, and assigned to a common assignee.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The invention relates to a main pole in a perpendicular magnetic recording head (PMR) and a method for making the same. In particular, a pole tip region is trimmed to define track width by a milling process and has a leading taper or leading and trailing edge taper so that the main pole becomes thinner at the air bearing surface (ABS) thereby providing large head field and narrow track width.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Perpendicular recording has been developed in part to achieve higher recording density than is realized with longitudinal recording devices. A PMR write head typically has a main pole with a small surface area at an air bearing surface (ABS) and a flux return pole (opposing pole) which is magnetically coupled to the main pole and has a large surface area at the ABS. Critical dimensions of the main pole include a neck height and a pole width in a pole tip adjacent to the ABS. Magnetic flux generated in the main pole layer passes through the pole tip into a magnetic media and then back to the write head by entering the flux return pole.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A PMR magnetic recording head combined with a double layered media has enabled numerous advancements in the technology and a continuous increase in hard disk drive (HDD) recording density beyond 100 Gb/in<sup>2</sup>. However, as track width shrinks, the write field decreases due to a small pole tip area and pole tip saturation if head-media spacing reduction cannot be applied suitably. As a result, this situation imposes a difficult challenge to achieve 1 Tb/in<sup>2</sup>. Thus, the lack of a strong write field limits current narrow track recording and presents an earlier obstacle for areal density growth than reaching the media super paramagnetic limit.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Fortunately, new technology options are being explored that promise to provide areal density growth beyond the aforementioned limits. New developments such as bit patterned magnetic recording (BPMR) and heat assisted magnetic recording (HAMR) are attractive but come with considerable risk and significant challenges in terms of manufacturing process, cost, and reliability. On the other hand, another candidate known as microwave assisted magnetic recording (MAMR) is expected to be easier and more practical to implement because the additional component is only a spin torque oscillator (STO) in PMR heads with conventional PMR media. The STO manufacturing process is essentially the same as for current tunnel magnetoresistive (TMR) heads, but is fabricated in the trailing gap between the main pole and trailing shield. Therefore, the main pole and STO must be integrated with the same or similar track width.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> part (a), a wide main pole <b>2</b> is shown with a narrow STO <b>1</b><i>a </i>having a width w that is substantially less than the width of the trailing edge <b>2</b><i>t </i>of the main pole along the cross track (x-axis) direction. Note that the main pole <b>2</b> and STO <b>1</b><i>a </i>move in a down track (z-axis) direction over a magnetic media to produce wide written tracks <b>3</b> having a width that essentially corresponds to the width of the trailing edge <b>2</b><i>t</i>. Since the field generation layer (FGL) of the STO is very thin and field amplitude is limited, the switching field reduction of the media is also limited. In conventional designs, the main pole has to be able to write without any assist but in MAMR designs, the assist by the STO brings further improvement to writing performance. Consequently, it is an advantage for both of the main pole and STO to have a narrow track design. For example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> part (b), STO <b>1</b><i>b </i>has a width w<b>1</b> essentially equal to that of the trailing edge of main pole <b>4</b>. In part (c), STO <b>1</b><i>c </i>has a width w<b>2</b> slightly less than main pole <b>4</b>, and in part (d), STO <b>1</b><i>d </i>has a width w<b>3</b> slightly larger than the trailing edge of main pole <b>4</b>. As a result, each of the main pole/STO configurations represented in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> parts (b)-(d) are able to write narrow tracks <b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">A search of the prior art was performed to identify main pole structures having a narrow pole tip made by ion milling. In U.S. Pat. No. 7,394,621, a method is disclosed for trimming a pole tip by ion milling. The main pole which is not tapered at the ABS is trimmed and then a top yoke is fabricated on the main pole to define a neck height for the pole tip portion.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">U.S. Pat. No. 7,337,530 teaches a trimmed and side beveled pole tip where a shield layer is used as a mask to trim the write pole. The S<b>3</b> shield is trimmed concurrently with the write pole to simplify the manufacturing process and has essentially the same width as the track width of the write pole.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In U.S. Patent Application 2006/0044677, the trailing edge of a pole tip is on a trimmed rectangular shaped portion of the write pole while the leading edge is on a trapezoidal shaped portion of the write pole.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">U.S. Patent Application 2006/0002024 describes a write pole with a leading edge taper.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Unfortunately, there is no prior art method available that can be relied upon to fabricate a narrow main pole having a track width approaching 50 nm and an overlying STO having a similar width for MAMR applications. Furthermore, a narrow main pole/STO design is needed that enables a large field at the ABS while minimizing side track erasure.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">One objective of the present invention is to provide a PMR write head with a main pole that has a trimmed width at the ABS of about 50 nm and at least a leading edge taper such that the milling depth at the back end of the pole tip portion is greater than or equal to the pole tip thickness at the ABS.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">A second objective of the present invention is to form a leading taper on the pole tip portion according to the first objective and with a taper angle that generates a write field (Heff) of about 15000 Oe and minimizes side track erasure.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Another objective of the present invention is to provide a PMR head having a main pole with leading edge taper on a pole tip portion according to the first two objectives that also includes side shields to suppress the fringing field on adjacent tracks, and includes a STO on the trailing side of the pole tip portion to enable a microwave assisted magnetic recording (MAMR) capability.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">These objectives are achieved in a first embodiment of the present invention wherein a main pole is fabricated with a top surface that is essentially planar and perpendicular to the ABS at the trailing edge of the pole tip, a pole tip having a first distance between a trailing edge and leading edge at the ABS, and a tapered side that extends from the leading edge to a bottom surface of the main pole where the bottom surface is essentially planar and formed parallel to the top surface. The pole tip has a track width defined by the width of the trailing edge at the ABS, and has two sides that extend a neck height distance in a direction perpendicular to the ABS and terminate at a first plane formed parallel to the ABS. Thus, a top surface of the pole tip including the trailing edge is coplanar with the top surface of the main pole. There is a bottom surface of the pole tip with a first section adjacent to the ABS that is part of the tapered leading edge of the main pole, and with a second section formed parallel to the top surface that connects the first section to the first plane. As a result of an ion milling process that trims the pole width, there is an exposed surface of the main pole formed coplanar with the second bottom section on either side of the pole tip. The exposed main pole surface has a front edge that extends from the junction of the tapered side and second bottom section in a cross-track direction for a second distance to a long side that is formed perpendicular to the front edge and extends from the front edge to a second plane. The second plane is parallel to the first plane and is on the opposite side of the first plane with respect to the ABS. The two sides of the main pole which are formed between the exposed main pole surface and top surface are each comprised of two sidewall sections which intersect at the first plane and form an angle greater than 90 degrees. Thus, the distance between the two sides of the main pole along the second plane where the second sidewall terminates is greater than the distance between the two sides along the first plane where the pole tip portion terminates.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">According to the first embodiment, the PMR head may be further comprised of a STO adjoining the top surface (trailing side) of the pole tip and having a width along the ABS substantially the same as that of the trailing edge. In addition, the PMR head may also include a trailing shield that extends from the ABS along the STO top surface and above a substantial portion of the main pole top surface. Moreover, there may be a full side shield proximate to each side of the pole tip to suppress the fringing field on adjacent tracks. The side shields may connect with the trailing shield.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In a second embodiment, the main pole layer described in the first embodiment is modified to include a tapered trailing edge that extends from the trailing edge of the pole tip to the top surface of the main pole and thereby forms a trailing tapered side that is comprised of three sections. A first section is the top surface of the pole tip portion and extends from the ABS to the first plane. A second section of the trailing tapered side extends from the first plane to the second plane, and a third section connects the second section with the top surface of the main pole. A STO may be formed along the first section of the trailing tapered side in a MAMR embodiment. There is preferably a trailing shield formed on the STO top surface and along a substantial portion of the trailing tapered side such that the side of the trailing shield facing the main pole layer conforms to the trailing tapered side. Furthermore, the second embodiment encompasses side shields proximate to the two sides of the pole tip as in the first embodiment. The side shields may be connected to the trailing shield.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The MAMR structure of the first embodiment may be formed by sequentially depositing a first insulation layer, etch stop layer, and a second insulation layer on a substrate. The two insulation layers may be comprised of alumina and share a common front side that is essentially parallel to the ABS formed in a subsequent step. The second insulation layer is patterned by a reactive ion etch (RIE) step to generate a tapered back side where a bottom surface of the second insulation layer that adjoins the etch stop layer extends a greater distance from the front side than the top surface of the second insulation layer. Thereafter, the main pole layer is deposited on the second insulation layer and on exposed portions of the etch stop layer. A first ion beam milling step is performed to define a track width along the front side of the insulation layer/main pole stack. The ion milling step extends a sufficient distance from the front side to trim a section of main pole layer along the top of the tapered back side of the second insulation layer. Moreover, the ion milling depth is equal to or greater than the pole tip thickness at the ABS. Next, a lapping process is performed to define the ABS by removing a section of the insulation layer/main pole stack adjacent to the front side of said stack.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">A method for forming the PMR head of the second embodiment is similar to that for the first embodiment except a first IBE milling step is inserted after the main pole deposition and before the milling step that defines track width. The first IBE milling step forms the trailing tapered side while the second milling step which defines track width has a milling depth greater than or equal to the pole width thickness at the ABS.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> parts (a)-(d) are cross-sectional views showing various main pole/STO configurations along the ABS and corresponding tracks written by each configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>a </i>is an oblique view of a main pole having a leading edge taper and with a pole tip trimmed according to a first embodiment of the present invention, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>b </i>shows a cross-sectional view of the main pole in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>a </i>and an overlying STO and trailing shield from a plane that is perpendicular to the ABS.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a top view of the main pole with trimmed pole tip depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a view from the ABS of the main pole in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>b </i>that has been modified to include side shields according to a second embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a </i>is an oblique view of a main pole having leading and trailing edge tapers and with a pole tip trimmed according to a third embodiment of the present invention, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>b </i>shows a cross-sectional view of the main pole in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a </i>and an overlying STO and trailing shield from a plane that is perpendicular to the ABS.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a top view of the main pole with trimmed pole tip depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a view from the ABS of the main pole in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>b </i>that has been modified to include side shields according to a fourth embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a plot of calculated write field (H<sub>eff</sub>) and gap field (H<sub>gap</sub>) as a function of leading taper angle in the main pole of the first embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is plot of write field (H<sub>eff</sub>) as a function of write current for the main pole structures of the first and third embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> shows a cross track profile of the write field for the main pole of the first embodiment, and for the second embodiment that has side shields present.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> shows a cross track profile of the write field for the main pole of the third embodiment, and for the fourth embodiment that has side shields present.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12-14</figref> are cross-sectional views depicting a sequence of steps used to fabricate a main pole having a leading edge taper and with a trimmed pole tip according to a first embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 15-18</figref> are cross-sectional views depicting a sequence of steps used to fabricate a main pole having a leading edge taper, a trailing edge taper, and with a trimmed pole tip according to a third embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The present invention is a PMR write head for use with magnetic storage media in a disk drive that provides a narrow track width and high head field with minimal side track erasure. A key feature is a main pole layer having at least a leading edge taper and with a track width defined by an ion milling step confined to the pole tip portion where the milling depth is greater than or equal to the thickness of the pole tip at the ABS. The exemplary embodiments include a STO between the pole tip and a trailing shield for MAMR applications. However, those skilled in the art will appreciate that the main pole with trimmed pole tip as described herein may be implemented in general for any PMR write head and is especially beneficial in providing a narrow track width of around 50 nm or less with a high head field. The PMR write head of the present invention may include side shields that connect with the trailing shield. The present invention is also a method for forming a main pole layer having a leading edge taper, or both of a leading edge taper and trailing edge taper, and with a track width defined by an ion milling process.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>a</i>, an oblique view is shown of a main pole layer <b>11</b> having a trimmed pole tip <b>11</b><i>p </i>according to a first embodiment of the present invention. Surrounding layers including insulation layers and an overlying STO and trailing shield are not depicted in order to simplify the drawing and point out the important aspects of the main pole. The main pole <b>11</b> has a planar top surface <b>11</b><i>t </i>formed perpendicular to the pole tip <b>11</b><i>p </i>at the trailing edge <b>11</b><i>b</i>, and a bottom surface <b>11</b><i>v </i>aligned parallel to the top surface. The bottom surface is connected to the leading edge <b>11</b><i>a </i>of the pole tip <b>11</b><i>p </i>by a tapered leading side <b>11</b><i>n </i>which intersects the bottom surface along a plane <b>20</b>-<b>20</b> that is parallel to pole tip <b>11</b><i>p </i>(and the ABS which is not shown). There is only one intersection point <b>12</b> along plane <b>20</b>-<b>20</b> visible from the oblique view. The pole tip thickness which is the distance between leading edge <b>11</b><i>a </i>and trailing edge <b>11</b><i>b </i>is from about 40 nm to 100 nm.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">A key feature is the pole tip portion that extends from the pole tip <b>11</b><i>p </i>in a direction perpendicular to the ABS and terminates along a first plane (not shown) that is parallel to the pole tip <b>11</b><i>p </i>and includes edge <b>16</b><i>b </i>along each side of the main pole. Thus, there is a side <b>11</b><i>s </i>connecting pole tip <b>11</b><i>p </i>to the first plane along each side of the main pole <b>11</b>. Sides <b>11</b><i>s </i>also connect the top surface of the pole tip region to a bottom surface that includes a tapered section <b>11</b><i>d</i>. In other words, the bottom surface of the pole tip <b>11</b><i>p </i>has a first section <b>11</b><i>d </i>formed along leading tapered side <b>11</b><i>n </i>and that extends from the leading edge <b>11</b><i>a </i>to an edge <b>13</b> where the first section intersects a front edge of a main pole surface <b>11</b><i>c</i>. As explained in a later section, main pole surface <b>11</b><i>c </i>is a planar surface formed on either side of the pole tip portion during an ion milling process that defines the track width (width of trailing edge <b>11</b><i>b</i>). A second section of the bottom surface of the pole tip portion is comprised of a planar surface <b>16</b><i>a </i>(<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>b</i>) formed parallel to top surface <b>11</b><i>t </i>and between the edges determined by the intersection of sides <b>11</b><i>s </i>with main pole surface <b>11</b><i>c</i>. Therefore, the second section of the pole tip bottom surface is coplanar with main pole surface <b>11</b><i>c </i>and is formed between sides <b>11</b><i>s</i>, and between edge <b>13</b> and the back end of the pole tip portion along the first plane as will be explained in more detail later with regard to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> which is a top view of the main pole shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>b</i>, a cross-sectional view of the main pole <b>11</b> is illustrated from a plane (not shown) formed perpendicular to the pole tip <b>11</b><i>p </i>and extending toward a back end of the main pole. In the exemplary embodiment that relates to a PMR write head for a MAMR application, there is a spin torque oscillator (STO) <b>18</b> contacting the top surface <b>11</b><i>t </i>of the main pole and extending for a certain distance from the ABS <b>15</b>-<b>15</b>. In one aspect, the STO <b>18</b> may extend the same neck height (NH) distance from the ABS as the pole tip portion that terminates at edge <b>16</b><i>b </i>along the first plane. Furthermore, the trailing shield <b>14</b> has a surface <b>14</b><i>s </i>facing the main pole <b>11</b> that is formed on the trailing side of STO <b>18</b> where the STO trailing side is defined as a side opposite the main pole top surface <b>11</b><i>t. </i></p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">An important feature is that the taper angle &#x3b2; formed between tapered leading side <b>11</b><i>n </i>and the ABS <b>15</b>-<b>15</b> is between 20 and 60 degrees, and preferably greater than 30 degrees in order to produce a sufficiently high head field of about 15000 Oe. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the taper angle &#x3b2; relationship to the write field (H<sub>eff</sub>) at the media and to the gap field (H<sub>gap</sub>) at the FGL is shown for a main pole <b>11</b> represented by <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>b</i>. Note that the gap field is calculated for a STO <b>18</b> having a bottom STO configuration (not shown) wherein a seed layer, spin injection layer (SIL), spacer, and FGL are formed sequentially from bottom to top on the trailing edge <b>11</b><i>b </i>and trailing side (top surface <b>11</b><i>t</i>) of the pole tip region. The definition of the write field is effective head field (N<sub>eff</sub>) in the following equation (1) which is calculated at a media spacing of 17.5 nm from the ABS. H<sub>gap </sub>is calculated for a distance of 25 nm between the top surface <b>11</b><i>t </i>of the pole tip portion and the center of STO <b>18</b> where the STO center is midway between top surface <b>11</b><i>t </i>and trailing shield <b>14</b>.
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>H</i><sub>eff</sub>=(<i>H</i><sub>in</sub><sup>2/3</sup><i>+H</i><sub>y</sub><sup>2/3</sup>)<sup>3/2</sup>&#x2003;&#x2003;(1)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
Here H<sub>in </sub>is in-plane and H<sub>y </sub>is the perpendicular component of the head field to the media. When the taper angle is 0 degrees, the resulting write field is below 7000 Oe which is too weak to write PMR media. By introducing a leading edge taper and a tapered leading side <b>11</b><i>n</i>, the write field (curve <b>50</b>) increases as taper angle increases and reaches 15000 Oe at a taper angle &#x3b2; of 40 degrees which corresponds to the current PMR media anisotropy field at room temperature. Therefore, the main pole <b>11</b> of the first embodiment is able to provide a large enough write field and gap field (curve <b>51</b>) even with a narrow track width of about 50 nm or less.
</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Returning to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>b</i>, the cross-sectional view of the milling depth resulting from the ion milling step that trims pole tip <b>11</b><i>p </i>is depicted. Edge <b>16</b><i>b </i>in this embodiment is formed along the first plane (not shown) and is the same distance from the ABS <b>15</b>-<b>15</b> as the back side of STO <b>18</b> which is the side formed opposite the ABS. The milling depth is defined as the distance between top surface <b>11</b><i>t </i>and pole tip bottom surface <b>16</b><i>a </i>that is coplanar with main pole surface <b>11</b><i>c </i>in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>a</i>. Note that the thickness of the pole tip <b>11</b><i>p </i>(distance between leading edge <b>11</b><i>a </i>and trailing edge <b>11</b><i>b</i>) is less than the milling depth. In other words, the distance along edge <b>16</b><i>b </i>between top surface <b>11</b><i>t </i>and a second section of the pole tip portion bottom surface that is coplanar with main pole surface <b>11</b><i>c </i>is greater than the pole tip thickness in the exemplary embodiment. In an alternative embodiment (not shown) where the lapping process forms an ABS at the intersection of pole tip bottom surface <b>16</b><i>a </i>and tapered side <b>11</b><i>n</i>, then the milling depth will be essentially equal to the thickness of the pole tip <b>11</b><i>p </i>at the ABS.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a top view of the main pole <b>11</b> of the first embodiment is depicted with overlying layers including trailing shield <b>14</b> and STO <b>18</b> removed. Main pole surface <b>11</b><i>c </i>adjacent to sides <b>11</b><i>s </i>has a front edge <b>11</b><i>f </i>formed parallel to the ABS <b>15</b>-<b>15</b> and separated therefrom by a distance m which varies depending on taper angle &#x3b2;. Main pole surface <b>11</b><i>c </i>is bounded by side <b>11</b><i>s </i>between front edge <b>11</b><i>f </i>and the first plane <b>21</b>-<b>21</b> and by a side <b>11</b><i>r </i>between plane <b>21</b>-<b>21</b> and second plane <b>22</b>-<b>22</b>. Front edge <b>11</b><i>f </i>extends a distance v from side <b>11</b><i>s </i>along the y-axis direction or parallel to the ABS <b>15</b>-<b>15</b> and represents one half of the pole tip width removed during the ion milling process that defines the track width. Main pole surface <b>11</b><i>c </i>has a long side <b>11</b><i>e </i>that is parallel to the x-axis (perpendicular to the ABS) and which connects front edge <b>11</b><i>f </i>to plane <b>22</b>-<b>22</b> at intersection point <b>17</b>. The angle &#x3b1; formed by the intersection of sides <b>11</b><i>s </i>and <b>11</b><i>r </i>is preferably greater than 90 degrees and less than 180 degrees. Pole tip portion bounded by sides <b>11</b><i>s</i>, pole tip <b>11</b><i>p</i>, and plane <b>21</b>-<b>21</b> extends a distance h<b>1</b> which is effectively the neck height (NH) of about 70 nm from the ABS. The distance h<b>2</b> between first plane <b>21</b>-<b>21</b> and second plane <b>22</b>-<b>22</b> is from 0 to 70 nm. Therefore, the length of side <b>11</b><i>e </i>of main pole surface <b>11</b><i>c </i>is equal to [(h<b>1</b>+h<b>2</b>)&#x2212;m]. Note that NH may vary from about 40 to 100 nm and is preferably equal to or greater than the distance that the STO <b>18</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>b</i>) extends from the ABS.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">According to a second embodiment of the present invention, the PMR head structure shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>b </i>may further include side shields <b>28</b> as seen from an ABS view in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. Otherwise, all the main pole features of the first embodiment are retained in the second embodiment. As appreciated by those skilled in the art, the addition of side shields is beneficial in suppressing the fringe field and thereby minimizing side track erasure. Preferably, each side shield <b>28</b> is a full side shield that extends from trailing shield <b>14</b> in a down track direction along the z-axis direction to substrate <b>8</b> that may be an insulation layer, for example. Thus, leading edge <b>11</b><i>a </i>and the interface of each side shield <b>28</b> with substrate <b>8</b> are essentially coplanar. Although the exemplary embodiment shows pole tip sides <b>11</b><i>s </i>formed at an angle &#x3b4; of 90 degrees with respect to leading edge <b>11</b><i>a</i>, the present invention also anticipates that angle &#x3b4; may be between 90 and 100 degrees (not shown) to compensate for a well known skew effect. As a result, the length (track width) of trailing edge <b>11</b><i>b </i>along the x-axis direction will be larger than the length of leading edge <b>11</b><i>a</i>. However, it should be understood that as the leading taper angle increases, the amount of side track erasure is adequately controlled even in an embodiment where &#x3b4; is 90 degrees. Moreover, STO <b>18</b> is preferably self aligned to pole tip lip. Side gap <b>29</b> is made of a dielectric material and separates the sides <b>11</b><i>s </i>and STO <b>18</b> from side shields <b>28</b>. The present invention also encompasses partial side shields (not shown) wherein the side shields contact the trailing shield but do not extend along the full length of the pole tip side <b>11</b><i>s</i>. It should be understood, however, that partial side shields will not provide as much advantage in controlling fringing field as full side shields in the preferred embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, the effectiveness is shown of a side shield structure according to the second embodiment in suppressing the fringing field of a main pole with a trimmed pole tip as previously described. Curve <b>55</b> represents the cross track profile of a write field generated by a main pole <b>11</b> of the first embodiment and curve <b>54</b> indicates how the fringing field decreases when a full side shield structure is incorporated as described in the second embodiment of the present invention. Curve <b>54</b> demonstrates how the write field is substantially decreased at cross-track distances greater than about 0.08 microns from the pole tip.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a</i>, a main pole <b>31</b> formed according to a third embodiment of the present invention is shown from an oblique view and with a cross-sectional view in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>b </i>along a plane that is perpendicular to the ABS <b>35</b>-<b>35</b>. Main pole <b>31</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a </i>has a planar top surface <b>31</b><i>u </i>that does not extend to the ABS at pole tip <b>31</b><i>p </i>but is connected to the trailing edge <b>31</b><i>b </i>of the pole tip by a tapered trailing side <b>31</b><i>t </i>comprised of sections <b>31</b><i>t</i><b>1</b>, <b>31</b><i>t</i><b>2</b>, <b>31</b><i>t</i><b>3</b>. Moreover, main pole <b>31</b> has a bottom surface <b>31</b><i>v </i>aligned parallel to top surface <b>31</b><i>u </i>and connected to the leading edge <b>31</b><i>a </i>by a tapered leading side <b>31</b><i>n</i>. Thus, main pole <b>31</b> is said to have both a leading taper and a trailing taper. Tapered leading side <b>31</b><i>n </i>and bottom surface <b>31</b><i>v </i>intersect along a plane <b>40</b>-<b>40</b> that is aligned parallel to pole tip <b>31</b><i>p</i>. Intersection point <b>32</b> is the only location on the plane <b>40</b>-<b>40</b> that intersects tapered leading side <b>31</b><i>n </i>which is visible from the oblique view in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a</i>. Similar to a leading taper, a trailing taper can bring further enhancement of the write field and gap field and H<sub>eff </sub>increases as the trailing taper angle increases (not shown). Those skilled in the art will appreciate that the third embodiment is a modified version of the first embodiment where the tapered trailing side <b>31</b><i>t </i>is employed instead of a planar top main pole surface that extends all the way to the ABS at the pole tip.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">A key feature is the pole tip portion that extends from the pole tip <b>31</b><i>p </i>in a direction perpendicular to the ABS and terminates along a first plane (not shown) that is parallel to the pole tip <b>31</b><i>p </i>and includes edge <b>36</b><i>b</i><b>1</b> along each side of the main pole. Thus, there are two sides <b>31</b><i>s </i>connecting pole tip <b>31</b><i>p </i>to the first plane. Sides <b>31</b><i>s </i>also connect the top surface of the pole tip portion to a bottom surface that includes a tapered section <b>31</b><i>d</i>. In other words, the bottom surface of the pole tip <b>31</b><i>p </i>has a first section <b>31</b><i>d </i>formed along tapered leading side <b>31</b><i>n </i>and that extends from the leading edge <b>31</b><i>a </i>to an edge <b>33</b> where the first section intersects a front edge of a main pole surface <b>31</b><i>c</i>. As explained in a later section, main pole surface <b>31</b><i>c </i>is a planar surface formed on either side of the pole tip portion during an ion milling process that defines the track width (width of trailing edge <b>31</b><i>b</i>). A second section of the bottom surface of the pole tip portion is comprised of a planar surface formed coplanar to main pole surface <b>31</b><i>c </i>and between the edges determined by the intersection of each side <b>31</b><i>s </i>with main pole surface <b>31</b><i>c</i>. Therefore, the second section of the pole tip bottom surface is formed between sides <b>31</b><i>s</i>, and between edge <b>33</b> and the back end of the pole tip portion along the first plane as will be explained in more detail later with regard to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> which is a top view of the main pole shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>b</i>, a cross-sectional view of the main pole <b>31</b> is illustrated from a plane (not shown) formed perpendicular to the pole tip <b>31</b><i>p </i>and extending toward a back end of the main pole. In the exemplary embodiment that relates to a PMR write head for a MAMR application, there is a spin transfer oscillator (STO) <b>38</b> contacting the top surface <b>31</b><i>t </i>of the main pole and extending for a certain distance from the ABS <b>35</b>-<b>35</b>. In one aspect, the STO <b>38</b> may extend the same NH distance from the ABS as the pole tip portion that terminates at edge <b>36</b><i>b</i><b>1</b>. Alternatively, STO <b>38</b> may extend less than the NH distance from the ABS. Furthermore, the trailing shield <b>34</b> has a surface <b>34</b><i>s </i>facing the main pole <b>31</b> that is formed on the trailing side of STO <b>38</b> where the STO trailing side is defined as a side opposite the main pole top surface <b>31</b><i>t. </i></p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">An important feature is that the leading taper angle &#x3b2; formed between the tapered leading side <b>31</b><i>n </i>and the ABS <b>35</b>-<b>35</b> is between 20 and 60 degrees, and preferably is greater than about 30 degrees in order to produce a sufficiently high head field. When the leading taper angle is 0 degrees, the resulting write field is below 7000 Oe which is too weak to write PMR media. By introducing a leading edge taper with a tapered leading side <b>31</b><i>n</i>, and a trailing edge taper with a tapered trailing side <b>31</b><i>t</i>, the write field increases as leading and trailing taper angles increase and reaches the current PMR media anisotropy field (15000 Oe) when the leading taper angle &#x3b2; is between 20 and 60 degrees and when trailing taper angle &#x3c3; is between 10 and 45 degrees. Therefore, the main pole <b>31</b> is able to provide a large enough write field and gap field even with a narrow track width of about 50 nm or less. Trailing taper angle &#x3c3; is preferably between 10 degrees and 45 degrees and contributes to a larger H<sub>eff </sub>as &#x3c3; increases.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">A cross-sectional view of the milling depth resulting from the ion milling step that trims pole tip <b>31</b><i>p </i>is depicted within the rectangle bounded by dashed line <b>36</b><i>a </i>on the bottom, dashed line <b>36</b><i>b </i>on the left, dashed line <b>36</b><i>c </i>on top, and ABS <b>35</b>-<b>35</b> on the right side. Edge <b>36</b><i>b</i><b>1</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a</i>) is the portion of dashed line <b>36</b><i>b </i>formed between tapered trailing edge <b>31</b><i>t </i>and dashed line <b>36</b><i>a</i>. In this embodiment, edge <b>36</b><i>b</i><b>1</b> and dashed line <b>36</b><i>b </i>are formed the same NH distance from the ABS <b>35</b>-<b>35</b> as the back side of STO <b>38</b> which is the side formed opposite the ABS. The milling depth is defined as the distance along edge <b>36</b><i>b</i><b>1</b> between top surface <b>31</b><i>t </i>and dashed line <b>36</b><i>a</i>. Note that dashed line <b>36</b><i>a </i>is coplanar with main pole surface <b>31</b><i>c </i>(<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a</i>), and the thickness of the pole tip <b>31</b><i>p </i>at the ABS <b>35</b>-<b>35</b> is less than the milling depth. In an alternative embodiment (not shown) where the lapping process forms an ABS at the intersection of dashed line <b>36</b><i>a </i>and tapered side <b>31</b><i>n</i>, then the milling depth will be essentially equal to the thickness of the pole tip <b>31</b><i>p </i>at the ABS.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, a top view of the main pole <b>31</b> of the third embodiment is depicted with overlying layers including trailing shield <b>34</b> and STO <b>38</b> removed. Main pole surface <b>31</b><i>c </i>adjacent to sides <b>31</b><i>s </i>has a front edge <b>31</b><i>f </i>formed parallel to the ABS <b>35</b>-<b>35</b> and separated therefrom by a distance m which depends on the leading taper angle. Main pole surface <b>31</b><i>c </i>is bounded in part by side <b>31</b><i>s </i>between front edge <b>31</b><i>f </i>and plane <b>41</b>-<b>41</b>, and by a side <b>31</b><i>r </i>between first plane <b>41</b>-<b>41</b> and second plane <b>42</b>-<b>42</b>. Front edge <b>31</b><i>f </i>extends a distance v from side <b>31</b><i>s </i>along the y-axis direction or parallel to the ABS <b>35</b>-<b>35</b> and represents one half of the pole tip width removed during the ion milling process that defines the track width. Main pole surface <b>31</b><i>c </i>has a long side <b>31</b><i>e </i>that is parallel to the x-axis (perpendicular to the ABS) and which connects front edge <b>31</b><i>f </i>to plane <b>42</b>-<b>42</b> at intersection point <b>37</b>. Angle &#x3b1; formed by the intersection of sides <b>31</b><i>s </i>and <b>31</b><i>r </i>is preferably greater than 90 degrees and less than 180 degrees. Pole tip portion bounded by sides <b>31</b><i>s</i>, pole tip <b>31</b><i>p</i>, and plane <b>41</b>-<b>41</b> extends a distance h<b>1</b> (neck height) of about 40 to 100 nm from the ABS. The distance h<b>2</b> between first plane <b>41</b>-<b>41</b> and second plane <b>42</b>-<b>42</b> is from 0 to 70 nm. Therefore, the length of side <b>31</b><i>e </i>of main pole surface <b>31</b><i>c </i>is equal to [(h<b>1</b>+h<b>2</b>)&#x2212;m]. The first section <b>31</b><i>t</i><b>1</b> of trailing tapered side <b>31</b><i>t </i>is shown between ABS <b>35</b>-<b>35</b> and the first plane <b>41</b>-<b>41</b> while the second section <b>31</b><i>t</i><b>2</b> of trailing tapered side <b>31</b><i>t </i>is formed between planes <b>41</b>-<b>41</b> and <b>42</b>-<b>42</b>. Third section <b>31</b><i>t</i><b>3</b> of trailing tapered side <b>31</b><i>t </i>connects the second section <b>31</b><i>t</i><b>2</b> with top surface <b>31</b><i>u </i>(<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a</i>).</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">According to a fourth embodiment of the present invention, the PMR head structure shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>b </i>may further include side shields <b>43</b> as seen from an ABS view in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>. Otherwise, all the main pole features of the third embodiment are retained in the fourth embodiment. As mentioned previously, the addition of side shields is beneficial in suppressing the fringe field and thereby minimizing side track erasure. Preferably, each side shield <b>43</b> is a full side shield that extends from trailing shield <b>34</b> in a down track direction along the z-axis to substrate <b>48</b> that may be an insulation layer, for example. Thus, leading edge <b>31</b><i>a </i>and the interface of each side shield <b>43</b> with substrate <b>48</b> are essentially coplanar. Although the exemplary embodiment shows pole tip sides <b>31</b><i>s </i>formed essentially perpendicular to leading edge <b>31</b><i>a</i>, the present invention also anticipates that the sides may be sloped at an angle between 90 and 100 degrees such that the length of trailing edge <b>31</b><i>b </i>is larger than that of leading edge <b>31</b><i>a </i>in an x-axis (cross track) direction to help overcome the skew effect during a writing process. However, it should be understood that the amount of side track erasure is adequately controlled even in the exemplary embodiment with vertical sidewalls <b>31</b><i>s </i>because of the leading taper. Preferably, STO <b>38</b> is self aligned to pole tip <b>31</b><i>p</i>. Side gap <b>39</b> is made of a dielectric material and separates the sides <b>31</b><i>s </i>and STO <b>38</b> from side shields <b>43</b>. The present invention also encompasses partial side shields (not shown) wherein the side shields contact the trailing shield but do not extend along the full length of the pole tip <b>31</b><i>p</i>. However, the advantage is not as great in controlling fringing field as when full side shields are employed.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the write field H<sub>eff </sub>as a function of write current is shown for the first and third embodiments. It is readily apparent that the main pole <b>31</b> in the third embodiment comprising a trailing taper and leading taper has a substantially larger H<sub>eff </sub>(curve <b>53</b>) than main pole <b>11</b> in the first embodiment (curve <b>52</b>) at the same write current. The plots are generated with a leading taper angle of 40 degrees. For curve <b>53</b>, the trailing taper angle is 30 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, the effectiveness in suppressing fringing field by addition of side shields to the main pole in the third embodiment is illustrated. Curve <b>57</b> shows the cross track profile for a main pole of the third embodiment without side shields and curve <b>56</b> shows the cross track profile for a main pole of the fourth embodiment where full side shields are included. Curve <b>56</b> demonstrates how the write field is substantially decreased at cross-track distances greater than about 0.08 microns from the pole tip.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The present invention is also a method of fabricating the aforementioned embodiments wherein a main pole has at least a tapered leading side and a trimmed pole width where the milling depth is less than the thickness of the pole tip at the ABS. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12-14</figref> illustrate a process sequence whereby a main pole according to the first embodiment is formed.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, a first insulation layer <b>6</b> made of alumina or the like is deposited on a substrate (not shown) by a method such as chemical vapor deposition (CVD) or physical vapor deposition (PVD). Thereafter, an etch stop layer <b>7</b> typically made of Ru and a second insulation layer <b>8</b> that serves as a substrate and is comprised of alumina or another dielectric material are sequentially deposited on first insulation layer <b>6</b> by conventional methods. Insulation layers <b>6</b>, <b>8</b> have a common front side formed along a plane <b>19</b>-<b>19</b> that is proximate to a location where an ABS will be formed in subsequent step. A photoresist (not shown) is coated on top surface <b>8</b><i>s </i>and then patterned by a standard lithography process. Next, a reactive ion etch (RIE) step is employed to transfer the photoresist pattern through the second insulation layer <b>8</b> at an angle to produce a tapered side <b>11</b><i>n </i>having a taper angle &#x3b2; as described previously. Since the ABS has not been formed yet, angle &#x3b2; is shown with respect to a plane <b>70</b>-<b>70</b> aligned parallel to plane <b>19</b>-<b>19</b> and that intersects the top edge of tapered side <b>11</b><i>n </i>at top surface <b>8</b><i>s</i>. The RIE step stops on etch stop layer <b>7</b> which prevents the RIE process from continuing into first insulation layer <b>6</b>. Tapered side <b>11</b><i>n </i>is sloped such that the interface between the bottom surface of second insulation layer <b>8</b> and etch stop layer <b>7</b> extends a distance f from the plane <b>19</b>-<b>19</b> which is greater than the length of top surface <b>8</b><i>s </i>between plane <b>19</b>-<b>19</b> and plane <b>70</b>-<b>70</b>. A certain portion of top surface <b>7</b><i>s </i>is uncovered on etch stop layer <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, a cross-sectional view from a plane perpendicular to the plane <b>19</b>-<b>19</b> is depicted. The photoresist pattern used during the previous RIE step is removed and another photoresist pattern (not shown) is formed on top surfaces <b>7</b><i>s</i>, <b>8</b><i>s </i>with an opening that defines where a main pole layer will be deposited in a subsequent step. Thereafter, a main pole layer <b>11</b> comprised of a magnetic layer such as CoFe or an alloy thereof is deposited by an electroplating process, for example, on top surface <b>7</b><i>s</i>, tapered side <b>11</b><i>n</i>, and top surface <b>8</b><i>s </i>of second insulation layer within the photoresist pattern opening. The present invention also encompasses a method in which a seed layer is deposited on the surfaces <b>7</b><i>s</i>, <b>8</b><i>s</i>, <b>11</b><i>n </i>prior to deposition of main pole layer <b>11</b>. Then, a chemical mechanical polish (CMP) step is performed to generate a planar top surface <b>11</b><i>t </i>that is parallel to top surface <b>7</b><i>s</i>. The second photoresist pattern is removed. The main pole has a front section <b>11</b><i>k </i>formed along plane <b>19</b>-<b>19</b> and above top surface <b>8</b><i>s. </i></p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">An ion beam milling step is employed to trim the main pole layer <b>11</b> including a portion of front section <b>11</b><i>k </i>and a portion of the main pole above tapered side <b>11</b><i>n</i>. Typically, a photoresist pattern (not shown) is formed on top surface <b>11</b><i>t </i>to protect main pole regions that are not to be removed by ion milling. The photoresist pattern is stripped after the ion milling step is completed. Milling depth is represented by t<b>1</b> and is the length of dashed line <b>16</b><i>b </i>in a down track (z-axis) direction between top surface <b>11</b><i>t </i>and dashed line <b>16</b><i>a</i>. As indicated earlier, dashed line <b>16</b><i>a </i>is coplanar with main pole surface <b>11</b><i>c </i>(not shown) and intersects tapered side <b>11</b><i>n</i>. Dashed line <b>16</b><i>b </i>indicates the distance that main pole <b>11</b> is trimmed in a direction perpendicular to the plane <b>19</b>-<b>19</b>. Thus, the ion milling process used to trim the main pole layer occurs within the rectangle bounded by dashed lines <b>16</b><i>a</i>, <b>16</b><i>b </i>and by top surface <b>11</b><i>t </i>and plane <b>19</b>-<b>19</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref>, the main pole <b>11</b> is shown after a lapping process is performed to define the ABS <b>15</b>-<b>15</b>. Main pole front section <b>11</b><i>k </i>is removed and a pole tip <b>11</b><i>p </i>is formed that connects tapered leading side <b>11</b><i>n </i>to top surface <b>11</b><i>t</i>. An important feature is that the thickness t<b>3</b> of the pole tip <b>11</b><i>p </i>at the ABS is less than or equal to the milling depth t<b>1</b>. As indicated earlier, if the ABS <b>15</b>-<b>15</b> intersects the junction of dashed line <b>16</b><i>a </i>and leading tapered side <b>11</b><i>n</i>, then a condition exists where t<b>1</b>=t<b>3</b>. One or more insulation layers (not shown) may be deposited to form a side gap and a write gap adjacent to the main pole <b>11</b>. Then a shield structure (not shown) including a trailing shield or trailing shield with side shields may be deposited by a conventional method as appreciated by those skilled in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In a MAMR embodiment, a STO (not shown) is formed on top surface <b>11</b><i>t </i>between dashed line <b>16</b><i>b </i>and plane <b>19</b>-<b>19</b> by a conventional sequence of steps following the CMP step that produces a smooth top surface <b>11</b><i>t</i>. Next, the STO is trimmed simultaneously with main pole <b>11</b> during the ion milling step to form a so called self-aligned STO. During the subsequent lapping process, a front portion of the STO above main pole front section <b>11</b><i>k </i>is removed so that the STO has a front side at the ABS <b>15</b>-<b>15</b> above trailing edge <b>11</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">A fabrication sequence for forming a main pole having both a leading taper and trailing taper according to an embodiment of the present invention is shown with regard to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 15-18</figref>. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref>, a first insulation layer <b>46</b>, etch stop layer <b>47</b>, and a second insulation layer <b>48</b> that serves as a substrate are sequentially deposited on a substrate (not shown). Insulation layers <b>46</b>, <b>48</b> may be made of alumina or another dielectric material and have a common front side formed along a plane <b>49</b>-<b>49</b> that is proximate to a location where an ABS will be formed in subsequent step. A photoresist patterning step and RIE step as previously described with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> are performed to generate a tapered side <b>31</b><i>n </i>on second insulation layer <b>48</b>. Tapered side <b>31</b><i>n </i>intersects top surface <b>47</b><i>s </i>of the etch stop layer at point <b>60</b> that is a greater distance from plane <b>49</b>-<b>49</b> than a point <b>61</b> where the tapered side intersects top surface <b>48</b><i>s</i>. As a result, a certain portion of top surface <b>47</b><i>s </i>is uncovered after the photoresist patterning and RIE sequence that defines tapered side <b>31</b><i>n </i>on second insulation layer <b>48</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">A main pole layer <b>31</b> comprised of a magnetic layer such as CoFe or an alloy thereof is deposited by an electroplating process, for example, on top surface <b>47</b><i>s</i>, tapered side <b>31</b><i>n</i>, and top surface <b>48</b><i>s </i>of the second insulation layer. The present invention also encompasses a method in which a seed layer is deposited on surfaces <b>47</b><i>s</i>, <b>48</b><i>s</i>, <b>31</b><i>n </i>prior to deposition of main pole layer <b>31</b>. Then, a CMP step is performed to generate a planar top surface <b>31</b><i>u </i>that is parallel to top surface <b>47</b><i>s</i>. The main pole has a front section <b>31</b><i>k </i>formed along the plane <b>49</b>-<b>49</b> and above top surface <b>48</b><i>s. </i></p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref>, a first ion milling step is performed wherein ions are directed toward top surface <b>31</b><i>u </i>at a certain angle to form a tapered trailing side <b>31</b><i>t </i>that extends from the plane <b>49</b>-<b>49</b> to top surface <b>31</b><i>u</i>. It should be understood that a photoresist masking layer (not shown) is formed on top surface <b>31</b><i>u </i>to protect main pole regions not to be removed during the first ion milling step. Intersection point <b>63</b> of top surface <b>31</b><i>u </i>and tapered side <b>31</b><i>t </i>is a distance k from plane <b>49</b>-<b>49</b>. Furthermore, intersection point <b>32</b> of tapered leading side <b>31</b><i>n </i>and bottom surface <b>31</b><i>v </i>is a distance g from the plane <b>49</b>-<b>49</b>. In the exemplary embodiment, plane <b>40</b>-<b>40</b> which is parallel to plane <b>49</b>-<b>49</b> includes both intersection points <b>32</b>, <b>63</b>. However, the present invention also anticipates that the distance k may be larger or smaller than the distance g. The trailing taper angle &#x3c3; formed between trailing tapered side <b>31</b><i>t </i>and plane <b>49</b>-<b>49</b> is between 10&#xb0; and 45&#xb0;. Leading taper angle &#x3b2; is shown as the angle formed between tapered leading side <b>31</b><i>n </i>and plane <b>71</b>-<b>71</b> formed parallel to plane <b>19</b>-<b>19</b> and intersecting the junction of tapered leading side <b>31</b><i>n </i>and top surface <b>8</b><i>s</i>. Note that trailing taper angle &#x3c3; is also formed between trailing tapered side <b>31</b><i>t </i>and plane <b>71</b>-<b>71</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</figref>, a second ion milling step is employed to trim the main pole layer <b>31</b> including a portion of front section <b>31</b><i>k</i>, a portion of the main pole above tapered side <b>31</b><i>n</i>, and a portion of the main pole along tapered trailing side <b>31</b><i>t</i>. Milling depth is represented by t<b>2</b> and is the length of dashed line <b>36</b><i>b </i>in a down track (z-axis) direction between tapered trailing side <b>31</b><i>t </i>and dashed line <b>36</b><i>a </i>which is perpendicular to plane <b>49</b>-<b>49</b>. Dashed line <b>36</b><i>b </i>indicates the distance that main pole <b>31</b> is trimmed in a direction perpendicular to the plane <b>49</b>-<b>49</b>. The upper boundary of the second ion milling step is indicated by dashed line <b>36</b><i>c</i>. Thus, ion milling to trim the main pole layer occurs within the rectangle bounded by dashed lines <b>36</b><i>a</i>, <b>36</b><i>b</i>, <b>36</b><i>c</i>, and plane <b>49</b>-<b>49</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">It should be understood that the process flow for each of the ion milling steps described herein typically follows a sequence of photoresist patterning to uncover a main pole region to be trimmed and protect portions of the main pole that are not to be trimmed, performing the ion milling step which may remove portions of adjoining insulation layers, and then removal of the photoresist pattern (mask).</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In a MAMR embodiment, a STO (not shown) is formed on the trailing tapered side <b>31</b><i>t </i>following the first ion milling step. In the second ion milling step, the STO is trimmed simultaneously with main pole <b>31</b> to form a self aligned STO which means the STO has a width along the eventual ABS that is essentially equivalent to the track width (width of trailing edge <b>31</b><i>b </i>in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a</i>). During the subsequent lapping process, a front portion of the STO above main pole front section <b>31</b><i>k </i>is removed so that the STO has a front side at the ABS <b>35</b>-<b>35</b> above trailing edge <b>31</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</figref>, a lapping process is performed to remove front section <b>31</b><i>k </i>and thereby define the ABS <b>35</b>-<b>35</b>. Pole tip <b>31</b><i>p </i>is formed and connects tapered leading side <b>31</b><i>n </i>to tapered trailing side <b>31</b><i>t</i>. An important feature is that the thickness t<b>4</b> of the pole tip <b>31</b><i>p </i>at the ABS is less than or equal to the milling depth t<b>2</b>. In an alternative embodiment where the ABS <b>35</b>-<b>35</b> intersects the junction of dashed line <b>36</b><i>a </i>and tapered leading side <b>31</b><i>n</i>, then a condition exists where t<b>2</b>=t<b>4</b>. One or more insulation layers (not shown) may be deposited to form a side gap and a write gap adjacent to the main pole <b>31</b>. Then a shield structure (not shown) including a trailing shield or trailing shield with side shields may be deposited by a conventional method. Additional insulation layers may be formed on the shield structure to complete the PMR write head as appreciated by those skilled in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The PMR head as described in the various embodiments of the present invention provides an advantage over the prior art in that a narrow track width as small as 50 nm or less may be fabricated with a self aligned STO and still provide a large head field of 15000 Oe or higher. Side track erasure is controlled with a leading taper. Furthermore, a leading taper may be combined with a trailing taper at the pole tip, and side shields may be included to improve performance. A fabrication sequence for making the PMR heads of the present invention may be performed with existing tools and processes to avoid additional manufacturing cost.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">While this invention has been particularly shown and described with reference to, the preferred embodiment thereof, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes in form and details may be made without departing from the spirit and scope of this invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>We claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A PMR write head with a main pole layer having a planar top surface that is connected to an air bearing surface (ABS) by a tapered trailing side, and a planar bottom surface that is formed parallel to said planar top surface and connected to the ABS by a tapered leading side, said main pole layer comprises:
<claim-text>(a) a pole tip portion, comprising:
<claim-text>(1) a pole tip formed along the ABS and having a leading edge where the tapered leading side terminates, and a trailing edge at the ABS where the tapered trailing side terminates, said trailing edge is located a pole tip thickness from the leading edge and has a track width in a cross-track direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(2) a top surface that is part of the tapered trailing side and extends from said trailing edge to a first plane that is parallel to the ABS and is formed a neck height distance from the ABS;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(3) two sides that are separated by a track width distance along the pole tip top surface, and connect the top surface to a pole tip bottom surface; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(4) the pole tip bottom surface that is part of the tapered leading side and having a first section formed along the tapered leading side between the ABS and a main pole surface that is aligned parallel to said planar top surface and has a front edge formed a first distance from the ABS, and a second section that is coplanar with said main pole surface and extends from the tapered leading side to said first plane;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) the main pole surface adjoining the second section of the bottom surface on each side of the pole tip portion wherein the front edge extends a second distance from a side of the pole tip portion in a cross-track direction to a long side that extends from the front edge in a direction perpendicular to the ABS to a second plane formed on an opposite side of the first plane with respect to the ABS, said second plane is parallel to the first plane; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) a side of the main pole layer formed between the main pole surface and said top surface, and between the first plane and the second plane.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The PMR write head of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprised of a spin torque oscillator (STO) that adjoins the top surface of the pole tip portion, and a trailing shield formed on a side of the STO opposite the top surface of the pole tip portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The PMR write head of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> further comprised of a side shield structure connected to said trailing shield and formed adjacent to each side of the pole tip portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The PMR write head of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the tapered leading side has a taper angle between about 20 degrees and 60 degrees with respect to the ABS.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The PMR write head of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the tapered trailing side has a taper angle between about 10 degrees and 45 degrees with respect to the ABS.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The PMR write head of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein a distance between the tapered trailing side and the tapered leading side along the first plane is greater than or equal to the pole tip thickness.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The PMR write head of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the neck height distance is between about 40 and 100 nm, and the pole tip thickness is from about 40 to 100 nm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The PMR write head of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein a distance between the first plane and second plane along a direction that is perpendicular to the ABS is from about 0 to 70 nm.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
