<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624535-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624535</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13250498</doc-number>
<date>20110930</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2010 1 0502035</doc-number>
<date>20100930</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>278</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>P</subclass>
<main-group>6</main-group>
<subgroup>14</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>31840026</main-classification>
<further-classification>318503</further-classification>
<further-classification>31840033</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Power supply circuit</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4535275</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>M&#xfc;ller</name>
<date>19850800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0134700</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Tanaka et al.</name>
<date>20090500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>307 106</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>10</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>31840026</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>318503</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>31840033</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>31840002</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>31840013</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>318801</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>31840027</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>307 106</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>307 101</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>307  91</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120081052</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120405</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wang</last-name>
<first-name>En Hui</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sun</last-name>
<first-name>Chi Ping</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hong Kong</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Xin</last-name>
<first-name>Fei</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wang</last-name>
<first-name>En Hui</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sun</last-name>
<first-name>Chi Ping</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hong Kong</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Xin</last-name>
<first-name>Fei</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Muncy, Geissler, Olds &#x26; Lowe, PLLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Johnson Electric S.A.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Murten</city>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Masih</last-name>
<first-name>Karen</first-name>
<department>2837</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A power supply circuit includes two half bridge circuits, a controller and two terminals for connecting a motor. The controller includes a signal input terminal, a phase inverter, a wiring board having four soldering pads, and two conductors. The four soldering pads are connected to the signal terminal, an output terminal of the phase inverter, control terminals of lower switches of the two half bridge circuits. Two ends of the first conductor are connected to the first and the fourth soldering pads and two ends of the second conductor are connected to the second and the third soldering pads. Alternatively, two ends of the first conductor are connected to the first and the third soldering pads and two ends of the second conductor are connected to the second and the fourth soldering pads.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="132.00mm" wi="151.05mm" file="US08624535-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="218.95mm" wi="153.59mm" file="US08624535-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="225.21mm" wi="154.01mm" file="US08624535-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This non-provisional patent application claims priority under 35 U.S.C. &#xa7;119(a) from Patent Application No. 201010502035.7 filed in The People's Republic of China on Sep. 30, 2010.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This invention relates to a power supply circuit especially for an electric motor and in particular, to a power supply circuit having a full bridge circuit.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a conventional power supply circuit for a brushless direct current motor M. The power supply circuit includes a full bridge circuit having a first switching circuit <b>11</b> and a second switching circuit <b>12</b>. The motor is arranged in the transverse branch of the full bridge circuit. Four switches K<b>1</b>&#x2dc;K<b>4</b> of the bridge circuit are controlled to be conductive or blocked by four signals SN<b>1</b>&#x2dc;SN<b>4</b>. The term blocked refers to the switch being in an open or non-conductive state.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">When the switches K<b>1</b>, K<b>4</b> are conductive and the switches K<b>2</b>, K<b>3</b> are blocked, current passes through the motor in a direction from a node a<b>1</b> to a node a<b>2</b>. When the switches K<b>2</b>, K<b>3</b> are conductive and the switches K<b>1</b>, K<b>4</b> are blocked, current passes through the motor in a direction from the node a<b>2</b> to the node a<b>1</b>. By controlling the two pairs of switches K<b>1</b>, K<b>4</b> and K<b>2</b>, K<b>3</b> to be alternately conductive, alternating current is supplied to the motor, which drives the motor to continuously rotate in a certain direction.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">For some different applications driven by motors, such as two different fans whose curved vanes bends toward opposite directions, the motors are required to rotate in both directions. It is desired to apply a same power supply circuit to the different applications with minimal modifications.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Accordingly, the present invention provides a power supply circuit comprising a first switching circuit, a second switching circuit, a controller and two terminals for connecting a motor. Each of the two switching circuits comprises a first switch and a second switch. The first switch of the first switching circuit and the second switch of the second switching circuit forming a first pair of switches. The second switch of the first switching circuit and the first switch of the second switching circuit forming a second pair of switches. Each of the switches has an input terminal, an output terminal and a control terminal for receiving a signal for controlling the switch to be conductive or blocked. For each of the switching circuits, the output terminal of its first switch is connected to the input terminal of its second switch, the input terminal of its first switch being connected to a higher voltage, the output terminal of its second switch being connected to a lower voltage. The two terminals for connecting the motor are respectively connected to the input terminals of the second switches of the two switching circuits. The controller is adapted for controlling the first pair of switches and the second pair of switches to be alternately conductive and comprises a signal input terminal for receiving a switch control signal and a phase inverter for inverting the phase of the switch control signal. The controller further comprises a wiring board having a first to a fourth soldering pads, a first conductor and a second conductor, each of the conductors having two ends. The first soldering pad is connected to the signal input terminal, the second soldering pad is connected to an output terminal of the phase inverter, the third soldering pad is connected to the control terminal of the second switch of the first switching circuit, and the fourth soldering pad is connected to the control terminal of the second switch of the second switching circuit. The two ends of the first conductor are connected to the first soldering pad and the fourth soldering pad and the two ends of the second conductor are connected to the second soldering pad and the third soldering pad; or, the two ends of the first conductor are connected to the first soldering pad and the third soldering pad and the two ends of the second conductor are connected to the second soldering pad and the fourth soldering pad.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Preferably, the controller further comprises a first delaying unit and a second delaying unit which are adapted for respectively and independently delaying the conduction of the second switches of the two switching circuits.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Preferably, the controller further comprises a first delaying unit connected between the third soldering pad and the control terminal of the second switch of the first switching circuit and a second delaying unit connected between the fourth soldering pad and the control terminal of the second switch of the second switching circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Preferably, the controller further comprises a first isolating unit connected between the signal input terminal and the phase inverter and a second isolating unit connected between the signal input terminal and the first soldering pad.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Preferably, the first switch of at least one of the two switching circuits is configured to follow the conductive state of the second switch of the other one of the two switching circuits.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Preferably, the control terminal of the first switch of at least one of the two switching circuits is connected to the input terminal of the second switch of the other one of the two switching circuits via a current limiter.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Preferably, the controller further comprises a voltage decreasing unit connected between the first isolating unit and the phase inverter.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Preferably, each of the isolating units has a high impedance operational amplifier, an optical transistor, or an electronic component having a P-N junction.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Preferably, each of the delaying units is a resistor-capacitor circuit, a capacitor of which is a stray capacitor in the corresponding second switch.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Preferably, the power supply circuit further comprises a sensor for detecting the position of a rotor of the motor, an output terminal of which is connected to the signal input terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The power supply circuit in the present invention can be applied to different applications where the direction of rotation of the motor is required to be different, simply by connecting the two conductors to the four soldering pads in different ways. Therefore, the power supply circuit has good compatibility. Furthermore, as only a few electronic components are needed, the circuit is compact and the cost of the circuit is low.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Preferred embodiments of the invention will now be described, by way of example only, with reference to figures of the accompanying drawings. In the figures, identical structures, elements or parts that appear in more than one figure are generally labeled with a same reference numeral in all the figures in which they appear. Dimensions of components and features shown in the figures are generally chosen for convenience and clarity of presentation and are not necessarily shown to scale. The figures are listed below.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a prior art power supply circuit for an electric motor;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a first connecting way of a power supply circuit in accordance with a preferred embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a second connecting way of the power supply circuit in accordance with the preferred embodiment of the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a graph showing dead zone times of the power supply circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a first connecting way of a power supply circuit <b>20</b> in accordance with a preferred embodiment of the present invention. The power supply circuit <b>20</b> is especially suitable for driving a brushless DC motor M having a permanent rotor and a stator with a stator winding. The power circuit <b>20</b> includes a first switching circuit <b>21</b>, a second switching circuit <b>22</b> and a controller <b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The first switching circuit <b>21</b> has two switches K<b>1</b>, K<b>2</b> and the second switching circuit <b>22</b> has two switches K<b>3</b>, K<b>4</b>. Each of the switches K<b>1</b>&#x2dc;K<b>4</b> has an input terminal, an output terminal and a control terminal for receiving a signal for controlling the switch to be conductive or blocked. In the embodiment, the switches K<b>1</b>, K<b>3</b> are PNP transistors and the switches K<b>2</b>, K<b>4</b> are N-channel MOSFETs. Sources O<b>2</b>, O<b>4</b> of the switches K<b>2</b>, K<b>4</b> function as output terminals and connected to ground. Gates C<b>2</b>, C<b>4</b> of the switches K<b>2</b>, K<b>4</b> function as control terminals. Emitters I<b>1</b>, I<b>3</b> of the switches K<b>1</b>, K<b>3</b> function as input terminals and connected to a direct current voltage Vdd. Bases C<b>1</b>, C<b>3</b> of the switches K<b>1</b>, K<b>3</b> function as control terminals and connected via current limiters R<b>1</b>, R<b>2</b> to drains I<b>4</b>, I<b>2</b> of the switches K<b>4</b>, K<b>2</b> which function as input terminals. Collectors O<b>1</b>, O<b>3</b> of the switches K<b>1</b>, K<b>3</b> function as output terminals and connected to input terminals I<b>2</b>, I<b>4</b> of the switches K<b>2</b>, K<b>4</b>. It should be understood that the switches K<b>1</b>&#x2dc;K<b>4</b> are not limited to above configuration and alternatively could be other types such as Insulated Gate Bipolar Transistors (IGBT) and Gate Turn-Off Thyristors (GTO).</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The stator winding of the brushless DC motor M is connected between two terminals T<b>1</b>, T<b>2</b> which are connected to the input terminals I<b>2</b>, I<b>4</b> of the switches K<b>2</b>, K<b>4</b>. Preferably, the power supply circuit <b>20</b> has a sensor <b>24</b> for detecting the position of the permanent rotor of the motor M. The sensor <b>24</b> may be Hall sensor, optical decoder or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The controller <b>23</b> is adapted for controlling the pair of switches K<b>1</b>, K<b>4</b> and the pair of switches K<b>2</b>, K<b>3</b> to be alternately conductive, thereby the stator winding is supplied with an alternating current to drive the motor. The controller <b>23</b> comprises a signal input terminal n<b>1</b> for receiving a switch control signal S<b>0</b>, a phase inverter K<b>5</b> for inverting the phase of the switch control signal S<b>0</b>, and a wiring board for supporting and connecting the electronic components of the controller <b>23</b> and the switching circuits <b>21</b>, <b>22</b>. On the wiring board a first to a fourth soldering pads S<b>1</b>&#x2dc;S<b>4</b> are formed and two conductors <b>26</b> are soldered. The second soldering pad S<b>2</b> is connected to an output terminal n<b>3</b> of the phase inverter K<b>5</b>. The third soldering pad S<b>3</b> is connected to the control terminal C<b>2</b> of the switch K<b>2</b>. The fourth soldering pad S<b>4</b> is connected to the control terminal C<b>4</b> of the switch K<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Preferably, the controller <b>23</b> further includes two isolating units, a voltage decreasing unit and two delaying units for preventing the switches K<b>1</b>&#x2dc;K<b>4</b> from forming a short circuit. The first isolating unit and the voltage decreasing unit are connected in series between the signal input terminal n<b>1</b> and an input terminal n<b>2</b> of the phase inverter K<b>5</b>. The second isolating unit is connected between the signal input terminal n<b>1</b> and the first soldering pad S<b>1</b>. The first delaying unit for delaying the conduction of the switch K<b>2</b> is connected between the third soldering pad S<b>3</b> and the control terminal C<b>2</b> of the switch K<b>2</b>. The second delaying unit for delaying the conduction of the switch K<b>4</b> is connected between the fourth soldering pad S<b>4</b> and the control terminal C<b>4</b> of the switch K<b>4</b>. The two isolating units are adapted for isolating the two delaying units so as to make them respectively generate an independent delaying time without being interfered by each other.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In this embodiment, the output signal of the sensor <b>24</b> is transmitted to the signal input terminal n<b>1</b> to function as the switch control signal S<b>0</b>. The first delaying unit includes a resistor R<b>3</b> connected between the direct current voltage Vdd and the control terminal C<b>2</b> of the switch K<b>2</b>. The second delaying unit includes a resistor R<b>4</b> connected between the direct current voltage Vdd and the control terminal C<b>4</b> of the switch K<b>4</b>. Each of the two resistors R<b>3</b>, R<b>4</b> forms a resistor-capacitor circuit together with a stray capacitor of the corresponding switch so as to utilize charging process of the capacitor to delay the conduction of the switch. The first isolating unit includes a first silicon diode D<b>1</b>, the cathode of which is connected to the signal input terminal n<b>1</b>. The second isolating unit includes a second silicon diode D<b>2</b>, the cathode of which is connected to the signal input terminal n<b>1</b>, and the anode of which is connected to the first soldering pad S<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The voltage decreasing unit includes a first resistor R<b>6</b> and a second resistor R<b>7</b>. One end of the resistor R<b>6</b> functions as the input terminal n<b>4</b> of the voltage decreasing unit and connected to the anode of the first diode D<b>1</b>, the other end of the resistor R<b>6</b> is functioned as output terminal n<b>2</b> of the voltage decreasing unit and connected to one end of the resistor R<b>7</b>, and the other end of the resistor R<b>7</b> is connected to ground. A third resistor R<b>5</b> is connected between the direct current voltage Vdd and the input terminal n<b>4</b> of the voltage decreasing unit. The phase inverter K<b>5</b> includes a NPN transistor, the collector of which functions as the output terminal n<b>3</b> of the phase inverter and connected to the second soldering pad S<b>2</b>, the emitter of which is connected to ground, and the base of which functions as the input terminal of the phase inverter and connected to the output terminal n<b>2</b> of the voltage decreasing unit. In this embodiment, the function of the voltage decreasing unit is to avoid the phase inverter K<b>5</b> to be wrongly conductive when the first diode D<b>1</b> is conductive. Moreover, the voltage decreasing unit should avoid over decreasing the voltage at the output terminal n<b>2</b> to a level lower than the conduction voltage of the transistor K<b>5</b> when the input terminal n<b>4</b> of the voltage decreasing unit is pulled to a high level by the pull-up resistor R<b>5</b>. Alternatively, each isolating unit may include other types of electronic component, such as high impedance operational amplifier, optical transistor, or other electronic component with a P-N junction.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In the first connecting way as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, two ends of the first conductor <b>25</b> are connected to the first soldering pad S<b>1</b> and the fourth soldering pad S<b>4</b>, thereby the anode of the second diode D<b>2</b> is connected to the control terminal C<b>4</b> of the switch K<b>4</b>. Two ends of the second conductor <b>26</b> are connected to the second soldering pad S<b>2</b> and the third soldering pad S<b>3</b>, thereby the output terminal n<b>3</b> of the phase inverter is connected to the control terminal C<b>2</b> of the switch K<b>2</b>. The conductors <b>25</b>, <b>26</b> may be wires or resistors with small resistance.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The operation of the first connecting way will be described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. When the voltage at node n<b>1</b> is high, the first diode D<b>1</b> is blocked, the voltage at node n<b>4</b> is pulled to a high level by the resistor R<b>5</b>, and the voltage at the base of the transistor K<b>5</b> is also high, which causes the transistor K<b>5</b> to be conductive, thereby the voltage at node n<b>3</b> is pulled down to ground and the switch K<b>2</b> is blocked. On the other hand, when the voltage at node n<b>1</b> is high, the second diode D<b>2</b> is also blocked, the voltage at the control terminal C<b>4</b> of the switch K<b>4</b> is pulled to a high level by the resistor R<b>4</b>, which causes the switch K<b>4</b> to be conductive, thereby the voltage at the input terminal I<b>4</b> of the switch K<b>4</b> is pulled to ground to cause the switch K<b>1</b> to be conductive and then the voltage at the output terminal O<b>1</b> of the switch K<b>1</b> is pulled to a high level to cause the switch K<b>3</b> to be blocked. In the process, the resistor R<b>4</b> and the stray capacitor of the switch K<b>4</b> form a RC circuit which delays the conduction of the switch K<b>4</b> and generates a dead zone time t<b>1</b> between the switch K<b>4</b> and the switch K<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Moreover, as the diodes D<b>1</b>, D<b>2</b> are blocked, the delaying time of the conduction of the switch K<b>4</b> is isolated from the voltage at the node n<b>4</b>. In the reverse case, that is, when the voltage at the node n<b>1</b> is low, the second diode D<b>2</b> is conductive, and the voltage at the control terminal C<b>4</b> of the switch K<b>4</b> is low, which causes the switch K<b>4</b> to be blocked. On the other hand, the first diode D<b>1</b> is also conductive, the voltage at the node n<b>4</b> is low, which causes the switch K<b>5</b> to be blocked, the voltage at the control terminal C<b>2</b> of the switch K<b>2</b> is pulled to a high level by the resistor R<b>3</b>, which causes the switch K<b>2</b> to be conductive, thereby the voltage at the input terminal I<b>2</b> of the switch K<b>2</b> is pulled to ground to cause the switch K<b>3</b> to be conductive and then the voltage at the output terminal O<b>3</b> of the switch K<b>3</b> is pulled to a high level to cause the switch K<b>1</b> to be blocked. In the process, the resistor R<b>3</b> and the stray capacitor of the switch K<b>2</b> form a RC circuit which delays the conduction of the switch K<b>2</b> and generates a dead zone time t<b>2</b> between the switch K<b>2</b> and the switch K<b>4</b>. In summary, the switches K<b>4</b>, K<b>2</b> are alternately conductive under the control of the single switch control signal S<b>0</b> and the switches K<b>1</b>, K<b>3</b> follow the conductive states of the switches K<b>4</b>, K<b>2</b> to supply the motor with an alternating current.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a second way of connecting the power supply circuit <b>20</b> in accordance with the preferred embodiment of the present invention. In the second way, the first conductor <b>25</b> is connected between the first soldering pad S<b>1</b> and the third soldering pad S<b>3</b>, thereby the anode of the second diode D<b>2</b> is connected to the control terminal C<b>2</b> of the switch K<b>2</b>. The second conductor <b>26</b> is connected between the second soldering pad S<b>2</b> and the fourth soldering pad S<b>4</b>, thereby the output terminal n<b>3</b> of the phase inverter is connected to the control terminal C<b>4</b> of the switch K<b>4</b>. When the voltage at the node n<b>1</b> is high, the transistor K<b>5</b> is conductive, the switch K<b>4</b> is blocked, and the switch K<b>2</b> is conductive, which causes the switch K<b>3</b> to be conductive and the switch K<b>1</b> to be blocked. When the voltage at the node n<b>1</b> is low, the transistor K<b>5</b> is blocked, the switch K<b>2</b> is blocked, and the switch K<b>4</b> is conductive, which causes the switch K<b>1</b> to be conductive and the switch K<b>3</b> to be blocked.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In the first connecting way, the switches K<b>1</b>, K<b>4</b> are conductive and the switches K<b>2</b>, K<b>3</b> are blocked when the voltage of the switch control signal S<b>0</b> is high, and the switches K<b>1</b>, K<b>4</b> are blocked and the switches K<b>2</b>, K<b>3</b> are conductive when the voltage of the switch control signal S<b>0</b> is low. While in the second connecting way, the switches K<b>1</b>, K<b>4</b> are blocked and the switches K<b>2</b>, K<b>3</b> are conductive when the voltage of the switch control signal S<b>0</b> is high, and the switches K<b>1</b>, K<b>4</b> are conductive and the switches K<b>2</b>, K<b>3</b> are blocked when the voltage of the switch control signal S<b>0</b> is low. That is, for the same switch control signal S<b>0</b>, different pairs of switches will be conductive in the two connecting ways. It is known that if the pair of switches firstly being conductive changes, the direction that the motor rotates will also change. In other words, if the pair of switches firstly being conductive changes from K<b>1</b>, K<b>4</b> to K<b>2</b>, K<b>3</b>, the direction of the current firstly flowing through the motor will change from the direction from T<b>1</b> to T<b>2</b> to the direction from T<b>2</b> to T<b>1</b>, which makes the direction of rotation of the motor also change. Therefore, the power supply circuit can be conveniently applied to different applications where the direction of rotation of the motor is different, simply by connecting the two conductors <b>25</b>, <b>26</b> to the four soldering pads S<b>1</b>&#x2dc;S<b>4</b> in different ways.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In the description and claims of the present application, each of the verbs &#x201c;comprise&#x201d;, &#x201c;include&#x201d;, &#x201c;contain&#x201d; and &#x201c;have&#x201d;, and variations thereof, are used in an inclusive sense, to specify the presence of the stated item but not to exclude the presence of additional items.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Although the invention is described with reference to one or more preferred embodiments, it should be appreciated by those skilled in the art that various modifications are possible. Therefore, the scope of the invention is to be determined by reference to the claims that follow.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A power supply circuit comprising a first switching circuit, a second switching circuit, a controller and two terminals for connecting a motor,
<claim-text>wherein each of the two switching circuits comprises a first switch and a second switch, the first switch of the first switching circuit and the second switch of the second switching circuit forming a first pair of switches, the second switch of the first switching circuit and the first switch of the second switching circuit forming a second pair of switches;</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of the switches has an input terminal, an output terminal and a control terminal for receiving a signal for controlling the switch to be conductive or blocked; for each of the switching circuits, the output terminal of its first switch is connected to the input terminal of its second switch, the input terminal of its first switch being connected to a higher voltage, the output terminal of its second switch being connected to a lower voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the two terminals for connecting the motor are respectively connected to the input terminals of the second switches of the two switching circuits;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the controller is adapted for controlling the first pair of switches and the second pair of switches to be alternately conductive and comprises a signal input terminal for receiving a switch control signal and a phase inverter for inverting the phase of the switch control signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the controller further comprises a wiring board having a first to a fourth soldering pads, a first conductor and a second conductor, each of the conductors having two ends;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first soldering pad is connected to the signal input terminal, the second soldering pad is connected to an output terminal of the phase inverter, the third soldering pad is connected to the control terminal of the second switch of the first switching circuit, and the fourth soldering pad is connected to the control terminal of the second switch of the second switching circuit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the two ends of the first conductor are connected to the first soldering pad and the fourth soldering pad and the two ends of the second conductor are connected to the second soldering pad and the third soldering pad; or, the two ends of the first conductor are connected to the first soldering pad and the third soldering pad and the two ends of the second conductor are connected to the second soldering pad and the fourth soldering pad.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The power supply circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the controller further comprises a first delaying unit and a second delaying unit which are adapted for respectively and independently delaying the conduction of the second switches of the two switching circuits.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The power supply circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the controller further comprises a first delaying unit connected between the third soldering pad and the control terminal of the second switch of the first switching circuit and a second delaying unit connected between the fourth soldering pad and the control terminal of the second switch of the second switching circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The power supply circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the controller further comprises a first isolating unit connected between the signal input terminal and the phase inverter and a second isolating unit connected between the signal input terminal and the first soldering pad.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The power supply circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first switch of at least one of the two switching circuits is configured to follow the conductive state of the second switch of the other one of the two switching circuits.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The power supply circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the control terminal of the first switch of at least one of the two switching circuits is connected to the input terminal of the second switch of the other one of the two switching circuits via a current limiter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The power supply circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the controller further comprises a voltage decreasing unit connected between the first isolating unit and the phase inverter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The power supply circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein each of the isolating units has a high impedance operational amplifier, an optical transistor, or an electronic component having a P-N junction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The power supply circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein each of the delaying units is a resistor-capacitor circuit, a capacitor of which is a stray capacitor in the corresponding second switch.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The power supply circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the power supply circuit further comprises a sensor for detecting the position of a rotor of the motor, an output terminal of which is connected to the signal input terminal.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
