<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624365-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624365</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13182869</doc-number>
<date>20110714</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>159</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>23</main-group>
<subgroup>495</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257668</main-classification>
<further-classification>257E2306</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Interposer based capacitors for semiconductor packaging</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5283717</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hundt</name>
<date>19940200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>361813</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5909350</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Anthony</name>
<date>19990600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>361118</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6970362</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Chakravorty</name>
<date>20051100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>361782</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7732929</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Otremba et al.</name>
<date>20100600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257777</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0140400</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Amey et al.</name>
<date>20090600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257664</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>18</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257668</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257676</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438111</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>61367209</doc-number>
<date>20100723</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Weiser</last-name>
<first-name>William B.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Meridian</city>
<state>ID</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Weiser</last-name>
<first-name>William B.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Meridian</city>
<state>ID</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Marvell International Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Hamilton</city>
<country>BM</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Coleman</last-name>
<first-name>William D</first-name>
<department>2823</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Some of the embodiments of the present disclosure provide a semiconductor package structure comprising a leadframe; an interposer disposed on the leadframe, the interposer comprising a plurality of dielectric layers including at least (i) a first dielectric layer and (ii) a second dielectric layer; a semiconductor device disposed on the interposer; and a capacitor that is embedded within the interposer, wherein the capacitor is formed using at least (i) a first conductive area disposed on the first dielectric layer and (ii) a second conductive area disposed on the second dielectric layer. Other embodiments are also described and claimed.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="171.37mm" wi="213.36mm" file="US08624365-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="246.72mm" wi="201.76mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624365-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="230.04mm" wi="199.90mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624365-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="265.26mm" wi="201.17mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624365-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="264.92mm" wi="186.69mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624365-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="137.67mm" wi="194.23mm" file="US08624365-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present disclosure claims priority to U.S. Patent Application No. 61/367,209, filed Jul. 23, 2010, the entire specification of which is hereby incorporated by reference in its entirety for all purposes, except for those sections, if any, that are inconsistent with this specification.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Embodiments of the present disclosure relate to semiconductor packaging, and more specifically, to providing interposer based capacitors for semiconductor packaging.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Unless otherwise indicated herein, the approaches described in this section are not prior art to the claims in the present disclosure and are not admitted to be prior art by inclusion in this section.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In the current state of integrated circuit technology, an integrated circuit device is often in the form of a chip or a die. Such a chip is typically mounted onto an underlying substrate such as, for example, a carrier substrate to form a semiconductor package. Some semiconductor packages generally include one or more chips coupled to a substrate such as, for example, a leadframe. An interposer is generally used for bonding more than one chip on a single leadframe.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In various application areas, one or more capacitors are generally coupled to a chip that is mounted on the lead frame. For example, a decoupling capacitor is used to decouple a power connection and a ground connection of the chip, to reduce a power to ground noise level. Generally, for a chip mounted on a leadframe, such a capacitor is located on a printed circuit board (PCB) on which the lead frame is mounted. A placement of the capacitor on the PCB results in a relatively large distance between the chip and the capacitor. However, a relatively short distance between the chip and the capacitor is desired, for example, to increase an effectiveness of the capacitor and to decrease an inductance between the power and ground connections.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In various embodiments, the present disclosure provides a semiconductor package structure comprising a leadframe; an interposer disposed on the leadframe, the interposer comprising a plurality of dielectric layers including at least (i) a first dielectric layer and (ii) a second dielectric layer; a semiconductor device disposed on the interposer; and a capacitor that is embedded within the interposer, wherein the capacitor is formed using at least (i) a first conductive area disposed on the first dielectric layer and (ii) a second conductive area disposed on the second dielectric layer. There is also provided a method comprising providing a lead frame; forming an interposer on the leadframe, wherein the interposer comprises a plurality of dielectric layers including at least (i) a first dielectric layer and a (ii) second dielectric layer; and disposing a semiconductor device on the interposer, wherein forming the interposer further comprises embedding a capacitor within the interposer using at least (i) a first conductive area disposed on the first dielectric layer and (ii) a second conductive area disposed on the second dielectric layer. There is also provided a semiconductor package structure comprising an interposer; a semiconductor device disposed on the interposer; a first capacitor that is embedded within the interposer; and a second capacitor that is embedded within the interposer.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In the following detailed description, reference is made to the accompanying drawings which form a part hereof wherein like numerals designate like parts throughout, and in which is shown by way of embodiments that illustrate principles of the present disclosure. It is to be understood that other embodiments may be utilized and structural or logical changes may be made without departing from the scope of the present disclosure. Therefore, the following detailed description is not to be taken in a limiting sense, and the scope of embodiments in accordance with the present disclosure is defined by the appended claims and their equivalents.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> schematically illustrates a semiconductor package structure, in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> schematically illustrates a plurality of dielectric layers of an interposer included in the semiconductor package structure of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> schematically illustrates each type of the dielectric layers of the interposer of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> in more detail, in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> schematically illustrates the interposer of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref> with all the dielectric layers combined, in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates an example method for forming the semiconductor package structure of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> schematically illustrates a semiconductor package structure <b>10</b> (also referred to herein as structure <b>10</b>), in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure. In various embodiments, the structure <b>10</b> includes a leadframe <b>14</b>. Although not illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the leadframe <b>14</b> may be mounted on, for example, a PCB. The leadframe <b>14</b> can be formed from any one or more of various materials, depending on the application. As an example, leadframe <b>14</b> comprises copper or a copper alloy. The leadframe <b>14</b> comprises a plurality of bonding fingers <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">A semiconductor device <b>20</b> and a semiconductor device <b>24</b> (also referred to herein as device <b>20</b> and device <b>24</b>, respectively) are mounted on the leadframe <b>14</b>. In various embodiments, the device <b>20</b> is mounted on the leadframe <b>14</b> through a die paddle <b>28</b>, and the device <b>24</b> is mounted on the leadframe <b>14</b> through an interposer <b>30</b>. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the interposer <b>30</b> is disposed on the leadframe <b>14</b>, and the device <b>24</b> is disposed on the interposer <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Although not labeled in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> for purposes of illustrative clarity, the devices <b>20</b> and <b>24</b> include a plurality of bond pads. One or more bond pads of the device <b>20</b> are electrically interconnected (e.g., using connectors <b>34</b>) to corresponding one or more of the bonding fingers <b>18</b>, for forming pin-out of the structure <b>10</b>. Similarly, one or more bond pads of the device <b>24</b> are electrically interconnected (e.g., using connectors <b>38</b>) to corresponding one or more of the bonding fingers <b>18</b> (e.g., via the interposer <b>30</b>), for forming pin-out of the structure <b>10</b>. Furthermore, one or more bond pads of the device <b>24</b> are electrically interconnected (e.g., via the interposer <b>30</b>) to corresponding one or more bond pads of the device <b>20</b>, as illustrate in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In various embodiments, the interposer <b>30</b> comprises a plurality of dielectric layers that are made of, for example, glass, ceramic or any appropriate dielectric material. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> schematically illustrates the plurality of dielectric layers of the interposer <b>30</b>, in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the interposer <b>30</b> includes a top layer <b>210</b>, a plurality of spacer layers <b>214</b><i>a</i>, . . . , <b>214</b><i>c</i>, a plurality of common layers <b>220</b><i>a</i>, . . . , <b>220</b><i>c</i>, and a plurality of capacitor layers <b>224</b><i>a </i>and <b>224</b><i>b</i>. Although only three spacer layers are illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, in various other embodiments, the interposer <b>30</b> can comprise any other appropriate number of spacer layers. In various other embodiments, the interposer <b>30</b> may not have any spacer layer. Although only three common layers and only two capacitor layers are illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, in various other embodiments, the interposer <b>30</b> can comprise any other appropriate numbers of common layers and/or capacitor layers. In some of these embodiments, the interposer <b>30</b> comprises at least one common layer and at least one capacitor layer.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> schematically illustrates each type of the dielectric layers of the interposer <b>30</b> in more detail, in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure. For example, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates the top layer <b>210</b>, an example spacer layer <b>214</b><i>a</i>, an example common layer <b>220</b><i>a</i>, and an example capacitor layer <b>224</b><i>a </i>of the interposer <b>30</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> in more detail. It is to be noted that the relative arrangement of various dielectric layers of the interposer <b>30</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> (e.g., the top layer <b>210</b> being in the right side of the capacitor layer <b>224</b><i>a</i>) has no significance&#x2014;various dielectric layers illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> are arranged in a random fashion. Furthermore, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> schematically illustrates the interposer <b>30</b> with all the dielectric layers combined, in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, the top layer <b>210</b> forms a top most layer of the interposer <b>30</b>. In various embodiments, the device <b>24</b> is disposed on a top surface of the top layer <b>210</b>. The top surface of the top layer <b>210</b> has a plurality of bond pads <b>340</b> for connecting to the bond pads of the device <b>24</b>, the bonding fingers <b>18</b> and/or the bond pads of the device <b>20</b>. The top surface of the top layer <b>210</b> also includes metal connections (labeled as connections <b>344</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) to interconnect one or more bond pads <b>340</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the common layers <b>220</b><i>a</i>, . . . , <b>220</b><i>c </i>and the capacitor layers <b>224</b><i>a </i>and <b>224</b><i>b </i>are arranged in an alternate manner (e.g., a capacitor layer on top of a common layer, and repeating this pattern). For example, the capacitor layers <b>224</b><i>a </i>and <b>224</b><i>b </i>and the common layers <b>220</b><i>a</i>, . . . , <b>220</b><i>c </i>are stacked in the interposer <b>30</b> such that individual capacitor layers are interleaved between two common layers. The spacer layers <b>214</b><i>a</i>, . . . , <b>214</b><i>c </i>of the interposer <b>30</b> separate the top layer <b>210</b> from the common layers and the capacitor layers.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In various embodiments, conductive material (e.g., a metal plate, also referred to herein as metal area) is disposed on top of each common layers <b>220</b><i>a</i>, . . . , <b>220</b><i>c</i>. For example, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a common metal area <b>320</b><i>a </i>is disposed on top of the common layer <b>220</b><i>a</i>. Similarly, although not illustrated in any of the figures, a common metal area <b>320</b><i>b </i>and a common metal area <b>320</b><i>c </i>(which are substantially similar in shape, size and/or conductive properties as the common metal area <b>320</b><i>a</i>) are disposed on top of the common layers <b>220</b><i>b </i>and <b>220</b><i>c</i>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In each of the common metal areas, one or more connectors are formed. For example, connectors <b>320</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> and <b>320</b><i>a</i><b>2</b> are formed on the common metal area <b>320</b><i>a</i>. In various embodiments, the connector <b>320</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> is an extension of the common metal area <b>320</b><i>a </i>to an edge of the common layer <b>220</b><i>a</i>, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. In various other embodiments, the connector <b>320</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> is provided through an appropriate metal connection between the common metal area <b>320</b><i>a </i>and the edge of the common layer <b>220</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The connector <b>320</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> of the common metal area <b>320</b><i>a </i>has corresponding connectors in each of the other common metal areas, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> (although the connectors are not labeled in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> for purposes of illustrative clarity). In various embodiments, the connector <b>320</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> also has corresponding connectors in each of the spacer layers <b>214</b><i>a</i>, . . . , <b>214</b><i>c </i>and the top layer <b>210</b>. For example, the spacer layer <b>214</b><i>a </i>has a connector <b>320</b><i>sa</i><b>1</b> and the top layer <b>210</b> has a connector <b>320</b><i>t</i><b>1</b>, where the connector <b>320</b><i>sa</i><b>1</b> and the connector <b>320</b><i>t</i><b>1</b> correspond to the connector <b>320</b><i>a</i><b>1</b>, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. Similarly, the connector <b>320</b><i>a</i><b>2</b> of the common metal area <b>320</b><i>a </i>has corresponding connectors in each of the other common metal areas, in each of the spacer layers <b>214</b><i>a</i>, . . . , <b>214</b><i>c </i>and the top layer <b>210</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The connector <b>320</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> and the corresponding connectors in the other dielectric layers (i.e., in the other common metal areas, the spacer layers, and top layer <b>210</b>) are substantially aligned, and the connector <b>320</b><i>a</i><b>2</b> and the corresponding connectors in the other dielectric layers are substantially aligned. For example, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the connector <b>320</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> and the corresponding connectors in the other dielectric layers are arranged such that these connectors are substantially aligned on top of each other in the interposer <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In various embodiments, once the various dielectric layers of the interposer are arranged, a metal strip connects the connector <b>320</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> and the corresponding connectors in the other dielectric layers, thereby forming a metal connection <b>404</b><i>a</i>, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. The metal connection <b>404</b><i>a </i>has a connection point at the top surface of the interposer <b>30</b>. In various embodiments, the connector <b>320</b><i>t</i><b>1</b> forms the connection point of the metal connection <b>404</b><i>a </i>at the top surface of the interposer <b>30</b>. Thus, the metal connection <b>404</b><i>a </i>couples the plurality of common metal areas <b>320</b><i>a</i>, <b>320</b><i>b </i>and <b>320</b><i>c</i>, and provides the connection point at the top surface of the interposer <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Similarly, another metal strip connects the connector <b>320</b><i>a</i><b>2</b> and the corresponding connectors in the other dielectric layers, thereby forming a metal connection <b>404</b><i>b</i>, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. Furthermore, the metal connection <b>404</b><i>a </i>has a corresponding connection point at the top surface of the interposer <b>30</b>. In various embodiments, the metal connection <b>404</b><i>a </i>and the meat connection <b>404</b><i>b </i>are coupled (e.g., using connections disposed on the top surface of the top layer <b>210</b>) to two respective bond pads of the interposer <b>30</b>, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, one or more conductive layers (e.g., one or more metal plates, also referred to herein as metal areas) are disposed on top of each of the capacitor layers <b>224</b><i>a </i>and <b>220</b><i>b</i>. For example, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, metal areas <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>1</b>, . . . , <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>6</b> are disposed on top of the capacitor layer <b>224</b><i>a</i>. Similarly, although not illustrated in any of the figures, metal areas <b>324</b><i>b</i><b>1</b>, . . . , <b>324</b><i>b</i><b>6</b> are disposed on top of the capacitor layer <b>224</b><i>b</i>. In various embodiments, metal areas <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> and <b>324</b><i>b</i><b>1</b> are substantially similar in shape, size and/or conductive properties; metal areas <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>2</b> and <b>324</b><i>b</i><b>2</b> are substantially similar in shape, size and/or conductive properties, and so on.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Furthermore, the metal areas <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> and <b>324</b><i>b</i><b>1</b> are arranged such that the metal areas <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> and <b>324</b><i>b</i><b>1</b> substantially aligned (e.g., on top of each other) when the various dielectric layers are assembled to form the interposer <b>30</b>, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. Similarly, the metal area <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>2</b> is substantially aligned with corresponding metal area <b>324</b><i>b</i><b>2</b>, the metal area <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>3</b> is substantially aligned with corresponding metal area <b>324</b><i>b</i><b>3</b>, and so on.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The shapes, sizes and number of the metal areas in each of the capacitor layers are based on, for example, a configuration and an application area of the structure <b>10</b>. For example, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates six metal areas in the capacitor layer <b>224</b><i>a</i>, which facilitates formation of six separate capacitors that are embedded within the interposer <b>30</b>, as will be discussed in more detail herein later. Accordingly, the number of metal areas in each of the capacitor layers is based at least in part of a desired number of capacitors that are to be embedded within the interposer <b>30</b>. Also, a capacitance of an embedded capacitor is associated with a shape and/or a size of corresponding metal areas. For example, by configuring a size of a metal area (and/or by appropriately shaping the metal area), the corresponding capacitance value can be controlled. The shapes, sizes and the number of metal areas in the capacitor layers in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref> are examples only, and in no way limit the scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">For each of the metal areas in each of the capacitor layers, one or more connectors are formed. For example, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, for the capacitor layer <b>224</b><i>a</i>, a connector <b>326</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> is formed for the metal area <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>1</b>, a connector <b>326</b><i>a</i><b>2</b> is formed for the metal area <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>2</b>, and so on. Similarly, although not illustrated in any of the figures, for the capacitor layer <b>224</b><i>b</i>, a connector <b>326</b><i>b</i><b>1</b> is formed for the metal area <b>324</b><i>b</i><b>1</b>, a connector <b>326</b><i>b</i><b>2</b> is formed for the metal area <b>324</b><i>b</i><b>2</b>, and so on.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In various embodiments, each connector of the various metal areas in the various capacitor layers is an extension of the corresponding metal area to an edge of the corresponding capacitor layer. For example, the connector <b>326</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> is an extension of the metal area <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> to an edge of the capacitor layer <b>224</b><i>a</i>. In various other embodiments, the connector <b>326</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> is provided through an appropriate metal connection between the metal area <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> and the edge of the capacitor layer <b>224</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The connector <b>326</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> of the metal area <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> has corresponding connectors in the corresponding metal areas of the other capacitor layers. For example, although not specifically labeled in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the connector <b>326</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> of the metal area <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> has the corresponding connector <b>326</b><i>b</i><b>1</b> in the metal area <b>324</b><i>b</i><b>1</b>. In various embodiments, the connector <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> also has corresponding connectors in each of the spacer layers <b>214</b><i>a</i>, . . . , <b>214</b><i>c </i>and the top layer <b>210</b>. For example, the spacer layer <b>214</b><i>a </i>has a connector <b>326</b><i>sa</i><b>1</b> and the top layer <b>210</b> has a connector <b>326</b><i>t</i><b>1</b> corresponding to the connector <b>326</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> of the metal area <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>1</b>, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Similarly, the connectors in each of the other metal areas in the capacitor layer <b>224</b><i>a </i>(e.g., connector <b>326</b><i>a</i><b>2</b> of the metal area <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>2</b>) have corresponding connectors in the corresponding metal areas of each of the other capacitor layers, in each of the spacer layers <b>214</b><i>a</i>, . . . , <b>214</b><i>c </i>and in the top layer <b>210</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">A connector in a metal area of a capacitor layer (e.g., connector <b>326</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> of the metal area <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> of the capacitor layer <b>224</b><i>a</i>) and the corresponding connectors in the other dielectric layers (e.g., in the corresponding metal areas of the other capacitor layers, the spacer layers, and top layer <b>210</b>) are substantially aligned. For example, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the connector <b>326</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> and the corresponding connector in the capacitor layer <b>224</b><i>b </i>(and the corresponding connectors in the spacer layers and the top layer <b>210</b>) are arranged such that these connectors are substantially aligned on top of each other in the interposer <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In various embodiments, once the various dielectric layers of the interposer <b>30</b> are arranged, a metal strip connects the connector <b>326</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> and the corresponding connectors in the other dielectric layers, thereby forming a metal connection <b>408</b>_<b>1</b>, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. The metal connection <b>408</b>_<b>1</b> has a connection point at a top surface of the interposer <b>30</b> (e.g., the connector <b>326</b><i>t</i><b>1</b> forms the connection point at the top surface of the interposer <b>30</b>). That is, the metal connection <b>408</b>_<b>1</b> couples the plurality of metal areas <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> and <b>324</b><i>b</i><b>1</b>, and provides the connection point at the top surface of the interposer <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Similarly, another metal strip connects the connector <b>326</b><i>a</i><b>2</b> and the corresponding connectors in the other dielectric layers, thereby forming a metal connection <b>408</b>_<b>2</b>, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. In a similar manner, each of the other metal areas of the (e.g., metal areas <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>3</b>, . . . , <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>6</b>) of the capacitor layer <b>224</b><i>a </i>is coupled to corresponding metal areas using corresponding metal connections (e.g., metal connections <b>408</b>_<b>3</b>, . . . , <b>408</b>_<b>6</b>). In various embodiments, each of the metal connections <b>408</b>_<b>1</b>, . . . , <b>408</b>_<b>6</b> is coupled to a corresponding bond pad of the interposer <b>30</b> (e.g., using connections disposed on the top surface of the top layer <b>210</b>), as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In various embodiments, a metal area (e.g., metal area <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>1</b>) of a capacitor layer and the corresponding metal areas (e.g., metal area <b>324</b><i>b</i><b>1</b>) in the other capacitor layers are interleaved with the common metal areas (e.g., common metal areas <b>320</b><i>a</i>, <b>320</b><i>b </i>and <b>320</b><i>c</i>), and each of these layers are parallel and are separated by a layer of dielectric material. Furthermore, the metal area of the capacitor layer and the corresponding metal areas in the other capacitor layers are electrically coupled by the corresponding metal connection (e.g., metal connection <b>408</b>_<b>1</b>). Similarly, the common metal areas are also electrically coupled by the metal connections <b>404</b><i>a </i>and <b>404</b><i>b</i>. Accordingly, the metal area of the capacitor layer and the corresponding metal areas, in conjunction with the common metal areas, form a capacitor.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">For example, metal areas <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>1</b> and <b>324</b><i>b</i><b>1</b>, in conjunction with the common metal areas <b>320</b><i>a</i>, <b>320</b><i>b </i>and <b>320</b><i>c</i>, form a first capacitor that is embedded within the interposer <b>30</b>, where the metal connections <b>404</b><i>a </i>and <b>404</b><i>b </i>form a first terminal of the first capacitor and the metal connection <b>408</b>_<b>1</b> forms a second terminal of the first capacitor.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Similarly, metal areas <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>2</b> and <b>324</b><i>b</i><b>2</b>, in conjunction with the common metal areas <b>320</b><i>a</i>, <b>320</b><i>b </i>and <b>320</b><i>c</i>, form a second capacitor that is embedded within the interposer <b>30</b>, where the metal connections <b>404</b><i>a </i>and <b>404</b><i>b </i>form a first terminal of the second capacitor and the metal connection <b>408</b>_<b>2</b> forms a second terminal of the second capacitor. In a similar manner, four more capacitors (e.g., corresponding to the metal areas <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>3</b>, . . . , <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>6</b>) are formed, which are embedded within the interposer <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The metal connection <b>404</b><i>a </i>(and also the metal connection <b>404</b><i>b</i>, which is coupled to the metal connection <b>404</b><i>a </i>through the common metal areas) is common to all the six capacitors that are embedded within the interposer <b>30</b>. In some applications, the metal connections <b>404</b><i>a </i>and <b>404</b><i>b </i>are used as a common ground terminal for the six capacitors.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In various embodiments, the six embedded capacitors of the interposer can be used for various purposes. As an example, the first capacitor is coupled between a first power connection (e.g., with a voltage of VDD<b>1</b>) and a ground connection of the device <b>38</b>, the second capacitor is coupled between a second power connection (e.g., with a voltage of VDD<b>2</b>) and the ground connection of the device <b>38</b>, and so on. Coupling a capacitor between a power connection and a ground connection has several advantages, e.g., facilitates reduction in a power to ground induction, reduction of noise in the power to ground connection, and/or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Although the interposer <b>30</b> has six embedded capacitors, a number of the capacitors embedded in the interposer <b>30</b> and the associated capacitance can be varied by configuring a number, shape and size of the metal areas in the capacitor layers, as previously discussed. For example, for a device that has three different power connections (e.g., with three different power supply voltages), the interposer <b>30</b> can have at least three embedded capacitors (e.g., each for the corresponding power connection).</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Embedding the capacitors in the interposer <b>30</b> of the lead frame <b>14</b> of the semiconductor package structure <b>10</b> has several advantages compared to a conventional semiconductor package structure employing a conventional leadframe and a conventional interposer. For example, in a conventional semiconductor package structure, capacitors used to decouple the power and ground connections of a device are generally mounted of a PCB on which the lead frame is mounted. Such placement of the capacitors in the conventional semiconductor package structure results in a relatively large distance between the device and the capacitors, thereby decreasing an effectiveness of the capacitors, increasing an inductance between the power and ground connections, and increasing noise between the power and ground connections. In contrast, in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure, the embedded capacitors (e.g., embedded within the interposer <b>30</b>) are located directly beneath the device <b>24</b>, thereby significantly reducing the distance between the device <b>24</b> and the capacitors compared to the conventional semiconductor package structure.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates an example method <b>500</b> for forming the structure <b>10</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure. At <b>504</b>, the lead frame <b>14</b> is provided (e.g., within the structure <b>10</b>, and disposed over, for example, an appropriate PCB). At <b>508</b>, an interposer <b>30</b> is formed on the leadframe <b>14</b>, where forming the interposer comprises embedding a capacitor within the interposer <b>30</b>. As an example, in the interposer <b>30</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-4</figref>, six capacitors are embedded in the interposer <b>30</b>. In various embodiments, the embedded capacitor is formed using at least (i) a first conductive area (e.g., the metal area <b>324</b><i>a</i><b>1</b>) disposed on a first dielectric layer (e.g., the capacitor layer <b>224</b><i>a</i>) and (ii) a second conductive area (e.g., the common metal area <b>320</b><i>a</i>) disposed on a second dielectric layer (e.g., the common layer <b>220</b><i>a</i>). At <b>512</b>, a semiconductor device <b>24</b> is disposed on the interposer <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The description incorporates use of the phrases &#x201c;in an embodiment,&#x201d; or &#x201c;in various embodiments,&#x201d; which may each refer to one or more of the same or different embodiments. Furthermore, the terms &#x201c;comprising,&#x201d; &#x201c;including,&#x201d; &#x201c;having,&#x201d; and the like, as used with respect to embodiments of the present disclosure, are synonymous.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The terms chip, integrated circuit, monolithic device, semiconductor device, die, and microelectronic device are often used interchangeably in the microelectronics field. The present invention is applicable to all of the above as they are generally understood in the field.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Various operations may have been described as multiple discrete actions or operations in turn, in a manner that is most helpful in understanding the claimed subject matter. However, the order of description should not be construed as to imply that these operations are necessarily order dependent. In particular, these operations may not be performed in the order of presentation. Operations described may be performed in a different order than the described embodiment. Various additional operations may be performed and/or described operations may be omitted in additional embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Although specific embodiments have been illustrated and described herein, it is noted that a wide variety of alternate and/or equivalent implementations may be substituted for the specific embodiment shown and described without departing from the scope of the present disclosure. The present disclosure covers all methods, apparatus, and articles of manufacture fairly falling within the scope of the appended claims either literally or under the doctrine of equivalents. This application is intended to cover any adaptations or variations of the embodiment disclosed herein. Therefore, it is manifested and intended that the present disclosure be limited only by the claims and the equivalents thereof.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A semiconductor package structure comprising:
<claim-text>a leadframe;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an interposer disposed on the leadframe, the interposer comprising a plurality of dielectric layers including at least (i) a first dielectric layer and (ii) a second dielectric layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a semiconductor device disposed on the interposer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a capacitor that is embedded within the interposer, wherein the capacitor is formed using at least (i) a first conductive area disposed on the first dielectric layer and (ii) a second conductive area disposed on the second dielectric layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The semiconductor package structure of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the plurality of dielectric layers of the interposer includes a plurality of capacitor layers and a plurality of common layers, the plurality of capacitor layers include the first dielectric layer, and the plurality of common layers include the second dielectric layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the capacitor further comprises a plurality of metal areas including the first conductive area, where each of the plurality of metal areas is disposed on a corresponding capacitor layer of the plurality of capacitor layers; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the capacitor further comprises a plurality of common metal areas including the second conductive area, where each of the plurality of common metal areas is disposed on a corresponding common layer of the plurality of common layers.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The semiconductor package structure of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the capacitor is coupled between a power connection and a ground connection of the semiconductor device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The semiconductor package structure of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the capacitor is a first capacitor, the semiconductor package structure further comprising:
<claim-text>a second capacitor that is embedded within the interposer, wherein the second capacitor is formed using at least (i) a third conductive area disposed on the first dielectric layer, and (ii) the second conductive area.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The semiconductor package structure of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the interposer further comprises a top layer and a plurality of spacer layers, wherein the spacer layer separates the top layer from the first dielectric layer and the second dielectric layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The semiconductor package structure of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the capacitor further comprises:
<claim-text>a first plurality of connectors, wherein each of the first plurality of connectors is disposed on a corresponding metal area of the plurality of metal areas; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second plurality of connectors, wherein each of the second plurality of connectors is disposed on a corresponding common metal area of the plurality of common metal areas.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The semiconductor package structure of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>each of the plurality of metal areas are substantially similar in shape, size and conductance properties; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of the plurality of common metal areas are substantially similar in shape, size and conductance properties.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The semiconductor package structure of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of capacitor layers and the plurality of common layers are stacked such that individual capacitor layers of the plurality of capacitor layers are interleaved between two common layers of the plurality of common layers.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>coupling a power connection and a ground connection of the semiconductor device to the capacitor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the capacitor is a first capacitor, and wherein forming the interposer further comprises:
<claim-text>embedding a second capacitor within the interposer using at least (i) a third conductive area disposed on the first dielectric layer and (ii) the second conductive area.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The semiconductor package structure of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the capacitor further comprises:
<claim-text>a first metal connection that couples the first plurality of connectors; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second metal connection that couples the second plurality of connectors, wherein the first metal connection and the second metal connection form two connection terminals of the capacitor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The semiconductor package structure of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the first metal connection is coupled to a first bond pad and the second metal connection is coupled to a second bond pad of the interposer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A method comprising:
<claim-text>providing a lead frame;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an interposer on the leadframe, wherein the interposer comprises a plurality of dielectric layers including at least (i) a first dielectric layer and a (ii) second dielectric layer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>disposing a semiconductor device on the interposer,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein forming the interposer further comprises
<claim-text>embedding a capacitor within the interposer using at least (i) a first conductive area disposed on the first dielectric layer and (ii) a second conductive area disposed on the second dielectric layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the plurality of dielectric layers of the interposer includes a plurality of capacitor layers and a plurality of common layers;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the plurality of capacitor layers and the plurality of common layers include the first dielectric layer and the second dielectric layer, respectively;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the capacitor comprises (i) a plurality of metal areas including the first conductive area and (ii) a plurality of common metal areas including the second conductive area; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>embedding the capacitor further comprises
<claim-text>disposing each of the plurality of metal areas on a corresponding capacitor layer of the plurality of capacitor layers, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>disposing each of the plurality of common metal areas on a corresponding common layer of the plurality of common layers.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein embedding the capacitor further comprises:
<claim-text>disposing a first plurality of connectors such that each of the first plurality of connectors is disposed on a corresponding metal area of the plurality of metal areas; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>disposing a second plurality of connectors such that each of the second plurality of connectors is disposed on a corresponding common metal area of the plurality of common metal areas.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>each of the plurality of metal areas are substantially similar in shape, size and conductance properties; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of the plurality of common metal areas are substantially similar in shape, size and conductance properties.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method structure of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein individual capacitor layers of the plurality of capacitor layers are interleaved between two common layers of the plurality of common layers.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein embedding the capacitor further comprises:
<claim-text>forming a first metal connection that couples the first plurality of connectors; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second metal connection that couples the second plurality of connectors, wherein the first metal connection and the second metal connection form two connection terminals of the capacitor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
