<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624440-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624440</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12769678</doc-number>
<date>20100429</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2009 1 0302843</doc-number>
<date>20090602</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>905</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>47</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>83</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>307125</main-classification>
<further-classification>323299</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Power management circuit and electronic device</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4935316</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Redey</name>
<date>19900600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7629769</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Gangstoe et al.</name>
<date>20091200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>320134</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0108941</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Sainomoto et al.</name>
<date>20070500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>320112</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2150658</doc-number>
<kind>Y</kind>
<date>19931200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>1667912</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20050900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>1967966</doc-number>
<date>20070500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>200818656</doc-number>
<date>20080400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>13</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>2</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20100301828</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20101202</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Shi</last-name>
<first-name>Yong-Song</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Shi</last-name>
<first-name>Yong-Song</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hong Fu Jin Precision Industry (ShenZhen) Co., Ltd</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Fureman</last-name>
<first-name>Jared</first-name>
<department>2836</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Bukhari</last-name>
<first-name>Aqeel</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The power management circuit includes a sampling unit, a reference voltage unit, a comparator, and a power managing unit. The sampling unit divides an input voltage from the power supply to generate a sampling voltage. The reference voltage unit receives the input voltage and generates a reference voltage when the input voltage is larger than a predetermined value. The comparator compares the sampling voltage with the reference voltage, generates a first signal when the sampling voltage is larger than the reference voltage, and generates a second signal when the sampling voltage is smaller than the reference voltage. The power managing unit establishes an electrical connection between the power supply and the load according to the first signal, and cuts off the electrical connection between the power supply and the load according to the second signal. A related electronic device is also provided.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="108.71mm" wi="165.18mm" file="US08624440-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="103.04mm" wi="204.47mm" file="US08624440-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="133.18mm" wi="165.61mm" file="US08624440-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The disclosed embodiments relate to power management circuits, and more particularly to a power management circuit and an electronic device.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Generally, a power management circuit is used in various electronic devices. The power management circuit is coupled between a power supply, for example a rechargeable battery, and a load. The power management circuit includes a detecting unit and a power managing unit. The detecting unit is used for detecting an input voltage from the power supply and generating a detecting voltage. The power managing unit compares the detecting voltage with a first standard voltage and a second standard voltage. When the power managing unit determines that the detecting voltage is larger than the first standard voltage, the power supply can provide the input voltage to the load through the power managing unit. When the power managing unit determines that the detecting voltage is smaller than the second standard voltage, the power supply stops providing the input voltage to the load through the power managing unit.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">However, because the input voltage from the power supply decreases, the detecting voltage may be smaller than the first standard voltage and larger than the second standard voltage, therefore the power managing unit is inefficient.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">What is needed, therefore, is a power management circuit and an electronic device to overcome the above described limitations.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Many aspects of the embodiments can be better understood with reference to the following drawings. The components in the drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the present embodiments. Moreover, in the drawings, like reference numerals designate corresponding parts throughout the views.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram of a power management circuit in accordance with an exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a circuit diagram of the power management circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in accordance with the exemplary embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a power management circuit <b>200</b> in accordance with an exemplary embodiment is illustrated. The power management circuit <b>200</b> is coupled between a power supply <b>100</b> and a load <b>300</b>. The power management circuit <b>100</b> includes a filtering unit <b>20</b>, a reference voltage unit <b>22</b>, a sampling unit <b>24</b>, a comparator <b>26</b>, and a power managing unit <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The filtering unit <b>20</b> is used for filtering an input voltage from the power supply <b>100</b>, and providing the filtered input voltage to the reference voltage unit <b>22</b> and the sampling unit <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The reference voltage unit <b>22</b> is used for receiving the filtered input voltage and generating a reference voltage when the filtered input voltage is larger than a predetermined value.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The sampling unit <b>24</b> is used for sampling the filtered input voltage to generate a sampling voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The comparator <b>26</b> is used for comparing the sampling voltage with the reference voltage. When the sampling voltage is larger than the reference voltage, the comparator <b>26</b> may generate a first signal. When the sampling voltage is smaller than the reference voltage, the comparator <b>26</b> may generate a second signal. In the embodiment, the first signal may be a high level signal, the second signal may be a low level signal.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The power managing unit <b>28</b> is coupled between the power supply <b>100</b> and the load <b>300</b> and is used for establishing an electrical connection between the power supply <b>100</b> and the load <b>300</b> according to the first signal, thus the power supply <b>100</b> provides the input voltage to the load <b>300</b>. The power managing unit <b>28</b> is also used for cutting off the electrical connection between the power supply <b>100</b> and the load <b>300</b> according to the second signal, thus the power supply <b>100</b> stop providing the input voltage to the load <b>300</b>. When the input voltage from the power supply <b>100</b> decreases, the power managing unit <b>28</b> only receives one of the first signal and the second signal from the comparator <b>26</b>, therefore the power managing unit <b>28</b> can work efficiently.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the filtering unit <b>20</b> includes a first capacitor C<b>1</b> and a second capacitor C<b>2</b>. The first capacitor C<b>1</b> and the second capacitor C<b>2</b> are coupled in parallel between the power supply <b>100</b> and ground.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The reference voltage unit <b>22</b> includes a first resistor R<b>1</b> and a zener diode D<b>1</b>. One end of the first resistor R<b>1</b> is coupled to the power supply <b>100</b>, the other end of the first resistor R<b>1</b> is coupled to a cathode of the zener diode D<b>1</b>, an anode of the zener diode D<b>1</b> is grounded.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The sampling unit <b>24</b> includes a second resistor R<b>2</b> and a third resistor R<b>3</b>. The second resistor R<b>2</b> and the third resistor R<b>3</b> are coupled in series between the power supply <b>100</b> and ground. The second resistor R<b>2</b> and the third resistor R<b>3</b> are used for dividing the input voltage from the power supply <b>100</b> to generate the sampling voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The comparator <b>26</b> includes an operational amplifier U<b>1</b>, a fourth resistor R<b>4</b>, and a generator <b>36</b>. The generator <b>36</b> includes a fifth resistor R<b>5</b>, a sixth resistor R<b>6</b>, and a seventh resistor R<b>7</b>. The operational amplifier U<b>1</b> includes a non-inverting input terminal <b>260</b>, an inverting input terminal <b>262</b>, and an output terminal <b>264</b>. The non-inverting input terminal <b>260</b> is coupled between the second resistor R<b>2</b> and the third resistor R<b>3</b>. The inverting input terminal <b>262</b> is coupled between the first resistor R<b>1</b> and the cathode of the zener diode D<b>1</b>. The fourth resistor R<b>4</b> is coupled between the non-inverting input terminal <b>260</b> and the output terminal <b>264</b>. The fifth resistor R<b>5</b> is coupled between the power supply <b>100</b> and the output terminal <b>264</b>. The sixth resistor R<b>6</b> is coupled between the output terminal <b>264</b> and the power managing unit <b>28</b>. One end of the seventh resistor R<b>7</b> is coupled to the power managing unit <b>28</b>, the other end of the seventh resistor R<b>7</b> is grounded.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The principal of the power management circuit <b>200</b> is described as follows. The operational amplifier U<b>1</b> compares the sampling voltage from the sampling unit <b>24</b> with the reference voltage from the reference voltage unit <b>22</b>. When the sampling voltage is larger than the reference voltage, the operational amplifier U<b>1</b> generates a first level voltage. When the sampling voltage is smaller than the reference voltage, the operational amplifier U<b>1</b> generates a second level voltage. The generator <b>36</b> generates the first signal according to the first level voltage and the input voltage, and generates the second signal according to the second level voltage and the input voltage. In this embodiment, the first level voltage is a high level voltage, the second level voltage is a low level voltage. In other embodiments, one having ordinary skill in the art can easily adapt corresponding logic circuit to have the first level voltage with low level voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">When the operational amplifier U<b>1</b> outputs a high level voltage, the high level voltage is transmitted to the power managing unit <b>28</b> through the resistor R<b>6</b>. Because the output terminal <b>264</b> is coupled to the power supply <b>100</b> through the resistor R<b>5</b>, the magnitude of the first signal generated by the comparator <b>26</b> is larger than a first standard voltage preset in the power managing unit <b>28</b>. The power managing unit <b>28</b> establishes an electrical connection between the power supply <b>100</b> and the load <b>300</b>, the load <b>300</b> can receive the input voltage from the power supply <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">When the operational amplifier U<b>1</b> outputs a low level voltage, the low level voltage is transmitted to the power managing unit <b>28</b> through the resistor R<b>6</b>, therefore the magnitude of the second signal generated by the comparator <b>26</b> is smaller than a second standard voltage preset in the power managing unit <b>28</b>. The power managing unit <b>28</b> cuts off the electrical connection between the power supply <b>100</b> and the load <b>300</b>, the load <b>300</b> cannot receive the input voltage from the power supply <b>100</b>. Because the power managing unit <b>28</b> only receives a first signal or a second signal from the comparator <b>26</b>, therefore the power managing unit <b>28</b> can work efficiently.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Further of alternative embodiments will become apparent to those skilled in the art without departing from the spirit and scope of what is claimed. Accordingly, the present invention should be deemed not to be limited to the above detailed description, but rather only by the claims that follow and equivalents thereof.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A power management circuit coupled between a power supply and a load, the power management circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a sampling unit for sampling an input voltage from the power supply to generate a sampling voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a reference voltage unit for receiving the input voltage and generating a reference voltage when the input voltage is larger than a predetermined value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparator for comparing the sampling voltage with the reference voltage, generating a first signal when the sampling voltage is larger than the reference voltage, and generating a second signal when the sampling voltage is smaller than the reference voltage; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a power managing unit for establishing an electrical connection between the power supply and the load according to the first signal, and cutting off the electrical connection between the power supply and the load according to the second signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the comparator comprising an operational amplifier, a fourth resistor and a fifth resistor, the operational amplifier comprising an inverting input terminal coupled to the reference voltage unit, a non-inverting input terminal coupled to the sampling unit, an output terminal coupled to the power managing unit, the fourth resistor is coupled between the non-inverting input terminal and the output terminal, the fifth resistor is coupled between the output terminal and the power supply.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The power management circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a filtering unit for filtering the input voltage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The power management circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the reference voltage unit comprises a first resistor and a zener diode, one end of the first resistor is coupled to the power supply, the other end of the first resistor is coupled to a cathode of the zener diode, an anode of the zener diode is grounded, the cathode of the zener diode is coupled to the comparator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The power management circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the sampling unit comprises a second resistor and a third resistor, the second resistor and the third resistor are coupled in series between the power supply and ground, the comparator comprises a first terminal coupled between the second resistor and the third resistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The power management circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the comparator further comprises a sixth resistor and a seventh resistor, the sixth resistor is coupled between the output terminal and the power managing unit, one end of the seventh resistor is coupled to the power managing unit, the other end of the seventh resistor is grounded.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A power management circuit coupled between a power supply and a load, the power management circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a sampling unit for sampling an input voltage from the power supply to generate a sampling voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a reference voltage unit for receiving the input voltage and generating a reference voltage when the input voltage is larger than a predetermined value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a power managing unit for establishing an electrical connection between the power supply and the load according to a first signal, and cutting off the electrical connection between the power supply and the load according to a second signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparator comprising an operational amplifier and a generator, the operational amplifier comprising an inverting input terminal coupled to the reference voltage unit, a non-inverting input terminal coupled to sampling unit, and an output terminal coupled to the power managing unit, the operational amplifier used for comparing the sampling voltage with the reference voltage, generating a first level voltage when the sampling voltage is larger than the reference voltage, and generating a second level voltage when the sampling voltage is smaller than the reference voltage, the generator generating the first signal according to the first level voltage and the input voltage, and generating the second signal according to the second level voltage and the input voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the comparator further comprising a fourth resistor, the generator comprising a fifth resistor, a sixth resistor and a seventh resistor, the fourth resistor is coupled between the non-inverting input terminal and the output terminal, the fifth resistor is coupled between the output terminal and the power supply, the sixth resistor is coupled between the output terminal and the power managing unit, one end of the seventh resistor is coupled to the power managing unit, the other end of the seventh resistor is grounded.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The power management circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the reference voltage unit comprises a first resistor and a zener diode, one end of the first resistor is coupled to the power supply, the other end of the first resistor is coupled to a cathode of the zener diode, an anode of the zener diode is grounded, the cathode of the zener diode is coupled to the comparator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The power management circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the sampling unit comprises a second resistor and a third resistor, the second resistor and the third resistor are coupled in series between the power supply and ground, the comparator comprises a first terminal coupled between the second resistor and the third resistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. An electronic device comprising a power supply, a power management circuit, and a load, the power management circuit coupled between the power supply and the load, the power management circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a sampling unit for sampling an input voltage from the power supply to generate a sampling voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a reference voltage unit for receiving the input voltage and generating a reference voltage when the input voltage is larger than a predetermined value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparator for comparing the sampling voltage with the reference voltage, generating a first signal when the sampling voltage is larger than the reference voltage, and generating a second signal when the sampling voltage is smaller than the reference voltage; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a power managing unit for establishing an electrical connection between the power supply and the load according to the first signal, and cutting off the electrical connection between the power supply and the load according to the second signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the comparator comprising an operational amplifier, a fourth resistor and a fifth resistor, the operational amplifier comprising an inverting input terminal coupled to the reference voltage unit, a non-inverting input terminal coupled to the sampling unit, an output terminal coupled to the power managing unit, the fourth resistor is coupled between the non-inverting input terminal and the output terminal, the fifth resistor is coupled between the output terminal and the power supply.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The electronic device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further comprising a filtering unit for filtering the input voltage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The electronic device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the reference voltage unit comprises a first resistor and a zener diode, one end of the first resistor is coupled to the power supply, the other end of the first resistor is coupled to a cathode of the zener diode, an anode of the zener diode is grounded, the cathode of the zener diode is coupled to the comparator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The electronic device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the sampling unit comprises a second resistor and a third resistor, the second resistor and the third resistor are coupled in series between the power supply and ground, the comparator comprises a first terminal coupled between the second resistor and the third resistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The electronic device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the comparator further comprises a sixth resistor and a seventh resistor, the sixth resistor is coupled between the output terminal and the power managing unit, one end of the seventh resistor is coupled to the power managing unit, the other end of the seventh resistor is grounded. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
