<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625174-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625174</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13438573</doc-number>
<date>20120403</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2011-221373</doc-number>
<date>20111005</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>93</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>358498</main-classification>
<further-classification>358496</further-classification>
<further-classification>358497</further-classification>
<further-classification>358474</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Automatic document feeder and image forming apparatus</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8064109</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Misu</name>
<date>20111100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>358496</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8395827</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Sheng et al.</name>
<date>20130300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>358498</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>B2-4331668</doc-number>
<date>20090900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>4</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>358498</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>358497</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>358496</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>358474</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130088762</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130411</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yamazaki</last-name>
<first-name>Akira</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kanagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ha</last-name>
<first-name>Hyundeok</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kanagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cho</last-name>
<first-name>Senggyu</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kanagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yamazaki</last-name>
<first-name>Akira</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kanagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ha</last-name>
<first-name>Hyundeok</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kanagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cho</last-name>
<first-name>Senggyu</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kanagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Oliff &#x26; Berridge, PLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Fuji Xerox Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Safaipour</last-name>
<first-name>Houshang</first-name>
<department>2673</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An automatic document feeder includes a transport path member that includes a transport path surface constituting a transport path, and an end portion of which moves in a direction in which it gets away from a feeder body to open the transport path, a support member that is relatively rotatable coaxially with the transport path member, a regulating portion that regulates the relative rotation of the end portion of the transport path member, and an impelling member that impels a portion to be regulated in a direction in which the portion to be regulated contacts the regulating portion, that supports the end portion of the transport path member at a first open position, and that allows the end portion of the transport path member to move to a second open position at which the transport path is opened larger than at the first open position.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="228.01mm" wi="165.02mm" file="US08625174-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="237.41mm" wi="164.08mm" file="US08625174-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="208.70mm" wi="146.56mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625174-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="189.91mm" wi="155.70mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625174-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="177.97mm" wi="159.60mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625174-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is based on and claims priority under 35 USC 119 from Japanese Patent Application No. 2011-221373 filed Oct. 5, 2011.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">Technical Field</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to an automatic document feeder and an image forming apparatus.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">According to an aspect of the invention, there is provided an automatic document feeder including: a transport path member that includes a transport path surface constituting a transport path through which an original document is transported in a feeder body, an end portion of which is rotatably supported by the feeder body, and the other end portion of which moves in a direction in which the other end portion gets away from the feeder body to open the transport path; a support member that is disposed in a wall portion on a side in the rotation shaft direction of the transport path member so as to be relatively rotatable coaxially with the transport path member and that includes a locking portion locked to a locking portion disposed in the feeder body when the transport path is opened; a regulation portion that is formed in the support member and that regulates the relative rotation of the other end portion of the transport path member in a direction in which the other end portion gets close to the feeder body by contacting a portion to be regulated disposed in the wall portion; and an impelling member of which an end is attached to the support member, of which the other end is attached to the other end portion of the transport path member, that impels the portion to be regulated in a direction in which the portion to be regulated contacts the regulating portion, that supports the other end portion of the transport path member at a first open position when the transport path is opened, and that allows the other end portion of the transport path member to move to a second open position at which the transport path is opened larger than at the first open position when a force in the direction in which the other end portion gets away from the feeder body is applied to the other end portion of the transport path member.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Exemplary embodiments of the present invention will be described in detail based on the following figures, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram illustrating the configuration of an image forming apparatus including an automatic document feeder according to an exemplary embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a diagram schematically illustrating a state where a transport path member of the automatic document feeder according to this exemplary embodiment is closed;</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram schematically illustrating a state where the other end portion of the transport path member of the automatic document feeder according to this exemplary embodiment is supported at a first open position; and</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagram schematically illustrating a state where the other end portion of the transport path member of the automatic document feeder according to this exemplary embodiment is supported at a second open position.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Hereinafter, an exemplary embodiment of the invention will be described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings. For the purpose of convenience of explanation, the arrow UP shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is defined as an upward direction of an image forming apparatus <b>100</b>. In the following description, the upward and downward directions are expressed with reference to the state where an automatic document feeder <b>12</b> closes a first glass platen <b>72</b> and a second glass platen <b>74</b>. An image forming apparatus <b>100</b> according to this exemplary embodiment includes an image recording apparatus <b>110</b> recording an image on a recording medium P such as a sheet of paper and an image reading apparatus <b>10</b> reading an image of an original document.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The image reading apparatus <b>10</b> is disposed in the upper part of the image forming apparatus <b>100</b> and serves to read an image of an original document and to convert the read image into an image signal. The image recording apparatus <b>110</b> is disposed in the lower part of the image forming apparatus <b>100</b> and serves to record an image on a recording medium P on the basis of the image signal converted by the image reading apparatus <b>10</b>. The configuration of the image recording apparatus <b>110</b> will be first described below.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The image recording apparatus <b>110</b> includes plural recording medium storage sections <b>130</b> storing recording mediums P such as sheets of paper having different sizes, an image forming section <b>120</b> forming a toner image on a recording medium P, a transport section <b>148</b> transporting a recording medium P to the image forming section <b>120</b> from the recording medium storage sections <b>130</b>, a fixing device <b>136</b> fixing the toner image formed by the image forming section <b>120</b> to the recording medium P, and a recording medium discharge section <b>140</b> to which the recording medium P to which the toner image is fixed by the fixing device <b>136</b> is discharged.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The image forming section <b>120</b> includes image forming units <b>122</b>Y, <b>122</b>M, <b>122</b>C, and <b>122</b>K forming color toner images of yellow (Y), magenta (M), cyan (C), and black (K), an intermediate transfer belt <b>124</b> as an example of an intermediate transfer member to which the toner images formed by the image forming units <b>122</b>Y, <b>122</b>M, <b>122</b>C, and <b>122</b>K are transferred, primary transfer rolls <b>126</b> as an example of a primary transfer member that transfers the toner images formed by the image forming units <b>1221</b>, <b>122</b>M, <b>122</b>C, and <b>122</b>K to the intermediate transfer belt <b>124</b>, and a secondary transfer roll <b>128</b> as an example of a secondary transfer member that transfers the toner images transferred to the intermediate transfer belt <b>124</b> to a recording medium P.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The image forming units <b>122</b>Y, <b>122</b>M, <b>122</b>C, and <b>122</b>K each have a photoreceptor drum <b>112</b> that rotates in one direction (the direction of arrow A in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) as an image supporting member supporting a formed image.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Around each photoreceptor drum <b>112</b>, a charging device <b>114</b> charging the photoreceptor drum <b>112</b>, an exposing device <b>116</b> exposing the charged photoreceptor drum <b>112</b> to form an electrostatic latent image on the photoreceptor drum <b>112</b>, a developing device <b>118</b> developing the electrostatic latent image formed on the photoreceptor drum <b>112</b> to form a toner image, and a cleaning device <b>144</b> removing the toner remaining on the surface of the photoreceptor drum <b>112</b> after the toner image is transferred to the intermediate transfer belt <b>124</b> are sequentially provided from the upstream side in the rotation direction of the photoreceptor drum <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The intermediate transfer belt <b>124</b> is supported by a backup roll <b>134</b> opposed to the secondary transfer roll <b>128</b> and a support roll <b>146</b> and circulates in one direction (the clockwise direction in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) in contact with the photoreceptor drum <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Each primary transfer roll <b>126</b> is opposed to the corresponding photoreceptor drum <b>112</b> with the intermediate transfer belt <b>124</b> interposed therebetween. A primary transfer position at which a toner image formed on the photoreceptor drum <b>112</b> is primarily transferred to the intermediate transfer belt <b>124</b> is formed between the primary transfer roll <b>126</b> and the photoreceptor drum <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The secondary transfer roll <b>128</b> is opposed to the backup roll <b>134</b> with the intermediate transfer belt <b>124</b> interposed therebetween. A secondary transfer position at which the toner images primarily transferred to the intermediate transfer belt <b>124</b> are secondarily transferred to a recording medium P is formed between the secondary transfer roll <b>128</b> and the backup roll <b>134</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The transport section <b>148</b> includes a pickup roll <b>132</b> picking up and sending a recording medium P stored in the recording medium storage section <b>130</b> and a pair of transport rolls <b>142</b> transporting the recording medium P picked up by the pickup roll <b>132</b> to the secondary transfer position.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The fixing device <b>136</b> is disposed downstream in the transport direction about the secondary transfer position and serves to fix the toner images transferred at the secondary transfer position to the recording medium P. A pair of discharge rolls <b>138</b> discharging the recording medium P to the recording medium discharge section <b>140</b> is disposed downstream in the transport direction about the fixing device <b>136</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">An image forming operation of forming an image in the image forming apparatus <b>100</b> according to this exemplary embodiment will be described below.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In the image recording apparatus <b>110</b> according to this exemplary embodiment, when it is intended to form an image on a recording medium P, a recording medium P picked up from the recording medium storage section <b>130</b> is first transported to the secondary transfer position by the pair of transport rolls <b>142</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">On the other hand, color toner images formed by the image forming units <b>122</b>Y, <b>122</b>M, <b>122</b>C, and <b>122</b>K are superimposed on the intermediate transfer belt <b>124</b> to form a color image. The color image formed on the intermediate transfer belt <b>124</b> is transferred to the recording medium P transported to the secondary transfer position.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The recording medium P to which the toner image is transferred is transported to the fixing device <b>136</b> and the transferred toner image is fixed by the fixing device <b>136</b>. The recording medium P to which the toner image is fixed is discharged to the recording medium discharge section <b>140</b> by the pair of discharge rolls <b>138</b>. In this way, a series of image forming operations is performed.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The configuration of the image recording apparatus <b>110</b> is not limited to this configuration, but a direct transfer type image recording apparatus not having an intermediate transfer member, or an inkjet type image recording apparatus, or an image recording apparatus capable of recording an image with a configuration other than the above-mentioned configuration may be employed.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The configuration of the image reading apparatus <b>10</b> according to this exemplary embodiment will be described below. The image reading apparatus <b>10</b> according to this exemplary embodiment is configured to be able to read both an original document under transport and a stationary original document.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">That is, the image reading apparatus <b>10</b> includes an automatic document feeder <b>12</b> having built therein a front side reading mechanism <b>70</b> reading an image on the front side of an original document under transport and an image on the front side of a stationary original document and a back side reading mechanism <b>94</b> reading an image on the back side of the original document under transport and a processing device <b>92</b> processing an image signal of the image read by the front side reading mechanism <b>70</b> or the back side reading mechanism <b>94</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The front side reading mechanism <b>70</b> will be described below. The front side reading mechanism <b>70</b> is disposed in the lower part of the image reading apparatus <b>10</b>. The front side reading mechanism <b>70</b> includes a first glass platen <b>72</b> as an example of a platform member on which an original document from which an image should be read in a stationary state is placed and a second glass platen <b>74</b> as an example of a transmissive member transmitting light applied to the original document under transport.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The front side reading mechanism <b>70</b> includes a first moving member <b>76</b> and a second moving member <b>78</b> which can move along the first glass platen <b>72</b>. The first moving member <b>76</b> is provided with a light-emitting portion <b>80</b> emitting light to an original document and a first mirror <b>82</b> receiving reflected light reflected by the original document. The second moving member <b>78</b> is provided with a second mirror <b>84</b> and a third mirror <b>86</b> guiding the light acquired from the first mirror <b>82</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The front side reading mechanism <b>70</b> further includes a focusing lens <b>88</b> optically reducing the optical image acquired from the third mirror <b>86</b> and a CCD (Charge Coupled Device) image sensor <b>90</b> photoelectrically converting the optical image focused by the focusing lens <b>88</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The image signal acquired by the CCD image sensor <b>90</b> is sent to the exposing device <b>116</b> by the processing device <b>92</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">When it is intended to read an image of an original document placed on the first glass platen <b>72</b>, the first moving member <b>76</b> and the second moving member <b>78</b> move in the scanning direction (the direction of arrow B), for example, at a ratio of 2:1. At this time, the light from the light-emitting portion <b>80</b> of the first moving member <b>76</b> is applied to a surface to be read of the original document and the reflected light from the original document is reflected sequentially by the first mirror <b>82</b>, the second mirror <b>84</b>, and the third mirror <b>86</b>, and is then guided to the focusing lens <b>88</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The light guided to the focusing lens <b>88</b> forms an image on the light-receiving surface of the CCD image sensor <b>90</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The CCD image sensor <b>90</b> is a one-dimensional sensor and simultaneously processes one line.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">When the reading of one line in the line direction (the main scanning direction) is ended, the first moving member <b>76</b> is made to move in the direction (the sub scanning direction) perpendicular to the main scanning direction and the next line of the original document is read. By repeatedly performing this operation over the entire size of the original document, the reading of a page of the original document is ended.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">On the other hand, the original document transported by the automatic document feeder <b>12</b> passes over the second glass platen <b>74</b>. At this time, the first moving member <b>76</b> and the second moving member <b>78</b> are stopped at the position indicated by the solid line in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The reflected light of the first line of the original document is reflected by the first mirror <b>82</b>, the second mirror <b>84</b>, and the third mirror <b>86</b>, is focused by focusing lens <b>88</b>, and an image is then read by the CCD image sensor <b>90</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">That is, one line in the main scanning direction is simultaneously processed by the CCD image sensor <b>90</b> which is a one-dimensional sensor and then the next line of the original document transported by the automatic document feeder <b>12</b> in the main scanning direction is read. That is, by causing the original document to pass through the reading position on the second glass platen <b>74</b> after the leading edge of the original document reaches the reading position on the second glass platen <b>74</b>, the reading of a page of the original document in the sub scanning direction is ended.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The configuration of the back side reading mechanism <b>94</b> will be described below. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 to 4</figref>, the back side reading mechanism <b>94</b> is built in the automatic document feeder <b>12</b> and includes an image sensor <b>96</b> as an example of a reading unit including a reading plane <b>96</b>A opposing a transport path surface <b>38</b> of a transport path member <b>40</b> to be described later so as to read an image of (the back side) of an original document. The image sensor <b>96</b> optically reads the image of an original document by irradiating the original document with light from a light-emitting portion such as a light-emitting diode and receiving the reflected light by the use of a light-receiving portion.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The configuration of the automatic document feeder <b>12</b> will be described below. The automatic document feeder <b>12</b> is disposed in the upper part of the image reading apparatus <b>10</b> and serves to automatically transport an original document so as to read the original document by the use of the front side reading mechanism <b>70</b> and the back side reading mechanism <b>94</b>. In the automatic document feeder <b>12</b>, a hinge portion (not shown in the drawings) is disposed on the deep side of the drawing surface of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and the part just close to the drawing surface of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> can move vertically about the hinge portion, that is, the first glass platen <b>72</b> and the second glass platen <b>74</b> can be opened and closed.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the automatic document feeder <b>12</b> includes a document platform <b>14</b> as an example of a document storage section in which an original document can be stored and placed, a transport section <b>20</b> transporting the original document placed on the document platform <b>14</b> to a document discharge section <b>18</b> to be described later, and a document discharge section <b>18</b> to which the original document transported through the transport path <b>30</b> in the transport section <b>20</b> is discharged.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The document platform <b>14</b> is provided with a lifting mechanism <b>16</b> lifting up and down the document platform <b>14</b>. The lifting mechanism <b>16</b> lifts up the document platform <b>14</b> up to the position at which an original document contacts a pickup roll <b>22</b> to be described later when the original document is placed on the document platform <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The transport section <b>20</b> includes a pickup roll <b>22</b> picking up an original document from the document platform <b>14</b>, a transport path <b>30</b> through which the original document picked up from the document platform <b>14</b> is transported, plural transport rolls <b>24</b> transporting the original document along the transport path <b>30</b>, a counter member <b>26</b> opposed to the second glass platen <b>74</b> disposed in the transport path <b>30</b>, and a discharge roll <b>28</b> discharging the original document to the document discharge section <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">A transport path member <b>40</b> including a transport path surface <b>38</b> constituting a part of the transport path <b>30</b> is disposed in the lower part of the automatic document feeder <b>12</b> opposed to the first glass platen <b>72</b> and the second glass platen <b>74</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, the transport path member <b>40</b> has a substantially trapezoidal shape which is flat in a side view and the top surface thereof serves as the transport path surface <b>38</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In the transport path member <b>40</b>, one end portion <b>40</b>A which is on the downstream side (the discharge roll <b>28</b> side) in the document transport direction is rotatably supported by the feeder body <b>12</b>A of the automatic document feeder <b>12</b>. Specifically, a spindle <b>32</b> formed in the feeder body <b>12</b>A is inserted into a through-hole (not shown) formed in the end portion <b>40</b>A of the transport path member <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Accordingly, the other end portion <b>40</b>B of the transport path member <b>40</b> is supported to be movable in the vertical direction about the spindle <b>32</b> and can open a part of the transport path <b>30</b> by moving (rotating) downward in the direction in which the other end portion gets away from the feeder body <b>12</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In the side wall portions in the rotation shaft direction of the transport path member <b>40</b>, the side wall portion <b>42</b> on the opening side (the side close to the drawing surface of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of the automatic document feeder <b>12</b> is provided with a hook member <b>44</b> as an example of a locking member and a lever member <b>46</b> as an example of an operation member. The hook member <b>44</b> and the lever member <b>46</b> are attached to the rotation shaft <b>48</b> rotatably disposed in the other end portion <b>40</b>B which is on the upstream side in the document transport direction of the transport path member <b>40</b> and rotate together.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Specifically, an annular portion <b>44</b>A is incorporated into the lower end portion of the hook member <b>44</b> and the annular portion <b>44</b>A is inserted into and fixed to the rotation shaft <b>48</b>. An annular portion <b>46</b>A is incorporated into the upper end portion of the lever member <b>46</b> and the annular portion <b>46</b>A is inserted into and fixed to the rotation shaft <b>48</b>. The hook member <b>44</b> is normally impelled in the direction (in the clockwise direction in the drawing) in which it is locked to a locking portion <b>34</b> as an example of a portion to be locked disposed in the feeder body <b>12</b>A by the use of an impelling member such as a torsion spring not shown.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Accordingly, the hook member <b>44</b> is normally locked to the locking portion <b>34</b> when the transport path <b>30</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is closed (by the transport path member <b>40</b>). The hook member rotates in the same direction along with the rotating operation of the lever member <b>46</b> in the downward direction (in the counterclockwise direction in the drawing) about the rotation shaft <b>48</b>, which is indicated by a virtual line in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, whereby the hook member is unlocked from the locking portion <b>34</b>. Accordingly, the locked state (the state where the transport path <b>30</b> is closed) of the transport path member <b>40</b> is released.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">That is, the other end portion <b>40</b>B of the transport path member <b>40</b> can move downward to open the transport path <b>30</b>. Since the side wall portion (not shown) opposite to the side wall portion <b>42</b> of the transport path member <b>40</b> is located on the side close to the hinge portion (on the deep side from the drawing surface of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of the automatic document feeder <b>12</b> and it is thus difficult to insert a finger thereto, the opposite side wall portion is provided with only a hook member <b>44</b> that is normally impelled in the direction in which it is locked to the locking portion <b>34</b> and that is unlocked from the locking portion <b>34</b> by interlocking with the hook member <b>44</b> of the side wall portion <b>42</b> with the rotating operation of the lever member <b>46</b> and is not provided with the lever member <b>46</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The side wall portion <b>42</b> of the transport path member <b>40</b> is provided with a link member <b>50</b> as an example of a support member including a portion to be locked <b>54</b> which contacts the locking portion <b>36</b> of the feeder body <b>12</b>A to regulate the movement thereof when the other end portion <b>40</b>B of the transport path member <b>40</b> moves downward about the spindle <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The link member <b>50</b> includes a thin plate-like base portion <b>52</b> and a thick plate-like portion to be locked <b>54</b> incorporated into the base portion <b>52</b> in the thickness direction thereof and can rotate relative to the transport path member <b>40</b> coaxially therewith. Specifically, an annular portion <b>56</b> is formed at an end portion of the link member <b>50</b>, and the annular portion <b>56</b> is relative-rotatably inserted into a cylindrical boss portion <b>45</b> protruding around a through-hole of the transport path member <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In the base portion <b>52</b> of the link member <b>50</b>, a hook-like attachment portion <b>58</b> is formed at the other end opposite to the annular portion <b>56</b>. An end of a coil spring <b>60</b> as an example of an impelling member is attached to the attachment portion <b>58</b> and the other end of the coil spring <b>60</b> is attached to an attachment portion <b>47</b> disposed in the other end portion <b>40</b>B in the side wall portion <b>42</b> of the transport path member <b>40</b>, that is, at a position adjacent to the rotation shaft <b>48</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">A protrusion <b>43</b> to be described later is normally impelled in the direction (in the clockwise direction in the drawing) in which it contacts a stopper <b>53</b> by the coil spring <b>60</b>. That is, a stopper <b>53</b> as an example of a regulating portion protruding in a flat panel shape in the thickness direction is formed in the part just below the attachment portion <b>58</b> of the link member <b>50</b> (the base portion <b>52</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">A protrusion <b>43</b> as an example of a portion to be regulated that is impelled in the clockwise direction in the drawing by the coil spring <b>60</b> to contact the stopper <b>53</b> is formed in the side wall portion <b>42</b> of the transport path member <b>40</b>. The protrusion <b>43</b> is formed in a rib shape coming in vertical contact (linear contact) with the stopper <b>53</b>, and the relative rotation of the other end portion <b>408</b> of the transport path member <b>40</b> in the direction in which it gets close to the feeder body <b>12</b>A is regulated by the protrusion <b>43</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">That is, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, when the other end portion <b>408</b> of the transport path member <b>40</b> moves downward about the spindle <b>32</b> and thus the portion <b>54</b> to be locked contacts the locking portion <b>36</b> to regulate the position of the link member <b>50</b>, the protrusion <b>43</b> contacts the stopper <b>53</b> with the impelling force of the coil spring <b>60</b>, whereby the movement of the other end portion <b>40</b>B of the transport path member <b>40</b> in the direction in which it gets close to the feeder body <b>12</b>A is regulated. Accordingly, the other end portion <b>408</b> of the transport path member <b>40</b> is supported at a first open position.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The operation of the automatic document feeder <b>12</b> including the transport path member <b>40</b> having the above-mentioned configuration will be described below. When an original document is placed on the document platform <b>14</b> to activate the image forming apparatus <b>100</b>, the original document is transported by the automatic document feeder <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">That is, the original document on the document platform <b>14</b> is picked up and sent to the transport path <b>30</b> by the pickup roll <b>22</b>, the original document picked up and sent to the transport path <b>30</b> is transported along the transport path <b>30</b> by the plural transport rolls <b>24</b>, and an image recorded on the front side of the original document is read by the front side reading mechanism <b>70</b> while passing over the second glass platen <b>74</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">When it is intended to read an image recorded on the back side of the original document, the image on the back side thereof is read by the back side reading mechanism <b>94</b> while transporting the original document over the transport path surface <b>38</b>. The original document of which at least the image on the front side is read in this way is discharged to the document discharge section <b>18</b> by the discharge roll <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">When the original document stays (a so-called jam occurs) on the transport path surface <b>38</b>, the part of the automatic document feeder <b>12</b> close to the drawing surface is lifted up about the hinge portion on the deep side to expose the lever member <b>46</b>. The lever member <b>46</b> is then operated to rotate downward. Then, a pair of hook members <b>44</b> is unlocked from the locking portion <b>34</b> of the feeder body <b>12</b>A, and the other end portion <b>40</b>B of the transport path member <b>40</b> moves downward with its weight about the spindle <b>32</b> of the end portion <b>40</b>A to open the transport path <b>30</b> (the transport path surface <b>38</b>) as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">At this time, the portion <b>54</b> to be locked of the link member <b>50</b> contacts the locking portion <b>36</b> of the feeder body <b>12</b>A to regulate the downward movement of the other end portion <b>40</b>B of the transport path member <b>40</b>. That is, the link member <b>50</b> having the portion to be locked <b>54</b> locked to the locking portion <b>36</b> supports the other end portion <b>40</b>B of the transport path member <b>40</b> by causing the protrusion <b>43</b> to contact the stopper <b>53</b> by the use of the coil spring <b>60</b>, that is, with the impelling force of the coil spring <b>60</b>. Accordingly, the other end portion <b>40</b>B of the transport path member <b>40</b> is supported at the first open position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> and the original document staying on the transport path surface <b>38</b> can be removed.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">When it is difficult to remove the original document at the first open position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the other end portion <b>40</b>B (for example, the lever member <b>46</b>) of the transport path member <b>40</b> supported at the first open position is pressed with a finger (a force in the opening direction is applied) so as to further move downward (in the counterclockwise direction in the drawing).</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Then, since the link member <b>50</b> is configured to be rotatable relative to the transport path member <b>40</b>, the other end portion <b>40</b>B of the transport path member <b>40</b> further moves downward (in the counterclockwise direction in the drawing) against the impelling force of the coil spring <b>60</b> (the coil spring <b>60</b> expands) in the state where the portion <b>54</b> to be locked of the link member <b>50</b> is locked to the locking portion <b>36</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. At this time, the protrusion <b>43</b> gets away from the stopper <b>53</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Accordingly, the other end portion <b>40</b>B of the transport path member <b>40</b> is supported at the second open position at which the opening angle is larger than at the first open position and the transport path <b>30</b> is opened larger than at the first open position. Therefore, it is possible to remove the original document staying on the transport path surface <b>38</b> more easily than at the first open position. That is, it is possible to improve the maintainability of the automatic document feeder <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">In this way, when the other end portion <b>40</b>B of the transport path member <b>40</b> can be opened to the second open position, the reading plane <b>96</b>A of the image sensor <b>96</b> of the back side reading mechanism <b>94</b> can be exposed to be visible from the direction perpendicular to the opening surface <b>12</b>B of the feeder body <b>12</b>A which is opened with the downward movement of the transport path member <b>40</b>. Accordingly, it is possible to facilitate the cleaning of the reading plane <b>96</b>A (the maintenance of the image sensor <b>96</b>) and to further improve the maintainability of the automatic document feeder <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">That is, when the other end portion <b>40</b>B of the transport path member <b>40</b> can be opened only to the first open position, the reading plane <b>96</b>A of the image sensor <b>96</b> is not visible from the direction perpendicular to the opening surface <b>12</b>B and it is thus difficult to insert a finger up to the reading plane <b>96</b>A. However, when the other end portion <b>40</b>B of the transport path member <b>40</b> can be opened to the second open position, it is easy to insert a finger up to the reading plane <b>96</b>A and it is possible to easily perform the cleaning of the reading plane <b>96</b>A (the maintenance of the image sensor <b>96</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">When the pressing of a finger on the other end portion <b>40</b>B (for example, the lever member <b>46</b>) of the transport path member <b>40</b> is released (the force is not applied any more), the other end portion <b>40</b>B of the transport path member <b>40</b> is automatically returned to the first open position at which the protrusion <b>43</b> contacts the stopper <b>53</b> with the impelling force of the coil spring <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">When it is intended to close the transport path <b>30</b> (the transport path surface <b>38</b>) by the use of the transport path member <b>40</b>, the other end portion <b>40</b>B of the transport path member <b>40</b> is manually made to move up. Then, since a pair of hook members <b>44</b> is impelled in the direction in which they are normally locked to the locking portion <b>34</b>, the hook members are automatically locked to the locking portions <b>34</b>. Accordingly, the transport path <b>30</b> is closed.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">While the automatic document feeder <b>12</b> and the image forming apparatus <b>100</b> according to this exemplary embodiment have been described with reference to the accompanying drawings, the automatic document feeder <b>12</b> and the image forming apparatus <b>100</b> according to this exemplary embodiment are not limited to the configurations shown in the drawing, but may be modified, changed, and improved in various forms.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">For example, the link member <b>50</b> and the coil spring <b>60</b> are not limited to the configuration in which they are disposed in only the side wall portion <b>42</b> of the transport path member <b>40</b>, but may be disposed in the opposite side wall portion thereof. The front side reading mechanism <b>70</b> and the back side reading mechanism <b>94</b> are not limited to the above-mentioned configuration, but may have other configurations capable of reading an image of an original document.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">The foregoing description of the exemplary embodiments of the present invention has been provided for the purposes of illustration and description. It is not intended to be exhaustive or to limit the invention to the precise forms disclosed. Obviously, many modifications and variations will be apparent to practitioners skilled in the art. The embodiments were chosen and described in order to best explain the principles of the invention and its practical applications, thereby enabling others skilled in the art to understand the invention for various embodiments and with the various modifications as are suited to the particular use contemplated. It is intended that the scope of the invention be defined by the following claims and their equivalents.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An automatic document feeder comprising:
<claim-text>a transport path member that includes a transport path surface constituting a transport path through which an original document is transported in a feeder body, an end portion of which is rotatably supported by the feeder body, and the other end portion of which moves in a direction in which the other end portion gets away from the feeder body to open the transport path;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a support member that is disposed in a wall portion on a side in the rotation shaft direction of the transport path member so as to be relatively rotatable coaxially with the transport path member and that includes a locking portion locked to a locking portion disposed in the feeder body when the transport path is opened;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a regulating portion that is formed in the support member and that regulates the relative rotation of the other end portion of the transport path member in a direction in which the other end portion gets close to the feeder body by contacting a portion to be regulated disposed in the wall portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an impelling member of which an end is attached to the support member, of which the other end is attached to the other end portion of the transport path member, that impels the portion to be regulated in a direction in which the portion to be regulated contacts the regulating portion, that supports the other end portion of the transport path member at a first open position when the transport path is opened, and that allows the other end portion of the transport path member to move to a second open position at which the transport path is opened larger than at the first open position when a force in the direction in which the other end portion gets away from the feeder body is applied to the other end portion of the transport path member.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The automatic document feeder according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a back side reading mechanism that is disposed in the feeder body so that a reading plane opposed to the transport path surface and used to read the back side of the original document is visible from a direction perpendicular to an open surface of the feeder body when the transport path member moves to the second open position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. An image forming apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>an image reading apparatus including the automatic document feeder according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> and a front side reading mechanism that reads the front side of an original document fed by the automatic document feeder or an original document placed on a platform member; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an image recording apparatus that records an image read by the image reading apparatus on a recording medium.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. An image forming apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>an image reading apparatus including the automatic document feeder according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> and a front side reading mechanism that reads the front side of an original document fed by the automatic document feeder or an original document placed on a platform member; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an image recording apparatus that records an image read by the image reading apparatus on a recording medium. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
