<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626345-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131225" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626345</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12844062</doc-number>
<date>20100727</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>265</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>23</main-group>
<subgroup>19</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>700277</main-classification>
<further-classification>700276</further-classification>
<further-classification> 62126</further-classification>
<further-classification>165257</further-classification>
<further-classification>236 51</further-classification>
<further-classification>236 493</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Method and system for optimal coordination control and soft repair of multiple rooftop heating and cooling units</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5385297</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Rein et al.</name>
<date>19950100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>236 493</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5711480</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Zepke et al.</name>
<date>19980100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>236 51</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5769314</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Drees et al.</name>
<date>19980600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>236 493</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0208392</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hudson</name>
<date>20080800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>700276</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>14</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>700277</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>700276</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 62126</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>165257</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>236 51</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>236 493</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>61228674</doc-number>
<date>20090727</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110022235</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110127</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Li</last-name>
<first-name>Haorong</first-name>
<address>
<city>Omaha</city>
<state>NE</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Li</last-name>
<first-name>Haorong</first-name>
<address>
<city>Omaha</city>
<state>NE</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Advent, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Nutech Ventures, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Lincoln</city>
<state>NE</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Gami</last-name>
<first-name>Tejal</first-name>
<department>2127</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Techniques are described that may be implemented in an adaptive control device to regulate multiple zone environmental units based upon multiple temperature values and multiple airflow values, where each temperature value and each airflow value is related to the temperature and the airflow in a specific zone. In an implementation, the input interface of the adaptive control device is configured to receive multiple temperature values and multiple air flow values from multiple zone sensors. The adaptive control device may calculate multiple operational values based on the multiple temperature values and the multiple air flow values. An operational value indicates a power state (e.g. power on/power off) for a zone environmental unit's fan, compressor, heater, exhaust fan, and damper. The adaptive control device's output interface is operable to transmit multiple sequencing commands to the plurality of zone environmental units.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="182.88mm" wi="105.58mm" file="US08626345-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="229.28mm" wi="184.15mm" file="US08626345-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="222.76mm" wi="187.79mm" file="US08626345-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="208.70mm" wi="114.30mm" file="US08626345-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present application claims the benefit under 35 U.S.C. &#xa7;119(e) of U.S. Provisional Application Ser. No. 61/228,674, filed Jul. 27, 2009, which is herein incorporated by reference in its entirety.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Multi-Roof Top Units (RTUs) are generally used for light commercial buildings with an open space. RTUs are configured as constant air volume systems, which causes these RTUs to be inefficient in ventilation, capacity, and humidity control.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Techniques are described that may be implemented in an adaptive control device to regulate multiple zone environmental units (RTUs) based upon multiple temperature values and multiple airflow values, where each temperature value and each airflow value is related to the temperature and the airflow in a specific zone. In an implementation, the input interface of the adaptive control device is configured to receive multiple temperature values and multiple air flow values from multiple zone sensors. The adaptive control device may calculate multiple operational values based on the multiple temperature values and the multiple air flow values. An operational value indicates a power state (e.g. power on/power off) for a zone environmental unit's fan, compressor, heater, exhaust fan, and damper. The adaptive control device's output interface is operable to transmit multiple sequencing commands to the plurality of zone environmental units.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">This Summary is provided solely to introduce subject matter that is fully described in the Detailed Description and Drawings. Accordingly, the Summary should not be considered to describe essential features nor be used to determine scope of the claims.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The detailed description is described with reference to the accompanying figures. In the figures, the left-most digit(s) of a reference number identifies the figure in which the reference number first appears. The use of the same reference numbers in different instances in the description and the figures may indicate similar or identical items.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view of an adaptive controller.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic view of an environment having a plurality of environmental zones and corresponding environmental zone units.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a flow diagram illustrating a procedure in an exemplary implementation of the adaptive control device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Zone environmental units, or Heating, Venting, and Air Conditioning systems (i.e. roof top units), are generally constant air systems, which causes these zone environmental units to be inefficient regulating humidity and ventilation.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Accordingly, techniques are described that may be implemented in an adaptive control device that provides sequencing commands to multiple zone environmental units. In an implementation, the adaptive control device's input interface may receive multiple temperature values and multiple airflow values from a plurality of zone sensors. The zone sensors may be dedicated to a specific zone within an enclosed structure. The adaptive control device may then calculate multiple operational values based on the received temperature values and airflow values. An operational value may indicate or signify a power state of a zone environmental unit's fan, compressor, heater, exhaust fan, and/or one or more coupled dampers. The adaptive control device's output interface may transmit multiple sequencing commands to the appropriate zone environmental units for sequencing the fans, compressors, heaters, exhaust fans, and dampers. The sequencing commands may be based on the calculated operation values.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">For example, an adaptive control device may receive temperature values and airflow values from two zone sensors; one zone sensor dedicated to a first zone in an enclosed structure and the other zone sensor dedicated to a second zone (distinct from the first zone) in the enclosed structure. The adaptive control device may then calculate operational values, based on the temperature values and airflow values from each respective zone, to determine whether the zone environmental units associated with these two zones should be powered on or powered off. The adaptive control device may then transmit a first sequencing command to the zone environmental unit dedicated to the first zone based on the first operational value. This first operational value may be determined from temperature values and airflow values associated with the first zone. The adaptive control device may also transmit a second sequencing command to the zone environmental unit dedicated to the second zone based on the second operational value, where the second operational value may be determined from temperature values and airflow values associated with the second zone. Each operational value may indicate to power on/off the respective zone environmental unit's fan, compressor, heater, exhaust fan, and damper depending the temperature value and airflow value associated with each respective zone.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In the following discussion, an example adaptive control device environment is first described. Exemplary procedures are then described that may be employed with the example environment, as well as with other environments and devices without departing from the spirit and scope thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Example Environment</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates an example adaptive control device environment <b>100</b> that is operable to perform the techniques discussed herein. The environment <b>100</b> includes an adaptive control device <b>102</b> operable to sequence commands to multiple zone environmental units <b>104</b>. The adaptive control device <b>102</b> may be configured in a variety of ways. For instance, an adaptive control device <b>102</b> may be configured as a central processing unit, a microcontroller with pre-programmed instructions, a stand-alone computing device, combinations thereof, and so forth. In the following description, a referenced component, such as a adaptive control device <b>102</b>, may refer to one or more entities, and therefore by convention reference may be made to a single entity (e.g., the adaptive control device <b>102</b>) or multiple entities (e.g., the mobile electronic devices <b>102</b>, the plurality of mobile electronic devices <b>102</b>, and so on) using the same reference number.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the adaptive control device <b>102</b> is illustrated as including a processor <b>106</b> and a memory <b>108</b>. The processor <b>106</b> provides processing functionality for the adaptive control device <b>102</b> and may include any number of processors, micro-controllers, or other processing systems and resident or external memory for storing data and other information accessed or generated by the adaptive control device <b>102</b>. The processor <b>106</b> may execute one or more software programs which implement the techniques and modules described herein. The processor <b>106</b> is not limited by the materials from which it is formed or the processing mechanisms employed therein and, as such, may be implemented via semiconductor(s) and/or transistors (e.g., electronic integrated circuits (ICs)), and so forth.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The memory <b>108</b> is an example of device-readable storage media that provides storage functionality to store various data associated with the operation of the adaptive control device <b>102</b>, such as the software program and code segments mentioned above, or other data to instruct the processor <b>106</b> and other elements of the adaptive control device <b>102</b> to perform the techniques described herein. Although a single memory <b>108</b> is shown, a wide variety of types and combinations of memory may be employed. The memory <b>108</b> may be integral with the processor <b>106</b>, stand-alone memory, or a combination of both. The memory may include, for example, removable and non-removable memory elements such as RAM, ROM, Flash (e.g., SD Card, mini-SD card, micro-SD Card), magnetic, optical, USB memory devices, and so forth.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> also illustrates the adaptive control device <b>102</b> as including an input interface <b>110</b> and an output interface <b>112</b>. The input interface <b>110</b> may provide functionality to receive data via a network <b>118</b>, and the output interface <b>112</b> may provide functionality to transmit data via the network <b>118</b>. Embodiments of the input interface <b>110</b> and the output interface <b>112</b> may include, for example, a port, a cable, a wireless receiver, and so forth. The network <b>118</b> may include a wireless network, a wired network, the Internet, an intranet, and so forth.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The environment <b>100</b> also includes a plurality of zone sensors <b>114</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. Each zone sensor <b>114</b> may be dedicated to a specific zone <b>202</b> (depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) to collect and/or to measure environmental characteristics of the specific zone <b>202</b>. For example, a zone sensor <b>114</b> may measure the temperature and the airflow in a specific zone. The input interface <b>112</b> may then receive a temperature value and an airflow value from the zone sensor <b>114</b> via the network <b>118</b>. Embodiments of the plurality of zone sensors <b>114</b> may include any generally known temperature/airflow sensor known in the art or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The adaptive control device <b>102</b> is further illustrated as including functionality to provide sequencing commands to control the power state of a zone environmental unit <b>104</b> via a calculation module <b>116</b>. For example, adaptive control device <b>102</b> may receive temperature values and airflow values via the input interface <b>110</b>. The calculation module <b>116</b> may calculate a plurality of operational values utilizing a set of equations, as described below, to determine whether a plurality of zone environmental units <b>104</b> should be powered on if the zone environmental units <b>104</b> are currently in a powered down state or whether the zone environmental units <b>104</b> should be powered off if the zone environmental units <b>104</b> are currently in a powered on state. Once the operational values are calculated, the output interface <b>112</b> may transmit a sequencing command to the plurality of zone environmental units <b>104</b> via the network <b>118</b>. The sequencing command may be a command to power on or power off, where the sequencing command(s) depend(s) on the calculated operational value(s).</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">An environment <b>200</b> is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The environment <b>200</b> includes a plurality of zones <b>202</b> with dedicated, or associated, zone environmental units <b>104</b> (each zone and zone environmental unit is depicted as an RTU with respective column and row). As depicted, there are 1 (row)&#xd7;m (column) environmental zone units. Each zone <b>202</b> may represent a specific region or specific boundary within an enclosed structure <b>204</b>. The enclosed structure <b>204</b>, for example, may include a commercial building and the like. The enclosed structure <b>204</b> may include multiple zone environmental units <b>104</b>. The zone environmental units <b>104</b> may include HVAC units, such as roof top units, and the like. The zone environmental units <b>104</b> may include fans, compressors, heaters, exhaust fans, dampers, (not shown) and so forth.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The zone environmental units <b>104</b> may be associated with one specific zone <b>202</b> within the enclosed structure <b>204</b>, or the zone environmental units <b>104</b> may be associated with multiple specific zones <b>202</b> within the enclosed structure <b>204</b>. For example, the zone environmental unit <b>104</b> may be dedicated to cooling a first zone <b>202</b> only. Conversely, the zone environmental unit <b>104</b> may be dedicated to cooling the first zone <b>202</b> and a second zone <b>202</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The calculation module <b>116</b> may calculate or determine the operational values based upon the following equations. The ideal number of operating fans (n<sub>i</sub>), where one zone environmental unit may include a fan, may be determined by the minimum total air flow rate required for the whole conditioning space {dot over (V)}<sub>i </sub>and the average RTU airflow rate, <o ostyle="single">{dot over (V)}</o><sub>RTU</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">
<maths id="MATH-US-00001" num="00001">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <msub>
          <mi>n</mi>
          <mi>i</mi>
        </msub>
        <mo>&#x2248;</mo>
        <mfrac>
          <msubsup>
            <mover>
              <mi>V</mi>
              <mo>.</mo>
            </mover>
            <mi>i</mi>
            <mstyle>
              <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
            </mstyle>
          </msubsup>
          <msubsup>
            <mover>
              <mover>
                <mi>V</mi>
                <mo>.</mo>
              </mover>
              <mi>_</mi>
            </mover>
            <mi>RTU</mi>
            <mstyle>
              <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
            </mstyle>
          </msubsup>
        </mfrac>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mn>1</mn>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mi>where</mi>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mstyle>
        <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
      </mstyle>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <msubsup>
            <mover>
              <mover>
                <mi>V</mi>
                <mo>.</mo>
              </mover>
              <mi>_</mi>
            </mover>
            <mi>RTU</mi>
            <mstyle>
              <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
            </mstyle>
          </msubsup>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mfrac>
              <mn>1</mn>
              <mrow>
                <mi>l</mi>
                <mo>&#xd7;</mo>
                <mi>m</mi>
              </mrow>
            </mfrac>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <munderover>
                <mo>&#x2211;</mo>
                <mi>i</mi>
                <mi>l</mi>
              </munderover>
              <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <munderover>
                  <mo>&#x2211;</mo>
                  <mi>j</mi>
                  <mi>m</mi>
                </munderover>
                <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                <msubsup>
                  <mover>
                    <mi>V</mi>
                    <mo>.</mo>
                  </mover>
                  <mi>ij</mi>
                  <mstyle>
                    <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                  </mstyle>
                </msubsup>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
        <mo>,</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mn>2</mn>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">and {dot over (V)}<sub>t </sub>is the maximum value for satisfying ventilation, heating, and cooling requirements for the enclosed structure <b>204</b>. The current baseline is that during the enclosed structure's hours, all supply fans are operating:
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>{dot over (V)}</i><sub>t</sub>=MAX(<i>{dot over (V)}</i><sub>v</sub><i>,{dot over (V)}</i><sub>h</sub><i>,{dot over (V)}</i><sub>c</sub>)&#x2003;&#x2003;(3),<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">where {dot over (V)}<sub>v </sub>is the minimum airflow rate required by ventilation, {dot over (V)}<sub>h </sub>is the minimum flow by heating, and {dot over (V)}<sub>c </sub>is the minimum airflow rate by cooling. These parameters, or values, can be calculated by Equations (4), (5) and (6):
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>{dot over (V)}</i><sub>v</sub><i>=R</i><sub>p</sub><i>P</i><sub>z</sub><i>+R</i><sub>a</sub><i>A</i><sub>z</sub>&#x2003;&#x2003;(4)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>{dot over (V)}</i><sub>h</sub><i>=R</i><sub>h</sub><i>{dot over (Q)}</i><sub>h</sub>&#x2003;&#x2003;(5)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>{dot over (V)}</i><sub>c</sub><i>=R</i><sub>c</sub><i>{dot over (Q)}</i><sub>c</sub>&#x2003;&#x2003;(6);<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">where R<sub>p </sub>is the outdoor airflow rate required per person (e.g., 7.5 cfm/person for supermarket); P<sub>z </sub>is the zone population (e.g., 8 person/1000 ft<sup>2 </sup>for supermarket); R<sub>a </sub>is the outdoor airflow rate required per unit area (e.g., 0.06 cfm/ft<sup>2 </sup>for supermarket). For a supermarket application, {dot over (V)}<sub>v </sub>is about 15 cfm/person or 0.12 cfm/ft<sup>2</sup>; R<sub>h </sub>is the supply airflow rate required per unit ton of heating load (about 200 cfm/ton for supermarket); R<sub>c </sub>is the supply airflow rate required per unit ton of cooling load (about 340 cfm/ton for supermarket); {dot over (Q)}<sub>h </sub>is the instantaneous heating load; and {dot over (Q)}<sub>c </sub>is the instantaneous cooling load. {dot over (Q)}<sub>h </sub>and {dot over (Q)}<sub>c </sub>can be calculated by:
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>{dot over (Q)}</i><sub>h</sub><i>=k</i><sub>env</sub>(<i>T</i><sub>b</sub><i>&#x2212;T</i><sub>amb</sub>)&#x2003;&#x2003;(7)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>{dot over (Q)}</i><sub>c</sub><i>=k</i><sub>env</sub><i>[T</i><sub>amb</sub><i>&#x2212;T</i><sub>b</sub>&#x2212;(<i>T</i><sub>sp,c</sub><i>&#x2212;T</i><sub>sp,h</sub>)]&#x2003;&#x2003;(8)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">where k<sub>env </sub>is the enclosed structure's <b>204</b> envelop load coefficient; T<sub>amb </sub>is the ambient temperature; T<sub>h </sub>is the balance temperature; T<sub>sp,h </sub>is the zone heating set point; and T<sub>sp,h </sub>is the zone cooling set point.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Each zone environmental unit may include multiple mode settings. For example, the zone environmental unit may have a cool mode for cooling periods, a heating mode for heating periods, economy, or economizer, mode for energy saving periods, and so forth. The locations of operating fans within the enclosed structure <b>204</b> may be determined by: Calculating the temperature offsets for each zone from its set points:</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">
<maths id="MATH-US-00002" num="00002">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <msub>
          <mi>&#x394;</mi>
          <mi>ij</mi>
        </msub>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mo>{</mo>
          <mtable>
            <mtr>
              <mtd>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>T</mi>
                    <mi>z</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>T</mi>
                    <mrow>
                      <mi>sp</mi>
                      <mo>,</mo>
                      <mi>c</mi>
                    </mrow>
                  </msub>
                </mrow>
              </mtd>
              <mtd>
                <mrow>
                  <mi>for</mi>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mstyle>
                    <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
                  </mstyle>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mi>cooling</mi>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mstyle>
                    <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
                  </mstyle>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mi>mode</mi>
                </mrow>
              </mtd>
            </mtr>
            <mtr>
              <mtd>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>T</mi>
                    <mrow>
                      <mi>sp</mi>
                      <mo>,</mo>
                      <mi>h</mi>
                    </mrow>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>T</mi>
                    <mi>z</mi>
                  </msub>
                </mrow>
              </mtd>
              <mtd>
                <mrow>
                  <mi>for</mi>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mstyle>
                    <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
                  </mstyle>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mi>heating</mi>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mstyle>
                    <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
                  </mstyle>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mi>mode</mi>
                    <mo>.</mo>
                  </mrow>
                </mrow>
              </mtd>
            </mtr>
          </mtable>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mn>9</mn>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Start the fans whose &#x394;T<sub>ij </sub>belongs to the top n<sub>i </sub>and if
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0002-0001" num="0031">1. &#x394;t<sub>off,ij</sub>&#x3e;&#x394;t<sub>of,min </sub>(e.g., 5 mins) and</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0002" num="0032">2. &#x394;T<sub>ij</sub>&#x3e;&#x394;T<sub>min </sub>(e.g., &#x2212;2 F)</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0033">Start the fans whose &#x394;T<sub>ij </sub>does not belong to the top n<sub>i </sub>but if
<ul id="ul0003" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0003-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0004" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0004-0001" num="0034">1. &#x394;T<sub>ij</sub>&#x3e;&#x394;T<sub>max </sub>(3 F) or</li>
        <li id="ul0004-0002" num="0035">2. &#x394;t<sub>off,ij</sub>&#x3e;&#x394;t<sub>off,max </sub>(e.g., 2 hrs) and &#x394;T<sub>ij</sub>&#x3e;&#x394;T<sub>min </sub>(e.g., &#x2212;2 F).</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0036">The zone environmental unit's <b>104</b> fan may be stopped if:
<ul id="ul0005" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0005-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0006" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0006-0001" num="0037">1. &#x394;T<sub>ij</sub>&#x3c;&#x394;T<sub>min </sub>(e.g., &#x2212;2 F) or</li>
        <li id="ul0006-0002" num="0038">2. &#x394;t<sub>on,ij</sub>&#x3e;&#x394;t<sub>on,max </sub>(e.g., 30 mins) and &#x394;T<sub>ij</sub>&#x3c;&#x394;T<sub>max </sub>(3 F)&#x2212;1 F.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0039">The compressor operation, where each zone environmental unit <b>104</b> may include a compressor, may be determined by:</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0040">First, define the operating mode as in Equation (10):</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0041">
<maths id="MATH-US-00003" num="00003">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mstyle>
          <mspace width="4.4em" height="4.4ex"/>
        </mstyle>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>mode</mi>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mo>{</mo>
            <mtable>
              <mtr>
                <mtd>
                  <mi>cooling</mi>
                </mtd>
                <mtd>
                  <mrow>
                    <mrow>
                      <mi>if</mi>
                      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                      <mstyle>
                        <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
                      </mstyle>
                      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                      <msubsup>
                        <mover>
                          <mi>V</mi>
                          <mo>.</mo>
                        </mover>
                        <mi>t</mi>
                        <mstyle>
                          <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                        </mstyle>
                      </msubsup>
                    </mrow>
                    <mo>=</mo>
                    <mrow>
                      <msub>
                        <mover>
                          <mi>V</mi>
                          <mo>.</mo>
                        </mover>
                        <mi>c</mi>
                      </msub>
                      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                                        </mrow>
                  </mrow>
                </mtd>
              </mtr>
              <mtr>
                <mtd>
                  <mi>economizing</mi>
                </mtd>
                <mtd>
                  <mrow>
                    <mrow>
                      <mi>if</mi>
                      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                      <mstyle>
                        <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
                      </mstyle>
                      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                      <msubsup>
                        <mover>
                          <mi>V</mi>
                          <mo>.</mo>
                        </mover>
                        <mi>t</mi>
                        <mstyle>
                          <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                        </mstyle>
                      </msubsup>
                    </mrow>
                    <mo>=</mo>
                    <mrow>
                      <msub>
                        <mover>
                          <mi>V</mi>
                          <mo>.</mo>
                        </mover>
                        <mi>v</mi>
                      </msub>
                      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                                         </mrow>
                  </mrow>
                </mtd>
              </mtr>
              <mtr>
                <mtd>
                  <mi>heating</mi>
                </mtd>
                <mtd>
                  <mrow>
                    <mrow>
                      <mi>if</mi>
                      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                      <mstyle>
                        <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
                      </mstyle>
                      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                      <msubsup>
                        <mover>
                          <mi>V</mi>
                          <mo>.</mo>
                        </mover>
                        <mi>t</mi>
                        <mstyle>
                          <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                        </mstyle>
                      </msubsup>
                    </mrow>
                    <mo>=</mo>
                    <mrow>
                      <msub>
                        <mover>
                          <mi>V</mi>
                          <mo>.</mo>
                        </mover>
                        <mi>h</mi>
                      </msub>
                      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                                         </mrow>
                  </mrow>
                </mtd>
              </mtr>
            </mtable>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mn>10</mn>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0042">Start all the compressor(s) of the zone environmental unit(s) <b>104</b> if mode=cooling and
<ul id="ul0007" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0007-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0008" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0008-0001" num="0043">1. FanStatus=&#x2018;on&#x2019; and</li>
        <li id="ul0008-0002" num="0044">2. &#x394;t<sub>off,ij</sub>&#x3e;&#x394;t<sub>off,min </sub>(e.g., 5 mins)</li>
        <li id="ul0008-0003" num="0045">3. One &#x394;T<sub>ij</sub>&#x3e;&#x394;T<sub>min </sub>(e.g., &#x2212;2 F).</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0046">The adaptive device control <b>102</b> may determine that each individual compressor should stage off one-by-one if &#x394;T<sub>ij </sub>drops at a rate higher than k<sub>T </sub>(e.g., 2 F in 10 minutes) and maintain the supply air dry-bulb temperature low than T<sub>sp,s </sub>(e.g., 55 F) if the dewpoint of the outdoor air is higher than (e.g., T<sub>sp,s </sub>(e.g., 55 F).</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0047">The heater operation, where each zone environmental unit <b>104</b> may include a heater, may be determined by:</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0048">Start all the heater(s) of the RTU if mode=heating and
<ul id="ul0009" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0009-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0010" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0010-0001" num="0049">1. FanStatus=&#x2018;on&#x2019; and</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0050">2. &#x394;t<sub>off,ij</sub>&#x3e;&#x394;t<sub>off,min </sub>(e.g., 5 mins)
<ul id="ul0011" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0011-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0012" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0012-0001" num="0051">3. &#x394;T<sub>ij</sub>&#x3e;&#x394;T<sub>min </sub>(e.g., &#x2212;2 F).</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0052">The adaptive control device <b>102</b> may determine that individual heaters may be staged off one-by-one if &#x394;T<sub>ij </sub>drops at a rate higher than k<sub>T </sub>(e.g., 2 F in 10 minutes).</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0053">The exhaust fan operation, where each zone operational unit <b>204</b> may include an exhaust fan, may be determined by:</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0054">The number of exhaust fans to be operated should be equal to the actual number of operating supply fans (n<sub>a</sub>). Define a parameter, w<sub>ef,ij</sub>, to quantify the priority of the exhaust fan associated with RTU<sub>ij</sub>. Update equation (11) every time the following conditions are checked:</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0055">1. If the supply fan of RTU<sub>ij </sub>is off, then &#x394;w<sub>ef,ij</sub>=1, otherwise, &#x394;w<sub>ef,ij</sub>=0</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0056">2. If &#x394;T<sub>ij</sub>&#x2267;Q F, then &#x394;w<sub>ef,ij</sub>=&#x394;T<sub>ij/[</sub>&#x394;T<sub>max </sub>((&#x3b1;[F])+&#x3b2;[F])], otherwise &#x394;w<sub>ef,ij</sub>=&#x394;T<sub>ij/[</sub>&#x394;T<sub>min </sub>((&#x3b1;[F])+&#x3b4;[F])]
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>w</i><sub>ef,ij</sub><i>=w</i><sub>ef,ij</sub><i>+&#x394;w</i><sub>ef,ij</sub>&#x2003;&#x2003;(11)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0057">In a typical design, the variable Q=0, the variable &#x3b1;=3, the variable &#x3b2;=2, and the variable &#x3b4;=1. The adaptive control device <b>102</b> may determine that exhaust fans whose w<sub>ef,ij </sub>belongs to the top n<sub>a </sub>may need to powered on or started.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0058">The damper operation, where each zone environmental unit <b>204</b> may be associated with a damper, may be determined by:</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0059">The outdoor damper position should be maintained at its possible minimum position (can be up to 100%):</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0060">
<maths id="MATH-US-00004" num="00004">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mrow>
  <msub>
    <mi>&#x3b2;</mi>
    <mi>min</mi>
  </msub>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mfrac>
    <msubsup>
      <mover>
        <mi>V</mi>
        <mo>.</mo>
      </mover>
      <mi>v</mi>
      <mstyle>
        <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
      </mstyle>
    </msubsup>
    <msubsup>
      <mover>
        <mi>V</mi>
        <mo>.</mo>
      </mover>
      <mi>t</mi>
      <mstyle>
        <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
      </mstyle>
    </msubsup>
  </mfrac>
</mrow>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0061">The current baseline is during the enclosed structure's 204 hours, the outdoor damper is maintained at a minimum position &#x3b2;<sub>min,b </sub>(10-30% according to test and balance) when the economizer is not enabled. Ideally, if the test and balance practice are accurate, &#x3b2;<sub>min</sub>&#x2267;&#x3b2;<sub>min,b</sub>, the same amount of outdoor air is delivered to the zone <b>202</b>, so no additional ventilation load is introduced from the whole enclosed structure perspective.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0062">If mode=cooling, modulate the damper position to meet {dot over (V)}<sub>o</sub>={dot over (V)}<sub>v </sub>in terms of the whole enclosed structure.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0063">If mode=economizing, modulate the damper position=100%.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0064">If mode=heating, modulate the damper position to meet {dot over (V)}<sub>o</sub>={dot over (V)}<sub>v </sub>in terms of the whole enclosed structure <b>204</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0065">Generally, any of the functions or equations described herein can be implemented using software, firmware, hardware (e.g., fixed logic circuitry), manual processing, or a combination of these implementations. The terms &#x201c;module&#x201d; and &#x201c;functionality&#x201d; as used herein generally represent software, firmware, hardware, or a combination thereof. The communication between modules in the adaptive control device <b>102</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> can be wired, wireless, or some combination thereof. In the case of a software implementation, for instance, the module represents executable instructions that perform specified tasks when executed on a processor, such as the processor <b>106</b> with the adaptive control device <b>102</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The program code can be stored in one or more device-readable storage media, an example of which is the memory <b>108</b> associated with the adaptive control device <b>102</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0066">Example Procedures</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0067">The following discussion describes procedures that may be implemented in an adaptive control device providing control functionality. Aspects of the procedures may be implemented in hardware, firmware, or software, or a combination thereof. The procedures are shown as a set of blocks that specify operations performed by one or more devices and are not necessarily limited to the orders shown for performing the operations by the respective blocks. In portions of the following discussion, reference may be made to the environment <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The features of techniques described below are platform-independent, meaning that the techniques may be implemented on a variety of control device platforms having a variety of processors.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0068"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> depicts a procedure <b>300</b> in an example implementation in which an adaptive control device <b>102</b> provides sequencing commands to multiple zone environmental units. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the adaptive control device receives a plurality of temperature values and a plurality of airflow values from a zone sensor <b>114</b> (Block <b>302</b>). The temperature values and the airflow values may represent a temperature reading and an airflow reading from a specific zone(s) <b>202</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0069">Upon receiving the temperature values and airflow values, the calculation module <b>116</b> may calculate an operational value or operational state of a zone environmental unit's fan compressor, heater, exhaust fan, and damper (Block <b>304</b>). The adaptive control device <b>102</b> may then determine whether more zone sensors <b>114</b> need to transmit temperature values and airflow values (Decision Block <b>306</b>) to the adaptive control device <b>102</b>. If more temperature values and airflow values need to be transmitted (&#x201c;YES&#x201d; from Decision Block <b>306</b>), the adaptive control device may receive these temperature values and airflow values upon/or after transmission (Block <b>302</b>). Otherwise (&#x201c;NO&#x201d; from Decision Block <b>308</b>), the adaptive control device <b>102</b> may transmit sequence commands to the zone environmental units <b>104</b> for sequencing the operation of each zone environmental unit's <b>104</b> fan, compressor, heater, exhaust fan, and damper.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0070">Although techniques to transmit multiple sequencing commands to multiple zone environmental units have been described in language specific to structural features and/or methodological acts, it is to be understood that the appended claims are not necessarily limited to the specific features or acts described. Rather, the specific features and acts are disclosed as exemplary forms of implementing the claimed devices and techniques.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00001" nb-file="US08626345-20140107-M00001.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00001" he="24.72mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08626345-20140107-M00001.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00002" nb-file="US08626345-20140107-M00002.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00002" he="8.13mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08626345-20140107-M00002.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00003" nb-file="US08626345-20140107-M00003.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00003" he="13.38mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08626345-20140107-M00003.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00004" nb-file="US08626345-20140107-M00004.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00004" he="7.79mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08626345-20140107-M00004.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method for controlling a conditioning space including a plurality of zones via a plurality of zone environmental units comprising:
<claim-text>receiving a plurality of temperature values and a plurality of airflow values, the plurality of temperature values and the plurality of airflow values associated with the plurality of zones;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a minimum number of operating supply fans based upon the plurality of airflow values;</claim-text>
<claim-text>operating a first group of supply fans comprising the minimum number of supply fans, each one of the first group of supply fans having a characteristic time offset difference greater than a minimum time offset difference and a characteristic temperature difference greater than a minimum temperature difference; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>operating a second group of supply fans, each one of the second group of supply fans having at least one of (A) a characteristic temperature difference greater than a maximum temperature difference or (B) a characteristic time offset difference greater than a maximum time offset difference and a characteristic temperature difference greater than a minimum temperature difference.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising ceasing operation of the first group of supply fans when at least one of (A) the characteristic temperature difference is less than the minimum temperature difference or (B) the characteristic time offset difference is greater than a maximum time offset difference and the characteristic temperature difference is less than a maximum temperature difference.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising operating a plurality of compressors associated with the first group of supply fans and the second group of supply fans, each one of the plurality of compressors having a characteristic time offset difference greater than a minimum time offset difference and a characteristic temperature difference greater than a minimum temperature difference.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising operating a plurality of heaters associated with the first group of supply fans and the second group of supply fans, each one of the plurality of heaters having a characteristic time offset difference greater than a minimum time offset difference and a characteristic temperature difference greater than a minimum temperature difference.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of zone environmental units comprise a plurality of rooftop units.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of zones comprise a plurality of regions in an enclosed structure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. An adaptive control device for controlling a conditioning space including a plurality of zones comprising:
<claim-text>an input interface operable to receive a plurality of temperature values and a plurality of airflow values, the plurality of temperature values and the plurality of air flow values associated with the plurality of zones;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a memory operable to store one or more modules;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a processor operable to execute the one or more modules to cause the processor to:
<claim-text>determine a minimum number of operating supply fans based upon the plurality of airflow values;</claim-text>
<claim-text>operate a first group of supply fans comprising the minimum number of supply fans, each one of the first group of supply fans having a characteristic time offset difference greater than a minimum time offset difference and a characteristic temperature difference greater than a minimum temperature difference; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>operate a second group of supply fans, each one of the second group of supply fans having at least one of (A) a characteristic temperature difference greater than a maximum temperature difference or (B) a characteristic time offset difference greater than a maximum time offset difference and a characteristic temperature difference greater than a minimum temperature difference;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>an output interface operable to transit a plurality of sequencing commands to a plurality of zone environmental units associated with the first group of supply fans and the second group of supply fans for operating the first group of supply fans and the second group of supply fans.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The adaptive control device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the processor is further operable to execute the one or more modules to cause the processor to cease operation of the first group of supply fans when at least one of (A) the characteristic temperature difference is less than the minimum temperature difference or (B) the characteristic time offset difference is greater than a maximum time offset difference and the characteristic temperature difference is less than a maximum temperature difference.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The adaptive control device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the processor is further operable to execute the one or more modules to cause the processor to operate a plurality of heaters associated with the first group of supply fans and the second group of supply fans, each one of the plurality of heaters having a characteristic time offset difference greater than a minimum time offset difference and a characteristic temperature difference greater than a minimum temperature difference.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The adaptive control device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the processor is further operable to execute the one or more modules to cause the processor to operate a plurality of compressors associated with the first group of supply fans and the second group of supply fans, each one of the plurality of compressors having a characteristic time offset difference greater than a minimum time offset difference and a characteristic temperature difference greater than a minimum temperature difference.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The adaptive control device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of zone environmental units comprise a plurality of rooftop units.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The adaptive control device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of zones comprise a plurality of regions in an enclosed structure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A method comprising:
<claim-text>receiving a plurality of temperature values and a plurality of airflow values, the plurality of temperature values and the plurality of airflow values associated with a plurality of zones within a conditioning space;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a minimum number of operating supply fans based upon the plurality of airflow values;</claim-text>
<claim-text>operating a first group of supply fans comprising the minimum number of supply fans, each one of the first group of supply fans having a characteristic time offset difference greater than a minimum time offset difference and a characteristic temperature difference greater than a minimum temperature difference;</claim-text>
<claim-text>operating a second group of supply fans, each one of the second group of supply fans having at least one of (A) a characteristic temperature difference greater than a maximum temperature difference or (B) a characteristic time offset difference greater than a maximum time offset difference and a characteristic temperature difference greater than a minimum temperature difference;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a mode of operation for a zone environmental unit associated with the first group of supply fans and the second group of supply fans;</claim-text>
<claim-text>operating a plurality of compressors associated with the first group of supply fans and the second group of supply fans when the mode of operation is cooling, each one of the plurality of compressors having a characteristic time offset difference greater than a minimum time offset difference and a characteristic temperature difference greater than a minimum temperature difference when the mode of operation is cooling; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>operating a plurality of heaters associated with the first group of supply fans and the second group of supply fans when the mode of operation is heating, each one of the plurality of heaters having a characteristic time offset difference greater than a minimum time offset difference and a characteristic temperature difference greater than a minimum temperature difference when the mode of operation is heating.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further comprising ceasing operation of the first group of supply fans when at least one of (A) the characteristic temperature difference is less than the minimum temperature difference or (B) the characteristic time offset difference is greater than a maximum time offset difference and the characteristic temperature difference is less than a maximum temperature difference.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
