<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622630-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622630</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12969428</doc-number>
<date>20101215</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>99138415 A</doc-number>
<date>20101109</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>381</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>6</main-group>
<subgroup>36</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>385 77</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Optical fiber connector</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6659654</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kao</name>
<date>20031200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>385 78</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2002090584</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20020300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>15</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>385 77</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120114287</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120510</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lin</last-name>
<first-name>I-Thun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taipei Hsien</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lin</last-name>
<first-name>I-Thun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taipei Hsien</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Lepisto</last-name>
<first-name>Ryan</first-name>
<department>2883</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Chiem</last-name>
<first-name>Erin</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An optical fiber connector includes a coupling portion. The coupling portion includes a first end surface and an opposite second end surface. The first end surface includes a number of lenses arranged thereat and a number of engaging holes formed therein. The second end surface includes a number of optical fiber holes formed therein and aligned with the respective lenses, and a number of posts formed thereon. Each of the posts has a spring member arranged thereon.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="135.55mm" wi="185.00mm" file="US08622630-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="178.48mm" wi="161.46mm" file="US08622630-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="207.77mm" wi="183.90mm" file="US08622630-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="183.90mm" wi="138.26mm" file="US08622630-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="212.51mm" wi="179.15mm" file="US08622630-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to optical fiber connectors.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Optical fiber connectors are widely used in optical fiber communication. Some optical fiber connectors include at least one optical fiber hole and one lens aligned with the hole. The optical fiber connector may be connected to another optical fiber connector or a device. Connecting optical fiber connectors can be difficult, and users may use too much force and damage the connectors.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">What is needed, therefore, is an optical fiber connector which can overcome the above shortcomings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Many aspects of the present optical fiber connector can be better understood with reference to the following drawings. The components in the drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the present optical fiber connector. Moreover, in the drawings, like reference numerals designate corresponding parts throughout the several views.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an isometric view of an optical fiber connector in accordance with a first embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exploded isometric view of the optical fiber connector of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the optical fiber connector including a coupling portion.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is another isometric view of the coupling portion of the optical fiber connector shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is an isometric view of an optical fiber connector in accordance with a second embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Embodiments of the present optical fiber connector will now be described in detail below and with reference to the drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 3</figref>, an optical fiber connector <b>10</b> in accordance with a first embodiment is provided. The optical fiber connector <b>10</b> includes a sheath <b>20</b> and a coupling portion <b>30</b>. The sheath <b>20</b> includes a recess <b>22</b> formed therein, and the coupling portion <b>30</b> is received in the recess <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The sheath <b>20</b> includes a plurality of through holes <b>23</b> defined therein from a back outside surface through to an inner surface <b>220</b> of the recess <b>22</b>, i.e, the through holes <b>23</b> are exposed in the recess <b>22</b>. The inner surface <b>220</b> is a flat surface. The through holes <b>23</b> are configured for receiving and guiding optical fibers (not shown) to the coupling portion <b>30</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the number of the through holes <b>23</b> is two. The sheath <b>20</b> further includes a pole <b>39</b> formed in a front end thereof across the recess <b>22</b> from a bottom surface of the recess <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The coupling portion <b>30</b> includes a first end surface <b>31</b>, a second end surface <b>32</b> opposite to (i.e, facing away from) the first end surface <b>31</b>, and a top surface <b>35</b> perpendicularly interconnecting the first end surface <b>31</b> and the second end surface <b>32</b>. When the coupling portion <b>30</b> is received in the recess <b>22</b>, the first end surface <b>31</b> is exposed to outside. The first end surface <b>31</b> has a groove <b>38</b> formed therein, and the pole <b>39</b> is engaged in the groove <b>38</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the groove <b>38</b> is formed along a central axis of the first end surface <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The first end surface <b>31</b> further includes a plurality of engaging structures formed therein, to be engaged with another optical fiber connector or a device. In the illustrated embodiment, the first end surface <b>31</b> includes two engaging holes <b>37</b> serving as the engaging structures. The engaging holes <b>37</b> are symmetrical about the central axis of the first end surface <b>31</b>, and are arranged adjacent to two sides of the coupling portion <b>30</b>, respectively. In this embodiment the other optical fiber connector or device which is coupled to the optical fiber connector <b>10</b> includes two protrusions to be engaged in the engaging holes <b>37</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The first end surface <b>31</b> further includes two lenses <b>70</b> arranged thereat. In the present embodiment, the lenses <b>70</b> are integrally formed on the first end surface <b>31</b>. The lenses <b>70</b> are also symmetrical about the central axis of the first end surface <b>31</b>, and are arranged adjacent to the groove <b>38</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The second end surface <b>32</b> has a recess <b>34</b> formed in a central area thereof, and the recess <b>34</b> is exposed to the top surface <b>35</b>. A bottom surface <b>340</b> of the recess <b>34</b> is parallel with the top surface <b>35</b>, and an inner surface <b>341</b> of the recess <b>34</b> opposes both the first and second end surfaces <b>31</b>, <b>32</b>. A plurality of optical fiber guiding grooves <b>36</b> corresponding to the through holes <b>23</b> are formed in the bottom surface <b>340</b>, and corresponding blind holes <b>33</b> are formed in the inner surface <b>341</b>. The blind holes <b>33</b> are aligned with the lenses <b>70</b>, respectively. When the coupling portion <b>30</b> is received in the recess <b>22</b>, optical fibers (not shown) from the through holes <b>23</b> can insert into the blind holes <b>33</b> through the guiding grooves <b>36</b>. The recess <b>34</b> exposes part of the optical fibers, such that adhesive can be applied in the recess <b>34</b> to fix the optical fibers in position.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Two posts <b>80</b> are formed on the second end surface <b>32</b>. The posts <b>80</b> are symmetrical about a central axis of the second end surface <b>32</b>, and are arranged adjacent to the recess <b>34</b>. Two spring members <b>40</b> surround the respective posts <b>80</b>, and one end of each of the spring members <b>40</b> can be fixed to the corresponding post <b>80</b>. When the coupling portion <b>30</b> is received in the recess <b>22</b>, the spring members <b>40</b> elastically contact the second end surface <b>32</b> and the inner surface <b>220</b>. In the present embodiment, the spring members <b>40</b> are coil springs and are in a compressed state. The pole <b>39</b> prevents the coupling portion <b>30</b> from escaping out from the recess <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The spring members <b>40</b> allow adjustments to the position of the coupling portion <b>30</b>, such that, when the other optical fiber connector or device is coupled to the coupling portion <b>30</b>, the coupling portion <b>30</b> can be easily and quickly engaged with the other optical fiber connector or device without any damage to the coupling portion <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, an optical fiber connector <b>100</b> in accordance with a second embodiment is provided. The optical fiber connector <b>100</b> is essentially similar to the optical fiber connector <b>10</b> illustrated above, except that an inner surface <b>2200</b> of a sheath <b>200</b> of the optical fiber connector <b>100</b> has two receiving holes <b>240</b> formed therein, and each of the receiving holes <b>240</b> is configured to receive a spring member <b>400</b> and a post <b>800</b> of the coupling portion <b>300</b> and guide movement of the spring member <b>400</b> and the post <b>800</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In other embodiments, the sheath of the optical fiber connector illustrated above can be replaced by a shell of a device. That is, the coupling portion can directly be elastically connected to a device with actions of the spring members, and the optical fibers can just be received in the guiding groove and optical fiber blind hole of the coupling portion.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">It is understood that the above-described embodiments are intended to illustrate rather than limit the disclosure. Variations may be made to the embodiments and methods without departing from the spirit of the disclosure. Accordingly, it is appropriate that the appended claims be construed broadly and in a manner consistent with the scope of the disclosure.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An optical fiber connector, comprising:
<claim-text>a sheath comprising a first recess formed therein and a pole;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a coupling portion detachably received in the first recess of the sheath, the coupling portion comprising a first end surface having a plurality of lenses arranged therein, and a groove defined in a center portion of the first end surface, and an opposing second end surface having a plurality of optical fiber holes formed therein and aligned with the respective lenses; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of spring members arranged between the second end surface and an inner surface of the sheath in the first recess, one end of each of the spring members abutting against the second end surface, and an opposite end of each of the spring members abutting against the inner surface of the sheath in the first recess;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the pole slidably engages in the groove.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The optical fiber connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second end surface of the coupling portion comprises a plurality of posts formed thereon, and the spring members surround the respective posts.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The optical fiber connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the sheath comprises a plurality of receiving holes formed in the inner surface in the first recess, the receiving holes receiving the posts and the spring members therein.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The optical fiber connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the coupling portion comprises a second recess formed therein, and the optical fiber holes are exposed in the second recess.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The optical fiber connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the sheath comprises a plurality of optical fiber holes formed therein, and the optical fiber holes are exposed in the first recess.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The optical fiber connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first end surface further has a plurality of engaging holes formed therein.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The optical fiber connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the pole extends from a bottom surface of the first recess at a front end of the first recess, and the groove is formed in the first end surface along a central axis of the first end surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The optical fiber connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein each of the spring members is a coil spring, the spring member is compressed between the second end surface and the inner surface of the sheath in the first recess, and the pole is configured for preventing the coupling portion from escaping out from the first recess.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. An optical fiber connector comprising:
<claim-text>a sheath comprising a first recess formed therein and a pole;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a coupling portion received in the first recess of the sheath, the coupling portion comprising a first end surface having a plurality of lenses arranged therein, and a groove defined in a center portion of the first end surface, and an opposing second end surface, the second end surface comprising a second recess formed therein, and a plurality of optical fiber holes formed in an inner surface thereof of the coupling portion in the second recess and aligned with the respective lenses; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of spring members arranged between the second end surface and an inner surface of the sheath in the first recess, one end of each of the spring members abutting against the second end surface, and an opposite end of each of the spring members abutting against the inner surface of the sheath in the first recess wherein the pole slidably engages in the groove.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The optical fiber connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the second end surface comprises a plurality of posts formed thereon, and the spring members surround the respective posts.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The optical fiber connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the sheath comprises a plurality of receiving holes formed in the inner surface thereof in the first recess, the receiving holes receiving the posts and the spring members therein.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The optical fiber connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein a bottom surface of the second recess comprises a plurality of guiding grooves formed therein, and the guiding grooves are aligned with the respective optical fiber holes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The optical fiber connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the first end surface further has a plurality of engaging holes formed therein.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The optical fiber connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the pole extends from a bottom surface of the first recess at a front end of the first recess, and the groove is formed in the first end surface along a central axis of the first end surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The optical fiber connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein each of the spring members is a coil spring, the spring member is compressed between the second end surface and the inner surface of the sheath in the first recess, and the pole is configured for preventing the coupling portion from escaping out from the first recess. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
