<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624658-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624658</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13561529</doc-number>
<date>20120730</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>327355</main-classification>
<further-classification>455323</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Frequency mixer having parallel mixer cores</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6807407</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Ji</name>
<date>20041000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>455326</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7205817</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Huang</name>
<date>20070400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7880547</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Lee et al.</name>
<date>20110200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>330295</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8107906</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Lum et al.</name>
<date>20120100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>455137</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8422967</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Rofougaran et al.</name>
<date>20130400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4551271</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>9</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>327355-361</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>455323</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>455326</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Jones</last-name>
<first-name>Theron L.</first-name>
<address>
<city>White Heath</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Davis</last-name>
<first-name>Richard D.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Champaign</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Imbornone</last-name>
<first-name>James</first-name>
<address>
<city>Methuen</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="004" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wang</last-name>
<first-name>Xuejin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fort Collins</city>
<state>CO</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Jones</last-name>
<first-name>Theron L.</first-name>
<address>
<city>White Heath</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Davis</last-name>
<first-name>Richard D.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Champaign</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Imbornone</last-name>
<first-name>James</first-name>
<address>
<city>Methuen</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="004" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wang</last-name>
<first-name>Xuejin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fort Collins</city>
<state>CO</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Advent, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Maxim Integrated Products, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Le</last-name>
<first-name>Dinh T.</first-name>
<department>2816</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A frequency mixer having parallel mixer cores is described that is configured to heterodyne a signal. In an implementation, the frequency mixer includes a first mixer core and a second mixer core. A first balun is connected to the first mixer core and configured to furnish a LO signal occurring in a first range of frequencies to the first mixer core. The mixer includes a second balun coupled to the second mixer core, and the second balun is configured to furnish a LO signal occurring in a second range of frequencies during a second time interval. The mixer includes a first biasing voltage source that is center tapped to the first balun and a second biasing voltage source is center tapped to the second balun to further prevent operation of the at least substantially non-operational mixer core.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="168.66mm" wi="218.36mm" file="US08624658-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="220.13mm" wi="167.72mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624658-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="227.33mm" wi="164.08mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624658-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="242.82mm" wi="164.76mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624658-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="157.14mm" wi="133.77mm" file="US08624658-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="160.10mm" wi="146.98mm" file="US08624658-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">It is often desirable to convert frequencies of a signal from a first frequency band to a second frequency band, especially in radio frequency (RF) systems, such as in cellular applications (e.g., cellular basestations). For example, frequency conversion is typically utilized to allow for the amplification, filtration, and data conversion of a received signal at a frequency other than the RF frequency. Thus, frequency mixers are typically utilized in these RF systems for frequency conversion. Frequency mixers include electrical circuits configured to create new frequencies from two signals applied to the frequency mixer. For example, frequency mixers may be utilized to shift signals from one frequency range to another (e.g., heterodyning the signals).</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">A frequency mixer having parallel mixer cores is described that is configured to heterodyne a signal. In one or more implementations, the frequency mixer includes a first mixer core that is connected to a radio frequency (RF) port and an intermediate frequency (IF) port. The frequency mixer also includes a second mixer core that is connected to the RF port and the IF port. A first local oscillator (LO) balun is connected to the first mixer core and configured to furnish an LO signal occurring in a first limited range of frequencies to the first mixer core during a first time interval. The frequency mixer also includes a second LO balun coupled to the second mixer core. The second LO balun is configured to furnish an LO signal occurring in a second limited range of frequencies to the second mixer core during a second timer interval. The frequency mixer also includes a first biasing voltage source that is center tapped to the first LO balun. The first biasing voltage source is configured to furnish a negative direct current (DC) voltage to the first mixer core when the first mixer core is at least substantially non-operational to further prevent operation of the first mixer core during the second time interval. A second biasing voltage source is center tapped to the second LO balun. The second biasing voltage source is configured to furnish the negative DC voltage to the second mixer core when the second mixer core is at least substantially non-operational to further prevent operation of the second mixer core during the first time interval.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">This Summary is provided to introduce a selection of concepts in a simplified form that are further described below in the Detailed Description. This Summary is not intended to identify key features or essential features of the claimed subject matter, nor is it intended to be used as an aid in determining the scope of the claimed subject matter.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The detailed description is described with reference to the accompanying figures. The use of the same reference numbers in different instances in the description and the figures may indicate similar or identical items.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> is a schematic diagram illustrating a frequency mixer having parallel cores in accordance with an example implementation of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> is a schematic diagram illustrating a frequency mixer having parallel cores in accordance with an example implementation of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</figref> is a schematic diagram illustrating a frequency mixer having parallel cores in accordance with an example implementation of the present disclosure</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1D and 1E</figref> are a circuit diagrams illustrating example implementations of the mixer cores shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A and 1B</figref>, wherein the mixer cores are implemented in a quad field-effect-transistor (FET) ring configuration.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">Overview</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Mixer circuits are commonly used in a number of applications. For example, mixer circuits are often used in radio frequency (RF) applications for up-converting (up-mixing) or down-converting (down-mixing). In this context, up-converting is the process of mixing a base band signal or IF signal, such as a differential IF signal, with an LO signal, such as a differential LO signal, that is generated by a local oscillator circuit that operates in the RF range. This process generates a mixed RF signal with the IF information included with (mixed with) the LO signal generated by the local oscillator. Down-converting is the process of mixing an RF signal, such as a differential RF signal, with an LO signal, such as a differential LO signal, that is generated by a local oscillator circuit that operates in the RF range. This process generates a mixed IF (or baseband) signal with the RF information included with (e.g., mixed with) the LO signal generated by the local oscillator.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">A typical type of mixer circuit includes a passive mixer circuit, which may be implemented using complementary-metal-oxide semiconductor (CMOS) circuit fabrication processes. In such circuits, the operation of such mixer circuits is dependent on the linear range of those circuits. Thus, the linear range of the circuit affects the one decibel (1 dB) compression point and the third intercept point (IP3), which are measures of the adverse affects of non-linearities on the gain and performance of such circuits. In this respect, current approaches for implementing passive mixer circuits have certain limitations. These limitations include limited linear ranges, which result in 1 dB compression points and IP3 points that are unacceptable for RF and IF signals with higher amplitudes (e.g. high signal swings).</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Accordingly, a frequency mixer is described that extends the range (e.g., signal swing) of the RF and IF signals while preventing degradation of the 1 dB metric for wideband, high-linearity multi-core mixers. In one or more implementations, the frequency mixer includes parallel mixer cores. The parallel mixer cores include a first mixer core that is connected to a radio frequency (RF) port and an intermediate frequency (IF) port as well as a second mixer core that is connected to the RF port and the IF port. A first local oscillator (LO) balun is connected to the first mixer core and configured to furnish an LO signal occurring in a first limited range of frequencies to the first mixer core during a first time interval. The frequency mixer also includes a second LO balun coupled to the second mixer core. The second LO balun is configured to furnish an LO signal occurring in a second limited range of frequencies to the second mixer core during a second time interval. The frequency mixer also includes a first biasing voltage source that is center tapped to the first LO balun. The first biasing voltage source is configured to furnish a negative direct current (DC) voltage to the first mixer core when the first mixer core is at least substantially non-operational to further prevent operation of the first mixer core during the second time interval. A second biasing voltage source is center tapped to the second LO balun. The second biasing voltage source is configured to furnish the negative DC voltage to the second mixer core when the second mixer core is at least substantially non-operational to further prevent operation of the second mixer core during the first time interval. It is understood that this application may be extended to N parallel cores, where N is the number of parallel cores.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">Example Frequency Mixers</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A through 1E</figref> illustrate a frequency mixer <b>100</b> in accordance with example implementations of the present disclosure. As shown, the frequency mixer <b>100</b> is a passive mixer configured to generate signals having new frequencies from a plurality of signals applied to the frequency mixer <b>100</b>. For example, the mixer <b>100</b> may be configured to perform up-conversion to an input signal such that the frequency of the output signal is higher from the frequency of the input signal. In another example, the mixer <b>100</b> may be configured to perform down-conversion of the input signal such that the frequency of the output signal is lower from the frequency of the input signal. Up-conversion mixers are typically utilized in transmitters, and down-conversion mixers are typically utilized in receivers. For example, up-converting includes the process of mixing a base band signal or IF signal, such as a differential IF signal, with an LO signal, such as a differential LO signal, that is generated by a local oscillator circuit that operates in the RF range. In another example, down-converting is the process of mixing an RF signal, such as a differential RF signal, with an LO signal, such as a differential LO signal, that is generated by a local oscillator circuit that operates in the RF range.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A through 1C</figref>, the frequency mixer <b>100</b> illustrated includes at least two parallel mixer cores <b>102</b>, <b>104</b>. The mixer cores <b>102</b>, <b>104</b> are coupled to two sets of differential ports (e.g., terminals) <b>106</b>, <b>108</b>. As shown, the frequency mixer <b>100</b> includes differential radio frequency (RF) ports <b>106</b>A (RF+), <b>106</b>B (RF&#x2212;) and differential intermediate frequency (IF) ports <b>108</b>A (IF+), <b>108</b>B (IF&#x2212;). The frequency mixer <b>100</b> also includes local oscillator (LO) ports <b>110</b>, <b>111</b> (<b>110</b>A [LO+], <b>110</b>B [LO&#x2212;], <b>111</b>A [LO+], <b>111</b>B [LO&#x2212;]) that are configured to facilitate conversion of signals furnished to the mixer <b>100</b>. As shown, the LO ports <b>110</b>A, <b>110</b>B are associated with the first mixer core <b>102</b>, and the LO ports <b>111</b>A, <b>111</b>B are associated with the second mixer core <b>104</b>. In an implementation, the LO portions <b>110</b>A, <b>110</b>B, <b>111</b>A, <b>111</b>B are utilized to furnish a differential LO signal to the gates of the respective transistors. The LO signal includes waveform characteristics occurring within the RF range. The RF ports <b>106</b>A, <b>106</b>B, the IF ports <b>108</b>A, <b>108</b>B, and the LO ports <b>110</b>A, <b>110</b>B are common to the first mixer core <b>102</b>, and the RF ports <b>106</b>A, <b>106</b>B, the IF ports <b>108</b>A, <b>108</b>B, and the LO ports <b>111</b>A, <b>111</b>B are common to the second mixer core <b>104</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1D and 1E</figref> illustrate example implementations of mixer cores <b>102</b>, <b>104</b>. Each mixer core <b>102</b>, <b>104</b> may comprise a quad FET ring mixer core that includes four transmission gates <b>112</b>, <b>114</b>, <b>116</b>, <b>118</b> arranged in a ring configuration (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref>). In one or more implementations, the transmission gates <b>112</b>, <b>114</b>, <b>116</b>, <b>118</b> may be metal-oxide-semiconductor field-effect transistors (MOSFETs). For example, each transmission gate (transistor) <b>112</b>, <b>114</b>, <b>116</b>, <b>118</b> may be an n-type MOSFET device. In another example, each transistor <b>112</b>, <b>114</b>, <b>116</b>, <b>118</b> may be a p-type MOSFET device. The transistors <b>112</b>, <b>114</b>, <b>116</b>, <b>118</b> each include a source contact (e.g., electrode), a drain contact, and a gate contact, which provide an electrical connection to the respective regions (e.g., source region, drain region, gate) of each transistor. Thus, the transistor <b>112</b> includes a source contact <b>112</b>A, a drain contact <b>112</b>B, and a gate contact <b>112</b>C; the transistor <b>114</b> includes a source contact <b>114</b>A, a drain contact <b>114</b>B, and a gate contact <b>114</b>C; the transistor <b>116</b> includes a source contact <b>116</b>A, a drain contact <b>116</b>B, and a gate contact <b>116</b>C; and the transistor <b>118</b> includes a source contact <b>118</b>A, a drain contact <b>118</b>B, and a gate contact <b>118</b>C. The transistors <b>112</b>, <b>114</b>, <b>116</b>, <b>118</b> each have an open configuration (e.g., open circuit to prevent current flow) and a closed configuration (e.g., closed circuit to allow current flow).</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">For the purposes of the present disclosure, source and drain contacts are described using the reference numbers <b>112</b>A, <b>112</b>B, <b>114</b>A, <b>114</b>B, <b>116</b>A, <b>116</b>B, <b>118</b>A, <b>118</b>B. While these example source and drain contacts are shown in a specific configuration, it will be appreciated that other configurations may be used (e.g., configurations where one or more source and drain regions are interchangeable in implementations of the frequency mixer <b>100</b>). In a specific implementation of the frequency mixer <b>100</b>, the quad FET ring mixer includes the drain contact <b>112</b>B of the first transistor <b>112</b> and the drain contact <b>114</b>B of the second transistor <b>114</b> are connected together (e.g., in communication) via an electrical connection (e.g., a wire trace, and so forth), which is connected to the RF port <b>106</b>B (RF&#x2212;). The quad FET ring mixer also includes the source contact <b>112</b>A of the first transistor <b>112</b> and the drain contact <b>116</b>B of the third transistor <b>116</b> are connected together via an electrical connection, which is connected to the IF port <b>108</b>A (IF+). The source contact <b>116</b>A of the third transistor <b>116</b> and the source contact <b>118</b>A of the fourth transistor <b>118</b> are communicatively connected together via an electrical connection, which is connected to the RF port <b>106</b>A (RF+). The source contact <b>114</b>A of the second transistor <b>114</b> and the drain contact <b>118</b>B of the fourth transistor <b>118</b> are communicatively connected together via an electrical connection, which is connected to the IF port <b>108</b>B (IF&#x2212;). The gate contact <b>112</b>C of the first transistor <b>112</b> and the gate contact <b>118</b>C of the fourth transistor <b>118</b> are each communicatively connected to the LO port <b>110</b>A (LO+) of the first mixer core <b>102</b> (and are communicatively connected to the LO port <b>111</b>A (LO+) within the second mixer core <b>104</b>). The gate contact <b>114</b>C of the second transistor <b>114</b> and the gate contact <b>116</b>C of the third transistor <b>116</b> are communicatively connected to the LO port <b>110</b>B (LO&#x2212;) of the first mixer core <b>102</b> (and communicatively connected to the LO port <b>111</b>B (LO&#x2212;) within the second mixer core <b>104</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In an implementation, when the alternating current (AC) voltage at the LO port <b>110</b>A furnishes a sufficient voltage to the respective gate contacts <b>112</b>C, <b>118</b>C, the respective transistors <b>112</b>, <b>118</b> transition from the open configuration to the closed configuration to allow for current flow and transistors <b>114</b>, <b>116</b> transition from the closed configuration to the open configuration due to the differential nature of the LO signal. While the transistors <b>112</b>, <b>118</b> are in the closed configuration, the RF port <b>106</b>B (RF&#x2212;) is communicatively connected to the IF port <b>108</b>A (IF+). Additionally, while the transistors <b>112</b>, <b>118</b> are in the closed configuration, the RF port <b>106</b>A (RF+) is also communicatively connected to the IF port <b>108</b>B (IF&#x2212;). Thus, the signal present at the RF port <b>106</b>B may pass through to the IF port <b>108</b>A, and vice versa. Additionally, the signal present at the RF port <b>106</b>A may pass through to the IF port <b>108</b>B, and vice versa. During this portion of the LO cycle, the transistors <b>114</b>, <b>116</b> are in the open configuration, and when the LO AC voltage inverts the LO port <b>110</b>B furnishes a sufficient voltage to the respective gate contacts <b>114</b>C, <b>116</b>C, the respective transistors <b>114</b>, <b>116</b> transition from the open configuration to the closed configuration to allow for current flow. While the transistors <b>114</b>, <b>116</b> are in the closed configuration, the RF port <b>106</b>B (RF&#x2212;) is communicatively connected to the IF port <b>108</b>B (IF&#x2212;). Additionally, while the transistors <b>114</b>, <b>116</b> are in the closed configuration, the RF port <b>106</b>A (RF+) is communicatively connected to the IF port <b>108</b>A (IF+). Thus, the signal present at the RF port <b>106</b>A may pass through to the IF port <b>108</b>A, and vice versa. Additionally, the signal present at the RF port <b>106</b>B may pass through to the IF port <b>108</b>B, and vice versa. During this portion of the LO cycle, the transistors <b>112</b>, <b>118</b> are in the open configuration. Thus, the differential AC signal at the LO ports <b>110</b>,<b>111</b> commutates the connections between the differential RF and IF ports (e.g., ports <b>106</b>A, <b>106</b>B, <b>108</b>A, <b>108</b>B).</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A through 1C</figref>, the frequency mixer <b>100</b> includes a first balanced-unbalanced device (balun) <b>120</b>, a second balun <b>122</b>, a third balun <b>124</b>, and a fourth balun <b>126</b>. In an implementation, the baluns <b>120</b>, <b>122</b>, <b>124</b>, <b>126</b> comprise a transformer coupled to various ports and/or circuitry configured to facilitate transmission of various RF signals (e.g., differential LO signals, differential RF signals). For example, the first balun <b>120</b> is coupled to a LO signal circuit <b>128</b> that is configured to furnish the LO signal. In implementations, the LO signal is a radio frequency (RF) signal communicated to the first balun <b>120</b> via the LO signal circuit <b>128</b>. As shown, the first balun <b>120</b> is coupled to a first driver <b>130</b> and a second driver <b>132</b>. The first driver <b>130</b> is connected to the second balun <b>122</b>, and the second driver <b>132</b> is connected to the third balun <b>124</b>. The drivers <b>130</b>, <b>132</b> are configured to amplify the LO signal before furnishing the amplified LO signal to the respective baluns <b>122</b>, <b>124</b>. For instance, the driver <b>130</b> furnishes an amplified LO signal to the second balun <b>122</b>, and the driver <b>132</b> furnishes an amplified LO signal to the third balun <b>124</b>. The second balun <b>122</b> and the third balun <b>124</b> are connected to a V<sub>CC </sub>voltage source <b>134</b> via respective center taps <b>136</b>, <b>138</b> at the primary winding portion <b>122</b>A, <b>124</b>A of the baluns <b>122</b>, <b>124</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A through 1C</figref>). In an implementation, the V<sub>CC </sub>voltage source <b>134</b> is a DC bias utilized to furnish a DC voltage to bias (and at least partially power) the respective drivers <b>130</b>, <b>132</b> (e.g., the center tap <b>136</b> is associated with the first driver <b>130</b>; the center tap <b>138</b> is associated with the second driver <b>132</b>). For example, the V<sub>CC </sub>voltage source <b>134</b> is configured to furnish a DC voltage to the primary winding portion <b>122</b>A of the balun <b>122</b> during the first time interval, and the V<sub>CC </sub>voltage source <b>134</b> is configured to furnish a DC voltage to the primary winding portion <b>124</b>A of the balun <b>124</b> during the second time interval.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In one or more implementations, the mixer <b>100</b> allows operation in two or more separate LO frequency bands. Thus, the LO signal circuit <b>128</b> is configured to furnish a LO signal to the first balun <b>120</b> occurring in a first frequency band (RF signal having a first limited range of frequencies) and to furnish a LO signal to the first balun <b>120</b> occurring in a second frequency band (RF signal having a second limited range of frequencies). In an implementation, an input pin <b>129</b> is configured to selectively activate and/or deactivate the mixer cores <b>102</b>, <b>104</b> by alternately powering the drivers <b>130</b>, <b>132</b>. For example, when the LO signal is occurring in the first frequency band, the input pin <b>129</b> is configured to enable operation of the first mixer core <b>102</b> by sufficiently powering the driver <b>130</b> (and not powering the second driver <b>132</b>), and when the LO signal is occurring in the second frequency band, the input pin <b>129</b> is configured to enable operation of the second mixer core <b>104</b> by sufficiently power the driver <b>132</b> (and not powering the first driver <b>130</b>). In an implementation, the input pin <b>129</b> may comprise control circuitry configured to selectively (e.g., alternately) power the drivers <b>130</b>, <b>132</b> as a function of the frequency band of the signal.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">A high signal swing at the IF ports (<b>108</b>A, <b>108</b>B) or the RF ports (<b>106</b>A, <b>106</b>B) may cause the gate-to-source voltage (V<sub>GS</sub>) to attain a greater positive voltage as compared to the threshold voltage (V<sub>T</sub>) of the respective transistor (V<sub>GS</sub>&#x3e;V<sub>T </sub>when the LO signal at the gates of the transistors is approximately zero volts (0V)), which causes the at least substantially inoperative mixer core <b>102</b>, <b>104</b> to become at least partially enabled (where conduction occurs between the source and the drain of the respective transistor). This may lead to a degraded P 1 dB (output power at one (1) decibel (dB) compression point) as compared to mixer cores (e.g., mixer cores <b>102</b>, <b>104</b>) having a completely inoperative mixer core and greater signal distortion at high signal levels. For example, an RF signal having a high signal swing may occur in a range of at least approximately one and a half gigahertz to at least approximately three gigahertz (1.5-3 GHz) at the drain and source regions of the transistors of the at least substantially inoperative mixer core may cause the transistors of the at least substantially inoperative mixer core to become at least partially operational during a portion (e.g., negative peak or trough) of the RF cycle. In another example, the RF signal range may be at least approximately one thousand six hundred and fifty megahertz to at least approximately two thousand eight hundred and fifty (1,650-2,850 MHz), with an RF signal breakpoint of at least approximately two gigahertz (2 GHz) separating the band of operation between the mixer cores <b>102</b>, <b>104</b>. Thus, the LO signal may include a negative direct current (DC) voltage to furnish an additional negative voltage to the gates of the transistors, which serves to reduce the possibility that the transistors of the at least substantially inoperative mixer core <b>102</b>, <b>104</b> become at least partially operational (at least partially enabled) during high RF or IF signal swings, which is described in greater detail below. Thus, the additional negative voltage applied to the gates of the transistors of the disabled mixer core <b>102</b>, <b>104</b> serves to require a greater negative voltage to be applied to the RF port <b>106</b>, or the IF port <b>108</b>, of the source and/or drain regions before the transistor becomes conductive.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In an implementation, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>, the secondary windings <b>122</b>B, <b>124</b>B of the second balun <b>122</b> and the third baluns <b>124</b> are connected to a respective biasing voltage source <b>144</b>, <b>145</b> configured to furnish a DC bias voltage to the LO signal. In a specific implementation, the biasing voltage source is a positive or negative threshold voltage (+/&#x2212;V<sub>T</sub>) source configured to furnish a voltage at least approximately equal to +/&#x2212;V<sub>T </sub>of the transistors <b>112</b>, <b>114</b>, <b>116</b>, <b>118</b> via center taps <b>140</b>, <b>142</b>. For example, the center taps <b>140</b>, <b>142</b> are connected to a first and a second biasing voltage source <b>144</b>, <b>145</b> (e.g., V<sub>T </sub>voltage source), respectively. The biasing voltage source <b>144</b>, <b>145</b> are configured to furnish the proper V<sub>T </sub>voltage to the center taps <b>140</b>, <b>142</b>, respectively. In other implementations, the DC biasing voltage source <b>144</b>, <b>145</b> powering the at least substantially non-operational mixer core may furnish a voltage ranging from at least approximately seventy percent to at least approximately ninety percent (70%-90%) of a negative (&#x2212;)V<sub>T </sub>of the transistors <b>112</b>, <b>114</b>, <b>116</b>, <b>118</b>. However, it is understood that more negative voltages may be desirable. For example, when the first mixer core <b>102</b> is enabled, or operational, (and the second mixer core <b>104</b> is at least substantially disabled, or at least substantially non-operational) the V<sub>T </sub>furnished to the center tap <b>140</b> is at least approximately a positive V<sub>T </sub>voltage, and the V<sub>T </sub>furnished to the center tap <b>142</b> is an at least a substantially negative V<sub>T </sub>voltage. In another example, when the second mixer core <b>104</b> is enabled (and the first mixer core <b>102</b> is at least substantially disabled) the V<sub>T </sub>voltage furnished to the center tap <b>142</b> is an at least approximately positive (+) V<sub>T </sub>voltage, and the V<sub>T </sub>voltage furnished to the center tap <b>140</b> is an at least substantially negative (&#x2212;) V<sub>T </sub>voltage. The positive (+) V<sub>T </sub>voltage serves to function as a center DC voltage for which the LO signal is centered about, which may generate an at least approximately fifty percent (50%) duty cycle for the enabled (on) mixer switching. As described above, the negative (&#x2212;) V<sub>T </sub>voltage serves to assist in preventing the inoperative mixer core transistors from becoming at least partially enabled.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In another implementation, the frequency mixer <b>100</b> may not include the negative biasing voltages to the at least substantially disabled mixer core center taps <b>140</b>, <b>142</b>. In this implementation, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref>, a positive DC bias voltage may be applied directly to the RF signal. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref>, the RF signal is furnished to the frequency mixer <b>100</b> via the RF (fourth) balun <b>126</b>. In an implementation, the secondary winding <b>126</b>A of the RF balun <b>126</b> may be connected to a center tap <b>146</b>, which is connected to a positive DC biasing voltage source (V<sub>AC</sub>) <b>148</b>. Thus, the V<sub>AC </sub>voltage may sufficiently bias the RF signal such that the signal swings do not cause conduction between the respective source and drain regions of the at least substantially disabled transistors (of the at least substantially disabled mixer core). The V<sub>AC </sub>voltage may be approximately equal to the V<sub>T </sub>of the transistors <b>112</b>, <b>114</b>, <b>116</b>, <b>118</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In another implementation, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</figref>, the biasing voltage sources <b>144</b>, <b>145</b> may be each coupled to respective differential impedance feeds <b>150</b>, <b>152</b>. As shown, the first differential impedance feed <b>150</b> is coupled to the balun <b>122</b>, and the second differential impedance feed <b>152</b> is coupled to the balun <b>124</b>. The biasing voltage sources <b>144</b>, <b>145</b> are configured to furnish a negative DC bias voltage to the respective differential impedance feed <b>150</b>, <b>152</b>, which furnishes a negative DC bias voltage to the respective balun <b>122</b>, <b>124</b>. For example, the biasing voltage source <b>144</b> is configured to furnish a negative DC bias voltage to the first differential impedance feed <b>150</b> when the first mixer core <b>102</b> is at least substantially inoperative (the first differential impedance feed <b>150</b> is configured to furnish a negative DC bias voltage to the balun <b>122</b>). The biasing voltage source <b>145</b> is configured to furnish a negative DC bias voltage to the second differential impedance feed <b>152</b> when the second mixer core <b>104</b> is at least substantially inoperative (the second differential impedance feed <b>152</b> is configured to furnish a negative DC bias voltage to the balun <b>124</b>). In one or more implementations, the differential impedance feeds <b>150</b>, <b>152</b> comprise impedance components <b>150</b>A, <b>150</b>B and impedance components <b>152</b>A, <b>152</b>B, respectively. The impedance components <b>150</b>A, <b>150</b>B, <b>152</b>A, <b>152</b>B may comprise resistive components, inductive components, combinations thereof, or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The frequency mixer <b>100</b> may also include a DC biasing voltage source <b>154</b> that is connected to the IF ports <b>108</b>A, <b>108</b>B. The DC biasing voltage source <b>154</b> is configured to furnish a positive DC voltage to the IF ports <b>108</b>A, <b>108</b>B. As shown, the DC biasing voltage source <b>154</b> is connected to an impedance component <b>156</b>A, and the impedance component <b>156</b>A is connected to the IF port <b>108</b>A. The DC biasing voltage source <b>154</b> is also connected to an impedance component <b>156</b>B, and the impedance component <b>156</b>B is connected to the IF port <b>108</b>B.</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">CONCLUSION</heading>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Although the subject matter has been described in language specific to structural features and/or process operations, it is to be understood that the subject matter defined in the appended claims is not necessarily limited to the specific features or acts described above. Rather, the specific features and acts described above are disclosed as example forms of implementing the claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A frequency mixer comprising:
<claim-text>a first mixer core coupled to a radio frequency (RF) port and an intermediate frequency (IF) port;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second mixer core coupled to the RF port and the IF port;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first local oscillator (LO) balun coupled to the first mixer core, the first LO balun configured to furnish a first LO signal to the first mixer core during a first time interval;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second LO balun coupled to the second mixer core, the second LO balun configured to furnish a second LO signal to the second mixer core during a second time interval, the first time interval different than the second time interval;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first biasing voltage source electrically connected to the first LO balun, the first biasing voltage source configured to furnish a negative direct current (DC) voltage to the first mixer core when the first mixer core is at least substantially non-operational;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second biasing voltage source electrically connected to the second LO balun, the second biasing voltage source configured to furnish the negative DC voltage to the second mixer core when the second mixer core is at least substantially non-operational;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first driver coupled to the first LO balun, the first driver configured to amplify the first LO signal during the first time interval;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second driver coupled to the second LO balun, the second driver configured to amplify the second LO signal during the second time interval; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>control circuitry operatively coupled to the first driver, the second driver, the first biasing voltage source the second biasing voltage source, the control circuitry configured to selectively power the first driver during the first time interval and to selectively power the second driver during the second time interval, the control circuitry configured to cause the first biasing voltage source to furnish a negative direct current (DC) voltage to the first mixer core when the first mixer core is at least substantially non-operational and to cause the second biasing voltage source to furnish the negative DC voltage to the second mixer core when the second mixer core is at least substantially non-operational.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The frequency mixer as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first biasing voltage source is electrically connected to the first LO balun via a center tap connection and the second biasing voltage source is electrically connected to the second LO balun via a center tap connection.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The frequency mixer as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first biasing voltage source is connected to a first differential impedance feed, the first differential impedance feed connected to the first LO balun, the first biasing voltage source configured to furnish a negative voltage to the first differential impedance feed when the first mixer core is at least substantially non-operational, wherein the second biasing voltage source is connected to a second differential impedance feed, the second differential impedance feed connected to the second LO balun, the second biasing voltage source configured to furnish a negative voltage to the second differential impedance feed when the second mixer core is at least substantially non-operational.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The frequency mixer as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a positive direct current (DC) biasing voltage source coupled to IF ports, the DC biasing voltage source configured to furnish a positive DC voltage to the IF ports.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The frequency mixer as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first LO balun and the second LO balun include a primary winding portion and a secondary winding portion, wherein a first biasing voltage source is electrically connected to the primary winding portion of the first LO balun and the second LO balun, the first biasing voltage source configured to furnish a DC voltage for powering the first driver during the first time interval and for powering the second driver during the second time interval, wherein a second biasing voltage source is electrically connected to the secondary winding portion of the first LO balun, the second biasing voltage source configured to furnish a negative voltage to prevent operation of the first mixer core during the second time interval, and wherein a third biasing voltage source center is electrically connected to the secondary winding portion of the second LO balun, the third biasing voltage source configured to furnish a negative voltage to prevent operation of the second mixer core during the first time interval.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A frequency mixer comprising:
<claim-text>a first mixer core coupled to a radio frequency (RF) port and an intermediate frequency (IF) port;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second mixer core coupled to the RF port and the IF port;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first local oscillator (LO) balun coupled to the first mixer core, the first LO balun configured to furnish a first LO signal to the first mixer core during a first time interval;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second LO balun coupled to the second mixer core, the second LO balun configured to furnish a second LO signal to the second mixer core during a second time interval, the first time interval different than the second time interval;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a RF balun coupled to the RF port, the RF balun configured to furnish a RF signal to the RF port;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a biasing voltage source electrically connected to the RF balun, the biasing voltage source configured to furnish a positive DC voltage to bias the RF signal about the positive DC voltage to disable the second mixer core when the first mixer core is enabled and to disable the first mixer core when the second mixer core is disabled;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first driver coupled to the first LO balun, the first driver configured to amplify the first LO signal during the first time interval;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second driver coupled to the second LO balun, the second driver configured to amplify the second LO signal during the second time interval; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>control circuitry operatively coupled to the biasing voltage source, the first driver, and the second driver, the control circuitry configured to selectively power the first driver during the first time interval and to selectively power the second driver during the second time interval, the control circuitry configured to cause the biasing voltage source to furnish a positive DC voltage to bias the RF signal about the positive DC voltage to disable the second mixer core when the first mixer core is enabled and to disable the first mixer core when the second mixer core is disabled.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The frequency mixer as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein at least one core mixer includes a metal-oxide-semiconductor field-effect transistor (MOSFET) device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The frequency mixer as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein a positive DC voltage is at least approximately equal to a threshold voltage of the MOSFET device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The frequency mixer as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the first LO balun and the second LO balun include a primary winding portion and a secondary winding portion, wherein a first biasing voltage source is electrically connected to the primary winding portion of the first LO balun and the second LO balun, the first biasing voltage source configured to furnish a DC voltage for powering the first driver during the first time interval and for powering the second driver during the second time interval, wherein a second biasing voltage source is electrically connected to the secondary winding portion of the first LO balun, the second biasing voltage source configured to furnish a negative voltage to prevent operation of the first mixer core during the second time interval, and wherein a third biasing voltage source center is electrically connected to the secondary winding portion of the second LO balun, the third biasing voltage source configured to furnish a negative voltage to prevent operation of the second mixer core during the first time interval.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
