<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623447-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623447</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12957445</doc-number>
<date>20101201</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>12</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>427 58</main-classification>
<further-classification>427384</further-classification>
<further-classification>427387</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Method for coating dielectric composition for fabricating thin-film transistors</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6440642</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Shelnut et al.</name>
<date>20020800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>430315</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7754510</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Wu et al.</name>
<date>20100700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438 30</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7795614</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Wu et al.</name>
<date>20100900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257 47</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7829625</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Wu et al.</name>
<date>20101100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>524506</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8154080</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Wu et al.</name>
<date>20120400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257347</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0094752</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ito et al.</name>
<date>20040500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0208779</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Klauk et al.</name>
<date>20050900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438795</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0215713</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hessell et al.</name>
<date>20050900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0244662</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Horn et al.</name>
<date>20051100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>428469</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0166456</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kuehnle et al.</name>
<date>20070700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>427240</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0093114</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Burns et al.</name>
<date>20090400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0042790</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lin</name>
<date>20110200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257635</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1085529</doc-number>
<kind>A2</kind>
<date>20010300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>13</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>427 58</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>427384-387</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120142515</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120607</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wu</last-name>
<first-name>Yiliang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Oakville</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CA</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liu</last-name>
<first-name>Ping</first-name>
<address>
<city>Mississauga</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CA</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wigglesworth</last-name>
<first-name>Anthony James</first-name>
<address>
<city>Oakville</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CA</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="004" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hu</last-name>
<first-name>Nan-Xing</first-name>
<address>
<city>Oakville</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CA</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wu</last-name>
<first-name>Yiliang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Oakville</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liu</last-name>
<first-name>Ping</first-name>
<address>
<city>Mississauga</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wigglesworth</last-name>
<first-name>Anthony James</first-name>
<address>
<city>Oakville</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="004" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hu</last-name>
<first-name>Nan-Xing</first-name>
<address>
<city>Oakville</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Fay Sharpe LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Xerox Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Norwalk</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Talbot</last-name>
<first-name>Brian K</first-name>
<department>1715</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An electronic device, such as a thin-film transistor, includes a substrate and a dielectric layer formed from a dielectric composition. The dielectric composition includes a dielectric material, a crosslinking agent, and a thermal acid generator. In particular embodiments, the dielectric material comprises a lower-k dielectric material and a higher-k dielectric material. When deposited, the lower-k dielectric material and the higher-k dielectric material form separate phases. The thermal acid generator allows the dielectric layer to be cured at relatively lower temperatures and/or shorter time periods, permitting the selection of lower-cost substrate materials that would otherwise be deformed by the curing of the dielectric layer.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="61.13mm" wi="118.36mm" file="US08623447-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="202.10mm" wi="121.50mm" file="US08623447-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="207.35mm" wi="117.26mm" file="US08623447-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present disclosure relates, in various embodiments, to thin-film transistors (TFTs) and/or other electronic devices comprising a dielectric layer. The dielectric layer is formed from a dielectric composition as described herein that includes a thermal acid generator. This allows the dielectric composition to be cured at a lower temperature and for a shorter period of time, enabling the use of roll-to-roll manufacturing and other processes.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">TFTs are generally composed of, on a substrate, an electrically conductive gate electrode, source and drain electrodes, an electrically insulating gate dielectric layer which separates the gate electrode from the source and drain electrodes, and a semiconducting layer which is in contact with the gate dielectric layer and bridges the source and drain electrodes. Their performance can be determined by the field effect mobility and the current on/off ratio of the overall transistor. High mobility and high on/off ratio are desired.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Organic thin-film transistors (OTFTs) can be used in applications such as radio frequency identification (RFID) tags and backplane switching circuits for displays, such as signage, readers, and liquid crystal displays, where high switching speeds and/or high density are not essential. They also have attractive mechanical properties such as being physically compact, lightweight, and flexible.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Organic thin-film transistors can be fabricated using low-cost solution-based patterning and deposition techniques, such as spin coating, solution casting, dip coating, stencil/screen printing, flexography, gravure, offset printing, ink jet-printing, micro-contact printing, and the like, or a combination of these processes. Such processes are generally simpler and more cost effective compared to the complex photolithographic processes used in fabricating silicon-based thin-film transistor circuits for electronic devices. To enable the use of these solution-based processes in fabricating thin-film transistor circuits, solution processable materials are therefore required.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In this regard, gate dielectric layers may be formed by these solution-based processes. However, the gate dielectric layer so formed should be free of pinholes and possess low surface roughness (or high surface smoothness), low leakage current, a high dielectric constant, a high breakdown voltage, adhere well to the gate electrode, and offer other functionality. It should also be compatible with semiconductor materials because the interface between the dielectric layer and the organic semiconductor layer critically affects the performance of the TFT.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Roll-to-roll manufacturing refers to the process, still somewhat in development, of creating electronic devices on a roll of flexible plastic or metal foil, similar to the gravure, offset, and flexographic printing processes used with paper. It is contemplated that large circuits made with thin-film transistors and other devices can be easily patterned onto these large substrates, which can be up to a few metres wide and 50 km long. This type of manufacturing would allow for large-scale low-cost devices, especially when compared to normal semiconductor manufacturing processes that use photolithography techniques on inch-size silicon wafers.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Low temperatures and increased speed of processing are critical to roll-to-roll manufacturing. It would be desirable to provide a dielectric layer and/or dielectric composition that could be processed at lower temperatures and/or shorter time periods, to allow for manufacture of an electronic device using roll-to-roll manufacturing and other processes.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">It would be also desirable to have a dielectric composition with good shelf-life at room temperature, which cures or crosslinks quickly at an elevated temperature.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Disclosed in embodiments are electronic devices and processes for making such electronic devices. Generally, the dielectric layer is formed from a dielectric composition as described herein that includes a thermal acid generator. This composition allows for curing of the dielectric composition at relatively lower temperatures and relatively shorter times. The electronic device comprises a dielectric layer, and the dielectric layer includes a crosslinking dielectric material and a thermal acid generator. In embodiments, the electronic devices are thin film transistors, particularly thin film transistors on a flexible substrate, such as low-cost polyethylene terephthalate (PET).</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Also disclosed in various embodiments is a process for fabricating an electronic device, comprising: depositing a dielectric composition on a substrate, the dielectric composition comprising a dielectric material, a crosslinking agent, and a thermal acid generator; and heating the dielectric composition to cure the dielectric composition, forming a dielectric layer on the substrate. A semiconductor layer can also be formed on the substrate, depending on various applications.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The thermal acid generator may be a hydrocarbylsulfonic acid blocked or neutralized with an amine. The thermal acid generator may be present in the amount of from about 0.001 to about 3 wt % of the dielectric material.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In some embodiments, the dielectric material comprises a lower-k dielectric material and a higher-k dielectric material. The lower-k dielectric material may have a dielectric constant of less than 4.0. The higher-k dielectric material may have a dielectric constant of 4.0 or higher. In particular combinations, the lower-k dielectric material is an acid-sensitive dielectric material selected from the group consisting of a small molecular organosilane, an oligomeric silane, a polysiloxane, a polyhedral oligomeric silsesquioxane, a silsesquioxane, a poly(silsesquioxane), and combinations thereof; and the higher-k dielectric material is selected from the group consisting of a polyimide, a polyester, a polyether, a polyacrylate, a polyvinyl, a polyketone, a polysulfone, a molecular glass compound, and combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The dielectric composition can be heated at a temperature of from about 80&#xb0; C. to about 140&#xb0; C. The dielectric composition may be heated for a period of from about 0.5 minutes to about 10 minutes.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In particular embodiments, the dielectric composition is heated at a temperature of from about 80&#xb0; C. to about 120&#xb0; C. for a period of from about 0.5 minutes to about 5 minutes.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Also disclosed is a dielectric composition that comprises a dielectric material, a crosslinking agent, a thermal acid generator, and an optional solvent.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The dielectric material may comprise an acid-sensitive dielectric material. In some embodiments, the dielectric material comprises a lower-k dielectric material and a higher-k dielectric material, wherein both the lower-k dielectric material and the higher-k dielectric material are miscible in the solvent.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The thermal acid generator may be a polymeric blocked sulfonic acid ester, an amine neutralized substituted naphthalenesulonic acid, an amine neutralized substituted benzenesulonic acid, or an amine neutralized acid phosphate.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The thermal acid generator may be present in the amount of from about 0.001 to about 3 wt % of the dielectric composition.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The dielectric composition may comprise an acid-sensitive dielectric material, a thermal acid generator, and an optional solvent. In embodiments, the acid-sensitive dielectric material comprises an organosilane group.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Electronic devices comprising a dielectric layer, wherein the dielectric layer is generated from a composition comprising the dielectric composition, are also disclosed.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">These and other non-limiting characteristics of the disclosure are more particularly disclosed below.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The following is a brief description of the drawings, which are presented for the purposes of illustrating the exemplary embodiments disclosed herein and not for the purposes of limiting the same.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> represents a first embodiment of a TFT according to the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> represents a second embodiment of a TFT according to the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> represents a third embodiment of a TFT according to the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> represents a fourth embodiment of a TFT according to the present disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">A more complete understanding of the components, processes and apparatuses disclosed herein can be obtained by reference to the accompanying drawings. These figures are merely schematic representations based on convenience and the ease of demonstrating the present disclosure, and are, therefore, not intended to indicate relative size and dimensions of the devices or components thereof and/or to define or limit the scope of the exemplary embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Although specific terms are used in the following description for the sake of clarity, these terms are intended to refer only to the particular structure of the embodiments selected for illustration in the drawings, and are not intended to define or limit the scope of the disclosure. In the drawings and the following description below, it is to be understood that like numeric designations refer to components of like function.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The modifier &#x201c;about&#x201d; used in connection with a quantity is inclusive of the stated value and has the meaning dictated by the context (for example, it includes at least the degree of error associated with the measurement of the particular quantity). When used in the context of a range, the modifier &#x201c;about&#x201d; should also be considered as disclosing the range defined by the absolute values of the two endpoints. For example, the range of &#x201c;from about 2 to about 10&#x201d; also discloses the range &#x201c;from 2 to 10.&#x201d;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The term &#x201c;comprising&#x201d; is used herein as requiring the presence of the named component and allowing the presence of other components. The term &#x201c;comprising&#x201d; should be construed to include the term &#x201c;consisting of&#x201d;, which allows the presence of only the named component, along with any impurities that might result from the manufacture of the named component.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The term &#x201c;room temperature&#x201d; refers to a temperature of from 20&#xb0; C. to 25&#xb0; C.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The term &#x201c;shelf life&#x201d; refers to the length of time the dielectric composition may be stored without becoming unsuitable for use. There should be no significant changes in the chemical or physical properties of the composition.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a bottom-gate bottom-contact TFT configuration according to the present disclosure. The TFT <b>10</b> comprises a substrate <b>16</b> in contact with the gate electrode <b>18</b> and a gate dielectric layer <b>14</b>. The gate electrode <b>18</b> is depicted here atop the substrate <b>16</b>, but the gate electrode could also be located in a depression within the substrate. It is important that the gate dielectric layer <b>14</b> separates the gate electrode <b>18</b> from the source electrode <b>20</b>, drain electrode <b>22</b>, and the semiconducting layer <b>12</b>. The semiconducting layer <b>12</b> runs over and between the source and drain electrodes <b>20</b> and <b>22</b>. The semiconductor has a channel length between the source and drain electrodes <b>20</b> and <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates another bottom-gate top-contact TFT configuration according to the present disclosure. The TFT <b>30</b> comprises a substrate <b>36</b> in contact with the gate electrode <b>38</b> and a gate dielectric layer <b>34</b>. The semiconducting layer <b>32</b> is placed on top of the gate dielectric layer <b>34</b> and separates it from the source and drain electrodes <b>40</b> and <b>42</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a bottom-gate bottom-contact TFT configuration according to the present disclosure. The TFT <b>50</b> comprises a substrate <b>56</b> which also acts as the gate electrode and is in contact with a gate dielectric layer <b>54</b>. The source electrode <b>60</b>, drain electrode <b>62</b>, and semiconducting layer <b>52</b> are located atop the gate dielectric layer <b>54</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates a top-gate top-contact TFT configuration according to the present disclosure. The TFT <b>70</b> comprises a substrate <b>76</b> in contact with the source electrode <b>80</b>, drain electrode <b>82</b>, and the semiconducting layer <b>72</b>. The semiconducting layer <b>72</b> runs over and between the source and drain electrodes <b>80</b> and <b>82</b>. The gate dielectric layer <b>74</b> is on top of the semiconducting layer <b>72</b>. The gate electrode <b>78</b> is on top of the gate dielectric layer <b>74</b> and does not contact the semiconducting layer <b>72</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Aspects of the present disclosure relate to an electronic device (e.g., a thin-film transistor) comprising a dielectric layer, the dielectric layer comprising a thermal acid generator. In some embodiments, the dielectric layer is a single homogeneous layer, or in other words is not composed of multiple phase-separated materials. Further aspects of the present disclosure relate to an electronic device comprising a phase-separated dielectric structure, the dielectric structure comprising a thermal acid generator. In the context of a thin-film transistor, the homogeneous dielectric layer or the phase-separated dielectric structure can also be referred to as a &#x201c;gate dielectric.&#x201d; The dielectric structure (both phase-separated and homogeneous layer) can be used in any suitable electronic device. Besides a thin-film transistor, other types of suitable electronic devices include, for example, an embedded capacitor and an electroluminescent lamp.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In fabricating the present dielectric structure, a dielectric composition is prepared which comprises a dielectric material, a crosslinking agent, a thermal acid generator, and optionally a solvent or a liquid. The dielectric composition may have a shelf-life greater than about 1 month at room temperature, including a shelf-life greater than 3 months, or greater than 6 months.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In some embodiments, the dielectric composition comprises an acid-sensitive dielectric material, a thermal acid generator, and an optional solvent. The acid-sensitive dielectric material may comprise an organosilane group. Electronic devices comprising a dielectric layer, wherein the dielectric layer is formed from the dielectric composition, are also disclosed.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In embodiments, any suitable insulating material can be used as the dielectric material. In further embodiments, the dielectric material is a thermally crosslinkable dielectric material. The term &#x201c;thermally crosslinkable&#x201d; refers to the fact that the dielectric material includes functional groups that can react with an additional crosslinking agent or with other functional groups in the dielectric material itself to form a crosslinked network upon heating. The dielectric material can comprise two or more different materials having different dielectric constants. For example, the dielectric material can comprise a lower-k dielectric material and a higher-k dielectric material.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The terms &#x201c;lower-k dielectric&#x201d; and &#x201c;higher-k dielectric&#x201d; are used to differentiate two types of material (based on the dielectric constant) in the dielectric composition and in the phase-separated dielectric structure.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In embodiments, the lower-k dielectric material is electrically insulating and is compatible or has good compatibility with a semiconductor layer in the device. The terms &#x201c;compatible&#x201d; and &#x201c;compatibility&#x201d; refer to how well the semiconductor layer performs electrically when it is adjacent to or contacting a surface rich in the lower-k dielectric material.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In embodiments, the lower-k dielectric material has a hydrophobic surface and therefore may exhibit satisfactory to excellent compatibility with polythiophene semiconducting polymers. In embodiments, the lower-k dielectric material has a dielectric constant (permittivity) of for instance less than 4.0, or less than about 3.5, or particularly less than about 3.0. The lower-k dielectric material may have non-polar or weak polar groups such as a methyl group, phenylene group, ethylene group, Si&#x2014;C, Si&#x2014;O&#x2014;Si, and the like. The lower-k dielectric material may be a silsesquioxane or a polyhedral oligomeric silsesquioxane (FOSS). In particular embodiments, the lower-k dielectric material is a polymer. Representative lower-k dielectric polymers include but are not limited to homopolymers such as polystyrene, poly(4-methylstyrene), poly(chlorostyrene), poly(a-methylstyrene), polysiloxane such as poly(dimethyl siloxane) and poly(diphenyl siloxane), polysilsesquioxane such as poly(ethyl silsesquioxane), poly(methyl silsesquioxane), and poly(phenyl silsesquioxane), polyphenylene, poly(1,3-butadiene), poly(&#x3b1;-vinylnaphtalene), polypropylene, polyisoprene, polyisobutylene, polyethylene, poly(4-methyl-1-pentene), poly(p-xylene), poly(cyclohexyl methacrylate), poly(propylmethacrylPOSS-co-methylmethacrylate), poly(propylmethacryIPOSS-co-styrene), poly(styrylPOSS-co-styrene), poly(vinyl cinnamate), and the like. In specific embodiments, the lower-k dielectric polymer is a polysilsesquioxane, particularly poly(methyl silsesquioxane). The dielectric constant is measured at room temperature and at 1 kHz frequency. In other embodiments, the lower-k dielectric material is a molecular compound such as a molecular glass compound.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In embodiments, the surface of the lower-k dielectric polymer, when cast as a film, has a low surface energy. To characterize the surface energy, advancing water contact angle can be used. A high contact angle indicates a low surface energy. In embodiments, the contact angle is 80 degrees or higher, or higher than about 90 degrees, or particularly higher than about 95 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In embodiments, the higher-k dielectric material is electrically insulating and contains polar groups such as a hydroxyl group, amino group, cyano group, nitro group, C&#x2550;O group, and the like. In embodiments, the higher-k dielectric material has a dielectric constant of 4.0 or more, 5.0 or more, or particularly 6.0 or more. In particular embodiments, the higher-k dielectric material is a polymer. General types of higher-k dielectric polymers may include polyimide, polyester, polyether, polyacrylate, polyvinyl, polyketone, and polysulfone. Specific representative higher-k dielectric polymers include but are not limited to homopolymers such as poly(4-vinyl phenol) (PVP), poly(vinyl alcohol), and poly(2-hydroxylethyl methacrylate) (PHEMA), cyanoethylated poly(vinyl alcohol) (PVA), cyanoethylated cellulose, poly(vinylidene fluoride) (PVDF), poly(vinyl pyridine), copolymers thereof, and the like. In embodiments, the higher-k dielectric material is PVP, PVA, or PHEMA. In other embodiments, the higher-k dielectric material is a molecular compound such as a molecular glass compound.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In embodiments, the higher-k dielectric polymer, when cast as a film, has a high surface energy. In terms of advancing water contact angle, the angle is for instance lower than 80 degrees, or lower than about 60 degrees, or lower than about 50 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In embodiments, the difference in magnitude of the dielectric constant of the higher-k dielectric material versus the lower-k dielectric material is at least about 0.5, or at least about 1.0, or at least about 2.0, for example from about 0.5 to about 200.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In embodiments, the dielectric structure has an overall dielectric constant of more than about 4.0, or more than about 5.0, particularly more than about 6.0. The overall dielectric constant can be characterized with a metal/dielectric structure/metal capacitor. Particularly for thin-film transistor applications, a high overall dielectric constant is desirable in embodiments, so that the device can be operated at a relatively low voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The dielectric material may be acid-sensitive. In particular embodiments, the lower-k dielectric material is acid-sensitive. As used herein, the term &#x201c;acid-sensitive&#x201d; refers to a dielectric material which is not stable when in contact with an acid at room temperature. For example, the acid may catalyze the dielectric material to react with H<sub>2</sub>O, O<sub>2</sub>, or itself to change the properties of the dielectric material such as molecular weight, solubility, etc. The acid-sensitive dielectric material may be a small molecular organosilane, an oligomeric silane, a polysiloxane, a silsesquioxane, a polyhedral oligomeric silsesquioxane, a poly(silsesquioxane), or combinations thereof. A small molecular organosilane has the formula Si(R)<sub>4</sub>, where each R is independently selected from alkyl or alkoxy. An oligomeric silane has the formula R&#x2032;&#x2014;[&#x2014;Si(R)<sub>2</sub>&#x2014;]<sub>m</sub>&#x2014;R&#x2033;, where each R, R&#x2032;, and R&#x2033; is independently selected from hydrogen, alkyl or alkoxy, and m is from 1 to 4.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In other embodiments, the acid sensitive lower-k dielectric material is a polymer comprising a silane group. Exemplary polymers include a polyacrylate, a polyvinyl, a polyimide, a polyester, a polyether, a polyketone, or a polysulfone comprising a silane group. An exemplary silane group is &#x2014;Si(R)<sub>3</sub>, where at least one R is chloro or alkoxy. Exemplary alkoxy groups include methoxy, ethoxy, cyclohexenyloxy, cyclopentenyloxy, butoxy, benzyloxy, and the like. Exemplary polymers comprising a silane group include the following:</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><chemistry id="CHEM-US-00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-C00001" he="143.93mm" wi="37.68mm" file="US08623447-20140107-C00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/>
</chemistry>
<br/>
where x and y are the molar fractions of the respective monomers. By using thermal acid generators, the dielectric composition comprising the acid-sensitive dielectric material has a long shelf-life at room temperature, while remaining capable of fast crosslinking at an elevated temperature due to the release of acid from the thermal acid generator.
</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">A crosslinking agent is present in the dielectric composition. When the dielectric composition comprises two or more materials, such as a higher-k dielectric material and a lower-k dielectric material which can separate into two or more phases during curing, the crosslinking agent causes crosslinking to occur between the higher-k dielectric material and the lower-k dielectric material throughout the phases. Other materials can be added into the dielectric composition. Representative crosslinking agents include poly(melamine-co-formaldehyde) resin, oxazoline functional crosslinking agents, blocked polyisocyanates, certain diamine compounds, dithiol compounds, diisocyanates, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">A thermal acid generator is also present in the dielectric composition. The thermal acid generator generates an acid when heated, catalyzing the crosslinking of the dielectric material to form a crosslinked dielectric layer that has good mechanical and electrical properties. The thermal acid generator generally should also have a good shelf-life in the dielectric composition.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In particular embodiments, the thermal acid generator is a hydrocarbylsulfonic acid. The term &#x201c;hydrocarbyl&#x201d; refers to a radical containing hydrogen and carbon, and which may be substituted. Exemplary hydrocarbylsulfonic acids include dodecylbenzenesulfonic acid, p-toluenesulfonic acid, and alkylnaphthalenedisulfonic acid. The thermal acid generator may be a hydrocarbylsulfonic acid blocked or neutralized with amine. Commercially available thermal acid generators include NACURE&#xae; 5225, NACURE&#xae; 2501, NACURE&#xae; 2107, and NACURE&#xae; 3483, all of which are available from King Industries.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">In some embodiments, the thermal acid generator is a polymeric blocked sulfonic acid ester such as NACURE &#xae; 5414; an amine-neutralized substituted naphthalenesulfonic acid such as NACURE&#xae; 3327, NACURE&#xae; 3525, NACURE&#xae; 3483, NACURE&#xae; 1419, or NACURE&#xae; 1557; an amine-neutralized substituted benzenesulfonic acid such as NACURE&#xae; 5225, NACURE&#xae; 5414, NACURE&#xae; 5528, NACURE&#xae; 2522, or NACURE&#xae; 2501; or an amine-neutralized acid phosphate such as NACURE&#xae; 4167 or NACURE&#xae; 4575.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The thermal acid generator may be present in the dielectric layer, or in the dielectric composition, in the amount of from about 0.001 to about 3 wt %, by weight of the dielectric material, including from about 0.1 to about 2 wt %.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">One, two or more suitable fluids can be used for the liquid (which facilitates the liquid depositing) or solvent which is used in the dielectric composition. In embodiments, the liquid/solvent is capable of dissolving the lower-k dielectric polymer and the higher-k dielectric polymer. Representative liquids include but are not limited to water; alcohols such as methanol, ethanol, propanol, butanol, pentanol, hexanol, ethylene glycol, dowanol, and methoxyethanol; acetates such as ethyl acetate and propylene glycol monoethyl ether acetate; ketones such as methyl isobutyl ketone, methyl isoamyl ketone, acetone, methyl ethyl ketone, and methyl propyl ketone; ethers such as petroleum ether, tetrahydrofuran, and methyl t-butyl ether; hydrocarbons such as hexane, cyclohexane, cyclopentane, hexadecane, and iso-octane; aromatic hydrocarbons such as toluene, xylene, ethyl benzene, and mesitylene; chlorinated solvents such as chloroform, dichloromethane, dichloroethane, chlorobenzene, dichlorobenzene, and trichlorobenzene; and other solvents such as dimethyl sulfoxide, trifluoroacetic acid, acetonitrile, dimethyl formamide, dimethyl acetamide, pyridine, and n-methyl-alpha-pyrrolidinone. The liquid/solvent may be from about 0 to about 98 wt % of the dielectric composition, including from about 50 wt % to about 90 wt %.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Inorganic nanoparticles may also be optionally included to boost the overall dielectric constant of the dielectric layer. These nanoparticles do not react with the dielectric polymers, and are generally dispersed throughout the dielectric layer. The nanoparticles have a particle size of from about 3 nm to about 500 nm, or from about 3 nm to about 100 nm. Any suitable inorganic nanoparticles can be used. Exemplary nanoparticles include metal nanoparticles such as Au, Ag, Cu, Cr, Ni, Pt and Pd; metal oxide nanoparticles such as Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>, TiO<sub>2</sub>, ZrO<sub>2</sub>, La<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>, Y<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>, Ta<sub>2</sub>O<sub>5</sub>, ZrSiO<sub>4</sub>, SrO, SiO, SiO<sub>2</sub>, MgO, CaO, HfSiO<sub>4</sub>, BaTiO<sub>3</sub>, and HfO<sub>2</sub>; and other inorganic nanoparticles such as ZnS and Si<sub>3</sub>N<sub>4</sub>. The addition of inorganic nanoparticles has several advantages. First, the dielectric constant of the overall gate dielectric layer can be increased. Second, when metal nanoparticles are added, the particles can function as electron traps to lower gate leakage of the gate dielectric layer.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The concentration of each of the above listed components in the dielectric composition varies from about 0.001 to about 99 percent by weight of the composition. The concentration of the lower-k dielectric material is for example from about 0.1 to about 30 percent by weight, or from about 1 to about 20 percent by weight. The concentration of the higher-k dielectric material is for example from about 0.1 to about 50 percent by weight, or from about 5 to about 30 percent by weight. The concentration of crosslinking agent will depend on the concentration of the dielectric polymers. The ratio of the crosslinking agent to the dielectric polymers is, for example, from about 1:99 to about 50:50, or from about 5:95 to about 30:70 by weight. The ratio of the catalyst to the dielectric polymers is for example from about 1:9999 to about 5:95, or from 1:999 to about 1:99 by weight. The inorganic nanoparticles can be for example from about 0.5 to about 30 percent by weight, or from about 1 to about 10 percent by weight.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">In embodiments, the lower-k dielectric material and the higher-k dielectric material are not phase separated in the dielectric composition. The phrase &#x201c;not phase separated&#x201d; means that the lower-k dielectric material and the higher-k dielectric material are dissolved in the liquid. The term &#x201c;dissolved&#x201d; indicates total dissolution or partial dissolution of the lower-k dielectric material and the higher-k dielectric material in the liquid. The lower-k dielectric polymer, the higher-k dielectric polymer, and the liquid may be miscible to form a single phase over certain ranges of temperature, pressure, and composition. The temperature range is for example from 0 to 150&#xb0; C., particularly at about room temperature. The pressure is generally about 1 atmosphere. In the dielectric composition prior to the liquid depositing, the lower-k dielectric material and the higher-k dielectric material can be present for example from about 0.1 to about 98 weight percent, or from about 0.5 to about 50 weight percent, based on the total weight of the lower-k dielectric polymer, the higher-k dielectric polymer, and the liquid. The ratio between the lower-k dielectric material to the higher-k dielectric material can be for example from about 1:99 to 99:1, or from about 5:95 to about 95:5, particularly from about 10:90 to about 40:60 (first recited value in each ratio represents the lower-k dielectric polymer).</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">In embodiments where the lower-k dielectric polymer, the higher-k dielectric material and the liquid are miscible to form a single phase (typically a clear solution) prior to the liquid depositing, the single phase can be confirmed by light scattering technique, or visually detected by human eyes without the assistance of any tools.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Prior to the liquid depositing, the dielectric composition may contain in embodiments aggregates of the lower-k dielectric material and/or higher-k dielectric polymer. These aggregates may be for example on a scale less than the wavelength of visible light, or less than 100 nm, particularly less than 50 nm. For purposes of the present disclosure, these aggregates, if present in the dielectric composition, are not considered the result of phase separation or phase-separated; moreover, these aggregates are not considered the &#x201c;first phase&#x201d; and/or the &#x201c;second phase.&#x201d;</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The dielectric composition is liquid deposited onto a substrate. Any suitable liquid depositing technique may be employed. In embodiments, the liquid depositing includes blanket coating such as spin coating, blade coating, rod coating, dip coating, and the like, and printing such as screen printing, ink jet printing, stamping, stencil printing, screen printing, gravure printing, flexography printing, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">In embodiments, the liquid depositing can be accomplished in a single step. The term &#x201c;single step&#x201d; refers to liquid depositing both the first and the second dielectric materials at the same time from one dielectric composition. This is different from the process for fabricating a conventional dual-layer dielectric structure, wherein two different dielectric materials are liquid deposited separately from two different dielectric compositions. &#x201c;Step&#x201d; in &#x201c;single step&#x201d; is different from the term &#x201c;pass&#x201d;. In embodiments, in order to increase thickness of the dielectric structure, more than 1 pass can be carried out during the single step deposition of the dielectric composition.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">In fabricating the dielectric structure, the present process involves causing phase separation of the lower-k dielectric material and the higher-k dielectric material to form a dielectric structure comprising two phases. The term &#x201c;causing&#x201d; includes spontaneous occurrence of phase separation during liquid deposition when the liquid evaporates. The term &#x201c;causing&#x201d; also includes external assistance for facilitating the phase separation during and after the liquid deposition. The dielectric composition is heated to cure the dielectric composition, resulting in the formation of a dielectric layer.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The term &#x201c;phase&#x201d; in &#x201c;first phase&#x201d; and &#x201c;second phase&#x201d; means a domain or domains of material in which a property such as chemical composition is relatively uniform. Accordingly, the term &#x201c;interphase&#x201d; refers to an area between the first phase and the second phase in the phase-separated dielectric structure in which a gradient in composition exists. In embodiments, the dielectric structure comprises the sequence: the first phase, optional interphase, and the second phase.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">In embodiments, the &#x201c;phase-separated&#x201d; nature of the present phase-separated dielectric structure is manifested by any of the following possible representative morphologies of the first phase and the second phase: (1) an interphase (in the form of a layer) present between the first phase (in the form of a layer) and the second phase (in the form of a layer); (2) one phase forms a plurality of &#x201c;dots&#x201d; in a continuous matrix of the other phase; (3) one phase forms a plurality of rod-shaped elements (e.g. cylinders) in a continuous matrix of the other phase; and (4) one phase is interpenetrating into the other phase to form bicontinuous domains. In embodiments, morphology (2), (3), or (4) may be present, but not (1).</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The &#x201c;phase-separated&#x201d; nature of the present phase-separated dielectric structure regarding the morphology of the first phase and the second phase can be determined by various analyses such as for example the following: Scanning Electron Microscopy (SEM) and Atomic Force Microscopy (AFM) analysis of surface and cross-section of the dielectric structure; and Transmission Electron Microscopy (TEM) analysis of a cross-section of the dielectric structure. Other tools such as light scattering and X-ray (wide angle and small angle X-rays) scattering could also be used.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">In embodiments, morphology (1) involving the interphase differs from a conventional dual-layer gate dielectric having an interfacial layer in that the interphase involves a gradient composition change; whereas the interfacial layer involves a discontinuous composition change, not a gradient composition change. In embodiments, another difference is that the present interphase is relatively thick, involving a thickness ranging from about 10 nm to about 50 nm, which typically is significantly larger than any interfacial layer found in a conventional dual-layer gate dielectric which may have a interfacial layer thickness of less than about 5 nm, particularly less than about 3 nm.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">In embodiments, the lower-k dielectric material is a majority of the first phase, and the higher-k dielectric material is a majority of the second phase. Similarly, the higher-k dielectric material is a minority of the first phase, and the lower-k dielectric material is a minority of the second phase. The term &#x201c;majority&#x201d; means more than 50% by weight of the total weight of the lower-k dielectric material and the higher-k dielectric material in a phase of the phase-separated dielectric structure. The term &#x201c;minority&#x201d; means less than 50% by weight of the total weight of the lower-k dielectric material and the higher-k dielectric material in a phase of the phase-separated dielectric structure.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">In embodiments, the lower-k dielectric material is in a higher concentration than the higher-k dielectric phase in a region of the dielectric structure closest to the semiconductor layer. Put another way, the first phase is closer to the semiconductor layer than the second phase.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">The term &#x201c;region&#x201d; refers to a thin slice (parallel to the surface of the dielectric structure) of the phase-separated dielectric structure closest to the semiconductor layer. The region is examined to determine its concentration of the lower-k dielectric material and the higher-k dielectric polymer. In embodiments, the region contains a portion of or all of the first phase and optionally a portion of or all of the second phase. In embodiments, the optional interfacial layer may be present in the phase-separated dielectric structure and thus the region may include the interfacial layer as long as the region has a sufficient thickness to include a portion or all of the first phase and optionally a portion or all of the second phase. The region has any suitable thickness for use in an analytical technique such as for example from about 1 nm to about 100 nm, or from about 5 nm to about 100 nm, or particularly from about 5 nm to about 50 nm.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">Various methods can be used to determine the concentration of the two dielectric polymers. For example, X-Ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy (XPS) can be used to analyze the concentration of each atom in the region. AFM could be used to determine domain size of different phases. TEM on a cross-section of the region could also be used to determine domain size of difference phases and concentration of each atom of different dielectric materials. In certain embodiments, the combination of different methods may be used. In case of significant variation in results from different methods, the results from TEM analysis is preferred.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">In embodiments of the &#x201c;region,&#x201d; the lower-k dielectric material is at a concentration for example ranging from about 60% to 100%, or from about 80% to 100%, and the higher-k dielectric material is at a concentration ranging from about 40% to 0%, or from about 20% to 0%. The concentration can be controlled by various factors such as the initial ratio of the lower-k dielectric material and the higher-k dielectric material in the dielectric composition, the concentration of the dielectric polymers in the dielectric composition, the miscibility of the dielectric polymers, the processing conditions such as the annealing time and annealing temperature.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">In order to achieve phase separation, in embodiments, the lower-k dielectric material and higher-k dielectric material are intentionally chosen to be immiscible or partial miscible in solid state. The miscibility (capability of a mixture to form a single phase) of the two dielectric polymers can be predicted by looking at their interaction parameter, x. Generally speaking, a material is miscible with another material which is similar to it.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">In embodiments where the phase-separated dielectric structure is layered (morphology (1)), the first phase has a thickness for example from about 1 nm to about 500 nm, or from about 5 nm to about 200 nm, or from about 5 nm to about 50 nm. The second phase has a thickness for example from about 5 nm to about 2 micrometer, or from about 10 nm to about 500 nm, or from about 100 nm to about 500 nm. The dielectric structure has an overall thickness for example from about 10 nm to about 2 micrometers, or from about 200 nm to about 1 micrometer, or from about 300 to about 800 nm.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">In embodiments, the phase-separated dielectric structure comprises a material blend. In embodiments, the phase-separated material blend is a binary blend. In other embodiments, the phase-separated material blend is a ternary blend or a quaternary blend when a third or a fourth dielectric material is added respectively. As used herein, the term &#x201c;blend&#x201d; merely indicates the presence of two or more polymers and does not imply the concentration or distribution of the lower-k dielectric material and the high-k dielectric material in the first phase and the second phase. Further aspects of the present disclosure relate to a thin-film transistor comprising a phase-separated, material blend gate dielectric.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">In embodiments, the present phase-separated dielectric structure contains intentionally created pores (also referred to as voids and apertures) such as those created using processes and materials similar to those described in for example Lopatin et al., U.S. Pat. No. 6,528,409; Foster et al., U.S. Pat. No. 6,706,464; and Carter et al., U.S. Pat. No. 5,883,219. In other embodiments, the present phase-separated dielectric structure does not contain such intentionally created pores (but pinholes may be present in certain embodiments which are not intentionally created but rather are an undesired byproduct of the present process). The pinhole density in embodiments is for example less than 50 per mm<sup>2 </sup>(square millimeter), or less than 10 per mm<sup>2</sup>, or less than 5 mm<sup>2</sup>. In further embodiments, the present phase-separated dielectric structure is pinhole free. In embodiments, there is absent a step to create pores in the dielectric structure.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">An optional interfacial layer may be present between the semiconductor layer and the phase-separated dielectric structure. The interfacial layer may be prepared using the materials and procedures disclosed in for example U.S. Pat. No. 7,282,735, the disclosure of which is totally incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">The dielectric composition of the present disclosure has several advantages. First, this composition has a long shelf-life when stored at room temperature. In other words, the composition has substantially the same chemical and physical properties, such as viscosity, over time. This allows fabrication of a reproducible dielectric layer. Second, the acid catalyst released from the thermal acid generator at an elevated temperature will accelerate the curing or crosslinking process, thus reducing curing temperature and time. This has particular benefits for roll-to-roll manufacturing on a low-cost flexible substrate. For dielectric compositions comprising both higher-k and lower-k dielectric materials, multiple-step deposition of different dielectric materials is avoided by using a single step feature. The phase-separated blended dielectric material may offer better properties via the combination of advantages of different polymers.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">Additional advantages accrue when the dielectric composition is used in conjunction with a selected substrate. For roll-to-roll manufacturing, the substrate must be structurally flexible. In embodiments, the substrate is plastic and is for example, poly(ethylene terephthalate) (PET). The thickness of the substrate may be from about 10 micrometers to about 10 millimeters, with an exemplary thickness being from about 50 to about 400 micrometers.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">As discussed above, after the dielectric composition is deposited on a substrate, the dielectric composition is cured by heating, forming a dielectric layer on the substrate. Normally, the dielectric composition is cured using a heat source, such as a hotplate or oven heating, to remove the liquid/solvent, and to cure the dielectric composition. Other heating methods include microwave, ultraviolet, and flash fusing. Referring to the Figures again, these heating methods typically heat all of the parts of the electronic device/transistor that are present on the substrate at the time the dielectric composition is applied. Due to the different construction of each part/layer, this application of heat can lead to deformation of, for example, the substrate. In addition, these methods are typically difficult to integrate with roll-to-roll processing, particularly for dielectric materials that require a relatively long curing time, such as 10 minutes or more. Thus, reducing the curing time is desirable. It is also desirable to reduce the processing temperature experienced by the substrate to avoid deformation of the substrate. Generally, the curing time can be shortened by increasing the curing temperature.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">The inclusion of the thermal acid generator in the dielectric composition permits both a lowering of the curing time and a reduction in the processing temperature experienced by the substrate. Whereas prior dielectric compositions need to be thermally cured at temperatures of 140&#xb0; C. to 160&#xb0; C., the present dielectric compositions can be thermally cured at temperatures of from about 80&#xb0; C. to about 140&#xb0; C. or from about 80&#xb0; C. to about 120&#xb0; C. Whereas prior dielectric compositions need to be cured for periods of about 30 minutes, the present dielectric compositions can be thermally cured for periods of from about 0.5 minutes to about 10 minutes or from about 0.5 minutes to about 5 minutes. As desired, the dielectric composition can first be dried before initiating curing. The term &#x201c;drying&#x201d; refers to the removal of solvent, while the term &#x201c;curing&#x201d; refers to the cross-linking of the dielectric composition. Drying and curing may occur simultaneously.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">In specific embodiments, the dielectric layer is formed from a dielectric composition comprising poly(methyl silsesquioxane), poly(4-vinyl phenol), a crosslinking agent, and a thermal acid generator. This dielectric composition is deposited on a PET substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">Electrodes</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">The gate electrode can be a thin metal film, a conducting polymer film, a conducting film made from conducting ink or paste, or the substrate itself can be the gate electrode, for example heavily doped silicon. Examples of gate electrode materials include but are not restricted to aluminum, gold, chromium, indium tin oxide, conducting polymers such as polystyrene sulfonate-doped poly(3,4-ethylenedioxythiophene) (PSS-PEDOT), conducting ink/paste comprised of carbon black/graphite or colloidal silver dispersion in polymer binders, such as ELECTRODAGT&#x2122;, available from Acheson Colloids Company. The gate electrode layer can be prepared by vacuum evaporation, sputtering of metals or conductive metal oxides, coating from conducting polymer solutions or conducting inks by spin coating, casting or printing. The thickness of the gate electrode layer ranges for example from about 10 to about 200 nanometers for metal films and in the range of about 1 to about 10 micrometers for polymer conductors.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">The source and drain electrode layers can be fabricated from materials which provide a low resistance ohmic contact to the semiconductor layer. Typical materials suitable for use as source and drain electrodes include those of the gate electrode materials such as gold, nickel, aluminum, platinum, conducting polymers and conducting inks. Typical thicknesses of source and drain electrodes are about, for example, from about 40 nanometers to about 10 micrometers with the more specific thickness being about 100 to about 400 nanometers.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">Semiconductor Layer</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">Materials suitable for use as the organic semiconductor layer include acenes, such as anthracene, tetracene, pentacene, and substituted pentacenes, perylenes, fullerenes, phthalocyanines, oligothiophenes, polythiophenes, and substituted derivatives thereof. In embodiments, the organic semiconductor layer is formed from a liquid processable material. Examples of suitable semiconductor materials include polythiophenes, oligothiophenes, and the semiconductor polymers described in U.S. Pat. Nos. 6,621,099, 6,774,393, 6,770,904, and 6,949,762, the disclosures of which are incorporated herein by reference in their entireties. Additionally, suitable materials include the semiconductor polymers disclosed in &#x201c;Organic Thin-film transistors for Large Area Electronics&#x201d; by C. D. Dimitrakopoulos and P. R. L. Malenfant, Adv. Mater., Vol. 12, No. 2, pp. 99-117 (2002), the disclosure of which is also incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">The semiconductor layer may be formed by any suitable means including but not limited to vacuum evaporation, spin coating, solution casting, dip coating, stencil/screen printing, flexography, gravure, offset printing, inkjet-printing, micro-contact printing, a combination of these processes, and the like. In embodiments, the semiconductor layer is formed by a liquid deposition method. In embodiments, the semiconductor layer has a thickness of from about 10 nanometers to about 1 micrometer. In further embodiments, the organic semiconductor layer has a thickness of from about 30 to about 150 nanometers. In other embodiments, the semiconductor layer has a thickness of from about 40 to about 100 nanometers.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">Gate Dielectric</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">The composition and formation of the gate dielectric are described herein. In embodiments, the dielectric is a highly crosslinked and robust layer. The dielectric layer comprises a thermal acid generator or the decomposition products of the thermal acid generator. In some embodiments, the dielectric is a homogeneous layer without phase separation. In other embodiments, the dielectric is a phase-separated gate dielectric, and the first phase and the second phase of the gate dielectric contact each other. In other embodiments, an interphase is present between the first phase and the second phase. In embodiments, the first phase of the gate dielectric contacts the semiconductor layer; in other embodiments, an interfacial layer is present between the first phase and the semiconductor layer. In embodiments, both the first phase and the second phase of the gate dielectric contact the semiconductor layer. In other embodiments, both the first phase and the second phase of the gate dielectric contact the semiconductor layer, wherein the contact area between the semiconductor layer and the first phase is larger than that between the semiconductor layer and the second phase in the channel region (the region between the source and drain electrodes) of the thin-film transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">The gate dielectric, the gate electrode, the semiconductor layer, the source electrode, and the drain electrode are formed in any sequence on the substrate. In embodiments, the gate electrode and the semiconductor layer are on opposite sides of the gate dielectric layer, and the source electrode and the drain electrode are both in contact with the semiconductor layer. The phrase &#x201c;in any sequence&#x201d; includes sequential and simultaneous formation. For example, the source electrode and the drain electrode can be formed simultaneously or sequentially. The composition, fabrication, and operation of field effect transistors are described in Bao et al., U.S. Pat. No. 6,107,117, the disclosure of which is totally incorporated herein by reference. The term &#x201c;on the substrate&#x201d; refers to the various layers and components with reference to the substrate as being the bottom or support for the layers and components which are on top of it. In other words, all of the components are on the substrate, even though they do not all directly contact the substrate. For example, both the dielectric layer and the semiconductor layer are on the substrate, even though one layer is closer to the substrate than the other layer.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">The following examples are for purposes of further illustrating the present disclosure. The examples are merely illustrative and are not intended to limit devices made in accordance with the disclosure to the materials, conditions, or process parameters set forth therein. All parts are percentages by volume unless otherwise indicated.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">EXAMPLES</heading>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">Comparative Example 1</heading>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">0.08 grams of poly(4-vinylphenol) (PVP, Aldrich, Mw=25,000) and 0.08 grams of melamine-formaldehyde resin (Aldrich, 84 wt % in n-butanol) were dissolved in 1.0 grams of n-butanol. Subsequently, 0.1 grams poly(methyl silsesquioxane) (PMSSQ) solution (&#x2dc;26 wt % in n-butanol) was added to the mixture. The resulting dielectric composition was filtered through a 0.2 &#x3bc;m syringe filter and spin coated onto the top of a glass substrate at 2000 rpm for 60 seconds. After being dried at 80&#xb0; C. for approximately 5 minutes, the dielectric layer was cured at 140&#xb0; C. for 30 minutes. After curing, the thickness of the dielectric layer was measured to be 530 nm. The dielectric layer was then thoroughly washed with n-butanol, and the thickness of the dielectric layer was measured again. It was found that there was no reduction of the film thickness, indicating a robust dielectric layer.</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">Comparative Example 2</heading>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">The formulation of Comparative Example 1 was spin coated onto a glass substrate. After being dried at 80&#xb0; C. for approximately 5 minutes, the dielectric layer was cured at 120&#xb0; C. for 10 minutes. After washing with n-butanol, no film was left on the substrate. This indicated that the dielectric layer was not crosslinked properly after curing at 120&#xb0; C. for 10 minutes.</p>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">Comparative Example 3</heading>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">The formulation of Comparative Example 1 was spin coated onto a glass substrate. After being dried at 80&#xb0; C. for approximately 5 minutes, the dielectric layer was cured at 140&#xb0; C. for 2 minutes. After washing with n-butanol, no film was left on the substrate. This indicated that the dielectric layer was not crosslinked properly after curing at 140&#xb0; C. for 2 minutes.</p>
<heading id="h-0009" level="1">Example 1</heading>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">0.012 grams of NACURE&#xae; 5225 (25% active component in isopropanol), a thermal acid generator, was added to the formulation of Comparative Example 1. After spin coating and drying, the dielectric layer was cured at 120&#xb0; C. for 10 minutes. The resulting dielectric layer was then thoroughly washed with n-butanol. The thickness of the dielectric was measured before and after n-butanol washing. There was no reduction of the film thickness after washing, indicating a robust dielectric layer that had been crosslinked properly.</p>
<heading id="h-0010" level="1">Example 2</heading>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">Example 2 was performed as described in Example 1, except the curing was at 140&#xb0; C. for 2 minutes. After washing with n-butanol, no reduction in film thickness was observed.</p>
<heading id="h-0011" level="1">Example 3</heading>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">Example 3 was performed as described in Example 1, except the curing was at 120&#xb0; C. for 2 minutes. After washing with n-butanol, the film had 97% of the thickness from prior to washing.</p>
<heading id="h-0012" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">Table A summarizes the results of the Examples. Table A shows that the addition of the thermal acid generator allows for reduction in both the curing temperature and in the curing time, while still arriving at a robust crosslinked dielectric layer.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00001" num="00001">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="42pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="56pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="42pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="42pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="4" rowsep="1">TABLE A</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>Contained</entry>
<entry>Temperature</entry>
<entry/>
<entry>Robust</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>NACURE 5225?</entry>
<entry>(C.)</entry>
<entry>Time (min)</entry>
<entry>film?</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="42pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="56pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="42pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="42pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>Comp Ex. 1</entry>
<entry>No</entry>
<entry>140</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
<entry>Yes</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Comp Ex. 2</entry>
<entry>No</entry>
<entry>140</entry>
<entry>2</entry>
<entry>No</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Comp Ex. 3</entry>
<entry>No</entry>
<entry>120</entry>
<entry>10</entry>
<entry>No</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Ex. 1</entry>
<entry>Yes</entry>
<entry>120</entry>
<entry>10</entry>
<entry>Yes</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Ex. 2</entry>
<entry>Yes</entry>
<entry>140</entry>
<entry>2</entry>
<entry>Yes</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Ex. 3</entry>
<entry>Yes</entry>
<entry>120</entry>
<entry>2</entry>
<entry>Yes</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<heading id="h-0013" level="1">Example 4</heading>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">Thin film transistors were fabricated on a polyethylene terephthalate substrate, with an aluminum gate electrode. The formulation of Example 1, containing a thermal acid generator, was spin coated on top of the aluminum gate electrode at 2000 rpm, followed by curing at 120&#xb0; C. for 10 minutes. After curing, a semiconductor layer was formed on top of the dielectric layer by spin coating a polythiophene, PQT, onto the dielectric layer at 1000 rpm for 120 seconds, followed by annealing at 140&#xb0; C. for 10 minutes in a vacuum oven. Gold source/drain electrodes were subsequently evaporated on top of the PQT semiconductor layer to complete the device.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">Transistors with a channel length of 90 &#x3bc;m and a channel width of 1000 &#x3bc;m were characterized with a Keithley SCS-4200 system. The devices showed mobility up to 0.06 cm<sup>2</sup>/V&#xb7;sec with a high on/off ratio of 10<sup>5</sup>, which is similar to devices having a dielectric layer crosslinked at 140&#xb0; C. for 30 minutes. Example 4 thus shows that the addition of a thermal acid generator to the dielectric layer/composition has no detrimental effect on the performance of the transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">It will be appreciated that variants of the above-disclosed and other features and functions, or alternatives thereof, may be combined into many other different systems or applications. Various presently unforeseen or unanticipated alternatives, modifications, variations or improvements therein may be subsequently made by those skilled in the art which are also intended to be encompassed by the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-chemistry idref="CHEM-US-00001" cdx-file="US08623447-20140107-C00001.CDX" mol-file="US08623447-20140107-C00001.MOL"/>
<us-chemistry idref="CHEM-US-00002" cdx-file="US08623447-20140107-C00002.CDX" mol-file="US08623447-20140107-C00002.MOL"/>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A process for fabricating an electronic device having a dielectric layer on a substrate, comprising:
<claim-text>depositing a dielectric composition on the substrate, the dielectric composition comprising a dielectric material, a crosslinking agent, and a thermal acid generator; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>heating the dielectric composition to cure the dielectric composition, forming the dielectric layer on the substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the dielectric material comprises a silicon-containing material selected from the group consisting of silsesquioxane, a polyhedral oligomeric silsesquioxane, a poly(silsesquioxane), a polyacrylate comprising a silane group, a polyvinyl comprising a silane group, a polyimide comprising a silane group, a polyester comprising a silane group, a polyether comprising a silane group, a polyketone comprising a silane group, or a polysulfone comprising a silane group; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the dielectric material comprises a lower-k dielectric polymer and a higher-k dielectric polymer; and wherein the silicon-containing material is the lower-k dielectric polymer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The process of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the thermal acid generator is a hydrocarbylsulfonic acid blocked or neutralized with amine.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The process of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the thermal acid generator is present in the amount of from about 0.001 to about 3 wt % of the dielectric material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The process of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the lower-k dielectric polymer has a dielectric constant of less than 4.0.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The process of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the higher-k dielectric polymer has a dielectric constant of 4.0 or higher.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The process of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the dielectric composition is heated at a temperature of from about 80&#xb0; C. to about 140&#xb0; C.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The process of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the dielectric composition is heated for a period of from about 0.5 minutes to about 10 minutes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The process of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the dielectric composition is heated for a period of from about 0.5 minutes to about 5 minutes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The process of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the silicon-containing material is an acid-sensitive dielectric material selected from the group consisting of a silsesquioxane, a polyhedral oligomeric silsesquioxane, a poly(silsesquioxane), and combinations thereof; and
<claim-text>wherein the higher-k dielectric polymer is selected from the group consisting of a polyimide, a polyester, a polyether, a polyacrylate, a polyvinyl, a polyketone, a polysulfone, a molecular glass compound, and combinations thereof.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The process of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the thermal acid generator is a hydrocarbylsulfonic acid blocked or neutralized with amine.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The process of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the thermal acid generator is a polymeric blocked sulfonic acid ester, an amine neutralized substituted naphthalenesulonic acid, an amine neutralized substituted benzenesulonic acid, or an amine neutralized acid phosphate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The process of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the thermal acid generator is present in the amount of from about 0.001 to about 3 wt % of the dielectric composition.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A process for fabricating an electronic device, comprising:
<claim-text>depositing a dielectric composition on a substrate, the dielectric composition comprising a dielectric material, a crosslinking agent, and a thermal acid generator; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>heating the dielectric composition to cure the dielectric composition, forming a dielectric layer on the substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the dielectric material comprises a a higher-k dielectric polymer and a lower-k dielectric polymer containing a silane group, wherein the lower-k dielectric polymer containing a silane group is selected from the group consisting of</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text><chemistry id="CHEM-US-00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-C00002" he="139.45mm" wi="48.01mm" file="US08623447-20140107-C00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/>
</chemistry>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein x and y are molar fractions. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
