<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623149-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623149</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13531891</doc-number>
<date>20120625</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>08</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>9</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>134 221</main-classification>
<further-classification>134 64 R</further-classification>
<further-classification>134122 R</further-classification>
<further-classification> 153092</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Air wiping device</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3270364</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Steele</name>
<date>19660900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 153091</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4033785</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Gibbs</name>
<date>19770700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>134 15</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5551226</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Keir et al.</name>
<date>19960900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5634236</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Darsey</name>
<date>19970600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 153091</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5943729</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Watkins</name>
<date>19990800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 153091</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6267822</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Watkins</name>
<date>20010700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>134 37</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6865875</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Watkins</name>
<date>20050300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0172932</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Watkins</name>
<date>20040900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0131852</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hooi</name>
<date>20090500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>1</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>134 64 R</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>134122 R</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>134 221</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 153092</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>10</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>11</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12689384</doc-number>
<date>20100119</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13531891</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120260943</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121018</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bettencourt</last-name>
<first-name>Stephen Paul</first-name>
<address>
<city>Warren</city>
<state>RI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bettencourt</last-name>
<first-name>Stephen Paul</first-name>
<address>
<city>Warren</city>
<state>RI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Best Medical International, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Springfield</city>
<state>VA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Carrillo</last-name>
<first-name>Bibi</first-name>
<department>1711</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An air wiping device for cleaning an elongated product that passes through the air wiping device. The air wiping device includes a housing having an internal tubular passage through which the elongated product extends with the housing tubular passage having an inlet end and an outlet end for respectively receiving and passing the elongated product; a plurality of air outlets mounted in the housing and adapted to direct a flow of compressed air in a direction having a component in an opposite direction to the flow of the elongated product through the housing; and a ceramic insert disposed in the internal tubular passage of the housing and through which the elongated product passes. The ceramic insert includes a tapered input through which the elongated product is received and an output through which the elongated product passes from the housing.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="208.28mm" wi="179.24mm" file="US08623149-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="187.03mm" wi="179.15mm" file="US08623149-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="198.29mm" wi="151.13mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623149-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="230.38mm" wi="157.48mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623149-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="163.07mm" wi="155.28mm" file="US08623149-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="165.27mm" wi="150.54mm" file="US08623149-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="243.08mm" wi="169.16mm" file="US08623149-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="161.21mm" wi="155.53mm" file="US08623149-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="192.36mm" wi="179.15mm" file="US08623149-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="221.91mm" wi="179.75mm" file="US08623149-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="124.80mm" wi="160.61mm" file="US08623149-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present application is a divisional of, and claims priority from U.S. patent application Ser. No. 12/689,384, entitled &#x201c;Air whipping device&#x201d;; filed on Jan. 19, 2010.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates in general to an air wiping device. More particularly the present invention relates to a cleaning device for a variety of different types of products, particularly elongated members such as fiber, wiring or cabling. Even more particularly the present invention relates an air wiping device that is characterized by minimizing damage or breakage to the fiber as well as minimizing damage to the air wiping device itself.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In the manufacturing of wire, or other similar elongated products, there is a need to remove liquids and contaminants from the surface of the product. For example, in the production of wire, it is necessary that cooling fluids or cleansing acids be removed from the wire prior to spooling, storage, or subsequent processing. It is known in this art to use compressed air to remove liquid or contaminants from wire, or the like, as it passes through a tube. By way of example refer to U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,634,236 and 6,267,822, as well as an air wipe product sold by Huestis Machine Corporation of Bristol Rhode Island, and the assignee of the present invention, all of which are hereby incorporated by reference herein in their entirety. These known air wiping devices use compressed air that is vented into the tube through radially or tangentially directed holes and the liquid is removed by the force of the pressurized air traveling in the opposite direction of the moving wire. There have been numerous problems associated with past attempts to remove liquid from moving elongated members using such prior art methods.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">One problem associated with known air wiping devices is that when one desires to change the cable size being processed, the entire air wipe product has to be substituted. Another problem with known air wiping devices is that in order to provide a hard surface in the inner tube of the air wiping device the entire device is usually constructed of a ceramic material as mentioned in U.S. Pat. No. 6,267,822. This makes the device expensive to manufacture. Also other devices that are used are constructed of materials that do not withstand the wear caused by the passing cable (at high speed), and thus damage to the device is common, particularly where initial misalignment occurs.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Accordingly, it is an object of the present invention to provide an improved air wiping device in which the entire air wiping device does not have to be substituted when one wants to change cable or wire size. Instead, in accordance with the present invention a separable insert is used that enables the substitution of tubing size to accommodate different size cabling or wiring. This insert substitution enables the construction of an overall less expensive device.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Another object of the present invention is to provide an improved air wiping device that is characterized by improved wear resistance. Normally the conventional air wiping device is installed in a production line and it is meant to be perfectly aligned on the central axis of the processed material. It is typical that operators may be too rushed or lazy to perform a proper alignment and thus the body wears out quickly. This usually results in the destruction of the device requiring a complete replacement of the device. However, in accordance with the improved air wiping device of the present invention the ceramic insert bore provides excellent wear resistance and compensates for misalignments. Moreover, the replaceable ceramic insert alone is less costly than the cost of a complete air wiping device.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">To accomplish the foregoing and other objects, features and advantages of the present invention there is provided an air wiping device for cleaning an elongated product that passes through the air wiping device. The air wiping device comprises a housing having an internal tubular passage through which the elongated product extends with the housing tubular passage having an inlet end and an outlet end for respectively receiving and passing the elongated product; a plurality of air outlets mounted in the housing and adapted to direct a flow of compressed air in a direction having a component in an opposite direction to the flow of the elongated product through the housing; and a ceramic insert disposed in the internal tubular passage of the housing and through which the elongated product passes. The ceramic insert includes a tapered input through which the elongated product is received and an output through which the elongated product passes from the housing. The ceramic insert provides an extremely durable work surface for the elongated product.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In accordance with other aspects of the present invention the housing is separated into two housing sections and the housing sections are preferably connected by a hinge that biases the housing sections to a closed position; the plurality of air outlets comprise nozzles that are disposed about a 360 degree locus; the ceramic insert is comprised of a pair of insert sections. The housing section includes a first housing section and a second housing section, the pair of insert sections including a first insert section and a second insert section, the first insert section mounted in the first housing section and the second insert section mounted in the second housing sections; including separate fastener means for removably attaching the respective insert sections to the housing sections; each of the insert sections and housing sections are substantially semicircular in shape; and the fasteners retain the insert sections in place in the elongated tubular passage and together define an inner passage through which the elongated product passes.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In accordance with another version of the present invention there is provided an air wiping device for cleaning an elongated product that passes through the air wiping device. The air wiping device comprises: a housing having an elongated internal tubular passage; said housing including first and second housing sections that together define the elongated internal tubular passage; a hinge that couples together the first and second housing sections and biases the housing sections to a closed position in which the elongated internal tubular passage is formed; a plurality of nozzles mounted in the housing and adapted to direct a flow of compressed air in a direction having a component in an opposite direction to the flow of the elongated product through the housing; said plurality of nozzles including a first set of nozzles mounted in the first housing section and a second set of nozzles mounted in the second housing section; and a ceramic insert disposed in the internal tubular passage of the housing and through which the elongated product passes; said ceramic insert including a first insert section supported by the first housing section and a second insert section supported by the second housing section; and said ceramic insert sections defining a tapered input through which the elongated product is received and an output through which the elongated product passes from the housing.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In accordance with other aspects of the present invention the plurality of nozzles are disposed about a 360 degree locus; including a mounting bracket for the housing that mounts the housing in a manner by which the housing may still move toward an open position should an object associated with the elongated product engage the tapered input so as to avoid damage to the device; the housing sections include a slot that is used for the support of the housing from the bracket; including separate fastener means for attaching the respective insert sections to the housing sections; each of the insert sections and housing sections are substantially semi-circular in shape; the fasteners retain the insert sections in place in the elongated tubular passage and together define an inner passage through which the elongated product passes; and the fasteners removably attach the insert sections so that other insert sections may be substituted.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In accordance with the present invention there is also provided a method of cleaning an elongated product by passing the elongated product through an air wiping device, and in which the air wiping device includes, a housing having an internal tubular passage through which the elongated product extends; a plurality of air outlets mounted in the housing and adapted to direct a flow of compressed air in a direction having a component in an opposite direction to the flow of the elongated product through the housing and a ceramic insert disposed in the internal tubular passage of the housing and through which the elongated product passes, said method including the steps of: removably mounting a first ceramic insert in the housing so as to accommodate a first size elongated product; after usage, removing the first ceramic insert; and substituting a second ceramic insert in the housing so as to accommodate a second size elongated product.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Numerous other objects, features and advantages can be realized in accordance with the present invention by referring to the accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of one embodiment of the air wiping device constructed in accordance with the principles of the present invention and illustrated as supported from a mounting bracket;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a front view of the air wiping device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a rear view of the air wiping device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a left side view of the air wiping device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a right side view of the air wiping device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a fragmentary perspective view at the right side of the device and showing the nozzle exploded from the housing;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is an illustration of the nozzle;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a fragmentary perspective view at the left side of the device;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a perspective view of the device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> with the housing in an open position;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a front view with the housing open; and</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a cross-section through one of the ceramic insert sections.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Reference is now made to the present preferred embodiment of the present invention which is illustrated in the accompanying drawings. The device of the present invention removes particulate matter or other adherent material from an elongated member such as wiring or cabling. The device will effectively remove any material loosely adhered to the elongated member such as liquids, particulate solids, contaminants or combinations thereof. Although it shows particular utility in removing liquids or other materials from elongated solids such as wires or cables, the principles of the present invention may also apply to cleaning any number of other elongated substances.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In accordance with the present invention, the device generally includes a housing having a chamber with a plurality of air inlets for receiving compressed air into the chamber, a central tube for receiving an elongated member as it is traveling into the chamber, and an exit for allowing the elongated member to leave the chamber. Furthermore, the compressed air is generally expelled (with removed material) through the central tube.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">As here embodied and depicted in the drawings, there is shown an air wiping device designated by the numeral <b>10</b>. The device <b>10</b> is used to remove liquid and/or other materials from an elongated member <b>11</b> having a generally circular cross-sectional area and moving in the direction of the arrows A illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</figref>, <b>6</b> and <b>8</b>. Additionally, air wiping device <b>10</b> is meant to be used in conjunction with a compressed air delivering system (not shown). Part of the delivery system is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 9</figref> by the air lines L. Device <b>10</b> includes housing <b>12</b> having an internal plenum chamber <b>14</b> into which the compressed air is coupled from the lines L.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The chamber <b>14</b> couples the compressed air to the plurality of nozzles <b>20</b>. The nozzles <b>20</b> are each meant to provide a jet stream of air or any other gas directed to the elongated product as the elongated product or member is conveyed through the air wiping device.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Reference is now made to the perspective view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> that illustrates the air wiping device <b>10</b> of the present invention as supported by the bracket <b>50</b>. Refer also to the partial perspective view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> which shows a portion of the bracket <b>50</b>. The bracket supports the device <b>10</b> primarily by means of an engagement of the planar-shaped bracket <b>50</b> with the slot <b>52</b>. From <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> it is noted that the bracket <b>50</b> is open at its top end so that the housing <b>12</b> can move from a closed position as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> to an open position as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>. A pair of spring loaded ball plungers engage mating holes in the bracket providing too less unit removal from the bracket or securing screws may be used for securing the housing to the bracket. This is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> wherein passages <b>54</b> may accommodate securing screws that may be spring loaded and have ends that are urged against the planar surface of the bracket <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The bracket <b>50</b> may also support a further bracket <b>56</b> whose position relative to the bracket <b>50</b> is adjustable by means of a knob <b>57</b>. A top end of the bracket <b>56</b> supports a guide piece <b>58</b> through which the elongated member may be supported and extend. The guide piece <b>58</b> is preferably constructed of a hard material such as a ceramic material.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The housing <b>12</b> is illustrated as being formed in two sections with a common depression <b>55</b> that provides a gripping surface for opening the two sections of the housing against the bias of a supporting spring. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> also illustrates by arrow B the direction of opening of a top housing section relative to a bottom housing section.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The housing <b>12</b> is considered as separated into two like housing sections identified as sections <b>12</b>A and <b>12</b>B in the drawings. These two sections are interconnected by means of a hinge arrangement that is best illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. This includes hinge plates <b>30</b>, hinge pin <b>32</b> and biasing spring <b>34</b>. The hinge pin <b>32</b> extends between the hinge plates <b>30</b> and the biasing spring <b>34</b> is wound about the hinge pin <b>32</b>. This arrangement biases the two housing sections to a closed position such as the one illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates the position of the nozzles <b>20</b>. These nozzles are adapted to be screwed into the respective housing sections with their being provided in the disclosed embodiment three nozzles for each of the housing sections. In this regard refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> that shows the three separate nozzles associated with respective housing sections <b>12</b>A and <b>12</b>B. Refer also to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> which shows the nozzles <b>20</b> coupling to the plenum chamber <b>14</b>. Refer also to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> in particular illustrates the construction of the nozzle <b>20</b> which includes a head, a threaded section and a port through which the compressed air passes. The nozzles are disposed so as to direct compressed air from an input plenum to an elongated internal tubular passage. The nozzles <b>20</b> may be of conventional design.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> illustrates the general shape of this internal passage which is adapted to receive the insert of the present invention. This internal passage <b>15</b> has a larger diameter section at <b>15</b>A and a substantially smaller diameter section at <b>15</b>B. It is noted that the smaller diameter section <b>10</b> <b>15</b>B is at the location where the nozzles direct compressed air to the tubular passage. A fluid passage is formed through each nozzle body to the tip of the nozzle to enable a flow of a fluid medium therethrough. A series of fluid passages associated with the plenum <b>14</b> may be used to connect the entry chamber with each of the individual spray nozzles. As indicated previously, there are three nozzles associated with each housing section. However, in other embodiments of the invention, fewer or greater numbers of nozzles associated with each section may be provided. These nozzles are generally situated around a 360 degree locus.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">An air or other fluid medium supply valve may be associated with the housing and is connected to a fluid supply medium which is not specifically shown herein, other than the indication of compressed air lines L. The fluid medium or air is supplied to the plenum under pressure and may flow through the plenum into the individual channels directing the compressed air to each of the individual spray nozzles. The spray nozzles inject the fluid spray under pressure into the central tubular passage and against the elongated member that is being conveyed through the air wiping device. The fluid jets from the nozzles are directed in the direction of arrow C as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. This direction is counter to and at an angle to the direction of movement of the wire <b>11</b> as the wire <b>11</b> progresses through the center passage, such as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> by the arrow A. The fluid stream may be applied against the wiring typically in a range of pressure of from 10 to 30 pounds per square inch or compressed air pressure from 10 to 100 pounds per square inch.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The application of the compressed air stream is under pressure sufficient to dislodge or blow off any collected dust, particulate matter or other contaminants that might cling to the wiring. This dislodged matter is urged in the opposite direction to the normal flow of the wiring through the air wiping device. As a result, as the wiring exits the housing through the output end of the device, the fiber has been cleaned substantially. As illustrated in, for example, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, the nozzles <b>20</b> are disposed at an angle X to the longitudinal axis Y. This angle X is preferably less than 45 degrees and is preferably in a range of 15-60 degrees to the longitudinal axis Y.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Now, in accordance with the present invention, there is provided a ceramic insert which is probably best illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</figref>. This insert is generally referred to by the reference number <b>40</b> and in, for example, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</figref>, the insert is shown as separated into two insert sections <b>40</b>A and <b>40</b>B. Each of the insert sections is substantially identical in shape and contour in the embodiment disclosed herein. The outer surface of each of the inserts is configured to match the tubular passage within the associated housing section.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">With reference to, for example, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> and the ceramic insert section <b>40</b>B, as with the other insert sections, there is included a tapered input <b>41</b> and an output at <b>42</b>, a constant diameter center passage <b>44</b> extends between the tapered input <b>41</b> and the output <b>42</b>. The elongated member being processed passes at a particular speed through the center passage <b>44</b>. The ceramic insert also has a larger diameter shown at D and a smaller diameter at E. There is also a transition between these two diameters D and E. The reduced diameter portion is important in minimizing the amount of ceramic material adjacent to the output end so that the nozzles <b>20</b> located at that area can more directly couple compressed air into the passage <b>44</b>. For this purpose, as noted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, there are a series of ports <b>46</b>, one associated with each of the nozzles <b>20</b>. In the present embodiment wherein there are three nozzles in each of the housing sections, then there would be three corresponding ports <b>46</b>. It is noted that the ceramic insert section <b>40</b>A is also provided with similar ports, illustrated at <b>46</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> also illustrates by arrow A the direction of passing of the elongated member. It is noted that the ports <b>46</b> are directed at an angle having a component that is opposite to the direction of travel of the elongated member.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Each of the ceramic insert sections also include an inlet flange <b>47</b> and an outlet flange <b>48</b>. Fasteners <b>49</b> are used for attaching each of the ceramic insert sections at their respective flanges <b>47</b> and <b>48</b>. Refer also to the left and right side views shown in respective <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref> for further illustrations of the flanges and the securing fasteners.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Each of the ceramic inserts when used with a particular wire or cable will have semicircular passages that correspond so that once these are mated together when the housing is in a closed position, such as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, a completed circular passage exists for receiving the elongated member. In order to substitute a different ceramic insert, one simply removes the fasteners and likewise removes each of the ceramic insert sections. Then, one can substitute another and different set of insert sections. A different set of insert sections may be used, for example, when accommodating a different size wire or cabling.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Having now described a limited number of embodiments of the present invention, it should now be apparent to one skilled in the art that numerous other embodiments and modifications thereof are contemplated as falling within the scope of the present invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method of cleaning an elongated product, comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>providing a housing having first and second housing sections that together define an internal tubular passage, wherein the first and second housing sections are connected by a spring-biased hinge;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a first set of nozzles mounted in the first housing section;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a second set of nozzles mounted in the second housing section, wherein said first set and said second set of nozzles are disposed about a 360 locus so as to direct a flow of compressed air to said internal tubular passage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a ceramic insert having first and second ceramic insert sections disposed removably in and extending through the internal tubular passage of the housing and through which the elongated product passes, the ceramic insert having ports corresponding to the first and second set of nozzles mounted in the housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>mounting the first ceramic insert section in the first housing section and mounting the second ceramic insert section in the second housing section by urging the two housing sections apart towards the spring-biased hinge in order to dispose in the tubular passage of the housing the ceramic insert;</claim-text>
<claim-text>coupling the first and second housing sections together using the spring biased hinge to form the internal tubular passage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>passing an elongated product through the ceramic insert extending through the internal tubular passage of the housing; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>directing the compressed air through the first and second set of nozzles in the housing to the ports in the ceramic insert to clean the elongated product. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
