<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623775-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623775</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13454109</doc-number>
<date>20120424</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>105</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>C</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>17</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>14</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>501 48</main-classification>
<further-classification>359356</further-classification>
<further-classification>252587</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Infrared absorbing filter and lens module having same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7618909</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Fujiwara et al.</name>
<date>20091100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>501 45</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0054511</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Fujiwara et al.</name>
<date>20050300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>501 45</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2013/0155495</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Wang</name>
<date>20130600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>359356</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>4-104918</doc-number>
<date>19920400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>11</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>501 48</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>252587</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>359356</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>2</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130222894</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130829</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hung</last-name>
<first-name>Hsin-Chin</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wu</last-name>
<first-name>Chia-Ying</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liao</last-name>
<first-name>Ming-Yang</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="004" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lin</last-name>
<first-name>Juin-Hong</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="005" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wei</last-name>
<first-name>Chao-Tsang</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hung</last-name>
<first-name>Hsin-Chin</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wu</last-name>
<first-name>Chia-Ying</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liao</last-name>
<first-name>Ming-Yang</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="004" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lin</last-name>
<first-name>Juin-Hong</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="005" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wei</last-name>
<first-name>Chao-Tsang</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Group</last-name>
<first-name>Karl</first-name>
<department>1731</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An infrared absorbing filter includes a glass plate molded by melting a composition of raw materials and cooling the melted composition. The composition of raw materials includes 28-33 by percentage weight (wt %) of phosphorus pentoxide (P<sub>2</sub>O<sub>5</sub>), 14-33 wt % of A oxide (A<sub>2</sub>O), 0.15-4 wt % of B oxide (BO), 2.5-8 wt % of copper oxide (CuO), 1.4-1.65 wt % of aluminum oxide (Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>). Wherein A is one of alkali metals, A<sub>2</sub>O is one of oxidizing alkali metals, B is one of alkaline earth metals, BO is one of oxidizing alkaline earth metals.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="97.87mm" wi="162.48mm" file="US08623775-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="202.61mm" wi="172.72mm" file="US08623775-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="168.32mm" wi="174.67mm" file="US08623775-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to lens modules and, particularly, to a lens module having an infrared absorbing filter for absorbing infrared light.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Lens modules may include at least one lens and a filter positioned at an image side of the lens. The filter may include a transparent substrate and an infrared filtering film coated on an object side of the transparent substrate. The filter is for reflecting infrared light rays while allowing the passage of visible light rays. However, about 5% or more of visible light rays are also reflected by the infrared filtering film. The reflected visible light rays form a glare in the image after multiple reflections in the lens module.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Therefore, it is desirable to provide a lens module, which can overcome the limitations described.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a cross-sectional schematic view of a lens module in accordance with an exemplary embodiment, the lens module including an infrared absorbing filter.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a spectrum chart of the infrared absorbing filter of the lens module of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Embodiments of the disclosure will be described with reference to the drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a lens module <b>100</b>, according to an exemplary embodiment, includes a lens barrel <b>10</b>, at least one lens <b>20</b>, an infrared absorbing filter <b>30</b>, and an image sensor <b>40</b>. Light coming into the lens barrel <b>10</b> passes the at least one lens <b>20</b> and the infrared absorbing filter <b>30</b>, and form optical images on the image sensor <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The lens barrel <b>10</b> is tubular-shaped and includes an object-side end <b>11</b> and an image-side end <b>12</b> opposite to the object-side end <b>11</b>. The lens barrel <b>10</b> defines a substantially tubular receiving room <b>13</b> extending through the object-side end <b>11</b> and the image-side end <b>12</b>. In the embodiment, the lens barrel <b>10</b> is made of light-shielding/opaque/black material(s).</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The at least one lens <b>20</b> is received in the receiving room <b>13</b>, adjacent to the object-side end <b>11</b>. Each of the at least one lens <b>20</b> can be made of plastic, glass, or other transparent materials, and can be spherical or aspherical. In the embodiment, the lens module <b>100</b> includes two lenses <b>20</b> arranged in the receiving room <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The infrared absorbing filter <b>30</b> is received in the receiving room <b>13</b>, between the at least one lens <b>20</b> and the image side end <b>12</b>. The infrared absorbing filter <b>30</b> is configured for absorbing infrared light rays penetrating through the at least one lens <b>20</b>. The infrared absorbing filter <b>30</b> includes a glass plate <b>31</b>, and the glass plate <b>31</b> includes an object-side surface <b>311</b> and an image-side surface <b>312</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The glass plate <b>31</b> is molded by melting a composition of raw materials and cooling the melted composition. The composition of raw materials includes 28-33 by percentage weight (wt %) of phosphorus pentoxide (P<sub>2</sub>O<sub>5</sub>), 14-33 wt % of A oxide (A<sub>2</sub>O), 0.15-4 wt % of B oxide (BO), 2.5-8 wt % of copper oxide (CuO), 1.4-1.65 wt % of aluminum oxide (Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>), 1-2 wt % of zine oxide (ZnO), and 15-22.5 wt % of fluoride. Wherein A is one of alkali metals, A<sub>2</sub>O is one of oxidizing alkali metals, B is one of alkaline earth metals, BO is one of oxidizing alkaline earth metals.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In the embodiment, P<sup>5+</sup> is one of the essential components of fluorophosphate glasses. If the percentage weight of P<sub>2</sub>O<sub>5 </sub>of the composition of raw materials is lower than 28%, the transmission of glass plate <b>31</b> will be decreased and the color of the glass plate <b>31</b> is green. If the percentage weight of P<sub>2</sub>O<sub>5 </sub>of the composition of raw materials is greater than 33%, the weather resistance and the surface fog degree of the glass plate <b>31</b> will be deteriorated when the weather is varied.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The A<sub>2</sub>O is chosen from the group consisting of lithium oxide (Li<sub>2</sub>O), sodium oxide (Na<sub>2</sub>O), and potassium oxide (K<sub>2</sub>O). Wherein the percentage weight of Li<sub>2</sub>O is 30-33%, the percentage weight of Na<sub>2</sub>O is 14-16%, and percentage weight of K<sub>2</sub>O is 22-24%. A<sup>+</sup> is one of the essential components of the glass plate <b>31</b> to improve the melt performance, the surface fog degree, and the transmission. If the percentage weight of A<sub>2</sub>O of the composition of raw materials is lower than 14%, the improving effect of above will not present. If the percentage weight of A<sub>2</sub>O of the composition of raw materials is greater than 33%, the surface fog degree and the processing feasibility of the glass plate <b>31</b> will be deteriorated.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The BO is chosen from the group consisting of magnesium oxide (MgO), calcium oxide (CaO), strontium oxide (SrO), and barium oxide (BaO). Wherein the percentage weight of MgO is 0.15-0.95%, the percentage weight of CaO is 0.15-4%, the percentage weight of SrO is 0.15-0.95%, and the percentage weight of BaO is 0.15-0.95%. B<sup>2+</sup> is one of the essential components of the glass plate <b>31</b> to improve the weather resistance, the surface fog degree, and the processing feasibility. If the percentage weight of BO of the composition of raw materials is lower than 0.15%, the improving effect of above will not present. If the percentage weight of BO of the composition of raw materials is greater than 4%, the surface fog degree of the glass plate <b>31</b> will be deteriorated.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Al<sup>3+</sup> is one of the essential components of the glass plate <b>31</b> to improve the surface fog degree, the heat resistance, the thermal shock, the mechanical strength, and the chemical durability. If the percentage weight of Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3 </sub>of the composition of raw materials is lower than 1.4%, the above mentioned improving effect will not be present. If the percentage weight of Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3 </sub>of the composition of raw materials is greater than 1.65%, the absorbing ability to the infrared light will be decreased.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Cu<sup>2+</sup> is one of the essential components of the glass plate <b>31</b> to absorb the infrared light. If the percentage weight of CuO of the composition of raw materials is lower than 2.5%, the absorbing ability to the infrared light will be decreased. If the percentage weight of CuO of the composition of raw materials is greater than 8%, there will be a number of flaws, such as impurities and stretch mark, formed on a surface of the glass plate <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Zn<sup>2+</sup> is used to correct the absorbing ability to the infrared light, and to improve the melt performance and the surface fog degree of the glass plate <b>31</b>. If the percentage weight of ZnO of the composition of raw materials is lower than 1%, the improving effect will not be present. If the percentage weight of ZnO of the composition of raw materials is greater than 2%, the surface fog degree of the glass plate <b>31</b> will be deteriorated.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">F<sup>&#x2212;</sup> is one of the essential anions of the glass plate <b>31</b> to decrease the melting point and improve the melt performance, the surface fog degree, and the weather resistance. If the percentage weight of fluoride of the composition of raw materials is lower than 15%, the weather resistance of the glass plate <b>31</b> will be deteriorated. If the percentage weight of fluoride of the composition of raw materials is greater than 22.5%, the percentage weight of O<sup>2&#x2212;</sup> will be decreased, and color of the glass plate <b>31</b> will be changed as the Cu<sup>2+</sup> is deoxidized to Cu<sup>+</sup>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">An anti-reflection film <b>32</b> is coated on the object-side surface <b>311</b> of the glass plate <b>31</b>. An infrared filtering film <b>33</b> is coated on the image-side surface <b>312</b> of the glass plate <b>31</b>. The anti-reflection film <b>32</b> provides an enhanced transmissivity for light, and thus less than about 3% of all light entering will be reflected by the anti-reflection film <b>32</b>. As the infrared filtering film <b>33</b> can further filter out the infrared light, less infrared lights will penetrate through the glass plate <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The image sensor <b>40</b> is positioned at the image-side end <b>12</b> and covers the receiving room <b>13</b>. The light passing the at least one lens <b>20</b> will be directly projected on an imaging surface of the image sensor <b>40</b> which converts the light to electrical signals.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Further referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, light enter into the lens module <b>100</b> from the object-side end <b>11</b> of the lens barrel <b>10</b> and strike the infrared absorbing filter <b>30</b>. The light rays penetrate the anti-reflection film <b>32</b>, then the glass plate <b>31</b>, and then the infrared filtering film <b>33</b>. The infrared constituent of the light rays penetrating the anti-reflection film <b>32</b> are absorbed by the glass plate <b>31</b>. The transmission of the light rays with wavelength from about 400 nm to about 500 nm will be above 80-90%. The middle wavelength (T50%) can be designed at any value from about 600 nm to about 650 nm. The transmission of the light rays with wavelength from about 750 nm to about 1100 nm will be lower than 3%.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Particular embodiments are shown and described by way of illustration only. The principles and the features of the present disclosure may be employed in various and numerous embodiments thereof without departing from the scope of the disclosure as claimed. The above-described embodiments illustrate the scope of the disclosure but do not restrict the scope of the disclosure.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An infrared absorbing filter, comprising:
<claim-text>a glass plate made from a composition of raw materials;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the composition of raw materials comprising: 28-33 by percentage weight (wt %) of phosphorus pentoxide (P<sub>2</sub>O<sub>5</sub>), 14-33 wt % of A oxide (A<sub>2</sub>O), 0.15-4 wt % of B oxide (BO), 2.5-8 wt % of copper oxide (CuO), 1.4-1.65 wt % of aluminum oxide (Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>);</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein A is one of alkali metals, A<sub>2</sub>O is one of oxidizing alkali metals, B is one of alkaline earth metals, and BO is one of oxidizing alkaline earth metals.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The infrared absorbing filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the composition of raw materials further comprises 1-2 wt % of zine oxide (ZnO).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The infrared absorbing filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein A<sub>2</sub>O is lithium oxide (Li<sub>2</sub>O), and the percentage weight of Li<sub>2</sub>O is 30-33%.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The infrared absorbing filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein A<sub>2</sub>O is sodium oxide (Na<sub>2</sub>O), and the percentage weight of Na<sub>2</sub>O is 14-16%.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The infrared absorbing filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein A<sub>2</sub>O is potassium oxide (K<sub>2</sub>O), and the percentage weight of K<sub>2</sub>O is 22-24%.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The infrared absorbing filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein BO is magnesium oxide (MgO), and the percentage weight of MgO is 0.15-0.95%.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The infrared absorbing filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein BO is calcium oxide (CaO), and the percentage weight of CaO is 0.15-4%.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The infrared absorbing filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein BO is strontium oxide (SrO), and the percentage weight of SrO is 0.15-0.95%.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The infrared absorbing filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein BO is barium oxide (BaO), and the percentage weight of BaO is 0.15-0.95%.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The infrared absorbing filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the composition of raw materials further comprises 15-22.5 wt % of fluoride.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A lens module, comprising:
<claim-text>at least one lens;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lens barrel receiving the at least one lens; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a infrared absorbing filter received in the lens barrel, comprising:
<claim-text>a glass plate made from a composition of raw materials;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the composition of raw materials comprising: 28-33 by percentage weight (wt %) of P<sub>2</sub>O<sub>5</sub>, 14-33 wt % of A<sub>2</sub>O, 0.15-4 wt % of BO, 2.5-8 wt % of CuO, 1.4-1.65 wt % of Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein A is one of alkali metals, A<sub>2</sub>O is one of oxidizing alkali metals, B is one of alkaline earth metals, and BO is one of oxidizing alkaline earth metals. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
