<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626002-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626002</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13741678</doc-number>
<date>20130115</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<disclaimer>
<text>This patent is subject to a terminal disclaimer.</text>
</disclaimer>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>10</main-group>
<subgroup>67</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>398209</main-classification>
<further-classification>375345</further-classification>
<further-classification>4551273</further-classification>
<further-classification>4552532</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e51">Method and system for optoelectronic receivers for uncoded data</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5430766</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Ota et al.</name>
<date>19950700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>375318</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5499244</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Mosch et al.</name>
<date>19960300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>370529</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6818407</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Hancock et al.</name>
<date>20041100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>435  71</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8358940</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kucharski</name>
<date>20130100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>398209</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0132235</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ozawa</name>
<date>20060600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>330254</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>48</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>398208-210</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>375345</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4551273</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4552532</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-cpc-text>H04B 10/691</classification-cpc-text>
<classification-cpc-text>H04B 10/6911</classification-cpc-text>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>7</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12830917</doc-number>
<date>20100706</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8358940</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13741678</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>61270665</doc-number>
<date>20090710</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130127535</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130523</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kucharski</last-name>
<first-name>Daniel</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Marcos</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kucharski</last-name>
<first-name>Daniel</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Marcos</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>McAndrews, Held &#x26; Malloy</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Luxtera, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Carlsbad</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Pascal</last-name>
<first-name>Leslie</first-name>
<department>2636</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A method and system for optoelectronic receivers for uncoded data are disclosed and may include amplifying received electrical signals in a signal amplifier comprising differential gain stages with signal detectors coupled to the outputs. First and second output voltages may be tracked and held utilizing the signal detectors. A difference between the tracked and held value may be amplified in a feedback path of the gain stage, which enables the dynamic configuration of a decision level. The received electrical signals may be generated from an optical signal by a PIN detector, an avalanche photodiode, or a phototransistor. The electrical signal may be received from a read channel. The feedback path may comprise digital circuitry, including an A/D converter, a state machine, and a D/A converter. The detectors may comprise envelope detectors utilized to detect maximum or minimum voltages. The signal amplifier may be integrated in a photonically-enabled CMOS chip.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="161.21mm" wi="197.44mm" file="US08626002-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="250.27mm" wi="196.68mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626002-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="197.02mm" wi="173.74mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626002-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="201.85mm" wi="179.58mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626002-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="221.49mm" wi="190.67mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626002-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="219.20mm" wi="184.23mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626002-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="205.74mm" wi="185.76mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626002-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="187.37mm" wi="167.05mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626002-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS/INCORPORATION BY REFERENCE</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation of application Ser. No. 12/830,917 filed on Jul. 6, 2010, which makes reference to and claims priority to U.S. Provisional Application Ser. No. 61/270,665 filed on Jul. 10, 2009. Each of the above stated applications is hereby incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FEDERALLY SPONSORED RESEARCH OR DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">[Not Applicable]</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">MICROFICHE/COPYRIGHT REFERENCE</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">[Not Applicable]</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Certain embodiments of the invention relate to signal processing. More specifically, certain embodiments of the invention relate to a method and system for single laser bidirectional links.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">As data networks scale to meet ever-increasing bandwidth requirements, the shortcomings of copper data channels are becoming apparent. Signal attenuation and crosstalk due to radiated electromagnetic energy are the main impediments encountered by designers of such systems. They can be mitigated to some extent with equalization, coding, and shielding, but these techniques require considerable power, complexity, and cable bulk penalties while offering only modest improvements in reach and very limited scalability. Free of such channel limitations, optical communication has been recognized as the successor to copper links.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Optical communication systems have been widely adopted for applications ranging from internet backbone, local area networks, data centers, supercomputing, to high-definition video. Due to superior bandwidth and low loss, optical fibers are the medium of choice for transporting high-speed binary data. However, virtually all data processing is still performed in the electrical domain. This necessitates an electrical-to-optical conversion (EO) in transmitters and optical-to-electrical (OE) conversion in receivers. Robust EO conversion is simpler, since electrical signals in the transmitter can be relatively large and well-controlled to match characteristics of lasers or optical modulators. On the other hand, OE recovery is complicated by numerous optical loss mechanisms present in practical links as well as penalties incurred due to transmitter non-idealities such as finite extinction ratio (ER).</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Further limitations and disadvantages of conventional and traditional approaches will become apparent to one of skill in the art, through comparison of such systems with the present invention as set forth in the remainder of the present application with reference to the drawings.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">A system and/or method for integrated control system for optoelectronic receivers for uncoded data, substantially as shown in and/or described in connection with at least one of the figures, as set forth more completely in the claims.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Various advantages, aspects and novel features of the present invention, as well as details of an illustrated embodiment thereof, will be more fully understood from the following description and drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> is a block diagram of a photonically enabled CMOS chip, in accordance with an embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> is a diagram illustrating an exemplary CMOS chip, in accordance with an embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</figref> is a diagram illustrating an exemplary CMOS chip coupled to an optical fiber cable, in accordance with an embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram of an uncoded data-enabled receiver, in accordance with an embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a block diagram of an uncoded data enabled receiver with dual signal detectors, in accordance with an embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a block diagram of an uncoded data enabled receiver with a DC-coupled photodetector, in accordance with an embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a block diagram of an uncoded data receiver with digital domain feedback, in accordance with an embodiment of the invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Certain aspects of the invention may be found in a method and system for optoelectronic receivers for uncoded data. Exemplary aspects of the invention may comprise amplifying received electrical signals in a signal amplifier comprising one or more differential gain stages with two or more signal detectors coupled to outputs of one or more of the differential gain stages. A value of a first sampled output voltage of a differential gain stage may be tracked and a value of a second sampled output voltage of the gain stage may be held utilizing the two or more signal detectors. A difference between the tracked value of the first sampled output voltage and the held value of the second sampled output voltage may be amplified in a feedback path of the differential gain stage, wherein the feedback path enables the dynamic configuration of a decision level for the signal amplifier. The received electrical signals may be generated from a received optical signal, which may be received utilizing a PIN detector, an avalanche photodiode, or a phototransistor. The electrical signal may be received from a read channel. The feedback path may comprise digital circuitry, including an analog-to-digital converter, a state machine, and a digital-to-analog converter. The signal detectors may comprise envelope detectors, which may be utilized to detect maximum or minimum voltages of the amplified received electrical signals. The signal amplifier may be integrated in a photonically-enabled CMOS chip.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> is a block diagram of a photonically enabled CMOS chip, in accordance with an embodiment of the invention. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>, there is shown optoelectronic devices on a CMOS chip <b>130</b> comprising optical modulators <b>105</b>A-<b>105</b>D, high-speed photodiodes <b>111</b>A-<b>111</b>D, monitor photodiodes <b>113</b>A-<b>113</b>H, and optical devices comprising taps <b>103</b>A-<b>103</b>K, optical terminations <b>115</b>A-<b>115</b>D, and grating couplers <b>117</b>A-<b>117</b>H. There is also shown electrical devices and circuits comprising amplifiers <b>107</b>A-<b>107</b>D, analog and digital control circuits <b>109</b>, and control sections <b>112</b>A-<b>112</b>D. The amplifiers <b>107</b>A-<b>107</b>D may comprise transimpedance and limiting amplifiers (TIA/LAs), for example. Optical signals are communicated between optical and optoelectronic devices via optical waveguides fabricated in the CMOS chip <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The optical modulators <b>105</b>A-<b>105</b>D comprise Mach-Zehnder or ring modulators, for example, and enable the modulation of the CW laser input signal. The optical modulators <b>105</b>A-<b>105</b>D comprise high-speed and low-speed phase modulation sections and are controlled by the control sections <b>112</b>A-<b>112</b>D. The high-speed phase modulation section of the optical modulators <b>105</b>A-<b>105</b>D may modulate a CW light source signal with a data signal. The low-speed phase modulation section of the optical modulators <b>105</b>A-<b>105</b>D may compensate for slowly varying phase factors such as those induced by mismatch between the waveguides, waveguide temperature, or waveguide stress and is referred to as the passive phase, or the passive biasing of the MZI.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">This mismatch between the waveguides may be intentional, such as in an imbalanced MZI, but is often unintentional in a nominally balanced MZI due to small imperfections in waveguide fabrication. The phase modulators then have a dual role: to compensate for the passive biasing of the MZI and to apply the additional phase modulation used to modulate the light intensity at the output port of the MZI according to a data stream. The former phase tuning and the latter phase modulation may be applied by separate, specialized devices, since the former is a low speed, slowly varying contribution, while the latter is typically a high speed signal. These devices are then respectively referred to as the LSPM and the HSPM. Examples for LSPM are thermal phase modulators (TPM), where a waveguide portion is locally heated up to modify the index of refraction of its constituting materials, or forward biased PIN junctions (PINPM) where current injection into the PIN junction modifies the carrier density, and thus the index of refraction of the semiconductor material. An example of an HSPM is a reversed biased PIN junction, where the index of refraction is also modulated via the carrier density, but which allows much faster operation, albeit at a lower phase modulation efficiency per waveguide length.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The outputs of the modulators are optically coupled via waveguides to the grating couplers <b>117</b>E-<b>117</b>H. The taps <b>103</b>D-<b>103</b>K comprise four-port optical couplers, for example, and are utilized to sample the optical signals generated by the optical modulators <b>105</b>A-<b>105</b>D, with the sampled signals being measured by the monitor photodiodes <b>113</b>A-<b>113</b>H. The unused branches of the taps <b>103</b>D-<b>103</b>K are terminated by optical terminations <b>115</b>A-<b>115</b>D to avoid back reflections of unwanted signals.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The grating couplers <b>117</b>A-<b>117</b>H comprise optical gratings that enable coupling of light into and out of the CMOS chip <b>130</b>. The grating couplers <b>117</b>A-<b>117</b>D are utilized to couple light received from optical fibers into the CMOS chip <b>130</b>, and the grating couplers <b>117</b>E-<b>117</b>H are utilized to couple light from the CMOS chip <b>130</b> into optical fibers. The grating couplers <b>117</b>A-<b>117</b>H may comprise single polarization grating couplers (SPGC) and/or polarization splitting grating couplers (PSGC). In instances where a PSGC is utilized, two input, or output, waveguides may be utilized.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The optical fibers may be epoxied, for example, to the CMOS chip, and may be aligned at an angle from normal to the surface of the CMOS chip <b>130</b> to optimize coupling efficiency. In an embodiment of the invention, the optical fibers may comprise single-mode fiber (SMF) and/or polarization-maintaining fiber (PMF). By integrating CMOS chips at each end of the optical fibers, a bidirectional link is enabled that may only require a single laser. In another embodiment of the invention, a single laser and a single fiber may be utilized to configure a bidirectional link. This may be enabled by using a PSGC, where two optical signals may be launched into the same fiber, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The high-speed photodiodes <b>111</b>A-<b>111</b>D convert optical signals received from the grating couplers <b>117</b>A-<b>117</b>D into electrical signals that are communicated to the amplifiers <b>107</b>A-<b>107</b>D for processing. The analog and digital control circuits <b>109</b> may control gain levels or other parameters in the operation of the amplifiers <b>107</b>A-<b>107</b>D, which then communicate electrical signals off the CMOS chip <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The control sections <b>112</b>A-<b>112</b>D comprise electronic circuitry that enable modulation of the CW laser signal received from the splitters <b>103</b>A-<b>103</b>C. The optical modulators <b>105</b>A-<b>105</b>D require high-speed electrical signals to modulate the refractive index in respective branches of a Mach-Zehnder interferometer (MZI), for example. In an embodiment of the invention, the control sections <b>112</b>A-<b>112</b>D may include sink and/or source driver electronics that may enable a bidirectional link utilizing a single laser.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In operation, the CMOS chip <b>130</b> may be operable to receive and process uncoded data. In an embodiment of the invention, the decision threshold uncertainty associated with OE conversion as well as baseline wander associated with unspecified run lengths and unbalanced data may be mitigated by utilizing track and hold peak detectors to monitor voltage levels in electrical signals at amplifier outputs. The photodetectors <b>111</b>A-<b>111</b>D may be coupled in a differential configuration with AC coupling via capacitors that connect cathode and anode terminals of the photodetectors to a first amplifier stage in the amplifiers <b>107</b>A-<b>107</b>D, which may generate differential outputs. Dual-mode (track/hold) peak detectors combined with a decision feedback circuit may be utilized to monitor the peak, or valley, voltages and enable the dynamic configuration of the decision level of received data signals.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Accordingly, optical signals comprising uncoded data may be communicated to the CMOS chip <b>130</b> via optical fibers and the grating couplers <b>117</b>A-<b>117</b>D. The optical signals may be converted to electrical signals by the photodetectors <b>111</b>A-<b>111</b>D. The electrical signals may be communicated to the amplifiers <b>107</b>A-<b>107</b>D, which may comprise a plurality of stages. The output voltages at both differential outputs of one or more stages of the amplifiers <b>107</b>A-<b>107</b>D may be monitored. By holding the measured peak voltage level of one differential output while tracking the other differential output voltage, decision levels for the amplifiers <b>107</b>A-<b>107</b>D may be dynamically configured. In this manner, uncoded data may be processed accurately without requiring active DC balancing. In another embodiment of the invention, output currents may be monitored as opposed to output voltages.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In an exemplary embodiment of the invention, data decision may be fed back from the output of the amplifiers <b>107</b>A-<b>107</b>D to peak detectors, and may be utilized to determine which peak detector is holding and which is tracking. Thus, the amplifiers <b>107</b>A-<b>107</b>D may comprise two feedback paths. The analog path may compare outputs of the peak detectors and feed the amplifier input. The decision feedback path may comprise binary output and control the mode of the peak detectors.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> is a diagram illustrating an exemplary CMOS chip, in accordance with an embodiment of the invention. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref>, there is shown the CMOS chip <b>130</b> comprising electronic devices/circuits <b>131</b>, optical and optoelectronic devices <b>133</b>, a light source interface <b>135</b>, CMOS chip front surface <b>137</b>A, CMOS chip back surface <b>137</b>B, an optical fiber interface <b>139</b>, and CMOS guard ring <b>141</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The light source interface <b>135</b> and the optical fiber interface <b>139</b> comprise grating couplers that enable coupling of light signals via the CMOS chip surface <b>137</b>, as opposed to the edges of the chip as with conventional edge-emitting devices. Coupling light signals via the CMOS chip surface <b>137</b> enables the use of the CMOS guard ring <b>141</b> which protects the chip mechanically and prevents the entry of contaminants via the chip edge.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The electronic devices/circuits <b>131</b> comprise circuitry such as the amplifiers <b>107</b>A-<b>107</b>D and the analog and digital control circuits <b>109</b> described with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>, for example. The optical and optoelectronic devices <b>133</b> comprise devices such as the taps <b>103</b>A-<b>103</b>K, optical terminations <b>115</b>A-<b>115</b>D, grating couplers <b>117</b>A-<b>117</b>H, optical modulators <b>105</b>A-<b>105</b>D, high-speed photodiodes <b>111</b>A-<b>111</b>D, and monitor photodiodes <b>113</b>A-<b>113</b>H.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In an embodiment of the invention, uncoded data may be received and processed by the CMOS chip <b>130</b> utilizing dual-mode track and hold peak detectors at the differential outputs of one or more stages in amplifiers, such as the amplifiers <b>107</b>A-<b>107</b>D. In this manner, the decision level may be accurately and dynamically configured for receiving and processing high-speed uncoded data.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In an exemplary embodiment of the invention, data decision may be fed back from the output of the amplifiers <b>107</b>A-<b>107</b>D to peak detectors, and may be utilized to determine which peak detector is holding and which is tracking. Thus, the amplifiers <b>107</b>A-<b>107</b>D may comprise two feedback paths. The analog path may compare outputs of the peak detectors and feed the amplifier input. The decision feedback path may comprise binary output and control the mode of the peak detectors.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</figref> is a diagram illustrating an exemplary CMOS chip coupled to an optical fiber cable, in accordance with an embodiment of the invention. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</figref>, there is shown the CMOS chip <b>130</b> comprising the CMOS chip front surface <b>137</b>A, the CMOS chip back surface <b>137</b>B, and the CMOS guard ring <b>141</b>. There is also shown a fiber-to-chip coupler <b>143</b>, an optical fiber cable <b>145</b>, and an optical source assembly <b>147</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The CMOS chip <b>130</b> comprising the electronic devices/circuits <b>131</b>, the optical and optoelectronic devices <b>133</b>, the light source interface <b>135</b>, the CMOS chip surface <b>137</b>, and the CMOS guard ring <b>141</b> may be as described with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In an embodiment of the invention, the optical fiber cable may be affixed, via epoxy for example, to the CMOS chip back surface <b>137</b>B. The fiber chip coupler <b>143</b> enables the physical coupling of the optical fiber cable <b>145</b> to the CMOS chip <b>130</b>, and may enable a bidirectional link using one laser source.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram of an uncoded data-enabled receiver, in accordance with an embodiment of the invention, which may be used in connection with the CMOS chip <b>130</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A-1C</figref>, for example. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, there is shown a receiver <b>200</b> comprising detector feedback path <b>210</b>, decision feedback path <b>220</b>, amplifiers <b>201</b>A . . . <b>201</b>N, a feedback amplifier <b>203</b>, detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B, a logic block <b>207</b>, a photodetector <b>209</b>, an inverter <b>211</b>, bias resistors RB<b>1</b> and RB<b>2</b>, feedback resistors RF<b>1</b> and RF<b>2</b>, and coupling capacitors C<b>1</b> and C<b>2</b>. There is also shown a photodetector bias voltage VPD, input signals Q<b>0</b> and Q<b>0</b>B, output signals Q<b>1</b>, Q<b>1</b>B, and Out, and a common-mode reference voltage VcmRef.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The amplifiers <b>201</b>A . . . <b>201</b>N comprise a number, N, of gain stages and may comprise differential amplifiers for amplifying received electrical signals generated by the photodetector <b>209</b>. The number of gain stages is not limited to the size shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. Accordingly, any number of gain stages may be utilized, depending on chip space and power requirements, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The feedback amplifier <b>203</b> may comprise a differential operational amplifier with common-mode feedback, for example, and may be operable to amplify a feedback signal comprising the output signals received from the detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B. The feedback amplifier <b>203</b> may utilize a common-mode reference voltage which may determine the common mode voltage of its outputs while the differential output of the feedback amplifier is proportional to the difference of voltages applied to its inputs, which may be determined by the detectors <b>205</b>A or <b>205</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B may comprise envelope detectors, such as semiconductor diodes, that may be operable to measure peak, or valley, voltage values of the output signals Q<b>1</b> and Q<b>1</b>B of the amplifier <b>201</b>A. The signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B comprise dual-mode capability, enabled to track a voltage or to hold a sampled voltage. In another embodiment of the invention, the detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B may monitor output currents. In an embodiment of the invention, the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B may be coupled at any stage along the receiver <b>200</b> path. The coupling point may be based on signal amplitude versus a reference voltage, where a higher amplitude may relax detector matching requirements, allowing smaller transistors and thus less signal path loading.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The logic block <b>207</b> may comprise decision logic that may be operable to control the track/hold modes of the detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B. The inverter <b>211</b> may ensure that the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B are always in opposite states, i.e. when the signal detector <b>205</b>A is in track mode, the signal detector <b>205</b>B is in hold mode.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The photodetector <b>209</b> may comprise a semiconductor photodetector, such as a germanium or silicon-germanium photodiode, integrated in the CMOS chip <b>130</b>, and may be operable to convert a received optical signal into an electrical signal. The photodetector may comprise a photoconductor, a photodiode, or an avalanche photodetector, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In operation, an optical signal may be detected by the photodetector <b>209</b> and converted to an electrical signal. The electrical signal may be AC-coupled to the differential amplifier <b>201</b>A via the capacitors C<b>1</b> and C<b>2</b>, resulting in input voltages Q<b>0</b> and Q<b>0</b>B. The photodetector <b>209</b> may be biased by the voltage VPD and the bias resistors RB<b>1</b> and RB<b>2</b>. The signals Q<b>0</b> and Q<b>0</b>B may be amplified by the amplifier <b>201</b>A, resulting in output voltages Q<b>1</b> and Q<b>1</b>B, which may be monitored by the signal detectors <b>205</b> and <b>205</b>B. One of the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B may hold a sampled voltage value while the other detector may track the output voltage. For example, when the signal detector <b>205</b>A is tracking the peak, or valley, voltage of Q<b>1</b>B, the detector <b>205</b>B may hold the peak, or valley, voltage of Q<b>1</b>. The state, sample or hold, of the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B may be configured by the logic block <b>207</b>, with the inverted signal being applied to the signal detector <b>205</b>A via the inverter <b>211</b>. In another embodiment of the invention, the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B may measure current as opposed to voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The output signals of the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B may be amplified by the feedback amplifier <b>203</b> and communicated back to the inputs of the amplifier <b>201</b>A via the feedback resistors RF<b>1</b> and RF<b>2</b>. In this manner, the difference between the tracked voltage and the hold voltage may be utilized as a feedback signal, thereby dynamically controlling the decision threshold of the receiver. In this manner, the receiver <b>200</b> may be operable to receive uncoded data without errors due to decision level shifts caused by long strings of unchanged bits, for example. Accordingly, no off-line calibration is required and effectively eliminates DC offset cancellation requirements since the decision level may be dynamically controlled.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In addition, due to the tracking capability of the receiver, initial decision feedback errors may be tolerated, providing a reliable startup without a training sequence regardless of the pattern received. In an exemplary embodiment, settling may be improved by applying a common-mode reference voltage to the first stage, amplifier <b>201</b>A, at startup and then switch to feedback control after data is detected, such as indicated by a loss of signal (LOS) circuit, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The RC constant of the receiver <b>200</b> may be affected by a pole of the feedback amplifier <b>203</b>. This may be mitigated using a fast, one-stage operational amplifier with a pole well above the dominant pole of the feedback loop. Similarly, to ensure stability of the non-linear feedback circuit, the droop of the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B in track mode should be faster than the voltage droop associated with AC coupling. Stability may also be enhanced by utilizing high-speed CMOS technology, such as 130 nm or better, thereby reducing the delay of decision feedback of the logic block <b>207</b>. For a smooth transition between track and hold modes of the detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B, standard injection and leakage mitigation techniques may be utilized.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In an exemplary embodiment of the invention, a data decision may be fed back from the output of the amplifier <b>201</b>N to the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B, and may be utilized to determine which signal detector is holding and which is tracking. Thus, the receiver <b>200</b> may comprise at least two feedback paths, the detector output feedback path <b>210</b> and the decision feedback path <b>220</b>. The analog detector output feedback path <b>210</b> may compare outputs of the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B and feed the receiver <b>200</b> input. The decision feedback path <b>220</b> may comprise binary outputs and control the mode of the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The invention is not limited to operation based on optical signals or optical communication, or necessarily limited to the embodiments shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A-1C</figref>. In a non-limiting example of another embodiment of the invention, the input signal to the receiver <b>200</b> may be from a magnetic or other disk drive, for example, where high throughput data transfer may be desired without data coding. Accordingly, aspects of the present invention may be incorporated into or operate in connection with a read channel, for example. In an exemplary embodiment, the output, Out, of the receiver <b>200</b> may comprise current-mode logic (CML) signals.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a block diagram of an uncoded data enabled receiver with dual signal detectors, in accordance with an embodiment of the invention. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, there is shown a receiver <b>200</b> comprising the amplifiers <b>201</b>A . . . <b>201</b>N, feedback amplifiers <b>303</b>A and <b>303</b>B, signal detectors <b>305</b>A-<b>305</b>D, the logic block <b>207</b>, the photodetector <b>209</b>, a current to voltage converter <b>311</b>, the bias resistors RB<b>1</b> and RB<b>2</b>, the feedback resistors RF<b>1</b> and RF<b>2</b>, and the coupling capacitors C<b>1</b> and C<b>2</b>. There is also shown a photodetector bias voltage VPD, input signals Q<b>0</b> and Q<b>0</b>B, output signals Q<b>1</b>, Q<b>1</b>B, and Out, and a common-mode reference voltage VcmRef.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The amplifiers <b>201</b>A . . . <b>201</b>N, the logic block <b>207</b>, the photodetector <b>209</b>, the bias resistors RB<b>1</b> and RB<b>2</b>, the feedback resistors RF<b>1</b> and RF<b>2</b>, and the coupling capacitors C<b>1</b> and C<b>2</b> may be as described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, and the detectors <b>305</b>A-<b>305</b>D may be substantially similar to the detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The feedback amplifiers <b>303</b>A and <b>303</b>B may comprise transconductance amplifiers, for example, that may be operable to receive input voltage signals from the signal detectors <b>305</b>A-<b>305</b>D and generate a proportional output current. The feedback amplifiers <b>303</b>A and <b>303</b>B may also receive as inputs the common-mode reference voltage VcmRef.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The current-to-voltage converter <b>311</b> may be operable to generate output voltages proportional to received input currents. The outputs of the current-to-voltage converter <b>311</b> may be coupled to the inputs of the amplifier <b>201</b>A via the feedback resistors RF<b>1</b> and RF<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In operation, an optical signal may be detected by the photodetector <b>209</b> and converted to an electrical signal. The electrical signal may be AC-coupled to the differential amplifier <b>201</b>A via the capacitors C<b>1</b> and C<b>2</b>, resulting in input voltages Q<b>0</b> and Q<b>0</b>B. The photodetector <b>209</b> may be biased by the voltage VPD and the bias resistors RB<b>1</b> and RB<b>2</b>. The signals Q<b>0</b> and Q<b>0</b>B may be amplified by the amplifier <b>201</b>A, resulting in output voltages Q<b>1</b> and Q<b>1</b>B, which may be monitored by the detectors <b>305</b>A-<b>305</b>D. In an exemplary embodiment, one pair of detectors may monitor a bottom, or valley, voltage, while the other pair of detectors may monitor peak voltages. For example, the signal detectors <b>305</b>A and <b>305</b>C may monitor bottom voltages of Q<b>1</b>B and Q<b>1</b>, respectively, and the signal detectors <b>305</b>B and <b>305</b>D may monitor peak voltages of Q<b>1</b>B and Q<b>1</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">One of each pair may hold a sampled voltage value while the other signal detector may track the output voltage. For example, when the signal detector <b>305</b>B is tracking the peak voltage of Q<b>1</b>B, the detector <b>305</b>D may hold the peak voltage of Q<b>1</b>. The state of the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B, sample or hold, may be configured by the logic block <b>207</b>, with the inverted signal being applied to the signal detectors <b>305</b>B and <b>305</b>C. In another embodiment of the invention, the signal detectors <b>305</b>A-<b>305</b>D may measure current as opposed to voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The output signals of the signal detectors <b>305</b>A-<b>305</b>D may be amplified by the feedback amplifiers <b>303</b>A and <b>303</b>B, with peak voltage measurements being communicated to one amplifier, and the valley values to the other amplifier. The output currents of the amplifiers <b>303</b>A and <b>303</b>B may be converted to output voltages by the current-to-voltage converter <b>311</b> and communicated back to the inputs of the amplifier <b>201</b>A via the feedback resistors RF<b>1</b> and RF<b>2</b>. In this manner, the difference between the tracked peak and valley voltages and the hold peak and valley voltages may be utilized as feedback signals, thereby dynamically controlling the decision threshold of the receiver. In this manner, the receiver <b>300</b> may be operable to receive uncoded data without errors due to decision level shifts caused by long strings of unchanged bits, for example. In an exemplary embodiment, the output, Out, of the receiver <b>300</b> may comprise current-mode logic (CML) signals.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In an exemplary embodiment of the invention, a data decision may be fed back from the output of the amplifier <b>201</b>N to the signal detectors <b>305</b>A-<b>305</b>D, and may be utilized to determine which signal detector is holding and which is tracking. Thus, the receiver <b>300</b> may comprise at least two feedback paths, the detector output feedback path <b>210</b> and the decision feedback path <b>220</b>. The analog detector output feedback path <b>210</b> may compare outputs of the signal detectors <b>305</b>A-<b>305</b>D and feed the receiver <b>300</b> input. The decision feedback path <b>220</b> may comprise binary outputs and control the mode of the signal detectors <b>305</b>A-<b>305</b>D.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Again, the invention is not limited to operation based on optical signals or optical communication, or limited necessarily to the embodiments shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A-1C</figref>. In a non-limiting example of another embodiment of the invention, the input signal to the receiver <b>300</b> may be from a magnetic or other disk drive, for example, where high throughput data transfer may be desired without data coding. Accordingly, aspects of the present invention may be incorporated into or operate in connection with a read channel, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a block diagram of an uncoded data enabled receiver with a DC-coupled photodetector, in accordance with an embodiment of the invention. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, there is shown a receiver <b>400</b> comprising the amplifiers <b>201</b>A . . . <b>201</b>N, the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B, the logic block <b>207</b>, the photodetector <b>209</b>, the inverter <b>211</b>, a low-pass filter <b>401</b>, and a feedback amplifier <b>403</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The amplifiers <b>201</b>A . . . <b>201</b>N, the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B, the logic block <b>207</b>, the photodetector <b>209</b>, and the inverter <b>211</b> may be as described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The low-pass filter <b>401</b> may comprise a filter in the feedback path of the receiver <b>400</b> to eliminate high-frequency effects in the feedback control.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The feedback amplifier <b>403</b> may comprise an operational amplifier, for example, that may be operable to amplify signals received from the detectors <b>405</b>A and <b>405</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">In operation, the receiver <b>400</b> may operate substantially similar to the receivers <b>200</b> and <b>300</b>, but with DC-coupled photodetector, which does not have the increased signal advantage of a differentially-coupled photodetector, but still provides the decision threshold tuning with the peak/valley voltage feedback loop control.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">An optical signal may be detected by the photodetector <b>209</b> and converted to an electrical signal. The electrical signal may be DC-coupled to the differential amplifier <b>201</b>A, resulting in input voltages Q<b>0</b> and Q<b>0</b>B. The photodetector <b>209</b> may be biased by the voltage VPD. The signals Q<b>0</b> and Q<b>0</b>B may be amplified by the amplifier <b>201</b>A, resulting in output voltages Q<b>1</b> and Q<b>1</b>B, which may be monitored by the signal detectors <b>205</b> and <b>205</b>B. One of the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B may hold a sampled voltage value while the other detector may track the output voltage. For example, when the signal detector <b>205</b>A is tracking the peak, or valley, voltage of Q<b>1</b>B, the signal detector <b>205</b>B may hold the peak, or valley, voltage of Q<b>1</b>. The state, either sample or hold, of the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B may be configured by the logic block <b>207</b>, with the inverted signal being applied to the signal detector <b>205</b>A via the inverter <b>211</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The output signals of the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B may be amplified by the feedback amplifier <b>403</b> and communicated back to the inputs of the amplifier <b>201</b>A via the low-pass filter <b>401</b>. In this manner, the difference between the tracked voltage and the hold voltage may be utilized as a feedback signal, thereby dynamically controlling the decision threshold of the receiver. In this manner, the receiver <b>400</b> may be operable to receive uncoded data from a DC-coupled photodetector without errors due to decision level shifts caused by long strings of unchanged bits, for example. Accordingly, no off-line calibration is required and DC offset cancellation requirements are effectively eliminated since the decision level may be dynamically controlled.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">In an exemplary embodiment of the invention, a data decision may be fed back from the output of the amplifier <b>201</b>N to the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B, and may be utilized to determine which signal detector is holding and which is tracking. Thus, the receiver <b>400</b> may comprise at least two feedback paths, the detector output feedback path <b>210</b> and the decision feedback path <b>220</b>. The analog detector output feedback path <b>210</b> may compare outputs of the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B and feed the receiver <b>400</b> input. The decision feedback path <b>220</b> may comprise binary outputs and control the mode of the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Once again, the invention is not limited to operation based on optical signals or optical communication, or limited necessarily to the embodiments shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A-1C</figref>. In a non-limiting example of another embodiment of the invention, the input signal to the receiver <b>400</b> may be from a magnetic or other disk drive, for example, where high throughput data transfer may be desired without data coding. Accordingly, aspects of the present invention may be incorporated into or operate in connection with a read channel, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a block diagram of an uncoded data receiver with digital domain feedback, in accordance with an embodiment of the invention. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, there is shown a receiver <b>500</b> comprising the amplifiers <b>201</b>A . . . <b>201</b>N, the detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B, the logic block <b>207</b>, the photodetector <b>209</b>, a digital-to-analog (D/A) converter <b>501</b>, a digital state machine <b>503</b>, and an analog-to-digital (A/D) converter <b>505</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The amplifiers <b>201</b>A . . . <b>201</b>N, the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B, the logic block <b>207</b>, and the photodetector <b>209</b> may be as described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The state machine <b>503</b> may comprise configurable logic that may control the feedback path parameters. For example, the state machine <b>503</b> may be operable to filter out out-of-band noise and/or provide appropriate gain levels for received digital signals.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">In operation, the receiver <b>500</b> may operate substantially similar to the receivers <b>200</b>, <b>300</b>, and/or <b>400</b>, for example, but with a digital feedback loop. An optical signal may be detected by the photodetector <b>209</b> and converted to an electrical signal. The electrical signal may be DC-coupled to the differential amplifier <b>201</b>A, resulting in input voltages Q<b>0</b> and Q<b>0</b>B. The photodetector <b>209</b> may be biased by the voltage VPD. The signals Q<b>0</b> and Q<b>0</b>B may be amplified by the amplifier <b>201</b>A, resulting in output voltages Q<b>1</b> and Q<b>1</b>B, which may be monitored by the signal detectors <b>205</b> and <b>205</b>B. One of the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B may hold a sampled voltage value while the other detector may track the output voltage. For example, when the signal detector <b>205</b>A is tracking the peak, or valley, voltage of Q<b>1</b>B, the signal detector <b>205</b>B may hold the peak, or valley, voltage of Q<b>1</b>. The state, either sample or hold, of the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B may be configured by the logic block <b>207</b>, via the state machine <b>503</b>. In another embodiment of the invention, the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B may measure current as opposed to voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">The output signals of the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B may be converted to digital signals by the A/D <b>505</b> and processed by the state machine <b>503</b>, which may perform filtering, amplification, and other desired processing steps accomplished by the analog feedback paths in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-4</figref>, as well as other digital processing steps not enabled by analog circuitry. A clock signal, Clock, may provide synchronized processing in the D/A <b>501</b>, the state machine <b>503</b>, and the A/D <b>505</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The processed signals may be converted back to analog signals by the D/A <b>501</b> before being communicated back to an input of the amplifier <b>201</b>A, thereby completing the feedback path. In this manner, the difference between the tracked voltage and the hold voltage may be utilized as a feedback signal, thereby dynamically controlling the decision threshold of the receiver <b>500</b>. Since the photodetector <b>209</b> is DC-coupled, there may be no baseline droop associated with AC-coupling, but because of the feedback stabilized decision threshold, the receiver <b>500</b> may be operable to receive uncoded data from a DC-coupled photodetector without errors. Accordingly, no off-line calibration is required and DC offset cancellation requirements may be effectively eliminated since the decision level may be dynamically controlled.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">In an exemplary embodiment of the invention, a data decision may be fed back from the output of the amplifier <b>201</b>N to the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B, and may be utilized to determine which signal detector is holding and which is tracking. Thus, the receiver <b>500</b> may comprise at least two feedback paths, the detector output feedback path <b>210</b> and the decision feedback path <b>220</b>. The analog detector output feedback path <b>210</b> may convert the signals to digital in the A/D <b>505</b> and compare outputs of the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B as well as feed the receiver <b>500</b> input. The decision feedback path <b>220</b> may comprise binary outputs and control the mode of the signal detectors <b>205</b>A and <b>205</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">In another exemplary embodiment of the invention, the digital feedback path described with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> may be utilized with the differentially-coupled photodetector configurations described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>. Similarly, however, the invention is not limited to operation based on optical signals or optical communication, or necessarily limited to the photodetector configurations described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref> or to the embodiments illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A-1C</figref>. In another non-limiting example of an embodiment of the invention, the input signal Q<b>0</b> to the receiver <b>500</b> may be from a magnetic or other disk drive, for example, where high throughput data transfer may be desired without data coding. Accordingly, aspects of the present invention may be incorporated into or operate in connection with a read channel, for example. In fact, aspects of the various embodiments may be used in any application desiring high throughput data transfer without data coding.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">In an embodiment of the invention, a method and system are disclosed for optoelectronic receivers for uncoded data. Aspects of the invention may comprise amplifying received electrical signals Q<b>0</b> and Q<b>0</b>B in a signal amplifier <b>107</b>A-<b>107</b>D, <b>200</b>, <b>300</b>, <b>400</b>, <b>500</b> comprising one or more differential gain stages <b>201</b>A . . . <b>201</b>N with two or more signal detectors <b>205</b>A, <b>205</b>B, <b>305</b>A-<b>305</b>D coupled to outputs of one or more of the differential gain stages <b>201</b>A . . . <b>201</b>N. A value of a first sampled output voltage Q<b>1</b>, Q<b>1</b>B of a differential gain stage <b>201</b>A . . . <b>201</b>N may be tracked and a value of a second sampled output voltage of the gain stage <b>201</b>A . . . <b>201</b>N may be held utilizing the two or more signal detectors <b>205</b>A, <b>205</b>B, <b>305</b>A-<b>305</b>D. A difference between the tracked value of the first sampled output voltage Q<b>1</b>, Q<b>1</b>B and the held value of the second sampled output voltage Q<b>1</b>, Q<b>1</b>B may be amplified in a feedback path of the differential gain stage <b>205</b>A, <b>205</b>B, <b>305</b>A-<b>305</b>D, wherein the feedback path enables the dynamic configuration of a decision level for the signal amplifier <b>107</b>A-<b>107</b>D, <b>200</b>, <b>300</b>, <b>400</b>, <b>500</b>. The mode of operation of the signal detectors <b>205</b>A, <b>205</b>B, <b>305</b>A-<b>305</b>D may be determined by a decision feed back circuit comprising logic circuit <b>207</b> and/or a digital state machine <b>503</b> with A/D and D/A converters <b>501</b> and <b>505</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The received electrical signals may be generated from a received optical signal, which may be received utilizing a PIN detector <b>117</b>A-<b>117</b>D, <b>209</b>, an avalanche photodiode <b>117</b>A-<b>117</b>D, <b>209</b>, or a phototransistor <b>117</b>A-<b>117</b>D, <b>209</b>. The electrical signal may be received from a read channel. The feedback path may comprise digital circuitry, including an analog-to-digital converter <b>505</b>, a state machine <b>503</b>, and a digital-to-analog converter <b>501</b>. The detectors <b>205</b>A, <b>205</b>B, <b>305</b>A-<b>305</b>D may comprise envelope detectors, which may be utilized to detect maximum or minimum voltages of the amplified received electrical signals Q<b>1</b>, Q<b>1</b>B. The signal amplifier <b>107</b>A-<b>107</b>D, <b>200</b>, <b>300</b>, <b>400</b>, <b>500</b> may be integrated in a photonically-enabled CMOS chip <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">While the invention has been described with reference to certain embodiments, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes may be made and equivalents may be substituted without departing from the scope of the present invention. In addition, many modifications may be made to adapt a particular situation or material to the teachings of the present invention without departing from its scope. Therefore, it is intended that the present invention not be limited to the particular embodiments disclosed, but that the present invention will include all embodiments falling within the scope of the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method for processing signals, the method comprising:
<claim-text>in a signal amplifier comprising one or more differential gain stages, two or more feedback paths, and two or more signal detectors coupled to outputs of one or more of said one or more differential gain stages:</claim-text>
<claim-text>amplifying received electrical signals utilizing one of said one or more differential gain stages;</claim-text>
<claim-text>tracking a value of a first sampled output signal and holding a value of a second sampled output signal of said one of said one or more differential gain stages utilizing said two or more signal detectors; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>controlling a mode of said signal detectors utilizing a second of said two or more feedback paths.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, comprising generating said received electrical signals from a received optical signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, comprising receiving said optical signal utilizing one or more of: a PIN photodiode, an avalanche photodiode, and a phototransistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, comprising receiving said electrical signal from a read channel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said feedback path comprises digital circuitry.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said digital circuitry comprises an analog-to-digital converter, a state machine, and a digital-to-analog converter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said two or more signal detectors comprise envelope detectors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, comprising detecting maximum voltages of said amplified received electrical signals utilizing said envelope detectors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, comprising detecting minimum voltages of said amplified received electrical signals utilizing said envelope detectors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said signal amplifier is integrated in a photonically-enabled CMOS chip.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said signal detectors measure output voltages.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said signal detectors measure output currents.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A system for processing signals, the system comprising:
<claim-text>one or more circuits in a signal amplifier comprising one or more differential gain stages, two or more feedback paths, and two or more signal detectors coupled to outputs of one or more of said one or more differential gain stages, said one or more circuits being operable to:</claim-text>
<claim-text>amplify received electrical signals utilizing one of said one or more differential gain stages;</claim-text>
<claim-text>track a value of a first sampled output signal and holding a value of a second sampled output signal of said one of said one or more differential gain stages utilizing said two or more signal detectors; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>control a mode of said signal detectors utilizing a second of said two or more feedback paths.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein said one or more circuits are operable to generate said received electrical signals from a received optical signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein said one or more circuits are operable to receive said optical signal utilizing one or more of: a PIN photodiode, an avalanche photodiode, and a phototransistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein said one or more circuits are operable to receive said electrical signal from a read channel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein said feedback path comprises digital circuitry.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein said digital circuitry comprises an analog-to-digital converter, a state machine, and a digital-to-analog converter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein said two or more signal detectors comprise envelope detectors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein said one or more circuits are operable to detect maximum voltages of said amplified received electrical signals utilizing said envelope detectors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein said one or more circuits are operable to detect minimum voltages of said amplified received electrical signals utilizing said envelope detectors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein said signal amplifier is integrated in a photonically-enabled CMOS chip.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein said signal detectors measure output voltages.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein said signal detectors measure output currents.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text>25. A method for processing signals, the method comprising:
<claim-text>in a signal amplifier comprising one or more differential gain stages, a decision feedback path and a detector output feedback path, and two or more signal detectors coupled to outputs of one or more of said one or more differential gain stages:</claim-text>
<claim-text>amplifying received electrical signals utilizing one of said one or more differential gain stages;</claim-text>
<claim-text>tracking a value of a first sampled output signal and holding a value of a second sampled output signal of said one of said one or more differential gain stages utilizing said two or more signal detectors;</claim-text>
<claim-text>amplifying a difference between said tracked value of said first sampled output signal and said held value of said second sampled output signal in said detector output feedback path of said signal amplifier, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>controlling a mode of said signal detectors utilizing said decision feedback path, wherein said decision feedback path and said detector feedback path enable the dynamic configuration of a decision level for said signal amplifier.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text>26. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00025">claim 25</claim-ref>, comprising generating said received electrical signals from a received optical signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text>27. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00026">claim 26</claim-ref>, comprising receiving said optical signal utilizing one or more of: a PIN photodiode, an avalanche photodiode, and a phototransistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text>28. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00025">claim 25</claim-ref>, comprising receiving said electrical signal from a read channel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029" num="00029">
<claim-text>29. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00025">claim 25</claim-ref>, wherein said detector output feedback path comprises digital circuitry.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030" num="00030">
<claim-text>30. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00029">claim 29</claim-ref>, wherein said digital circuitry comprises an analog-to-digital converter, a state machine, and a digital-to-analog converter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031" num="00031">
<claim-text>31. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00025">claim 25</claim-ref>, wherein said two or more signal detectors comprise envelope detectors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032" num="00032">
<claim-text>32. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00031">claim 31</claim-ref>, comprising detecting maximum voltages of said amplified received electrical signals utilizing said envelope detectors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033" num="00033">
<claim-text>33. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00031">claim 31</claim-ref>, comprising detecting minimum voltages of said amplified received electrical signals utilizing said envelope detectors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034" num="00034">
<claim-text>34. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00025">claim 25</claim-ref>, wherein said signal amplifier is integrated in a photonically-enabled CMOS chip.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035" num="00035">
<claim-text>35. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00025">claim 25</claim-ref>, wherein said signal detectors measure output voltages.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036" num="00036">
<claim-text>36. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00025">claim 25</claim-ref>, wherein said signal detectors measure output currents.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037" num="00037">
<claim-text>37. A system for processing signals, the system comprising:
<claim-text>a signal amplifier comprising one or more differential gain stages, a decision feedback path and a detector output feedback path, and two or more signal detectors coupled to outputs of one or more of said one or more differential gain stages, said signal amplifier being operable to:
<claim-text>amplify received electrical signals utilizing one of said one or more differential gain stages;</claim-text>
<claim-text>track a value of a first sampled output signal and holding a value of a second sampled output signal of said one of said one or more differential gain stages utilizing said two or more signal detectors;</claim-text>
<claim-text>amplify a difference between said tracked value of said first sampled output signal and said held value of said second sampled output signal in said detector output feedback path of said signal amplifier, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>control a mode of said signal detectors utilizing said decision feedback path, wherein said decision feedback path and said detector feedback path enable the dynamic configuration of a decision level for said signal amplifier.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038" num="00038">
<claim-text>38. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00037">claim 37</claim-ref>, wherein said signal amplifier is operable to generate said received electrical signals from a received optical signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039" num="00039">
<claim-text>39. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00038">claim 38</claim-ref>, wherein said signal amplifier is operable to receive said optical signal utilizing one or more of: a PIN photodiode, an avalanche photodiode, and a phototransistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040" num="00040">
<claim-text>40. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00037">claim 37</claim-ref>, wherein said signal amplifier is operable to receive said electrical signal from a read channel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041" num="00041">
<claim-text>41. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00037">claim 37</claim-ref>, wherein said detector output feedback path comprises digital circuitry.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042" num="00042">
<claim-text>42. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00041">claim 41</claim-ref>, wherein said digital circuitry comprises an analog-to-digital converter, a state machine, and a digital-to-analog converter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043" num="00043">
<claim-text>43. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00037">claim 37</claim-ref>, wherein said two or more signal detectors comprise envelope detectors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044" num="00044">
<claim-text>44. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00043">claim 43</claim-ref>, wherein said signal amplifier is operable to detect maximum voltages of said amplified received electrical signals utilizing said envelope detectors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045" num="00045">
<claim-text>45. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00043">claim 43</claim-ref>, wherein said signal amplifier is operable to detect minimum voltages of said amplified received electrical signals utilizing said envelope detectors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046" num="00046">
<claim-text>46. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00037">claim 37</claim-ref>, wherein said signal amplifier is integrated in a photonically-enabled CMOS chip.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047" num="00047">
<claim-text>47. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00037">claim 37</claim-ref>, wherein said signal detectors measure output voltages.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048" num="00048">
<claim-text>48. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00037">claim 37</claim-ref>, wherein said signal detectors measure output currents. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
