<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626325-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626325</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12953481</doc-number>
<date>20101124</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2010 1 0523454</doc-number>
<date>20101028</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>617</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>17</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>700 94</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Audio device and method for appending identification data into audio signals</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6345100</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Levine</name>
<date>20020200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>380205</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6389055</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>August et al.</name>
<date>20020500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>375130</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6691083</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Breen</name>
<date>20040200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0322426</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Nyboe et al.</name>
<date>20091200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0002891</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Shiraishi et al.</name>
<date>20100100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0019775</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ikejiri</name>
<date>20100100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0034513</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Nakano et al.</name>
<date>20100200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>386 94</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0246202</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>McMillan et al.</name>
<date>20111000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>704270</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>8</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>700 94</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>704500-504</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>704E19009</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>713176</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>386260</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120109346</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120503</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Feng</last-name>
<first-name>Xue-Wen</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Qiu</last-name>
<first-name>Jian-Ming</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Guo</last-name>
<first-name>Dong-Jiao</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Feng</last-name>
<first-name>Xue-Wen</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Qiu</last-name>
<first-name>Jian-Ming</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Guo</last-name>
<first-name>Dong-Jiao</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hong Fu Jin Precision Industry (ShenZhen) Co., Ltd</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Flanders</last-name>
<first-name>Andrew C</first-name>
<department>2656</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An audio device includes a processor, a storage unit, an audio processing module, a silence detection circuit, a condition determining circuit, a direct current (DC) level bias circuit and an appending circuit. The audio device generates identification data, control signals, and original audio signals. The silence detection circuit detects silence segments of the original audio signals, and generates driving signals if the silence segments are detected. Then the condition determining circuit determines if the identification data needs to be appended into the silence segments according to the driving signals and the control signals, and outputs the identification data in DC signal form if the identification data needs to be appended into the silence segments. After DC voltage level of the identification data in DC signal form is biased, the appending circuit appends the biased identification data into the silence segments of the original audio signals.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="157.06mm" wi="133.27mm" file="US08626325-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="150.54mm" wi="138.94mm" file="US08626325-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="181.19mm" wi="136.23mm" file="US08626325-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="195.50mm" wi="180.51mm" file="US08626325-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="212.51mm" wi="134.20mm" file="US08626325-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="135.55mm" wi="160.10mm" file="US08626325-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="135.55mm" wi="154.60mm" file="US08626325-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="141.73mm" wi="153.25mm" file="US08626325-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="140.97mm" wi="172.38mm" file="US08626325-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The disclosure relates to audio devices, and particularly to an audio device capable of appending identification data into audio signals.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">With development and usage of multimedia technology and digital communication technology, multimedia works, such as, image works, audio works, and video works, need to be authenticated and protected to insure information security. When producing or generating audio works, for example, producing discs, original audio signals are output directly through a digital to analog converter. Thus, if the audio works are pirated, it is difficult to find out pirated headstream, which results in serious damage in business.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">An audio device includes an audio processing module, at least one processor, a storage unit, a silence detection circuit, a condition determining circuit, a direct current (DC) level bias circuit and an appending circuit. The audio processing module generates original audio signals. The at least one processor generates identification data and control signals according to an input of a user, wherein the identification data is appended into the original audio signals according to the control signals. The storage unit stores the identification data. The silence detection circuit detects silence segments of the original audio signals, and generates driving signals if at least one of the silence segments of the original audio signals is detected. The condition determining circuit determines if the identification data needs to be appended into the silence segments according to the driving signals and the control signals, and outputs the identification data in DC signal form if the identification data needs to be appended into the silence segments of the original audio signals. The DC level bias circuit biases DC voltage level of the identification data in DC signal form. The appending circuit appends the biased identification data into the silence segments of the original audio signals</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Other advantages and novel features will become more apparent from the following detailed description when taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic diagram of one embodiment of an audio device as disclosed.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic diagram of another embodiment of an audio device as disclosed.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a circuit diagram of one embodiment of an audio device as disclosed.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a flowchart of one embodiment of a method for appending identification data into audio signals as disclosed.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 to 8</figref> are schematic diagrams of simulation signal effect of an audio device.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic diagram of one embodiment of an audio device <b>10</b> as disclosed. In one embodiment, the audio device <b>10</b>, such as, a set top box, generates or records audio signals, and appends identification data into the audio signals to form an audio work. When the audio work appended with the identification data are pirated, the identification data can be picked to find out a pirated headstream. It should be understood that &#x201c;pirated headstream&#x201d; is defined to be an original audio work which is pirated from. The audio device <b>10</b> includes at least one processor <b>100</b>, an audio processing module <b>110</b>, a silence detection circuit <b>120</b>, a condition determining circuit <b>130</b>, a direct current (DC) level bias circuit <b>140</b>, an appending circuit <b>150</b>, and a storage unit <b>180</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The audio processing module <b>110</b> may comprise computerized code in the form of one or more programs that are stored in the storage unit <b>180</b> (or memory). The computerized code includes instructions that are executed by the at least one processor <b>100</b> to provide functions for the audio processing module <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The processor <b>100</b> generates identification data and control signals according to an input of a user. In one embodiment, the input of the user may be a selection if the audio device <b>10</b> needs to append the identification data into audio signals. The user may do the selection on a selection page by a mouse. The identification data is appended into audio signals according to the control signals. In one embodiment, the identification data includes digital right information, such as, a hardware serial number of the audio device <b>10</b>, which is convenient for finding out the pirated headstream. The identification data includes a header, digital right information, and a trailer. For example, if the identification data is &#x201c;10101010111101000010100101010101&#x201d;, thus, &#x201c;10101010&#x201d; is the header, &#x201c;1111010000101001&#x201d; is the digital right information, and &#x201c;01010101&#x201d; is the trailer. If the user selects that the audio device <b>10</b> needs to append the identification data into the audio signals, the processor <b>100</b> generates the control signals with high level. In one embodiment, the high level may be a voltage level greater than a predetermined value, such as, 3.3V, representing digital signals &#x201c;1&#x201d;. If the user selects that the audio device <b>10</b> needs not be append the identification data into the audio signals, the processor <b>100</b> generates the control signals with low level. In one embodiment, the low level may a voltage level nearly to be 0, representing digital signals &#x201c;0&#x201d;. The storage unit <b>180</b> stores the identification data. The audio processing module <b>110</b> generates original audio signals. In alternative embodiment, the storage unit <b>180</b> further stores the control signals and the original audio signals.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The silence detection circuit <b>120</b> is connected to the audio processing module <b>110</b>, and detects silence segments of the original audio signals and generates driving signals if at least one of the silence segments of the original audio signals is detected. In one embodiment, the silence detection circuit <b>120</b> detects the silence segments of the original audio signals according to voltage amplitude of the original audio signals. That is, the silence detection circuit <b>120</b> detects if an absolute value of the voltage amplitude of the original audio signals is less than a maximum value of the silence segments, such as, 166 mV, to determine the silence segments of the original audio signals. In one embodiment, the driving signals may be high level logic signals, representing digital signals &#x201c;1&#x201d;. In one embodiment, the high level of the driving signals may also be a voltage level greater than the predetermined value, such as, 3.3V</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The condition determining circuit <b>130</b> is connected to the silence detection circuit <b>120</b>, the processor <b>110</b> and the DC level bias circuit <b>140</b>, and determines if the identification data needs to be appended into the silence segments of the original audio signals according to the driving signals and the control signals. The condition determining circuit <b>130</b> further outputs the identification data in DC signals form if the identification data needs to be appended into the silence segments of the original audio signals. In one embodiment, the control signals may be high/low level logic signals to control the identification data to be appended into the original audio signals. For example, when the control signals are high level logic signals, such as, logic signals with a voltage level greater than 3.3V, the identification data needs to be appended into the original audio signals. At this time, if the condition determining circuit <b>130</b> also receives the driving signals, the condition determining circuit <b>130</b> determines that the identification data needs to be appended into the detected silence segments of the original audio signals. When the control signals are low level logic signals, such as, logic signal with a voltage level nearly to be 0V, the identification data needs not to be appended into the original audio signals.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The DC level bias circuit <b>140</b> biases DC voltage level of the identification data in DC signals form received from the condition determining circuit <b>130</b>. The appending circuit <b>150</b> receives the biased identification data and the original audio signals, and appends the biased identification data into the silence segments of the original audio signals.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic diagram of another embodiment of an audio device <b>20</b> as disclosed. The audio device <b>20</b> is similar to the audio device <b>10</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> except that the audio device <b>20</b> further includes a voltage follower <b>160</b> and the latter processing module <b>170</b>. The voltage follower <b>160</b> is connected between the audio processing module <b>110</b> and the silence detection circuit <b>120</b> and between the audio processing module <b>110</b> and the appending circuit <b>150</b>. The voltage follower <b>160</b> isolates the audio processing module <b>110</b> and the silence detection circuit <b>120</b>, isolates the audio processing module <b>110</b> and the appending circuit <b>150</b>, and buffers the original audio signals. Thus, signals generated by the silence detection circuit <b>120</b> and the appending circuit <b>150</b> do not feedback to the audio processing module <b>110</b>, which avoids influence on the original audio signals and insures quality of the original audio signals. The latter processing module <b>170</b> processes the audio signals appended with the identification data, such as, recording, and outputs the processed audio signals to other devices or display devices.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a circuit diagram of one embodiment of the audio devices <b>10</b> and <b>20</b>. In one embodiment, the silence detection circuit <b>120</b> includes a first comparator <b>1200</b>, a second comparator <b>1210</b>, and an AND gate <b>1220</b>. The first comparator <b>1200</b> includes a first inverting input terminal, a first non-inverting input terminal, and a first output terminal The first non-inverting input terminal receives the original audio signals from the audio processing module <b>110</b> or the voltage follower <b>160</b> via a first resistor R<b>1</b>. The first inverting input terminal receives a first reference voltage Vcc via a second resistor R<b>2</b>, and is connected to the ground via a third resistor R<b>3</b>. In one embodiment, the first reference voltage Vcc and resistance of the second resistor R<b>2</b> and the third resistor R<b>3</b> are related to the maximum value of the silence segments of the original audio signals. The first reference voltage Vcc is divided by the second resistor R<b>2</b> and the third resistor R<b>3</b>, and divided voltage on the third resistor R<b>3</b> is equal to the maximum value of the silence segments of the original audio signals. For example, the maximum value of the silence segments of the original audio signals is 166 mV, the first reference voltage Vcc is 3.3V, the resistance of the second resistor R<b>2</b> is 27K ohm, and the resistance of the third resistor R<b>3</b> is 1K ohm.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The second comparator <b>1210</b> includes a second inverting input terminal, a second non-inverting input terminal, and a second output terminal The second inverting input terminal receives the original audio signals from the audio processing module <b>110</b> or the voltage follower <b>160</b> via a fourth resistor R<b>4</b>. The second non-inverting input terminal receives a second reference voltage &#x2212;Vcc via a fifth resistor R<b>5</b>, and is connected to the ground via a sixth resistor R<b>6</b>. The second reference voltage &#x2212;Vcc and the first reference voltage Vcc have the same values and inverted phases. In one embodiment, the second reference voltage &#x2212;Vcc and resistance of the fifth resistor R<b>5</b> and the sixth resistor R<b>6</b> are related to the maximum value of the silence segments of the original audio signals. The second reference voltage &#x2212;Vcc is divided by the fifth resistor R<b>5</b> and the sixth resistor R<b>6</b>, and an absolute value of divided voltage on the sixth resistor R<b>6</b> is equal to the maximum value of the silence segments of the original audio signals.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The AND gate <b>1220</b> includes two input terminals and an output terminal One input terminal of the AND gate <b>1220</b> is connected to the first output terminal of the first comparator <b>1200</b> via a seventh resistor R<b>7</b>, and is connected to the ground via an eighth resistor R<b>8</b>. Another input terminal of the AND gate <b>1220</b> is connected to the second output terminal of the second comparator <b>1210</b> via a ninth resistor R<b>9</b>, and is connected to the ground via a tenth resistor R<b>10</b>. The output terminal of the AND gate <b>1220</b> outputs the driving signals. The seventh resistor R<b>7</b> and the eighth resistor R<b>8</b> bias voltage level of output signals of the first comparator <b>1200</b> into voltage level suitable for the AND gate <b>1220</b>, and the ninth resistor R<b>9</b> and the tenth resistor R<b>10</b> bias voltage level of output signals of the second comparator <b>1210</b> into voltage level suitable for the AND gate <b>1220</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The condition determining circuit <b>130</b> includes a first AND gate <b>1300</b> and a second AND gate <b>1310</b>. The first AND gate <b>1300</b> and the second AND gate <b>1310</b> respectively includes two input terminals and one output terminal. One input terminal of the first AND gate <b>1300</b> receives the control signals from the processor <b>100</b> or the storage unit <b>180</b>, and another input terminal of the first AND gate <b>1300</b> receives the driving signals from the silence detection circuit <b>120</b>. The first AND gate <b>1300</b> determines if the identification data needs to be appended into the silence segments of the original audio signals, and outputs the determination result via the output terminal to one input terminal of the second AND gate <b>1310</b>. In one embodiment, the determination result may be high or low level logic signals. Another input terminal of the second AND gate <b>1310</b> receives the identification data from the processor <b>100</b> or the storage unit <b>180</b> via an eleventh resistor R<b>11</b> and connected to the ground via a twelfth resistor R<b>12</b>, and the output terminal of the second AND gate <b>1310</b> outputs the identification date in DC signal form.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The DC level bias circuit <b>140</b> includes a thirteenth resistor R<b>13</b> and a fourteenth resistor R<b>14</b>. The thirteenth resistor R<b>13</b> has one end receiving the identification data in DC signal form and another end outputting the biased identification data. The fourteenth resistor R<b>14</b> has one end connected to the another end of the thirteenth resistor R<b>13</b> and another end connected to the ground.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The appending circuit <b>150</b> includes a difference amplifier <b>1500</b>, and the difference amplifier <b>1500</b> includes an inverting input terminal, a non-inverting input terminal, and an output terminal. The inverting input terminal of the difference amplifier <b>1500</b> receives the biased identification data from the DC level bias circuit <b>140</b> via a fifteenth resistor R<b>15</b>, and is connected to the ground via a sixteenth resistor R<b>16</b>. The non-inverting input terminal of the difference amplifier <b>1500</b> is connected to the output terminal of the difference amplifier <b>1500</b> via a seventeenth resistor R<b>17</b>, and receives the original audio signals from the audio processing module <b>110</b> or the voltage follower <b>160</b> via an eighteenth resistor R<b>18</b>. The output terminal of the difference amplifier <b>1500</b> outputs the audio signals appended with the identification data. In one embodiment, the difference amplifier <b>1500</b> has good noise suppressing performance, which can reduce noise and insure quality of the audio signals appended with the identification data.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In one embodiment, the original audio signals are input to the silence detection circuit <b>120</b> after generated by the audio processing module <b>110</b>. If the voltage amplitude of some segments of the original audio signals is greater than the maximum value of the silence segments, that is, these segments of the original audio signals are not the silence segments, voltage on the non-inverting input terminal of first comparator <b>1200</b> is greater than the voltage on the inverting input terminal of the first comparator <b>1200</b>, the first comparator <b>1200</b> outputs low level logic signals. Voltage on the inverting input terminal of the second comparator <b>1210</b> is greater than the voltage on the non-inverting input terminal of the second comparator <b>1210</b>, so the second comparator <b>1210</b> outputs high level logic signals. Thus, the AND gate <b>1220</b> outputs low level logic signals, and does not output driving signals.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">If the voltage amplitude of some segments of the original audio signals is negative and absolute value of the voltage amplitude of these segments of the original audio signals is greater than the maximum value of the silence segments, that is, these segments of the original audio signals are not the silence segments, voltage on the non-inverting input terminal of first comparator <b>1200</b> is less than the voltage on the inverting input terminal of the first comparator <b>1200</b>, the first comparator <b>1200</b> outputs high level logic signals. Voltage on the inverting input terminal of the second comparator <b>1210</b> is less than the voltage on the non-inverting input terminal of the second comparator <b>1210</b>, so the second comparator <b>1210</b> outputs low level logic signals. Thus, the AND gate <b>1220</b> outputs low level logic signals, and does not output driving signals.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">If the AND gate <b>1220</b> outputs low level logic signals, no matter what are the control signals, the first AND gate <b>1300</b> of the condition determining circuit <b>130</b> outputs low level logic signals. Thus, the identification data needs not be appended into these segments of the original audio signals.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">If the voltage amplitude of some segments of the original audio signals is negative and absolute value of the voltage amplitude of these segments of the original audio signals is less than the maximum value of the silence segments or the voltage amplitude of some segments of the original audio signals is less than the maximum value of the silence segments, that is, these segments of the original audio signals are the silence segments, voltage on the non-inverting input terminal of first comparator <b>1200</b> is less than the voltage on the inverting input terminal of the first comparator <b>1200</b>, the first comparator <b>1200</b> outputs high level logic signals. Voltage on the inverting input terminal of the second comparator <b>1210</b> is greater than the voltage on the non-inverting input terminal of the second comparator <b>1210</b>, so the second comparator <b>1210</b> outputs high level logic signals. Thus, the AND gate <b>1220</b> outputs high level logic signals, that is, the driving signals.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">When the silence detection circuit <b>120</b> outputs the driving signals and if the control signals represent that the identification data needs to be appended into the original audio signals, the first AND gate <b>1300</b> of the condition determining circuit <b>130</b> outputs high level logic signals, that is, a determination result that the identification data needs to be appended into the original audio signals. Thus, the second AND gate <b>1310</b> outputs the input identification data in DC signal form. Because DC voltage level of the identification data in DC signal form is different from that of the difference amplifier <b>1500</b> of the appending circuit <b>150</b>, the thirteenth resistor R<b>13</b> and the fourteenth resistor R<b>14</b> bias the DC voltage level. In one embodiment, resistance of the thirteenth resistor R<b>13</b> is 20K ohm, and resistance of the fourteenth resistor R<b>14</b> is 1 k ohm.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a flowchart of one embodiment of a method for appending identification data into audio signals as disclosed. In step S<b>400</b>, the audio processing module <b>110</b> generates original audio signals. In one embodiment, the voltage follower <b>160</b> first buffers the original audio signals to avoid signals generated by the silence detection circuit <b>120</b> and the appending circuit <b>150</b> influence the original audio signals. In step S<b>410</b>, the silence detection circuit <b>120</b> detects silence segments of the original audio signals, and generates driving signals if at least one of the silence segments of the original audio signals are detected. In one embodiment, the silence detection circuit <b>120</b> detects the silence segments according to voltage amplitude of the original audio signals. That is, the silence detection circuit <b>120</b> utilizes the first comparator <b>1200</b>, the second comparator <b>1210</b>, and the AND gate <b>1220</b> to detect if the voltage amplitude of the original audio signals is smaller the maximum value of the silence segments, such as 166 mv, to detect the silence segments of the original audio signals.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In step S<b>420</b>, the condition determining circuit <b>130</b> receives the driving signals from the silence detection circuit <b>120</b>, and receives the control signals and the identification data from the processor <b>100</b> or the storage unit <b>180</b>. In step S<b>430</b>, the condition determining circuit <b>130</b> determines if the identification data needs to be appended into the silence segments of the original audio signals according to the control signals and the driving signals. In one embodiment, the control signals may be high/low level logic signals to control if the identification data needs to be appended into the original audio signals. For example, when the control signals are high level logic signals, the identification data needs to be appended into the original audio signals. When the control signals are low level logic signals, the identification data needs not to be appended into the original audio signals. If the condition determining circuit <b>130</b> determines that the identification data needs not be appended into the silence segments of the original audio signals, the process returns to step S<b>410</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">If the condition determining circuit <b>130</b> determines that the identification data needs to be appended into the silence segments of the original audio signals, in step S<b>440</b>, the condition determining circuit <b>130</b> outputs the identification data in DC signal form. In one embodiment, steps S<b>430</b> and S<b>440</b> include that the silence detection circuit <b>120</b> and the processor <b>100</b> respectively input the driving signals and the control signals to two input terminals of the first AND gate <b>1300</b> of the condition determining circuit <b>130</b>, to determine if the identification data needs to be appended into the silence segments of the original audio signals. If the identification data needs to be appended into the silence segments of the original audio signals, the first AND gate <b>1300</b> output the determination result to one input terminal of the second AND gate <b>1310</b>, the processor <b>100</b> inputs the identification data to another input terminal of the second AND gate <b>1310</b>, and the second AND gate <b>1310</b> outputs the identification data in DC signal form from the output terminal of the second AND gate <b>1310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In step S<b>450</b>, the DC level bias circuit <b>140</b> biases the DC voltage level of the identification data in DC signal form. Because the DC voltage level of the identification data in DC signal form is different from that of the difference amplifier <b>1500</b> of the appending circuit <b>150</b>, the thirteenth resistor R<b>13</b> and the fourteenth resistor R<b>14</b> bias the DC voltage level.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In step S<b>460</b>, the appending circuit <b>150</b> appends the biased identification data into the silence segments of the original audio signals. In one embodiment, the DC level bias circuit <b>140</b> output the biased identification data to the inverting input terminal of the difference amplifier <b>1500</b>, the audio processing module <b>110</b> or the voltage follower <b>160</b> outputs the original audio signals to the non-inverting input terminal of the difference amplifier <b>1500</b>, and the difference amplifier <b>1500</b> appends the biased identification data into the silence segments of the original audio signals.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 to 8</figref> are schematic diagrams of simulation signal effect of the audio devices <b>10</b> and <b>20</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows the control signals, the identification data, the original audio signals, and output audio signal (that is, the audio signals appended with the identification data) at a long time, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 to 8</figref> are respectively one part of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. The control signals are high level logic signals and the original audio signals are in silence segments in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. The control signals are high level logic signals and the original audio signals are in non-silence segments in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>. The control signals are low level logic signals and the original audio signals are in silence segments is <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>. As show in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 to 8</figref>, the output audio signals appended with the identification data at the silence segments and the original audio signals are nearly superposed. That is, the audio devices <b>10</b> and <b>20</b> appending the identification data into the silence segments of the original audio signals have less influence on the original audio signals, which insures quality of the output audio signals appended with the identification data.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The audio devices <b>10</b> and <b>20</b> and the method for appending identification data into audio signals appends the identification data into the original audio signals. Thus, when the audio signals appended with the identification data are pirated, the identification data can be picked to find out pirated headstream, which insures safety and protection of the audio signals.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The foregoing disclosure of various embodiments has been presented for purposes of illustration and description. It is not intended to be exhaustive or to limit the invention to the precise forms disclosed. Many variations and modifications of the embodiments described herein will be apparent to one of ordinary skill in the art in light of the above disclosure. The scope of the invention is to be defined only by the claims appended hereto and their equivalents.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An audio device, comprising:
<claim-text>an audio processing module, to generate original audio signals;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one processor, to generate identification data and control signals according to an input of a user, wherein the identification data is appended into the original audio signals according to the control signals;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a storage unit, to store the identification data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a silence detection circuit, to detect silence segments of the original audio signals, and to generate driving signals if at least one of the silence segments of the original audio signals is detected;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a condition determining circuit, to determine if the identification data needs to be appended into the silence segments of the original audio signals according to the driving signals and the control signals, and to output the identification data in direct current (DC) signal form if the identification data needs to be appended into the silence segments of the original audio signals;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a DC level bias circuit, to bias DC voltage level of the identification data in DC signal form;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an appending circuit, to append the biased identification data into the silence segments of the original audio signals; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a voltage follower connected between the audio processing module and the silence detection circuit and between the audio processing module and the appending circuit, to isolate the audio processing module and the silence detection circuit, isolate the audio processing module and the appending circuit, and buffer the original audio signals.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The audio device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the identification data comprises digital right information.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The audio device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the silence detection circuit comprises:
<claim-text>a first comparator, comprising a first inverting input terminal, a first non-inverting input terminal, and a first output terminal, the first non-inverting input terminal receiving the original audio signals via a first resistor, the first inverting input terminal receiving a first reference voltage via a second resistor and connected to the ground via a third resistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second comparator, comprising a second inverting input terminal, a second non-inverting input terminal, and a second output terminal, the second inverting input terminal receiving the original audio signals via a fourth resistor, the second non-inverting input terminal receiving a second reference voltage via a fifth resistor and connected to the ground via a sixth resistor, wherein the second reference voltage and the first reference voltage have same voltage value and inverted phases; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an AND gate, comprising two input terminals and an output terminal, one input terminal of the AND gate connected to the first output terminal of the first comparator via a seventh resistor and connected to the ground via an eighth resistor, another input terminal of the AND gate connected to the second output terminal of the second comparator via a ninth resistor and connected to the ground via a tenth resistor, and the output terminal of the AND gate outputting the driving signals.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The audio device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the condition determining circuit comprises:
<claim-text>a first AND gate, to determine if the identification data needs to be appended into the silence segments of the original audio signals according to the driving signals and the control signals, comprising two input terminals and an output terminal, one input terminal of the first AND gate receiving the control signals, and another input terminal of the first AND gate receiving the driving signals from the silence detection circuit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second AND gate, comprising two input terminals and an output terminals, one input terminal of the second AND gate connected to the output terminal of the first AND gate, another input terminal of the second AND gate receiving the identification data via an first resistor and connected to the ground via a second resistor, and the output terminal of the second AND gate outputting the identification data in DC signal form.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The audio device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the DC level bias circuit comprises:
<claim-text>a first resistor with one end receiving the identification data in DC signal form and another end outputting the biased identification data; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second resistor with one end connected to the another end of the first resistor and another end grounded.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The audio device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the appending circuit comprises a difference amplifier comprising an inverting input terminal, a non-inverting input terminal, and an output terminal, the inverting input terminal of the difference amplifier receiving the biased identification data via a first resistor and connected to the ground via a second resistor, the non-inverting input terminal of the difference amplifier connected to the output terminal of the difference amplifier via a third resistor and receiving the original audio signals via an fourth resistor, and the output terminal of the difference amplifier outputting audio signals appended with the identification data.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A method for appending identification data into audio signals, comprising:
<claim-text>generating original audio signals;</claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting silence segments of the original audio signals, and generating driving signals if at least one of the silence segments of the original audio signals is detected;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving control signals and identification data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>respectively inputting the driving signals and the control signals to two input terminals of a first AND gate, to determine if the identification data needs to be appended into the silence segments of the original audio signals;</claim-text>
<claim-text>outputting a determination result from an output terminal of the first AND gate to one input terminal of a second AND gate, inputting the identification data to another input terminal of the second AND gate, and outputting the identification data in DC signal form from an output terminal of the second AND gate if the identification data needs to be appended into the silence segments of the original audio signals;</claim-text>
<claim-text>biasing DC voltage level of the identification data in DC signal form; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>appending the biased identification data into the silence segments of the original audio signals.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method for appending identification data into audio signals of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, further comprising: buffering the original audio signals. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
