<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622763-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622763</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13517617</doc-number>
<date>20120614</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>23</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>62</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439328</main-classification>
<further-classification>439160</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Card edge connector</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6200149</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Chi-Chung</name>
<date>20010300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439160</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7121862</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Tang et al.</name>
<date>20061000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439327</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0167558</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Guan et al.</name>
<date>20100700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439 65</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0034055</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yao et al.</name>
<date>20110200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439329</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0104926</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Li et al.</name>
<date>20110500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>8</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439327</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439328</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439567</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439160</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120322286</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121220</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Fu</last-name>
<first-name>Xiao-Zhi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kunshan</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yao</last-name>
<first-name>Ze-Lin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kunshan</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bu</last-name>
<first-name>Xue-Wu</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kunshan</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Fu</last-name>
<first-name>Xiao-Zhi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kunshan</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yao</last-name>
<first-name>Ze-Lin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kunshan</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bu</last-name>
<first-name>Xue-Wu</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kunshan</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chung</last-name>
<first-name>Wei Te</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chang</last-name>
<first-name>Ming Chieh</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Vu</last-name>
<first-name>Hien</first-name>
<department>2833</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A card edge connector (<b>100</b>) includes an insulative housing (<b>1</b>) and a latch retained at one end of the insulative housing (<b>1</b>). The insulative housing (<b>1</b>) includes a mounting slot (<b>16</b>). The latch (<b>3</b>) has a resilience extending portion (<b>311</b>) retained in the mounting slot (<b>16</b>) upwardly. The mounting slot (<b>16</b>) defines a pressing face (<b>112</b>) latching with the extending portion (<b>311</b>) for preventing the extending portion (<b>311</b>) from moving downwardly, thereby the latch (<b>3</b>) could be stably retained on the housing.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="152.32mm" wi="387.77mm" file="US08622763-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="197.61mm" wi="130.81mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622763-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="195.41mm" wi="168.49mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622763-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="201.08mm" wi="142.75mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622763-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="196.17mm" wi="119.38mm" file="US08622763-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention generally relates to a card edge connector and more particularly to a card edge connector with a latch assembled therein.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">U.S. patent application Ser. No. 20110104926 discloses a card edge connector including an iusultive housing, a plurality of contacts retained in the insulative housing and a latch assembled in one side of the insulative housing. The insulative housing includes two opposite side walls, an inserting slot and two end walls located between the two side walls. The end wall includes a mounting slot pass therethrough along an up-to-down direction, a first limiting wall and a second limiting wall located on the outside of the mounting slot and a guiding slot formed between the first and second limiting wall. The second limiting wall has a limiting slot passing therethrough downwardly. The latch includes a base and an inserting portion extending into the mounting slot from the base. The inserting portion includes a vertical plating portion, a connecting portion extending outside from a middle of the plating portion and a limiting portion extending outside from the connecting portion. The plating portion is assembled into the mounting slot along a down-to-up direction, the connecting portion is assembled into the guiding slot along the down-to-up direction. The limiting portion is located in the limiting slot to prevent the latch from moving upwardly. But the latch could be easily move downwardly by the outside force.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Other objects, advantages and novel features of the present invention will become more apparent from the following detailed description of the present embodiment when taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The present invention provides a cable connector comprises an insulative housing extending along a left-to-right direction, a plurality of contacts retained in the insulative housing and a latch assembled on one side of the insulative housing. the insulative has a pair of opposite two side walls, inserting face, a mounting face, an inserting slot formed between two side walls and two end walls located in two sides of the inserting slot, one of the end wall having a mounting slot. The latch has a base, a inserting portion extending from the base. The inserting portion having a extending portion extending into the mounting slot upwardly, the mounting slot having at least one pressing face abutting against the extending portion to prevent the extending portion from moving downwardly</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Other objects, advantages and novel features of the present invention will become more apparent from the following detailed description of the present embodiment when taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an assembled perspective view of a card edge connector according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exploded, perspective view of the card edge connector as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is another exploded perspective view of the card edge connector as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the card edge connector taken along line <b>4</b>-<b>4</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Reference will now be made to the drawing figures to describe the preferred embodiment of the present invention in detail.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a card edge connector <b>100</b> includes an insulative housing <b>1</b>, a plurality of contacts <b>2</b> retained in the insulative housing <b>1</b> and a latch <b>3</b> retained in the insulative housing <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-4</figref>, the insulative housing <b>1</b> includes a pair of opposite side walls <b>11</b>, a middle inserting slot <b>12</b> formed between two side walls <b>11</b>, a plurality of terminal slots <b>13</b> depressing from each of the two side walls <b>11</b> and communicating with the inserting slot <b>12</b> and two end walls <b>15</b> located in the two ends of the inserting slot <b>12</b>. The length direction of the insulative housing <b>1</b> is defined as a left-to-right direction and a direction which is vertical with the two side walls <b>11</b> is defined as a front-to-rear direction. The insulative housing <b>1</b> includes an inserting face <b>101</b> mating with a daughter printed circuit board and a mounting face <b>102</b> mounting on a mother printed circuit board.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The end wall <b>15</b> includes a mounting slot <b>16</b> passing through the inserting face <b>101</b> and the mounting face <b>102</b>, two positioning blocks <b>161</b> located in the front and rear inner sides of a top of the mounting slot <b>16</b>, a first limiting wall <b>17</b> and a second limiting wall <b>18</b> located outside of the mounting slot <b>16</b> and separated from each other by a guiding slot <b>160</b> formed between the first and second limiting walls <b>17</b>, <b>18</b>. Along the left-to-right direction, two positioning blocks <b>161</b> is located on an inner side of the first and second limiting walls <b>17</b>, <b>18</b>. Two recesses <b>111</b> are defined on the end wall <b>15</b> and extend downwardly from the inserting face <b>101</b> but not passing downwardly through the side walls <b>11</b>. Along the front-to-rear direction, two positioning blocks <b>161</b> are located between the two recesses <b>111</b>, and a bottom of the recess <b>111</b> is below the positioning blocks <b>161</b>. Bottoms of the recesses <b>111</b> are formed with two pressing faces <b>112</b> which are parallel with the inserting face <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The positioning block <b>161</b> is stagger with the pressing face <b>112</b> along a height and width direction. The position block <b>161</b> is located above the pressing face <b>112</b>, the pressing faces <b>112</b> are located on two sides of the positioning blocks <b>161</b> along a front-to-rear direction. The recess <b>111</b> is communicated with the mounting slot <b>16</b>, and a cross section of a space which is formed by the mounting slot <b>16</b> and the guiding slot <b>160</b> is like a T-sharp. The first and second limiting walls <b>17</b>, <b>18</b> and the guiding slot <b>160</b> surround the mounting slot <b>16</b> and abreast along a front-to-back direction. A top of the first limiting wall <b>17</b> extends to the inserting face <b>101</b> and a bottom of the first limiting wall <b>17</b> extends to the mounting face <b>102</b>. A top of the second limiting wall <b>18</b> extends to the inserting face <b>101</b> and a bottom of the second limiting wall <b>18</b> is located above the mounting face <b>102</b>. So that the height of the second limiting wall <b>18</b> is shorter than that of the first limiting wall <b>17</b>. The bottom of the second limiting wall <b>18</b> includes a limiting slot <b>180</b> which is communicated with the guiding slot <b>160</b> along a front-to-back direction.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-3</figref>, the contacts <b>2</b> are mounted in the terminal slots <b>13</b>. Each of the contacts <b>2</b> includes a retaining portion <b>20</b> retained in the terminal slot <b>13</b>, a contacting portion <b>21</b> extending into the inserting slot <b>12</b> upwardly from one end of the retaining portion <b>20</b> for contacting with the daughter printed circuit board and a soldering portion <b>24</b> extending downwardly from another end of the retaining portion <b>20</b> for soldering to the mother printed circuit board.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The latch <b>3</b> includes a base <b>30</b>, an inserting portion <b>31</b> extending inwardly into the mounting slot <b>16</b> from the base <b>30</b> and an elastic arm <b>32</b> extending outwardly from the base <b>30</b> for retaining the daughter printed circuit board. The inserting portion <b>31</b> includes a planar portion <b>310</b>, an extending portion <b>311</b> extending upwardly from the planar portion <b>310</b>, a connecting portion <b>312</b> extending outwardly and vertically from a middle of the planar portion <b>310</b> and extending along a top to bottom direction and a limiting portion <b>313</b> extending outside from a bottom part of the connecting portion <b>312</b> and located outside of the planar portion <b>310</b>. The extending portion <b>311</b> includes a first retaining tail <b>3111</b> and a second retaining tail <b>3112</b> separated from each other, a pressing slot <b>3113</b> located between the first and second retaining tails <b>3111</b>, <b>3112</b>, and two latching portions <b>3114</b> from tops of the first and second retaining tails <b>3111</b>, <b>3112</b>. The latching portion <b>3114</b> includes a guiding face <b>3115</b> to guide the extending portion <b>3111</b> inserting into the mounting slot <b>16</b>. The first and second retaining tails <b>3111</b>, <b>3112</b> can move close to each other. The first and second retaining portions <b>3111</b>, <b>3112</b> are pressed to defect toward each other and then inserted in to the mounting slot <b>16</b> along a bottom to up direction. When the first and second retaining tails <b>3111</b>, <b>3112</b> move beyond the pressing faces <b>112</b> and elastic recovery, the latching portions <b>3114</b> insert into the recesses <b>111</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The latching portion <b>3114</b> has a gap with the recesses <b>111</b> along a front-to-back direction. The pressing faces <b>112</b> are located under the latching portions <b>3114</b> to prevent the latch <b>3</b> from moving downwardly. The first and second retaining tails <b>3111</b>, <b>3112</b> are retained in the mounting slot <b>16</b>, the positioning blocks <b>16</b> is located above the extending portions <b>311</b> to prevent the extending portions <b>311</b> from moving upwardly. The limiting portions <b>313</b> abuts against the second limiting walls <b>18</b> to prevent the latch <b>3</b> from moving upwardly further. Thus, the latch <b>3</b> is retained in a right location of the insulative housing <b>1</b>. The elastic arm <b>32</b> includes a convex or locking lug <b>33</b> located in an outside thereof. The convex <b>33</b> could insert into a notch of the daughter printed circuit board to lock the daughter printed circuit board.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The card edge connector <b>100</b> includes a positioning block <b>161</b> extending into the mounting slot <b>16</b>. The latch <b>3</b> includes two extending portions <b>311</b> which latch with the mounting slot <b>16</b> to retain the latch <b>3</b>. The positioning blocks <b>161</b> and pressing faces <b>112</b> of the recess <b>111</b> prevent the extending portions <b>311</b> from moving upwardly or downwardly, respectively. Thereby the latch <b>3</b> could be stably retained on the insulative housing <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">It is to be understood, however, that even though numerous characteristics and advantages of the present invention have been set forth in the foregoing description, together with details of the structure and function of the invention, the disclosure is illustrative only, and changes may be made in detail, especially in matters of shape, size, and arrangement of parts within the principles of the invention to the full extent indicated by the broad general meaning of the terms in which the appended claims are expressed.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A card edge connector comprising:
<claim-text>an insulative housing extending along a left-to-right direction and having two opposite side walls, an inserting face, a mounting face, an inserting slot formed between the two side walls and two end walls located in two opposite ends of the inserting slot, one end wall having a mounting slot;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of contacts retained in the insulative housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a latch assembled to the insulative housing from a bottom to a top of the mounting slot, the latch having a base, an inserting portion extending inwardly from the base and an elastic arm extending outwardly from the base, the inserting portion having an extending portion inserted into the mounting slot upwardly, the end wall having a pressing face latching with the extending portion to prevent the latch from moving downwardly;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the mounting slot has at least one positioning block on a top thereof, the positioning block is located over the extending portion to prevent the latch from moving upwardly;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the positioning block is stagger with the pressing face along a height and width direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the inserting portion has a planar portion connecting with a bottom of the extending portion, the extending portion has a pair of first and second separated retaining tails extending upwardly from the planar portion and two latching portions extending outwardly from tops of the first and second retaining tails, respectively,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the latching portion has a guiding face guiding the extending portion inserting into the mounting slot; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the one end wall has a recess depressing downwardly from the inserting face but not downwardly passing therethrough, the recess communicates with the mounting slot and is located closed to the positioning block, the pressing face is located in a bottom of the recess.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The card edge connector as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the latching portion has a gap with the recess along a front-to-back direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The card edge connector as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the end wall has a first limiting wall, a second limiting wall and a guiding slot formed between the first and second limiting walls and communicating with the mounting slot, a cross section of a space which is formed by the mounting slot and the guiding slot is like a T-sharp.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The card edge connector as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the first limiting wall extends upwardly to the inserting face and extending downwardly to the mounting face, the second limiting wall extends upwardly to the inserting face, a bottom of the second limiting wall is located above the mounting face, the inserting portion includes a limiting portion abutting against the second limiting portion upwardly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A card edge connector comprising:
<claim-text>an insulative housing having an inserting slot for receiving a daughter board and a mounting slot located on one end of the inserting slot, the mounting slot having two positioning blocks at a top thereof and two pressing faces below the positioning block;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of contacts retained in the insulative housing, the contact includes a contacting portion extending into the inserting slot and a soldering portion extending out of the insulative housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a latch having an inserting portion inserted into the mounting slot along a bottom to upper direction, the inserting portion having an extending portion, and at least a part of the inserting portion located between the positioning block and pressing face to prevent the extending portion from moving upwardly or downwardly;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the positioning block is stagger with the pressing face along a height and width direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the inserting portion has a planar portion connecting with a bottom of the extending portion, the extending portion has a pair of first and second separated retaining tails extending upwardly from the planar portion and two latching portions extending outwardly from tops of the first and second retaining tails, respectively; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the latching portion has a guiding face guiding the extending portion inserting into the mounting slot.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A card edge connector for use with a module, comprising:
<claim-text>an insulative housing defining an elongated receiving slot along a lengthwise direction for receiving said module;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of contacts disposed in the housing with contacting sections extending into the receiving slot;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mounting slot formed at one end of the housing in the lengthwise direction, said mounting slot communicating with an exterior outwardly in the lengthwise direction and downwardly in a vertical direction perpendicular to said lengthwise direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a latch discrete from the housing and assembled to the housing, said latch defining a base, an elastic arm extending outwardly essentially along the lengthwise direction with thereon a locking lug for locking into a notch of said module, an inserting portion extending from the base and received in the mounting slot, a latching portion formed on the inserting portion to latch to the housing for preventing downward movement of the latch;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the inserting portion and the associated latch are hidden in the housing for providing a good-looking appearance of the whole connector;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein housing provides an at least partially upward pressing face to engage the latching portion thereto;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the housing and the latch uses different material under condition that that of the latch is softer than that of the housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the housing further provides a downward pressing face to engage the latch for preventing upward movement of the latch; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said upward pressing face is located around an upper region of the housing while the downward pressing face is located around a lower region of the housing.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The card edge connector as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein said upward pressing face upwardly communicates with an exterior for injection molding consideration of the housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The card edge connector as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the housing provides a positioning block to hide the inserting portion thereunder while upwardly exposing the latching portion for injection molding consideration of the housing. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
