<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08621960-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08621960</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13316638</doc-number>
<date>20111212</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>203</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>37</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 74665A</main-classification>
<further-classification> 74665 GA</further-classification>
<further-classification>29734413</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Single motor power seat</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3241384</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Grimm</name>
<date>19660300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 74353</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3564935</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Vigneri</name>
<date>19710200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 74354</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4299316</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Reinmoeller</name>
<date>19811100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>192 488</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4470318</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Cremer et al.</name>
<date>19840900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4932290</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Toyoda et al.</name>
<date>19900600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5088841</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Ikegaya et al.</name>
<date>19920200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2973441</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5163734</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hakansson</name>
<date>19921100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5292164</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Rees</name>
<date>19940300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>296 6515</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5303881</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Aronne</name>
<date>19940400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>244122 R</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5427345</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Yamakami et al.</name>
<date>19950600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5882075</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Partington et al.</name>
<date>19990300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6126132</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Maue</name>
<date>20001000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6626064</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Maue et al.</name>
<date>20030900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>21</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 74665 A</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 74665 B</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 74665 GA</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>29734413</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>61426108</doc-number>
<date>20101222</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120160056</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120628</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wrong</last-name>
<first-name>David J</first-name>
<address>
<city>Newmarket</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CA</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wrong</last-name>
<first-name>David J</first-name>
<address>
<city>Newmarket</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Miller Canfield</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Magna Seating Inc</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Aurora, Ontario</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Ho</last-name>
<first-name>Ha D</first-name>
<department>3658</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A multi-output transmission assembly includes first and second gears rotatable in opposite directions, an output shaft, first and second collars slidably coupled to the output shaft, and an actuator coupled to the first and second collars. The first collar is rotated by the first gear in a first direction. The second collar is rotated by the second gear in a second direction. The actuator moves the first and second collars along the output shaft. With the actuator in a neutral position, the first and second collars are disengaged from the output shaft and the output shaft does not rotate. With the actuator in a first position, the first collar engages the output shaft and the output shaft rotates in the first direction. With the actuator in a second position, the second collar engages the output shaft and the output shaft rotates in the second direction.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="156.46mm" wi="249.17mm" file="US08621960-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="249.26mm" wi="165.35mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621960-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="210.82mm" wi="176.87mm" file="US08621960-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="210.23mm" wi="174.33mm" file="US08621960-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="205.74mm" wi="156.97mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621960-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="242.23mm" wi="151.21mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621960-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="240.28mm" wi="150.62mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621960-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="236.47mm" wi="149.94mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621960-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="224.96mm" wi="141.65mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08621960-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The invention relates to a motor vehicle seat assembly, and more particularly to a power seat adjuster including a single motor and a multi-output transmission assembly to provide the desired adjustability of the seat assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Motor vehicles include seat assemblies having a seat cushion and a seat back for supporting occupants within the vehicle. Most front row seat assemblies, such as driver and passenger seat assemblies, are adjustably mounted on a floor of the vehicle. It is common that such seat assemblies include power seat adjusters for adjusting the position of the seat assembly relative to the vehicle floor. A typical power seat adjuster can be operated to adjust the seat assembly in a generally horizontal or fore/aft direction and a generally vertical or up/down direction.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The generally horizontal or fore/aft direction of the seat assembly corresponds to a longitudinal axis of the vehicle. Movement of the seat assembly along the longitudinal axis moves the seat assembly closer to or farther away from the vehicle steering wheel and/or instrument panel. To allow fore and aft adjustment, the seat assembly typically includes a seat track mechanism having an upper track slidably coupled with a lower track. The upper track is attached to an underside of the seat cushion and the lower track is attached to the vehicle floor. A threaded lead screw is driven by a first electric motor and a nut translating along the lead screw is connected to and moves the upper track relative to the lower track, thereby moving the seat assembly in the fore/aft direction.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">For the generally vertical or up/down direction of the seat assembly, front and rear portions of the seat cushion are typically controlled separately. A first gear mechanism is disposed between the upper track and the front portion of the seat cushion and a second gear mechanism is disposed between the upper track and the rear portion of the seat cushion. The first gear mechanism is actuated by a second electric motor to allow up and down adjustment of the front portion of the seat cushion. Similarly, the second gear mechanism is actuated by a third electric motor to allow up and down adjustment of the rear portion of the seat cushion. Thus, simultaneous actuation of the second and third electric motors moves the entire seat cushion in the up/down direction.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The power seat adjuster can also be configured to pivot or recline the seat back relative to the seat cushion. A recliner mechanism is disposed between the seat back and the seat cushion. The recliner mechanism is actuated by a fourth electric motor to allow pivotal movement of the seat back.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">As described above, conventional power seat adjusters can include four or more electric motors for providing adjustment of the seat assembly. While the use of multiple electric motors is effective in adjusting the position of the seat assembly, the cost of the electric motors is relatively expensive and increases the weight and complexity of the seat assembly. It is therefore desirable to provide an improved power seat adjuster using a single motor to provide the desired adjustability of the seat assembly.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to one aspect of the invention, a multi-output transmission assembly for a power seat adjuster includes an input shaft that actuates a first gear set and a second gear set. A first output shaft includes a first male spline lock, a second male spline lock, and a third male spline lock disposed laterally between the first and second male spline locks. A first collar is slidably coupled to the first output shaft and is rotated by the first gear set in a first rotational direction. The first collar includes a first female spline lock for selectively engaging the first male spline lock on the first output shaft. A second collar is slidably coupled to the first output shaft and is rotated by the second gear set in a second rotational direction, opposite the first rotational direction. The second collar includes a second female spline lock for selectively engaging the second male spline lock on the first output shaft. A first actuator is adapted for selectively engaging the third male spline lock on the first output shaft. The first actuator is coupled to the first and second collars and moves the first and second collars laterally along the first output shaft. With the first actuator in a neutral position, the first actuator engages the third male spline lock to prevent rotation of the first output shaft. With the first actuator in a first position, the first female spline lock on the first collar engages the first male spline lock to rotate the first output shaft in the first rotational direction in response to actuation of the first gear set. With the first actuator in a second position, the second female spline lock on the second collar engages the second male spline lock to rotate the first output shaft in the second rotational direction in response to actuation of the second gear set. The assembly may also include second, third, and fourth output shafts driven in the first and second rotational directions by the first and second gear sets.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to another aspect of the invention, a multi-output transmission assembly is provided for a power seat adjuster. The transmission assembly includes a first input gear that is selectively rotatable in a first rotational direction and a second input gear that is selectively rotatable in a second rotational direction, opposite the first rotational direction. An output shaft includes a first male spline lock and a second male spline lock that are laterally spaced apart. A first collar is slidably coupled to the output shaft and is rotated by the first input gear in the first rotational direction. The first collar includes a first female spline lock for selectively engaging the first male spline lock on the output shaft. A second collar is slidably coupled to the output shaft and is rotated by the second input gear in the second rotational direction. The second collar includes a second female spline lock for selectively engaging the second male spline lock on the output shaft. An actuator is adapted for selectively engaging the second male spline lock on the output shaft. The actuator is coupled to the first and second collars and moves the first and second collars laterally along the output shaft. With the actuator in a neutral position, the actuator engages the second male spline lock to prevent rotation of the output shaft. With the actuator in a first position, the first female spline lock on the first collar engages the first male spline lock to rotate the output shaft in the first rotational direction in response to rotation of the first input gear in the first rotational direction. With the actuator in a second position, the second female spline lock on the second collar engages the second male spline lock to rotate the output shaft in the second rotational direction in response to rotation of the second input gear in the second rotational direction.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Advantages of the present invention will be readily appreciated as the same becomes better understood by reference to the following detailed description when considered in connection with the accompanying drawings wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a multi-output transmission assembly for a power seat adjuster according to a first embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a first, fragmentary, perspective view of the multi-output transmission assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a second, fragmentary, perspective view of the multi-output transmission assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a fragmentary, perspective view of a multi-output transmission assembly for a power seat adjuster according to a second embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> is a cross-section view of the multi-output transmission assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> with an actuator in a neutral position;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref> is a cross-section view of the multi-output transmission assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> with the actuator in a first position;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</figref> is a cross-section view of the multi-output transmission assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> with the actuator in a second position; and</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is an enlarged view of the cross-section shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 3</figref>, a power seat adjuster <b>10</b> for a motor vehicle seat assembly includes a single motor (not shown) that is coupled to a multi-output transmission assembly <b>11</b>. The power seat adjuster <b>10</b> is adapted for providing the desired adjustability of the seat assembly. The transmission assembly <b>11</b> includes a housing (not shown) and an input shaft <b>12</b> driven by the motor. First and second drive gears <b>14</b>, <b>16</b> are mounted on the input shaft <b>12</b> for rotation therewith. The first drive gear <b>14</b> actuates or drives a first gear set <b>18</b>. The first gear set <b>18</b> is comprised of a plurality of gears <b>18</b>.<b>1</b>, <b>18</b>.<b>2</b>, <b>18</b>.<b>3</b>, <b>18</b>.<b>4</b>, <b>18</b>.<b>5</b>, <b>18</b>.<b>6</b>, <b>18</b>.<b>7</b> and a first ring gear <b>18</b>.<b>8</b>. More specifically, the first drive gear <b>14</b> meshingly engages a first gear <b>18</b>.<b>1</b>; a step down portion <b>19</b>.<b>1</b> of the first gear <b>18</b>.<b>1</b> meshingly engages a second gear <b>18</b>.<b>2</b>; a step down portion (not shown) of the second gear <b>18</b>.<b>2</b> meshingly engages a third gear <b>18</b>.<b>3</b>; a step down portion (not shown) of the third gear <b>18</b>.<b>3</b> meshingly engages the first ring gear <b>18</b>.<b>8</b>; the first ring gear <b>18</b>.<b>8</b> meshingly engages fourth and fifth gears <b>18</b>.<b>4</b>, <b>18</b>.<b>5</b>; step down portions (not shown) of the fourth and fifth gears <b>18</b>.<b>4</b>, <b>18</b>.<b>5</b> meshingly engage a sixth gear <b>18</b>.<b>6</b>; and a step down portion <b>19</b>.<b>6</b> of the sixth gear meshingly engages a seventh gear <b>18</b>.<b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The second drive gear <b>16</b> actuates or drives a second gear set <b>22</b>. The second gear set <b>22</b> is comprised of a plurality of gears <b>22</b>.<b>1</b>, <b>22</b>.<b>2</b>, <b>22</b>.<b>3</b>, <b>22</b>.<b>4</b>, <b>22</b>.<b>5</b>, <b>22</b>.<b>6</b>, <b>22</b>.<b>7</b> and a second ring gear <b>22</b>.<b>8</b>. More specifically, the second drive gear <b>16</b> meshingly engages a reverse idler gear <b>20</b>, which in turn meshingly engages an eighth gear <b>22</b>.<b>1</b>; a step down portion <b>23</b>.<b>1</b> of the eighth gear <b>22</b>.<b>1</b> meshingly engages a ninth gear; <b>22</b>.<b>2</b>; a step down portion <b>23</b>.<b>2</b> of the ninth gear <b>22</b>.<b>2</b> meshingly engages a tenth gear <b>22</b>.<b>3</b>; a step down portion <b>23</b>.<b>3</b> of the tenth gear <b>22</b>.<b>3</b> meshingly engages the second ring gear <b>22</b>.<b>8</b>; the second ring gear <b>22</b>.<b>8</b> meshingly engages eleventh and twelfth gears <b>22</b>.<b>4</b>, <b>22</b>.<b>5</b>; step down portions <b>23</b>.<b>4</b>, <b>23</b>.<b>5</b> of the eleventh and twelfth gears <b>22</b>.<b>4</b>, <b>22</b>.<b>5</b> meshingly engage a thirteenth gear <b>22</b>.<b>6</b>; and a step down portion (not shown) of the thirteenth gear <b>22</b>.<b>6</b> meshingly engages a fourteenth gear <b>22</b>.<b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The transmission assembly <b>11</b> also includes four output shafts, namely, a first output shaft <b>24</b>, a second output shaft <b>26</b>, a third output shaft <b>28</b>, and a fourth output shaft <b>30</b>. The first gear set <b>18</b> selectively drives each output shaft <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>, <b>28</b>, <b>30</b> in a first rotational direction, for example, counterclockwise when viewed from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The second gear set <b>22</b> selectively drives each output shaft <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>, <b>28</b>, <b>30</b> in a second rotational direction, for example, clockwise when viewed from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. Each output shaft <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>, <b>28</b>, <b>30</b> includes an inner shaft portion <b>32</b> extending through and fixed to an outer shaft portion <b>34</b>. The inner shaft portion <b>32</b> of each one of the first, second, third, and fourth output shafts <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>, <b>28</b>, <b>30</b> is operatively coupled to an adjustment device for moving a portion of the seat assembly. For example, the inner shaft portion <b>32</b> of the first output shaft <b>24</b> is operatively coupled to a pair of seat track drives (not shown) for moving the seat assembly fore and aft. The inner shaft portion <b>32</b> of the second output shaft <b>26</b> is operatively coupled to a front lift drive (not shown) for lifting or ing a front end of a seat cushion. The inner shaft portion <b>32</b> of the third output shaft <b>28</b> is operatively coupled to a rear lift drive (not shown) for lifting a rear end of the seat cushion. The inner shaft portion <b>32</b> of the fourth output shaft <b>30</b> is operatively coupled to a recliner drive (not shown) for pivoting a seat back relative to the seat cushion.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the outer shaft portion <b>34</b> of each output shaft <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>, <b>28</b>, <b>30</b> includes three male spline locks that are laterally spaced apart, namely, a first male spline lock <b>35</b>.<b>1</b>, a second male spline lock <b>35</b>.<b>2</b>, and a third male spline lock <b>35</b>.<b>3</b>. The third male spline lock <b>35</b>.<b>3</b> is disposed laterally between the first and second male spline locks <b>35</b>.<b>1</b>, <b>35</b>.<b>2</b>. First and second collars <b>36</b>, <b>38</b> are slidably mounted on the outer shaft portion <b>34</b> of each output shaft <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>, <b>28</b>, <b>30</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>. The first gear <b>18</b>.<b>1</b> includes a shoulder <b>39</b>.<b>1</b> that is internally splined. The first collar <b>36</b> is externally splined and is engaged with the internal splines of the shoulder <b>39</b>.<b>1</b> of the first gear <b>18</b>.<b>1</b> to rotate therewith. The first collar <b>36</b> also includes a first female spline lock (not shown) that is adapted for selectively engaging with the first male spline lock <b>35</b>.<b>1</b> on the outer shaft portion <b>34</b> of the first output shaft <b>24</b>. Similarly, the eighth gear <b>22</b>.<b>1</b> includes a shoulder <b>40</b>.<b>1</b> that is internally splined. The second collar <b>38</b> is externally splined and is engaged with the internal splines of the shoulder <b>40</b>.<b>1</b> of the eighth gear <b>22</b>.<b>1</b> to rotate therewith. The second collar <b>38</b> also includes a second female spline lock (not shown) that is adapted for selectively engaging with the second male spline lock <b>35</b>.<b>2</b> on the outer shaft portion <b>34</b> of the first output shaft <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Each of the second, third, and fourth output shafts <b>26</b>, <b>28</b>, <b>30</b> include similar arrangements. More specifically, the fourth gear <b>18</b>.<b>4</b> includes a shoulder <b>39</b>.<b>4</b> that is internally splined and is engaged with the external splines of the first collar <b>36</b> on the second output shaft <b>26</b>. Likewise, the eleventh gear <b>22</b>.<b>4</b> includes a shoulder <b>40</b>.<b>4</b> that is internally splined and is engaged with the external splines of the second collar <b>38</b> on the second output shaft <b>26</b>. The fifth gear <b>18</b>.<b>5</b> includes a shoulder <b>39</b>.<b>5</b> that is internally splined and is engaged with the external splines of the first collar <b>36</b> on the third output shaft <b>28</b>. Likewise, the twelfth gear <b>22</b>.<b>5</b> includes a shoulder (not shown) that is internally splined and is engaged with the external splines of the second collar (not shown) on the third output shaft <b>28</b>. Finally, the seventh gear <b>18</b>.<b>7</b> includes a shoulder <b>39</b>.<b>7</b> that is internally splined and is engaged with the external splines of the first collar <b>36</b> on the fourth output shaft <b>30</b>. Likewise, the fourteenth gear <b>22</b>.<b>7</b> includes a shoulder (not shown) that is internally splined and is engaged with the external splines of the second collar (not shown) on the fourth output shaft <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">An actuator <b>41</b> with an actuation pin <b>42</b> is disposed along each one of the output shafts <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>, <b>28</b>, <b>30</b> generally between the first and second collars <b>36</b>, <b>38</b>. The actuators <b>40</b> are prevented from rotating by the housing of the transmission assembly <b>11</b>. Referring to the actuator <b>41</b> on the first output shaft <b>24</b>, the actuator <b>41</b> is coupled to each of the first and second collars <b>36</b>, <b>38</b> for slidably moving the first and second collars <b>36</b>, <b>38</b> laterally, as is described below. The actuator <b>41</b> is operable between a neutral position, a first position disposed laterally away from the neutral position toward the first gear <b>18</b>.<b>1</b>, and a second position disposed laterally away from the neutral position toward the eighth gear <b>22</b>.<b>1</b>. The housing of the transmission assembly <b>11</b> may include stops that determine the first and second positions of the actuator <b>41</b>. The actuator <b>41</b> includes a third female spline lock (not shown) that is adapted for engaging with the third male spline lock <b>35</b>.<b>3</b> on the outer shaft portion <b>34</b> of the first output shaft <b>24</b>. In the neutral position, the actuator <b>41</b> is engaged with the third male spline lock <b>35</b>.<b>3</b>, the first collar <b>36</b> is disengaged from the first male spline lock <b>35</b>.<b>1</b>, and the second collar <b>38</b> is disengaged from the second male spline lock <b>35</b>.<b>2</b> such that the first output shaft <b>24</b> does not rotate. With the actuator <b>41</b> in the neutral position and in response to rotation of the input shaft <b>12</b>, the first collar <b>36</b> rotates with rotation of the first gear <b>18</b>.<b>1</b> and the second collar <b>38</b> rotates with rotation of the eighth gear <b>22</b>.<b>1</b>, but the first output shaft <b>24</b> remains stationary.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In response to moving the actuator <b>41</b> laterally to the first position, the first and second collars <b>36</b>, <b>38</b> move with the actuator <b>41</b> along the outer shaft portion <b>34</b> of the first output shaft <b>24</b>. The actuator <b>41</b> disengages from the third male spline lock <b>35</b>.<b>3</b> and urges the first collar <b>36</b> to engage with the first male spline lock <b>35</b>.<b>1</b> on the outer shaft portion <b>34</b> of the first output shaft <b>24</b>. With the actuator <b>41</b> in the first position such that the first collar <b>36</b> is engaging the first male spline lock <b>35</b>.<b>1</b>, the first output shaft <b>24</b> is rotated in the counterclockwise direction by rotation of the first gear <b>18</b>.<b>1</b> in response to rotation of the input shaft <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Alternatively, in response to moving the actuator <b>41</b> laterally to the second position, the first and second collars <b>36</b>, <b>38</b> move with the actuator <b>41</b> along the outer shaft portion <b>34</b> of the first output shaft <b>24</b>. The actuator <b>41</b> disengages from the third male spline lock <b>35</b>.<b>3</b> and urges the second collar <b>38</b> to engage with the second male spline lock <b>35</b>.<b>2</b> on the outer shaft portion <b>34</b> of the first output shaft <b>24</b>. With the actuator <b>41</b> in the second position such that the second collar <b>38</b> is engaging the second male spline lock <b>35</b>.<b>2</b>, the first output shaft <b>24</b> is rotated in the clockwise direction by rotation of the eighth gear <b>22</b>.<b>1</b> in response to rotation of the input shaft <b>12</b>. Similar operation is contemplated for the actuators <b>41</b> on each of the second, third, and fourth output shafts <b>26</b>, <b>28</b>, <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In a second embodiment of the invention, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 through 6</figref>, a power seat adjuster <b>100</b> for a motor vehicle seat assembly includes a single motor (not shown) that is coupled to a multi-output transmission assembly <b>102</b>. Only a portion of the multi-output transmission assembly <b>102</b> is shown in the Figures. The transmission assembly <b>102</b> includes a housing (not shown) and an input shaft (not shown) driven by the motor. First and second drive gears (not shown) are mounted on the input shaft for rotation therewith. The first drive gear drives a first input gear <b>104</b> in a first rotational direction, for example, clockwise. The first input gear <b>104</b> includes a neck <b>106</b> extending laterally therefrom. The second drive gear drives a second input gear <b>108</b> in a second rotational direction, for example, counterclockwise. More specifically, the second drive gear meshingly engages a reverse idler gear (not shown), which in turn meshingly engages the second input gear <b>108</b>. The second input gear <b>108</b> includes a neck <b>110</b> extending laterally therefrom. The neck <b>106</b> of the first input gear <b>104</b> extends within the neck <b>110</b> of the second input gear <b>108</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A through 6</figref>, however, the first and second input gears <b>104</b>, <b>108</b> are not fixed together. As such, the first and second input gears <b>104</b>, <b>108</b> are free to rotate in opposite directions.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The transmission assembly <b>102</b> also includes an output shaft <b>112</b> that extends laterally through the necks <b>106</b>, <b>110</b> of the respective first and second input gears <b>104</b>, <b>108</b>. The output shaft <b>112</b> includes an inner shaft portion <b>114</b> extending through and fixed to an outer shaft portion <b>116</b>. The inner shaft portion <b>114</b> of the output shaft <b>112</b> is adapted to be operatively coupled to an adjustment device of the seat assembly. For example, the adjustment device can be a seat track drive for moving the seat assembly fore and aft, a front lift drive for lifting or tilting a front end of a seat cushion, a rear lift drive for lifting or tilting a rear end of the seat cushion, or a recliner drive for pivoting a seat back relative to the seat cushion.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The outer shaft portion <b>116</b> of the output shaft <b>112</b> includes two male spline locks that are laterally spaced apart, namely, a first male spline lock <b>118</b> and a second male spline lock <b>120</b>. The first male spline lock <b>118</b> is disposed toward the first and second input gears <b>104</b>, <b>108</b> and the second male spline lock <b>120</b> is disposed away from the first and second input gears <b>104</b>, <b>108</b>. First and second collars <b>122</b>, <b>124</b> are slidably mounted on the outer shaft portion <b>116</b> of the output shaft <b>112</b>. More specifically, the first collar <b>122</b> is disposed within the second collar <b>124</b> and includes a flange <b>126</b> that is received by the second collar <b>124</b> to couple the first and second collars <b>122</b>, <b>124</b> together. The first and second collars <b>122</b>, <b>124</b> are coupled together such that they move laterally along the output shaft <b>112</b> as a single unit, however, like the first and second input gears <b>104</b>, <b>108</b>, the first and second collars <b>122</b>, <b>124</b> are free to rotate in opposite directions. As such, the first collar <b>122</b> rotates with the first input gear <b>104</b> in the clockwise direction and the second collar <b>124</b> rotates with the second output gear <b>108</b> in the counterclockwise direction, as is described below.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The neck <b>106</b> of the first input gear <b>104</b> is internally splined. The first collar <b>122</b> is externally splined and is engaged with the internal splines of the neck <b>106</b> such that the first collar <b>122</b> rotates with the first input gear <b>104</b> in the clockwise direction. The splined engagement allows the first collar <b>122</b> to move laterally relative to the first input gear <b>104</b>. The first collar <b>122</b> also includes a first female spline lock <b>128</b> that is adapted for selectively engaging with the first male spline lock <b>118</b> on the outer shaft portion <b>116</b> of the output shaft <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The neck <b>110</b> of the second input gear <b>108</b> is externally splined. The second collar <b>124</b> is internally splined and is engaged with the external splines of the neck <b>110</b> such that the second collar <b>124</b> rotates with the second input gear <b>108</b> in the counterclockwise direction. The splined engagement allows the second collar <b>124</b> to move laterally relative to the second input gear <b>108</b>. The second collar <b>124</b> also includes a second female spline lock <b>130</b> that is adapted for selectively engaging with the second male spline lock <b>120</b> on the outer shaft portion <b>116</b> of the output shaft <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">An actuator <b>132</b> with an actuation pin <b>134</b> and a backplate <b>136</b> is coupled to the second collar <b>124</b> for slidably moving the first and second collars <b>122</b>, <b>124</b> laterally, as is described below. The first and second collars <b>122</b>, <b>124</b> are free to rotate relative to the actuator <b>132</b>. The actuator <b>132</b> itself is prevented from rotating by the housing of the transmission assembly <b>102</b>. The actuator <b>132</b> is operable between a neutral position, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>, a first position disposed laterally away from the neutral position toward the first and second input gears <b>104</b>, <b>108</b>, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>, and a second position disposed laterally away from the neutral position and away from the first and second input gears <b>104</b>, <b>108</b>, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</figref>. The housing of the transmission assembly <b>102</b> may include stops that determine the first and second positions of the actuator <b>132</b>. The backplate <b>136</b> includes a third female spline lock <b>138</b> that is adapted for selectively engaging with the second male spline lock <b>120</b> on the outer shaft portion <b>116</b> of the output shaft <b>112</b>. In the neutral position, the actuator <b>132</b>, and more specifically the third female spline lock <b>138</b> in the backplate <b>136</b>, is engaged with the second male spline lock <b>120</b> such that the output shaft <b>112</b> does not rotate. With the actuator <b>132</b> in the neutral position, the first collar <b>122</b> is disengaged from the first male spline lock <b>118</b> on the outer shaft portion <b>116</b> of the output shaft <b>112</b> and the second collar <b>124</b> is disengaged from the second male spline lock <b>120</b> on the outer shaft portion <b>116</b> of the output shaft <b>112</b>. Further, with the actuator <b>132</b> in the neutral position and in response to rotation of the input shaft, the first collar <b>122</b> rotates with the first input gear <b>104</b> and the second collar <b>124</b> rotates with the second input gear <b>108</b>, but the output shaft <b>112</b> remains stationary.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In response to moving the actuator <b>132</b> laterally to the first position, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>, the first and second collars <b>122</b>, <b>124</b> move with the actuator <b>132</b> along the output shaft <b>112</b> toward the first and second input gears <b>104</b>, <b>108</b>. The third female spline lock <b>138</b> disengages from the second male spline lock <b>120</b> and urges the first female spline lock <b>128</b> in the first collar <b>122</b> to engage with the first male spline lock <b>118</b> on the outer portion <b>116</b> of the output shaft <b>112</b>. With the actuator <b>132</b> in the first position such that the first collar <b>122</b> is engaging the first male spline lock <b>118</b>, the output shaft <b>112</b> is rotated by the first input gear <b>104</b> in the clockwise direction in response to rotation of the input shaft.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Alternatively, in response to moving the actuator <b>132</b> laterally to the second position, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</figref>, the first and second collars <b>122</b>, <b>124</b> move with the actuator <b>132</b> along the output shaft <b>112</b> away from the first and second input gears <b>104</b>, <b>108</b>. The third female spline lock <b>138</b> disengages from the second male spline lock <b>120</b> and urges the second female spline lock <b>130</b> in the second collar <b>124</b> to engage with the second male spline lock <b>120</b> on the outer portion <b>116</b> of the output shaft <b>112</b>. With the actuator <b>132</b> in the second position such that the second collar <b>124</b> is engaging the second male spline lock <b>120</b>, the output shaft <b>112</b> is rotated by the second input gear <b>108</b> in the counterclockwise direction in response to rotation of the input shaft.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The invention has been described here in an illustrative manner, and it is to be understood that the terminology used is intended to be in the nature of words of description rather than limitation. Many modifications and variations of the present invention are possible in light of the above teachings. It is, therefore, to be understood that within the scope of the appended claims, the invention may be practiced other than as specifically enumerated within the description.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A multi-output transmission assembly for a power seat adjuster, said multi-output transmission assembly comprising:
<claim-text>a first gear set;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second gear set;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first output shaft;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first collar slidably coupled to said first output shaft and rotated by said first gear set in a first rotational direction, wherein said first collar is selectively engaged with said first output shaft for rotating said first output shaft;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second collar slidably coupled to said first output shaft and rotated by said second gear set in a second rotational direction, opposite said first rotational direction, wherein said second collar is selectively engaged with said first output shaft for rotating said first output shaft; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first actuator coupled to said first and second collars for sliding said first and second collars along said first output shaft;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said first actuator moves between a neutral position preventing rotation of said first output shaft, a first position wherein said first collar is engaged with said first output shaft to rotate said first output shaft in said first rotational direction in response to actuation of said first gear set, and a second position wherein said second collar is engaged with said first output shaft to rotate said first output shaft in said second rotational direction in response to actuation of said second gear set.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The multi-output transmission assembly set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> including an input shaft that actuates said first gear set to rotate said first collar in said first rotational direction and simultaneously actuates said second gear set to rotate said second collar in said second rotational direction in response to rotation of said input shaft.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The multi-output transmission assembly set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> wherein said first and second collars rotate relative to said first output shaft when said first actuator is in said neutral position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The multi-output transmission assembly as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref> wherein said first output shaft includes a first male spline lock, a second male spline lock, and a third male spline lock disposed laterally between said first and second male spline locks, and wherein said first actuator is engaged with said third male spline lock when said first actuator is in said neutral position, said first collar is engaged with said first male spline lock when said first actuator is in said first position, and said second collar is engaged with said second male spline lock when said first actuator is in said second position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The multi-output transmission assembly set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref> including a second output shaft, a third collar slidably coupled to said second output shaft and selectively engaged with said second output shaft for rotating said second output shaft, and a fourth collar slidably coupled to said second output shaft and selectively engaged with said second output shaft for rotating said second output shaft, wherein said second output shaft is rotatable in said first and second rotational directions independently of said first output shaft.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The multi-output transmission assembly set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> including a second actuator coupled to said third and fourth collars for sliding said third and fourth collars along said second output shaft, wherein said second actuator moves between a neutral position preventing rotation of said second output shaft, a first position wherein said third collar is engaged with said second output shaft to rotate said second output shaft in said first rotational direction in response to rotation of said input shaft, and a second position wherein said fourth collar is engaged with said second output shaft to rotate said second output shaft in said second rotational direction in response to rotation of said input shaft.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The multi-output transmission assembly set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> including a third output shaft, a fifth collar slidably coupled to said third output shaft and selectively engaged with said third output shaft for rotating said third output shaft, and a sixth collar slidably coupled to said third output shaft and selectively engaged with said third output shaft for rotating said third output shaft, wherein said third output shaft is rotatable in said first and second rotational directions independently of said first and second output shafts.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The multi-output transmission assembly set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref> including a third actuator coupled to said fifth and sixth collars for sliding said fifth and sixth collars along said third output shaft, wherein said third actuator moves between a neutral position preventing rotation of said third output shaft, a first position wherein said fifth collar is engaged with said third output shaft to rotate said third output shaft in said first rotational direction in response to rotation of said input shaft, and a second position wherein said sixth collar is engaged with said third output shaft to rotate said third output shaft in said second rotational direction in response to rotation of said input shaft.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The multi-output transmission assembly set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> including a fourth output shaft, a seventh collar slidably coupled to said fourth output shaft and selectively engaged with said fourth output shaft for rotating said fourth output shaft, and an eighth collar slidably coupled to said fourth output shaft and selectively engaged with said fourth output shaft for rotating said fourth output shaft, wherein said fourth output shaft is rotatable in said first and second rotational directions independently of said first, second, and third output shafts.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The multi-output transmission assembly set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref> including a fourth actuator coupled to said seventh and eighth collars for sliding said seventh and eighth collars along said fourth output shaft, wherein said fourth actuator moves between a neutral position preventing rotation of said fourth output shaft, a first position wherein said seventh collar is engaged with said fourth output shaft to rotate said fourth output shaft in said first rotational direction in response to rotation of said input shaft, and a second position wherein said eighth collar is engaged with said fourth output shaft to rotate said fourth output shaft in said second rotational direction in response to rotation of said input shaft.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The multi-output transmission assembly set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref> wherein said first gear set includes a first gear meshingly engaging a second gear, said second gear meshingly engaging a third gear, said third gear meshingly engaging a first ring gear, said first ring gear meshingly engaging fourth and fifth gears, at least one of said fourth and fifth gears meshingly engaging a sixth gear, and said sixth gear meshingly engaging a seventh gear, wherein said first gear is coupled with said first collar for rotating said first collar, said fourth gear is coupled with said third collar for rotating said third collar, said fifth gear is coupled with said fifth collar for rotating said fifth collar, and said seventh gear is coupled with said seventh collar for rotating said seventh collar.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The multi-output transmission assembly set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> wherein said input shaft includes a first drive gear meshingly engaging said first gear.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The multi-output transmission assembly set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref> wherein said second gear set includes an eighth gear meshingly engaging a ninth gear, said ninth gear meshingly engaging a tenth gear, said tenth gear meshingly engaging a second ring gear, said second ring gear meshingly engaging eleventh and twelfth gears, at least one of said eleventh and twelfth gears meshingly engaging a thirteenth gear, and said thirteenth gear meshingly engaging a fourteenth gear, wherein said eighth gear is coupled with said second collar for rotating said second collar, said eleventh gear is coupled with said fourth collar for rotating said fourth collar, said twelfth gear is coupled with said sixth collar for rotating said sixth collar, and said fourteenth gear is coupled with said eighth collar for rotating said eighth collar.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The multi-output transmission assembly set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> wherein said input shaft includes a second drive gear meshingly engaging an idler gear, said idler gear meshingly engaging said eighth gear.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A multi-output transmission assembly for a power seat adjuster, said multi-output transmission assembly comprising:
<claim-text>a first input gear selectively rotatable in a first rotational direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second input gear selectively rotatable in a second rotational direction, opposite said first rotational direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an output shaft;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first collar slidably coupled to said output shaft and rotated in said first rotational direction by said first input gear, wherein said first collar is selectively engaged with said output shaft for rotating said output shaft;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second collar slidably coupled to said output shaft and rotated in said second rotational direction by said second input gear, wherein said second collar is selectively engaged with said output shaft for rotating said output shaft: and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an actuator coupled to said first and second collars for sliding said first and second collars along said output shaft;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said actuator moves between a neutral position preventing rotation of said output shaft, a first position wherein said first collar is engaged with said output shaft to rotate said output shaft in said first rotational direction in response to rotation of said first input gear in said first rotational direction, and a second position wherein said second collar is engaged with said output shaft to rotate said output shaft in said second rotational direction in response to rotation of said second input gear in said second rotational direction.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The multi-output transmission assembly as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref> wherein said first and second collars rotate relative to said output shaft when said actuator is in said neutral position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The multi-output transmission assembly as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref> wherein said output shaft includes a first male spline lock and a second male spline lock, said first and second male spline locks laterally spaced apart, and wherein said first collar includes a first female spline lock for selectively engaging said first male spline lock when said actuator is in said first position, and wherein said second collar includes a second female spline lock for selectively engaging said second male spline lock when said actuator is in said second position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The multi-output transmission assembly as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref> wherein said actuator includes a third female spline lock for selectively engaging said second male spline lock when said actuator is in said neutral position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The multi-output transmission assembly as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref> wherein said first input gear includes a first neck and said second input gear includes a second neck, said first neck extending axially within said second neck.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The multi-output transmission assembly as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref> wherein said first neck is internally splined and said first collar is externally splined for splined engagement with said first neck, and wherein said second neck is externally splined and said second collar is internally splined for splined engagement with said second neck.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The multi-output transmission assembly as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref> wherein said first collar extends axially within said second collar, and wherein said output shaft extends axially through said first neck and said first collar. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
