<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624361-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624361</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13677863</doc-number>
<date>20121115</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>29</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257622</main-classification>
<further-classification>977762</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Self-formation of high-density defect-free and aligned nanostructures</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6121118</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Jin et al.</name>
<date>20000900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6830990</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Honer et al.</name>
<date>20041200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6933212</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Lee et al.</name>
<date>20050800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7595543</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Weber et al.</name>
<date>20090900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7843041</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kodaira et al.</name>
<date>20101100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257622</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7875500</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Inada et al.</name>
<date>20110100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438113</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0117741</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Heath et al.</name>
<date>20090500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2012/0148799</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Patolsky et al.</name>
<date>20120600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00009">
<othercit>Li, Y., et al. &#x201c;Progress Toward Nanowire Deivce Assembly Technology&#x201d; &#x201c;Nanowires&#x201d; edited by P. Prete, Intech. Mar. 2010. pp. 373-394.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00010">
<othercit>Long, Y., et al. &#x201c;Recent Advances in Large-Scale Assembly of Semiconducting Inorganic Nanowires and Nanofibers for Electronics, Sensors and Photovoltaics&#x201d; Chem. Soc. Rev., vol. 41. Jul. 2012. pp. 4560-4580.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00011">
<othercit>San Paulo, A., et al. &#x201c;Suspended Mechanical Structures Based on Elastic Silicon Nanowire Arrays&#x201d; Nano Letters, vol. 7, No. 4. Mar. 2007. pp. 1100-1104.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00012">
<othercit>Tamboli, A., et al. &#x201c;Wafer-Scale Growth of Silicon Microwire Arrays for Photovoltaics and Solar Fuel Generation&#x201d; IEEE Journal of Photovoltaics, vol. 2, Issue 3. Jul. 2012. pp. 294-297.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>22</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257622</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>977762</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>14</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13670921</doc-number>
<date>20121107</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13677863</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>International Business Machines Corporation</orgname>
<address>
<city>Armonk</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cheng</last-name>
<first-name>Cheng-Wei</first-name>
<address>
<city>White Plains</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Jeehwan</first-name>
<address>
<city>White Plains</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Park</last-name>
<first-name>Hongsik</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yorktown Heights</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Tutunjian &#x26; Bitetto, P.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Percello</last-name>
<first-name>Louis J.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>International Business Machines Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Armonk</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Smith</last-name>
<first-name>Bradley K</first-name>
<department>2894</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A device and method for forming nanostructures includes providing a monocrystalline semiconductor layer on a flexible substrate and stressing the substrate in accordance with a crystal cleave plane to initiate cracks in the semiconductor layer. The cracks are propagated on the crystal cleave plane through the semiconductor layer where the cracks are spaced by an intercrack distance as determined by applying a particular strain. The strain is released to provide parallel structures on the flexible substrate.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="83.57mm" wi="171.03mm" file="US08624361-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="234.44mm" wi="178.82mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624361-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="246.72mm" wi="186.69mm" file="US08624361-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="215.90mm" wi="170.35mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624361-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="242.91mm" wi="176.95mm" file="US08624361-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">RELATED APPLICATION INFORMATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a Continuation application of co-pending U.S. patent application Ser. No. 13/670,921 filed on Nov. 7, 2012, incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to semiconductor devices and fabrication, and more particularly to methods and devices having nanowires or nanodots formed by stress-induced cracking.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Nanowires are fabricated to increase surface area relative to volume in many applications, such as, in applications where absorption of radiation is of interest. Conventional methods for fabricating nanowires (NWs) may include different forms of lithography (e.g., E-beam lithography, photolithography, etc.). While effective, these processes are expensive and difficult to control, especially for sizes less than 20 nm. In addition to being cost-inefficient, lithography is extremely low throughput and prone to line-edge roughness, which results in a large scattering effect for carrier transport. Also, damage from dry etching processes leads to surface defects in the nanowires.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Another process includes VLS (vapor-liquid-solid) growth. VLS growth suffers from many issues, e.g., it is difficult to control the density of the nanowires and there is no alignment among the nanowires. In addition, VLS growth results in poor uniformity of material properties (dimensions and crystallinity). The nanowires are random and vertical, and the crystal quality is less than a Czochralski (CZ) single crystal, which leads to high defect density.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">A device and method for forming nanostructures includes providing a monocrystalline semiconductor layer on a flexible substrate and stressing the substrate in accordance with a crystal cleave plane to initiate cracks in the semiconductor layer. The cracks are propagated on the crystal cleave plane through the semiconductor layer where the cracks are spaced by an intercrack distance as determined by applying a particular strain. The strain is released to provide parallel structures on the flexible substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Another method for forming nanostructures includes providing a monocrystalline semiconductor layer on a flexible substrate; bending the substrate in accordance with a first crystal cleave plane to provide a first strain in the semiconductor layer; bending the substrate in accordance with a second crystal cleave plane to provide a second strain in the semiconductor layer; propagating cracks on the first and second crystal cleave planes through the semiconductor layer where the cracks are spaced by an intercrack distance as determined by applying a particular strain; releasing the strain to provide dot structures on the flexible substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Yet another method for forming nanostructures includes providing a monocrystalline semiconductor layer on a flexible substrate; bending the substrate in accordance with a crystal cleave plane to provide a strain in the semiconductor layer; propagating cracks on the crystal cleave plane through the semiconductor layer where the cracks are spaced by an intercrack distance as determined by applying a particular strain computed to provide a dimension for the parallel structures that is equal to the intercrack distance; releasing the strain to provide parallel structures on the flexible substrate; oxidizing the parallel structures to passivate and isolate adjacent parallel structures; doping the semiconductor layer; and forming an electronic device or photonic device on the parallel structures.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">A nanostructure device includes a flexible substrate; a monocrystalline semiconductor layer formed on the flexible substrate and a plurality of parallel cracks formed in accordance with a crystal cleave plane in the semiconductor layer, the cracks being spaced apart by an intercrack distance as determined by applying a particular strain to form parallel structures. A dielectric material is formed in the cracks between and over the parallel structures on the semiconductor layer.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Another nanostructure device includes a flexible substrate; a monocrystalline semiconductor layer formed on the flexible substrate; and a plurality of parallel cracks formed in accordance with two crystal cleave planes in the semiconductor layer. The cracks are spaced apart by intercrack distances in two dimensions as determined by applying a particular strain to form dot structures. A dielectric material is formed in the cracks between and over the dot structures on the semiconductor layer.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Yet another nanostructure device includes a flexible substrate; a monocrystalline semiconductor layer formed on the flexible substrate; and a plurality of parallel nanowires extending along a crystal cleave plane in the semiconductor layer. The nanowires have a thickness and a width. The width includes an intercrack distance determined in accordance with a particular strain applied to the semiconductor layer to form the cracks. An oxide is formed between and over the nanowires to passivate and isolate adjacent nanowires. An electronic device or photonic device is formed on the nanowires.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">These and other features and advantages will become apparent from the following detailed description of illustrative embodiments thereof, which is to be read in connection with the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The disclosure will provide details in the following description of preferred embodiments with reference to the following figures wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a cross-sectional view of a flexible substrate having a semiconductor layer formed thereon in accordance with the present principles;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the flexible substrate in bending to create and propagate cracks in the semiconductor layer in accordance with the present principles;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the flexible substrate with parallel structures formed and having dielectric materials formed over and in-between the parallel structures in accordance with the present principles;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref> is a top down view showing the flexible substrate with parallel structures formed and having a transparent dielectric material formed over the parallel structures for ease of viewing the parallel structures in accordance with the present principles;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cross-sectional view of another flexible substrate having a semiconductor layer formed thereon in accordance with the present principles;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the flexible substrate in bending along one axis to create and propagate cracks in the semiconductor layer in accordance with the present principles;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the flexible substrate in bending along a second axis to create and propagate cracks in the semiconductor layer in accordance with the present principles;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the flexible substrate with dot structures formed in a grid pattern and having dielectric materials formed over and in-between the dot structures in accordance with the present principles;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref> is a top down view showing the flexible substrate with dot structures formed in the grid pattern and having a transparent dielectric material formed over the dot structures for ease of viewing the dot structures in accordance with the present principles;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the flexible substrate with parallel structures formed and having illustrative devices formed with the parallel structures in accordance with the present principles;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</figref> is a top down view showing the flexible substrate with parallel structures formed and having the illustrative devices formed with the parallel structures in accordance with the present principles;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the flexible substrate with dot structures formed and having illustrative devices formed with the dot structures in accordance with the present principles;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8B</figref> is a top down view showing the flexible substrate with dot structures formed and having the illustrative devices formed with the dot structures in accordance with the present principles; and</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a block/flow diagram showing methods for forming nanostructures in accordance with illustrative embodiments.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In accordance with the present principles, methods for forming nanostructures (e.g., wires, dots, etc.) using a stress-inducing manipulation of semiconductor materials are provided. The term nanostructures will be employed throughout this disclosure to include nanowires and nanodots. It should be understood that while the prefix nano will be employed to designate nano-sized dimensions, structures having sizes in the micron range (micro-sized) are also contemplated in accordance with the present principles.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In particularly useful embodiments, a semiconductor layer is applied to a flexible substrate and flexed to produce micro cracks along crystal lines. The micro cracks are propagated through the materials to cause the semiconductor layer to separate from other sections of the semiconductor layer. By controlling the bending and therefore the stress along the crystal line in the semiconductor materials, fine lines of semiconductor material can be produced. The fine lines of the semiconductor material form nanowires along the flexible substrate. These nanowires may be employed in forming a plurality of different electrical/electronic structures. In one embodiment, a dielectric layer may be deposited to provide electrical isolation between the nanowires. In other embodiments, the flexible substrate may be flexed in two orthogonal (or transvers) planes to cause the formation of islands or nanodots on the flexible substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In another embodiment, temperature differences may be employed to form or propagate cracks; e.g., ultra low temperatures (e.g., cryogenic temperatures) or high temperatures may be employed to facilitate crack initiation and increase crack density.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">It is to be understood that the present invention will be described in terms of a given illustrative architecture having a substrate or flexible substrate; however, other architectures, structures, substrate materials and process features and steps may be varied within the scope of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">It will also be understood that when an element such as a layer, region or substrate is referred to as being &#x201c;on&#x201d; or &#x201c;over&#x201d; another element, it can be directly on the other element or intervening elements may also be present. In contrast, when an element is referred to as being &#x201c;directly on&#x201d; or &#x201c;directly over&#x201d; another element, there are no intervening elements present. It will also be understood that when an element is referred to as being &#x201c;connected&#x201d; or &#x201c;coupled&#x201d; to another element, it can be directly connected or coupled to the other element or intervening elements may be present. In contrast, when an element is referred to as being &#x201c;directly connected&#x201d; or &#x201c;directly coupled&#x201d; to another element, there are no intervening elements present.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Embodiments in accordance with the present principles may include a design for an integrated circuit chip, which may be created in a graphical computer programming language, and stored in a computer storage medium (such as a disk, tape, physical hard drive, or virtual hard drive such as in a storage access network). If the designer does not fabricate chips or the photolithographic masks used to fabricate chips, the designer may transmit the resulting design by physical means (e.g., by providing a copy of the storage medium storing the design) or electronically (e.g., through the Internet) to such entities, directly or indirectly. The stored design is then converted into the appropriate format (e.g., GDSII) for the fabrication of photolithographic masks, which typically include multiple copies of the chip design in question that are to be formed on a wafer. The photolithographic masks are utilized to define areas of the wafer (and/or the layers thereon) to be etched or otherwise processed.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Methods as described herein may be used in the fabrication of integrated circuit chips. The resulting integrated circuit chips can be distributed by the fabricator in raw form (that is, as a single flexible substrate that has multiple structures formed thereon), as a bare die, or in a packaged form. In the latter case the chip is mounted in a single chip package (such as a plastic carrier, with leads that are affixed to a motherboard or other higher level carrier) or in a multichip package (such as a ceramic carrier that has either or both surface interconnections or buried interconnections). In any case the chip is then integrated with other chips, discrete circuit elements, and/or other signal processing devices as part of either (a) an intermediate product, such as a motherboard, or (b) an end product. The end product can be any product that includes integrated circuit chips, ranging from toys and other low-end applications to advanced computer products having a display, a keyboard or other input device, and a central processor.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The nanowires and quantum dot embodiments as described herein may be employed in a plurality of applications and structures. For example, the present structures may be employed in devices to provide quasi one-dimensional effects (electron or photon confinement) (quantum dots) and/or provide a large ratio of surface area to volume. The nanowire/nanodot semiconductor layer is less constrained as a substrate than for device fabrication compared to bulk or thin film materials and is suitable for flexible electronics and photonics designs. The present principles find utility in devices such as, tri-gate transistors, high-gain photodetectors, various sensors with high sensitivity, infra-red detectors using intersub-band transition, photo-emitters and lasers with extremely small footprints, nanogenerators for self-powered systems, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Referring now to the drawings in which like numerals represent the same or similar elements and initially to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a structure <b>100</b> is shown in accordance with one illustrative embodiment. Structure <b>100</b> includes a flexible substrate <b>102</b>. The flexible substrate may include a polymeric material(s), such as, e.g., thermoplastics, e.g., polyethylene terephthalate (PET), polyimide, etc.; reinforced epoxy resins, such as e.g., prepreg boards, etc. The flexible substrate <b>102</b> preferably includes elastic properties to permit full recovery during bending in accordance with the present principles. A semiconductor layer <b>104</b> is provided on the flexible substrate <b>102</b>. The semiconductor layer <b>104</b> preferably includes a monocrystalline form of a semiconductor material. In one embodiment, the semiconductor material includes Si, although other crystalline materials may be employed, such as Ge, GaAs, etc. For purposes of this disclosure, the present principles will be described in terms of monocrystalline Si. In one illustrative embodiment, the flexible substrate <b>102</b> may include a thickness of between about 0.1 mm and 10 mm. The semiconductor layer <b>104</b> may include a thickness of between about 1 nm and about 1000 nm.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The semiconductor layer <b>104</b> may be deposited on the flexible substrate <b>102</b> using epitaxial growth or the semiconductor layer <b>104</b> may be bonded to the flexible substrate using an adhesive. In other embodiments, additional layers may be employed between the flexible substrate <b>102</b> and the semiconductor layer <b>104</b>. The flexible substrate <b>102</b> and the semiconductor layer <b>104</b> are formed or provided having determined thicknesses to assist in achieving desired bending stress/strain in the next steps.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the flexible substrate <b>102</b> with the semiconductor layer <b>104</b> formed thereon is bent in a two point bending process. The two point bending flexes the device <b>100</b> about a single axis of rotation. This can be performed using a fixture or may include applying the device over a radiused surface. The bending radius and the thicknesses of the layers <b>102</b>, <b>104</b> may be guided by beam theory computations to ensure sufficient strain is provided along crystal lines. In one embodiment, the semiconductor layer <b>104</b> is positioned to have a &#x201c;110&#x201d; crystal plane aligned to an axis of bending. In one embodiment, a machine chuck is employed to clamp two edges which can have a torque applied to cause bending.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In one embodiment, uniaxial tensile strain is induced to initiate and propagate cracking in the single crystalline semiconductor layer <b>104</b>. For example, cracking occurs along a Si cleavage plane 110. An intercrack distance <b>105</b> is proportional to the amount of tensile strain occurring in the bent semiconductor layer <b>104</b>. Cracks <b>106</b> in a nanoscale thick Si film can be self-formed when tensile strain is high enough to form cracks <b>106</b> with a nanometer scale inter-crack distance <b>105</b>. For semiconductor layer <b>104</b>, a thickness can be provided, e.g., between about 20 nm to about 900 nm, and a uniaxial strain can be computed such that the intercrack distance <b>105</b> provides a second dimension (width) for nanowires <b>112</b> formed by the bending. If the width dimension that is desired is to be close to the thickness dimension selected, a bending moment is selected to provide a uniaxial strain that will yield the desired intercrack distance <b>105</b> to achieve the width of the nanowires <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The uniaxial tensile strain is applied by two-point bending of the flexible substrate <b>102</b> until cracks located at the intercrack distance <b>105</b> propagate through the thickness of the semiconductor layer <b>104</b>. The crack propagation may be assisted by various mechanisms once cracks <b>106</b> are initiated. For example, cracks <b>106</b> may be accelerated by changing temperatures, employing vibration, increasing strain, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In another embodiment, in addition to or instead of bending, the substrate <b>102</b> and layer <b>104</b> are subjected to rapid temperature changes to cause expansion or contraction to induce cracking. The temperature changes may be induced using, e.g., cryogenic cooling, flash heating or combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, a cross-sectional view of the device <b>100</b> is shown in accordance with one embodiment. After crack formation and propagation through the semiconductor layer <b>104</b>, stress/strain is released from the device. Depending on how the device <b>100</b> will be employed, a dielectric material <b>108</b> may be deposited over the semiconductor layer <b>104</b>. The dielectric material <b>108</b> may include, e.g., an oxide, such as silicon dioxide, a nitride, such as silicon nitride, silicon oxynitride, etc. In one example, a natural oxide may be formed as a dielectric material <b>108</b> by oxidizing the surface of the semiconductor layer <b>104</b>. In other examples, a chemical vapor deposition or similar deposition process may be employed to form dielectric material <b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In one embodiment, prior to forming the dielectric material <b>108</b>, an etching process may be performed to increase the width of the cracks (<b>106</b>) between nanowires <b>112</b> to control the width of nanowires <b>112</b> and ensure the dielectric material <b>108</b> electrically isolates adjacent nanowires <b>112</b>. The etching process may include a wet etch, using a diluted acid, e.g., HF, HCl, etc. In one embodiment, the flexible substrate <b>102</b> may be mounted permanently or temporarily on an additional rigid substrate (not shown) for stability during processing or operation.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, a top down view is shown for the structure in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> with the dielectric layer <b>108</b> on top appearing transparent to view the underlying nanowires <b>112</b>. The nanowires <b>112</b> extend along the entire device <b>100</b> in a crystal direction (e.g., 110 in Si). The nanowires <b>112</b> are high-density defect-free and aligned along the crystal direction (e.g., 110 in Si).</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">It should be understood that the semiconductor layer <b>104</b> may be doped during formation or after formation either before or after crack inducement. It should also be understood that different portions of the semiconductor layer <b>104</b> may be doped differently depending on the specific applications of the nanowires <b>112</b>. This may be achieved by forming masks on the surface of the semiconductor layer <b>104</b> and doping exposed areas. The dielectric material <b>108</b> may be formed after doping the semiconductor layer <b>104</b> or the nanowires <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Processing may continue, which employs the unique nature of the nanowires <b>112</b> formed in accordance with the present principles. The nanowires <b>112</b> may be employed to form transistor devices, capacitors, electric wires, photosensitive devices, biosensors, wrap-around multi-channel transistors, etc. It should be understood that parts of the nanowires <b>112</b> may be etched away to create nanowires less than a full length of the device <b>100</b>. In this way, nanowires <b>112</b> may be employed locally to form devices in isolation of other devices downstream along the same semiconductor crystal direction (e.g., 110).</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a structure <b>200</b> is shown in accordance with another illustrative embodiment. Structure <b>200</b> includes the flexible substrate <b>102</b>, and the semiconductor layer <b>104</b> as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>, the flexible substrate <b>102</b> with the semiconductor layer <b>104</b> formed thereon is bent in a first two point bending process similar to the process described with the respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The two point bending flexes the device <b>200</b> about a single axis of rotation, which will be arbitrarily designated as the x-axis (&#x201c;x&#x201d;). This can be performed using a fixture or may include applying the device <b>200</b> over a radiused surface. The bending radius and the thicknesses of the layers <b>102</b>, <b>104</b> may be guided by beam theory computations to ensure sufficient strain is provided along crystal lines. In one embodiment, the semiconductor layer <b>104</b> is positioned to have a &#x201c;100&#x201d; crystal plane aligned to an axis of bending.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In one embodiment, uniaxial tensile strain is induced to initiate and propagate cracking in the single crystalline semiconductor layer <b>104</b>, as before. For example, cracking occurs along a Si cleavage plane &#x201c;100&#x201d;. An intercrack distance <b>105</b> is proportional to the amount of tensile strain occurring in the bent semiconductor layer <b>104</b>. Cracks <b>106</b> in a nanoscale thick Si film can be self-formed when tensile strain is high enough to form cracks <b>106</b> with a nanometer scale inter-crack distance <b>105</b>. For semiconductor layer <b>104</b>, a thickness can be provided, e.g., between about 20 nm to about 900 nm, and a uniaxial strain can be computed such that the intercrack distance <b>105</b> provides a second dimension (width) for nanowires <b>212</b> formed by the bending. If the width dimension that is desired is to be close to the thickness dimension selected, a bending moment is selected to provide a uniaxial strain that will yield the desired intercrack distance <b>105</b> to achieve this width of the nanowires <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The uniaxial tensile strain is applied by two-point bending of the flexible substrate <b>102</b> until cracks located at the intercrack distance <b>105</b> propagate through the thickness of the semiconductor layer <b>104</b>. The crack propagation may be assisted by various mechanisms once cracks <b>106</b> are initiated. For example, cracks <b>106</b> may be accelerated by changing temperatures, vibrations, increasing strain, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>, the flexible substrate <b>102</b> with the semiconductor layer <b>104</b> formed thereon is bent in a second two point bending process similar to the process described with the respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>. The two point bending flexes the device <b>200</b> about a second axis of rotation, which will be designated as the y-axis (&#x201c;y&#x201d;) and is orthogonal to the x-axis. This can be performed using a fixture or may include applying the device <b>200</b> over a radiused surface. The bending radius and the thicknesses of the layers <b>102</b>, <b>104</b> may be guided by beam theory computations to ensure sufficient strain is provided along crystal lines. In one embodiment, the semiconductor layer <b>104</b> is positioned to have nanowires <b>212</b> or nanodots <b>214</b> correspond to, e.g., a &#x201c;001&#x201d; or &#x201c;010&#x201d; crystal plane aligned with an axis (&#x201c;y&#x201d;) of bending.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In one embodiment, uniaxial tensile strain is induced to initiate and propagate cracking in the single crystalline semiconductor layer <b>104</b>. For example, cracking occurs along a Si cleavage plane &#x201c;001&#x201d; or &#x201c;010&#x201d;, if the original cleave plane (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>) is &#x201c;110&#x201d;. Note that the cleave planes are orthogonal between <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A and 5B</figref>. Other transverse relationships between cleave planes may be provided and employed as needed. An intercrack distance <b>205</b> is proportional to the amount of tensile strain occurring in the bent semiconductor layer <b>104</b> in the second bending process. Cracks <b>206</b> in a nanoscale thick Si film can be self-formed when tensile strain is high enough to form cracks <b>206</b> with the nanometer scale inter-crack distance <b>205</b>. For semiconductor layer <b>104</b>, a thickness, width and length are now provided for nanodots, or quantum dots <b>214</b>. A uniaxial strain can be computed such that the intercrack distance <b>205</b> provides a third dimension (length) for nanodots <b>214</b> formed by the bending.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The uniaxial tensile strain may be applied by a four-point bending step where the bend axes (e.g., x and y) are applied concurrently on the flexible substrate <b>102</b> until cracks located at the intercrack distances <b>105</b> and <b>205</b> propagate through the thickness of the semiconductor layer <b>104</b>. The crack propagation may be assisted by various mechanisms once cracks <b>106</b> and <b>206</b> are initiated. For example, cracks <b>106</b> and <b>206</b> may be accelerated by changing temperatures, employing vibration, increasing strain, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref>, a cross-sectional view of the device <b>200</b> is shown in accordance with one embodiment. After crack formation and propagation through the semiconductor layer <b>104</b>, stress/strain is released from the device. Depending on how the device <b>200</b> will be employed, a dielectric material <b>108</b> may be deposited over the nanodots <b>214</b>. The dielectric material <b>108</b> may include, e.g., an oxide, such as silicon dioxide, a nitride, such as silicon nitride, silicon oxynitride, etc. In one example, a natural oxide may be formed as a dielectric material <b>108</b> by oxidizing the surface of the nanodots <b>214</b>. In other examples, a chemical vapor deposition or similar deposition process may be employed to form dielectric material <b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In one embodiment, prior to forming the dielectric material <b>108</b>, an etching process may be performed to increase the width of the cracks (<b>106</b>, <b>206</b>) between nanodots <b>214</b> to ensure the dielectric material <b>108</b> electrically isolates adjacent nanodots <b>214</b> and provides appropriate spacing between the dots <b>214</b>. The etching process may include a wet etch, using a diluted acid, e.g., HF, HCl, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref>, a top down view is shown for the structure in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref> with the dielectric layer <b>108</b> on top appearing transparent to view the underlying nanodots <b>214</b>. The nanodots <b>214</b> include edges that extend along two different crystallographic directions. These different directions may be orthogonal but may include other configurations, e.g., two of the 100, 011, 010, 001, 011, etc. crystal directions may be employed. The nanodots <b>214</b> are high-density defect-free and aligned along the two crystal directions, and may be employed to form a quantum dot array. The array may be employed in providing photonic crystals, an array of nano-scale photo-emitters or lasers, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">It should be understood that the semiconductor layer <b>104</b> may be doped during formation or after formation either before or after crack inducement. It should also be understood that different portions of the semiconductor layer <b>104</b> may be doped differently depending on the specific applications of the nanodots <b>214</b>. This may be achieved by forming masks on the surface of the semiconductor layer <b>104</b> and doping exposed areas. The dielectric material <b>108</b> may be formed after doping the semiconductor layer <b>104</b> or nanodots <b>214</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Processing may continue which employs the unique nature of the nanodots <b>214</b> formed in accordance with the present principles. The nanodots <b>214</b> may be employed to form quantum confinement structures, transistor devices, capacitors, photosensitive devices, biosensors, etc. It should be understood that the nanodots <b>214</b> may be etched away to create spaces between nanodots (e.g., a checkerboard pattern, etc.).</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A and 7B</figref>, illustrative devices are depicted in accordance with the present principles where <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</figref> depicts a cross-sectional view and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</figref> depicts a top view with dielectric material being transparent to view underlying materials. A device <b>150</b> is formed with multiple nanowires <b>112</b> and may include a transistor device or the like. A longitudinal element <b>160</b> is formed over or with a single nanowire <b>112</b>. This may include a capacitive element, a contact, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8A and 8B</figref>, illustrative devices are depicted in accordance with the present principles where <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</figref> depicts a cross-sectional view and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8B</figref> depicts a top view with dielectric material being transparent to view underlying materials. A device <b>170</b> is formed with nanodots <b>214</b> and employs contacts <b>172</b> and <b>174</b> to connect to the device <b>170</b>. Note that devices <b>150</b>, <b>160</b> and <b>170</b> depict illustrative uses of the devices in accordance with the present principles. These devices <b>150</b>, <b>160</b> and <b>170</b> should not be considered as limiting as other devices and structures are also contemplated.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, methods for forming nanostructures (e.g., wires or dots) are illustratively shown in accordance with exemplary embodiments. It should also be noted that, in some alternative implementations, the functions noted in the blocks may occur out of the order noted in the figure(s). For example, two blocks shown in succession may, in fact, be executed substantially concurrently, or the blocks may sometimes be executed in the reverse order, depending upon the functionality involved. It will also be noted that each block of the block diagrams and/or flowchart illustration, and combinations of blocks in the block diagrams and/or flowchart illustration, can be implemented by special purpose hardware-based systems that perform the specified functions or acts, or combinations of special purpose hardware and computer instructions.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">In block <b>302</b>, a monocrystalline semiconductor layer is provided or formed on a flexible substrate. The semiconductor layer may include monocrystalline silicon.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">In block <b>304</b>, the substrate is bent in accordance with one or more crystal cleave planes of the semiconductor layer to provide a strain in the semiconductor layer. It should be noted that other mechanisms may be employed for inducing cracks, for example, cooling or heating may be employed. In block <b>306</b>, bending the substrate includes bending the substrate using a two point bend or over a radiused surface. In block <b>308</b>, bending the substrate may include bending the substrate in accordance with a first crystal cleave plane to provide a first strain in the semiconductor layer and in accordance with a second crystal cleave plane to provide a second strain in the semiconductor layer. The bending may be carried out separately (e.g., two, two-point bending operations) or concurrently (one, four-point bending operation).</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">In block <b>310</b>, cracks are propagated on the crystal cleave plane(s) through the semiconductor layer where the cracks are spaced by an intercrack distance as determined by applying a particular strain. In block <b>312</b>, propagating cracks may be accelerated by applying or removing energy, e.g., one or more of a temperature change, vibration, increased stress, etc., to the semiconductor layer. In one embodiment, in addition to or instead of bending, the substrate and semiconductor layer are subjected to rapid temperature changes to cause expansion or contraction to induce cracking. The temperature changes may be induced using, e.g., cryogenic cooling, flash heating or combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In block <b>314</b>, a strain corresponding with an intercrack distance may be computed and applied to provide and control a dimension or dimensions for the nanostructures that is equal to the intercrack distance. In block <b>316</b>, the strain corresponding with an intercrack distance may be computed for two cleave planes and applied to provide dimensions for dot structures that are equal to the intercrack distance in two dimensions.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">In block <b>318</b>, the strain is released to provide parallel structures or dots on the flexible substrate. In block <b>322</b>, the nanostructures may optionally be etched prior to forming a dielectric material.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">In block <b>324</b>, a dielectric material is formed over the nanostructures and in between the nanostructures to ensure electrical isolation between adjacent structures. In block <b>326</b>, the dielectric material may include oxidizing the nanostructures to form a passivation layer to isolate and maintain a gap between adjacent structures.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">In block <b>328</b>, the semiconductor layer may be doped. The doping may be performed at any time during the fabrication process, e.g., in-situ during formation of the semiconductor layer, after formation, etc. In block <b>330</b>, the nanostructures are employed in an electronic or photonic device, or the electronic or photonic is formed on or using the nano structures.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">Having described preferred embodiments for self-formation of high-density defect-free and aligned nanowires (which are intended to be illustrative and not limiting), it is noted that modifications and variations can be made by persons skilled in the art in light of the above teachings. It is therefore to be understood that changes may be made in the particular embodiments disclosed which are within the scope of the invention as outlined by the appended claims. Having thus described aspects of the invention, with the details and particularity required by the patent laws, what is claimed and desired protected by Letters Patent is set forth in the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A nanostructure device, comprising:
<claim-text>a flexible substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a monocrystalline semiconductor layer formed on the flexible substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of parallel cracks formed in accordance with a crystal cleave plane in the semiconductor layer, the cracks being spaced apart by an intercrack distance as determined by applying a particular strain to form parallel structures; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a dielectric material formed in the cracks between and over the parallel structures on the semiconductor layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein parallel structures include nanowires.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the cracks extend through an entire thickness of the semiconductor layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a dimension for the parallel structures is determined by the intercrack distance.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the parallel structures are doped to change conductivity.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising an electronic or photonic device formed on the parallel structures.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the dielectric material includes an oxide of the semiconductor layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the semiconductor layer includes monocrystalline silicon.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the flexible substrate includes a polymeric material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A nanostructure device, comprising:
<claim-text>a flexible substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a monocrystalline semiconductor layer formed on the flexible substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of parallel cracks formed in accordance with two crystal cleave planes in the semiconductor layer, the cracks being spaced apart by intercrack distances in two dimensions as determined by applying a particular strain to form dot structures; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a dielectric material formed in the cracks between and over the dot structures on the semiconductor layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein dot structures include nanodots or quantum dots.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the cracks extend through an entire thickness of the semiconductor layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein a width and a length of each dot is determined by the intercrack distances in the two dimensions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the dot structures are doped to change conductivity.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising an electronic or photonic device formed with the dot structures.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the dielectric material includes an oxide of the semiconductor layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the semiconductor layer includes monocrystalline silicon.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the flexible substrate includes a polymeric material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A nanostructure device, comprising:
<claim-text>a flexible substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a monocrystalline semiconductor layer formed on the flexible substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of parallel nanowires extending along a crystal cleave plane in the semiconductor layer, the nanowires having a thickness and a width, the width including an intercrack distance determined in accordance with a particular strain applied to the semiconductor layer to form the cracks;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an oxide formed between and over the nanowires to passivate and isolate adjacent nanowires; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an electronic device or photonic device formed on the nanowires.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of parallel nanowires are cracked along a second crystal cleave plane in the semiconductor layer to form dot structures.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the nanowires are doped to change conductivity.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the semiconductor layer includes monocrystalline silicon and the flexible substrate includes a polymeric material. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
