<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624324-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624324</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13572337</doc-number>
<date>20120810</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>29</main-group>
<subgroup>423</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>21</main-group>
<subgroup>28</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257368</main-classification>
<further-classification>257288</further-classification>
<further-classification>257412</further-classification>
<further-classification>257E29116</further-classification>
<further-classification>257E29128</further-classification>
<further-classification>257E21177</further-classification>
<further-classification>257E21182</further-classification>
<further-classification>438151</further-classification>
<further-classification>438197</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Connecting through vias to devices</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7868425</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kondo et al.</name>
<date>20110100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257616</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0173738</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kondo et al.</name>
<date>20050800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257262</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0239241</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ouyang et al.</name>
<date>20051000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438197</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0108363</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Forbes et al.</name>
<date>20090400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257368</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0018032</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kondo et al.</name>
<date>20110100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257192</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2013/0017642</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Milgrew et al.</name>
<date>20130100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438 49</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257288</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257368</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257412</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E29128</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E29116</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E21182</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E21177</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438151</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438197</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chen</last-name>
<first-name>Ming-Fa</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taichung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wang</last-name>
<first-name>Yu-Young</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Jan</last-name>
<first-name>Sen-Bor</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tainan</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chen</last-name>
<first-name>Ming-Fa</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taichung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wang</last-name>
<first-name>Yu-Young</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Jan</last-name>
<first-name>Sen-Bor</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tainan</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Slater &#x26; Matsil, L.L.P.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company, Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Hsin-Chu</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Mandala</last-name>
<first-name>Victor A</first-name>
<department>2826</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Methods and devices for connecting a through via and a terminal of a transistor formed of a strained silicon material are provided. The terminal, which can be a source or a drain of a NMOS or a PMOS transistor, is formed within a substrate. A first contact within a first inter-layer dielectric (ILD) layer over the substrate is formed over and connected to the terminal. A through via extends through the first ILD layer into the substrate. A second contact is formed over and connected to the first contact and the through via within a second ILD layer and a contact etch stop layer (CESL). The second ILD layer is over the CESL, and the CESL is over the first ILD layer, which are all below a first inter-metal dielectric (IMD) layer and the first metal layer of the transistor.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="152.48mm" wi="196.77mm" file="US08624324-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="200.32mm" wi="117.26mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624324-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="210.90mm" wi="131.15mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624324-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="208.87mm" wi="114.64mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624324-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="208.20mm" wi="157.14mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624324-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="200.66mm" wi="168.40mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624324-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application relates to the following co-pending and commonly assigned patent application: Ser. No. 13/457,823, filed Apr. 27, 2012, entitled &#x201c;Through-Substrate Vias and Methods for Forming the Same.&#x201d;</p>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Since the invention of the integrated circuit (IC), the semiconductor industry has experienced rapid growth due to continuous improvements in the integration density of semiconductor devices (e.g., transistors, diodes, resistors, capacitors, etc.) and continuous reduction in the critical dimension (CD) of semiconductor devices. With the continuous reduction of the CD of semiconductor devices, the scale of the gate, source and drain of a transistor decreases accordingly, which results in the decrease of carriers that determine the magnitude of the current in the transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In various techniques to improve the performance of transistors, one method is to apply mechanical stress to the channel of a transistor to increase the carrier mobility and to reduce resistance. Strained silicon transistors are a result of the application of such a method.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">On the other hand, the integration improvements and reductions on CD of semiconductor devices are essentially two-dimensional (2D) in nature, in that the volume occupied by the integrated devices is essentially on the surface of the semiconductor wafer. Although dramatic improvements in lithography have resulted in considerable improvement in 2D IC formation, there are physical limits to the density that can be achieved in two dimensions.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In an attempt to further increase circuit density, three-dimensional (3D) ICs have been investigated. In a typical formation process of a 3D IC, two dies are bonded together and electrical connections are formed between each die and contact pads on a substrate. For example, one attempt involved bonding two dies on top of each other. The stacked dies are then bonded to a carrier substrate and wire bonds electrically coupled contact pads on each die to contact pads on the carrier substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In a 3D IC, the two dies may be bonded together on top of each other using various means such as through vias, e.g., through silicon vias (TSVs) or through-substrate vias. Generally, a through via is formed by etching a vertical via through a substrate and filling the via with a conductive material, such as copper.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">For a more complete understanding of the present disclosure, and the advantages thereof, reference is now made to the following descriptions taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-5</figref> illustrate various intermediate stages of a process for forming a connection between a strained silicon transistor and a through via in accordance with an embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Corresponding numerals and symbols in the different figures generally refer to corresponding parts unless otherwise indicated. The figures are drawn to clearly illustrate the relevant aspects of the various embodiments and are not necessarily drawn to scale.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF ILLUSTRATIVE EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The making and using of the embodiments are discussed in detail below. It should be appreciated, however, that the present disclosure provides many applicable inventive concepts that can be embodied in a wide variety of specific contexts. The specific embodiments discussed are merely illustrative of specific ways to make and use the disclosure, and do not limit the scope of the disclosure. Throughout the various views and illustrative embodiments, like reference numbers are used to designate like elements.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In the following description, embodiments are disclosed in the context of forming a connection between a through silicon via used in forming a three-dimensional integrated circuit (3D IC) and a terminal of a strained silicon transistor of a circuit. The connection is made by contacts formed in a first inter-layer dielectric (ILD) layer over a substrate, a contact etch stop layer (CESL) over the first ILD layer, and a second ILD layer over the CESL, which are all below a first inter-metal dielectric (IMD) layer and the first metal layer of the transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a substrate <b>101</b> is provided. The substrate <b>101</b> may be a part of a circuit, a device, a die, or a wafer. The substrate <b>101</b> may comprise, for example, bulk silicon, doped or undoped, or an active layer of a semiconductor-on-insulator (SOI) substrate. Generally, an SOI substrate comprises a layer of a semiconductor material, such as silicon, formed on an insulator layer. The insulator layer may be, for example, a buried oxide (BOX) layer or a silicon oxide layer, provided on a substrate, typically a silicon or glass substrate. Other substrates, such as a multi-layered or gradient substrate, or substrates comprising compound semiconductor substrates, e.g., gallium arsenide, or alloy semiconductor substrate, e.g., silicon-germanium, may also be used. The substrate <b>101</b> has a front side where a transistor <b>100</b> and other devices may be formed, and a backside opposite to the front side.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">A plurality of shallow trench isolations (STIs) <b>109</b>, or other isolation structures, may be formed in the substrate <b>101</b> to isolate device regions. The STIs <b>109</b> may be formed by etching substrate <b>101</b> using photolithography techniques to form recesses. Generally, photolithography involves depositing a photoresist material, which is then masked, exposed, and developed. After the photoresist mask is patterned, an etching process may be performed to remove unwanted portions of the substrate <b>101</b>. In an embodiment in which the substrate <b>101</b> comprises bulk silicon, the etching process may be a wet or dry, anisotropic or isotropic, etch process. The recesses are then filled with a dielectric material such as an oxide layer formed by any oxidation process, such as wet or dry thermal oxidation in an ambient comprising an oxide, H<sub>2</sub>O, NO, or a combination thereof, or by chemical vapor deposition (CVD) techniques using tetra-ethyl-ortho-silicate (TEOS) and oxygen as a precursor. A planarization step may be performed to planarize the surface of the isolation material with a top surface of the substrate <b>101</b>. The planarization step may be accomplished, for example, using a chemical mechanical polishing (CMP) process known and used in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">A well <b>102</b>, where the source and drain of a transistor may be formed within, may be formed between two STIs <b>109</b>. There is only one well <b>102</b> shown for one transistor <b>100</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, while there may be many wells for many transistors in an actual device. In an embodiment, the well <b>102</b> may be a p-type well to host the source and drain of a NMOS transistor <b>100</b>. Alternatively, the well <b>102</b> may be an n-type well to host the source and drain of a PMOS transistor <b>100</b>. In an embodiment, a high temperature thermal procedure may be performed, such as an annealing procedure, to drive and to activate the dopants in the p-type well or the n-type well <b>102</b>. For example, in an embodiment, the well <b>102</b> may be formed by implanting p-type ions, such as boron ions, at a dose of about 1E12 to about 1E14 atoms/cm<sup>2 </sup>and at an energy of about 20 KeV to about 500 KeV. In an embodiment, the well may have a depth of about 10,000 &#x212b; to about 30,000 &#x212b; and a width of about 3,000 &#x212b; to about 10,000 &#x212b;. Other embodiments may utilize different depths, widths, and/or doping parameters.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Two terminals <b>103</b> of the transistor <b>100</b>, which are the source and the drain of the transistor <b>100</b>, may be formed within the well <b>102</b>. The transistor <b>100</b> may be a NMOS transistor or a PMOS transistor. The region <b>104</b> between the two terminals <b>103</b> is the channel for the transistor <b>100</b>. A recess for a terminal <b>103</b> may be first etched into the well <b>102</b>. The etching of the recess may be performed by a dry plasma etching process. In an embodiment, where the substrate <b>101</b> is a silicon substrate, the plasma etching process may employ fluorine chemistry. After forming the recess in the well <b>102</b>, selective epitaxy may be performed to form the terminal <b>103</b>. A terminal <b>103</b> may be either the source or the drain of the transistor <b>100</b>. The epitaxially grown material for the terminal <b>103</b> may be a lattice-mismatched semiconductor material having a different lattice constant from that of the substrate <b>101</b> material. The lattice-mismatched material for the terminals <b>103</b> may be referred as a strained silicon material.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In an embodiment, the transistor <b>100</b> is a PMOS transistor and the lattice-mismatched material, or the strained silicon material for the terminals <b>103</b>, may be silicon germanium with a composition Si<sub>1-x</sub>Ge<sub>x</sub>, where x may be within a range of about 0.1 to about 0.3. In another embodiment, the transistor <b>100</b> is an NMOS transistor and the lattice-mismatched material or the strained silicon material for the terminals <b>103</b> may be silicon carbon or silicon-germanium-carbon (Si1-x-yGexCy) where the mole fraction of carbon y is greater than a tenth of the mole fraction of germanium x. In an embodiment, the lattice-mismatched material such as silicon germanium may be grown by CVD using Si<sub>2</sub>H<sub>6 </sub>(disilane) and GeH<sub>4 </sub>(germane) as source gases, with a substrate temperature of 600 to 900 degrees C., a Si<sub>2</sub>H<sub>6 </sub>partial pressure of 30 mPa, and a GeH<sub>4 </sub>partial pressure of 60 mPa. There may be other ways to grow the silicon germanium or any other strained silicon material for the terminals <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The strained silicon material for the terminals <b>103</b> is a form of silicon in which a tensile strain is applied to the silicon lattice as a result of the difference in the dimensionalities of the strained silicon lattice and the lattice of the underlying silicon material on which it is formed. In an embodiment, the silicon germanium lattice for the terminals <b>103</b> is more widely spaced than a pure silicon lattice for the substrate <b>101</b>, with the spacing becoming wider as the percentage of germanium increases. Because the silicon lattice aligns with the larger silicon germanium lattice during formation, a tensile strain is formed to the silicon layer for the terminals <b>103</b> that the silicon atoms are pulled apart from one another. Consequently, carrier mobility is dramatically increased in strained silicon compared to relaxed silicon, providing a potential increase in mobility of 80% or more for electrons and 20% or more for holes across the channel.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">A gate insulating layer <b>118</b> may be formed on the surface of the substrate <b>101</b>. The gate insulating layer <b>118</b> may be grown by thermal oxidation, or may be deposited by CVD. In an embodiment, the gate insulating layer <b>118</b> may have a thickness of range between about 3 &#x212b; and about 50 &#x212b;. In an embodiment, a silicon oxide layer may be used as the gate insulating layer for a gate formed of polysilicon material. The gate insulating layer <b>118</b> may be another material such as an oxide-nitride-oxide (ONO). In an embodiment, the gate insulating layer <b>118</b> may be a high dielectric layer with a dielectric constant that is greater than about 10 and may have a dielectric constant that is from about 15 to about 25. The gate insulating layer <b>118</b> may be a material selected from the group consisting of hafnium oxide (HfO), hafnium silicon oxide (HfSiO), hafnium oxide nitride (HfON), and similar materials. In an alternative embodiment, the gate insulating layer <b>118</b> may be formed from a material having a relative permittivity greater than about 5. Examples of such materials include aluminum oxide, lanthanum oxide, zirconium oxide, or combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">A gate electrode <b>117</b> may be formed over the gate insulating layer <b>118</b>. The thickness of the gate electrode <b>117</b> may be in a range between about 500 &#x212b; and about 2000 &#x212b;. In an embodiment, the gate electrode <b>117</b> may comprise polysilicon. In an alternative embodiment, the gate electrode may comprise another material such as polycrystalline silicon germanium. Alternatively, the gate electrode <b>117</b> may be a metal gate instead of a polysilicon gate. In one embodiment, the metal gate electrode <b>117</b> may comprise hafnium, zirconium, titanium, tantalum, aluminum or an alloy or metal carbide thereof. Metal carbide may be hafnium carbide, zirconium carbide, titanium carbide, tantalum carbide, aluminum carbide or the like. In another embodiment, the metal gate electrode <b>117</b> may be formed of a conductive material, such as a metal silicide (e.g., titanium silicide, cobalt silicide, nickel silicide, tantalum silicide), a metal nitride (e.g., titanium nitride, tantalum nitride), doped poly-crystalline silicon or poly-crystalline silicon germanium, or any other conductive materials. Combinations of these materials can be used.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">A lithography step may then be performed followed by an etching step using a photoresist mask as an etch mask to form a gate stack comprising the gate insulating layer <b>118</b> and the gate electrode <b>117</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The etching masks may comprise an antireflective coating (BARC) hard mask layer.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Gate barriers <b>115</b> may be formed on the sides of the gate electrode <b>117</b> and gate insulating layer <b>118</b>. In an embodiment, the gate barriers <b>115</b> may be formed by CVD of a dielectric material, e.g., silicon oxide or silicon nitride, followed by an anisotropic etching of the dielectric material. In another embodiment, the gate barriers <b>115</b> may be a composite barrier comprising a dielectric liner and a barrier body. The dielectric liner may be formed by the deposition of a dielectric liner material, e.g., silicon oxide, and the barrier body material, e.g. silicon nitride, followed by an anisotropic etch using reactive ion etching. In another embodiment, the liner may be an oxide and the barrier body may be a nitride.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">A first inter-layer dielectric (ILD) layer <b>111</b> may be formed over the substrate <b>101</b>. The gate stack of the gate insulating layer <b>118</b>, the gate electrode <b>117</b>, and the gate barrier <b>115</b> may be contained within the first ILD layer <b>111</b>. The first ILD layer <b>111</b> may comprise a low dielectric constant (k value less than about 3.0) or an extreme low dielectric constant (k value less than about 2.5). For example, the first ILD layer <b>111</b> may comprise an oxide, SiO<sub>2</sub>, borophosphosilicate glass (BPSG), TEOS, spin-on glass (SOG), undoped silicate glass (USG), fluorinated silicate glass (FSG), high-density plasma (HDP) oxide, or plasma-enhanced TEOS (PETEOS), as examples. A planarization process, such as a CMP process, may be performed to planarize the first ILD layer <b>111</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">A plurality of contacts <b>113</b> may be formed within the first ILD layer <b>111</b>. The contacts <b>113</b> may be formed over the terminals <b>103</b>, i.e., the source and the drain. Contacts <b>113</b> are connected to the terminals <b>103</b>. Contacts <b>113</b> may be formed by, etching recesses from a top surface of the first ILD layer <b>111</b> to reach the terminals <b>103</b>. A thin barrier layer (not shown) may be deposited over the sidewalls of the recesses, such as by CVD, atomic layer deposition (ALD), physical vapor deposition (PVD), thermal oxidation, or a combination thereof. The barrier layer may comprise a nitride or an oxynitride, such as titanium nitride, titanium oxynitride, tantalum nitride, tantalum oxynitride, tungsten nitride, a combination thereof, and/or the like. A conductive material may be deposited over the thin barrier layer and in the recess to form the contacts <b>113</b>. The conductive material may be formed by an electro-chemical plating process, CVD, ALD, PVD, a combination thereof, and/or the like. The conductive materials may be selected from the group comprising copper, tungsten, aluminum, silver, gold, a combination thereof, and/or the like. The contacts may be formed of a compound comprising a semiconductor material and a metal such as cobalt (Co) or nickel (Ni). Excess conductive material and barrier layer may be removed by, for example, CMP, thereby forming the contacts <b>113</b> in connection with the terminals <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">A through via <b>121</b> may be formed between two STIs <b>109</b>, within the first ILD layer and into the substrate. The through via <b>121</b> may be a through silicon via, a through-substrate via, or some other kinds of through via. The through via <b>121</b> may be formed by etching an opening from a top surface of the first ILD layer <b>111</b> into the substrate <b>101</b>. The depth of the opening may be in a range of about 10 um&#x2dc;300 um and the width of through via <b>121</b> may be in a range of about 1 um&#x2dc;30 um. A liner <b>105</b> may be formed over the first ILD layer <b>111</b> and the substrate <b>101</b> in the opening, covering the sidewalls and bottom of the opening. The liner <b>105</b> may be either TEOS or silicon nitride, or any suitable dielectric materials. The liner <b>105</b> may be formed using a plasma enhanced chemical vapor deposition (PECVD) process, or other methods such as PVD or a thermal process. A thin barrier layer <b>107</b> may be deposited over the liner <b>105</b>, using methods such as by CVD, ALD, PVD, thermal oxidation, or a combination thereof. The barrier layer <b>107</b> may comprise a nitride or an oxynitride, such as titanium nitride, titanium oxynitride, tantalum nitride, tantalum oxynitride, tungsten nitride, or a combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">A conductive material may be deposited in the opening over the thin barrier layer <b>107</b> to form the through via <b>121</b>. The conductive material may be formed by an electro-chemical plating process, CVD, ALD, PVD, or a combination thereof. The conductive material may be selected from a group consisting copper, tungsten, aluminum, silver, gold, a combination thereof, and/or the like. Excess conductive material and barrier layer may be removed by, for example, CMP, thereby forming the through via <b>121</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The through via <b>121</b> may be used to connect two dies on top of each other. The through via <b>121</b> may be either electrically connected to an electrical device, e.g., such as the transistor <b>100</b>, or may be electrically coupled to an external electrical connection on the front side of the substrate <b>101</b>. The through via <b>121</b> may act as a pass-through via, allowing devices coupled to the front side of the substrate <b>101</b> to electrically communicate to devices coupled to the backside of the substrate <b>101</b>, or to communicate with devices of a different die.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">A contact etch stop layer (CESL) <b>119</b> may be formed over the first ILD layer <b>111</b>, the contacts <b>113</b>, the gate electrode <b>117</b>, and the through via <b>121</b>, to act as a high stress layer. The CESL <b>119</b> may be blanket formed of silicon nitride, silicon carbide, silicon oxide, or any other high-stress material. The stress may be compressive or tensile in nature and may have a magnitude in the range of 0.1 to 4 giga-pascals (GPa). The CESL <b>119</b> may be formed by a CVD process. The CVD process can be a low-pressure CVD (LPCVD) process or a PECVD process, as commonly known and used in the art. The stress applied on the CESL generates tensile or compressive strain in the channel of the transistor <b>100</b> on the semiconductor substrate to improve the carrier mobility further.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a second inter-layer dielectric (ILD) layer <b>121</b> may be formed over the CESL <b>119</b>. The second ILD layer <b>121</b> may comprise a low dielectric constant (k value less than about 3.0) or an extreme low dielectric constant (k value less than about 2.5). In an embodiment, the second ILD layer <b>121</b> may comprise an oxide, SiO<sub>2</sub>, BPSG, TEOS, SOG, USG, FSG, HDP oxide, or PETEOS. A planarization process, such as a CMP process, may be performed to planarize the second ILD layer <b>121</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, contacts <b>123</b>, <b>125</b>, and <b>127</b> may be formed in the second ILD layer <b>121</b> and the CESL <b>119</b>. Openings through the second ILD layer <b>121</b> and the CESL <b>119</b> may be formed by photolithography techniques by depositing and patterning a photoresist layer to expose a portion of the second ILD layer <b>121</b> and the CESL <b>119</b> corresponding to the desired position of the openings. Thereafter, the second ILD layer <b>121</b> and the CESL <b>119</b> may be etched using an anisotropic etching process. The contact <b>123</b>, <b>125</b>, and <b>127</b> may be formed with a conductive material selected from a group consisting copper, tungsten, aluminum, silver, gold, or a combination thereof. Excessive amounts of the conductive material may be removed from the top surface of the second ILD layer <b>121</b> using a planarization process, such as a CMP process.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In an embodiment, the contact <b>127</b> is formed over a contact <b>113</b> and the through via <b>121</b>. The contact <b>127</b> connects the through via <b>121</b> with one contact <b>113</b> in the first ILD layer <b>111</b>, which is further connected to a terminal <b>103</b> in the substrate <b>101</b>. Therefore an electrical connection may be formed between the through via <b>121</b> and the terminal <b>103</b>, going through the contact <b>127</b> in the CESL <b>119</b> and the second ILD layer <b>121</b>, and the contact <b>113</b> in the first ILD layer <b>111</b>. The terminal <b>103</b> may be the source or the drain of the transistor <b>100</b>. The contact <b>125</b> is connected to the gate electrode <b>117</b>. The contact <b>123</b> is connected to another terminal <b>103</b> of the transistor <b>100</b>. The contact <b>125</b> and the contact <b>123</b> connect the transistor source or drain, and gate to other part of the circuit, while the contact <b>127</b> connects to the through via which may be further connected to devices of other die.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, an etching stop layer (ESL) <b>129</b> may be formed over the second ILD layer <b>121</b>, covering the contacts <b>123</b>, <b>125</b>, and <b>127</b>. The ESL <b>129</b> may be formed by a thin film growing technique. The ESL <b>129</b> may be made of an oxide material, a nitride material or a carbon-based diamond material. The ESL <b>129</b> may be formed by a CVD process. The CVD process can be a LPCVD process or a PECVD process, as commonly known and used in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a first metal layer M<sub>1 </sub>may be formed over the ESL <b>129</b>. The first metal layer M<sub>1 </sub>may comprise a layer of conductive wiring comprising conductive lines <b>135</b> and vias <b>133</b>. The conductive lines <b>135</b> and vias <b>133</b> are formed in an inter-metal dielectric (IMD) layer <b>131</b> which is over the ESL <b>129</b>. The conductive lines <b>135</b> may be formed of any conductive material selected from a group consisting copper, tungsten, aluminum, silver, gold, a combination thereof, and/or the like. The IMD layer <b>131</b> may comprise a low dielectric constant or an extreme low dielectric constant (ELK) material, such as an oxide, SiO<sub>2</sub>, BPSG, TEOS, SOG, USG, FSG, HDP oxide, or PETEOS. A planarization process, such as a CMP process, may be performed to planarize the IMD layer <b>131</b>. The conductive lines <b>135</b> and vias <b>133</b> may be formed, e.g., using a plating and etching process or through a damascene or dual-damascene process, in which openings are etched into the corresponding dielectric layer and the openings are filled with a conductive material.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, a second metal layer M<sub>2 </sub>may be formed over the first metal layer M<sub>1</sub>. The second metal layer M<sub>2 </sub>may comprise a layer of conductive wiring comprising conductive lines <b>145</b> and vias <b>143</b>. The conductive lines <b>145</b> and vias <b>143</b> are formed in an IMD layer <b>141</b> which is over the IMD layer <b>131</b>. The conductive lines <b>145</b> may be formed of any conductive material selected from a group consisting copper, tungsten, aluminum, silver, gold, a combination thereof, and/or the like. The IMD layer <b>141</b> may comprise a low dielectric constant or an extreme low dielectric constant (ELK) material, such as an oxide, SiO<sub>2</sub>, BPSG, TEOS, SOG, USG, FSG, HDP oxide, or PETEOS. A planarization process, such as a CMP process, may be performed to planarize the IMD layer <b>141</b>. The conductive lines <b>145</b> and vias <b>143</b> may be formed, e.g., using a plating and etching process or through a damascene or dual-damascene process, in which openings are etched into the corresponding dielectric layer and the openings are filled with a conductive material.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Generally, more metallization layers M<sub>3</sub>-M<sub>n </sub>comprising conductive lines and vias to electrically couple individual devices may further be formed over the second metal layer M<sub>2</sub>. The layers of conductive lines and vias may be formed in layers of IMD layers. In an embodiment the metallization layers M<sub>3</sub>-M<sub>n </sub>may be formed of copper, although other materials, such as tungsten, aluminum, gold, or the like, could alternatively be utilized. On top of the metallization layers, a passivation layer having external contacts may be formed. The external contacts may include an under-bump metallization (UBM) structure.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Although the present disclosure and its advantages have been described in detail, it should be understood that various changes, substitutions and alterations can be made herein without departing from the spirit and scope of the disclosure as defined by the appended claims. Moreover, the scope of the present application is not intended to be limited to the particular embodiments of the process, machine, manufacture, and composition of matter, means, methods and steps described in the specification. As one of ordinary skill in the art will readily appreciate from the disclosure of the present disclosure processes, machines, manufacture, compositions of matter, means, methods, or steps, presently existing or later to be developed, that perform substantially the same function or achieve substantially the same result as the corresponding embodiments described herein may be utilized according to the present disclosure. Accordingly, the appended claims are intended to include within their scope such processes, machines, manufacture, compositions of matter, means, methods, or steps.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A device comprising:
<claim-text>a terminal of a transistor formed of a strained silicon material and formed within a substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first contact over the terminal and connected to the terminal, formed within a first inter-layer dielectric (ILD) layer over the substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a through via extending through the first ILD layer into the substrate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second contact over the first contact and the through via, connected to the first contact and the through via, and formed within a second ILD layer and a contact etch stop layer (CESL), wherein the second ILD layer is over the CESL, and the CESL is over the first ILD layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a gate of the transistor formed within the first ILD layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third contact over the gate and connected to the gate, formed within the second ILD layer and the CESL;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a via over the third contact and connected to the third contact; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a metal contact of a first metal layer over the via and connected to the via.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>an etching stop layer (ESL) over the second ILD layer and a first inter-metal dielectric (IMD) layer over the ESL, wherein the via goes through the ESL and the first IMD layer in contact with the third contact.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the transistor is a NMOS transistor or a PMOS transistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the terminal is a source or a drain of the transistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the substrate comprises a material selected from a group consisting essentially of a doped bulk silicon substrate, an undoped bulk silicon substrate, a semiconductor-on-insulator (SOI) substrate, a compound semiconductor substrate, or an alloy semiconductor substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the strained silicon material comprises a silicon germanium, or a silicon-germanium-carbon.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the through via comprises a conductive material selected from a group consisting essentially of copper, tungsten, aluminum, silver, gold, or a combination thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the through via comprises a liner and a barrier layer around the through via extending through the first ILD layer into the substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first ILD layer and the second ILD layer comprise a material selected from a group consisting essentially of an oxide, SiO<sub>2</sub>, borophosphosilicate glass (BPSG), tetraethylorthosilicate (TEOS), spin-on glass (SOG), undoped silicate glass (USG), fluorinated silicate glass (FSG), high-density plasma (HDP) oxide, or plasma-enhanced TEOS (PETEOS).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first contact and the second contact comprise a conductive material selected from a group consisting essentially of copper, tungsten, aluminum, silver, gold, or a combination thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the CESL comprises a material selected from a group consisting essentially of silicon nitride, silicon carbide, silicon oxide, or other high-stress material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the gate comprises a gate insulating layer and a gate electrode.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the gate electrode is a metal gate electrode comprises a material selected from a group consisting essentially of hafnium, zirconium, titanium, tantalum, aluminum, a metal carbide, a metal silicide, a metal nitride, or a combination thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A method of manufacturing a device, comprising:
<claim-text>forming a terminal of a transistor within a substrate using a strained silicon material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first inter-layer dielectric (ILD) layer over the substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first contact within the first ILD layer, wherein the first contact is over the terminal and connected to the terminal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a through via extending through the first ILD layer into the substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a contact etch stop layer (CESL) over the first ILD layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second ILD layer over the CESL; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second contact within the second ILD layer and the CESL, wherein the second contact is over the first contact and the through via and connected to the first contact and the through via.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>forming a gate of the transistor within the first ILD layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a third contact within the second ILD layer and the CESL, wherein the third contact is over the gate and connected to the gate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a via over the third contact and connected to the third contact; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a metal contact of a first metal layer over the via and connected to the via.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>forming an etching stop layer (ESL) over the second ILD layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first inter-metal dielectric (IMD) layer over the ESL; wherein the via goes through the ESL and the first IMD layer in contact with the third contact.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the transistor is a NMOS transistor or a PMOS transistor, and the terminal is a source or a drain of the transistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the strained silicon material comprises a silicon germanium, or a silicon-germanium-carbon.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. A device comprising:
<claim-text>a terminal of a transistor formed of a strained silicon material and formed within a substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first contact over the terminal and connected to the terminal, formed within a first inter-layer dielectric (ILD) layer over the substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a gate of the transistor formed within the first ILD layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a through via extending through the first ILD layer into the substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second contact over the first contact and the through via, connected to the first contact and the through via, and formed within a second ILD layer and a contact etch stop layer (CESL), wherein the second ILD layer is over the CESL, and the CESL is over the first ILD layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third contact over the gate and connected to the gate, formed within the second ILD layer and the CESL;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a via over the third contact and connected to the third contact; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a metal contact of a first metal layer over the via and connected to the via.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
