<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622771-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622771</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13159454</doc-number>
<date>20110614</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>391</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20110101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>24</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439660</main-classification>
<further-classification>439884</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Electrical connector having versatile contact mating surfaces</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7390219</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Hai</name>
<date>20080600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7963806</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Kline et al.</name>
<date>20110600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439660</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2002/0055286</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>MacDougall et al.</name>
<date>20020500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439108</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>13</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110306249</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20111215</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Pan</last-name>
<first-name>Feng</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kunshan</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Pan</last-name>
<first-name>Feng</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kunshan</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chang</last-name>
<first-name>Ming Chieh</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chung</last-name>
<first-name>Wei Te</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Zarroli</last-name>
<first-name>Michael</first-name>
<department>2833</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An electrical contact (<b>22</b>) includes a first beam (<b>28</b>), a second beam (<b>29</b>), and a receiving cavity (<b>20</b>) defined between the first beam and the second beam. The first beam has a first mating face (<b>281</b>) facing to the receiving cavity, and the second beam has a second mating face (<b>291</b>) facing to the receiving cavity. The first mating face cooperates with the second mating face to form a first mating area to clamp a first area of a mating contact. The first beam has a third mating face (<b>282</b>). The third mating face forms a second mating area facing sidewardly to abut against a second area of a mating contact. The first beam projects sidewardly to form the third mating face.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="112.86mm" wi="321.48mm" file="US08622771-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="190.75mm" wi="166.54mm" file="US08622771-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="218.95mm" wi="168.49mm" file="US08622771-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="182.96mm" wi="150.79mm" file="US08622771-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="156.13mm" wi="165.78mm" file="US08622771-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="147.49mm" wi="163.24mm" file="US08622771-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to an electrical contact and an electrical connector having such electrical contact for communication applications.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Arts</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In communication applications, a header connector and a receptacle connector mating with the header connector are widely used for transmitting high speed signals. Generally, the header connector comprises a plurality of header contacts each having a flat shape, and the receptacle connector comprises a plurality of receptacle contacts each having a bifurcated shape or dual beams for mating with the header contact. There are two mating types between header contacts and receptacle contacts, namely broadside couple and edge couple.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">U.S. Pat. No. 7,390,219, issued on Jun. 24, 2008, to Pan discloses a receptacle having edge couple contacts. According to the disclosure, the receptacle comprises a plurality of contacts disposed in a vertical plane. Each of the contacts comprises a bifurcated mating portion defining a mating slot. The bifurcated mating portion comprises a pair of contact surfaces facing to the mating slot for edge coupling with a mating header contact.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The edge-coupling receptacle has no way to provide a broadside couple with the mating connector. Therefore, the applications of the receptacle are restricted</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Hence, an improved cable connector assembly is desired to offer advantages over the related art.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">An object of the present invention is to provide an electrical contact and an electrical connector having the same that can broadside couple or edge couple with a mating connector.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">To achieve the above-mentioned object, an electrical connector comprises a housing, and at least one contact module mounted on the housing. The at least one contact module comprises an insulative body, and a plurality of contacts retained on the insulative body. Each of the contacts has a fork portion extending beyond the insulative body. Each of the fork portions comprises a first beam, a second beam, and a receiving cavity defined between the first and the second beams. The first beam has a first mating face facing to the receiving cavity, and the second beam has a second mating face facing to the receiving cavity. The first mating face cooperates with the second mating face to form a first mating area to clamp a first area of a mating contact. The first beam has a third mating face. The third mating face forms a second mating area facing sidewardly to abut against a second area of a mating contact. The first mating area and the second area are selectively mating with a mating contact.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to the present invention, an electrical contact comprises a first beam, a second beam, and a receiving cavity defined between the first beam and the second beam. The first beam has a first mating face facing to the receiving cavity, and the second beam has a second mating face facing to the receiving cavity. The first mating face cooperates with the second mating face to form a first mating area to clamp a first area of a mating contact. The first beam has a third mating face. The third mating face forms a second mating area facing sidewardly to abut against a second area of a mating contact. The first mating area and the second mating area are selectively mating with the different areas of a mating contact.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to the present invention, the electrical contact and an electrical connector having the same provide a first mating area and a second mating area selectively mating with mating contacts. The first mating area can provide an edge couple, and the second mating area can provide a broadside couple. Therefore, the applications of the electrical contact and the electrical connector having the same are improved.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWING</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of an electrically connector in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a partly exploded view of the electrical connector as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view of a contact module of the electrical connector in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a side view of the contact module showing a contact of the contact module edge coupled with a contact of a mating connector; and</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a top view of the contact module showing a contact of the contact module broadside coupled with a contact of a mating connector.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Reference will now be made in detail to a preferred embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, an electrical connector <b>100</b> comprises an insulative housing <b>1</b>, and a plurality of contact modules <b>2</b> arranged side to side and received in the insulative housing <b>1</b>. The insulative housing <b>1</b> comprises a mating face <b>11</b>, a mounting face <b>12</b> opposite to the mating face <b>11</b>, and a plurality of contact holes <b>13</b> through the mating face <b>11</b> and the mounting face <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The contact modules <b>2</b> are mounted to the insulative housing <b>1</b> from the mounting face <b>12</b> side. Each of the contact module <b>2</b> comprises an insulative body <b>21</b>, and a plurality of contacts <b>22</b> assembled, e.g. insert molded, to the insulative body <b>21</b>. The contacts <b>22</b> of each contact module <b>2</b> are substantially arranged in a vertical plane. Each of the contacts <b>22</b> comprises a middle portion (not shown) embed in the insulative body <b>21</b>, a fork portion <b>24</b> extending forwardly from the middle portion and beyond the insulative body <b>21</b>, and a tail portion <b>25</b> extending downwardly from the middle portion and beyond the insulative body <b>21</b>. The fork portion <b>24</b> comprises a first base <b>26</b>, a second base <b>27</b>, a first beam <b>28</b> extending forwardly from the first base <b>26</b> and projecting to a side direction, and a second beam <b>29</b> extending forwardly from the second base <b>27</b> and projecting to the side direction. A receiving cavity <b>20</b> is formed between a first beam <b>28</b> and a corresponding second beam <b>29</b> for receiving a contact <b>3</b> of a mating connector. A slot <b>260</b> is formed between a first base <b>26</b> and a corresponding second base <b>27</b>. The slot <b>260</b> has a dimension or height which is larger than the smallest dimension or height of the receiving cavity <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, each of the first beams <b>28</b> has a first mating face <b>281</b> facing to a corresponding receiving cavity <b>20</b>, and the second beam <b>29</b> has a second mating face <b>291</b> facing to the receiving cavity <b>20</b>. The first mating face <b>281</b> and the second face <b>291</b> are cooperated to form a first mating area. The first and the second mating faces <b>281</b>, <b>291</b> have an arcate shape so that the receiving cavity <b>20</b> is enlarged at the free end of the first and the second mating faces <b>281</b>, <b>291</b> for guiding the mating contact <b>3</b>. The height in vertical direction of the slot <b>260</b> is larger than the smallest height of the receiving cavity <b>20</b> so that the first surface <b>31</b> of the mating contact <b>3</b> is stably clamped between the first mating face <b>281</b> and the second mating face <b>291</b> to achieve an edge couple. The first mating face <b>281</b> has a width in horizontal direction not larger than the width of the first beam <b>28</b>, and the second mating face <b>291</b> has a width in horizontal direction not larger than the width of the second beam <b>29</b>. In this embodiment, the width of the first mating face <b>281</b> is equal to the width of the first beam <b>28</b>, and the width of the second mating face <b>291</b> is equal to the width of second beam <b>29</b>. Therefore, the first beam <b>28</b> can directly form the first mating face <b>281</b>, and the second beam <b>29</b> can directly form the second mating face <b>291</b>, which saves material and simplifies manufacturing.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Moreover, the first beam <b>28</b> comprises a third mating face <b>282</b> projecting to a side direction, and the second beam <b>29</b> comprises a fourth mating face <b>292</b> projecting to the side direction. The third mating face <b>282</b> and the fourth mating face <b>292</b> are disposed in a common vertical plane to form a second mating area. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the second mating area abuts against a second surface <b>32</b> of the mating contact <b>3</b> to achieve a broadside couple. The first surface <b>31</b> of the mating contact <b>3</b> is perpendicular to the second surface <b>32</b> of the mating contact <b>3</b>. In this embodiment, the second mating area becomes larger since it is formed by the third surface <b>282</b> and the fourth surface <b>292</b>. Optionally, the second mating area also could be formed by one of the third and the fourth mating faces <b>282</b>, <b>292</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The first mating area and the second area are selectively mated with the first surface <b>31</b> or second surface <b>32</b> of the mating contact. Therefore, it is unnecessary to change the structure of the electrical connector <b>100</b> to achieve side couple or edge couple. The applications of the electrical connector <b>100</b> are versatile.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">It is to be understood, however, that even though numerous characteristics and advanarmes of the present invention have been set forth in the foregoing description, together with details of the structure and function of the invention, the disclosure is illustrative only, and changes may be made in detail, especially in matters of shape, size, and arrangement of parts within the principles of the invention to the full extent indicated by the broad general meaning of the terms in which the appended claims are expressed.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An electrical connector comprising:
<claim-text>a housing; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one contact module mounted on the housing, the at least one contact module comprising an insulative body and a plurality of contacts assembled to the insulative body, each of the contacts having a fork portion extending beyond the insulative body, each of the fork portions comprising a first beam, a second beam, and a receiving cavity defined between the first and the second beams;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first beam has a first mating face facing to the receiving cavity, and the second beam has a second mating face facing to the receiving cavity,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first mating face cooperates with the second mating face to form a first mating area to clamp a first region of a mating contact;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first beam has a third mating face;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the third mating face forms a second mating area facing sidewardly to abut against a second region of a mating contact;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first beam projects sidewardly to form the third mating face.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The electrical connector as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the receiving cavity is enlarged at free ends of the first and the second beams for guiding the mating contact.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The electrical connector as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second beam projects sidewardly to form a fourth mating face, the third and the fourth mating faces cooperated to form the second mating area.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The electrical connector as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the fork portion comprises a first base and a second base, the first beam extending forwardly from the first base and projecting to a side direction, the second beam extending forwardly from the second base and projecting to the side direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The electrical connector as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein a slot is formed between the first base and the second base, the slot having a height greater than the smallest height of the receiving cavity.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The electrical connector as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first mating face has a width less than the width of the first beam, and the second mating face has a width less than the width of the second beam.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. An electrical contact comprising:
<claim-text>a first beam;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second beam; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a receiving cavity defined between the first beam and the second beam;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first beam has a first mating face facing to the receiving cavity, and the second beam has a second mating face facing to the receiving cavity;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first mating face cooperates with the second mating face to form a first mating area to clamp a first region of a mating contact;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first beam has a third mating face;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the third mating face forms a second mating area facing sidewardly to abut against a second region of a mating contact;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first beam projects sidewardly to form the third mating face.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The electrical contact as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the first beam projects sidewardly to form said third mating face.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The electrical contact as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> wherein the second beam projects sidewardly to form a fourth mating face, the third and the fourth mating faces cooperated to form the second mating area.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The electrical contact as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the receiving cavity is enlarged at free ends of the first and the second beams for guiding the mating contact.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. An electrical contact arrangement comprising:
<claim-text>first and second beams having common root section while being spaced from each other along a vertical direction in a side view to define a receiving space therebetween in said vertical direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said first and second beams defining respectively a pair of projecting configurations in the vertical direction toward each other into said receiving space under condition that said projecting configuration are formed by being directly stamped from sheet metal so as to form a first contact area facing in the vertical direction for allowing a planar section of a mating contact to be sandwiched between the pair of projections and in the receiving space; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said pair of projecting configurations being further commonly sideward projecting, by bending, in a top view so as to commonly form a second contact area facing in a transverse direction for allowing a planar section of another mating contact to abut against the second contact area sideward; wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first contact area and the second contact area are defined in two different orientations perpendicular to each other.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The electrical contact arrangement as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second beams define another sideward projection behind the projecting configuration opposite to said projecting configuration in the top view to enhance resiliency of the first and second beams.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The electrical contact arrangement as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the first contact area is defined by a thickness dimension of the first and second beams while the second contact area is defined by a planar dimension of the first and second beams. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
