<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622164-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622164</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13104068</doc-number>
<date>20110510</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-108797</doc-number>
<date>20100510</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>197</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>60</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>17</main-group>
<subgroup>354</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>180247</main-classification>
<further-classification>180246</further-classification>
<further-classification>180233</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Control apparatus for four-wheel drive vehicle, four-wheel drive vehicle, and control method</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5802489</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Orbach et al.</name>
<date>19980900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>701 50</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7793749</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Baasch et al.</name>
<date>20100900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>180247</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7806220</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Sharma et al.</name>
<date>20101000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>180247</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8042642</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Marsh et al.</name>
<date>20111000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>180247</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>11157355</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19990600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>11157356</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19990600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>11189065</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19990700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>9</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>180247</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>180246</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>180233</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110271781</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20111110</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Takaira</last-name>
<first-name>Koji</first-name>
<address>
<city>Toyota</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Takaira</last-name>
<first-name>Koji</first-name>
<address>
<city>Toyota</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Gifford, Krass, Sprinkle, Anderson &#x26; Citkowski, P.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Toyota Jidosha Kabushiki Kaisha</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Toyota-shi, Aichi-ken</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Adams</last-name>
<first-name>Tashiana</first-name>
<department>3611</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Arce</last-name>
<first-name>Marlon</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">When a count value concerning with the travel of the vehicle in a two-wheel drive state reaches or exceeds a predetermined value, the state of drive in a transfer is temporarily switched to a four-wheel drive state by connecting a synchromesh mechanism while keeping a mesh clutch disconnected, so that rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state, such as a second output shaft, are temporarily rotated. Thus, the rotary members are restrained from remaining in contact at fixed portions and therefore being partially worn. Besides, there is no need to provide a mechanism for temporarily rotating the rotary members, such as the second output shaft, separately from the synchromesh mechanism that is normally provided for the four-wheel drive travel in the related art. Therefore, it is possible to improve durability without involving cost increase, space efficiency deterioration, etc.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="241.30mm" wi="160.36mm" file="US08622164-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="254.25mm" wi="183.13mm" file="US08622164-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="210.99mm" wi="182.54mm" file="US08622164-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="243.59mm" wi="181.44mm" file="US08622164-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="162.98mm" wi="189.74mm" file="US08622164-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="237.15mm" wi="169.84mm" file="US08622164-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority to Japanese Patent Application No. 2010-108797 filed on May 10, 2010 which is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety including the specification, drawings and abstract.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The invention relates to a control apparatus for a four-wheel drive vehicle, a four-wheel drive vehicle, and a control method for a four-wheel drive vehicle that are capable of switching between a two-wheel drive state and a four-wheel drive state.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">A four-wheel drive vehicle capable of switching between a two-wheel drive state in which the vehicle travels by transmitting power only to main driving wheels and a four-wheel drive state in which the vehicle travels by transmitting power both to the main driving wheels and to auxiliary driving wheels is well known. Examples of such a vehicle include those described in Japanese Patent Application Publication No. 11-189065 (JP-A-11-189065), Japanese Patent Application Publication No. 11-157355 (JP-A-11-157355), and Japanese Patent Application Publication No. 11-157356 (JP-A-11-157356). The 4WD vehicles described in Japanese Patent Application Publication No. 11-189065 (JP-A-11-189065), Japanese Patent Application Publication No. 11-157355 (JP-A-11-157355), and Japanese Patent Application Publication No. 11-157356 (JP-A-11-157356), in particular, are constructed so that, for example, when the 2WD mode is selected, the auxiliary driving wheels that act as driven wheels during the four-wheel drive state are disconnected from a power transmission path to the auxiliary driving wheels, so that the rotary members of the power transmission path are stopped from rotating. That is, these vehicles are constructed so that during the 2WD mode, power is not transmitted to the power transmission path that is provided for the auxiliary driving wheels and, furthermore, the rotary members of the power transmission path are not rotated together with rotation of the auxiliary driving wheels that act as driven wheels during the two-wheel drive state.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">However, in a construction in which there is a rotary member that stops rotating when the two-wheel drive state is entered, the rotary member and a member that contacts the rotary member are always in contact with each other at fixed contact portions during a stop of rotation. Therefore, there may arise a risk of decline in durability due to progress of local striking wear or the like that is caused by input of vibration from outside, for example, rotating vibration from an engine or the like. Concretely, the contact between a shaft and a bearing, the contact between a chain and a gear (sprocket), etc. are conceivable. For example, in the contact between the shaft and the bearing, the rollers of the bearing have line contact at fixed portions with a contact surface (rolling surface portion) of the shaft, so that there is possibility of striking wear (fretting) or the like being caused on the fixed contact portions by input of vibration from outside. In particular, in the case where the lubricating performance of oil has declined due to stop of rotation, this problem may more conspicuously manifest itself.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">With respect to this problem, the foregoing patent application No. 11-189065 proposes that a link mechanism that links a rotary member that stops rotating when the 2WD mode is selected and a rotary member of a power transmission path to the main driving wheels is provided separately from a mechanism for the 4WD travel, and when the 2WD mode has been selected, the link mechanism is actuated on the basis of elapse of a predetermined time interval or the like so as to rotate the rotary member that stops rotating when the 2WD mode is selected, without switching the mode of drive to the 4WD mode. Besides, the foregoing patent application also proposes as still another related-art technology that, for example, in order to secure oil lubrication, the amount of oil is increased to increase the portion that is dipped into the oil, or the configuration of the ribs in the housing case is adjusted, or holes through which the oil is allowed to enter are provided, or oil is actively fed by using an oil pump, among other arrangements. However, there is possibility of drawbacks of cost increase or space efficiency deterioration related to the measure of providing the foregoing link mechanism separately from the mechanism for the 4WD travel and the like, efficiency deterioration due to a large amount of time needed for evaluation regarding various adjustments and the like, increased stirring resistance resulting from increased amount of oil, etc. These problems are not yet known to public, and no proposal has been made regarding a technology that restrains the contact at fixed portions and appropriately secures oil lubrication during the two-wheel drive state without involving drawbacks of cost increase, efficiency deterioration, etc.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The invention provides a control apparatus for a four-wheel drive vehicle, a four-wheel drive vehicle, and a control method for a four-wheel drive vehicle that are able to improve durability by restraining partial wear of a rotary member that stops rotating when the two-wheel drive state is entered.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">A first aspect of the invention relates to (a) a control apparatus for a four-wheel drive vehicle that is capable of switching a state of drive between a two-wheel drive state in which the vehicle travels by transmitting power transmitted by a drive force source only from a main drive shaft to main driving wheels and a four-wheel drive state in which the vehicle travels by transmitting the power to the main driving wheels, and also by transmitting the power from the main drive shaft to an auxiliary drive shaft through putting into a connected state a first power connection/disconnection device capable of connecting and disconnecting a power transmission path between the main drive shaft and the auxiliary drive shaft, and by transmitting the power from the auxiliary drive shaft to auxiliary driving wheels through putting into the connected state a second power connection/disconnection device capable of connecting and disconnecting a power transmission path between the auxiliary drive shaft and the auxiliary driving wheels, wherein (b) when the state of drive is switched to the two-wheel drive state, both the first power connection/disconnection device and the second power connection/disconnection device are put into a disconnected state, and (c) when a count value concerning a travel of the vehicle in the two-wheel drive state becomes equal to or greater than a predetermined value, the state of drive is temporarily switched to the four-wheel drive state by putting one of the first power connection/disconnection device and the second power connection/disconnection device into the connected state.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to the first aspect of the invention, for example, when the count value concerning the travel in the two-wheel drive state becomes equal to or greater than the predetermined value, the state of drive is temporarily switched to the four-wheel drive state as one of the first power connection/disconnection device and the second power connection/disconnection device is put into the connected state. Therefore, for example, the rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state, such as the auxiliary drive shaft and the like, are temporarily rotated, so that the contact of the rotary members at fixed portions is restrained. Hence, the partial wear of the rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state is restrained, so that durability can be improved.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Besides, since there is no need to provide a mechanism for temporarily rotating the rotary members, such as the auxiliary drive shaft and the like, separately from the mechanisms that are normally provided for the travel in the four-wheel drive state (e.g., the first power connection/disconnection device and the second power connection/disconnection device), it is possible to improve durability without involving drawbacks of cost increase, space efficiency deterioration, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Besides, for example, with a construction in which the oil gathering in a lower portion of a case is splashed upward by rotation of rotary members, such as the auxiliary drive shaft and the like, the oil is splashed upward by rotating the rotary members such as the auxiliary drive shaft and the like. Therefore, oil lubrication can be appropriately secured for the rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state, so that the partial wear of the rotary members can be further restrained and the durability can be further improved. In this case, since it is not necessary to increase the amount of oil, it is possible to improve the durability without involving drawbacks of efficiency deterioration due to an increase in the amount of oil and the like. It should be apparent that, whether the construction in which the oil is splashed upward is adopted, since the rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state, such as the auxiliary drive shaft and the like, are temporarily rotated, the contact of the rotary members at fixed portions is restrained, so that the control apparatus restrains partial wear of the rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Furthermore, if the connected state of one of the first power connection/disconnection device and the second power connection/disconnection device is maintained although the state of drive is switched to the four-wheel drive state, the vehicle as a whole remains in the two-wheel drive state in effect, so that efficiency deterioration can be restrained and changes in the vehicle behavior caused by the switching to the four-wheel drive state in effect can also be avoided.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Besides, the four-wheel drive vehicle may have a construction in which an oil for lubrication is splashed upward by rotation of the auxiliary drive shaft, and the power that is transmitted to the auxiliary drive shaft when the state of drive is temporarily switched to the four-wheel drive state may be smaller than the power for splashing the oil upward by rotation of the auxiliary drive shaft. With this construction, it is possible to restrain the efficiency deterioration resulting from the splashing up of the oil for lubrication due to rotation of the auxiliary drive shaft while restraining the partial wear of the rotary members that do not rotate, for example, during the two-wheel drive state.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Besides, when the count value concerning the travel in the two-wheel drive state becomes equal to or greater than a predetermined value, the state of drive may be temporarily switched to the four-wheel drive state by putting the first power connection/disconnection device into the connected state while maintaining the disconnected state of the second power connection/disconnection device. With this construction, for example, because only the first power connection/disconnection device is put into the connected state, the rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state, such as the auxiliary drive shaft and the like, are certainly rotated without transmitting power to the auxiliary driving wheels.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Besides, the first power connection/disconnection device may be a power connection/disconnection device that includes a synchromesh mechanism, and the second power connection/disconnection device may be a power connection/disconnection device that does not include a synchromesh mechanism. With this construction, for example, in a four-wheel drive vehicle in which the second power connection/disconnection device is not equipped with a synchromesh mechanism and therefore it is difficult to rotate the auxiliary drive shaft from the side of the auxiliary driving wheels through the driving connection therewith by putting only the second power connection/disconnection device into the connected state during the travel of the vehicle, it is possible to improve durability by restraining the partial wear of the rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state. Besides, since the second power connection/disconnection device is not equipped with a synchromesh mechanism, a simple mechanism is sufficient to construct the second power connection/disconnection device, achieving further improvements in cost cut, space efficiency, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Besides, the count value concerning the travel in the two-wheel drive state may be a cumulative travel time in the two-wheel drive state or a cumulative travel distance in the two-wheel drive state. With this construction, the state of drive can be temporarily switched to the four-wheel drive state at an appropriate timing (time) such that the rotary members that do not rotate, for example, during the two-wheel drive state, are restrained from remaining in contact at fixed portions.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Besides, the count value concerning the travel in the two-wheel drive state may be an accumulated value obtained when a value related to rotation speed of the drive force source is greater than or equal to a predetermined rotation speed. With this construction, in conjunction with the problem in which as the rotation vibration of the drive force source that is a source of vibration that causes the striking wear or the like increases with, for example, increases in the value related to the rotation speed of the drive force source, it becomes more likely that local striking wear and the like of rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state will progress, it is possible to take a measure in which when the value related to the rotation speed of the drive force source is greater than or equal to the predetermined rotation speed and therefore the foregoing striking wear and the like are likely to progress, the state of drive is able to be temporarily switched to the four-wheel drive state in an appropriate manner, depending on the then accumulated value. In other words, because the switching to the four-wheel drive state is not carried out on the basis of an accumulated value obtained when the value related to the rotation speed of the drive force source is less than the predetermined value and therefore the progress of striking wear and the like is unlikely, it is possible to restrain the efficiency deterioration caused by the temporary switching to the four-wheel drive state.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Besides, the predetermined value may be reduced with increases in a value related to rotation speed of the drive force source. With this construction, in conjunction with the problem in which as the rotation vibration of the drive force source that is a source of vibration that causes the striking wear or the like increases with, for example, increases in the value related to the rotation speed of the drive force source, it becomes more likely that local striking wear and the like of rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state will progress, it is possible to cause the temporary switch to the four-wheel drive state to be performed more readily the higher the value related to the rotation speed of the drive force source.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">A second aspect of the invention relates to a four-wheel drive vehicle that is capable of switching a state of drive between a two-wheel drive state in which the vehicle travels by transmitting power provided by a drive force source only from a main drive shaft to main driving wheels and a four-wheel drive state in which the vehicle travels by transmitting the power to the main driving wheels, and also by transmitting the power from the main drive shaft to an auxiliary drive shaft through putting into a connected state a first power connection/disconnection device capable of connecting and disconnecting a power transmission path between the main drive shaft and the auxiliary drive shaft, and by transmitting the power from the auxiliary drive shaft to auxiliary driving wheels through putting into the connected state a second power connection/disconnection device capable of connecting and disconnecting a power transmission path between the auxiliary drive shaft and the auxiliary driving wheels, the four-wheel drive vehicle including:</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">a control apparatus that puts both the first power connection/disconnection device and the second power connection/disconnection device into a disconnected state when the state of drive is switched to the two-wheel drive state, that temporarily switches the state of drive to the four-wheel drive state by putting one of the first power connection/disconnection device and the second power connection/disconnection device into the connected state when a count value concerning a travel of the vehicle in the two-wheel drive state becomes equal to or greater than a predetermined value.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">A third aspect of the invention relates to a control method for a four-wheel drive vehicle, the control method includes:</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">switching a state of drive between a two-wheel drive state in which the vehicle travels by transmitting power provided by a drive force source only from a main drive shaft to main driving wheels and a four-wheel drive state in which the vehicle travels by transmitting the power to the main driving wheels, and also by transmitting the power from the main drive shaft to an auxiliary drive shaft through putting into a connected state a first power connection/disconnection device capable of connecting and disconnecting a power transmission path between the main drive shaft and the auxiliary drive shaft, and by transmitting the power from the auxiliary drive shaft to auxiliary driving wheels through putting into the connected state a second power connection/disconnection device capable of connecting and disconnecting a power transmission path between the auxiliary drive shaft and the auxiliary driving wheels, wherein both the first power connection/disconnection device and the second power connection/disconnection device are put into a disconnected state when the state of drive is switched to the two-wheel drive state;
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0002-0001" num="0024">detecting a count value concerning a travel of the vehicle in the two-wheel drive state; and</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0002" num="0025">temporarily switching the state of drive to the four-wheel drive state by putting one of the first power connection/disconnection device and the second power connection/disconnection device into the connected state when the count value becomes equal to or greater than a predetermined value.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0026">According to the second and third aspects of the invention, for example, when the count value concerning the travel in the two-wheel drive state becomes equal to or greater than the predetermined value, the state of drive is temporarily switched to the four-wheel drive state as one of the first power connection/disconnection device and the second power connection/disconnection device is put into the connected state. Therefore, the rotary members that do not rotate, for example, during the two-wheel drive state, such as the auxiliary drive shaft and the like, are temporarily rotated, so that the contact of the rotary members at fixed portions is restrained. Hence, the partial wear of the rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state is restrained, so that durability can be improved.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0026" num="0027">The features, advantages, and technical and industrial significance of this invention will be described below with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which like numerals denote like elements, and wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram illustrating a construction of a vehicle to which the invention is applied, and is also a block diagram illustrating portions of a control system that is provided in the vehicle;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a skeleton diagram of a transfer provided in a vehicle power transmission apparatus shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a functional block diagram illustrating portions of control functions performed by an electronic control unit shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagram showing a relation (a predetermined-value map) in which the higher the engine rotation speed is, the smaller the predetermined value is made; and</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a flowchart illustrating portions of control operations of the electronic control unit, that is, a control operation for improving durability by restraining the partial wear of rotary members that do not rotate when the vehicle is in a two-wheel drive state.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0032" num="0033">In this invention, a four-wheel drive vehicle has a vehicle power transmission apparatus in a motive power transmission path between a drive force source and main driving wheels. The drive force source is, for example, an internal combustion engine that produces motive power through combustion of fuel, such as a gasoline engine, a diesel engine, etc. However, the drive force source may also be a different prime mover, such as an electric motor or the like, either alone or in combination with an engine.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0034">Preferably, the vehicle power transmission apparatus is constructed of a transmission alone, or of a torque converter and a transmission that has a plurality of gear speeds, or of a torque converter-equipped transmission and a transfer, a speed reduction mechanism portion or a differential mechanism portion. This transmission includes: a planetary gear-type automatic transmission of any one of various kinds that selectively achieves one of a plurality of gear speeds (transmission ratio step) by selectively linking rotating elements of a plurality of planetary gear devices, for example, a planetary gear-type automatic transmission of four forward speeds, five forward speeds, six forward speeds, or more forward speeds; a synchronous mesh-type parallel two-shaft transmission that includes plural pairs of speed change gears on two shafts and that selectively puts one of the pairs of speed change gears into a power transmission state by using a synchronous device; a synchronous mesh-type parallel two-shaft automatic transmission that is a kind of synchronous mesh-type parallel two-shaft transmission that is capable of automatically, switching the transmission ratio step by using a synchronous device that is driven by a hydraulic actuator; a generally termed DCT (dual clutch transmission) that is a kind of synchronous mesh-type parallel two-shaft automatic transmission that has two input shaft systems in whose input shafts are connected with their respective clutches and with speed change gears of either odd or even-numbered speeds; a generally termed belt-type continuously variable transmission in which a drive belt that functions as a power transmission member is disposed around a pair of variable pulleys whose effective diameters are variable and the speed change ratio between the pulleys is steplessly changed; a generally termed traction-type continuously variable transmission in which a plurality of rollers are sandwiched between a pair of cones rotatable about a common axis so that the rollers are rotatable about their own axes that intersect with the common axis of the two cones, and the speed change ratio between the two cones is variable by changing the angle of intersection between the rotation axes of the rollers and the common axis of the cones; or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0035">Hereinafter, embodiments of the invention will be described in detail with reference to the drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram illustrating a construction of a vehicle <b>10</b> to which the invention is applied, and is also a block diagram illustrating portions of a control system that is provided in the vehicle <b>10</b>. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the vehicle <b>10</b> is a four-wheel drive vehicle that moves basically as, for example, an FR (front mounted engine and rear wheel drive) type vehicle, and has a vehicle power transmission apparatus <b>18</b> that transmits power from an engine <b>12</b> as a vehicle-traction drive force source to a pair of left and right front wheels <b>14</b>R and <b>14</b>L (that will be referred to as &#x201c;front wheels <b>14</b>&#x201d; when the left and right front wheels do not need to be distinguished from each other) provided as auxiliary driving wheels and to a pair of left and right rear wheels <b>16</b>R and <b>16</b>L (that will be referred to as &#x201c;rear wheels <b>16</b>&#x201d; when the left and right rear wheels do not need to be distinguished from each other) provided as main driving wheels. The vehicle power transmission apparatus <b>18</b> includes: an automatic transmission <b>22</b> that has a torque converter <b>20</b> that is linked to the engine <b>12</b>; a transfer (power distribution device) <b>24</b> that is linked to an output side of the automatic transmission <b>22</b> and that distributes the power received from the automatic transmission <b>22</b> to the side of the front wheels <b>14</b> and to the side of the rear wheels <b>16</b>; a front propeller shaft <b>26</b> and a rear propeller shaft <b>28</b> that transmit the power distributed by the transfer <b>24</b> to the front wheel <b>14</b> side and the rear wheel <b>16</b> side; a front wheel differential gear device <b>30</b> and a rear wheel differential gear device <b>32</b> that are linked to the front propeller shaft <b>26</b> and the rear propeller shaft <b>28</b>, respectively; a pair of left and right front wheel axles <b>34</b>R (which includes <b>34</b>R<b>1</b> and <b>34</b>R<b>2</b>) and <b>34</b>L (that will be referred to as &#x201c;front wheel axles <b>34</b>&#x201d; when the left and right front wheel axles do not need to be distinguished from each other) and a pair of left and right rear wheel axles <b>36</b>R and <b>36</b>L (that will be referred to as &#x201c;rear wheel axles <b>36</b>&#x201d; when the left and right rear wheel axles do not need to be distinguished) that transmit the power transmitted via the front wheel differential gear device <b>30</b> and the rear wheel differential gear device <b>32</b>, respectively, to the front wheels <b>14</b> and the rear wheels <b>16</b>, respectively. In the vehicle power transmission apparatus <b>18</b> constructed as described above, the power generated by the engine <b>12</b> is transmitted to the two front wheels <b>14</b> and to the rear wheels <b>16</b> via their respective power transmission paths from the torque converter <b>20</b>, the automatic transmission <b>22</b>, the transfer <b>24</b>, the front propeller shaft <b>26</b> or the rear propeller shaft <b>28</b>, the front wheel differential gear device <b>30</b> or the rear wheel differential gear device <b>32</b>, the left and right front wheel axles <b>34</b> or the left and right rear wheel axles <b>36</b>, etc. Besides, in the front wheel differential gear device <b>30</b>, a mesh clutch <b>38</b> as a generally termed ADD (automatic disconnecting differential) mechanism for switching the front wheel differential gear device <b>30</b> between a locked state and a free state is provided at the front wheel axle <b>34</b>R side (i.e., between the front wheel differential gear device <b>30</b> and the front wheel <b>14</b>R).</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0037">The engine <b>12</b> is an internal combustion engine, such as a gasoline engine, a diesel engine, etc., which generates drive force by combustion of fuel injected into the cylinders of the engine <b>12</b>. Besides, the torque converter <b>20</b> is, for example, a fluid-type power transmission device that includes a pump impeller linked to a crankshaft of the engine <b>12</b>, a turbine impeller linked to an input shaft of the automatic transmission <b>22</b>, and a stator impeller fixed to a transmission case <b>40</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) via a one-way clutch, and that transmits power via a fluid between the pump impeller and the turbine impeller. Besides, the automatic transmission <b>22</b> is, for example, a type of automatic transmission that includes a plurality of friction engagement elements, and that selectively establishes a plurality of speed change ratios according to combinations of engagement and disengagement of the friction engagement elements, and that outputs drive force after changing the speed of the drive force that is input through the input shaft.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0038">The transfer <b>24</b>, for example, selectively switches between cutoff (disconnection) and connection of power transmission between the rear propeller shaft <b>28</b> and the front propeller shaft <b>26</b> so as to transmit the power from the automatic transmission <b>22</b> to only the rear wheels <b>16</b>, or to the front wheels <b>14</b> and the rear wheels <b>16</b>. Besides, the transfer <b>24</b>, for example, selectively establishes one of a high-speed-side gear speed (high-speed-side transmission ratio step) H and a low-speed-side gear speed (low-speed-side transmission ratio step) L, and also has a function as an auxiliary transmission that changes the speed of the power from the automatic transmission <b>22</b> and transmits it to a subsequent portion in the transmission path.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a skeleton diagram of the transfer <b>24</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a developed diagram in which axes of an input shaft <b>66</b>, a first output shaft <b>48</b>, a second output shaft <b>60</b>, a first shift fork shaft <b>96</b> and a second shift fork shaft <b>100</b> described below are shown in a common plane. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the transfer <b>24</b> includes a transfer case <b>42</b> as a non-rotary member that is linked to a vehicle rear side of the transmission case <b>40</b> of the automatic transmission <b>22</b>. Besides, in the transfer case <b>42</b>, the transfer <b>24</b> has: an auxiliary transmission <b>46</b> composed mainly of a single-pinion type planetary gear device <b>44</b>; the first output shaft <b>48</b> as a main drive shaft that is supported by the transfer case <b>42</b> so as to be rotatable about an axis C<b>1</b> and that is linked to the rear propeller shaft <b>28</b>; a mesh clutch device <b>50</b> that selectively establishes one of the low-speed-side gear speed L and the high-speed-side gear speed H as one of two power transmission paths from the auxiliary transmission <b>46</b> to the first output shaft <b>48</b> is put into a linked state; a drive gear <b>52</b> provided so as to be selectively switched between a permitted state and a prevented state regarding the rotation relative to the first output shaft <b>48</b> (the rear propeller shaft <b>28</b>); and a synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> that is a synchronous device (synchronous mesh mechanism) for switching the drive gear <b>52</b> between the permitted state and the prevented state regarding the rotation relative to the first output shaft <b>48</b>. These components of the transfer <b>24</b> are provided on the axis C<b>1</b>. Besides, in the transfer case <b>42</b>, the transfer <b>24</b> also has the second output shaft <b>60</b> as an auxiliary drive shaft that is supported by the transfer case <b>42</b> via bearings <b>56</b> and <b>58</b> so as to be rotatable about an axis C<b>2</b> and that is linked to the front propeller shaft <b>26</b>, and a driven gear <b>62</b> provided on the second output shaft <b>60</b> so as to be unrotatable relative to the second output shaft <b>60</b>. These components of the transfer <b>24</b> are provided on the axis C<b>2</b>. The transfer <b>24</b> further includes a chain <b>64</b> that links the drive gear <b>52</b> and the driven gear <b>62</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0040">The transfer <b>24</b> transmits rotation of the input shaft <b>66</b>, which is supported by the transfer case <b>42</b> so as to be rotatable about the axis C<b>1</b>, to the first output shaft <b>48</b> via the auxiliary transmission <b>46</b>. Furthermore, while the relative rotation of the drive gear <b>52</b> with respect to the first output shaft <b>48</b> is permitted, the power transmission from the first output shaft <b>48</b> to the second output shaft <b>60</b> is not performed (i.e., the power transmission path from the first output shaft <b>48</b> to the second output shaft <b>60</b> is cut off). On the other hand, while the relative rotation of the drive gear <b>52</b> to the first output shaft <b>48</b> is prevented, the power transmission from the first output shaft <b>48</b> to the second output shaft <b>60</b> is performed via the driven gear <b>52</b>, the chain <b>64</b> and the driven gear <b>62</b> (i.e., the power transmission path from the first output shaft <b>48</b> to the second output shaft <b>60</b> is connected). The input shaft <b>66</b> is linked to an output shaft <b>68</b> of the automatic transmission <b>22</b>, and is therefore rotated by drive force (torque) input from the engine <b>12</b> via the automatic transmission <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0041">The planetary gear device <b>44</b> has a sun gear <b>81</b> that is linked to an outer peripheral surface of the input shaft <b>66</b> so as to be unrotatable about the axis C<b>1</b> relative to the input shaft <b>6</b>, a ring gear R<b>1</b> that is arranged generally coaxially with the sun gear S<b>1</b> and that is linked, unrotatably about the axis C<b>1</b>, to the transfer case <b>42</b> that is a fixed member that is fixed to a vehicle body; and a carrier CA<b>1</b> that supports a plurality of pinions P<b>1</b> that mesh with the sun gear S<b>1</b> and the ring gear R<b>1</b> so that the pinions P<b>1</b> are rotatable about their own axes and revolvable around the sun gear S<b>1</b>. Therefore, the rotation speed of the sun gear S<b>1</b> is equal to that of the input shaft <b>66</b>, and the rotation speed of the carrier CA<b>1</b> is reduced relative to that of the input shaft <b>66</b>. Besides, a clutch gear <b>72</b> that is a non-synchronous-side member of a synchronous mesh mechanism <b>70</b> that participates in the establishment of the high-speed-side gear speed H is fixed so as to be unrotatable about the axis C<b>1</b> relative to the sun gear S<b>1</b>. The synchronous mesh mechanism <b>70</b> is a portion of a mesh clutch device <b>50</b>. Besides, a clutch gear <b>76</b> that is a non-synchronous-side member of a mesh clutch <b>74</b> of the mesh clutch device <b>50</b> which participates in the establishment of the low-speed-side gear speed L is fixed so as to be unrotatable about the axis C<b>1</b> relative to the carrier CA<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0042">The mesh clutch device <b>50</b> includes the synchronous mesh mechanism <b>70</b> for establishing the high-speed-side gear speed H, and the mesh clutch <b>74</b> for establishing, the low-speed-side gear speed L. The synchronous mesh mechanism <b>70</b> is a so-called synchromesh mechanism that is well known, and, for example, has: a clutch hub <b>78</b> that is spline-fitted to the first output shaft <b>48</b> so as to be relatively unrotatable about the axis C<b>1</b> with respect to the first output shaft <b>48</b>; a cylindrical sleeve <b>80</b> that is spline-fitted to the clutch hub <b>78</b> so as to be relatively unrotatable about the axis C<b>1</b> and relatively slidable in the direction along the axis C<b>1</b> with respect to the clutch hub <b>78</b>; the clutch gear <b>72</b> that has outer peripheral teeth that are relatively unrotatable about the axis C<b>1</b> but relatively slidable in the direction along the axis C<b>1</b> with respect to inner peripheral teeth of an inner peripheral surface of the sleeve <b>80</b> and that is disposed between the planetary gear device <b>44</b> and the clutch hub <b>78</b> and is fixed to the sun gear S<b>1</b> as described above; and a synchronizer ring (synchronous ring) <b>82</b> that prevents the sleeve <b>80</b> from moving toward the clutch gear <b>72</b> while the rotation of the sleeve <b>80</b> and the rotation of the clutch gear <b>72</b> are in an asynchronous state. In this embodiment, the synchronizer ring <b>82</b> functions as a synchronous device that synchronizes the sleeve <b>80</b> and the clutch gear <b>72</b> when the sleeve <b>80</b> and the clutch gear <b>72</b> are about to be meshed with each other. The sleeve <b>80</b> corresponds to a shift ring that is moved in the direction along the axis C<b>1</b> by a shift actuator <b>84</b>. The mesh clutch <b>74</b> includes the sleeve <b>80</b> and the clutch gear <b>76</b> that has inner peripheral teeth which are relatively unrotatable about the axis C<b>1</b> and relatively slidable in the direction along the axis C<b>1</b> with respect to outer peripheral teeth <b>86</b> provided in an outer peripheral portion of the sleeve <b>80</b>, and that is disposed at an opposite side of the outer peripheral teeth <b>86</b> to the clutch gear <b>72</b> and is fixed to the carrier CA<b>1</b> as described above. In the mesh clutch device <b>50</b> constructed as described above, the sleeve <b>80</b> slides in the direction along the axis C<b>1</b> to mesh with the clutch gear <b>72</b> so that the auxiliary transmission <b>46</b> establishes the high-speed-side gear speed H, and the sleeve <b>80</b> slides in the direction along the axis C<b>1</b> to mesh with the clutch gear <b>76</b> so that the auxiliary transmission <b>46</b> establishes the low-speed-side gear speed L. At this time, the path that transmits power to the first output shaft <b>48</b> via the carrier CA<b>1</b> and the clutch gear <b>76</b> corresponds to a power transmission path that establishes the low-speed-side gear speed L, and the path that transmits power to the first output shaft <b>48</b> via the sun gear S<b>1</b> and the clutch gear <b>72</b> corresponds to a power transmission path that establishes the high-speed-side gear speed H. Besides, the transfer <b>24</b> assumes a power transmission cut-off state (neutral state) when the sleeve <b>80</b> does not mesh with either one of the clutch gears <b>72</b> and <b>76</b> as shown in, for example, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. When the gear speed is switched between the high-speed-side gear speed H and the low-speed-side gear speed L, the switching is performed via the power transfer cut-off state.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0043">The synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> is, for example, a known synchromesh mechanism, and has: a clutch hub <b>88</b> that is spline-fitted to the first output shaft <b>48</b> so as to be relatively unrotatable about the axis C<b>1</b> with respect to the first output shaft <b>48</b>; a cylindrical sleeve <b>90</b> that is spline-fitted to the clutch hub <b>88</b> so as to be relatively unrotatable about the axis C<b>1</b> and relatively slidable in the direction along the axis C<b>1</b> with respect to the clutch hub <b>88</b>; a clutch gear <b>92</b> which has outer peripheral teeth that mesh with inner peripheral teeth of an inner peripheral surface of the sleeve <b>90</b> so as to be relatively unrotatable about the axis C<b>1</b> and relatively slidable in the direction along the axis C<b>1</b> with respect to the inner peripheral teeth of the sleeve <b>90</b>, and which is disposed between the drive gear <b>52</b> and the clutch hub <b>88</b> and is fixed to the drive gear <b>52</b>; and a synchronizer ring <b>94</b> that prevents the sleeve <b>90</b> from moving toward the clutch gear <b>92</b> when the rotation of the sleeve <b>90</b> and the rotation of the clutch gear <b>92</b> are asynchronous. In this embodiment, the synchronizer ring <b>94</b> functions as a synchronous device that synchronizes the sleeve <b>90</b> and the clutch gear <b>92</b> when the sleeve <b>90</b> and the clutch gear <b>92</b> are about to be meshed with each other. The sleeve <b>90</b> corresponds to a shift ring that is moved in the direction along the axis C<b>1</b> by the shift actuator <b>84</b>. The sleeve <b>90</b> is usually positioned at a neutral position at which the sleeve <b>90</b> assumes a state of cutting off the power transmission as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, but is able to be slid and moved in the direction along the axis C<b>1</b> by the shift actuator <b>84</b> to a transmission position at which the power transmission is possible. In the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> constructed as described above, the sleeve <b>90</b> is positioned, for example, at a position relative to the clutch hub <b>88</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, when the shift actuator <b>84</b> that moves the sleeve <b>90</b> is not driven. When the sleeve <b>90</b> is at this relative position, the drive gear <b>52</b> is relatively rotatable about the axis C<b>1</b> with respect to the first output shaft <b>48</b>, and the drive gear <b>52</b> is rotated freely relative to the first output shaft <b>48</b>, so that the power transmission to the second output shaft <b>60</b> side via the drive gear <b>52</b> is not performed (cut off). On the other hand, when the shift actuator <b>84</b> is driven to move the sleeve <b>90</b> to the drive gear <b>52</b> side until the sleeve <b>90</b> meshes with the clutch gear <b>92</b> and therefore a synchronizing operation of the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> is completed, the relative rotation of the drive gear <b>52</b> about the axis C<b>1</b> with respect to the first output shaft <b>48</b> is prevented, and the drive gear <b>52</b> is rotated integrally with the first output shaft <b>48</b>, so that the power transmission to the second output shaft <b>60</b> side via the drive gear <b>52</b>, the chain <b>64</b>, the driven gear <b>62</b>, etc. is performed (connected). Thus, the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> functions as a first power connecting/disconnecting device that is able to connect and disconnect the power transmission path between the first output shaft <b>48</b> and the second output shaft <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0044">The mesh clutch device <b>50</b> is constructed so that as the first shift fork shaft <b>96</b> that corresponds to an output member of the shift actuator <b>84</b> and that is thrust in the direction parallel to the axis C<b>1</b> is moved in the direction parallel to the axis C<b>1</b> by driving the shift actuator <b>84</b>, the sleeve <b>80</b> is moved in the direction along the axis C<b>1</b> via a first shift fork <b>98</b> that is fixed to the first shift fork shaft <b>96</b> so as to be engageable with the sleeve <b>80</b> in the direction along the axis C<b>1</b> and relatively rotatable about the axis C<b>1</b> with respect to the sleeve <b>80</b>. Besides, the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> is constructed so that as the second shift fork shaft <b>100</b> that corresponds to an output member of the shift actuator <b>84</b> and that is thrust in the direction parallel to the axis C<b>1</b> is moved in the direction parallel to the axis C<b>1</b> by driving the shift actuator <b>84</b>, the sleeve <b>90</b> is moved in the direction along the axis C<b>1</b> via a second shift fork <b>102</b> that is fixed to the second shift fork shaft <b>100</b> so as to be engageable with the sleeve <b>90</b> in the direction along the axis C<b>1</b> and relatively rotatable about the axis C<b>1</b> with respect to the sleeve <b>90</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0045">Referring back to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the motive power distributed to the second output shaft <b>60</b> by the transfer <b>24</b> is input to the front wheel differential gear device <b>30</b> via the front propeller shaft <b>26</b>. An end portion of the front propeller shaft <b>26</b> is provided with a drive pinion <b>104</b> that is a bevel gear. The gear teeth of the drive pinion <b>104</b> are constructed so as to fit to the teeth of a ring gear <b>106</b> that is a bevel gear of the front wheel differential gear device <b>30</b>. This ring gear <b>106</b> is fixed to a differential case <b>108</b>, and rotates (revolves) integrally with the differential case <b>108</b> about an axis of the front axles <b>34</b>. The front wheel axles <b>34</b> include front wheel axles <b>34</b>R and <b>34</b>L on an axis, and the front wheel axle <b>34</b>R includes front wheel axles <b>34</b>R<b>1</b> and <b>34</b>R<b>2</b>. As described above, the front wheel differential gear device <b>30</b> is a differential gear device that is provided with the mesh clutch <b>38</b> as an ADD mechanism.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0046">The mesh clutch <b>38</b> switches between a power transmission state in which power is transmitted between the front wheel axle <b>34</b>R<b>1</b> and the front wheel axle <b>34</b>R<b>2</b> and a power cutoff state in which the power transmission is cut off. That is, the mesh clutch <b>38</b> is made up of, for example, a known dog clutch or the like that selectively links the front wheel axle <b>34</b>R<b>1</b> and the front wheel axle <b>34</b>R<b>2</b> to each other, and functions as a second power connection/disconnection device that selectively switches between disconnection and connection of the power transmission between the front wheel differential gear device <b>30</b> and the front wheel <b>14</b>R. That is, the mesh clutch <b>38</b>, when in the released state (disconnected state), cuts off the power transmission path between the front wheel differential gear device <b>30</b> and the front wheels <b>14</b>R, and, when in the connected state, connects the power transmission path between the front wheel differential gear device <b>30</b> and the front wheel <b>14</b>R. The mesh clutch <b>38</b>, for example, during the two-wheel drive state, is put into the disconnected state, cutting off the power transmission path between the front wheel differential gear device <b>30</b> and the front wheel <b>14</b>R.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0047">Concretely, the ADD device <b>110</b> includes the mesh clutch <b>38</b> and an electric motor <b>112</b> for switching the state of operation of the mesh clutch <b>38</b> (i.e. between the connected state and the disconnected state). The ADD device <b>110</b> is able to selectively switch the mesh clutch <b>38</b> between the connected state and the disconnected state by driving the motor <b>112</b> and thereby switch between the power transmission state in which the front wheel axle <b>34</b>R<b>1</b> and the front wheel axle <b>34</b>R<b>2</b> are meshed and the power cutoff state in which the front wheel axles <b>34</b>R<b>1</b> and the <b>34</b>R<b>2</b> are not meshed.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0048">When the ADD device <b>110</b> establishes the power transmission state in which power can be transmitted between the front wheel axle <b>34</b>R<b>1</b> and the front wheel axle <b>34</b>R<b>2</b>, the power (drive force) generated by the engine <b>12</b> and distributed by the transfer <b>24</b> is transmitted to the front wheel differential gear device <b>30</b> via the front propeller shaft <b>26</b>, and then is transmitted to the left and right front wheels <b>14</b> via the left and right front wheel axles <b>34</b>. At this time, the rest of the drive force, that is, the amount of drive force other than the amount of drive force that is distributed to the front wheels <b>14</b> by the transfer <b>24</b> whose synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> is in the connected state, is transmitted to the left and right rear wheels <b>16</b> via the rear propeller shaft <b>28</b>, the rear wheel differential gear device <b>32</b> and the left and right rear wheel axles <b>36</b>. Thus, the vehicle <b>10</b> is in a front-and-rear wheel drive state (four-wheel drive state).</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0049">On the other hand, when the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> is put into the disconnected state, the power from the engine <b>12</b> is transmitted only to the left and right rear wheels <b>16</b> by the transfer <b>24</b>, so that the vehicle <b>10</b> is in a rear wheel drive state (two-wheel drive state). At this time, if the ADD device <b>110</b> is in the power transmission state in which power can be transmitted between the front wheel axle <b>34</b>R<b>1</b> and the front wheel axle <b>34</b>R<b>2</b>, rotation of the left and right front wheels <b>14</b> rotate the front wheel axles <b>34</b>, the front wheel differential gear device <b>30</b>, the front propeller shaft <b>26</b>, the second output shaft <b>60</b>, the driven gear <b>62</b>, the chain <b>64</b>, the drive gear <b>52</b>, etc. In that case, torque acts in the deceleration direction for the vehicle <b>10</b>, and efficiency declines. Therefore, in the vehicle <b>10</b> in this embodiment, for example, in association with the two-wheel drive state, the mesh clutch <b>38</b> is disconnected to bring about the power cutoff state in which the ADD device <b>110</b> does not transmit power between the front wheel axle <b>34</b>R<b>1</b> and the front wheel axle <b>34</b>R<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0050">Thus, the vehicle <b>10</b> is a four-wheel drive vehicle that adopts a part-time 4WD system capable of selectively switching between the two-wheel drive state in which both the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> capable of connecting and disconnecting the power transmission path between the first output shaft <b>48</b> and the second output shaft <b>60</b> and the mesh clutch <b>38</b> capable of connecting and disconnecting the power transmission path between the second output shaft <b>60</b> and the front wheels <b>14</b> are put into the disconnected state and therefore power from the engine is transmitted from the first output shaft <b>48</b> only to the rear wheels <b>16</b>, and the four-wheel drive state in which power from the engine <b>12</b> is transmitted to the rear wheels <b>16</b> and, in addition, power from the engine <b>12</b> is also transmitted from the first output shaft <b>48</b> to the second output shaft <b>60</b> by putting the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> into the connected state, and then is transmitted from the second output shaft <b>60</b> to the front wheels <b>14</b> by putting the mesh clutch <b>38</b> into the connected state.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0051">Besides, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the vehicle <b>10</b> is equipped with, for example, an electronic control unit <b>130</b> that includes a four-wheel drive vehicle control apparatus for switching between the two-wheel drive state and the four-wheel drive state. The electronic control unit <b>130</b> includes, for example, a so-called microcomputer that includes a CPU, a RAM, a ROM, input/output interfaces, etc. The CPU performs an output control of the engine <b>12</b>, a gear ratio shift control of the automatic transmission <b>22</b>, a switching control of the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> of the transfer <b>24</b> and the mesh clutch <b>38</b> of the front wheel differential gear device <b>30</b>, etc. by performing signal processing according to programs that are stored beforehand in the ROM and utilizing the temporary storage function of the RAM.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0052">The electronic control unit <b>130</b> is supplied with various signals, for example, a signal that represents the engine rotation speed N<sub>E </sub>detected by an engine rotation speed sensor <b>114</b>, a signal that represents a vehicle speed V that corresponds to the output rotation speed N<sub>RP </sub>of the rear propeller shaft <b>28</b> that is detected by a rear propeller rotation speed sensor <b>116</b>, signals that represent wheel speeds N<sub>FR</sub>, N<sub>FL</sub>, N<sub>RR </sub>and N<sub>RL </sub>that correspond to the rotation speeds N<sub>W </sub>of the individual wheels (i.e., the front wheels <b>14</b>R and <b>14</b>L and the rear wheels <b>16</b>R and <b>16</b>L) that are detected by wheel speed sensors <b>118</b>, a signal that represents the operation position P<sub>DIAL </sub>of a drive state-switching dial switch <b>122</b> that is detected by a dial position sensor <b>120</b>, signals that represent the two-wheel drive state S<sub>2WD </sub>and the four-wheel drive state S<sub>4WD</sub>, respectively, that are detected by a drive state-detecting switch <b>124</b> and that indicate that the switching of the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> in the transfer <b>24</b> has been completed, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0053">Besides, the electronic control unit <b>130</b> outputs, for example, an engine output control command signal S<sub>E </sub>for an output control of the engine <b>12</b>, a ratio shift control command signal S<sub>T </sub>for a ratio shift control of the automatic transmission <b>22</b>, a high/low switching control command signal S<sub>HL </sub>for switching the gear speed of the auxiliary transmission <b>46</b> between the high-speed-side gear speed H and the low-speed-side gear speed L by causing the shift actuator <b>84</b> to actuate the mesh clutch device <b>50</b> via the first shift fork shaft <b>96</b>, a drive state-switching control command signal S<sub>2-4 </sub>for switching the state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b> between the two-wheel drive state and the four-wheel drive state by causing the shift actuator <b>84</b> to actuate the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> via the second shift fork shaft <b>100</b>, an ADD switching control command signal S<sub>ADD </sub>for switching the power transmission path extending between the front wheel differential gear device <b>30</b> and the front wheel <b>14</b>R between the disconnected state and the connected state by causing the electric motor <b>112</b> to actuate the mesh clutch <b>38</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0054">The drive state-switching dial switch <b>122</b> is a dial-type switch that is provided, for example, near the driver's seat, and that is manually operated by a user. The drive state-switching dial switch <b>122</b> has three operation positions P<sub>DIAL </sub>for commanding the switching to the two-wheel drive state (H-2WD) combined with the high-speed-side gear speed H, the four-wheel drive state (H-4WD) combined with the high-speed-side gear speed H, or the four-wheel drive state (L-4WD) combined with the low-speed-side gear speed L. This drive state-switching dial switch <b>122</b> is not limited to a dial type switch as described above, but this switching function may also be realized by employing, for example, a slide type switch, a seesaw type switch, or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0055"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a functional block diagram illustrating portions of control functions performed by the electronic control unit <b>130</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a transfer switching control portion, that is, transfer switching control means <b>132</b>, controls the switching of the transfer <b>24</b> on the basis of, for example, signals that represent the operation positions P<sub>DIAL </sub>of the drive state-switching dial switch <b>122</b>. Concretely, when the selected operation position P<sub>DIAL </sub>of the drive state-switching dial switch <b>122</b> is such that usually a signal representing the two-wheel drive state (H-2WD) is generated, the transfer switching control means <b>132</b> outputs a high/low switching control command signal S<sub>HL </sub>for switching the gear speed of the auxiliary transmission <b>46</b> to the high-speed-side gear speed H to the shift actuator <b>84</b>, so that the shift actuator <b>84</b> switches the gear speed of the auxiliary transmission <b>46</b> to the high-speed-side gear speed H by accordingly actuating the mesh clutch device <b>50</b> via the first shift fork shaft <b>96</b>. Furthermore, the transfer switching control means <b>132</b> also outputs to the shift actuator <b>84</b> a drive state-switching control command signal S<sub>2-4 </sub>for switching the state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b> to the two-wheel drive state, so that the shift actuator <b>84</b> disconnects the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> via the second shift fork shaft <b>100</b>. On another hand, when the operation position P<sub>DIAL </sub>is such that usually a signal representing the four-wheel drive state (H-4WD) is generated, the transfer switching control means <b>132</b> outputs to the shift actuator <b>84</b> the high/low switching control command signal S<sub>HL </sub>for switching the gear speed of the auxiliary transmission <b>46</b> to the high-speed-side gear speed H, as in the foregoing case of the two-wheel drive state (H-2WD). Furthermore, the transfer switching control means <b>132</b> outputs to the shift actuator <b>84</b> a drive state-switching control command signal S<sub>2-4 </sub>for switching the state of drive of the transfer <b>24</b> to the four-wheel drive state, so that the shift actuator <b>84</b> connects the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> via the second shift fork shaft <b>100</b>. On the other hand, when the operation position P<sub>DIAL </sub>is such that usually a signal representing the four-wheel drive state (L-4WD) is generated, the transfer switching control means <b>132</b> outputs to the shift actuator <b>84</b> a high/low switching control command signal S<sub>HL </sub>for switching the gear speed of the auxiliary transmission <b>46</b> to the low-speed-side gear speed L, so that the shift actuator <b>84</b> switches the gear speed of the auxiliary transmission <b>46</b> to the low-speed-side gear speed L by actuating the mesh clutch device <b>50</b> via the first shift fork shaft <b>96</b>. Furthermore, the transfer switching control means <b>132</b> outputs to the shift actuator <b>84</b> the drive state-switching control command signal S<sub>2-4 </sub>for switching the state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b> to the four-wheel drive state, as in the case of the foregoing four-wheel drive state (H-4WD).</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0056">An ADD connection/disconnection switching control portion, that is, ADD connection/disconnection switching control means <b>134</b>, controls the switching of the mesh clutch <b>38</b> on the basis of, for example, the signals that represent the operation positions P<sub>DIAL </sub>of the drive state-switching dial switch <b>122</b>. Concretely, when the selected operation position P<sub>DIAL </sub>is such that usually the signal representing the two-wheel drive state (H-2WD) is generated, the ADD connection/disconnection switching control means <b>134</b> outputs to the motor <b>112</b> an ADD switching control command signal S<sub>ADD </sub>for cutting off the power transmission path between the front wheel differential gear device <b>30</b> and the front wheel <b>14</b>R, so that the motor <b>112</b> is operated to disconnect the mesh clutch <b>38</b>. When the operation position P<sub>DIAL </sub>is such that usually the signal representing one of the four-wheel drive state (H-4WD) and the four-wheel drive state (L-4WD) is generated, the ADD connection/disconnection switching control means <b>134</b> outputs to the motor <b>112</b> an ADD switching control command signal S<sub>ADD </sub>for connecting the power transmission path between the front wheel differential gear device <b>30</b> and the front wheel <b>14</b>R, so that the motor <b>112</b> is operated to connect the mesh clutch <b>38</b>, on condition that the signal that shows that the switching of the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> in the transfer <b>24</b> has been completed is a signal that represents the four-wheel drive state S<sub>4WD</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0057">In this embodiment, for example, when the driver has selected the two-wheel drive state (H-2WD) by the drive state-switching dial switch <b>122</b>, both the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> and the mesh clutch <b>38</b> are put into the disconnected state. Therefore, while the two-wheel drive state (H-2WD) is selected, none of the drive gear <b>52</b>, the driven gear <b>62</b>, the chain <b>64</b>, the second output shaft <b>60</b>, the bearings <b>56</b> and <b>58</b>, etc. is rotated by the first output shaft <b>48</b>, and none of them is rotated by rotation of the front wheels <b>14</b>. Thus, these components remain stopped during the two-wheel drive state. That is, during the stop of rotation, contact at fixed portions constantly exists, for example, between the drive gear <b>52</b> and the chain <b>64</b>, between the driven gear <b>62</b> and the chain <b>64</b>, and between the second output shaft <b>60</b> and the bearings <b>56</b> and <b>58</b>, giving a risk of decline in durability due to local progress of striking wear or the like that is caused by input of vibration from outside, for example, rotating vibration from the engine <b>12</b> or the like. In particular, in the vehicle <b>10</b> in accordance with this embodiment, which is designed so that the oil OIL (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) gathering in a lower portion of the transfer case <b>42</b> is splashed upward by rotation of the driven gear <b>62</b> and the chain <b>64</b> in order to improve the lubricating performance, the problem of the foregoing decline in durability may more conspicuously manifest itself as the lubricating performance declines when the driven gear <b>62</b> and the chain <b>64</b> stop rotating.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0058">Therefore, in order to temporarily rotate rotary members, such as the second output shaft <b>60</b> and the like, that normally do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state, the electronic control unit <b>130</b> in this embodiment temporarily switches the state of drive to the four-wheel drive state by connecting at least one of the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> and the mesh clutch <b>38</b>, for example, when a count value CNT concerning the travel in the two-wheel drive state reaches a predetermined value CNT&#x2032;. For example, when the count value CNT concerning the travel in the two-wheel drive state becomes equal to or greater than the predetermined value CNT&#x2032;, the electronic control unit <b>130</b> temporarily switches only one of the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> and the mesh clutch <b>38</b> to the connected state. It is to be noted herein that the mesh clutch <b>38</b> (ADD device <b>110</b>) is a power connecting/disconnecting device that is not equipped with a synchromesh mechanism, and therefore it is difficult to switch the mesh clutch <b>38</b> to the connected state during a travel of the vehicle <b>10</b> during which the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> is not in the connected state. Therefore, in this embodiment, for example, when the count value CNT concerning the travel in the two-wheel drive state becomes equal to or greater than the predetermined value CNT&#x2032;, only the state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b> is temporarily switched to the four-wheel drive state by putting only the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> into the connected state, without switching the mesh clutch <b>38</b> (ADD device <b>110</b>), that is, while keeping the mesh clutch <b>38</b> in the disconnected state.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0059">Incidentally, the count value CNT concerning the travel in the two-wheel drive state is a count value that shows a cumulative travel time CNT-T or a cumulative travel distance CNT-D of the vehicle <b>10</b> during the two-wheel drive state that is obtained by counting time pulses of a constant frequency which have been set beforehand as reference pulses or by counting rotation pulses that have been set beforehand as reference pulses and that are detected from a rotary member that rotates as the vehicle <b>10</b> travels. As for the cumulative travel time CNT-T, it is permissible to avoid the counting of time, for example, during a temporary stop of the vehicle <b>10</b> in the two-wheel drive state, and to determine a cumulative travel time by summing the count values obtained before and after the temporary stop. Alternatively, it is also permissible to determine a cumulative travel time that includes the duration of a temporary stop of the vehicle <b>10</b> in the two-wheel drive state. That is, the vehicle travel time in this embodiment may include, for example, the duration of a vehicle state in which the engine <b>12</b> is operating while the vehicle <b>10</b> is at a stop. Besides, for example, as the engine rotation speed N<sub>E </sub>increases, the rotation vibration of the engine <b>12</b> that is a source of vibration that causes the striking wear or the like increases, so that the local striking wear or the like of rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state, such as the second output shaft <b>60</b> and the like, becomes more likely to progress. Therefore, it is also permissible to adopt, for example, a construction in which the foregoing reference pulses are counted only when the engine rotation speed N<sub>E </sub>is greater than or equal to a predetermined rotation speed N<sub>E</sub>&#x2032; while the vehicle <b>10</b> is traveling in the two-wheel drive state, and an accumulated value of the count values obtained when the engine rotation speed N<sub>E </sub>is greater than or equal to the rotation speed N<sub>E</sub>&#x2032; is determined as a count value CNT concerning the travel of the vehicle <b>10</b> in the two-wheel drive state. The predetermined rotation speed N<sub>E</sub>&#x2032; is a criterion value for determining whether or not the counting is necessary which is determined beforehand through experiments or the like as an engine rotation speed N<sub>E </sub>above which the local striking wear or the like of the rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state, such as the second output shaft <b>60</b> and the like, is likely to progress. Although the condition that the engine rotation speed N<sub>E </sub>is greater than or equal to the predetermined rotation speed N<sub>E</sub>&#x2032; is adopted as the condition for the counting in this embodiment, the condition for the counting may also be a condition that a value related to the engine rotation speed N<sub>E</sub>, instead of the engine rotation speed N<sub>E </sub>itself, is greater than or equal to a predetermined engine rotation speed-related value. Examples of the value related to the engine rotation speed N<sub>E </sub>include the rotation speed of the output shaft <b>68</b> of the automatic transmission <b>22</b>, the output rotation speed N<sub>RP </sub>of the rear propeller shaft <b>28</b>, the vehicle speed V, the rotation speed N<sub>W </sub>of each wheel, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0060">Besides, the predetermined value CNT&#x2032; is a 4WD switching criterion threshold value that is found and set beforehand empirically or by design for use for determining whether or not a given count value CNT is such that it is necessary to temporarily switch the state of drive to the four-wheel drive state because the vehicle <b>10</b> has continually been in the two-wheel drive state so that a risk of decline in the durability of the rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state, such as the second output shaft <b>60</b> and the like, is likely to arise. Besides, as the engine rotation speed N<sub>E</sub>, for example, becomes higher, more rotation vibration is produced by the engine <b>12</b>, which is a source of vibration that causes the striking wear or the like, so that local striking wear of rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state, such as the second output shaft <b>60</b> or the like, becomes more likely to progress. Therefore, it is also permissible to adopt a construction in which the higher the engine rotation speed N<sub>E </sub>(or a value related to the engine rotation speed N<sub>E</sub>) is, the smaller the predetermined value CNT&#x2032; is made in order to facilitate the temporary switching to the four wheel drive. For example, the electronic control unit <b>130</b> calculates the predetermined value CNT&#x2032; from an actual engine rotation speed N<sub>E </sub>on the basis of a relation in which the higher the engine rotation speed N<sub>E</sub>, the smaller the predetermined value CNT&#x2032;, for example, a relation as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> (predetermined-value map). However, since the engine rotation speed N<sub>E </sub>is not constantly fixed during the travel of the vehicle in the two-wheel drive state, it is appropriate, for example, to serially calculate an average value of the engine rotation speed N<sub>E </sub>during the traveling of the vehicle in the two-wheel drive state and serially calculate a predetermined value CNT&#x2032; on the basis of the average value of the engine rotation speed N<sub>E</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0061">Referring back to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a drive state determination portion, that is, drive state determination means <b>136</b>, determines the present state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b>, on the basis of, for example, signals representing the two-wheel drive state S<sub>2WD </sub>and the four-wheel drive state S<sub>4WD</sub>, respectively, which are detected by the drive state-detecting switch <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0062">A two-wheel drive state counting portion, that is, two-wheel drive state counting means <b>138</b>, counts the reference pulses and serially outputs a count value CNT concerning the travel of the vehicle <b>10</b> in the two-wheel drive state, as long as it is determined by the drive state determination means <b>136</b> that the present state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b> is the two-wheel drive state. At this time, the two-wheel drive state counting means <b>138</b> may count the reference pulses, for example, only when the engine rotation speed N<sub>E </sub>is greater than or equal to the predetermined rotation speed N<sub>E</sub>&#x2032;. Besides, if it is determined by the drive state determination means <b>136</b> that the present state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b> is the four-wheel drive state, or after the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> is forced to assume the connected state by the transfer switching control means <b>132</b> as described below, the count value CNT is reset (set to an initial value of zero).</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0063">A count value determination portion, that is, count value determination means <b>140</b>, determines whether or not, for example, the count value CNT obtained by the two-wheel drive state counting means <b>138</b> is equal to or greater than the predetermined value CNT&#x2032;. At this time, the count value determination means <b>140</b> may serially calculate an average value of the engine rotation speed N<sub>E</sub>, for example, during the travel of the vehicle <b>10</b> in the two-wheel drive state, and may serially calculate a predetermined value CNT&#x2032; from the calculated average value of the engine rotation speed N<sub>E </sub>on the basis of, for example, a relation (predetermined-value map) as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0064">For example, if it is determined by the count value determination means <b>140</b> that the count value CNT has become equal to or greater than the predetermined value CNT&#x2032;, the transfer switching control means <b>132</b> outputs to the shift actuator <b>84</b> the drive state-switching control command signal S<sub>2-4 </sub>for forcing the state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b> to be switched to the four-wheel drive state even when the operation position P<sub>DIAL </sub>of the drive state-switching dial switch <b>122</b> is such that usually the signal representing the two-wheel drive state (H-2WD) is generated, so that the shift actuator <b>84</b> periodically forces the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> to assume the connected state, via the second shift fork shaft <b>100</b>. Besides, for example, if it is determined via switch time elapse determination means <b>142</b> that a predetermined switch time T<b>4</b>wd&#x2032; has elapsed, the transfer switching control means <b>132</b> outputs to the shift actuator <b>84</b> the drive state-switching control command signal S<sub>2-4 </sub>for switching the state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b> to the two-wheel drive state, so that the shift actuator <b>84</b> puts the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> into the disconnected state, via the second shift fork shaft <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0065">A switch time elapse determination portion, that is, switch time elapse determination means <b>142</b>, determines whether or not the switch time T<b>4</b>wd during which the state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b> has been forced to be switched and held to the four-wheel drive state by the transfer switching control means <b>132</b> even though the operation position P<sub>DIAL </sub>is such that the signal representing the two-wheel drive state (H-2WD) is usually generated, and therefore the signal sent from the drive state-detecting switch <b>124</b> has been switched and held to the signal that represents the four-wheel drive state S<sub>4WD </sub>has reached or exceeded a predetermined switch time T<b>4</b>wd&#x2032;. The predetermined switch time T<b>4</b>wd&#x2032; is a forced four-wheel drive state switch time that is empirically found and set beforehand as a time for appropriately securing the lubricating performance due to the oil OIL splashed upward by rotation of the driven gear <b>62</b> and the chain <b>64</b> which is achieved by temporarily switching the state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b> to the four-wheel drive state.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0066"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a flowchart illustrating portions of control operations of the electronic control unit <b>130</b>, that is, a control operation for improving durability by restraining the partial wear of rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state, such as the second output shaft <b>60</b> and the like. This control operation is repeatedly executed in a very short cycle time of, for example, several milliseconds to several ten milliseconds.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0067">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, firstly in step S<b>10</b> (hereinafter, the term &#x201c;step&#x201d; will be omitted) that corresponds to the drive state determination means <b>136</b>, it is determined whether or not the present state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b> is the two-wheel drive state, on the basis of, for example, the signals representing the two-wheel drive state S<sub>2WD </sub>and the four-wheel drive state S<sub>4WD </sub>detected by the drive state-detecting switch <b>124</b>. If the determination in S<b>10</b> is negative, the present routine is ended. If the determination in S<b>10</b> is affirmative, the counting of the reference pulses for outputting a count value CNT concerning the travel in, for example, the two-wheel drive state, is started in S<b>20</b>, which corresponds to the two-wheel drive state counting means <b>138</b>. Concretely, the counting of the reference pulse for finding the cumulative travel time (2WD time count) CNT-T or the cumulative travel distance (2WD distance count) CNT-D in the two-wheel drive state is started. Next, in S<b>30</b>, which corresponds to the drive state determination means <b>136</b>, it is determined whether or not, for example, the present state of drive is the two-wheel drive state, as in S<b>10</b>. If the determination in S<b>30</b> is affirmative, it is then determined in S<b>40</b>, which corresponds to the count value determination means <b>140</b>, whether or not, for example, the count value CNT (the 2WD time count CNT-T or the 2WD distance count CNT-D) has become equal to or greater than a predetermined value CNT&#x2032; (a predetermined time count value CNT-T&#x2032; or a predetermined distance count value CNT-D&#x2032;). The predetermined value CNT&#x2032; may be, for example, a constant value, or may also be a predetermined value CNT&#x2032; that is serially calculated from the average value of the engine rotation speed N<sub>E </sub>during the travel in the two-wheel drive state by using a map as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. If the determination in S<b>40</b> is negative, the process returns to S<b>30</b>. If the determination in S<b>40</b> is affirmative, the process proceeds to S<b>50</b>, which corresponds to the transfer switching control means <b>132</b>. In <b>850</b>, for example, even if the operation position P<sub>DIAL </sub>is such as to usually generate the signal that represents the two-wheel drive state (H-2WD), the drive state-switching control command signal S<sub>2-4 </sub>for forcing the state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b> to be switched to the four-wheel drive state is output to the shift actuator <b>84</b>, so that the shift actuator <b>84</b> forces the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> to enter the connected state via the second shift fork shaft <b>100</b>. In this case, the state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b> is forced to switch to the four-wheel drive state, but the operation position P<sub>DIAL </sub>remains such as to usually generate the signal that represents the two-wheel drive state (H-2WD), so the switching of the mesh clutch <b>38</b> (the ADD device <b>110</b>) is not performed, but the mesh clutch <b>38</b> remains in the disconnected state. Therefore, the vehicle <b>10</b>, in effect, remains in the two-wheel drive state, so that deterioration of efficiency is restrained and changes in the vehicle behavior caused by switching the vehicle <b>10</b> into the four-wheel drive state in effect are avoided. Next, in S<b>60</b>, which corresponds to the switch time elapse determination means <b>142</b>, it is determined whether or not the switch time T<b>4</b>wd during which the signal from the drive state-detecting switch <b>124</b> has been switched and held to the signal that represents the four-wheel drive state S<sub>4WD </sub>has reached or exceeded the predetermined switch time T<b>4</b>wd&#x2032;. If the determination in S<b>60</b> is negative, the process of S<b>60</b> is repeated. If the determination in S<b>60</b> is affirmative, the process proceeds to S<b>70</b>, which corresponds to the transfer switching control means <b>132</b>. In S<b>70</b>, for example, the drive state-switching control command signal S<sub>2-4 </sub>for switching the state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b> to the two-wheel drive state is output to the shift actuator <b>84</b>, so that the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> is put into the disconnected state via the second shift fork shaft <b>100</b>. In this case, the state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b> that has been forced to switch to the four-wheel drive state is switched back to the two-wheel drive state. Therefore, because the switching of the mesh clutch <b>38</b> (the ADD device <b>110</b>) has not been performed, the switching of the mesh clutch <b>38</b> (the ADD device <b>110</b>) is not performed in this step either, but the mesh clutch <b>38</b> remains in the disconnected state. If the determination in S<b>30</b> is negative, or after S<b>70</b> is executed, the count value CNT is reset (set to the initial value of zero) in S<b>80</b>, which corresponds to the two-wheel drive state counting means <b>138</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0068">As described above, according to the embodiment, when the count value CNT concerning the travel in the two-wheel drive state becomes equal to or greater than the predetermined value CNT&#x2032;, at least one of the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> and the mesh clutch <b>38</b> is put into the connected state for a temporary switch to the four-wheel drive state. Therefore, the rotary members that do not rotate, for example, during the two-wheel drive state, such as the second output shaft <b>60</b> and the like, are temporarily rotated, so that the contact of the rotary members at fixed portions is restrained. Hence, the partial wear of the rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state is restrained, so that durability can be improved.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0069">Besides, there is no need to provide a mechanism for temporarily rotating the rotary members, such as the second output shaft <b>60</b>, separately from the mechanisms that are normally provided for the travel of the vehicle in the four-wheel drive state in the related art. Therefore, it is possible to improve durability without involving drawbacks of cost increase, space efficiency deterioration, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0070">Besides, for example, if a construction in which the oil OIL gathering in the lower portion of the transfer case <b>42</b> is splashed upward by rotation of rotary members, for example, the driven gear <b>62</b>, the chain <b>64</b>, etc., is adopted, the oil OIL can be splashed upward by temporarily rotating the rotary members, such as the driven gear <b>62</b>, the chain <b>64</b>, etc., so that the oil lubrication of the rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state can be appropriately secured, and so that the partial wear of the rotary members can be further restrained and therefore the durability can be further improved. In this case, since there is no need to increase the amount of oil, it is possible to improve the durability without involving drawbacks, such as deteriorated efficiency caused by increased stirring resistance due to an increase in the amount of oil, or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0071">Furthermore, in the invention, when the foregoing switch to the four-wheel drive state is performed, the disconnected state of one of the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> and the mesh clutch <b>38</b> is maintained, so that the vehicle <b>10</b> as a whole remains in the two-wheel drive state in effect. Therefore, the deterioration of efficiency can be restrained, and the changes in the vehicle behavior caused by switching the vehicle into the four-wheel drive state in effect can be avoided.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0072">Besides, according to the embodiment, when the count value CNT concerning the travel in the two-wheel drive state becomes equal to or greater than the predetermined value CNT&#x2032;, only the state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b> is switched to the four-wheel drive state by putting only the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> into the connected state, without switching the mesh clutch <b>38</b> (the ADD device <b>110</b>), that is, while keeping the mesh clutch <b>38</b> in the disconnected state. Therefore, for example, by putting only the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> into the four-wheel drive state, the rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state, such as second output shaft <b>60</b> and the like, are certainly rotated without transmitting power to the front wheels <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0073">Besides, according to the embodiment, the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> is a power connection/disconnection device that is equipped with a synchromesh mechanism, and the mesh clutch <b>38</b> is a power connection/disconnection device that is not equipped with a synchromesh mechanism. Therefore, for example, in a four-wheel drive vehicle in which the mesh clutch <b>38</b> is not equipped with a synchromesh mechanism and therefore it is difficult to rotate the second output shaft <b>60</b> from the side of the front wheels <b>14</b> through the driving connection with the front wheels <b>14</b> by putting only the mesh clutch <b>38</b> into the connected state during the travel of the vehicle, the embodiment makes it possible to improve the durability by restraining the partial wear of the rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state. Besides, since the mesh clutch <b>38</b> is not equipped with a synchromesh mechanism, for example, the construction of the mesh clutch <b>38</b> can be a simple one, thus improving the cost cut, the space utility, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0074">According to this embodiment, the count value CNT concerning the travel in the two-wheel drive state is the cumulative travel time CNT-T or the cumulative travel distance CNT-D during the two-wheel drive state, so that the state of drive can be temporarily switched to the four-wheel drive state at an appropriate timing (time) such that the fixed-portion contact of the rotary members that do not rotate during, for example, the two-wheel drive state, is restrained.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0075">Besides, according to the embodiment, the count value CNT concerning the travel in the two-wheel drive state is an accumulated value of count values that are obtained when the engine rotation speed N<sub>E </sub>is greater than or equal to the predetermined rotation speed N<sub>E</sub>&#x2032;. Therefore, it is possible to take a countermeasure as described below against the problem in which as the rotation vibration of the engine <b>12</b> that is a source of vibration that causes the striking wear or the like increases with, for example, increases in the engine rotation speed N<sub>E</sub>, it becomes more likely that the local striking wear and the like of rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state, such as the second output shaft <b>60</b> and the like, will progress. That is, in the countermeasure, when the engine rotation speed NE is greater than or equal to the predetermined engine rotation speed NE&#x2032; and therefore the foregoing striking wear and the like are likely to progress, the state of drive is temporarily switched to the four-wheel drive state in an appropriate manner, depending on the then accumulated value of count values mentioned above. In other words, because the switching to the four-wheel drive state is not carried out on the basis of an accumulated value obtained when the engine rotation speed N<sub>E </sub>is less than the predetermined rotation speed N<sub>E</sub>&#x2032; and therefore the progress of the striking wear and the like is unlikely, it is possible to restrain the efficiency deterioration caused by the temporary switching to the four-wheel drive state.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0076">Besides, according to the embodiment, the higher the engine rotation speed N<sub>E</sub>, the smaller the predetermined value CNT&#x2032; is made. Therefore, in conjunction with the problem in which as the rotation vibration of the engine <b>12</b> that is a source of vibration that causes the striking wear or the like increases with, for example, increases in the engine rotation speed N<sub>E</sub>, it becomes more likely that the local striking wear and the like of rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state, such as the second output shaft <b>60</b> and the like, will progress, it is possible to cause the temporary switch to the four-wheel drive state to be performed more readily the higher the engine rotation speed N<sub>E</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0077">While an embodiment of the invention has been described in detail above with reference to the drawings, it is to be understood that the invention is also applicable in other forms as well.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0078">For example, although in the foregoing embodiment, only the state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b> is temporarily switched to the four-wheel drive state by putting only the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> into the connected state when the count value CNT concerning the travel in the two-wheel drive state becomes equal to or greater than the predetermined value CNT&#x2032;, this manner of operation is not essential. For example, it is also permissible to put only the mesh clutch <b>38</b> into the connected state if the mesh clutch <b>38</b> is equipped with a synchromesh mechanism. Besides, it is also permissible to temporarily switch to the ordinary four-wheel drive state by putting both the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> and the mesh clutch <b>38</b> into the connected state. In short, the invention is applicable to any construction as long as the state of drive is temporarily switched to the four-wheel drive state by putting at least one of the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> and the mesh clutch <b>38</b> into the connected state when the count value CNT concerning the travel in the two-wheel drive state becomes equal to or greater than the predetermined value CNT&#x2032;. In such constructions, it is possible to achieve a certain degree of effect of improving durability by restraining the partial wear of the rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state, as in the foregoing embodiment. Besides, other effects can also be achieved, including improvement of the durability without involving drawbacks of cost increase, space efficiency deterioration, etc., appropriate securement of oil lubrication, improvement of the durability without involving drawbacks of efficiency deterioration due to increased stirring resistance involved with an increase in the amount of oil, and the like, restraint of efficiency deterioration, and avoidance of changes in the vehicle behavior caused by the switching to the four-wheel drive state in effect.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0079">Besides, in the foregoing embodiment, the predetermined switch time T<b>4</b>wd&#x2032; as a duration for which the state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b> is forced to be switched and held to the four-wheel drive state is such as to appropriately secure the lubricating performance achieved by the oil OIL being splashed by rotation of the driven gear <b>62</b> and the chain <b>64</b>. However, it is not altogether necessary to intend to improve the lubricating performance by splashing the oil OIL upward. For example, it suffices that by forcing the state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b> to switch to the four-wheel drive state, the rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state, such as the second output shaft <b>60</b> and the like, are temporarily rotated, so that the contact of the rotary members at fixed portions (e.g., contact between the second output shaft <b>60</b> and the bearings <b>56</b> and <b>58</b>) is restrained. That is, the duration for which the state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b> is forced to be switched to the four-wheel drive state may be much shorter than the predetermined switch time T<b>4</b>wd&#x2032; set for appropriately securing the lubricating performance. In another view, the power transmitted to the second output shaft <b>60</b> when the state of drive of the transfer <b>24</b> is forced to switch to the four-wheel drive state may be smaller than the power needed for splashing the oil OIL upward by rotation of the rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state. That is, the power transmitted to the second output shaft <b>60</b> when the state of drive in the transfer <b>24</b> is forced to switch to the four-wheel drive state does not need to be as large as the power needed for splashing the oil OIL upward, but may appropriately be as large as the power needed for temporarily rotating the rotary members, for example, the second output shaft <b>60</b> and the like, so that at least the foregoing contact at fixed portions is restrained. In this manner, too, it is possible to achieve a certain degree of effect of improving the durability by restraining the partial wear of the rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state, such as the second output shaft <b>60</b> and the like. Besides, it is also possible to restrain the efficiency deterioration caused by the oil OIL being splashed upward by rotation of the rotary members that do not rotate during the two-wheel drive state, such as the second output shaft <b>60</b> and the like. Besides, it is also possible to achieve the effects of improving the durability without involving drawbacks of cost increase, space efficiency deterioration, etc., and restraining efficiency deterioration and avoiding changes in the vehicle behavior caused by the switching to the four-wheel drive state in effect. Incidentally, in the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b>, the power transmitted to the second output shaft <b>60</b> can be made smaller than the power needed for splashing the oil OIL upward by rotation of the rotary members, such as the second output shaft <b>60</b> and the like, by, for example, stopping the movement of the sleeve <b>90</b> toward the clutch gear <b>92</b> during a transitional state in which the inner peripheral teeth of the sleeve <b>90</b> and the outer peripheral teeth of the synchronizer ring <b>94</b> are in contact with each other before the sleeve <b>90</b> and the clutch gear <b>92</b> mesh in an action of the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b>, and then moving the sleeve <b>90</b> back to a side opposite the clutch gear <b>92</b> side.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0080">Besides, the foregoing embodiment is an embodiment in which the invention is applied to the vehicle <b>10</b> equipped with the transfer <b>24</b> that has the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> that is a Warner-type synchronous mesh device that is equipped with a single synchronizer ring <b>94</b> and performs a synchronous action using the synchronizer ring <b>94</b>. However, this does not limit the invention; that is, the invention is suitably applicable to four-wheel drive vehicles equipped with a transfer that has a constant-load type synchronous mesh device or a so-called multi-cone synchromesh mechanism that is made up of an outer synchronizer ring and an inner synchronizer ring that each have a cone surface (tapered surface) as well as a middle ring that is disposed between the outer and inner synchronizer rings and that has tapered surfaces that slide respectively on the tapered surfaces of the synchronizer rings, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0081">Besides, in the foregoing embodiment, the invention is applied to the synchromesh mechanism <b>54</b> of a type in which the sleeve <b>90</b> is moved in the direction along the axis by the second shift fork shaft <b>100</b> that is mechanically moved in the left and right directions by driving the shift actuator <b>84</b>. However, the invention can be suitably applied to a type of transfer that performs a switching control by moving the sleeve <b>90</b> in the axis direction by a drive device such as a hydraulic actuator or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0082">Besides, in the foregoing embodiment, the invention is applied to the vehicle <b>10</b> whose basic arrangement is a front-mounted engine rear-wheel drive (FR) arrangement, more specifically, the vehicle <b>10</b> whose rear wheels <b>16</b> are the main driving wheels and whose front wheels <b>14</b> are auxiliary driving wheels. However, the invention can also be suitably applied to a four-wheel drive vehicle whose basic arrangement is a front-mounted engine front wheel drive (FF) arrangement, that is, a vehicle whose front wheels <b>14</b> are the main driving wheels and whose rear wheels <b>16</b> are auxiliary driving wheels. In short, the invention is suitably applicable to any four-wheel drive vehicle of a so-called part-time 4WD type that is capable of switching between the two-wheel drive state and the four-wheel drive state.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0083">Besides, the foregoing embodiment is mere an embodiment, and the invention can also be carried out with various modifications and improvements on the basis of the knowledge of a person having ordinary skill in the art.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A control apparatus for a four-wheel drive vehicle that is capable of switching a state of drive between a two-wheel drive state in which the vehicle travels by transmitting power provided by a drive force source only from a main drive shaft to main driving wheels and a four-wheel drive state in which the vehicle travels by transmitting the power to the main driving wheels, and also by transmitting the power from the main drive shaft to an auxiliary drive shaft by putting into a connected state a first power connection/disconnection device capable of connecting and disconnecting a power transmission path between the main drive shaft and the auxiliary drive shaft, and by transmitting the power from the auxiliary drive shaft to auxiliary driving wheels by putting into the connected state a second power connection/disconnection device capable of connecting and disconnecting a power transmission path between the auxiliary drive shaft and the auxiliary driving wheels, the control apparatus comprising
<claim-text>a control portion that puts both the first power connection/disconnection device and the second power connection/disconnection device into a disconnected state when the state of drive is switched to the two-wheel drive state, the control portion temporarily switches only one of the first power connection/disconnection device and the second power connection/disconnection device into the connected state when a count value concerning a travel of the vehicle in the two-wheel drive state becomes equal to or greater than a predetermined value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The control apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the four-wheel drive vehicle has a construction in which an oil for lubrication is splashed upward by rotation of the auxiliary drive shaft; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the power that is transmitted to the auxiliary drive shaft, when the control portion temporarily switched only one of the first power connection/disconnection device and the second power connection/disconnection device into the connected state when the count value concerning the travel of the vehicle in the two-wheel drive state becomes equal to or greater than the predetermined value, is smaller than the power for splashing the oil upward by rotation of the auxiliary drive shaft.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The control apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein when the count value concerning the travel in the two-wheel drive state becomes equal to or greater than the predetermined value, the state of drive is temporarily switched by putting the first power connection/disconnection device into the connected state while maintaining the disconnected state of the second power connection/disconnection device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The control apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the first power connection/disconnection device is a power connection/disconnection device that includes a synchromesh mechanism; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second power connection/disconnection device is a power connection/disconnection device that does not include a synchromesh mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The control apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the count value concerning the travel in the two-wheel drive state is a cumulative travel time in the two-wheel drive state or a cumulative travel distance in the two-wheel drive state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The control apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the count value concerning the travel in the two-wheel drive state is an accumulated value obtained when a value related to rotation speed of the drive force source is greater than or equal to a predetermined rotation speed.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The control apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the predetermined value is reduced with increases in a value related to rotation speed of the drive force source.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A four-wheel drive vehicle that is capable of switching a state of drive between a two-wheel drive state in which the vehicle travels by transmitting power provided by a drive force source only from a main drive shaft to main driving wheels and a four-wheel drive state in which the vehicle travels by transmitting the power to the main driving wheels, and also by transmitting the power from the main drive shaft to an auxiliary drive shaft by putting into a connected state a first power connection/disconnection device capable of connecting and disconnecting a power transmission path between the main drive shaft and the auxiliary drive shaft, and by transmitting the power from the auxiliary drive shaft to auxiliary driving wheels by putting into the connected state a second power connection/disconnection device capable of connecting and disconnecting a power transmission path between the auxiliary drive shaft and the auxiliary driving wheels, the four-wheel drive vehicle comprising
<claim-text>a control apparatus that puts both the first power connection/disconnection device and the second power connection/disconnection device into a disconnected state when the state of drive is switched to the two-wheel drive state, a control portion temporarily switches only one of the first power connection/disconnection device and the second power connection/disconnection device into the connected state when a count value concerning a travel of the vehicle in the two-wheel drive state becomes equal to or greater than a predetermined value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A method of controlling a four-wheel drive vehicle, the method comprising:
<claim-text>switching a state of drive between a two-wheel drive state in which the vehicle travels by transmitting power provided by a drive force source only from a main drive shaft to main driving wheels and a four-wheel drive state in which the vehicle travels by transmitting the power to the main driving wheels, and also by transmitting the power from the main drive shaft to an auxiliary drive shaft by putting into a connected state a first power connection/disconnection device capable of connecting and disconnecting a power transmission path between the main drive shaft and the auxiliary drive shaft, and by transmitting the power from the auxiliary drive shaft to auxiliary driving wheels by putting into the connected state a second power connection/disconnection device capable of connecting and disconnecting a power transmission path between the auxiliary drive shaft and the auxiliary driving wheels, wherein both the first power connection/disconnection device and the second power connection/disconnection device are put into a disconnected state when the state of drive is switched to the two-wheel drive state;</claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting a count value concerning a travel of the vehicle in the two-wheel drive state; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>temporarily switching only one of the first power connection/disconnection device and the second power connection/disconnection device into the connected state when the count value becomes equal to or greater than a predetermined value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
