<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625835-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625835</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13584266</doc-number>
<date>20120813</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>25</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>N</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>381380</main-classification>
<further-classification>  2209</further-classification>
<further-classification>  2 69</further-classification>
<further-classification>381388</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Apparel with built-in headphone extension wire device</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4993065</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Chiou</name>
<date>19910200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>379430</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6466681</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Siska et al.</name>
<date>20021000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>381372</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7519192</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Laycock et al.</name>
<date>20090400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>381301</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8280038</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Johnson et al.</name>
<date>20121000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>379430</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0110529</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Semcken</name>
<date>20110500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>381 74</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0299714</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ma et al.</name>
<date>20111200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>381384</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2013/0095701</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Golko et al.</name>
<date>20130400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439660</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>3</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>381380</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>  2100-250</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>11</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>12</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>61523326</doc-number>
<date>20110813</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130044908</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130221</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gotlieb</last-name>
<first-name>Lawrence Mark</first-name>
<address>
<city>Encino</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gotlieb</last-name>
<first-name>Lawrence Mark</first-name>
<address>
<city>Encino</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Ensey</last-name>
<first-name>Brian</first-name>
<department>2652</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Yu</last-name>
<first-name>Norman</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present invention provides for the embodiments for a combined apparel and conductive extension wire assembly to bridge connectivity between a portable audio listening devices and transducers that emit audio sounds. The combined garment and extension wire assembly comprises of a garment (such as a shirt, jacket, cap, etc.) having an electrical wire with a connector on one end positioned within the interior of a garment pocket for conductive connectivity to the audio output of a portable listening device held within said pocket. The extension wire assembly shall channel through the interior of the garment through passageways or within garment seams, extending to garment apertures wherein a left and right channel wire shall respectively pass through and exit the apparel fabric having each wire ending with a connector enabling further conductive connectivity respectively to left and right channel transducers emitting audio sounds.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="191.26mm" wi="192.02mm" file="US08625835-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="219.46mm" wi="194.14mm" file="US08625835-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="157.82mm" wi="135.21mm" file="US08625835-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="168.40mm" wi="98.38mm" file="US08625835-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="233.60mm" wi="182.03mm" file="US08625835-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="217.85mm" wi="196.77mm" file="US08625835-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="213.61mm" wi="195.24mm" file="US08625835-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="204.72mm" wi="109.98mm" file="US08625835-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="193.12mm" wi="107.36mm" file="US08625835-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="153.67mm" wi="139.95mm" file="US08625835-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="208.87mm" wi="173.65mm" file="US08625835-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="245.19mm" wi="174.67mm" file="US08625835-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present non-provisional patent application claims the benefit of priority filing date of U.S. Provisional Patent Application No. 61/523,326, which is entitled &#x201c;APPAREL WITH BUILT-IN HEADPHONE EXTENSION WIRE DEVICE&#x201d; which was filed on Aug. 13, 2011, and which is incorporated in full by reference herein.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The invent for the merger of textiles and electronics has dated back for over a half a century when Claude Shannon and Edward O. Thorp created the first wearable computer used to predict the outcome of the gambling roulette wheel. Since then, other designers have created product that integrate electronic listening devices into apparel. One general category of designs provides for earphones that are permanently affixed to the article of clothing. While a second general category provides for the entire manual installation and removal of all electronic component parts within a garment. The present invention provides for a headphone extension wire device to be made permanently affixed to and a part of an apparel garment. The headphone extension wire device is to bridge the conductive connection between the audio output port of a personal portable electronic listening device and the stereo mini-plugs of a headphone set. Having concealed wiring configured within the confines of the garment provides a great utility to the user in that there will be no tangling of wires when using a portable listening device. Additionally, the user will avoid dangling wires that often get snagged and pulled such that the earphones become either dislodged or misaligned from the user's ears. The foregoing problem is especially prevalent with rigorous activities such as exercise, which is often a time of high preference for use of a portable listening device.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention provides for the integration of electrical connectors with conductive wiring that is permanently embedded within an apparel article to provide for the interconnection between conductive elements without a break in conductivity therebetween during use. The present invention also provides for complementary electrical connectors enabling the connector joints to be broken repeatedly by attachment and detachment of the contact supporting structure of each connector.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">As used herein, &#x201c;earbud,&#x201d; &#x201c;headphone&#x201d; and &#x201c;earphone&#x201d; mean any device placed in or on the human ear for producing audible sound. As used herein, &#x201c;electronic devices&#x201d; means any portable electronic entertainment apparatus, such as an MP3 player, radio, television, tape or compact disc player, electronic game, multimedia computer, walkie talkie, or cellular telephone. As used herein, &#x201c;apparel,&#x201d; &#x201c;textile&#x201d;, &#x201c;garment&#x201d; and &#x201c;clothing&#x201d; shall mean clothing that a human being wears, such as a sweatshirt, hooded sweatshirt, jacket, hooded jacket, t-shirt, tank top t-shirt, collared shirt, hats, baseball caps, etc. This invention shall not be limited to the styles of apparel, and shall encompass any cut of cloth, fabric or material worn by a person that can feasibly encapsulate the spirit of this invention.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PRIOR ART</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Wired clothing having various designs, structures and configurations have been disclosed in the prior art. Prior art does not teach or disclose the use of a headphone extension wire device of the present invention that connects to an electronic device held within a pocket to a garment on the one end, and to headphone mini plugs on the other end having the design, structure and configuration of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Accordingly, it is an object of the present invention to provide a headphone extension wire device made permanently apart of and embedded within an apparel garment. It is a further object of the present invention to resolve problems faced with prior art as well as improve upon prior inventions by providing further utilities to the user that the prior art cannot offer.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">An example of wired clothing having various designs, structures and configurations shall been disclosed in the prior art for, U.S. Pat. No. 8,107,653 to James Wolfe (Venice, Calif.) that discloses wired clothing that houses earbuds and wiring within a hooded garments, wherein the wiring apparatus and earbuds are permanently affixed and/or embedded within a hooded garment.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The disclosure of the Wolfe invention embodies the entire wire with earbud apparatus to be permanently affixed to the garment. Such method is problematic in that it does not provide for an economically reasonable means to repair or replace broken wires or when a transducer speaker no longer functions. Repairing the speaker by replacement is impractical and often cost prohibitive relative to the inexpensive garment product as a whole. With no reasonable means to repair or replace a broken speaker, the garment is rendered to be no more than a regular article of clothing, and thereby loses perhaps its greatest functionality and differentiating attribute. The present invention alleviates the problem of broken speakers as the speaker itself is not permanently affixed to the apparel, and may effortlessly be interchangeable with a working replacement.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The Wolfe invention having apparel with permanently built-in earphones may be problematic for the consumer inasmuch as the length of the wire may not be desirable (the wire that extends from the earbud to the exit point from within the apparel at the neckline). The present invention alleviates this potential annoyance, as the consumer may have selective variations of the length of the wire and choose an optimal length for comfort and appearance. As well, the consumer may have choice not to connect any headphone attachment when wearing the apparel and not using a listening device.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Apparel with permanently built-in earphones is restrictive in its maintenance. Current technology for earbuds is such that the earbud itself, while may be made to be waterproof, still remains sensitive to heat temperatures. By permanently affixing the earbuds to the garment, the textile will likewise be restrictive to heat inasmuch as the garment may only be washed and dried with restrictively low temperatures to protect the integrity of the permanently attached earbud. The present invention alleviates the restrictive nature of the current product as the headphones are removable from the apparel and the garment itself may be separately washed and dried at varied degrees of temperatures without the threat of damage to the speakers.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">A second example of prior art is U.S. Pat. No. 7,519,192 to Logan Laycock, Landon Laycock and Larry R. Laycock (Alpine, Utah), that discloses wired clothing that houses headphones and wiring within a hooded garments, wherein the entire wiring apparatus including the earbuds affixed to the wiring, may be removed in its entirety. Such method is cumbersome and may be a great annoyance to the user as each time the wire assembly is to be removed, the user must reassemble the wiring by threading and fastening the passageways. In practice the garment will likely require the turning of the garment inside-out to accomplish the threading and reassembling of the wiring, and take an extensive period of time with undue frustration.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In addition to the problems resolved for prior art, another object of the present invention is to provide further utilities to the consumer by allowing for the removal of the headphone attachment assembly. A great benefit is offered to the consumer by providing quality choice selection for the speakers, and aesthetic variety wherein prior art patents do not disclose the design, structure and configuration of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The detachable headphone attachment assembly provides a consumer with choice of style of headphones whether it be earbuds, over-the-ear headphones, on-ear headphones, sports headphones, or other design configurations now known or to be developed. As well, having the detachable feature from the garment provides to the user with the ability to use the headphones on their own, or with other garments styles of the present invention. This feature becomes more relevant upon expending a high cost for high quality expensive earphones.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In recent years many companies have come to market various designs for their earbuds. Many consider the earbud as a fashion accessory, and the multitude of designs variations in the marketplace reflect demand for aesthetic selection of the earbud. The present invention would allow for the consumer with choice and opportunity to provide change for the overall look of the clothing, by making available different earbud and lanyard designs and colors that may accessorize the garment.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The present invention provides for a headphone extension wire device made permanently affixed to and a part of an apparel garment. The headphone extension wire device includes an elongated cable wire having a first end to be connected to audio output port of a portable electronic listening device and a dual second end consisting of a left ear headphone connector port, and right ear headphone connector port. The headphone extension wire device on the first end shall have a male connector held within a pocket of the apparel garment that shall be dedicated to carry a portable electronic listening device. The dual connector ports on the other end of the extension wire shall be suspended outside the garment, and shall be used to receive the complementary connection jacks of a left transducer and right transducer of an accessory headphone attachment assembly. Additionally, the extension wire shall be configured to allow for the attachment of an earphone with microphone assembly to be used with a cellular telephone. Between the ends of the extension wire device will be the conductive wiring comprising of a right channel wire and left channel wire that shall be permanently affixed to the interior of the garment.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWING</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Further objects, features, and advantages of the present invention will become apparent upon the consideration of the following detailed description of the presently-preferred embodiment when taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a front view of an exemplary garment with the embedded headphone extension wire device according to the preferred embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> illustrates a partial front view of an exemplary garment near the neckline showing one of the two connecting ports of the headphone extension wire device;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> illustrates a partial front view of garment showing the extension wire connector jack within a pocket. It further illustrates a slit in the fabric on the inside of the pocket wherein the connector jack and connected wire is threaded through to the interior of the pocket;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> illustrates a partial front view of the garment showing the left earphone and right earphone connecting ports of the extension wire device and the headphone attachment assembly exemplified with earbuds;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref> illustrates an alternative headphone attachment assembly incorporating a microphone and earbud speaker attachment device intended for use with a hands-free cellular phone;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a front view of an exemplary garment with the embedded headphone extension wire device with an attached headphone attachment assembly according to the preferred embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates a front view of an exemplary garment with the embedded headphone extension wire device with a method to attach over-the-ear headphones according to an embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates a left side view of an exemplary garment with the embedded headphone extension wire device according to an embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates a right side view of an exemplary garment with the embedded headphone extension wire device according to an embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates a partial left side view with the extension wire device connected to an exemplary portable electronic device that is held within the pocket of the garment.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> illustrates a rear view of an exemplary garment with the embedded headphone extension wire device according to an embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> illustrates the headphone attachment assembly method of connecting to a &#x2018;Y&#x2019; adapter device, to be used as a listening device separate and apart from the garment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The combined apparel with embedded headphone extension wire device <b>1</b> and its component parts of the preferred embodiment of the present invention are represented in detail by <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 8</figref> of the drawings. The present invention consists of three component part categories that combine together for the preferred embodiment of the combined apparel with embedded headphone extension wire device <b>1</b>, namely, (1) apparel item <b>1</b><i>a</i>, (2) extension wire device <b>101</b> and (3) headphone attachment assembly (<b>100</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>; <b>200</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The first component part category of apparel is exemplified in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 8</figref> of the drawings as a t-shirt <b>1</b><i>a</i>. Although garment <b>1</b><i>a </i>is portrayed in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1 through 8</figref> as a t-shirt, garment <b>1</b><i>a </i>may include any clothing that a human being wears, such as a sweatshirt, hooded sweatshirt, jacket, hooded jacket, t-shirt, tank top t-shirt, collared shirt, overalls, swimwear, wetsuit, hats, baseball caps or any cut of cloth that can feasibly encapsulate the spirit of this invention. The garment <b>1</b><i>a </i>shall be designed to include a pocket <b>2</b> to hold a portable electronic listening device, such as an MP3 player, cellular telephone, walkie talkie, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Garment pocket <b>2</b> is exemplary in nature, and is depicted on garment <b>1</b><i>a </i>of the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1 through 8</figref> of the drawings on the exterior left side bottom portion of the garment (where all references to left and right is from the perspective of the user). Pocket <b>2</b> may be positioned elsewhere on garment <b>1</b><i>a </i>and be configured in such a manner consistent with the present invention. The pocket <b>2</b> on the apparel is configured to be sized in a manner large enough to be consistent to hold a portable electronic listening device. Pocket <b>2</b> is exemplary in nature, and may be designed with an opening on the top or side of the pocket which will allow for the ingress/egress of a portable electronic listening device. Alternatively, pocket <b>2</b> may be configured with a means of open and closure of the pocket by design of a zipper, Velcro&#xae; (Registered Trademark), or as in one embodiment, with a flap <b>103</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The flap <b>103</b> may be unsecured or secured by a latching device such as a button, magnet, Velcro&#xae; or the like, not illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">For garments comprising of a style with a hood, such as a hooded sweatshirt, hooded jacket, hooded t-shirt, etc., such articles of clothing typically are constructed with a drawstring to control the opening and closing of the hood's opening surrounding the user's face when the hood is positioned to cover the user's head. For hooded garments, the drawstrings are a functioning aspect of the garment, independent from the present invention. The present invention shall be configured in hooded garments, separate and apart from any drawstrings for the hood, and shall operate independently from the hood's drawstrings.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The second component part category of the present invention is the extension wire device <b>101</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 8</figref> of the drawings. The extension wire device <b>101</b> shall comprise on one end with connector jack <b>4</b> to be inserted into the output audio port of a portable listening device. The other end of the extension wire device shall comprise of a right connector jack <b>15</b><i>a </i>and left connector jack <b>15</b><i>b </i>that will be used to connect to the headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b> or <b>200</b> (more fully described below). Between the ends of the extension wire device shall be a conductive cable consisting of a left channel wire and right channel wire, and be configured with the apparel as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 8</figref> of the drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The third component part category of the present invention is the headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b> or <b>200</b>. The headphone attachment assembly shall consist on one end with a right <b>16</b><i>a</i>, <b>16</b><i>d </i>and left <b>16</b><i>b</i>, <b>16</b><i>c</i>, <b>16</b><i>e </i>connector jacks and on the other end shall respectively consist of a right <b>19</b><i>a</i>, <b>202</b><i>d </i>and left <b>19</b><i>b</i>, <b>19</b><i>c</i>, <b>202</b><i>e </i>transducer that shall emit sounds. The ends shall be joined together by a conductive electrical wire. Illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A</figref>, <b>2</b>B, and <b>3</b> are transducers <b>19</b><i>a</i>, <b>19</b><i>b</i>, <b>19</b><i>c </i>that are inserted into the user's ear canal and are commonly known as earbuds. Illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> are transducers <b>202</b><i>d</i>, <b>202</b><i>e </i>that are placed over the user's ears and are commonly known as over-the-ear headphones <b>200</b><i>a</i>. The transducers illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A through 4</figref> are exemplary and other styles of transducers that emit sounds may be configured and designed in such a manner consistent with the present invention including on-ear headphones, sports earbuds, clip earbuds, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">All lanyards <b>13</b><i>a</i>, <b>13</b><i>b</i>, <b>17</b><i>a</i>, <b>17</b><i>b</i>, <b>17</b><i>c</i>, <b>17</b><i>d</i>, <b>17</b><i>e </i>illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-9</figref> provide for nothing other than aesthetic appeal. The current invention may be constructed without having the lanyard house any of the corresponding wiring and shall function no differently.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is an illustration of an alternative use for the headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b> separate and apart from use with the headphone extension wire device embedded within the garment <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a combined garment and embedded headphone extension wire device <b>1</b>, in accordance with the present invention. To operate, the garment and headphone extension wire device <b>1</b> will require the connection of an headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b>, not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, and discussed in greater detail below. The combined garment, headphone extension wire device <b>1</b> shall include an embedded headphone extension wire device <b>101</b>, which shall permanently be affixed and made a part of the garment and shall be described in greater detail below. To fully operate and produce audio sounds he combined garment, headphone extension wire device <b>1</b> shall require an headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b> comprising of a right earphone assembly <b>100</b><i>a </i>and a left earphone assembly <b>100</b><i>b</i>, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A</figref>, <b>3</b> and described in greater detail below. Alternatively, the combined garment, headphone extension wire device <b>1</b> may operate with over-the-ear headphone attachment assembly <b>200</b> comprising of a right earphone transducer <b>202</b><i>d </i>and a left earphone transducer <b>202</b><i>e</i>, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> and described in greater detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In one embodiment, as show in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, having the pocket <b>2</b> on the exterior of the garment, a cutting of the interior fabric creating slit <b>5</b> is to allow for the threading of the male jack connector <b>4</b> and a portion of the extension wire <b>6</b> of the headphone extension wire device <b>101</b> to the interior of the pocket <b>2</b>. Headphone extension wire device <b>101</b> may be comprised on one end with a male headphone jack connector <b>4</b>, comprised of a 3.5 mm TRRS (Tip, Ring, Ring, Sleeve) 4 conductor male plug <b>3</b> format. Further description of the male jack connector <b>4</b> is discussed below. Connector <b>4</b> shall be threaded from within the interior of the garment, through slit <b>5</b> and loosely be held within the interior of the pocket <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">It is not intended that connector <b>4</b> be restrictive to only a 3.5 mm TRRS format and other connector configurations may be employed including but not limited to a 3 conductor TRS connector, 2.5 mm jack sizing, and any other type of connector, now known, or to be commonly employed in the future, for the purpose of connecting the audio output port of a portable listening device to the headphone extension wire device <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In one embodiment of this invention, as show in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a cable <b>6</b> comprising of two conductive electrical wires, having one wire designated for the right channel, and the second wire designated for the left channel shall connect from the male jack plug connector <b>4</b> thread through slit <b>5</b> and be sewn into the fabric of the seem to garment <b>1</b><i>a </i>on the left side. At the point where the lower portion of the sleeve meets with the left side seem <b>6</b><i>a</i>, the wire shall continue therefrom and be sewn into the seem of the sleeve on the back left side of the garment <b>7</b>. At the point where the top portion of the sleeve meets with the top left shoulder seem <b>7</b><i>a</i>, the wire shall continue therefrom and be sewn into the seem of the shoulder on the garment's top <b>8</b> and extend until the point where the dual wire shall separate into two single wire extensions within the top left section of the garment's collar <b>9</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In a different embodiment of the invention, not herein shown, additional fabric may be sewn and affixed to the interior of the garment <b>1</b><i>a </i>to create an internal passageway into which the wire of the headphone extension wire device shall be threaded and held on the left side of the garment and similarly follow the path of sewn-in wire <b>6</b>, <b>7</b>, <b>8</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In a different embodiment of the invention, not herein shown, the fabric pattern of the garment <b>1</b><i>a </i>may strategically be cut longer on one end such that when sewn at the seems an elongated fabric will be on the inside of the garment <b>1</b><i>a</i>. Said elongated fabric shall be folded and sewn at the seem line thus creating an elongated passageway into which the headphone extension wire <b>101</b> may be threaded.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The configuration of the path of wire extension device <b>101</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is one embodiment of the invention. The extension wire device <b>101</b> may be configured to take on a different path on the interior of the garment <b>1</b><i>a </i>dependant on the cut pattern of the garment <b>1</b><i>a</i>, and the choice placement for pocket <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In one embodiment of the invention, as show in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the garment's <b>1</b><i>a </i>collar <b>102</b> is comprised of sewn fabric to the body of the garment <b>1</b><i>a </i>at the neckline, wherein there is a folded fabric creating an outer fabric surface of the collar fabric, inner fabric surface of the collar, and a hollowing within the fold creating the inner surface. That portion of wire <b>8</b> of the headphone extension wire <b>101</b> is threaded through to the interior hollowed surface of the garment collar <b>102</b> wherein the dual wire is split into two individual wires at the split point <b>9</b>. Also, at the split point <b>9</b> a securing device will be applied to ensure that the wires do not further separate.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Extending from the split point <b>9</b>, is the single left side extension wire section <b>10</b> that is threaded inside the hollowing inner surface of the collar <b>102</b> on the left side neck line of collar <b>102</b>. The exterior fabric of collar <b>102</b> on the left side will have an exit hole <b>12</b><i>b </i>from which left extension wire section <b>10</b> will exit collar <b>102</b> and continue within the left hollowed lanyard <b>13</b><i>b</i>. Left wire section <b>14</b><i>b </i>shall continue within the hollowing of the lanyard <b>13</b><i>b </i>from the hole <b>12</b><i>b </i>and end by connecting to the left female connector <b>15</b><i>b</i>. The left female connector <b>15</b><i>b </i>shall consists of a TRS female connector port <b>20</b><i>b </i>that will allow for the left audio channel of the left part of the headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b><i>b </i>to be connected (as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>). Headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b><i>b </i>may be substituted with headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b><i>c </i>for use with a cellular telephone. The configuration of headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b><i>c </i>is discussed in greater detail below. (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>)</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Extending from the dual wire split point <b>9</b>, is the right extension wire section <b>11</b> that is threaded inside the hollowing inner surface of the collar <b>102</b> and is threaded through the collar <b>102</b> and extend through the back of the garment collar portion in the neckline and continue around the neck and turn and follow towards the front right side of the collar <b>102</b>. The exterior fabric of collar <b>102</b> on the front right side will have an exit hole <b>12</b><i>a </i>from which right extension wire section <b>11</b> will exit collar <b>102</b> and continue embedded within the right hollowed lanyard <b>13</b><i>a</i>. Right wire section <b>14</b><i>a </i>shall continue within the hollowing of the lanyard <b>13</b><i>a </i>from the hole <b>12</b><i>a </i>and end by connecting to the right female connector <b>15</b><i>a</i>. The right female connector <b>15</b><i>a </i>consists of a connector that will allow for the right audio channel of the headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b><i>a </i>to be connected (as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In another embodiment of the invention not herein illustrated, cut patterns different than garment <b>1</b><i>a </i>may not include a collar <b>2</b>. Such embodiments of the invention will utilize an extra fabric sewn to the inside of garment that shall be folded with the side ends sewn creating a hollowed passageway for which the extension wire device <b>101</b> may be threaded around the neck of the user. The added fabric shall be sewn into the inside of the garment near the user's neck, and the wiring of the extension wire device <b>101</b> shall be threaded within the hollowing of the extra fabric and follow a similar path as that created by collar <b>102</b> for the portions of wire <b>9</b>, <b>10</b>, <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> the right and left female connectors <b>20</b><i>a </i>and <b>20</b><i>b </i>respectively, will be configured to allow for the connection of a 3.5 mm TRS conductor male jack. The Tip Ring Sleeve format on each connector will allow for use of a earphone attachment assemblies <b>100</b><i>a</i>, <b>100</b><i>b </i>as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>. It will also allow for the connection of earphone/microphone attachment <b>100</b><i>c </i>as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>. Alternatively, the right and left connector <b>15</b><i>a</i>, <b>15</b><i>b </i>may be configured with a male jack which will in turn require the complementary connectors on the headphone attachment assembly <b>16</b><i>a</i>, <b>16</b><i>b </i>be configured with corresponding female connector ports to allow for connectivity (not illustrated in the figures).</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> illustrates a partial view of the left section of the extension wire device from the point of the embedded left channel wire <b>10</b> within collar <b>102</b>, and ending at the left female connector <b>15</b><i>b</i>. Lanyard <b>13</b><i>b </i>shall permanently be affixed on one end (by sewing or otherwise) to the interior hollowing of collar <b>102</b> close to the exit hole <b>12</b><i>b</i>. Lanyard <b>13</b><i>b </i>shall extend through the hole <b>12</b><i>b </i>and continue and end at connector <b>15</b><i>b</i>. Left wire section <b>10</b> of the extension wire device <b>101</b> shall thread through the open end of the lanyard <b>13</b><i>b </i>that is within collar <b>102</b>. Left wire section <b>14</b><i>b </i>shall continue through the hollowing of the lanyard <b>13</b><i>b </i>and attach and be connected to connector <b>15</b><i>b</i>. Left female connector <b>20</b><i>a</i>, will be configured to allow for the connection of the male jack of the headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b><i>b </i>(or <b>100</b><i>c </i>for cellular telephone applications). This portion of the left extension wire assemble described herein for <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>, will have an equivalent configuration for the right side (not herein shown).</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> illustrates a partial view of the garment pocket <b>2</b> containing the male connector <b>4</b> held within the pocket <b>2</b> and connected to extension wire device <b>101</b> at wire section <b>6</b> that is threaded through the interior slit hole <b>5</b>, and leading extension wire section <b>6</b> up the left side of the garment. Male jack <b>3</b> is configured with a TRRS (Tip, Ring, Ring, Sleeve) 4 conductor jack having a tip <b>3</b><i>a </i>to connect to the left channel wire and speaker, first ring <b>3</b><i>b </i>to connect to the right channel wire and speaker, the second ring <b>3</b><i>c </i>to act as the common ground for both the left and right channels, and the sleeve <b>3</b><i>d </i>to connect to the microphone <b>23</b>, when used in conjunction with headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b><i>c </i>(as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>). TRRS male connector jack <b>3</b> is exemplary in nature, and in other embodiments may be configured differently such as a TRS (Tip, Ring, Sleeve) format, 2.5 mm connector jack, or other variations that would be consistent with the use of a portable electronic listening device. Pocket flap <b>103</b> is exemplary in nature and the configuration of pocket <b>2</b> may take on different designs (as previously stated).</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> illustrates a partial view of the earphone extension wire device <b>101</b> at the collar <b>102</b> of the garment and the detached headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b>. The headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b> comprises of a right earphone attachment <b>100</b><i>a </i>and a left earphone attachment <b>100</b><i>b</i>. For operation of audio only, both the right <b>100</b><i>a </i>and left <b>100</b><i>b </i>earphone attachment assemblies are constructed in the same manner. At one end of the assembly is the transducer that emits audio sounds and is exemplified in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> as an earbuds <b>19</b><i>a </i>(on right side), <b>19</b><i>b </i>(on left side). Attached to the earbuds <b>19</b><i>a</i>, <b>19</b><i>b </i>are lanyards <b>17</b><i>a</i>, <b>17</b><i>b </i>(respectively) that will be made of various lengths to provide the user with choice and comfort for their personal preferences. The lanyards <b>17</b><i>a</i>, <b>17</b><i>b </i>shall respectively extend from the earbuds <b>19</b><i>a</i>, <b>19</b><i>b </i>until the male connector on the other end of each assembly <b>16</b><i>a</i>, <b>16</b><i>b </i>(respectively). Threaded within the lanyard <b>17</b><i>a</i>, <b>17</b><i>b </i>is the conductive wiring <b>18</b><i>a</i>, <b>18</b><i>b </i>(respectively) of the headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b> that will attach and bridge the electrical connection between the earbuds <b>19</b><i>a</i>, <b>19</b><i>b </i>and the male connectors <b>16</b><i>a</i>, <b>16</b><i>b </i>(respectively). The male connector <b>16</b><i>a</i>, <b>16</b><i>b </i>will comprise of connector jacks <b>21</b><i>a </i><b>21</b><i>b </i>(respectively). Assembly of the right headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b><i>a </i>will require the insert of the jack <b>21</b><i>a </i>into the complementary right earphone extension wire female connector <b>20</b><i>a</i>. Assembly of the left headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b><i>b </i>will require the insert of the jack <b>21</b><i>b </i>into the left earphone extension wire female connector <b>20</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref> illustrates the headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b><i>c </i>that encompasses the feature of a microphone <b>23</b> to be used as a hands free cellular listening and speaking device. The headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b><i>c </i>comprises of an transducer that emits audio sounds <b>19</b><i>c </i>and is exemplified in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref> as an earbud. Attached to the earbud <b>19</b><i>c </i>is a hollowed lanyard <b>17</b><i>c </i>that will be made of various lengths to provide the user with choice and comfort for their personal preferences. The lanyard <b>17</b><i>c </i>shall extend from the earbud <b>19</b><i>c </i>until the male connector <b>16</b><i>c </i>on the other end of the assembly. Threaded within the lanyard is the conductive wire <b>18</b><i>c </i>that will provide the electrical connection between the earbud <b>19</b><i>c </i>to the microphone <b>23</b> that is embedded within the lanyard <b>17</b><i>c</i>. The microphone <b>23</b> will have the function of transmitting audio sounds for the application of speaking into the cellular telephone when a cellular telephone is used as the portable electronic device for the combined apparel with embedded headphone extension wire device <b>1</b>. Extending from the microphone <b>23</b> is an electrical wire <b>18</b><i>d </i>that will provide the electrical connection between both the earbud <b>19</b><i>c </i>and microphone <b>23</b> to the male connector <b>16</b><i>c</i>. The male connector <b>16</b><i>c </i>will comprise of a TRS connection pin that will allow for audio sounds to travel to the earbud and the use of transmitting audio sounds from the microphone <b>23</b> to the cellular telephone. Assembly to the combined apparel with embedded headphone extension wire device <b>1</b> of the earphone/microphone attachment assembly <b>100</b><i>c </i>will require the insert of the male jack <b>22</b> into the earphone extension wire complementary female connector <b>20</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a combined apparel with embedded headphone extension wire device <b>1</b> exemplified with a t-shirt garment <b>1</b><i>a</i>, embedded extension wire device <b>101</b>, and applied connection of the headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b>, in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates a combined apparel with embedded headphone extension wire device <b>1</b> exemplified with a t-shirt garment <b>1</b><i>a</i>, embedded extension wire device <b>101</b>, and disassembled over-the-ear headphone attachment assembly <b>200</b>, in accordance with the present invention. Over-the-ear headphone attachment assembly <b>200</b> will be comprised of an over-the-ear headphone set <b>200</b><i>a </i>featuring a right and left transducer that emit sounds <b>202</b><i>d</i>, <b>202</b><i>e </i>(respectively). Over-the-ear headphone attachment assembly <b>200</b> also will be comprised of a set of two headphone extension wires <b>200</b><i>b </i>that will bridge connectivity between the over-the-ear headphones <b>200</b><i>a </i>and the extension wire device <b>101</b> of the preferred embodiment of the invention. The right headphone wire extension wire <b>203</b><i>d </i>and left headphone extension wire <b>203</b><i>e </i>will each be configured in the same manner when the over-the-ear attachment assembly <b>200</b> is used for listening only. For utilization of a cellular telephone (not illustrated in the drawings) the left extension wire <b>203</b><i>e </i>may be substituted with another extension wire that utilizes a built-in microphone and configuring said microphone similarly to the configuration of microphone <b>23</b> within headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b><i>c </i>(as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>). The right extension wire <b>203</b><i>d </i>will be comprised of two male connectors <b>16</b><i>d</i>, <b>204</b><i>d </i>one on each end of the extension wire <b>203</b><i>d</i>. Connector <b>16</b><i>d </i>shall be configured with a male jack <b>21</b><i>d </i>to be inserted to the complementary female connector <b>15</b><i>a </i>of the extension wire device <b>101</b>. In another embodiment of this invention the right connector <b>15</b><i>a </i>of the extension wire device <b>101</b> may be constructed with a male jack, thereby requiring complementary connector <b>16</b><i>d </i>to be constructed with a female connector to provide for the proper connection. Right extension wire connectors <b>21</b><i>d</i>, <b>204</b><i>d </i>will be joined together by a conductive electrical wire <b>18</b><i>d </i>that is embedded within the hollow of a lanyard <b>17</b><i>d</i>. Right extension wire connector <b>204</b><i>d </i>will be configured with a male jack <b>205</b><i>d </i>and shall make its electrical connection by insert into the female connector port <b>201</b><i>d </i>of the right transducer <b>202</b><i>d </i>of the over-the-ear headphones <b>200</b><i>a</i>. The left extension wire <b>203</b><i>e </i>shall be similarly constructed, configured, connected, and function as its counterpart extension wire <b>203</b><i>d </i>on the right side (having the left over-the-ear headphone attachment assembly parts <b>21</b><i>e</i>, <b>16</b><i>e</i>, <b>17</b><i>e</i>, <b>18</b><i>e</i>, <b>204</b><i>e</i>, <b>205</b><i>e</i>, <b>201</b><i>e</i>, <b>202</b><i>e </i>respectively correspond with the right side counterparts <b>21</b><i>e</i>, <b>16</b><i>e</i>, <b>17</b><i>e</i>, <b>18</b><i>e</i>, <b>204</b><i>e</i>, <b>205</b><i>e</i>, <b>201</b><i>e</i>, <b>202</b><i>e</i>).</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates a left side perspective view of the combined apparel with embedded headphone extension wire device <b>1</b> exemplified with a t-shirt garment <b>1</b><i>a</i>, embedded extension wire device <b>101</b>, in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates a right side perspective view of the combined apparel with embedded headphone extension wire device <b>1</b> exemplified with a t-shirt garment <b>1</b><i>a</i>, embedded extension wire device <b>101</b>, in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates a partial left side perspective view of an exemplary electronic listening device <b>24</b>, held within pocket <b>2</b>, attached to the earphone extension wire device <b>101</b>. The female output connector port of the electronic portable listening device connected to the male TRRS connector <b>4</b> of the earphone extension wire device <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> illustrates a back-side side perspective view of the combined apparel with embedded headphone extension wire device <b>1</b> exemplified with a t-shirt garment <b>1</b><i>a</i>, embedded extension wire device <b>101</b>, in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> illustrates an alternative function for the headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b> wherein the headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b> may be used separate and apart from the garment <b>1</b><i>a</i>. The headphone attachment assembly <b>100</b> comprised of a right and left transducer for emitting sounds with wire attachment capabilities <b>100</b><i>a</i>, <b>100</b><i>b </i>(respectively) shall connect the male connectors <b>16</b><i>a</i>, <b>16</b><i>b </i>(respectively) by inserting the connector jacks <b>21</b><i>a</i>, <b>21</b><i>b </i>(respectively) respectively into the female connectors <b>25</b><i>a</i>, <b>25</b><i>b </i>(respectively), of &#x2018;Y&#x2019; adapter <b>26</b>. &#x2018;Y&#x2019; adapter <b>26</b> shall have affixed to it a lanyard <b>27</b> leading from adapter <b>26</b> to the male connector <b>29</b>. &#x2018;Y&#x2019; adapter <b>26</b> shall have connected the left channel/right channel cable <b>28</b> leading from adapter <b>26</b> to the male connector <b>29</b>, and embedded within the hollowed lanyard <b>27</b>. Connector <b>29</b> shall have a male TRRS connector jack <b>30</b> to be inserted into an electronic portable listening device, not shown. Not illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is the availability of use with earphone/microphone attachment assembly <b>100</b><i>c </i>to utilize the feature for use with a hands-free cellular phone device. Not illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is the availability and utilization of the over-the-ear headphone attachment assembly <b>200</b> separate and apart from the combined apparel with embedded headphone extension wire device <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Other attachments now know or later to be created may be adaptable to the current invention and enhance the user's experience. For instance, an attachment device (not shown) may connect between the extension wire device <b>101</b> and the portable electronic listening device <b>24</b> that may control certain desirable features such as song play, pause, stop, volume control, and song selections. Further features such as connect/disconnect of a telephone call may be employed when the portable electronic listening device is a cellular telephone.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">While the invention hereinbefore described is effectively adapted to fulfill the aforesaid objects, it is to be understood that the invention is not intended to be limited to the specific preferred embodiment of the garment with headphone extension wire device <b>1</b>. Rather, it is to be taken as including all reasonable equivalents within the scope of the invention.</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">FIELD OF INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The present invention relates to electrical connectors. In particular for electrical connectors integrated with the use of clothing to provide a means of connectivity between portable listening devices such as mp3 players or cellular telephones connecting to headphones such as in-ear, over-the-ear, and the like.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A combined garment and earphones extension wire device, comprising:
<claim-text>a garment having a pocket to house a potable listening device, an aperture on the inside of the pocket creating passage to the interior of said garment, elongated internal passageways beginning adjacent to said pocket and leading to a top left and top right aperture in close proximity to each of the user's ear;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a headphone extension wire device includes an elongated cable wire having a first end with male connector to be connected to an audio output port of a portable electronic listening device and a dual second end extending through said top left and said top right apertures to the opposing end consisting of first left and right audio connector ports respectively;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a hollow first lanyard where said extension wire from said top left and said top right apertures to said audio connector ports threads through;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a headphone attachment assembly having a left and right earphone attachment, said left and right earphone attachments each having an earphone at one end connected to conductive wiring which extends to a second left and right audio connector ports at the opposing end;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said second left and right audio connector ports are connectable to said first left and right audio connector ports;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a hollow second lanyard wherein the conductive wiring between the earphones and the second connector ports threads through.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The combined garment and earphones extension wire device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein extension wire device includes a beginning with a male jack configured in TRRS (Tip, Ring, Ring, Sleeve) 4 conductor jack format providing conductive connection provided for left channel wire, right channel wire, common ground for both the left and right channels, and connection availability for a microphone.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The combined garment and earphones extension wire device as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein extension wire device is comprised of a dual wiring designated for the left channel wire and right channel wire wherein the extension ends with dual left and right channel connector ports suspended outside the garment, enabling complementary connection jacks providing for conductive connection to a left and right transducer. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
