<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625387-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625387</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12498339</doc-number>
<date>20090706</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>897</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>38</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>38</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>3835</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>367 19</main-classification>
<further-classification>367 21</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Methods of range selection for positioning marine seismic equipment</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4376301</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Roberts</name>
<date>19830300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>367 19</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5128904</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Chambers</name>
<date>19920700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>367129</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5359575</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Williams et al.</name>
<date>19941000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>367127</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6411902</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Wiltshire</name>
<date>20020600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>702  7</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7457195</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Jones</name>
<date>20081100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>367 38</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>7</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>367 19</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>1</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>2</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11385159</doc-number>
<date>20060321</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>ABANDONED</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12498339</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20090268552</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20091029</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Frivik</last-name>
<first-name>Svein Arne</first-name>
<address>
<city>Oslo</city>
<country>NO</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>NO</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Combee</last-name>
<first-name>Leendert</first-name>
<address>
<city>Oslo</city>
<country>NO</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>NO</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Frivik</last-name>
<first-name>Svein Arne</first-name>
<address>
<city>Oslo</city>
<country>NO</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Combee</last-name>
<first-name>Leendert</first-name>
<address>
<city>Oslo</city>
<country>NO</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>WesternGeco L.L.C.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Houston</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Breier</last-name>
<first-name>Krystine</first-name>
<department>3645</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A method for selecting a signal arrival for determining an accurate position of seismic equipment includes the steps of transmitting a signal from a pinger; predicting a direct arrival and a reflected arrival of the signal at a receiver, wherein each arrival is the time between the transmission of the signal to reception of the signal; measuring arrivals of the signal at the receiver; selecting the measured signal arrival that is similar to the predicted direct arrival as a preliminary signal arrival; defining a confidence interval for the actual direct arrival of the signal based on the predicted direct arrival and the predicted reflected arrival; and finalizing the signal arrival, wherein the selected preliminary signal arrival is the finalized signal arrival if it is within the confidence interval.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="80.09mm" wi="168.57mm" file="US08625387-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="233.26mm" wi="168.23mm" file="US08625387-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a divisional application of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 11/385,159, filed on Mar. 21, 2006 now abandoned.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates in general to methods for determining the position of seismic spreads and more particularly to a model based range selection method for determining the geometric configuration and position of seismic equipment in a seismic spread.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In underwater acoustic navigation of a marine seismic spread, ranges are measured to determine the geometric relationship between the seismic equipment and a position of the seismic equipment and the spread. An accurate range is the travel time of the direct arrival of a signal from a pinger by a particular receiver. The direct arrival is the acoustic signal traveling along the path of shortest travel time in the water column without being influenced by the reflection from a boundary. Reflections from a boundary, the sea-surface or sea floor, travel a longer distance than the direct arrival signals and are therefore subject to a time delay relative to the direct arrival. Tracking the reflections rather than the direct arrival signals may deteriorate the acoustic ranges and may cause the acoustic network solution to deteriorate, resulting in a deteriorated positioning of the seismic equipment.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Historically, the ranges with time delays due to reflections are filtered to avoid their introduction in the positioning solution. The traditional methods for &#x201c;editing&#x201d; the ranges have been manual, i.e. by adjusting the range by subtracting the effect of the reflection or by setting a range to passive. These prior art methods for editing are manageable for positioning systems that rely on only a few hundred ranges. However, these prior art methods fail when the number of ranges increase. For example, WesternGeco's intrinsic range modulated acoustic ranging system may include more than 10,000 ranges.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Therefore, it is a desire to provide a method of selecting the direct range for accurately positioning marine seismic equipment that addresses drawbacks of the prior art methods. It is a further desire to provide a method of range selection that utilizes information about the seismic spread as well as environmental parameters to predict direct arrival and reflected arrival of a signal by a receiver. It is a still further desire to provide a method for rejecting reflected signals that are received. It is a still further desire to condition a range based on a received reflected signal.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Accordingly, methods for selecting an accurate signal arrival by a receiver from a pinger for accurately positioning seismic equipment are provided. The methods are particularly adapted for ranging systems such as disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 5,668,775, which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">An embodiment of a method for selecting a signal arrival for determining an accurate position of seismic equipment includes the steps of transmitting a signal from a pinger; measuring arrivals of the signal at a receiver, wherein each arrival is the time between the transmission of the signal to reception of the signal; selecting one of the signal arrivals as a preliminary signal arrival; calculating a confidence interval for an estimated direct arrival of the signal; and selecting a final signal arrival, wherein the selected preliminary signal arrival is the selected final signal arrival if it is within the confidence interval.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Another embodiment of a method for selecting a signal arrival for determining an accurate position of seismic equipment includes the steps of transmitting a signal from a pinger; predicting a direct arrival and a reflected arrival of the signal at a receiver, wherein each arrival is the time between the transmission of the signal to reception of the signal; measuring arrivals of the signal at the receiver; selecting the measured signal arrival that is similar to the predicted direct arrival as a preliminary signal arrival; and finalizing the selected signal arrival, wherein the selected preliminary signal arrival is the finalized signal arrival if it correlates with the predicted direct arrival.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">A further embodiment of a method for selecting a signal arrival for determining an accurate position of seismic equipment includes the steps of transmitting a signal from a pinger; predicting a direct arrival and a reflected arrival of the signal at a receiver, wherein each arrival is the time between the transmission of the signal to reception of the signal; measuring arrivals of the signal at the receiver; selecting the measured signal arrival that is similar to the predicted direct arrival as a preliminary signal arrival; defining a confidence interval for the actual direct arrival of the signal based on the predicted direct arrival and the predicted reflected arrival; and finalizing the signal arrival for calculating the receiver position, wherein the selected preliminary signal arrival is the finalized signal arrival if it is within the confidence interval.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The foregoing has outlined the features and technical advantages of the present invention in order that the detailed description of the invention that follows may be better understood. Additional features and advantages of the invention will be described hereinafter which form the subject of the claims of the invention.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The foregoing and other features and aspects of the present invention will be best understood with reference to the following detailed description of a specific embodiment of the invention, when read in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic of an embodiment of a spread seismic equipment of a ranging system of the present invention illustrating the propagation paths of an acoustic event; and</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an embodiment of a method of range selection for accurately positioning marine seismic equipment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Refer now to the drawings wherein depicted elements are not necessarily shown to scale and wherein like or similar elements are designated by the same reference numeral through the several views.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an illustration of an embodiment of a spread of seismic equipment of a seismic positioning system of the present invention, generally designated by the numeral <b>10</b>, illustrated as a shallow water geometry in 2D. Seismic spread <b>10</b> includes at least one streamer <b>12</b> having at least one pinger <b>14</b> and a plurality of receivers <b>16</b>. As is well known in the art, a seismic spread commonly includes multiple streamers <b>12</b> each of which includes a plurality of pingers <b>14</b> and receivers <b>16</b>. The geographic location of at least one point in the spread is typically known from convention means, such as a global positioning system. For example, the geographic location of pinger <b>14</b> may be determined by a global positioning system.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">An acoustic transmitter <b>14</b>, also referred to as a pinger, produces an acoustic event that is recorded by the plurality of receivers <b>16</b>. Each receiver <b>16</b> receives an acoustic signal from pinger <b>14</b> at two different times, a direct wave <b>18</b> arrival and a reflected wave <b>20</b> arrival.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">As shown in relation to receiver <b>16</b><i>a</i>, pinger <b>14</b> creates an acoustic event. The direct wave <b>18</b><i>a </i>is the acoustic event traveling the shortest distance in the water column without being influenced by a boundary <b>21</b> and provides the desired direct or accurate range <b>22</b><i>a </i>for positioning the seismic equipment. In the illustration of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, boundary <b>21</b> is the seafloor but may be the water surface. Reflection <b>20</b><i>a </i>travels a longer distance than direct wave <b>18</b><i>a </i>and therefore its arrival at receiver <b>16</b><i>a </i>is time delayed. An accurate range <b>22</b><i>a </i>for receiver or hydrophone <b>16</b><i>a </i>is determined by the travel time of direct wave <b>18</b><i>a</i>. Thus, it is necessary to detect and track the arrival of direct wave <b>18</b><i>a </i>and not the arrival time of reflections <b>20</b><i>a </i>to determine range <b>22</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">An accurate image of the spread of the seismic equipment and its geographic position is necessary for a proper acoustic network. In a ranging positioning system <b>10</b> independent of water depth <b>24</b>, it is desired to range as long as possible to ensure that all ranges <b>22</b> (short and long) make a proper acoustic network.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Tracking reflection <b>20</b> arrivals, rather than direct wave <b>18</b> arrivals, may deteriorate acoustic ranges <b>22</b> due to the time delay of the arrival of reflection <b>20</b> at a particular receiver <b>16</b>. This deterioration or break down in the positioning estimates for the seismic equipment is most common in shallow water environments, but also occurs in deeper waters when the seismic spread is towed deep. In shallow water, typically less than 30 to 40 meters, the ratio of range <b>22</b> length to water depth <b>24</b> becomes high (much greater than 10). Thus, the time delay between the arrival of direct wave <b>18</b> and reflection wave <b>20</b> becomes smaller as a function of offsets, and accurate selection of ranges <b>22</b> becomes more difficult.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a diagram of an embodiment of a method of positioning seismic equipment, generally denoted by the numeral <b>26</b>. Method <b>26</b> is described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, and more particularly in relation to receiver <b>16</b><i>a </i>and pinger <b>14</b> for purposes of simplicity. Method <b>26</b> includes: step <b>28</b>&#x2014;measuring ranges; step <b>30</b>&#x2014;selecting an initial range; step <b>32</b>&#x2014;predicting a direct range; step <b>34</b>&#x2014;finalizing range selection; and step <b>36</b>&#x2014;determining the position of the seismic equipment.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Range prediction step <b>32</b> includes estimating the arrival time of direct wave <b>18</b><i>a </i>and reflection <b>20</b><i>a </i>at receiver <b>16</b><i>a</i>, and the difference between the arrival times, thereby predicting the direct range. The predicted direct ranges for each receiver is calculated using the sound speed profile, pinger-receiver geometry, water depth, streamer depth, and may include other parameters that may influence the time delay of the arrival of the reflection. Direct range prediction model <b>32</b> may be a complex propagation model, ray tracing model or a more simplistic geometrical consideration with velocity information. The direct predicted range from step <b>32</b> may be utilized in the step of selecting an initial range <b>30</b> and/or the step of finalizing a range selection <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In step <b>28</b> an acoustic event is created by pinger <b>14</b> propagating direct wave <b>18</b><i>a </i>and reflected wave <b>20</b>, the arrival of each is measured or recorded at receiver <b>16</b><i>a</i>. Thus, at step <b>28</b> the arrival measurements provide at least two possible ranges, a direct range and a reflected range. In preliminary range selection step <b>30</b>, the measured arrivals are compared so that the preliminary direct range may be selected. Results from range prediction model <b>32</b> may be utilized to select this preliminary direct range selection, i.e. arrival of direct wave <b>18</b><i>a</i>. The preliminary direct range selection may be fed into seismic equipment position determination step <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, finalizing the range selection step <b>34</b> is conducted before determining the seismic equipment position <b>36</b>. Step <b>34</b> includes creating a confidence interval in which arrival of direct wave <b>18</b> is likely to occur at a receiver <b>16</b>. The confidence interval may be calculated in direct range prediction step <b>32</b> or may be determined using separate criteria as an additional check point for selecting the direct range. The preliminary direct range selected in step <b>30</b> for a receiver may be compared to the calculated confidence interval. If the preliminary direct range selected correlates with the confidence interval, the preliminary direct range is finalized and passed to positioning step <b>36</b>. If the preliminary direct range selected does not correlate with the confidence interval, the preliminary range is deemed bad. If the preliminary direct range is bad it may be rejected in finalizing step <b>34</b> and not passed to equipment positioning step <b>36</b>. Alternatively, if the preliminary direct range is bad the preliminary direct range may be conditioned and the conditioned range passed to equipment positioning step <b>36</b>. The conditioned range may be an estimated arrival of direct wave <b>18</b>. Desirably, in equipment positioning step <b>36</b> a conditioned range is given less weight than a measured direct wave arrival.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">From the foregoing detailed description of specific embodiments of the invention, it should be apparent that a method and system for solving the position of seismic equipment that is novel has been disclosed. Although specific embodiments of the invention have been disclosed herein in some detail, this has been done solely for the purposes of describing various features and aspects of the invention, and is not intended to be limiting with respect to the scope of the invention. It is contemplated that various substitutions, alterations, and/or modifications, including but not limited to those implementation variations which may have been suggested herein, may be made to the disclosed embodiments without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention as defined by the appended claims which follow.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method for selecting a signal arrival for determining an accurate position of seismic equipment, comprising:
<claim-text>predicting a direct arrival and a reflected arrival of a signal transmitted from a pinger to a receiver, wherein each arrival is the time between the transmission of the signal to reception of the signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>defining a confidence time interval for reception of the direct signal arrival based on the predicted direct signal arrival;</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting the signal from the pinger;</claim-text>
<claim-text>measuring the direct and the reflected arrivals of the signal at the receiver;</claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting the measured signal arrival that is similar to the predicted direct arrival as a preliminary signal arrival; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>finalizing a signal arrival for determining the position of seismic equipment, wherein the selected preliminary signal arrival is the finalized signal arrival if the selected preliminary signal arrival was measured within the confidence time interval, and wherein the finalizing the selected arrival comprises adjusting the selected preliminary signal arrival to substantially match the predicted direct signal arrival when the selected preliminary signal arrival was measured outside of the confidence time interval.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising determining the position of the receiver relative to the pinger based on the finalized signal arrival.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the pinger and the receiver are provided in a marine environment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising determining the position of the receiver relative to the pinger based on the finalized signal arrival.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the pinger and the receiver are provided in a marine environment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A method for selecting a signal arrival for determining an accurate position of seismic equipment, comprising:
<claim-text>estimating a direct arrival of a signal, wherein an arrival is the time between transmission from pinger to reception at a receiver;</claim-text>
<claim-text>calculating a confidence time interval for reception of the direct arrival based on the estimated direct signal arrival;</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting the signal from the pinger;</claim-text>
<claim-text>measuring arrivals of the signal at the receiver;</claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting one of the measured signal arrivals as a preliminary signal arrival;</claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting a final signal arrival from the measured signal arrivals, wherein selecting the final signal arrival comprises one selected from the group of selecting the selected preliminary signal arrival as the selected final signal arrival if the selected preliminary signal arrival was measured within the confidence time interval and conditioning the selected preliminary signal arrival to substantially equal the estimated direct signal arrival at the receiver when the selected preliminary arrival was measured outside of the confidence time interval; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining the position of the receiver relative to the pinger based on the finalized signal arrival.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein calculating the direct signal arrival comprises utilizing the pinger-receiver geometry and a sound speed profile of the medium in which the pinger and receiver are provided.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
