<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625121-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625121</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13655226</doc-number>
<date>20121018</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2011-232128</doc-number>
<date>20111021</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>12</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>46</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>N</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>358  113</main-classification>
<further-classification>358  11</further-classification>
<further-classification>358505</further-classification>
<further-classification>358509</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e61">Image reading device and image forming apparatus</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2009-075184</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20090400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>11</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>17</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>17</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130100476</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130425</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>KYOCERA Document Solutions Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Osaka</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Fukuma</last-name>
<first-name>Nobuhiro</first-name>
<address>
<city>Osaka</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Arent Fox LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Kyocera Document Solutions Inc.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Osaka</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Pham</last-name>
<first-name>Thierry L</first-name>
<department>2673</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The image reading device includes a light emitting portion, stick-like light guiding member, holding member and case member. An end portion the light guiding member is disposed to face the light emitting portion. The holding member holds the light emitting portion and the light guiding member. The holding member has first and second positioned portions. The first and second positioned portions are formed at one end part and another end part of the holding member in a main scanning direction, respectively. The holding member is attached to the case member. The case member has first and second positioning portions. The first and second positioning portions are formed integrally with the case member. The first and second positioning portions are configured to restrict the inserted first and second positioned portions from moving in a direction transverse to the main scanning direction, respectively.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="152.40mm" wi="176.28mm" file="US08625121-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="233.26mm" wi="164.76mm" file="US08625121-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="187.88mm" wi="171.53mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625121-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="191.94mm" wi="164.76mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625121-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="189.91mm" wi="174.24mm" file="US08625121-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="164.08mm" wi="163.41mm" file="US08625121-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="193.97mm" wi="172.21mm" file="US08625121-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="227.84mm" wi="102.36mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625121-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="181.69mm" wi="166.79mm" file="US08625121-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="199.39mm" wi="169.50mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625121-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="122.09mm" wi="124.80mm" file="US08625121-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="158.67mm" wi="145.80mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625121-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="152.57mm" wi="136.99mm" file="US08625121-20140107-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="157.31mm" wi="166.12mm" file="US08625121-20140107-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00014" num="00014">
<img id="EMI-D00014" he="203.45mm" wi="165.44mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625121-20140107-D00014.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00015" num="00015">
<img id="EMI-D00015" he="208.20mm" wi="172.21mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625121-20140107-D00015.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00016" num="00016">
<img id="EMI-D00016" he="193.29mm" wi="164.08mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625121-20140107-D00016.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00017" num="00017">
<img id="EMI-D00017" he="178.31mm" wi="166.79mm" file="US08625121-20140107-D00017.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">INCORPORATION BY REFERENCE</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is based on and claims the benefit of priority from Japanese Patent. Application No. 2011-232128, filed on 21 Oct. 2011, the content of which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to an image reading device and an image forming apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In recent years, an image reading device has been reported that employs an LED as a light source, paying attention to environmental issues. As such an image reading device that employs an LED, for example, an image reading device has been reported that is configured to dispose a plurality of LEDs in a main scanning direction at predetermined intervals.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">However, the image reading device that requires a plurality of LEDs has been disadvantageous in terms of cost performance in some cases.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In contrast, another image reading device has been reported that is configured to dispose a high-intensity LED at one end of a long stick-like light guiding member in a main scanning direction, which is composed of an acrylic resin or polycarbonate to extend in the main scanning direction.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In such a case, only a single (or a small number of) LED(s) is required, which brings about an advantage in terms of cost performance.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">However, in order to uniformly irradiate a document with light in the aforementioned type of image reading device having the light guiding member, it is necessary to implement highly accurate positioning by taking into consideration a positional relationship thereof with related members such as a reflecting member.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The present disclosure provides an image reading device, in which a light guiding member is positioned with high accuracy with a simple configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Moreover, the present disclosure provides an image forming apparatus that includes such an image reading device.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The image reading device includes a light emitting portion, a light guiding member, a holding member and a case member. The light guiding member is stick-like, and an end portion thereof is disposed to face the light emitting portion. The holding member holds the light emitting portion and the light guiding member. The holding member has a light reflecting portion, a first holding portion, a second holding portion, a first positioned portion, and a second positioned portion. The first holding portion is configured to hold the light emitting portion such that an optical axis is aligned with a main scanning direction. The second holding portion is configured to cause the light guiding member to be positioned with respect to the light reflecting portion, and to hold the light guiding member such that a central axis thereof is substantially coaxial with the optical axis. The first positioned portion is formed at one end part of the holding member in the main scanning direction, and the second positioned portion is formed at another end part of the holding member in the main scanning direction. The holding member is attached to the case member. The case member has a first positioning portion and a second positioning portion. The first positioning portion is formed integrally with the case member. The first positioned portion is inserted into the first positioning portion. The first positioning portion is configured to restrict the inserted first positioned portion from moving in a direction transverse to the main scanning direction. The second positioning portion is formed integrally with the case member. The second positioned portion is inserted into the second positioning portion. The second positioning portion is configured to restrict the inserted second positioned portion from moving in a direction transverse to the main scanning direction.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The present disclosure also relates to an image forming apparatus including the image reading device described above.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The image reading device of the present disclosure includes a light emitting portion, a light guiding member, a holding member and a case member. The light guiding member is stick-like, and an end portion thereof is disposed to face the light emitting portion. The holding member is configured to hold the light emitting portion and the light guiding member. The holding member has a first positioned portion and a second positioned portion. The first positioned portion is formed at one end part of the holding member in a main scanning direction, and the second positioned portion is formed at another end part of the holding member in the main scanning direction. The holding member is attached to the case member. The case member has a first positioning portion and a second positioning portion. The first positioning portion is formed integrally with the case member. The first positioned portion is inserted into the first positioning portion. The first positioning portion is configured to restrict the inserted first positioned portion from moving in a direction transverse to the main scanning direction. The second positioning portion is formed integrally with the case member. The second positioned portion is inserted into the second positioning portion. The second positioning portion is configured to restrict the inserted second positioned portion from moving in a direction transverse to the main scanning direction.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram illustrating an arrangement of components of a copy machine as an image forming apparatus;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view of a light emitting unit <b>400</b> that is incorporated into an image reading device <b>300</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view of the light emitting unit <b>400</b>, in which a cover member <b>311</b><i>b </i>and a cover member <b>311</b><i>c </i>are removed from the state shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref> is a diagram illustrating the light emitting unit <b>400</b> in a state where a holding member <b>420</b> is attached to a first frame <b>311</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</figref> is a diagram illustrating the light emitting unit <b>400</b> in a state where the holding member <b>420</b> is attached to the first frame <b>311</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a diagram illustrating the light emitting unit <b>400</b> in a state where the holding member <b>420</b> is not attached;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a perspective view illustrating the holding member <b>420</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a diagram illustrating a positional relationship among a light guiding member <b>340</b>, the holding member <b>420</b>, and the first frame <b>311</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a perspective view illustrating the holding member <b>420</b> holding the light guiding member <b>340</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a diagram illustrating a setup for positioning a plate-like member <b>427</b> of the holding member <b>420</b> and an LED substrate <b>430</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a perspective view of the light guiding member <b>340</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a diagram illustrating a setup for positioning a base end hole <b>423</b><i>a </i>formed at the holding member <b>420</b> and a base end of the light guiding member <b>340</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a diagram illustrating a setup for positioning a tip end hole <b>423</b><i>b </i>formed in the plate-like member <b>427</b> of the holding member <b>420</b> and a tip end of the light guiding member <b>340</b>; and</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13A</figref> is a diagram illustrating steps for attaching the holding member <b>420</b> to the first frame <b>31</b>.<b>1</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13B</figref> is a diagram illustrating steps for attaching the holding member <b>420</b> to the first frame <b>311</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13C</figref> is a diagram illustrating steps for attaching the holding member <b>420</b> to the first frame <b>311</b>; and</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13D</figref> is a diagram illustrating steps for adjusting an angular position of the holding member <b>420</b> being attached to the first frame <b>311</b>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Descriptions are hereinafter provided for an embodiment of an image forming apparatus according to the present disclosure with reference to the drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">An overall configuration of a copy machine <b>1</b> as the image forming apparatus of the present embodiment will be described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the copy machine <b>1</b> as the image forming apparatus includes an image reading device <b>300</b> disposed at an upper side in a vertical direction Z and an apparatus main body M. The apparatus main body M, which is disposed at a lower side in the vertical direction Z, forms a toner image on a sheet of paper T as a sheet-like medium to be printed, based on image information that is read by the image reading device <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">It should be noted that, in the following descriptions of the copy machine <b>1</b>, a sub-scanning direction X is also referred to as a &#x201c;lateral direction&#x201d; of the copy machine <b>1</b>, and a main scanning direction Y (a direction penetrating <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) is also referred to as a &#x201c;depth direction&#x201d; of the copy machine <b>1</b>. The vertical direction Z is orthogonal to the sub-scanning direction X and the main scanning direction Y.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Firstly, descriptions are provided for the image reading device <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the image reading device <b>300</b> includes a reader unit <b>301</b> that reads an image of a document G, and a document feed unit <b>70</b> that is disposed above the reader unit <b>301</b> and feeds the document G to the reader unit <b>301</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The reader unit <b>301</b> includes a chassis <b>306</b>, and a first reader surface <b>302</b>A and a second reader surface <b>302</b>B that are disposed above the chassis <b>306</b>. Moreover, the reader unit <b>301</b> includes a light guiding member <b>340</b>, a plurality of mirrors <b>321</b>, <b>322</b> and <b>323</b>, a first frame <b>311</b> and a second frame <b>312</b>, an imaging lens <b>357</b>, a CCD <b>358</b> that serves as reading means and a CCD substrate <b>361</b>, in an internal space <b>304</b> of the chassis <b>306</b>. The light guiding member <b>340</b> irradiates the document G mounted on the first reader surface <b>302</b>A or the second reader surface <b>302</b>B with light received from a light emitting portion that serves as a light source. The first frame <b>311</b> and second frame <b>312</b> are housings moving in the sub-scanning direction X. The CCD substrate <b>361</b> performs predetermined processing on image information that is read by the CCD <b>358</b> and outputs the image information to the apparatus main body M. The light guiding member <b>340</b> and the mirror <b>321</b> are housed in the first frame <b>311</b>. The second mirror <b>322</b> and the third mirror <b>323</b> are housed in the second frame <b>312</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The light guiding member <b>340</b> and the light emitting portion are assembled into the first frame <b>311</b> of a housing, and are unitized as a light emitting unit <b>400</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) to be attached to the chassis <b>306</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The light emitting unit <b>400</b> will be described later in detail.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The document feed unit <b>70</b> is connected with the reader unit <b>301</b> by a connecting portion (not illustrated) so as to be openable and closable. The document feed unit <b>70</b> includes a document mounting portion <b>71</b> on an upper side thereof and feed rollers (not illustrated) inside. The document feed unit <b>70</b> has a function of protecting the first reader surface <b>302</b>A and the second reader surface <b>302</b>B of the reader unit <b>301</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The first reader surface <b>302</b>A is used when a document G is read, which is fed by the document feed unit <b>70</b>. The first reader surface <b>302</b>A is formed on an upper surface of a first contact glass <b>335</b>A to which the document G is fed. The first reader surface <b>302</b>A is positioned in the vicinity of a left lateral face of the chassis <b>306</b>. It should be noted that such a position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is also referred to as a &#x201c;first reading position.&#x201d;</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The second reader surface <b>302</b>B is used when a document G is read without using the document feed unit <b>70</b>. The second reader surface <b>302</b>B is formed on an upper surface of a second contact glass <b>335</b>B on which the document G is mounted. The second reader surface <b>302</b>B is positioned more to the right than the first reader surface <b>302</b>A, and occupies most of the reader unit <b>301</b> in the sub-scanning direction X.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The first reader surface <b>302</b>A and the second reader surface <b>302</b>B each extend in both the sub-scanning direction X and the main scanning direction Y.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">A document G mounted on the document mounting portion <b>71</b> is fed by the document feed unit <b>70</b>. The document G mounted on the document mounting portion <b>71</b> is fed to the first reader surface <b>302</b>A of the reader unit <b>301</b> by the feed rollers provided inside the document feed unit <b>70</b>. In this case, the first frame <b>311</b> and the second frame <b>312</b> do not move but remain in the first reading position. In addition, the document feed unit <b>70</b> slidingly feeds the document G on the first reader surface <b>302</b>A, and the CCD <b>358</b> reads an image on a surface of the document G.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">On the other hand, the document feed unit <b>70</b> is opened, and a document G is mounted on the second reader surface <b>302</b>B. In this case, the first frame <b>311</b> and the second frame <b>312</b> each move in the sub-scanning direction X, while they are maintaining a length of a light path H (to be described later) constant. As a result, an image of the document G that is mounted on the second reader surface <b>302</b>B is read.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In the internal space <b>304</b> of the chassis <b>306</b>, the plurality of mirrors <b>321</b>, <b>322</b> and <b>323</b> form the light path H through which the light from the document G travels into the imaging lens <b>357</b>. Since the first frame <b>311</b> moves in the sub-scanning direction X at a predetermined speed A and the second frame <b>312</b> moves in the sub-scanning direction X at a predetermined speed A/2, the length of the light path H is maintained constant even while image reading is being performed.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Next, descriptions are provided for the apparatus main body M.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The apparatus main body M includes an image forming unit GK and a paper feeding/discharging portion KH. The image forming unit GK forms a predetermined toner image on a sheet of paper T based on predetermined image information. The paper feeding/discharging portion KH feeds the sheet of paper T to the image forming unit GK, and discharges the sheet of paper T on which a toner image has been formed.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">An external shape of the apparatus main body M is composed of a case body BD as a housing.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the image forming unit GK includes photoreceptor drums <b>2</b><i>a</i>, <b>2</b><i>b</i>, <b>2</b><i>c </i>and <b>2</b><i>d </i>as image supporting bodies (photoreceptors), charging portions <b>10</b><i>a</i>, <b>10</b><i>b</i>, <b>10</b><i>c </i>and <b>10</b><i>d</i>, laser scanner units <b>4</b><i>a</i>, <b>4</b><i>b</i>, <b>4</b><i>c </i>and <b>4</b><i>d </i>as exposure units, developing units <b>16</b><i>a</i>, <b>16</b><i>b</i>, <b>16</b><i>c </i>and <b>16</b><i>d</i>, toner cartridges <b>5</b><i>a</i>, <b>5</b><i>b</i>, <b>5</b><i>c </i>and <b>5</b><i>d</i>, toner feeding portions <b>6</b><i>a</i>, <b>6</b><i>b</i>, <b>6</b><i>c </i>and <b>6</b><i>d</i>, drum cleaning portions <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>11</b><i>b</i>, <b>11</b><i>c </i>and <b>11</b><i>d</i>, static eliminators <b>12</b><i>a</i>, <b>12</b><i>b</i>, <b>12</b><i>c </i>and <b>12</b><i>d</i>, an intermediate transfer belt <b>7</b>, primary transfer rollers <b>37</b><i>a</i>, <b>37</b><i>b</i>, <b>37</b><i>c </i>and <b>37</b><i>d</i>, a secondary transfer roller <b>8</b>, an opposing roller <b>183</b>, and a fusing unit <b>9</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the paper feeding/discharging portion KH includes a paper feeding cassette <b>52</b>, a manual feeding portion <b>64</b>, a paper path L for a sheet of paper T, a pair of resist rollers <b>80</b>, a first discharging portion <b>50</b><i>a</i>, and a second discharging portion <b>50</b><i>b</i>. It should be noted that the paper path L is an assembly of a first paper path L<b>1</b>, a second paper path L<b>2</b>, a third paper path L<b>3</b>, a manual paper path La, a reverse paper path Lb, and a post-processing paper path Lc.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Components of the image forming unit GK and the paper feeding/discharging portion KH are described hereinafter in detail.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In the image forming unit GK, charging by the charging portions <b>10</b><i>a</i>, <b>10</b><i>b</i>, <b>10</b><i>c </i>and <b>10</b><i>d</i>, exposure by the laser scanner units <b>4</b><i>a</i>, <b>4</b><i>b</i>, <b>4</b><i>c </i>and <b>4</b><i>d</i>, development by the developing units <b>16</b><i>a</i>, <b>16</b><i>b</i>, <b>16</b><i>c </i>and <b>16</b><i>d</i>, primary transfer by the intermediate transfer belt <b>7</b> and the primary transfer rollers <b>37</b><i>a</i>, <b>37</b><i>b</i>, <b>37</b><i>c </i>and <b>37</b><i>d</i>, static elimination by the static eliminators <b>12</b><i>a</i>, <b>12</b><i>b</i>, <b>12</b><i>c </i>and <b>12</b><i>d</i>, and cleaning by the drum cleaning portions <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>11</b><i>b</i>, <b>11</b><i>c </i>and lid are performed on a surface of each of the photoreceptor drums <b>2</b><i>a</i>, <b>2</b><i>b</i>, <b>2</b><i>c </i>and <b>2</b><i>d </i>from an upstream side to a downstream side in sequence.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In addition, in the image forming unit GK, secondary transfer is performed by the intermediate transfer belt <b>7</b>, the secondary transfer roller <b>8</b> and the opposing roller <b>18</b>, and fixation is performed by the fusing unit <b>9</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Each of the photoreceptor drums <b>2</b><i>a</i>, <b>2</b><i>b</i>, <b>2</b><i>c </i>and <b>2</b><i>d </i>is composed of a cylindrically shaped member.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The charging portions <b>10</b><i>a</i>, <b>10</b><i>b</i>, <b>10</b><i>c </i>and <b>10</b><i>d </i>uniformly negatively charge (negative polarity) or positively charge (positive polarity) the surfaces of the photoreceptor drums <b>2</b><i>a</i>, <b>2</b><i>b</i>, <b>2</b><i>c </i>and <b>2</b><i>d</i>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The laser scanner units <b>4</b><i>a</i>, <b>4</b><i>b</i>, <b>4</b><i>c </i>and <b>4</b><i>d </i>are disposed to be spaced apart from the surfaces of the photoreceptor drums <b>2</b><i>a</i>, <b>2</b><i>b</i>, <b>2</b><i>c </i>and <b>2</b><i>d</i>, respectively. Each of the laser scanner units <b>4</b><i>a</i>, <b>4</b><i>b</i>, <b>4</b><i>c </i>and <b>4</b><i>d </i>is configured to include a laser light source, a polygonal mirror, a polygonal mirror driving motor and the like, which are not illustrated.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The laser scanner units <b>4</b><i>a</i>, <b>4</b><i>b</i>, <b>4</b><i>c </i>and <b>4</b><i>d </i>scan and expose the surfaces of the photoreceptor drums <b>2</b><i>a</i>, <b>2</b><i>b</i>, <b>2</b><i>c </i>and <b>2</b><i>d</i>, respectively, based on the image information related to the image that is read by the reader unit <b>301</b>. An electrical charge is eliminated from exposed portions of each surface of the photoreceptor drums <b>2</b><i>a</i>, <b>2</b><i>b</i>, <b>2</b><i>c </i>and <b>2</b><i>d</i>. In this way, an electrostatic latent image is formed on the surface of each of the photoreceptor drums <b>2</b><i>a</i>, <b>2</b><i>b</i>, <b>2</b><i>c </i>and <b>2</b><i>d. </i></p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The developing units <b>16</b><i>a</i>, <b>16</b><i>b</i>, <b>16</b><i>c </i>and <b>16</b><i>d </i>cause color toners to be attached to the photoreceptor drums <b>2</b><i>a</i>, <b>2</b><i>c </i>and <b>2</b><i>d</i>, and form color toner images on the surfaces of the photoreceptor drums <b>2</b><i>a</i>, <b>2</b><i>b</i>, <b>2</b><i>c </i>and <b>2</b><i>d</i>, respectively. The developing units correspond to four colors of yellow, cyan, magenta and black, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The toner cartridges <b>5</b><i>a</i>, <b>5</b><i>b</i>, <b>5</b><i>c </i>and <b>5</b><i>d </i>store toners of yellow, cyan, magenta and black, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The toner feeding portions <b>6</b><i>a</i>, <b>6</b><i>b</i>, <b>6</b><i>c </i>and <b>6</b><i>d </i>are provided correspondingly to the toner cartridges <b>5</b><i>a</i>, <b>5</b><i>b</i>, <b>5</b><i>c </i>and <b>5</b><i>d </i>and the developing units <b>16</b><i>a</i>, <b>16</b><i>b</i>, <b>16</b><i>c </i>and <b>16</b><i>d</i>, respectively. In addition, the toner feeding portions <b>6</b><i>a</i>, <b>6</b><i>b</i>, <b>6</b><i>c </i>and <b>6</b><i>d </i>supply the color toners stored in the toner cartridges <b>5</b><i>a</i>, <b>5</b><i>b</i>, <b>5</b><i>c </i>and <b>5</b><i>d </i>to the developing units <b>16</b><i>a</i>, <b>16</b><i>b</i>, <b>16</b><i>c </i>and <b>16</b><i>d</i>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The intermediate transfer belt <b>7</b> is stretched around a driven roller <b>35</b>, the opposing roller <b>18</b> composed of a driving roller, a tension roller <b>36</b>, and the like. Since the tension roller <b>36</b> biases the intermediate transfer belt <b>7</b> from inside to outside, a predetermined tension is applied to the intermediate transfer belt <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The primary transfer rollers <b>37</b><i>a</i>, <b>37</b><i>b</i>, <b>37</b><i>c </i>and <b>37</b><i>d </i>are disposed on the opposite sides of the photoreceptor drums <b>2</b><i>a</i>, <b>2</b><i>b</i>, <b>2</b><i>c </i>and <b>2</b><i>d</i>, respectively, so as to sandwich the intermediate transfer belt <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Predetermined parts of the intermediate transfer belt <b>7</b> are nipped between the primary transfer rollers <b>37</b><i>a</i>, <b>37</b><i>b</i>, <b>37</b><i>c </i>and <b>37</b><i>d </i>and the photoreceptor drums <b>2</b><i>a</i>, <b>2</b><i>b</i>, <b>2</b><i>c </i>and <b>2</b><i>d</i>, respectively. The predetermined nipped parts are pressed against the surfaces of the photoreceptor drums <b>2</b><i>a</i>, <b>2</b><i>b</i>, <b>2</b><i>c </i>and <b>2</b><i>d</i>, respectively. Primary transfer nips N<b>1</b><i>a</i>, N<b>1</b><i>b</i>, N<b>1</b><i>c </i>and N<b>1</b><i>d </i>are formed between the photoreceptor drums <b>2</b><i>a</i>, <b>2</b><i>b</i>, <b>2</b><i>c </i>and <b>2</b><i>d </i>and the primary transfer rollers <b>37</b><i>a</i>, <b>37</b><i>b</i>, <b>37</b><i>c </i>and <b>37</b><i>d</i>, respectively. At the primary transfer nips N<b>1</b><i>a</i>, N<b>1</b><i>b</i>, N<b>1</b><i>c </i>and N<b>1</b><i>d</i>, respectively, toner images of the respective colors developed on the photoreceptor drums <b>2</b><i>a</i>, <b>2</b><i>b</i>, <b>2</b><i>c </i>and <b>2</b><i>d </i>are sequentially primarily transferred onto the intermediate transfer belt <b>7</b>. In this manner, a full-color toner image is formed on the intermediate transfer belt <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Primary transfer bias application portions (not illustrated) apply a primary transfer bias to the primary transfer rollers <b>37</b><i>a</i>, <b>37</b><i>b</i>, <b>37</b><i>c </i>and <b>37</b><i>d</i><b>6</b>, for the purpose of transferring the toner images of the colors formed on the photoreceptor drums <b>2</b><i>a</i>, <b>2</b><i>h</i>, <b>2</b><i>c </i>and <b>2</b><i>d </i>onto the intermediate transfer belt <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The static eliminators <b>12</b><i>a</i>, <b>12</b><i>b</i>, <b>12</b><i>c </i>and <b>12</b><i>d </i>remove electricity (eliminate an electrical charge) from the surfaces of the photoreceptor drums <b>2</b><i>a</i>, <b>2</b><i>b</i>, <b>2</b><i>c </i>and <b>2</b><i>d</i>, on which the primary transfer has been performed, by irradiating the surfaces of the photoreceptor drums <b>2</b><i>a</i>, <b>2</b><i>b</i>, <b>2</b><i>c </i>and <b>2</b><i>d</i>, respectively, with light.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The drum cleaning portions <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>11</b><i>b</i>, <b>11</b><i>c </i>and <b>11</b><i>d </i>remove toner and attached matter remaining on the surfaces of the photoreceptor drums <b>2</b><i>a</i>, <b>2</b><i>b</i>, <b>2</b><i>c </i>and <b>2</b><i>d</i>, respectively, and feed the removed toner to a predetermined collection mechanism for collection.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The secondary transfer roller <b>8</b> secondarily transfers the full-color toner image, which has been primarily transferred to the intermediate transfer belt <b>7</b>, to the sheet of paper T. Secondary transfer bias application portions (not illustrated) apply a secondary bias to the secondary transfer roller <b>8</b> for the purpose of transferring the full-color toner image formed on the intermediate transfer belt <b>7</b> to the sheet of paper T.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The secondary transfer roller <b>8</b> is configured to be movable between an abutting position of abutting the intermediate transfer belt <b>7</b>, and a separated position of being separated from the intermediate transfer belt <b>7</b>. More specifically, the secondary transfer roller <b>8</b> is disposed in the abutting position when secondarily transferring the toner image, which has been primarily transferred to the surface of the intermediate transfer belt <b>7</b>, to the sheet of paper T, and is otherwise disposed in the separated position.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">A predetermined part of the intermediate transfer belt <b>7</b> is sandwiched between the secondary transfer roller <b>8</b> and the opposing roller <b>18</b>. The sheet of paper T is pressed against an outer surface of the intermediate transfer belt <b>7</b> (the surface onto which the toner image has been primarily transferred). A secondary transfer nip N<b>2</b> is formed between the intermediate transfer belt <b>7</b> and the secondary transfer roller <b>8</b>. At the secondary transfer nip N<b>2</b>, the full-color toner image, which has been primarily transferred to the intermediate transfer belt <b>7</b>, is secondarily transferred to the sheet of paper T.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The fusing unit <b>9</b> includes a heating rotator <b>9</b><i>a </i>that is heated by a heater, and a pressing rotator <b>9</b><i>b </i>that is brought into pressure contact with the heating rotator <b>9</b><i>a</i>. The heating rotator <b>9</b><i>a </i>and the pressing rotator <b>9</b><i>b </i>nip and apply pressure, and feed the sheet of paper T, to which the toner image has been secondarily transferred. Since the sheet of paper T is fed while being nipped between the heating rotator <b>9</b><i>a </i>and the pressing rotator <b>9</b><i>b</i>, the toner transferred to the sheet of paper is fused and pressed to be fixed on the sheet of paper T.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, two paper feeding cassettes <b>52</b> that store sheets of paper T are disposed in a vertical arrangement at a lower portion of the apparatus main body M. The paper feeding cassettes <b>52</b> are configured to be withdrawable from the housing of the apparatus main body M in a horizontal direction. The paper feeding cassette <b>52</b> stores the sheets of paper T as being stacked on a paper tray <b>60</b>. A sheet of paper T placed on the paper tray <b>60</b> is fed to the paper path L by a cassette feeding portion <b>51</b> that is disposed at an end on a paper feeding side (a left end of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of the paper feeding cassettes <b>52</b>. The cassette feeding portion <b>51</b> includes a double feed preventing mechanism that is composed of a forward feed roller <b>61</b> for picking up a sheet of paper T from the paper tray <b>60</b> and a pair of feed rollers <b>63</b> for feeding the sheet of paper T one at a time to the paper path L.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">The manual feeding portion <b>64</b> is provided on a right lateral face (the right side in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of the apparatus main body M. The manual feeding portion <b>64</b> is primarily provided for the purpose of feeding a sheet of paper T, which is different in size and type from the sheets of paper T stored in the paper feeding cassette <b>52</b>, to the apparatus main body M. The manual feeding portion <b>64</b> includes a manual feeding tray <b>65</b> and a paper feeding roller <b>66</b>, in which the manual feeding tray <b>65</b> in its closed state composes a part of the right lateral face of the apparatus main body M. A lower end of the manual feeding tray <b>65</b> is rotationally connected (so as to be openable and closable) to the apparatus main body M in the vicinity of the paper feeding roller <b>66</b>. The paper feeding roller <b>66</b> feeds a sheet of paper T, which is placed on the manual feeding tray <b>65</b> in the opened state, to the manual paper path La.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The first discharging portion <b>50</b><i>a </i>and the second discharging portion <b>50</b><i>b </i>are provided at an upper portion in the apparatus main body M. The first discharging portion <b>50</b><i>a </i>and the second discharging portion <b>50</b><i>b </i>discharge a sheet of paper T outside the apparatus main body M. The first discharging portion <b>50</b><i>a </i>and the second discharging portion <b>50</b><i>b </i>will be described later in detail.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The paper feed path L includes the first paper path L<b>1</b> from the cassette feeding portion <b>51</b> to the secondary transfer nip N<b>2</b>, the second paper path L<b>2</b> from the secondary transfer nip N<b>2</b> to the fusing unit <b>9</b>, the third paper path L<b>3</b> from the fusing unit <b>9</b> to the first discharging portion <b>50</b><i>a</i>, the manual paper path La that guides a sheet of paper T fed from the manual feeding portion <b>64</b> to the first paper path L<b>1</b>, the reverse paper path Lb that reverses and returns the sheet of paper T, which is fed from upstream to downstream in the third paper path L<b>3</b>, to the first paper path L<b>1</b>, and a post-processing paper path Lc that feeds the sheet of paper T, which is fed from upstream to downstream in the third paper path L<b>3</b>, to a post-processing device (not illustrated) that is connected to the second discharging portion <b>50</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">In addition, a first junction P<b>1</b> and a second junction P<b>2</b> are provided midway in the first paper path L<b>1</b>. A first branch portion Q<b>1</b> is provided midway in the third paper path L<b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The first junction P<b>1</b> is a junction where the manual paper path La joins the first paper path L<b>1</b>. The second junction P<b>2</b> is a junction where the reverse paper path Lb joins the first paper path L<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">The first branch portion Q<b>1</b> is a branch portion where the post-processing paper path Lc branches off the third paper path L<b>3</b>. A switching member <b>58</b> is provided at the first branch portion Q<b>1</b>. The switching member <b>58</b> causes a feeding direction of a sheet of paper T discharged from the fusing unit <b>9</b> to be switched between the third paper path L<b>3</b> leading to the first discharging portion <b>50</b><i>a </i>and the post-processing paper path Lc leading to the second discharging portion <b>50</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">More specifically, a sensor for detecting a sheet of paper T and the pair of resist rollers <b>80</b> are disposed between the second junction P<b>2</b> and the secondary transfer roller <b>8</b>, in which the purpose of the pair of resist rollers <b>80</b> is skew correction of the sheet of paper T, and timing adjustment between forming of an toner image in the image forming unit GK and feeding of the sheet of paper T. The sensor is disposed immediately anterior to the pair of resist rollers <b>80</b> in the feeding direction of a sheet of paper T (upstream in the feeding direction). The pair of resist rollers <b>80</b> is a pair of rollers that feeds a sheet of paper T by performing the correction or the timing adjustment based on a detected signal from the sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">The reverse paper path Lb reverses a sheet of paper T, which has been fed from the first branch portion Q<b>1</b> toward the discharging portion <b>50</b>, returns the sheet of paper T to the first paper path L<b>1</b>, and feeds the sheet of paper T upstream of the pair of resist rollers <b>80</b> disposed upstream of the secondary transfer roller <b>8</b>. At the secondary transfer nip N<b>2</b>, a predetermined toner image is transferred to an unprinted surface of the sheet of paper T that has been reversed by the reverse paper path Lb.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">The first discharging portion <b>50</b><i>a </i>is formed at an end of the third paper path L<b>3</b>. The first discharging portion <b>50</b><i>a </i>is disposed at an upper portion of the apparatus main body M. The first discharging portion <b>50</b><i>a </i>opens upon the right side of the apparatus main body M (on the right or a side of the manual feeding portion <b>64</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). The first discharging portion <b>50</b><i>a </i>discharges a sheet of paper T, which is fed through the third paper path L<b>3</b>, outside the apparatus main body M.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">A discharged paper accumulating portion M<b>1</b> is formed at an opening side of the first discharging portion <b>50</b><i>a</i>. A bottom face of the discharged paper accumulating portion M<b>1</b> composes a part of an upper face of the apparatus main body M. After predetermined toner images are formed on sheets of paper T, the sheets of paper T are discharged from the first discharging portion <b>50</b><i>a</i>, and are stacked and accumulated at the discharged paper accumulating portion M<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">The second discharging portion <b>50</b><i>b </i>is formed at an end of the post-processing paper path Lc. The second discharging portion <b>50</b><i>b </i>opens upon a left side of the apparatus main body M (on the left or a side where a post-processing device is connected in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). The second discharging portion <b>50</b><i>b </i>discharges a sheet of paper T, which is fed through the post-processing paper path Lc, outside the apparatus main body M.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">A post-processing device (not illustrated) is connected at an opening side of the second discharging portion <b>50</b><i>b</i>. The post-processing device performs post-processing (stapling, punching, etc.) on a sheet of paper T discharged from the image forming apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">It should be noted that a sensor for detecting a sheet of paper T is disposed at a predetermined position in each paper path.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the main paper paths L<b>1</b> to L<b>3</b> and the reverse paper path Lb are arranged to extend primarily in the vertical direction on the left side of the apparatus main body M (the left side in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). A cover <b>40</b> is provided at the left side of the apparatus main body M (the left side in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) such that the cover <b>40</b> forms a part of a lateral face of the apparatus main body M. The cover <b>40</b> is coupled at a lower end thereof to the apparatus main body M via a fulcrum shaft <b>43</b>. The fulcrum shaft <b>43</b> is disposed in a direction that intersects the main paper paths L<b>1</b> to L<b>3</b> and the reverse paper path Lb. The cover <b>40</b> is configured to be rotatable between a closed position (position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) and an opened position (not illustrated) about the fulcrum shaft <b>43</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">The cover <b>40</b> is composed of a first cover portion <b>41</b> rotationally connected to the apparatus main body M via the fulcrum shaft <b>43</b>, and a second cover portion <b>42</b> rotationally connected to the apparatus main body M via the same fulcrum shaft <b>43</b>. The first cover portion <b>41</b> is positioned more outside the apparatus main body M than the second cover portion <b>42</b>. It should be noted that, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the portion hatched by falling diagonal broken lines from top right to bottom left is the first cover portion <b>41</b>, and the portion hatched by falling diagonal broken lines from top left to bottom right is the second cover portion <b>42</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">When a paper jam occurs in the main paper paths L<b>1</b> to L<b>3</b>, it is possible to cause the cover <b>40</b> to rotate from the closed position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> to the opened position (not illustrated) so as to open the main paper paths L<b>1</b> to L<b>3</b>, and to remove a jammed sheet of paper in the main paper paths L<b>1</b> to L<b>3</b>. On the other hand, when a paper jam occurs in the reverse paper path Lb, it is possible to open the reverse paper path Lb by rotating the cover <b>40</b> to the opened position subsequently to cause the second cover portion <b>42</b> to rotate about the fulcrum shaft <b>43</b> toward the apparatus main body M side (the right side in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) to release the reverse paper path Lb, and to remove a jammed sheet of paper in the reverse paper path Lb.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">Next, with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 to 13B</figref>, descriptions are provided for the lighting unit <b>400</b> and the image reading device <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">The light emitting unit <b>400</b> includes an LED <b>410</b> as a emitting portion, the light guiding member <b>340</b>, the holding member <b>420</b>, and the first frame <b>311</b> (a case member) for housing the holding member <b>420</b>. Moreover, the lighting unit <b>400</b> has an adjustment mechanism <b>600</b> configured to cause the holding member <b>420</b> to rotationally move.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, the first frame <b>311</b> includes a main frame part <b>311</b><i>a </i>with a substantially box-like shape having an open top portion and two cover members <b>311</b><i>b </i>and <b>311</b><i>c </i>that cover the open top portion of the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a </i>has outer wail portions <b>3111</b> and <b>3112</b> that are disposed opposite to each other on both outer sides of the frame part <b>311</b><i>a </i>with respect to the main scanning direction Y.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">The holding member <b>420</b> is positioned and held on a top face of the outer wall portion <b>3111</b> and the outer wall portion <b>3112</b> via a positioning portion <b>500</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">The positioning portion <b>500</b> is formed integrally with the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a</i>. The positioning portion <b>500</b> holds and positions the holding member <b>420</b>. The positioning portion <b>500</b> positions to restrict the holding member <b>420</b> from moving in a direction transverse to the main scanning direction Y.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">The positioning portion <b>500</b> has a first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>formed on a side of the outer wall portion <b>3111</b> and a second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>formed on a side of the outer wall portion <b>3112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">The first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>is disposed in a backward side in an insertion direction K (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13A</figref>) of the holding member <b>420</b> in the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">The second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>is disposed in a forward side in the insertion direction K (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13A</figref>) of the holding member <b>420</b> in the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">The first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>is formed continuously to an upper portion of the outer wall portion <b>3111</b>. The first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>is formed continuously to and integrally with the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a</i>. More specifically, the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>is formed at a support wall <b>3111</b><i>a </i>extending upward from the outer wall portion <b>3111</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">The first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>has a cylindrical inner face <b>501</b><i>a </i>and a hollow portion <b>502</b><i>a </i>formed by the inner face <b>501</b><i>a </i>(see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">With respect to the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a</i>, a central axis CS of the cylindrical hollow portion <b>502</b><i>a </i>is substantially coaxial with an optical axis AX of the light guiding member <b>340</b> in a state where the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>is inserted into the cylindrical hollow portion <b>502</b><i>a </i>(see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">In other words, the inner face <b>501</b><i>a </i>has a cylindrical shape, of which center is the optical axis AX. Moreover, the hollow portion <b>502</b><i>a </i>has a cylindrical shape, of which center is the optical axis AX.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">In addition, the inner face <b>501</b><i>a </i>of the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>is configured to correspond to an outer cylindrical face of the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>(to be described below).</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">The first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>(to be described below) is inserted into and mated with the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">The first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>restricts the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>inserted into the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>from moving in a direction transverse to the main scanning direction Y.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">For example, the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>restricts the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>from moving in a direction perpendicular to the main scanning direction Y.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">As a result, the holding member <b>420</b> is accurately positioned.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">The first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>supports the holding member <b>420</b> so as to be movable in the main scanning direction (an optical axis direction AX).</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">Moreover, the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>supports the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>so as to be rotatable around the optical axis AX.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">The second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>is formed continuously to an upper portion of the outer wall portion <b>3112</b>. The second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>is formed continuously to and integrally with the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a</i>. More specifically, the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>is formed on a support wall <b>3112</b><i>a </i>extending upward from the outer wall portion <b>3112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">The second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>has a cylindrical inner face <b>501</b><i>b </i>and a hollow portion <b>502</b><i>b </i>formed by the inner face <b>501</b><i>b </i>(see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13A</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">With respect to the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b</i>, the central axis CS of the cylindrical hollow portion <b>502</b><i>b </i>is substantially coaxial with the optical axis AX of the light guiding member <b>340</b> in a state where the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>is inserted into the hollow portion <b>502</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111">In other words, the inner face <b>501</b><i>b </i>has a cylindrical shape, of which center is the optical axis AX. Moreover, the hollow portion <b>502</b><i>b </i>has a cylindrical shape, of which center is the optical axis AX.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">In addition, the inner face <b>501</b><i>b </i>of the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>is configured to correspond to an outer cylindrical face of the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>(to be described below).</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">The second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>(to be described below) is inserted into and mated with the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">The second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>restricts the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>inserted into the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>from moving in a direction transverse to the main scanning direction Y.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">For example, the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>restricts the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>from moving in a direction perpendicular to the main scanning direction Y.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116">The second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>restricts the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>from moving in the direction transverse to the main scanning direction Y and accurately positions the holding member <b>420</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0117">The second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>supports the holding member <b>420</b> so as to be movable in the main scanning direction (the optical axis direction AX).</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0118">Moreover, the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>supports the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>so as to be rotatable around the optical axis AX.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0119">When the holding member <b>420</b> is attached to the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a</i>, the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>penetrates the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>(see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13A and 13B</figref>) More specifically, the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>penetrates the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b</i>, and thereafter the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>is mated with the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0120">In other words, an inner diameter of the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>is configured to allow not only the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>to penetrate, but also the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>not to penetrate but to mate with.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0121">In the present embodiment, an inner diameter of the cylindrical hollow portion <b>502</b><i>b </i>of the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>is larger than an inner diameter of the cylindrical hollow portion <b>502</b><i>a </i>of the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0122">The first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>and the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>hold to restrict the holding member <b>4120</b> from moving in the direction transverse to the optical axis AX via the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>and the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0123">Here, the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>and the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>support the holding member <b>420</b> so as to be movable in the direction of the optical axis AX (the main scanning direction Y) via the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>and the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0124">Moreover, the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>and the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>support the holding member <b>420</b> so as to be rotatable around the optical axis AX via the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>and the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b</i>. In a state where the holding member <b>420</b> is attached to the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a</i>, the lighting unit <b>400</b> (the image reading device <b>300</b>) causes the holding member <b>420</b> to rotate to change (adjust) an angle of irradiating a document with light from the light guiding member <b>340</b> (an orientation of a light irradiating portion <b>341</b> to be described below).</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0125">The holding member <b>420</b> is positioned and held to the main frame part <b>331</b><i>a </i>by the positioning portion <b>500</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0126">The holding member <b>420</b> is held to the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a </i>in a state of being restricted from moving in the direction transverse to the main scanning direction Y (the optical axis direction AX) by the positioning portion <b>500</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0127">In addition, as will be described later, the holding member <b>420</b> positions the LED <b>410</b> via an LED substrate <b>430</b>, and positions the light guiding member <b>340</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0128">The holding member <b>420</b> has a positioned portion <b>530</b> that is formed at an end portion of the holding member <b>420</b> in the main scanning direction Y (the optical axis direction AX). The positioned portion <b>510</b> is inserted into and mated with the positioning portion <b>500</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0129">Moreover, the holding member <b>420</b> has a restricting portion <b>550</b> that restricts rotational movement around the optical axis AX.</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0130">The positioned portion <b>510</b> has the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>and the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0132" num="0131">The first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>is formed at the holding member <b>420</b> on a side of the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>in the main scanning direction Y.</p>
<p id="p-0133" num="0132">The second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>is formed at the holding member <b>420</b> on a side of the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>in the main scanning direction Y.</p>
<p id="p-0134" num="0133">The first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>has a cylindrical outer face <b>511</b><i>a </i>centered about the optical axis AX, which is configured to correspond to the inner face <b>501</b><i>a </i>of the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0135" num="0134">The first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>is inserted into and mated with the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0136" num="0135">The first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>is inserted into the hollow portion <b>502</b><i>a </i>of the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a</i>, and the outer face <b>511</b><i>a </i>is in surface contact with the inner face <b>501</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0137" num="0136">The first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>is held to the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>such that the central axis CS of the cylindrical outer face <b>511</b><i>a </i>is positioned to be substantially coaxial with the optical axis AX of the light guiding member <b>340</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0138" num="0137">The first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>inserted into the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>is held to the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a</i>, such that the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>is restricted from moving in the direction transverse to the main scanning direction Y.</p>
<p id="p-0139" num="0138">Accordingly, the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>is restricted from moving in the direction perpendicular to the main scanning direction Y.</p>
<p id="p-0140" num="0139">Here, the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>is supported by the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>so as to be rotatable about the optical axis AX.</p>
<p id="p-0141" num="0140">The second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>has a cylindrical outer face <b>511</b><i>b </i>centered about the optical axis AX, which is configured to correspond to the inner face <b>501</b><i>b </i>of the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0142" num="0141">The second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>is inserted into and mated with the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b</i>. The second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>is inserted into the hollow portion <b>502</b><i>b </i>of the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b</i>, and the outer face <b>511</b><i>b </i>is in surface contact with the inner face <b>501</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0143" num="0142">The second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>is held to the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>such that the central axis CS of the cylindrical outer face <b>511</b><i>b </i>is positioned to be substantially coaxial with the optical axis AX of the light guiding member <b>340</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0144" num="0143">The second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>inserted into the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>is held to the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b</i>, such that the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>is restricted from moving in the direction transverse to the main scanning direction Y.</p>
<p id="p-0145" num="0144">Accordingly, the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>is restricted from moving in the direction perpendicular to the main scanning direction Y.</p>
<p id="p-0146" num="0145">Here, the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>is supported by the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>so as to be rotatable about the optical axis AX.</p>
<p id="p-0147" num="0146">When the holding member <b>420</b> is attached to the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a</i>, the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>penetrates the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>(see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13A and 13B</figref>). More specifically, the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>penetrates the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b</i>, and is subsequently mated with the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0148" num="0147">In other words, the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>has an outer diameter that allows the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>not only to penetrate the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b</i>, but also to mate with the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0149" num="0148">In the present embodiment, an outer diameter of the cylindrical outer face <b>511</b><i>a </i>of the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>is smaller than an outer diameter of the cylindrical outer face <b>511</b><i>b </i>of the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0150" num="0149">As a result, it is possible for the image reading device to position and hold the holding member <b>420</b> to the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a </i>with high accuracy, by inserting the holding member <b>420</b> with the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>as a top into the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b</i>, and further moving the holding member <b>420</b> in the insertion direction.</p>
<p id="p-0151" num="0150">The first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>and the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>are held to the holding member <b>420</b> so as to be restricted from moving in the direction transverse to the optical axis AX via the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>and the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0152" num="0151">Here, the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>and the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>are supported by the holding member <b>420</b> so as to be movable in a direction of the optical axis AX (the main scanning direction Y) via the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>and the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0153" num="0152">Moreover, the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>and the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>are supported by the holding member <b>420</b> so as to be rotatable about the optical axis AX via the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>and the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b</i>. As described above, in a state where the holding member <b>420</b> is attached to the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a</i>, the lighting unit <b>400</b> (the image reading device <b>300</b>) causes the holding member <b>420</b> to rotate to change (adjust) an angle of irradiating a document with light from the light guiding member <b>340</b> (an orientation of the light irradiating portion <b>341</b> to be described below).</p>
<p id="p-0154" num="0153">The restricting portion <b>550</b> restricts rotational movement about the optical axis AX.</p>
<p id="p-0155" num="0154">The restricting portion <b>550</b> is formed on a plate-like member <b>427</b> disposed at an end of the holding member <b>420</b> on a side of the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0156" num="0155">The restricting portion <b>550</b> is a rib formed at an inner face of the plate-like member <b>427</b>, in the main scanning direction Y.</p>
<p id="p-0157" num="0156">The restricting portion <b>550</b> is engaged with a groove <b>551</b>, which is formed on an outer side of the outer wall portion <b>3112</b>, to restrict rotational movement about the optical axis AX.</p>
<p id="p-0158" num="0157">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 83</figref>, the light guiding member <b>340</b> and the LED substrate <b>430</b> (LED <b>410</b>) are positioned to the holding member <b>420</b> with a predetermined positional relationship. Since the holding member <b>420</b> is positioned and held to the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a</i>, the light guiding member <b>340</b> and the LED <b>410</b>, which are positioned to the holding member <b>420</b>, are positioned with respect to the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0159" num="0158">The holding member <b>420</b> described above has a first holding portion <b>422</b>, a second holding portion <b>423</b>, and a light reflecting portion <b>421</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0160" num="0159">The holding member <b>420</b> holds the LED <b>410</b> by the first holding portion <b>422</b>, such that the optical axis AX of the LED <b>410</b> is aligned with the main scanning direction Y. Moreover, the holding member <b>420</b> holds the light guiding member <b>340</b> by the second holding portion <b>423</b>, such that the central axis CS of the light guiding member <b>340</b> is substantially coaxial with the optical axis AX.</p>
<p id="p-0161" num="0160">Descriptions are hereinafter provided in detail for the LED <b>410</b>, the LED substrate <b>430</b>, the light guiding member <b>340</b> and the holding member <b>420</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0162" num="0161">The LED <b>410</b> is a Light Emitting Diode (LED) that functions as the light emitting portion. In the present embodiment, a single LED <b>410</b> is employed.</p>
<p id="p-0163" num="0162">The LED <b>410</b> is disposed on a side of a tip end <b>340</b><i>b </i>of the light guiding member <b>340</b>. More specifically, the LED <b>410</b> is disposed such that a light emitting face thereof faces an end face of the tip end <b>340</b><i>b </i>of the light guiding member <b>340</b>. The LED <b>410</b> emits light toward the end face of the tip end <b>340</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0164" num="0163">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the LED <b>410</b> is mounted on the LED substrate <b>430</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0165" num="0164">The LED substrate <b>430</b> is positioned and held at a predetermined position (a predetermined orientation) of the holding member <b>420</b> by the first holding portion <b>422</b> that is formed on an end side of the holding member <b>420</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0166" num="0165">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the first holding portion <b>422</b> has a pair of positioning protrusions <b>422</b><i>a </i>and <b>422</b><i>b</i>. The positioning protrusions <b>422</b><i>a </i>and <b>422</b><i>b </i>protrude from an outer surface of the plate-like member <b>427</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0167" num="0166">The positioning protrusions <b>422</b><i>a </i>and <b>422</b><i>b </i>are mated with positioning holes <b>435</b><i>a </i>and <b>435</b><i>b </i>of the LED substrate <b>430</b>. The positioning protrusions <b>422</b><i>a </i>and <b>422</b><i>b </i>position the LED <b>410</b> mounted on the LED substrate <b>430</b> such that the light emitting face of the LED <b>41</b>.<b>0</b> faces the end face of the light guiding member <b>340</b> on a side of the tip end <b>340</b><i>b </i>in the main scanning direction Y.</p>
<p id="p-0168" num="0167">The positioning protrusions <b>422</b><i>a </i>and <b>422</b><i>b </i>(the first holding portion <b>422</b>) indirectly position and hold the LED <b>410</b> via the LED substrate <b>430</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0169" num="0168">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the light guiding member <b>340</b> is a stick-like light guiding member that is disposed along the main scanning direction Y. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11 and 12</figref>, a cross-sectional shape of the light guiding member <b>340</b> is substantially polygonal. The light guiding member <b>340</b> is a light guiding member that is composed of acrylic resin or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0170" num="0169">Both ends of the light guiding member <b>340</b> are positioned and held by the holding member <b>420</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0171" num="0170">More specifically, the tip end <b>340</b><i>b </i>is positioned and held to the second holding portion <b>423</b> (a tip end hole portion <b>423</b><i>b</i>) that is formed in the holding member <b>420</b>. The base end <b>340</b><i>a </i>is positioned and held to the second holding portion <b>423</b> (a base end hole portion <b>423</b><i>a</i>). Accordingly, the light guiding member <b>340</b> is positioned and held to the holding member <b>420</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0172" num="0171">An end face on a side of the tip end <b>340</b><i>b </i>of the light guiding member <b>340</b> is disposed to face the light emitting face of the LED <b>410</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0173" num="0172">The light guiding member <b>340</b> guides light, which is emitted from the LED <b>410</b> disposed on the side of the tip end <b>340</b><i>b</i>, not only in a longitudinal direction (the main scanning direction) of the light guiding member <b>340</b>, but also to the light irradiating portion <b>341</b> (to be described later).</p>
<p id="p-0174" num="0173">The light guiding member <b>340</b> has the light irradiating portion <b>341</b> that is formed at a part of an outer periphery along the main scanning direction Y. The light irradiating portion <b>3411</b> emits internally-guided light outside.</p>
<p id="p-0175" num="0174">The light irradiating portion <b>341</b> is disposed in a predetermined direction, such that the first reader surface <b>302</b>A or the second reader surface <b>302</b>B can be irradiated with light, in a state where the light guiding member <b>340</b> is held to the first frame <b>311</b> via the holding member <b>420</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0176" num="0175">Moreover, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, the light guiding member <b>340</b> has convex portions <b>342</b>, <b>343</b> and <b>344</b> on the outer periphery, which extend along the longitudinal direction (the main scanning direction Y). The purpose of the convex portions <b>342</b>, <b>343</b> and <b>344</b> is to prevent the light guiding member <b>340</b> from being attached in a wrong orientation when the light guiding member <b>340</b> is held to the holding member <b>420</b> during production.</p>
<p id="p-0177" num="0176">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, the convex portion <b>342</b> is located on the outer periphery substantially opposite to (in an opposite position of) the light irradiating portion <b>341</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0178" num="0177">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 to 12</figref>, the convex portion <b>342</b> extends over an entirety of the light guiding member <b>340</b> in the longitudinal direction thereof. A tip face <b>342</b><i>a </i>of the convex portion <b>342</b> is a flat face that is orthogonal to a protruding direction (a direction indicated by an arrow R<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) of the convex portion <b>342</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0179" num="0178">The convex portions <b>343</b> and <b>344</b> each lie between the light irradiating portion <b>341</b> and the convex portion <b>342</b> on the outer periphery. The convex portion <b>343</b> and the convex portion <b>344</b> are located to be opposite to each other. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, protruding directions of the convex portion <b>343</b> and the convex portion <b>344</b> are each configured to be aligned with a direction (a direction indicated by an arrow R<b>2</b>) orthogonal to the protruding direction (the direction indicated by the arrow R<b>1</b>) of the convex portion <b>342</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0180" num="0179">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, the convex portions <b>343</b> and <b>344</b> each lie on the side of the base end <b>340</b><i>a </i>of the light guiding member <b>340</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0181" num="0180">More specifically, the convex portions <b>343</b> and <b>344</b> are each formed only in a predetermined range of length from the base end <b>340</b><i>a</i>, but not formed on a side of the tip end <b>340</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0182" num="0181">In addition, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, each of the convex portions <b>343</b> and <b>344</b> is configured to be a tapered ridge, in which a protruding height in a radial direction of the light guiding member <b>340</b> progressively decreases as a distance from the base end <b>340</b><i>a </i>increases. Moreover, a tip face <b>343</b><i>a </i>of the convex portion <b>343</b> and a tip face <b>344</b><i>a </i>of the convex portion <b>344</b> are flat faces that are orthogonal to the protruding direction (the direction indicated by the arrow R<b>2</b>) shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0183" num="0182">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the holding member <b>420</b> has the light reflecting portion <b>421</b>, the first holding portion <b>422</b>, the second holding portion <b>423</b>, and the positioned portion <b>510</b> (the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>and the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b</i>). The holding member <b>420</b> positions and holds the LED <b>410</b> and the light guiding member <b>340</b> in predetermined positions and orientations.</p>
<p id="p-0184" num="0183">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the light reflecting portion <b>421</b> is disposed to face the light irradiating portion <b>341</b> on the outer peripheral surface of the light guiding member <b>340</b>. The light reflecting portion <b>421</b> is disposed to face the light guiding member <b>340</b> over an entirety thereof in the longitudinal direction (the main scanning direction Y).</p>
<p id="p-0185" num="0184">The light reflecting portion <b>421</b> is disposed on the outer periphery of the light guiding member <b>340</b>, and has an inner light-reflecting face. When light is emitted from the outer periphery of the light guiding member <b>340</b> toward the inner face (the light is leaked from the light guiding member <b>340</b>), the inner face reflects the light toward the light guiding member <b>340</b>. When the light is leaked from the light guiding member <b>340</b>, the inner face reflects the light in the same direction as a direction of the light emitted from the light irradiating portion <b>341</b>, thereby increasing the irradiation efficiency of the light guiding member <b>340</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0186" num="0185">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the first holding portion <b>422</b> has the pair of positioning protrusions <b>422</b><i>a </i>and <b>422</b><i>b </i>formed on the plate-like member <b>427</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0187" num="0186">The positioning protrusions <b>422</b><i>a </i>and <b>422</b><i>b </i>are inserted into the positioning holes <b>435</b><i>a </i>and <b>435</b><i>b </i>of the LED substrate <b>430</b>, thereby positioning and holding the LED substrate <b>430</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0188" num="0187">The positioning protrusions <b>422</b><i>a </i>and <b>422</b><i>b </i>(the first holding portion <b>422</b>) position and hold the LED <b>410</b> mounted on the LED substrate <b>430</b> via the LED substrate <b>430</b>, such that the LED <b>410</b> faces the end face of the light guiding member <b>340</b> on a side of the ti end <b>340</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0189" num="0188">The positioning protrusions <b>422</b><i>a </i>and <b>422</b><i>b </i>(the first holding portion <b>422</b>) hold the LED <b>410</b>, such that the optical axis AX is aligned with the main scanning direction Y.</p>
<p id="p-0190" num="0189">Here, in the present embodiment, the optical axis AX refers to a central line (axis) of emitted beams of light. The optical axis AX is formed, for example, along a direction perpendicular to a light-emitting surface. The optical axis AX is, for example, a line (axis) that extends from a center of gravity of the light-emitting surface in a planar shape in a direction perpendicular to the light-emitting surface.</p>
<p id="p-0191" num="0190">For a case where the planar shape of the light-emitting surface is square or rectangular, the optical axis AX is, for example, a line (axis) that extends from an intersecting point of diagonal lines thereof in a direction perpendicular to the light-emitting surface. Moreover, for a case where the planar shape of the light-emitting surface is circular, the optical axis AX is, for example, a line (axis) that extends from a central point thereof in a direction perpendicular to the light-emitting surface.</p>
<p id="p-0192" num="0191">The holding member <b>420</b> has the base end hole portion <b>423</b><i>a </i>and the tip end hole portion <b>423</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0193" num="0192">The base end <b>340</b><i>a </i>of the light guiding member <b>340</b> is mated with the base end hole portion <b>423</b><i>a</i>. The tip end <b>340</b><i>b </i>of the light guiding member <b>340</b> is mated with the tip end hole portion <b>423</b><i>b</i>. In this manner, the holding member <b>420</b> positions and holds the light guiding member <b>340</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0194" num="0193">The base end hole portion <b>423</b><i>a </i>and the tip end hole portion <b>423</b><i>b </i>(the second holding portion <b>423</b>) position the light guiding member <b>340</b>, such that the light guiding member <b>340</b> is located in a predetermined positional relationship with the light reflecting portion <b>421</b>, and hold the light guiding member <b>340</b> such that the central axis CS is substantially coaxial with the optical axis.</p>
<p id="p-0195" num="0194">Here, in the present embodiment, the central axis CS refers to a central line (axis) that extends in a longitudinal direction of the light guiding member <b>340</b>. The central axis CS is, for example, a line (axis) that passes through the center of a cross section of the light guiding member <b>340</b>, and extends in the longitudinal direction thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0196" num="0195">The central axis CS is, for example, a line (axis) that passes through a center of gravity of a cross section of the light guiding member <b>340</b> perpendicular to the longitudinal direction and extends in the longitudinal direction.</p>
<p id="p-0197" num="0196">For a case where the planar shape of the light-emitting surface is square or rectangular, the central axis CS is, for example, a line (axis) that passes through an intersecting point of diagonal lines thereof, and extends in the longitudinal direction. Moreover, for a case where the planar shape of the light-emitting surface is circular, the central axis CS is, for example, a line (axis) that passes through a central point thereof, and extends in the longitudinal direction.</p>
<p id="p-0198" num="0197">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, the base end hole portion <b>423</b><i>a </i>is a substantially hexagonal through-hole that is formed in the holding member <b>420</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0199" num="0198">The base end hole portion <b>423</b><i>a </i>includes a guiding groove <b>4231</b>, a first flat edge <b>4232</b>, a second flat edge <b>4233</b> and a contactless edge <b>4234</b>. The convex portion <b>342</b> of the light guiding member <b>340</b> mates with the guiding groove <b>4231</b> slidably in the main scanning direction Y. The tip face <b>343</b><i>a </i>of the convex portion <b>343</b> is in surface contact with the first flat edge <b>4232</b> slidably in the main scanning direction Y. The tip face <b>344</b><i>a </i>of the convex portion <b>344</b> is in surface contact with the second flat edge <b>4233</b> slidably in the main scanning direction Y. The contactless edge <b>4234</b> faces the guiding groove <b>4231</b> in the inner periphery edge, and is not in contact with the outer periphery of the light guiding member <b>340</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0200" num="0199">The base end hole portion <b>423</b><i>a </i>positions the base end <b>340</b><i>a </i>of the light guiding member <b>340</b>, such that the base end <b>340</b><i>a </i>is restricted from rotating and moving in the main scanning direction Y, through mating of the convex portion <b>343</b> with the guiding groove <b>4231</b>, surface contact of the first flat edge <b>4232</b> with the convex portion <b>342</b>, and surface contact of the second flat edge <b>4233</b> with the convex portion <b>344</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0201" num="0200">Here, the guiding groove <b>4231</b> is configured to guide movement of the light guiding member <b>340</b>, and suppresses the light guiding member <b>340</b> from being inserted in an irregular manner (at a different rotation angle).</p>
<p id="p-0202" num="0201">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, the tip end hole portion <b>423</b><i>b </i>is a substantially square through-hole that is formed in the plate-like member <b>427</b> of the holding member <b>420</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0203" num="0202">The tip end hole portion <b>423</b><i>b </i>includes a guiding groove <b>4236</b>, a third flat edge <b>4237</b>, a fourth flat edge <b>4238</b> and a contactless edge <b>4239</b>. The convex portion <b>342</b> of the light guiding member <b>340</b> mates with the guiding groove <b>4236</b> slidably in the main scanning direction Y. A first outer peripheral plane <b>346</b> forming an outer periphery of the light guiding member <b>340</b> is in surface contact with the third flat edge <b>4237</b> slidably in the main scanning direction Y. A second outer peripheral plane <b>347</b> facing the first outer peripheral plane <b>346</b> is in surface contact with the fourth flat edge <b>4238</b> slidably in the main scanning direction Y. The contactless edge <b>4239</b> faces the guiding groove <b>4236</b>, and is not in contact with the outer periphery of the light guiding member <b>340</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0204" num="0203">The tip end hole portion <b>423</b><i>b </i>positions the tip end <b>340</b><i>b </i>of the light guiding member <b>340</b>, such that the tip end <b>340</b><i>b </i>is restricted from rotating and moving in the main scanning direction Y through mating the convex portion <b>342</b> with the guiding groove <b>4236</b>, surface contact of the third flat edge <b>4237</b> with the first outer peripheral plane <b>346</b> and surface contact of the fourth flat edge <b>4238</b> with the second outer peripheral plane <b>347</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0205" num="0204">As described above, both ends of the light guiding member <b>340</b> in the main scanning direction Y are held to the holding member <b>420</b> by the second holding portion <b>423</b> (<b>423</b><i>a </i>and <b>423</b><i>b</i>). The light guiding member <b>340</b> is positioned and held to the holding member <b>420</b> in a state of being spaced away from the light reflecting portion <b>421</b>. Both ends of the light guiding member <b>340</b> are in contact with the holding member <b>420</b>, and an intermediate portion of the light guiding member <b>340</b> is maintained spaced away from the holding member <b>420</b>. Accordingly, even if the light guiding member <b>340</b> is deformed due to thermal expansion or the like, the light guiding member <b>340</b> is prevented from being in contact with the light reflecting portion <b>421</b>. As a result, the light reflecting portion <b>421</b> is prevented from being deformed due to thermal expansion of the light guiding member <b>340</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0206" num="0205">In the present embodiment, the LED <b>410</b> is positioned and held to the holding member <b>420</b> by the first holding portion <b>422</b> via the LED substrate <b>430</b>. Moreover, the light guiding member <b>340</b> is positioned and held to the holding member <b>420</b> by the second holding portion <b>423</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0207" num="0206">In other words, the holding member <b>420</b> positions and holds the LED <b>410</b> and the light guiding member <b>340</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0208" num="0207">In addition, the holding member <b>420</b> is positioned and held to the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a </i>(the first frame <b>311</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0209" num="0208">As a result, such a simple configuration provides the image reading device <b>300</b> (the light emitting unit <b>400</b>), in which the LED <b>410</b> and the light guiding member <b>340</b> are accurately positioned.</p>
<p id="p-0210" num="0209">Furthermore, the lighting unit <b>400</b> (the image reading device <b>300</b>) includes the adjustment mechanism <b>600</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>) that is capable of adjusting the light irradiating portion <b>341</b> (the orientation of the light) after assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0211" num="0210">The adjustment mechanism <b>600</b> causes the holding member <b>420</b> to rotationally move, such that the light guiding member <b>340</b> rotates around the optical axis AX.</p>
<p id="p-0212" num="0211">The adjustment mechanism <b>600</b> is directly or indirectly coupled to the holding member <b>420</b>, and causes the holding member <b>420</b> to rotate such that the light guiding member <b>340</b> rotates around the optical axis AX.</p>
<p id="p-0213" num="0212">The adjustment mechanism <b>600</b> is configured to apply a force to the holding member <b>420</b> in a circumferential direction around the optical axis AX (in a direction of an arrow W).</p>
<p id="p-0214" num="0213">In the present embodiment, the holding member <b>420</b> is attached to the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a</i>, in a state where the cylindrical positioned portion <b>510</b> is inserted into the positioning portion <b>500</b> having a cylindrical inner face.</p>
<p id="p-0215" num="0214">As a result, when the adjustment mechanism <b>600</b> applies a predetermined force to the holding member <b>420</b> in the circumferential direction around the optical axis AX, the positioned portion <b>510</b> rotationally slides relative to the positioning portion <b>500</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0216" num="0215">In other words, since the holding member <b>420</b> rotates around the optical axis AX due to the force applied by the adjustment mechanism <b>600</b>, the LED <b>410</b> and the light guiding member <b>340</b>, which are positioned and held to the holding member <b>420</b>, also rotate around the optical axis AX (the central axis CS).</p>
<p id="p-0217" num="0216">As a result, the LED <b>410</b> rotates around the optical axis AX. Moreover, the LED <b>410</b> rotates while its positional relationship with the light guiding member <b>340</b> is maintained.</p>
<p id="p-0218" num="0217">As a result, the light guiding member <b>340</b> rotates around the optical axis AX so as to change the orientation of the light irradiating portion <b>341</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0219" num="0218">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the adjustment mechanism <b>600</b> has an adjustment operation portion <b>610</b> that is externally exposed.</p>
<p id="p-0220" num="0219">The adjustment operation portion <b>610</b> is disposed to be exposed externally from an arcuate cutout <b>615</b> formed at the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0221" num="0220">The adjustment operation portion <b>610</b> moves (or is guided) in an arc (in the direction of the arrow W). The adjustment operation portion <b>610</b> is coupled to the holding member <b>420</b> via a transfer mechanism (not shown). For example, the transfer mechanism may include cams, gears and screws. Moreover, the transfer mechanism may be a rod member or the like that directly couples the holding member <b>420</b> with the adjustment operation portion <b>610</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0222" num="0221">Movement (an operation by the user) of the adjustment operation portion <b>610</b> is transferred to the holding member <b>420</b> through the transfer mechanism.</p>
<p id="p-0223" num="0222">In other words, when the user moves the adjustment operation portion <b>610</b>, the holding member <b>420</b> rotates around the optical axis AX at a predetermined angle.</p>
<p id="p-0224" num="0223">Accordingly, the light guiding member <b>340</b>, which is positioned and held to the holding member <b>420</b>, rotates around the optical axis AX, thereby changing the orientation of the light irradiating portion <b>341</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0225" num="0224">For a case where the transfer mechanism is configured as a member directly coupling the holding member <b>420</b> with the adjustment operation portion <b>610</b>, the adjustment operation portion <b>610</b> is configured to move around the optical axis AX in the circumferential direction. In such a case, it may be that the adjustment operation portion <b>610</b> is configured to be spaced away from the optical axis AX at a predetermined distance. For example, it may be that the adjustment operation portion <b>610</b> is configured to be spaced away from the optical axis AX at least 50 mm, preferably at least 80 mm, and more preferably at least 100 mm. The reason for this is that such spacing allows fine adjustment of the rotation angle of the light guiding member <b>340</b> (the orientation of the light irradiating portion <b>341</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0226" num="0225">Next, descriptions are provided for assembly steps of the light emitting unit <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0227" num="0226">Firstly, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, an operator inserts the light guiding member <b>340</b> into the base end hole portion <b>423</b><i>a </i>of the holding member <b>420</b>, while the tip end <b>340</b><i>b </i>is placed on the front side. More specifically, the operator mates the convex portion <b>342</b> with the guiding groove <b>4231</b>, and inserts the tip end <b>340</b><i>b </i>into the base end hole portion <b>423</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0228" num="0227">Subsequently, the operator further inserts the light guiding member <b>340</b> in a direction of an arrow F. In addition, the operator mates the tip end <b>340</b><i>b </i>of the light guiding member <b>340</b> with the tip end hole portion <b>423</b><i>b</i>, and mates the base end <b>340</b><i>a </i>with the base end hole portion <b>423</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0229" num="0228">In this manner, the light guiding member <b>340</b> is held to the holding member <b>420</b>, such that the positional relationship with the light reflecting portion <b>421</b> and the orientation of the light irradiating portion <b>341</b> are adjusted.</p>
<p id="p-0230" num="0229">Subsequently, the operator attaches the LED substrate <b>430</b> to the holding member <b>420</b>. More specifically, the operator attaches the LED substrate <b>430</b> to the holding member <b>420</b>, by mating the positioning protrusions <b>422</b><i>a </i>and <b>422</b><i>b </i>(the first holding portion <b>422</b>), which are formed on the holding member <b>420</b>, with the positioning holes <b>435</b><i>a </i>and <b>435</b><i>b</i>, which are formed in the LED substrate <b>430</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0231" num="0230">As a result, the LED <b>410</b> is held via the LED substrate <b>430</b> at a position where the light emitting face of the LED <b>410</b> faces the end face of the light guiding member <b>340</b> on a side of the tip end <b>340</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0232" num="0231">Subsequently, the operator attaches the holding member <b>420</b>, which holds the LED <b>410</b> and the light guiding member <b>340</b>, to the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a </i>(a component of the first frame <b>311</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0233" num="0232">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13A to 13C</figref>, the operator inserts the holding member <b>420</b> into a hollow portion of the positioned portion <b>510</b>, and subsequently attaches the holding member <b>420</b> to the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0234" num="0233">More specifically, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13A and 13B</figref>, the operator passes the first positioned portion <b>51</b><i>a </i>of the holding member <b>420</b> through the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>(hollow portion <b>502</b><i>b</i>).</p>
<p id="p-0235" num="0234">Subsequently, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13C</figref>, the operator further moves the holding member <b>420</b> in the insertion direction K, inserts the first positioned portion <b>510</b><i>a </i>into the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a</i>, and inserts the second positioned portion <b>510</b><i>b </i>into the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0236" num="0235">As a result, the holding member <b>420</b> is held to be positioned to the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a </i>(a component of the first frame <b>311</b>). More specifically, the holding member <b>420</b> is held to the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a </i>such that the holding member <b>420</b> is restricted from moving in a direction transverse to the main scanning direction Y.</p>
<p id="p-0237" num="0236">Subsequently, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the operator places the two cover members <b>311</b><i>b </i>and <b>311</b><i>c </i>so as to cover the upper opening of the main frame part <b>311</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0238" num="0237">In this manner, the light emitting unit <b>400</b> in the present embodiment is assembled.</p>
<p id="p-0239" num="0238">Next, the operator checks whether irradiation of light from the light guiding member <b>340</b> is at a predetermined angle.</p>
<p id="p-0240" num="0239">For a case where the irradiation of light from the light guiding member <b>340</b> is not at the predetermined angle (a predetermined position is not irradiated with light), the operator moves the adjustment operation portion <b>610</b> in the direction of the arrow W, and adjusts the irradiation angle of light from the light guiding member <b>340</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0241" num="0240">More specifically, when the operator moves the adjustment operation portion <b>610</b> in the direction of the arrow W, the movement of the adjustment operation portion <b>610</b> is transferred to the holding member <b>420</b> via the transfer mechanism (not shown). Accordingly, the holding member <b>420</b> rotates around the optical axis AX. In addition, since the light guiding member <b>340</b> held to the holding member <b>420</b> rotates around the optical axis AX, the orientation of the light irradiating portion <b>341</b> is changed (adjusted) Accordingly, the irradiation angle of light from the light guiding member <b>340</b> is changed (adjusted).</p>
<p id="p-0242" num="0241">According to the present embodiment, the image reading device is capable of accurately positioning the light guiding member with a simple configuration. The image reading device restricts movement in a direction, in particular, transverse to the main scanning direction Y (for example, upper, lower, left and right directions) with high accuracy.</p>
<p id="p-0243" num="0242">Moreover, the image reading device does not require any other fixing members when the holding member <b>420</b> is positioned and fixed. Accordingly, it is possible that the image reading device reduces the number of parts.</p>
<p id="p-0244" num="0243">In addition, since the image reading device positions and fixes the holding member without using any other fixing members, it is possible to suppress a decrease in accuracy of attachment due to accumulation of tolerances and production errors.</p>
<p id="p-0245" num="0244">Although a preferred embodiment has been described above, the present disclosure can be implemented in various modes without being limited to the aforementioned embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0246" num="0245">For example, the image forming apparatus of the present disclosure is not particularly limited, and may be a copy machine, a printer, a facsimile machine, or a multi-functional printer having functions thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0247" num="0246">The copying medium shaped like a sheet is not limited to paper, and may be a sheet of film, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0248" num="0247">Moreover, although the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>and the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>have cylindrical hollow portions in the image reading device according to the present embodiment, the present disclosure is not limited thereto. For example, the image reading device may be configured such that only one of the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>and the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>has a cylindrical hollow portion. For example, the image reading device may be configured such that only the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>has a cylindrical hollow portion.</p>
<p id="p-0249" num="0248">In addition, the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>and the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>may not be completely cylindrical, but may have a cylindrical inner face partially opened in the image reading device. For example, the image reading device may be configured such that the first positioning portion <b>500</b><i>a </i>has a completely cylindrical hollow portion, and the second positioning portion <b>500</b><i>b </i>has a cylindrical hollow portion partially opened.</p>
<p id="p-0250" num="0249">Here, &#x201c;partially opened&#x201d; represents that an aperture angle around the central axis CS is less than 180 degrees, preferably less than 90 degrees, or more preferably less than degrees, for example.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An image reading device, comprising:
<claim-text>a light emitting portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a stick-like light guiding member, of which end portion is disposed to face the light emitting portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a holding member configured to hold the light emitting portion and the light guiding member; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a case member to which the holding member is attached, wherein the holding member includes:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light reflecting portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first holding portion configured to hold the light emitting portion such that an optical axis thereof is aligned with a main scanning direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second holding portion configured to cause the light guiding member to be positioned with respect to the light reflecting portion, and to hold the light guiding member such that a central axis thereof is substantially coaxial with the optical axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first positioned portion that is formed at one end part of the holding member in the main scanning direction; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second positioned portion that is formed at another end part of the holding member in the main scanning direction, and wherein the case member includes:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first positioning portion which is formed integrally with the case member and into which the first positioned portion is inserted, the first positioning portion being configured to restrict the first positioned portion thus inserted from moving in a direction transverse to the main scanning direction; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second positioning portion which is formed integrally with the case member and into which the second positioned portion is inserted, the second positioning portion being configured to restrict the second positioned portion thus inserted from moving in a direction transverse to the main scanning direction.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The image reading device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first positioning portion is disposed at an inner part with respect to a direction in which the holding member is inserted into the case member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The image reading device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the first positioning portion includes:</claim-text>
<claim-text>an inner face configured to be cylindrically opened or partly cylindrically opened; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a hollow portion formed by the inner face.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The image reading device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the first positioning portion is configured to be such that a central axis of the cylindrical hollow portion is substantially coaxial with an optical axis of the light guiding member, in a state where the first positioned portion is inserted into the first positioning portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The image reading device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein an outer face of the first positioned portion is configured to be cylindrical so as to correspond to the inner face of the first positioning portion, and the first positioned portion is mated with the first positioning portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The image reading device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the second positioning portion includes an inner face configured to be cylindrically opened or partly cylindrically opened and a hollow portion formed by the inner face, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein an inner diameter of the cylindrical hollow portion of the second positioning portion is larger than an inner diameter of the cylindrical hollow portion of the first positioning portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The image reading device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first positioning portion and the second positioning portion are configured to support the holding member rotationally around the optical axis via the first positioned portion and the second positioned portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The image reading device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the holding member includes a restricting portion configured to restrict a rotational movement of the holding member around the optical axis.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The image reading device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, further comprising an adjustment mechanism configured to cause the holding member to rotationally move such that the light guiding member rotationally moves around the optical axis.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. An image forming apparatus comprising an image reading device,
<claim-text>the image reading device comprising:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light emitting portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a stick-like light guiding member, of which end portion is disposed to face the light emitting portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a holding member configured to hold the light emitting portion and the light guiding member; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a case member to which the holding member is attached,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the holding member includes:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light reflecting portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first holding portion configured to hold the light emitting portion such that an optical axis thereof is aligned with a main scanning direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second holding portion configured to cause the light guiding member to be positioned with respect to the light reflecting portion, and to hold the light guiding member such that a central axis thereof is substantially coaxial with the optical axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first positioned portion that is formed at one end part of the holding member in the main scanning direction; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second positioned portion that is formed at another end part of the holding member in the main scanning direction, and wherein the case member includes:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first positioning portion, which is formed integrally with the case member and into which the first positioned portion is inserted, the first positioning portion being configured to restrict the first positioned portion thus inserted from moving in a direction transverse to the main scanning direction; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second positioning portion, which is formed integrally with the case member and into which the second positioned portion is inserted, the second positioning portion being configured to restrict the second positioned portion thus inserted from moving in a direction transverse to the main scanning direction.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. An image reading device, comprising:
<claim-text>a light emitting portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a stick-like light guiding member, of which end portion is disposed to face the light emitting portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a holding member configured to hold the light emitting portion and the light guiding member; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a case member to which the holding member is attached,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the holding member includes:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first positioned portion that is formed at one end part of the holding member in a main scanning direction; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second positioned portion that is formed at another end part of the holding member in the main scanning direction, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the case member includes:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first positioning portion which is formed integrally with the case member and into which the first positioned portion is inserted, the first positioning portion being configured to restrict the first positioned portion thus inserted from moving in a direction transverse to the main scanning direction; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second positioning portion which is formed integrally with the case member and into which the second positioned portion is inserted, the second positioning portion being configured to restrict the second positioned portion thus inserted from moving in a direction transverse to the main scanning direction. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
